[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff and
this is episode
676 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of patreon questions before we
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of the great
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to jessica k i want to send a thank you
shout out to nick a let's send a big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
blackhawks fan i want to send a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter
pack northwest dan let's send a thank
you shout out to my good friend lefty's
farm let's send a thank you shout out
and a fist bump to nick p let's follow
that up with a thank you shout out to my
buddy mister let's send another thank
you shout out to ken of reaper let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to frankie i want to send a big
thank you shout out to rasufa then let's
wrap it all up with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to ivan m
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description this
is also the part of the show where i do
invite you to join the discord server
we're at approximately 1500 members on
the discord server i think you would
have a good time over there come join us
if you like the podcast if you like my
ramblings if you're into growing ganja
if you're into growing from seed if
you're into growing from clone if you're
into the cannabis community i think my
discord server is a great spot for you
come join the server come join the party
we're smoking out we're talking about
growing we're doing yoga over there
we're talking about sports we're talking
about all kinds of great stuff come join
us on the discord server there is a link
in the show notes and in the video
description and once again big shout out
to everybody who hangs out on the
discord server it wouldn't be quite the
same without you there all right where
do we go from here i get to talk about
being in the greenhouse if you've been
watching the show i'm sure you've heard
me talk about the greenhouse project
i've got going on that's right i did
some breeding in a greenhouse i was at
the greenhouse earlier today my fingers
are still sticky my arm hair is still
sticky but i am super excited because
the seeds that are happening in that
greenhouse are almost ready they're
getting super hard they're getting a
nice dark color to them they're getting
some tiger stripes they look really
really good i'm really excited so pretty
soon we will have some outdoor bred irie
genetic seeds i was amazed i've talked
about this before on the show i'm just
kind of talking about it again because
i'm excited i like to give you guys
updates on what's going on with my
projects uh bring you in make you feel
included but i am super excited those
plants happened much more quickly than i
expected it to happen they were ready
for pollen earlier than i anticipated uh
the pollen dumped earlier than
anticipated
the seeds hardened up much more quickly
so i learned a lot this year with our
inaugural outdoor run people have been
asking a lot of questions since i've
been hinting about what i put out there
i'll give you a couple of a couple of
ideas of what went out there this year i
did put an arise male the king solomon
male was in the greenhouse so everything
that got pollinated uh was pollinated by
king solomon the first male that i
should talk about that we put out there
was the platinum tangy why did i put
platinum tangy out there because that
makes sun-kissed seeds i'm very familiar
with the platinum tangy plant and i'm
very familiar with the sun-kissed cross
so i'll be able to tell what that
platinum tangy plant is doing outdoors
compared to what it does indoors then
once the seeds are made i've got plenty
of that makes sun kisses what that makes
i've got plenty of sun-kissed seeds that
were made indoors now i've got sun kiss
made outdoors now the next move is to
grow both of those in similar conditions
and see if the outdoor produced seeds
show any difference than the indoor
produced seeds of the same cross they
use the same exact genetics but one was
made indoors one was made in a
greenhouse i personally honestly
realistically do not know if we will see
any difference in the expression um
there were different things in the
environment which may uh fall in line in
epigenetics or i don't know how it may
work they may there may be differences
what is what i'm saying and i want to
grow them i'm excited to find out so we
started off with that platinum tangy
outdoors there is a blueberry cookies
plant outdoor so that we can make more
blue raspberry truffle a lot of people
are asking for blue raspberry truffle
seeds we're making some outdoors there
is a mandarin sunset plant outside so we
can make more of the lady marmalade
there are some new things some things
that i'm making brand new crosses of and
there are others out there that we don't
need to talk about right now i do like
leaving a little bit of suspense got to
build that suspense a little bit we'll
talk more about what's out there in the
future but i wanted to kind of tease you
a little bit they're getting the seeds
are getting hard the buds are getting
fat they're so sticky and so stinky
i was out there at the greenhouse and
then i had to run a couple of errands
and everywhere i went after that they
gave me dirty looks because i was
stinking so good it was beautiful it's a
beautiful aroma but it went so fast it
happened so quickly i was amazed so next
year we're going to do things a little
bit but a lot a bit differently and we
should produce two or three times as
many seeds next year i'm excited get
excited with me because pretty soon i
will be sending these seeds out for
testers all right now i do want to take
a moment to give my buddy mike a shout
out if you are a follower of the podcast
you know that oftentimes i do have my
buddy white mike on the podcast uh mike
is my buddy he does the uh we say that i
do the grow part of the house i do all
the everything that involves plants that
is my job the part that involves
paperwork uh contacting the lawyer uh
all of that stuff that is sort of mike's
department so we say that mike handles
the front of the house i handle the back
of the house uh mike is kind of my tag
team partner when it comes to the
cannabis industry big shout out to mike
for his all of his hard work dedication
to our industry and our community what
i'm heading at you guys is mike has a
patreon page where he has recently
posted a great patreon post you can go
read his post if you are interested in
becoming a cannabis activist a cannabis
advocate if you want to be involved if
you want to go to city council and speak
if you want some ammo if you want some
education mike is a great source of that
information a great source for that
education he recently posted a couple of
things on his patreon that i think would
be beneficial for you to read if you
want to be active in this community so
big up to my buddy mike go check him out
at patreon.com forward slash white mike
and really briefly i'll just explain why
we call him white mike uh mike is my
buddy that i'm a white guy with
dreadlocks i know that that's a cliche
thing but i'm the white guy with
dreadlocks smoking a fat joint with the
music too loud in the car driving too
fast and mike will politely remind me
he'll say hey buddy you're the white guy
with dreadlocks with the music too loud
smoking a joint driving too fast pick
one or two of those and only do one or
two of those at a time or you're gonna
go to jail today and i'd be like yeah
you're kind of right buddy and so it's
kind of a joke that i call him white
mike he's just just make sure to follow
the rules he's a super uptight white guy
but i need that on my team because i'm
the [ __ ] opposite we create a good
balance
so that's why you got the name white
mike
just a white dude super he listens to
311 and where's jenko's uh what more
white dude could you ask for right big
shout out to my buddy white mike nothing
but love for that guy good dude uh i
read genetics in the podcast would not
be here without mike's encouragement
support advice and activism so big up
dude thank you go support white mike
that's enough rambling and kissing
mike's ass let's move forward i do have
some patreon questions here laid out in
front of me big up to everybody that
supports the show on patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart which
one do we read first i think i'm going
to grab this one right here it's just to
the left of me convenient um this one
came from do they want their name said
they signed their name j6 big up to j6
at j6 organics this question says ross
to jeff i hope you were keeping well and
feeling irie my brother i'm feeling
great thank you i hope you're feeling
irie hope things are good hope the
plants look good hope the garden is
going well it says here i enjoyed
listening to your girl from your heart
podcast shows and recently i stumbled
upon episode 602 where you speak in
detail about the silver thiosulfate
recipe and the method used in creating
your solution yes thank you for
listening bro i'm hoping that that's
working well for you i hope you're on
the path to making some silver
thiosulfate and some femme seeds and
thank you for listening by the way it
does say here is my question upon mixing
the two-part solution together this
solution is further diluted to a
one-to-nine ratio sounds like you're on
the right path we've made one liter and
we use up to 100 milliliters so yeah if
you got a one to nine um you didn't
mention anything about storing the other
900 milliliters that is a good uh good
point to bring up can this solution be
stored if so what's the best practice
for storage and what is the shelf life
yes you can store that solution the best
practice would be to keep it cold the
colder the better uh the colder you can
keep that solution the better it is
ideally and i probably should have
mentioned this before we got to this
point ideally it would store better uh
let me start from the very very
beginning we're gonna do a good better
best sort of situation here they store
better as powders non-diluted into
anything the powder by itself in the
refrigerator in a cool dry dark place is
the best way to store it so keep the
powder stored that lasts forever then
the next longest storage method is to
have uh part a and part b mixed into the
water but not mixed together those will
last longer then when you mix them
together they last a little bit less
time so i hope i said that in the
correct manner uh don't mix them they
last the longest
parts a and b
the powder into the water will last a
little less longer and then once you
cross them all together mix them all
together it lasts even less longer so um
the best way possible would be keep it
powder then keep them divided then once
you mix it you can store it in a cool
dry dark place like the refrigerator
i've got a jar in the fridge now an
important important note if you're going
to put your silver thiosulfate in the
refrigerator make sure to clearly mark
what that stuff is it is clear it's
odorless we don't want anybody drinking
it i do not think it would be harmful if
you took a couple of swigs out of that
but let's not give that any risk let's
not give that an opportunity clearly
label that silver thiosulfate if you've
got children in the house people that
can't read people that drink i'm not
trying to judge anybody but let's set
them up for success let's set ourselves
up for success let's clearly label that
that is silver thiosulfate maybe put a
ring of tape around the the rim of the
jar or the bottle so that nobody can
easily pull that open so if they do open
it they go why the [ __ ] is there
electrical tape or duct tape on my my
moonshine or my jar of water here make
them think another step before they pour
that silver thiosulfate down their golet
and make themselves sick and blame it on
you
set yourself up for success set
everybody in your house up for success
by clearly labeling the silver
thiosulfate that is stored in your
fridge mine is in a bag and then it's
labeled and then it's clear i'm the only
one here that goes in the fridge nobody
else is going in there so if anybody
else goes in there drink it they're an
intruder and uh they can have the
diarrhea that it gives them i'm proud of
them um so you can store it in the
fridge is the best way cool dry dark
place it stores where well cold you know
i've never honestly stored any for too
long i make the one to nine ratio and
then i use the hundred milliliters and
that you're correct and then i make the
bottle a spray and then i spray the
plant but then i use that again in three
days i pour more of that into the
container and when i spray i spray the
[ __ ] out of the plant so i use the whole
leader i never uh over the course of a
feminized project i don't have any left
i'll use that entire leader so
i usually don't store it for very long i
don't know how long it can be stored for
me silver thiosulfate is super
affordable super cheap to make it
doesn't cost that much for 20 or 30
bucks you can make gallons of it so i
just make a fresh batch every time i'm
trying to make new feminized seeds i've
got a batch mixed up now because i'm
actually beginning to make some new
seeds that's a good segue right guys we
didn't talk about that i am starting to
make more feminized seeds a lot of
people are asking for uh the orange gasm
the golden goats the lemon jeffries and
a couple of other things they are in the
works you guys have started that so give
me a little bit of time don't rush me be
patient let me get it done correctly but
feminized seeds are coming i know you
want them i know they're in high demand
people have practically been begging for
the femme seeds it takes a lot of time
it takes a lot of space to make them i
did have other projects ahead of that
there was a learning curve learning to
adjust and breed in a whole room with
led lighting so um yeah give me some
patience and we'll get those femme seats
coming up uh they're they're in the
works you guys all right so you can
store the silver thio sulfate in a cool
dry dark place
it's so cheap that i honestly just make
more of it and i really don't store a
lot of it because i use all of what i
make to reverse the plants that i'm
working with so i just make that one
liter uh use that you're going to use it
for the next 20. honestly i start
reversing a plant sometimes up to two
weeks before i'm gonna flip it so two
weeks before flower it gets a spray a
week before a flower it gets a spray the
day before flower it gets a spray then
every three days for 21 days it'll get a
spray so i'm going to spray it 10 times
ish
maybe a couple of more if if that plant
takes a long time if it's a longer
flowering sativa i'll spray it more
times even into flour just to remind it
hey [ __ ] don't go back to veg keep
making those flowering balls keep making
pollen for me i'm just reminding it just
giving it the the spray that it needs to
keep doing that
encouraging it to keep producing pollen
for me so i spray it enough to where i
use all of it i don't ever have any
leftovers and then i just make more next
time because it's very cost effective if
you're doing it correctly it is very
very cost effective this is one of the
most affordable ingredients that we can
buy for the garden is making our own
silver biosulfate so i think i covered
most of that what's the best place to
store it and what's the shelf life i
honestly don't know the exact shelf life
because i've never uh it's never lasted
me that long it's like asking me the
shelf life life of cheesecake i don't
it's never lasted that long dude never
gotten to that point so um i don't know
i wish i could give you better info on
that but i really i would be lying and
making some [ __ ] up and that's not how i
do the show so uh big respect thank you
for the great question uh store it in
the fridge uh label it make sure
everybody in the household knows that
that stuff is not to drink with uh not
to drink not to make any food don't
consume that then i think everything
will go well for you and just make more
dude it's super affordable it's kind of
fun to make it and then you know you
have a fresh
potent batch every time you work with it
because it does lose quality over time
here's one thing to think about if it
changes colors
it's going bad if it starts getting dark
if you start seeing stuff floating in it
if the lid of the jar starts turning
dark purple then it's probably time to
replace that you don't want to use that
product all right
thank you for the question bro i look
forward to some replies on this all
right i do have another question let's
see it says to read the one from cincy
so we're gonna grab this one right here
this one came from patreon this one came
from a person who i called cincy nasty
in the last episode and they have been
asked they've asked me to call them
cincy loco or cincy crazy so big shout
out to my buddy cynthia crazy they asked
why i called them cincynasty i'll
explain i'm a sneakerhead i recently
discovered some nike dunk sb lows that
said nasty boys on the back of them and
they are made for the cincinnati reds
team i don't care or know too much about
baseball no offense to baseball if
that's your thing go for it yay team i'm
very ignorant to sports and baseball but
i love these shoes and i read about them
to see why they said nasty boys on the
back there's a cincinnati reds team from
one year that there were three or four
players that just kicked ass and took
the team to the championship
uh go team go team but that's why the
shoes are called that so when i read the
word cincy i put nasty at the end of it
because they were the cincinnati reds
they were the nasty boys that's where
all that math came through in my head
hope i didn't offend you by calling you
cincy nasty also i have another friend
who goes by cincynasty on instagram so i
think it was just embedded in my brain
big shout out to my buddy cincy nasty
hope you're well bro haven't heard from
you in a long time he posts a lot of
great graffiti pictures he does not do
the graffiti he posts the pictures you
guys don't go paint [ __ ] that's not
yours unless you're really talented
all right let's get focused read this
message from my buddy cincy loco or
cinti crazy this one goes like this let
me kind of find the the meat because
there's a lot of stuff that's just for
me and not for you guys in this one it
says good evening great podcast this
week i thought you did an amazing job of
breaking down all the questions so
everyone can understand first of all
that is a huge compliment because i
understand that not everybody learns in
the same way
i'm kind of a hands-on learner i hated
school but i love to learn if that makes
any sense if you're the kind of teacher
that just sits there and reads from a
book and expects me to follow along and
then learn something i'm bored about a
page in especially if you've got an
annoying voice i've already checked out
i'm thinking about other stuff what i'm
going to do when i get out of your dumb
ass class
if you're a fun entertaining teacher if
you can let me touch some things and
play with them and try to break stuff
and rebuild it then i'm gonna learn some
[ __ ] so i'm glad that you see that i try
to teach from a lot of different angles
that's why i kind of repeat myself
that's why some things i beat it into
the ground because still some people
i'll i'll give i'll tell you a hundred
times that day one is when you flip the
plants 2 12 12 that's day one and i'll
still get 24 emails asking when is day
one so i've got to say things a lot of
different ways um all right it's gonna
go on it says it has been really cool
i've got uh so he talks about a grow
that he's working on that we've talked
about then it says um
so he's doing a little bit of breeding
and he's talking about his breeding
project the main question is since these
plants are autos i'm wondering is it
better to have a taller plant with a lot
of bud separation so everything gets
light or is a smaller bushier plant
better for thc production so he's asking
about phenotypical expression of the
shape of the plant and wondering which
will give better thc production now
unfortunately i do not have an answer on
that those are plants uh i don't know
the traits of those plants um you could
probably grow a hundred seeds of the
crust that you made and you could find
25 squat plants and 25 tall plants and
you're going to find different ratios of
cannabinoids through those phenotypes
especially since you've created um it's
not real it's kind of an f1 it's kind of
a polyhybrid you're going to find a i
said polyhybrid excuse me for that
you're going to find a huge mix of
progeny in there
so i'm really not sure um taller plant
with a lot of bud separation so
everything gets light or a smaller
bushier plant
most people are going to prefer a
shorter bushier plant if you're making
seeds to share with people sell to
people they're going to want the shorter
bushier plants
most people are growing indoors a large
percent of the people growing indoors
are growing in a tent those people are
gonna want shorter plants it's just
gonna make sense for them um
sometimes they sacrifice that short
bushy faster flowering time for the thc
potency so they and i think they
understand that i think that they know
that that is part of the gamble uh in my
opinion i think that you get a better
potency from a photoperiod plant but i
don't have anything to back that up
that's just from from what i i've seen
and i don't really have any science
sorry i'm talking about my ass let's get
back to focus uh then it says does this
matter at all all of the autos will get
you faded but not as heavily as the
regular photo period plants we have
grown so i think that statement backed
up what i was just trying to say uh this
person is growing autos and photos and
he says those autos get him faded but
not as much as the photoperiod plants uh
that does make sense the autos are kind
of in a hurry those photo periods they
got all day they're just gonna build up
potency build up the hormones and the
precursors to make that potency um so i
understand that now
it says my goal has two parts with this
project goal one is to increase the thc
and have plants that yield well uh so i
guess that's number two is plants that
yield well that's always a good goal
high potency high yields that's what
everybody wants you get a good lab test
it looks good on the label looks good on
the jar people want to buy it and smoke
it and then if there's a lot of it you
can sell a lot of that [ __ ] and make
some money so that's always a good goal
it says which fino will help me reach
that goal more quickly the tall fino or
the short fino i really have no way to
predict that i honestly don't have a way
to predict that a couple of things you
could do you could take the taller pheno
and the shorter pheno and get a lab test
of them which one of them gives you a
higher thc percentage then breed to that
one you've obviously got a higher thc
start
so you've got that ingredient that
you're looking for it's dominant you
know it's there use that one that is a
very good way to set yourself up for
success you know the ingredient you're
looking for is there um
so what i would do i would select a male
and i would pollinate both of them and i
know that sounds like a lot of work but
you just put the one male plant next to
your tall pheno next to your short fino
and you let them do their magic right
let them finish get the seeds out of
there the seeds are probably gonna take
six to eight weeks to finish cut the
both plants down label them tall and
skinny and short and squatty pull the
seeds out grow as many of the seeds as
you can from both of them
grow those seeds under scientifically
controlled conditions grow 50 or 100
tall and lanky seeds and grow 50 to 100
short and squatty seeds right next to
each other feed them exactly the same
give them the same environment make it
scientific acts like you got two little
kids in the room and if you give one one
extra [ __ ] cheez-it they're gonna
throw a fit act like you got little kids
in the room and feed them and treat them
all exactly the same and then see which
do you like better maybe you're gonna
find out that that thc isn't exactly
what you're looking for maybe one of
them has a terp that really [ __ ] you up
and gets you right where you need to be
it's not always about the thc that's
something really important to keep in
mind you may find a terpene you may find
a cannabinoid combination you may find a
few things that mix together in one of
those phenotypes that really blast you
just the way you need to get blasted
sometimes that's like what the breeders
discover for ourselves we have the
opportunity to breed and grow so many
seeds we find something unique to
ourselves then we discover that when we
share it it's unique to a lot of people
and they enjoy it as well so don't focus
too much on finding thc focus on finding
a very balanced plan a plant that grows
well a plant that produces well and then
it's got some terps what's the point of
having a plant that grows a lot of buds
and gets you really high if when you
smoke it it tastes like you're smoking
burnt pubes nobody's going to want to
smoke that it's not enjoyable no matter
how high it gets me probably not going
to smoke your buds it's smelling tastes
like burnt pubes it's got to have some
good terps to it some good aromas good
flavors good bag of peel good colors
it's got to be sticky there are a lot of
other things to think about that go
along with that thc so i understand the
desire for thc and high yield that's
what we want you want to get high and
you want a lot of it right but you got
to get some other things in there
let me get myself back on track what i
would do i would breed to both of those
i would take both your plants pollinate
them you've got seeds of both grow them
both see what you like here is something
that you can do early on to help you
decide how to move forward have you ever
thought about predicative testing we can
plant as many a population of seeds from
both so you got shortened squat cross to
your male uh you got tall and skinny
cross to your mail you got those seeds
growing you can get little test kits
that you can you basically open up fold
unfold a matchbook and you rub part of
the leaf tissue on the matchbook and you
close it back up and then you put a
number on it shorten squat plant number
two shorten squat plant number three and
continue label each one according to
what plant number you've got you send
those tests off to a laboratory they can
tell you if that plant is a male or a
female which is a great thing to have we
already can eliminate the plants we
don't need if we're looking for males
and females they can also detect the
presence of cannabinoid precursors which
means they can tell you if those plants
later on in their life will develop high
thc high cbd high thcv they can dictate
and pred and predict all of the
cannabinoids that may be present in that
plant they are in very very low
concentrations and low ratios at this
time but they know that if the presence
of this cannabinoid and this other i'm
not sure the detectors and the markers
on the test but they can say this plant
has potential for being a high thc
potency plant they can tell you that
when the plants are three four five or
six inches tall so you don't have to
waste a lot of time so if your main goal
is for potency you can send in a lab
test
and this is this is kind of new science
backwards breeding
be open-minded to this this is a new way
and a backwards way of doing it you can
send in a lab test then they will send
you back the numbers find the outliers
within those populations so if you're
looking for high thc and you've got 50
plants find the top 10 thc plants in
those tests and get rid of get rid of
the other 40. so you've got your 10
highest thc potency females left from
each side now you just went from 100
plants down to 20 and we know that these
are all going to be high thc highly
potent plants now we grow them we flour
them out we finish them and now we look
for all of the other traits which we may
desire to make those plants what we want
for the market for ourselves we already
know they're going to have high thc now
we find the one with the terps now we
find the one that doesn't get powdery
mildew now we find the one that grows
the way we want it to grow does it grow
tall and skinny does it grow short and
squat you find the one that works for
you is there one that tastes amazing do
a couple of them taste like burnt pubes
like we talked about earlier now you
already know that what you've got is all
high potency plants they're going to
have the potency you're looking for now
we just got to find the other markers in
that population so that's another option
is predicative testing to remove the
outliers or include the outliers from a
population then select from those that
will definitely minimize population
quite quickly but if you don't have
access and funding for that type of lab
what you would do is grow them dude grow
them out just like any other pheno hunt
and smoke them smoke them yourself smoke
them with your friends and see what
turns heads and what gets attention you
will know some stuff will definitely
turn some heads some stuff will get
ignored it may be completely different
for you and your crew i said earlier
maybe sometimes you'll create some [ __ ]
that everybody goes dude what is that
like i've been at concerts before and
lit up a joint and i've had everybody
for 50 feet turn and look at me like
what the [ __ ] are you smoking they've
all wanted to buy seeds or buy an eighth
off me and they all circled around like
vultures that's how you know you hit
gold sometimes you light up some weed
and you try to pass it to your friends
and they go
i'm good that smells like you're smoking
your fingernails over there
sometimes you smoke some [ __ ] that
you're like i'm not super fond of this
and you smoke it with one of your
friends and they're like dude i've got
this medical problem that i've had my
whole life and when i smoke that [ __ ] i
feel amazing and you're like when i
smoked it i didn't notice anything there
might be a terp a cannabinoid a compound
in there that works beautifully for
something they've got going on that's
always beautiful to find because then
you give them a clone of that plant or
you give them seeds or whatever you're
like here you go buddy that's your magic
medicine now that feels good that you've
helped out a friend for the rest of
their [ __ ] life they found relief
from something that bugged them for a
long time you didn't even know you made
their medicine i've had that happen
before big up to those people they know
who they are but the real answer here uh
the only real way to know this is to
grow out these seeds i would cross the
mail to the shortened squat i would
cross the mail the selected mail one
male pick one dude that you really like
pick one dude and pollinate all of the
plants the squatty and the tall one
pollinate both of those with the same
dude get those seeds clearly label them
and grow them both under the same
conditions and see how you like that
that's the only way to find out is to
run the plants run the mix and see what
you made otherwise you're just kind of
guessing i have no way of telling you
like which is going to have higher thc
by looking at these plants i would have
to smoke it maybe run it through a lab i
don't have that ability and keep in mind
again
i know i've said this but i just want to
stress this part because this we all get
consumed by uh lab reports and lab
numbers and terpene reports and test
results and all that [ __ ] but here's
something that i said the other day in a
live chat and all the growers in there
laughed pretty hard i've never had a
liquid chromatography machine come back
and try to buy another bag
no matter how high the lab report was
none of those machines have ever called
me and hit me up for another eighth does
that make any sense to you people buy
weed we're not growing machine we're not
growing weed for machines people smoke
weed people smoke dabs not high pressure
liquid chromatography machines uh we can
impress those machines very easily i
know how to manipulate a lab test we can
get high [ __ ] numbers if we really
really wanted to push it we could really
push it to where people are showing up
at the grow going what the [ __ ] are you
guys doing we can get cnn there it
wouldn't be hard to manipulate a lab
test uh but what's the point like the
numbers are just like if you smoke it
and it doesn't get you where you want to
be it could say 100 thc on the label and
it doesn't matter to me it's got to have
some terps it's got to have a few other
things to get my attention it's got to
be tasty i can smoke all the wheat i
want i live in colorado there's all the
weed like i can go to the store and i
could buy
two ounces today and two ounces tomorrow
and if i can smoke two ounces by myself
in a day i gotta get better weed but my
point is i can smoke all the weed we can
get dabs we can get edibles we can get
as [ __ ] up as we want i need it to
taste good that's one of the most
important parts to me i don't want to
smoke bad tasting herb herb that burns
my throat or herb that makes my tongue
feel weird i'm not into it why smoke
that [ __ ] when there's good [ __ ] so my
point is i don't focus too much on the
numbers because the machines aren't
gonna come by another eighth the people
are gonna come by another eighth and
they're the ones that are gonna say damn
that smells skunky dan that was super
sticky damn that tastes like bubble gum
and popsicles they're the ones that are
gonna come back with some money not the
machine so don't focus too much on those
numbers that's my main point here
let me get my high ass back on track
obviously i've been smoking something
[ __ ] good today uh cincy loco thank
you for the great message dude i think i
answered this honestly um which one will
help me get to that goal quicker um i
shouldn't harp too much on that part but
when you're breeding don't focus on
getting to the goal more quickly focus
on getting the goal accurately there's
no fast tracking and breeding doing it
the fast way
will get you [ __ ] up that's the way to
[ __ ] it all up do it the quick way so uh
grow from your heart breathe with love
and take your time man put some love and
art into your art put some love skills
some passion and do it correctly um
it's only gonna you're gonna do two
plants side by side it's not gonna take
you much longer the hard part will be
growing both of them but it's fun then
you get to compare you get to take a
bunch of notes which we're gonna talk
about in a future episode all right it
goes on to say i'd prefer uh let's see
since iloco or cincy nasty would be
preferred
then he asked what gave me the nasty
vibe
nothing to do with any of the things
that you listed i think i explained that
a moment ago it all stemmed from a pair
of shoes from the cincinnati reds
triggered my brain got the add going
speaking of 80d it is time to wrap up
this podcast episode you guys cincy
thank you for the great message bro i
want to thank you guys again for
listening to another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast
676 episodes that's amazing that's
[ __ ] tremendous to me i haven't done
anything else 676 times successfully so
thank you for all the support thank you
for listening hanging out it was pointed
out recently that episode 710 is coming
up what are we gonna do for episode 710
what's gonna happen or have to take some
dabs or do something but i'm afraid to
dab on the show because i don't want
youtube
to get mad at me and put me on
restriction for something weird
anyway i'm rambling i'm stoned i hope
you had a good time hope you had as much
fun as i did it would not have been the
same without you so make sure you pop in
for the next episode if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know i would love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
send me your feedback don't worry about
my little ego i could take some bruises
let me know your real honest opinion of
the show if we need to make some
adjustments or corrections i'll take
your feedback
we'll see what happens from there ah
don't forget about patreon.com if you
feel like the episode was educational
informative or entertaining maybe you'd
just like to send me a tip on patreon
all you have to do is visit patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart big
up and big thanks to everybody who
supports the show uh if you need any
more information please do check out the
website
iregenetics.com all the information you
need is at iregenetics.com there's a
link to the patreon there's a link to
the web store there are links to seed
vendors on there there's a link to the
discord everything you need
iriegenetics.com
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls that
is all i've got for you for this episode
you know i'll be back in just a couple
of days with fresh new content i'm gonna
give a giant shout out to my buddy og
tony and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you