[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
677 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to go over a
little checklist i've created i've got a
list of things that can help us keep our
plants and our garden and our equipment
in top working order before i get to
that list let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those great folks who support the
show on patreon let's start off with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to red eyed optimist let's
send a big thank you shout out to mr
mean green i want to send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to rosta green
thumb let's send a thank you shout out
to brendan grosz i want to send a big
thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter of my buddy made while
medicated let's send a big thank you
shout out to luke i want to send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to thomas
m let's send a big high five and a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter my
buddy godfather kush let's send a thank
you shout out to another long time
supporter zackson starker let's not
forget about my buddy captain mojo then
let's wrap it all up with a big thank
you shout out to my buddy mobius grows
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends speaking of show notes and video
descriptions this is the part of the
show where i invite you to join the irie
genetics discord server there are
approximately 1 500 members of the irie
genetics discord server and honestly i
don't know why you are missing the party
join us it's a good time it's a party
there are a lot of great things going on
on the discord server we are doing
actions and waffles today somebody got a
great pack of unreleased seeds they've
got a one-of-one pack some seeds that
have never been released uh they've got
the only pack so far they got that on
the discord on a waffle there the only
way to get access to that was the
discord server so join us on the discord
i talk about it a lot there are actions
there are waffles happening uh there is
yoga going on there's grow talk
happening there's help and advice and
just random hanging out over on the
discord i do invite you join me there's
a link of course in the show notes and
the video description i do look forward
to seeing you on the discord server i
will be there as soon as i'm done
recording it takes a little while for
that file from that camera and that
camera to load up into the computer as
they load i go take dabs in the discord
server with the crew so that's my way of
winding down and hanging out join me i
might be there when you pop in all right
that's enough rambling about the discord
server what else do we want to talk
about let's get right into the main
topic of this show we've been talking
enough let's get right to the main part
this show will come out right before the
first i think it actually comes out on
the 31st if there are that many days
this month i didn't keep good count we
should be right about the first as this
episode comes out as many people listen
to this episode it will be the first of
the month this is a good time to run
through a checklist of things in our
garden to make sure that everything is
in top working condition a lot of things
get overlooked
we get busy i'm extremely busy it is
outdoor season it is harvest season uh
we're shifting from the uh summer to the
fall from the warm to the cold is what i
call it so we've got to rebuild all the
indoor grows it is harvest time for the
outdoor season they're going to be a lot
of seeds to shuck it is going to be busy
when you get that busy a lot of things
get overlooked i always say that there's
that one corner that doesn't get swept
there's always that one tray that
doesn't get washed there's that one
plant in the back that gets ignored it
is now time to make sure we get to all
those small details because over time
they will build up and that's what
causes us problems stay on top of your
[ __ ] so my point is it is the first of
the month it is a good time to go
through the checklist it's also payday
so you should have a few bucks to handle
any supplies or corrections that need to
be made and if not now's the time to
start thinking about budgeting more
properly for the grow because [ __ ] will
come up things will go awry and we've
got to return money into our investment
if we want it to keep returning for us
all right let me get myself back on
track first of the month update the
first of the month the first thing i
would think about is clean everything
clean everything all everything in the
grow space everything outside the grow
space everything involved in the grow it
is time to clean it let's clean if
you've got lights with the glass
reflection with the glass space there
let's clean that glass if you've got air
conditioners if you've got fans let's
clean all of that stuff clean everything
you know it needs to be cleaned it is
your facility it's your grow it's your
space clean it start at the ceiling work
your way all the way down to the floor
clean the floor clean the tops of the
lights the tops of my lights get really
dusty i've got some hps lights they're
big squares the top of that gets really
dusty up there clean that [ __ ] if you've
got led lights turn off the lights if
you're going to clean your lights let
them cool that's a quick disclaimer let
the lights cool down before you clean
them clean all the glass if you've got
leds clean the diodes really carefully i
don't know how you do that with your
lights read the instructions but it may
be time to clean your lights and your
equipment i had some fungus gnats but he
gave me a clone and it came with free
fungus gnats my fault should have
quarantined that sucker better but
around my grow light there are a bunch
of fungus gnats right around the led
bulb so i had to get some q-tips and
some rubbing alcohol and clean out all
the dead fungus gnats there's things
like that that will need to be done
clean everything that thing you've been
avoiding there's something we've all got
that one area that one little thing
that's a pain in the ass to clean clean
it now's the time just take a moment
just dedicate that day to it it is
cleaning day let's do it let's talk
about stuff in depth that we should
clean filters we often overlook cleaning
filters you've got air conditioner
filters that need to be cleaned are your
carbon filters still working how long
have those carbon filters been around do
you need to replace them the next time
you replace your carbon filter get a
piece of duct tape and write the date on
that duct tape and put that somewhere on
your carbon filter just so you can look
and say this has been here for a year
it's almost time to change it they're
supposed to give you two years they're
supposed to be good for two years
mine don't last that long which is a
compliment i'm thinking that i'm growing
the dank and you can smell it and that
carbon filter just ain't working so i
replace it about every year or so maybe
every year and a half even though you're
supposed to get two years
is it working go outside give it a smell
leave for a little while don't come back
directly into the grow area walk around
outside the grow area and see can you
smell it bring somebody new see if they
smell it you've probably gone nose blind
and you don't even smell your grow
anymore
let's be safe is the carbon filter
working so clean your filters your air
conditioner filters your carbon filter
what about uh in your hydro setup i know
when i run a hydro setup i put a filter
that goes from the tank uh between the
tank and the emitters there is a filter
thing it's like a 45 degree angle that
hangs down so that all the heavy [ __ ]
falls into there as the water passes
through the watering system has that
filter been taken out and cleaned
thoroughly have you cleaned your hydro
lines like the whole system starting
from the pump all the way down to the
emitters maybe just uh take the emitters
out of the plants if you can and just
run some sort of cleaner through there
maybe an enzyme maybe some faizan
something just to clean all that [ __ ]
out of there you may be surprised what
comes out of your watering system when i
build tables with long big auto watering
systems and long pvc pipes and long
flex tubes
we make a cap on one inch where we can
open it and actually blast water through
and clean it and you would be amazed at
all the nutrient build up and all the
gunk and junk that builds up inside
those lines and you don't know it's
there and you're basically feeding the
plants that stuff every time you're
watering and you don't know it's there
so take a minute clean out your hydro
lines all that stuff may be built up
with gunk
use an enzyme an enzymatic product will
definitely help break that down physe
antonia will push it out then make sure
you rinse that stuff out of your system
out of the hydro lines out of all the
tubes out of everything before you put
it back uh put the emitters back in the
plants we don't want to put
hydrozyme or too much hydrozyme or too
much physant into the plant so the
natural part is fine but you don't want
to do too much
uh the cleaning ratio will be stronger
than what you're using for feeding so
clean all those tubes uh clean the glass
on the lights i talked about if you have
vented lights clean that glass between
the bulb and your canopy clean that
that's going to reduce if that is dirty
that's going to drastically reduce the
amount of lumens
that make it from the light bulb down to
your canopy that glass is already
cutting enough down any speck of dirt
any foliar feed any pesticide spray that
gathered on that lens is going to
drastically reduce the amount of light
that makes it to your canopy it will
drastically reduce light penetration
speaking of bulbs how long has it been
since you've taken a light meter a lumen
meter a par meter any sort of meter to
your lights to test how much they're
putting out if you're using hps or uh
metal halides
they put out a hundred percent you can
turn them down but they're still putting
out whatever you've got it turned to
it's putting out a hundred percent of
that power is the bulb giving you a
hundred percent of those lumens
my recommendation when you get a new
bulb get a par meter uh some sort of a
meter something reliable that you're
going to use next time also a basic
lumen meter is perfect get a piece of
string or a ruler or a tape measure some
way that you can measure consistently
what i'm going to say is get a piece of
string about 18 inches long it's about
18 inches right get a piece of string
about 18 inches long and tie it to the
end of your lumen meter put one end at
the light and then hold it the length of
that string now every time you measure
you're 18 inches from the light and see
what the number is on your lumen meter
write that number down then every few
months every couple of months hold that
lumen meter up to the light at the same
distance and see what number it is
showing you if it's gone down to if it's
30 50 less than what it was showing you
it is definitely time to change that
bulb you're paying for a hundred percent
of that electricity and you're getting
50 to 70 of the output from that bulb if
you swap out that bulb you'll get 100
output again you'll be getting the
electricity that you're paying for is
the cost of that bulb offsetting the
waste of electricity that you're
spending you're pumping the electricity
into it let's have a bulb that will give
us the light that we're paying for right
so test your bulbs mark the date
somewhere when you do get a new bulb
when you do finally replace those bulbs
at the grow store that i used to shop at
a long time ago before things got real
busy when you would buy a new bulb they
would take the bulb out of the box and
write the date on the little copper part
that screws into the the fixture that
was a cool idea but if i wanted to see
the date of my bulb i had to unscrew it
and take it out of there and look now i
take a piece of duct tape and i write
the date that i put a new bulb in my
light fixture and i put that duct tape
on the light fixture and i want to know
when that light went in there it's
printed right there on the light fixture
i just got to look right there says that
one in january first i've got plenty of
time on that bulb let's measure the
lumens i know how long it's been there i
don't know how many lumens it's given me
things are working out make some notes
set yourself up for success all of the
notes you make are setting yourself up
for success we smoke that's why we grow
most of us are consumers that's why we
grow that's what inspired us to grow
i really enjoy getting just a nice
little buzz just getting in the zone you
know what i mean just a little stony
focus get baked a little bit and then go
in the grow and put on some music and
just get in the zone and get work done
but then sometimes i'll come out and be
like huh i don't even know what i just
did for the past four hours in the grow
make some notes do some documentation
set yourself up for success that way if
you do something you got a note like hey
i did this and this and this and the
next time you want to do great results
you got some notes you say i did this
and this and this it works just the same
when you're marking down your equipment
when did i buy these bulbs when did i
buy this carbon filter when did i
install whatever equipment i'm using
when did i buy that air conditioner
all that stuff write it down keep your
receipts also because when [ __ ] breaks
and you want to argue with them for
their warranty you're going to need that
receipt where am i on this list i've got
a lot of stuff going on
uh mark all your dates and new stuff
down some more easy to find either on a
clipboard on the door or put duct tape
on the gear that you're marking the date
uh the filters and the emitters on your
hydro setup those need to be cleaned
i've talked about that already they need
to be cleaned in a big commercial
environment i was cleaning those almost
every day we would walk through uh as
we're watering walk the rows and make
sure all of the emitters are spraying
and if one's not spraying you'd have a
little bucket or a little uh dish with
more emitters in your hand just pull one
out
put pull the dead one out put the fresh
one in and then we'd go put those dirty
emitters in a bucket with either like
rubbing alcohol or physin or h2o2
something just to kind of pre-clean them
and then later in the day somebody would
go and poke them clean them up put those
in the clean bin then you got new fresh
ones tomorrow so that when you find all
the dead emitters just replace them and
that's because we used a bunch of chunky
nutrients some of the stuff we were
using uh the carbonaria and the shine
together would really clog up the hydro
system so we'd really have to do some
cleaning on that i am kind of rambling
let's get myself back on focus um
clean all of the equipment you know the
equipment in the room clean that [ __ ]
clean all of it then clean all of your
tools um your ph pen clean it it's dirty
it's really funky all your scissors
they're dirty clean them ah just take
out the trash clean all of the stuff you
know what is dirty you know what's funky
uh do you have let's see let me get
myself back on notes because i do have
some notes here clean the ceiling start
at the ceiling uh you may not think the
ceiling's dirty it is clean the ceiling
clean the walls clean the floor uh
everything in between there give it a
clean is the dosatron working properly i
know that's a big uh big facility device
but let's test that thing is it working
properly let's go and make sure like if
you've got this bottle set up to spit
seven milliliters per dosing every time
just pull out the emitter and see if
it's actually spitting out however many
milliliters you think it's actually
spitting out test the dosatron let's see
if all the auto uh auto automated
equipment automated was the word i'm
looking for i promise see if all of the
automated feeding equipment is working
is all of the automation working we pay
a lot of money for automation we pay a
lot of money to rely on that stuff is it
working the way we think it is working
let's test all of those things anything
you think you've got set to cycle on or
cycle off at a certain time have you
checked it in a while have you checked
the timers are the timers where you
think they are sometimes you think that
you change that fan to come on at a
certain time and go off at a certain
time when you change the timer but maybe
you missed a fan or something check on
all of that stuff i'm just double
checking because it's the first of the
month it is a good time to make a
checklist and run through and make sure
you've got everything because again we
do get overloaded as growers we also
smoke a little bit of ganja so we do
have a tendency to miss some detail so
i'm just trying to make a list to help
you out to set you up for success now
what else are we going to think about um
the are the drains clear i've got the
luxury and a commercial environment to
have a floor drain are all those drains
clear do they need to be clear do we
need to run a snake down there do we
need to get a plumber do we need some
help getting those drains cleared how
are the drains now let's talk about
stuff that everybody's got going on in
their grow the scissor and mix area i've
got a little table where i keep my
scissors and all my mixing stuff and my
notes is that area cleaned up is that
clean and tidy you can get more work
done if you've got a nice area set
yourself up for success don't have all
kinds of excessive [ __ ] on your
workspace if you use these bottles maybe
have these bottles right here have some
notes here on how to use them have your
measuring equipment have some scissors
have like
some towels or some rags to clean up
some messes have your safety equipment
but then you don't really need a lot of
other you don't need a bunch of
excessive [ __ ] around it just makes it's
distracting and it makes messes and it
will slow you down so is your area clean
how about your scissors and your mixing
cups are they clean i use a scale for
powder nutrients is your scale for
measuring nutrients clean is it
calibrated that's something important to
think about is that scale calibrated
because i'm using that to measure
five grams of powdered nutrients per
gallon of water if that thing is off
then i am not feeding properly at all
which we can double check with our ec
and our ph meters are those clean and
calibrated those need attention as well
um something we may not think about but
i think needs attention are the smoke
alarms the smoke detectors and
carbon monoxide detectors have they been
tested are they working are they in good
working condition those are gonna
possibly save a life so fire alarms uh
co2 alarms and then you need that fire
extinguisher if you do have a fire
hopefully you've got a fire extinguisher
check that bad dog do you know how to
use the fire extinguisher having it is
one thing knowing how to use it is
another thing do you know how to use it
are you ready to use it are you gonna
[ __ ] your pants and freak out or you're
gonna pull the pan aim toward the bottom
of the fire and spray in bursts in a
sweeping motion which one are you gonna
do do you know how to use that so be
ready for that then how about a first
aid kit i don't want you to get hurt in
your grow i really hope you don't i've
been cutting grows before i've seen
people have problems in grows if you
have a basic first aid kit it can really
help you out many of you may be in a
place where you shouldn't be growing
what's gonna happen if you're growing
some ganja and you cut your finger or
you get ph down in your eye and you need
some emergency medical help do you have
a plan who you gonna call hopefully
ghostbusters is in your neighborhood
maybe you got a friend that can back you
up maybe you're not able to call 9-1-1
and say hey i'm working in my weed
garden in my basement and i got ph down
in my eye i need some help you may have
to call a friend and guide them to you
and get some help and say hey i got to
get to the doctor but we can't let them
know what's going on here have a plan in
place if some [ __ ] like that is a
possibility who are you going to call
luckily we've got all these devices i've
got my iphone where i can open it up i
can unlock it really easily without too
much complication and i can speak to it
to give it commands to who to call for
me maybe if you don't have that sort of
device you got to figure out some sort
of backup plan of what you're going to
do if [ __ ] does go wrong you got to have
somebody in mind that can get to you and
help you out before the police get there
that may be something you need i don't
want anything to go wrong but i want you
to have a plan if it does a basic first
aid kit could really help you out uh
you've got some band-aids some gauze uh
some tape in there maybe a tourniquet or
something i'm not sure what you might
need but a basic first aid kit could
really help you out speaking of basic
first aid how about personal protective
equipment a lot of us are applying
pesticides or doing some sort of spray
applications in our grow have you
cleaned your respirator do you know how
to clean your mask properly have you
been properly trained or have you read
how to clean your respirator and your
mask are your cartridges up to date
you've got to have the proper cartridges
in your mask and they've got to be uh
new and not expired and not have too
many miles on them or you're basically
just wearing that mask for discomfort so
you keep your carts up to date and keep
your mask clean also how about your
suits are you using fresh tyvek suits
every time you're not supposed to
recycle those suits
basically you guys clean everything
this is just basically a responsibility
checklist that i'm just trying to remind
you to clean everything we've gotten to
the scissors the ph equipment the
measuring equipment how about you're
measuring cups i've also got measuring
cups and shot glasses that i use to
measure nutrients clean those it doesn't
take very long pour a cleaner in there
hit it with a rag let it dry next time
you need to use it it's nice and clean
and nice and shiny makes you feel good
the grow looks good you've set yourself
up for success it's one less problem
you're gonna have in the future one less
thing slowing you down when you're
trying to get work done let me catch my
breath and see where i am in the notes
how long has it been since you've
cleaned your sprayer whatever you were
spraying your plants with how long has
it been since you've actually given that
thing a good cleaning i've got a
handheld pump sprayer and the commercial
grow we use paint sprayers sometimes
those will need maintenance the handheld
sprayer you need to run some clean water
through it and clean that hose out there
might be stuff stuck in the tubes and
you don't want to spray the wrong
product on your plants at the wrong time
if you think you've mixed up this and
there's still some of the last previous
spray left in the tubes that could cause
problems the paint sprayers can be a
pain in the ass they oftentimes need
re-primed and they definitely need to be
cleaned out very frequently so keep your
paint sprayer up to speed by just
general maintenance there are a lot of
good videos i found that almost every
brand paint sprayer i think the one that
we like the most is the graco they've
got a great
youtube presence where you can read
about re-priming and cleaning all those
machines really easily they don't pay me
to talk about that but i think it's
really helpful for you if you've got i
think it's graco is the name of the
brand the blue one right i can see it on
my head i've got the image in my head
but i can't think of the name of the
brand i'm pretty sure it's graco
if you go to youtube and type in graco
paint sprayer all the info you need is
right there they'll teach you how to
take it apart and rebuild it and you can
do it in just a couple of hours save
yourself a lot of money on a maintenance
plan from that company because they'll
come fix it for you but you can do it
yourself it's really easy and you don't
want to wait for them if you need to
spray today you need that [ __ ] fixed and
they take a week to come so yeah just
fix it yourself all the videos are right
there on youtube so take care of your
paint sprayer clean that [ __ ] out if
that's what you're using a lot of people
will tell me that a paint sprayer isn't
the way to go it's very effective for me
i like what i'm doing with that if
you're using a fogger now is definitely
the time to clean out your fogger ah
clean that [ __ ] up is it time to do a
dump run um we are approaching harvest
season right now people are going to
have a lot of sticks a lot of stems a
lot of root balls a lot of leftover junk
that they don't need from the grow
where's that gonna go
if you've got an indoor grove and you're
pulling down crops every couple of
months where are all those sticks and
root balls and leftover where's all that
[ __ ] going is it time for you to do a
dump run sometimes my garage builds up a
little bit of a mess it is all grow
waste and grow trash i wait till i've
got a nice pile then we do a dump run we
just take it all to the dump at one time
instead of doing just a bunch of small
runs you take it all at once but is it
time is it time for you to do a dump run
have you been building up a bunch of
stuff that big pile is going to
contribute to uh where bugs can hide if
you had a pest problem and you threw all
that [ __ ] out in the garage out in the
backyard the bugs are building there and
they're going to work their way back
into your grow eventually let's get rid
of all of that trash that old root ball
stuff those old sticks do you need to do
a dump run all right maybe it is time
for a dump run where are we on my list
of good stuff here
now we are to the part that should be
obvious to a lot of people but gets
often overlooked it is time to clean and
calibrate our ph meters those ph meters
need to be calibrated approximately once
a week it should have a check mark on it
that shows you that it is calibrated it
only takes a couple of minutes to
calibrate it especially once you get
good at it if you do it every week
you'll get out your seven solution and
your four solution and you'll be able to
go bloop bloop bloop and you'll get them
calibrated in just a couple of minutes
it won't take you time at all
one thing i do recommend
is having more than one calibration
standard available so if you've got the
four solution and the seven solution
maybe have another bottle of the seven
solution and test them to each other
after you take it out of the seven put
it in the other seven and see if they
both read seven that way you know that
one of your solutions isn't bad and you
are properly calibrated so it's time to
clean and calibrate your ph pin your ph
meter however cheap however expensive it
is now is a good time to clean it
remember if the ph meter dries it dies
so make sure you keep it moist keep it
clean it will work much better for a
much longer time also the ec pans your
condo electrical conductivity or your
tds meter whichever one you're using the
ppm ec uh there are a lot of meters you
can use clean that one also it'll work
much better and last much longer if you
clean it i don't think those need much
calibration but do clean
that how about nutrient inventory if it
is the first of the month that is a good
time to do a nutrient inventory shake
your bottles what are you low on do you
need to go buy some stuff do you need to
order some things do you need to restock
on stuff it is a really good time to
check and see what you might need look
through the rest of the month in your
grow schedule and say we're going to
feed this we're going to feed this we're
going to feed this do i have that stuff
so then when it comes time to mix in
your bloom booster you don't grab the
bottle and go oh i should have ordered
that a week ago let's order it now that
way we've got all of the stuff we need
throughout the grow and there are no
surprises no late [ __ ] products no
missing products in our reservoir we've
got everything we need let's just order
the [ __ ] right now if we're going to
order nutrients how about pesticide
inventory what pesticide products do you
use is it time to order more pesticides
i just say shake the bottles i just go
down and just shake the bottles and if
one feels light i write it down and
order another one it's that easy don't
let yourself run out of [ __ ] it's your
grow you're responsible for it you know
what you're gonna need you're the one
that's gonna order it you're the one
going to use it get that [ __ ] now make
it easy it's the first of the month
reinvest some of your last harvest back
into the next harvest try to make the
next grow better every single time so
what about other basic inventory what
are other things that i always need to
order for my grows gloves we are
constantly ordering gloves how many pair
of gloves do you go through a day in
your garden it's not a big math equation
think about how long you're in there how
many times you change gloves multiply
that by however many times a week you're
in the grow multiply that times four
that's a month that's how many pairs of
gloves you go through in a month how
many boxes do you need let's order them
now so we don't have to sit around and
wait for gloves to come when we do need
them it's really easy to order gloves a
lot of people like to wear a mask
especially the tremors let's order all
the masks
masks that's a fun word order all of the
[ __ ] that you think you need i don't
know what you need in your grow but
let's order it now i go through a lot of
clone plugs like a lot of rapid routers
i go through a lot of plant tags um just
basic things that i know i'm going to
need i try to order that stuff on the
first that way it comes i have to make
one trip to the groce store or i get one
big box from amazon saves on shipping
saves on moving around just makes it so
much easier to do one big monthly order
all right now here's another thing we're
going to segue into that a lot of people
may have overlooked
let's double check our security what do
you have going on for your security the
first thing i recommend is just if
wherever you're growing whatever
building it is in if you're growing in a
in a room inside of a house let's just
check the security walk around outside
just see are there any light leaks do
you hear any fans do you smell anything
is there anything that would tip you off
that there is a grow inside of that room
or that building because if you can find
it that means that thieves that means it
snitches and that means that cops can
find that grow as well and we don't want
those folks finding our grows so be very
careful walk around see if you can see
any light leaking out of your grow do
you smell anything do you hear fans do
you hear any sort of air conditioning do
you hear [ __ ] cycling is it weird do you
feel vibrations from the blowers just go
check outside
if you're growing like in a big building
walk around the whole building if you're
growing in a room inside of a building
check that outside of that area and then
check like
if you're growing in the room adjacent
to this one sit in this room and see if
you hear a smell or see anything that
would alert you to a grow in the other
room just double check your security
then check your safety is that all
locked up is there a way for anybody to
get in there people often forget that
when you put an air conditioner in the
window all i gotta do is push that air
conditioner in and i'm in your grow it's
it's a hint that it's there and it's an
entryway so keep that [ __ ] in mind when
you're building your rooms don't give me
too many access points and give me too
many hints people are out there and
they're trying to get [ __ ] from you it's
a weird time right now and people are
going [ __ ] crazy for anything they
can get protect yourself so check your
security do you have security cameras do
you have security camera footage do you
have backups of your security camera
footage do you have all your cameras set
up the way that they need to be then
think about where all of that camera
footage is going is that saved somewhere
within your house is it on a dvr in your
house where that dvr could possibly be
stolen or is it backed up somewhere to
the internet to where it's stored in a
cloud and a server to where that footage
is always accessible and can't be taken
away from you another detail i would
think about is how long has it been
since you've changed your security codes
and passwords and who has keys if you've
got a facility with a gate maybe you had
to give keys to
an electrician maybe an hvac tech has a
key maybe an old employee has a key
think about where those keys are also
who has passcodes to your alarm system
who has passcodes to your cameras who
has any sort of passwords or codes to
anything think about that now may be the
time to do that thing where you log out
of all devices change your password and
log back in now may be the time to do
that sort of stuff especially if you had
any firing rehiring
any breakups any shifts
any riffs in the matrix now may be the
time to change passwords and do some
sort of security upgrades things like
that you never know what people are up
to especially now things are weird you
guys
so back up your security footage change
your security passwords and security
codes just because we don't know maybe
also change any locks that may need to
be changed now let's talk about some
other things you may need to think about
uh do you have msds
sheets msds sheets are very important in
my opinion uh if you were to uh get a
product in your eye or accidentally
think that the the ph down was kombucha
and you pick it up and take a drink of
it you got to go to the hospital they're
going to want to know all of the
information about all of the products
you may have exposed yourself or
consumed
have an msds sheet for all of your
products whenever in a commercial grow
we're required to have a folder of msds
sheets anytime we get a new product like
if this was a grow product this is just
a bottle of water but if this was a
nutrient as soon as it came into the
grow i would put it on the table and i
would go to the internet and i would
type in this product msds sheet and i
would print that msds sheet out and put
it in a folder and it would be
alphabetically in a folder that sits on
a desk with the pesticide logs and a few
other important logs in a commercial
grow we are required to have those
sheets for every product that is inside
of the facility in your personal grow it
would just be a good idea just in case
something does go wrong just to have
that product there that product msds
sheet there available for you the other
thing i would have is a spray log in
commercial environments we're required
to write down every pesticide
application we spray
we write down what room we sprayed what
products we sprayed how much of that
product was applied
we write down the epa number we write
down the number of the employee who
sprayed that they've got an epa number
and a training number as well
there are a lot of details that go along
with the spray products so i recommend a
spray log even in your personal grow
this will help you out for a couple of
reasons if i don't want you to get sick
i don't want you to spray pesticides in
your eyes i don't want you to get any
sort of rash but if you do and you've
got that pesticide log and the msds
sheet you've got some hints some clues
if we've got to take you to the hospital
because you're in anaphylactic shock
those two things may help me out to
figure out how to save your life so the
msds sheet and the spray log i think are
very important even in a personal grow
just consider those msds sheets and
those spray logs as part of the notes
that you should be taking anyway you
should be taking copious notes with your
grow you should be making a nice journal
if things go right you're going to want
to be able to repeat that process and if
you've got good notes then you know
exactly what you did and you can repeat
it if you just guess you're just
guessing who knows if we're going to get
it right again next time it's not like
grandma's cake recipe or grandma's
breakfast recipe you can't just guess
and throw some of this [ __ ] in there it
might work but it's not going to be the
same every single time if you have notes
if you've got documentation we can
repeat the process and in a commercial
environment that's what's required is a
repeatable provable process with
quantifiable results
now let me move forward here's another
thing that
most growers may not think about but
once you get a little bit more advanced
maybe i think about it because i'm a
business owner and i work in big
commercial industry grows how about an
expense report how much are you spending
on your grow are you documenting your
monthly electrical bill are you
documenting your monthly water bill are
you documenting how much you spend on
nutrients are you documenting how much
you spent on soil are you documenting
how much you spent on the equipment and
setting up the grow are you considering
your time and energy are you paying
yourself are you documenting how many
hours a week or a month you spend in
that grow space let's just start writing
down an expense report how much are we
spending how much time are we putting
into this then let's also keep good
notes on the harvest reports write down
every gram you harvest anything that you
pull out of there let's document that as
well then over time you'll have a couple
of quantifiable reports you can see what
you're spending you can see if you're
spending more or less than when you
started and you can see if you're
pulling more or less product than when
you started and you can see if you are
improving or if you're getting worse
maybe then you can find areas to improve
once you start taking notes you start
seeing like oh i could have done this
better could have done this better last
time we did this and we didn't get as
much herb this time we did this we got
more you can start seeing those things
so start taking copious notes i really
think that having a journal and taking a
lot of notes is really important then
when you see that cost and expense sheet
then you really see like oh i used to
spend
300 bucks i don't i'm just guessing how
much a week or a month you might spend i
used to spend 300 bucks a month on herb
and since i spent 1200 bucks on building
that grow that means that if i spend if
i make enough herb for four months worth
of herb that i've paid off all my
equipment everything after that i'm just
kind of paying for electricity and water
and my energy then you know like i've
paid off the equipment now maybe i can
upgrade to a new light it really will
help you out once you start seeing like
what you're putting in and what you're
getting out of it you'll want to improve
at that rate so i really think that the
expense report is just part of the basic
grow journaling if you're taking a lot
of details and taking notes that expense
report will fall right in line with the
rest of your notes maybe it's just
another page maybe it's another part of
the spreadsheet however you're doing it
i think once you get comfortable and
used to it it'll just be another part of
the documentation which you are keeping
another thing that i think is important
is to have goals and plans if you've got
that expense sheet it will help you set
goals and it will help you make plans
how do you know you're reaching any
goals how do you know you're successful
if you never wrote down any goals and
made any plans we all want to grow some
weed right if you get a harvest that's
cool that's success but how do you know
that the next harvest is better how do
you know that the next one is better
let's have some goals let's have some
plans write down a schedule i'm going to
plant this many seeds at this day i'm
going to put them into small pots this
day then they're going to go into bigger
pots this day i intend to flower on this
day leave yourself some openings some
windows like maybe the plants don't grow
as fast as you need it or maybe they
grow faster but try to have an idea a
schedule i've been growing so long that
when we go to a commercial grow i can
look at the height i can look at the
space and i can say here is the schedule
we're going to need nine weeks of flower
that means it nine weeks in the flower
room that's undeniable that's what we
need so they've gotta flower nine weeks
in here how big can i get them uh by the
time they're done how big do i have to
get them in here before i flower them to
max them out at their maximum height in
this room before we're done that tells
me how many weeks we can veg so i just
automatically start thinking uh two
weeks in the cloner two weeks in small
pots three weeks in big pots then we
move them into the flower room it'll
work perfectly i just start scheduling i
make a plan and then we stick to those
plans and schedules and create routines
and rhythms and standard operating
procedures the way to do that is to have
some goals and have some plans and if
you're working with multiple people it
is really important to get all of those
people on the same plan make sure
everybody knows
the goal and make sure everybody knows
they're part of the puzzle to reach that
goal if everybody thinks they're a
trimmer nobody's going to water plants
if everybody thinks they're watering
plants nobody's going to defoliate make
sure everybody knows their role the
easiest way to do that is to find
somebody that can be the leader that
knows everything that needs to be done
they can delegate all of the jobs for
the day so have some goals have some
plans create objectives have an expense
sheet but most importantly in that grow
have a bunch of fun i know i just gave
you a bunch of tasks a bunch of
assignments a bunch of [ __ ] to think
about but most importantly go in there
and have fun but it's i think it's
easier to have fun when we set ourselves
up for success and that's what i'm
trying to help you do here is set
yourself up for success if you go in
that grow and all of the equipment works
smoothly everything just runs you push
that button and all the processes happen
and the plants go shebang you'll be
encouraged to be in there more often it
feels good you'll want to grow grow more
which means you'll be touching the
things more you'll be paying attention
you'll be learning which means you'll
want to grow more it'll just trigger
it'll just trigger more inspiration
you'll get better and better and better
put a little work into it and watch how
much it inspires you that's all it takes
you'll see that you can accomplish small
goals you'll want to hit bigger goals
every day all right i think that
concludes my first of the month garden
checklist i hope i taught you some
things i hope i inspired you to do some
things maybe you're typing out this list
as we go ah you're gonna have to listen
a couple more times and keep up because
i feel like i was going quite quickly
for this episode ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers and growers clone cutters and
paul and chuckers i want to thank you
once again for listening to episode 607
of the grow from your heart podcast if
you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy also if you feel like the
show is educational informative or
entertaining maybe you like to throw me
a buck just because you learned a couple
of things all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need to support the show is right there
on the screen and again i do invite you
to join the discord server that link is
in the show notes and the video
description any other information you
need you can find it iriegenetics.com
there's a link to the patreon there's a
link to the discord there's a link to
seed vendors there's a lot of great
information at
iregenetics.com all right that is all
i've got for you you know i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy johnny caniseed and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]