[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 68 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're
a cannabis activist or even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host Roston
Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I want to send a big thank you
shout out to the Mystic Roots man for
letting me use their music on the show
big thanks to cat CP and the entire
Mystic Roots crew what's up everybody
I'm not going to do any ads this episode
because I have a lot of stuff written
down going to drop that music out a
little bit I've been telling you guys
that I'm going to do a lesson on
growroom scheduling well I've started
working on that and I have got a lot of
information before I get to that part I
want to talk about a couple of things I
went and got my medical marijuana card
renewed a couple of days ago and I was
thinking I should talk about that on the
show I'm going to turn down the music
real quiet here and just start the show
right now no ads this time you guys no
ads uh quick shout out to high grow
under growing supplies and super huge
shout out to Rocky Mountain worm company
and Nature's green remedies that's my
ads for today um I got a lot to talk
about I got my medical marijuana card
renewed um dude the process has gotten
super simple um I pretty much called
made an appointment I showed up they got
me in at my schedule appointment time
that's the first time that's ever
happened at a medical marijuana doctor
uh they got me in there they got me seen
they got my uh it's a it's not a license
you guys it's it bugs me for some reason
because we don't nobody here has a
marijuana license it's a medical
marijuana recommendation from a doctor
uh it's not a prescription it's not a
license so he writes out a
recommendation for you and then um you
know I was debating on if I wanted to
talk about this or not on the table in
the doctor's office there's just a
little sign and it says increased plant
count will require records and then
there's a dollar sign and then an amount
of plants and then another dollar sign
and an amount of plants and if you uh
provide records and you tell this doctor
that you are in need of a higher plant
count he will increase your plant count
for a small fee so if you're not a
Colorado resident and if you're not
familiar with all that what that means
is when you go to this doctor when you
get your medical marijuana card you are
now um allowed to grow six plants in
your private residence these doctors are
now able to write in recommendations
that you are able to grow more cannabis
and possess more cannabis than the
original six but to do that you've got
to bring a little bit of doctor note uh
some sort of History some sort of record
saying that something's wrong with you
and you also have to pay a fee so uh for
a small fee I walked out of there with a
handsome plant count I won't talk about
the numbers on the show I don't really
have a huge plant count I don't need
that many I just wanted to be safe so
and I went for what he would give me
just see if he would do it and I got the
highest he offered there so uh that was
super easy uh I wanted to talk about the
benefits of doing that um the reason I
did it is because of course I grow and I
want to keep my grow protected with my
medical marijuana card um that allows me
it gives me a little bit more safety I
feel like and also uh the recreational
shops are really high priced if you were
to buy a gr of hash at a recreational
shop it would cost you probably twice as
much as it would at a medical shop so uh
I keep my medical marijuana privileges
intact a lot for that because sometimes
I do run out of shatter and I have to go
I go up to green and healthy wellness in
Colorado Springs and I purchased grams
of hash uh from our friends hunt and uh
the Jordans and the John's up at uh
green and healthy wellness so that's a
good reason to keep my uh medical
marijuana card intact uh so I talked
about the benefits I talked about the
process and I talked about the cost I
feel like I cover the medical marijuana
card experience it was super easy this
time I'm not going to uh say the
doctor's name or anything on the podcast
but if you like his information just
email me it's grow from yourheart
hotmail.com and I'll get you that doctor
he is in PUO Colorado so if you're
looking for a doctor in pelo I've got a
recommendation for you uh let's move on
to my next topic I really want to get to
the grow lesson but I've got a few
things written down that I want to cover
um this is just kind of a personal thing
I keep seeing a lot of people talking
about the temperature of their eail um
the enail is the little box it plugs
into the wall that's got a a an LED or
an LCD display on there it's usually an
LED right little LED light display uh
shows numbers and then it's got an up
and down switch on it you can make the
temperature hotter and cooler and then
the one I have actually has a USB port
in it so that you can charge your iPhone
or whatever kind of phone you got on
there but then it's got a little cord
that comes out and it attaches to the
nail and it heats up the nail for you
all the time so that's the enail then
your dab nail is always hot right uh the
temperature on your
nail does not match what the numbers on
that box say that's what I'm trying to
get to here that's going to be my point
a lot of people say they've seen
pictures of my email and right now it's
flashing at 852 uh it's jumping between
uh 850 and
852 and honestly if you tried to take a
dab with that at 852 degrees I feel like
that'd be too hot but that is not a
representation of degrees that is simply
a setting on the box I don't think that
and maybe there is one brand maybe one
or two brands that does this but I don't
think that that coil is sending the the
temperature to that nail and all the way
back to there and telling it that it's
860° that is more of a setting like a
like if you turn your volume on your car
stereo to 11 you're not putting out 11
anything you're just on 11 you know that
11 is like I know that my car stereo I
could crank it up to about 28 before the
subwoofer starts sounding like complete
crap so I know that 26 is my ideal temp
on my car stereo it doesn't mean I'm
putting out 26 anything in particulars
it's just the level where it is and
that's what I think your enails are
doing uh we have established that the
860 I'm seeing on my screen right now on
my LED is actually a frequency that is
being put out and that's what's being
measured by that number so you got to
keep in mind that that number has to
travel all the way down the cord and
then it has to get to the coil and that
coil is the heating part that coil has
to heat whatever type of nail you're
using I'm using this new Highly Educated
uh it's the enil insert which one is it
it's got the name printed on it let me
read it I I knew the name until I
started talking it is the the H adapter
so I'm using that one so you've got to
heat up this Barrel shaped piece and
then the head of the nail heats up after
that cuz the Heat's got to travel so for
it to know what the exact heat is on the
head of that nail would be kind of kind
of ridiculous to ask of that device so
my point is that number doesn't match
the head of the nail you guys that is a
frequency or a dial setting so when you
find the ideal number just remember that
ideal number and that's kind of where
you want to be you're not actually
getting at 856 de or I've seen some of
them said perfectly 710 because people
think that's the perfect temp that
number is not correlating to The Nail
you guys so when you see my pictures and
it's at 850 quit bitching at me I think
that's my point here all right I have
another topic written down but the
iPhone has locked me out here we go uh
the next one oh the pesticide issue man
we talked about this a little bit um in
a previous episode I talked about about
some of the dispensaries that got in
trouble and I saw a quick article I'm
scrolling through my phone here I should
have been a little more
prepared people are kind of upset about
this pesticide issue and here is what I
saw this was all over um it was all over
social media websites today it says uh
pesticide violations were issued to the
following recreational marijuana grow
facilities and then it lists mindful
Green Solutions evolutionary Holdings
Green Cross Colorado MMJ America organic
green
altitude East treatments r i n and Sweet
Leaf all violators were using Eagle 20
and petroleum based fungus side that is
harmful to humans and animals altitude
East treatments was also using Mallet
and avot both harmful to humans and
animals Green Cross Denver was also
using Mallet many of these violations
are well known and then it goes on to
talk about a lot more stuff you know I
don't know the original source of that
because I've seen it cut and pasted on
so many different social media sites
that I don't know who to give credit to
that but uh these guys were spraying
Eagle 20 on plants and then selling
those buds to people and the weird part
here is MMJ America just won a Cannabis
Cup so what's going on with that these
guys are did they enter their Eagle 20
Laden buds into the Cannabis Cup or are
they growing separate cups or separate
crops and entering that and not even
giving the public a chance to go buy
that because I suspect that that's what
some of the shops do so these uh plants
have been taken off the market those
plants will never make it to harvest and
those buds will never be sold to
customers or patients but I'm sure that
there was medicine or product that did
make it out of the door and has been
treated with Eagle 20 or whatever else
they were listing here that we
definitely should not be consuming if
this were to happen to if these were
tomatoes and they discovered that these
people had been spraying tomatoes with
these products the Tomato farmer or
distributor or whoever's in charge at
that point would have to go make some
sort of a press release and apologize
they have to be held accountable
this would have been a much larger deal
if this would have been another
Agricultural Product or a Horticultural
product and what's ridiculous is the
Cannabis industry makes so much money
that they should have been kind of on
top of this and been doing the right
thing anyway like we're getting legal
cannabis here and then we're trying to
set the pace here and then they're going
to go and do [ __ ] like this which really
puts I don't know kind of a black eye on
the legal cannabis industry I don't know
I think that the people that were
leading the industry should have been
more responsible with our industry all
right so I can't say to not shop at
those stores or anything like that do
what you want to do but I would
definitely pay more attention to where
my medicine is coming from and I would
pay more attention to what's going in my
medicine all the more reason you guys to
grow your own cannabis that's my
solution that's what I think all right
I've got a couple of more notes what
else did I want to get on to actually
we're going to let's just get right to
it I want to talk about growroom
scheduling you guys uh we're 10 minutes
into the show already and I have got a
lot of notes here so this is probably
going to end up taking us a couple of
episodes here honestly so we're going to
get through the veg process today and
then the next lesson will be uh planning
your flowering Cycles so I wrote a whole
bunch of stuff and honestly it took me a
little bit to get this together because
uh and I'm going to apologize right now
I know that the last few episodes have
been a little wonky I seriously had a
major concussion and I can't focus to
write long uh long things like I used to
Long lessons and [ __ ] it's coming back
to me slowly but it takes me a little
more effort and a lot more time to focus
and write down [ __ ] so please bear with
me but the lessons are coming back
things are getting better I know that
things have not been the way they should
be with the show but I have not been the
way I should be so I couldn't bring you
the show you needed I'm getting my [ __ ]
back together which means the show is
getting its [ __ ] back together too I
apologize for being kind of slacking off
but I didn't even know when you get a
head injury you don't know what the
hell's going on and it's crazy weird so
uh I'm getting back to it and the show's
getting back to it so let me prove that
to you here is what I have written and
uh I have got a lot here I think I'm
going to try to read it off the computer
because the phone screen is Tiny let's
pull up the same thing here on the phone
same thing on the computer does it match
no this one's not updated all right
we're just going to read it off the
phone it goes like this so an average
grow should take about 100 to 120 days
maybe 150 days total in the soil before
harvesting drying trimming and curing
our goal our goal is to provide our
plants with optimal conditions
appropriate feedings careful training
and selective pruning in order to
produce the finest medicine we can offer
to our patients or clients I think that
every day in each cycle is an
opportunity to show the plant some love
and help your crop reach its full
potential I feel like each feeding each
application of teas bug sprays folar
feeding and any interaction with your
plants is your chance to make sure your
crop reaches your client's expectations
and the plants full potential a great
way to improve your crops is to start a
solid growth schedule today I want to
talk about two different schedules a
grower should be on top of the first
schedule will be the basic planning of a
crop from seed to clone all the way up
to harvest time I want to discuss the
phases of growth from a small Clon or
seedling into vegetative growth into the
flowering phase I want to break down the
flowering phase into trimesters and talk
about what the plants are doing and what
they want through the flowering phase I
will also talk about what you could be
doing at each phase to improve your
Harvest um I wrote here that if I can
get you through 120-day grow lesson in
this episode I'll just start my I'll
start my discussion on planning a
schedule that keeps your grow space
producing as much herb as possible with
as little downtime as possible uh this
of course will take multiple lights in
at least two small grow spaces but
setting up a small Perpetual grow to
keep yourself supplied with head stash
is probably easier than you think I
realize now that I've written way too
much for one episode so this is
definitely going to be broken down you
guys so here's where we get into it
before you begin your grow I suggest
getting yourself a planner and making a
schedule in advance you can be flexible
uh because cuz these are plants but try
to stick with your plant if you can uh I
also suggest taking a lot of notes you
guys take a lot of notes don't wonder
what you did to that plant to make it so
special write down what you did so that
you know all right so uh here's where
I'll describe the uh phases of growth
and time frames of our plant I said that
this grow is going to take about 100 to
120 days if you want to go larger plant
you can go up to 150 I've seen people
take a lot longer that's the veg period
is what you're going to make your
difference there so we'll start off with
seedlings or clones right and that's
going to take about 14 days to be in the
seedling phase I think about 14 days
when you start germinating it from the
day you germinate it uh till the day
it's like a little plant it's about 14
days we're going to call that 14 days a
clone takes about 14 days to root and
get ready to be a plant so I'm going to
say seeding and clone phase is about 14
days the veg growth depends on your goal
you guys if you want to veg if you're
going in small pots you can veg for two
weeks if you're going to go into larger
pots you you can veg I've seen people
veg for 30 45 days I've also seen guys
veg for 60 days some of the outdoor
plants that people veg for the the early
start of the year before the outdoor
season I've seen people veg plants for
four or five or six months to put them
outside so what's going to happen is
your plants are going to get bigger and
bigger and bigger the longer you veg so
we're just going to go for a short veg
in this one so your flowering phase I'm
going to go for a 9we flowering phase
most of the plants I work with are about
9 to 10 weeks uh n weeks is a good
number because that gives us three
trimesters of three weeks each to talk
about I can talk about my theory of the
trimesters on the
plants um so yeah that that'll help us
out so we got 14 days in seedling 63
days in flowering you're looking at 77
days there that gives us about 30 days
to veg and fix any problems so uh let's
just basically start a short grow from
Cedar clone uh this is kind of the the
grow I'm going to talk about now is
basically the type I would of grow I
would do if I were searching through a
10 pack of seeds to find the keepers in
the pack so for this I would usually use
like a three gallon pot or a 5 gallon
pot and I would use I don't know
probably like between nine and 16 just
depends on how small I'm going to keep
the plants and how tight I want to cramp
them in the space under the light this
just one light is all I'm talking about
right now so if we start from seeds or
clones the only difference will be the
first two weeks really once the Clones
root and the seedlings take off
everything I'm talking about is going to
work the same for seeds and clones if
you're working with seeds you'll have to
be sure that you eliminate the males
before we get too far into flour but
that's going to be your major
difference um so let's start with this
we'll say this is like if we're starting
day one we'll say start day one right
now so today would we we would cut our
clones and start uh germinating our
seeds I'm not going to do any lessons on
germinating seeds or cutting clones
because I'm pretty sure I've covered
that in past episodes uh if you need to
refresher course uh go back and listen
to those or if you guys want a brand new
episode on that email me and I will go
back and listen to the old episode and
I'll try to do an update for you but
only if enough people ask for it that
episode's out there so it should work uh
so we cut our clones and we started our
seeds for day one uh this is where you
want to Mark the date get out your grow
calendar and Mark it today is day one uh
for clothes and seeds I recommend a
24-hour light cycle you guys to start
the first couple of weeks uh the first
few days are just a waiting game pretty
much if you're waiting for seeds they'll
pop up they'll pop up from whatever
medium you've put them in in like 48
Hours hopefully or maybe it'll take him
a couple days to start growing to the
light I suggest putting your seedlings
into I use beer cups like Solo
cups uh put those put your seedlings
into the cups with a light potting mixes
with plenty of drainage and holes in the
bottoms of the cups of course uh once
your seedlings have developed a nice tap
route of like about an inch to three
inches long that's when you want to
throw those in your dirt so clones will
be lazy but they'll root around 10 to 14
days some of you guys are going to take
a little longer to get your clones to
root uh it's all about a healthy mother
plant a good rooting environment uh be
patient and if it takes you more time to
get your clones rooted just plan that
into your next run give yourself an
extra week or an extra 5 days whatever
it takes and then you'll start learning
how to keep healthy your mother plants
you'll start learning how to clone
better and you'll speed up your cloning
time it'll get better uh take a lot of
extra clones at first because they're
going to die if you're not good at
cloning if you're new at this take
extras CU you will lose some and don't
be sad about it uh so after several days
let's see where was I the seedings
ceilings are going to start growing tall
and skinny in the first few days after
several days they'll develop their first
true leaves by this time the Clones are
rooted and ready for cups and the
seedings will be small plants and
catching up to the clones so I wouldn't
feed the seedings until about 7 to 10
days in and when you do feed them focus
on root inoculant and building a good
root base for the plants uh I like a
worm casting tea or something like that
maybe something like great white uh you
can use ogt uh something something that
focuses on rude inoculant you want uh
trichoderma uh yeah you guys hopefully
you've caught on to what I'm talking
about by now we've talked a lot about
root inoculant with sha so I would feed
the Clones the same thing when you put
those into cups uh I definitely like to
feed my clones and my seedlings a lot of
rote inoculants to get that soil uh
funky and get the roots fat fat uh the
better Roots the better the fruits is
what I say all the time so by now I feel
like we should be putting our clones
into cups and starting week three if
everything went correctly uh we fed the
plants once uh this makes me feel like
everything is one lesson now now that
we've gotten to week three and the
clones and the ceilings are caught up I
feel like there won't be much difference
between the clone the seedling clone and
the seedling that was hard to say uh the
seedlings May grow more quickly because
they have what we call seed Vigor but
that's not always the case if you have
good clones um I've seen some clones out
grow seedlings before and it's been kind
of surprising so all we've done up to
this point is pretty much plant our
seeds and clones uh we've gotten our
starter plants into cups and we've fed
them some worm tea or some rude
inoculant maybe some great white maybe
some ogt uh something like that to get
them started um and now I'm going to
call this the beginning of veg some
people may may call it preeg because we
haven't gone into our big pots yet but
I'm going to call it veg starting now
now that we've gotten out of the cloner
now that we're not little baby seedlings
anymore I'm going to say we're into veg
so the veg State can last as long as you
want uh the longer you veg like I said
earlier the larger your plants are going
to get uh the veg phase is where we do
90% of the topping training and pruning
of your plants uh we kind of did a
lesson on topping and stuff like that
but I plan to do another episode uh all
about improving your crops and improving
your improving your yields and things so
that'll come in handy um also your
plants are going to take up 90% of the
nitrogen that they use through their
entire lives during the veget vegetative
phase of their plants uh people tend to
really Overlook the veg phase and they
focus only on the bloom phase because
that's when you can see your buds but uh
the veg phase is just as important and
so is your veg space you guys a lot of
people don't spend the time building a
proper veg room and uh it really would
help you out if you if you teach those
kids how to run before you put them on
the track they'd be a lot better
performing kid so I feel like if we use
each day as a chance to prepare the
plants for Bloom our crop will look much
better at Harvest Time uh my veg phas
for my example of this grow is going to
be short you guys gosh give me one
second I'm going to press pause and take
a drink I'll probably take a dab while
I'm there excuse me for one second all
right guys I feel like we are at the
beginning of veg is where I left off so
I like to feed my plants uh the first
day of each week Mondays are usually my
feeding day for my personal crops for me
starting everything on on a Monday helps
me keep track of everything so on the
first day of EG I would feed my plants a
nice base nutrient a light humic acid uh
some potassium silicates to build strong
cell walls and I would also keep
focusing on root development we
shouldn't need any CAG or anything like
that for the first couple of weeks
everything should be cool so for the
first couple of weeks your plant should
be cool in the cups but we're going to
have to plant them into larger pots
pretty soon uh you don't want to see
them get root Bound in those cups and
they'll also get tall and skinny we want
them to Bush out a little bit so when we
put them into a larger pot they'll start
bushing out so it's also a good time to
adjust your lights uh from 24 hours to
an 186 uh schedule you want them on for
18 hours off for six uh plants like a
rest period and it's also going to save
you money on your energy bill so now
you've got your plants into cups they're
nice and healthy uh they're starting to
kind of grow a little bit they've got
nice Roots we're about 3 weeks in I
think uh by the fourth week is when we
should start putting everything into
larger pots uh if we leave them in the
cups too long they're going to get root
they're going to start getting stretchy
and also when you put them in bigger
pots they can go a little bit longer
without needing water so that'll help
you out too so if you're going to veg
for a couple extra weeks and you have
time for time and space go for bigger
pots uh for my example we're just going
to do a quick crop and we're going to
use three gallon pots and they'll be
just fine um so carefully put everything
from your cups into a three gallon pot
or a larger pot whichever you're going
to use um and I think I've talked about
transplanting I think I've talked a
little bit about doing that so if you
guys need help transplanting let me know
and I'll talk more about that but I'm
pretty sure I've covered it so carefully
put everything into a larger pot and
feed them um we should be about week
four maybe into week five by now you
guys I hope you started doing these into
into pots around week four I hope you
didn't wait too long so feed them and
you're going to feed them a strong dose
of rud inoculant of course we're always
going to do that through veg right up to
uh kind of the start of flour feed them
a veg based nutrient I use uh if I'm
using bottled nutrients for this I would
recommend Botanicare pure blend Pro soil
formula the grow formula uh they don't
pay me to say that it's just what I use
uh I would use some humic acid in there
uh for this grow for my recommendation
if you're using bottles I would say
liquid karma from Botanicare I would use
a fulvic acid which uh organicare sells
a liquid fulvic acid that works great
for this um I would use some Cal magag
at this point you guys you're going to
start needing some calag in there a very
light dose of Cal Mag to start because
your babies um aren't ready for it just
yet possibly and I don't want you to
burn them so be careful with that cow
mag but it's about to be time I would
also recommend something to feed the
microbes uh basic molasses or something
like Humbolt honey or something like
that uh hybri would be good uh anything
like that with a lot of uh molassy type
stuff there so uh now our plants are in
their final pots they've been fed these
plants can be topped or super cropped or
manipulated into a screen of green or
whatever you have planned for them uh
just make sure that if you're going to
do any topping or pruning uh do that
about 10 10 to 14 days before you start
flowering the plants your plants need a
little bit of time to recover after
you've topped them uh plants are apical
dominant which means they want to top so
after you've cut the tops the hormones
have to move around it's got to move
hormones around and you want those
hormones built up in the tips of your
plants before you flower them it's
really helpful for your plants if you
start topping stuff and pruning things
and then flower right away you're just
going to make little tiny Buds and
confuse the [ __ ] out of your plant
you'll be disappointed so now that we
are in our bigger pots and we fed
everything I'm going to say we are in
full veg mode uh we have our plants in
the finishing pots things have been
topped and super cropped we've got our
lights on a veg schedule of 18 on and 6
hours off we should be feeding a solid
veg recipe at the start of every week
and watching for any signs of bug
problems um it'd be a good idea to start
a bug prevention regimen by now if you
haven't already started spraying or
doing something to keep the mites away
uh NE oil is a great way to prevent bugs
while you're in veg but do not ever
spray a flowering plant with neem oil uh
one application of NE on a flowering
plant will ruin the entire thing the
flavor will be miserable if you make
extracts they will taste like neem oil
uh just please don't do that you guys
don't spray anything on your flowering
plants uh any bug sprays or anything on
your flowering plants if you're going to
spray stuff on flowering plants make
sure it's a well well thought out fol
your feed please uh so um yeah I think I
can hold write a whole separate rant on
Pest Management in another episode so I
said that we should feed on Monday of
every week right that's my opinion I
like to feed on Monday I mix up
nutrients uh I mix up a nice reservoir
of nutrients and feed the plants uh
every Monday they get a nice healthy
feed and then usually by Wednesday or
Thursday they need more uh they need a
water so I'll just feed them clean ph
balanced water with no nutrients in it
I'll just feed them that and then on
Monday again I will give them nutrients
and then the next time that they're
thirsty probably that next Wednesday or
Thursday they will get a fully organic
worm tea that I have brewed for like 36
hours I'll put worm castings in there
I'll put grok Kashi in there I put a
little bit of uh dragonfly Earth
medicine the Lush roots in there put a
little bit of fish hydr slate I put some
sea crop um and then I'll feed my plants
that and they get fed teas probably
twice in veg and probably three times
during the flower phase and I think it
makes a huge difference because I make a
a pretty awesome tea that Sean taught me
how to make I really think it makes a
difference so that's kind of my feeding
idea I don't think I've ever broken down
my week to week feeding schedule I don't
want to be responsible for your weekly
feeding I kind of want to let you
experiment and find what works for you
but if you've got questions about
specific nutrients uh let me know and
I'll do my best to figure out how to
incorporate that into your growth for
you that's going to take a lot of work
so like I was saying earlier we can veg
as long as we want for my example we're
going to veg for about 30 days you can
top and manipulate the plants as much as
you want while in veg did I already read
this no but I would stop talking about I
would stop talking topping about two
weeks before flowering my short crops
don't really get much uh topping and
pruning you guys if I'm running a seed
crop and I want to see what the
seedlings are I really don't uh top much
I take two clones from each plant just
before I flow it I clean up the bottoms
just a little bit uh and then once I
flow or I clean up the bottoms once I
flower but my small crops really don't
get much topping or pruning I try to let
the get the test crops just in and out
quickly so I can see what I'm working
with cuz if I've got a bunch of boys in
there or if I don't see the traits I'm
looking for then I just want to get that
out of there and scrap it as soon as
possible I'm looking for specific traits
at this point so uh for the next 30 days
while we're in veg basically we need to
watch for bugs watch for problems and
keep the plants as healthy and happy as
possible so I suggest checking each
plant every single day I know that
sounds ridiculous but however many
plants you've got you should be in there
you should touch every plant every
single day that's how you know you're
growing from your heart that's how you
know you've got solid medicine that
doesn't need to be sprayed with Eagle 20
that's how you know that if you do see a
problem you'll be on top of it and
you'll be able to cure it you'll be able
to solve the problem before it gets out
of control that's super important being
a good Gardener so I suggest checking
each day and make notes of what you see
uh if you see anything that stands out
to you make a note of it if it's good if
it's bad if it's weird if you're not
sure if it's new if it's questionable
make a note and don't forget because I
know you're going to say I'll membership
the notes are in my head dude we're
potheads we're pot growers we're dabbers
you're going to forget you're going to
forget something write it down and when
maybe one day you're going to want to
run a business and the guy with the
notes will get the opportunity to run a
business over the guy with a head full
of [ __ ] and ideas you've written
something down that shows you've done
something the other guy's like I
remember doing this the people that are
hiring you to be their Master gr at
their dispensary don't want your hopes
and dreams in your head they want to see
it on paper if you take notes you got
something that's documented and now that
it's legal you don't have to worry about
it I understand you old school Growers
didn't want any notes I get it but now
you can so uh so set a date for your
flowering cycle is what I think you
should do uh decide how long you want a
veg set a date for your flowering cycle
and then commit to that and veg for that
long get your plants trimmed up get them
pruned get them topped if you're going
to put them in a screen of green like
Spence taught us about put them in the
screen of green and get them nice and
happy and then we'll get them ready for
the flowering
cycle uh I've gone for 30 minutes and I
don't think I can get enough of the
flowering cycle to make it worth your
listen in to this episode so I think
we're just going to start wrapping up
the show at 30 minutes you guys really
listen a lot when I put out shorter
episodes you don't seem to get uh the
attention deficit disorder so we're just
going to do a short episode here I
appreciate you guys for listening I will
come back in a week and I will have a
solid lesson about the flowering
schedule for you I hope to get Spence on
an upcoming episode I was talking to
Shawn and he'll be back in the future
I've got an episode coming up about how
to improve your garden I've got a lot of
things planned you guys I'm really
getting back on my game so I'm getting
more lessons written down
uh getting more episodes planned I
appreciate you sticking through my rough
patch there while I had to do some
sloppy episodes um big thanks to
everybody who sent me well wishes on
taking care of my head wishing me better
on my head I feel much better uh I'd
like to say him about I kept saying as
was 90% dude I'm about 85% back I keep
noticing um sometimes I'll say the wrong
word in a sentence the other day I told
somebody that I was going to um eat this
banana and I was actually holding a
burrito and I didn't even realize that I
I kept saying banana but it was a
burrito and they corrected me and I said
yeah this banana is tasty and they're
like it's a [ __ ] burrito dude so I
realized I was doing that um I was
describing something that was uh purple
and I called it orange and I know I did
that but I don't uh yeah so there's
stuff like that that's going on in my
head that's still a little bit Goofy and
sometimes I forget my password still
when I try to log into my computer but
I'm getting it back together so I do
appreciate you guys sticking with me
through that it's been a really scary
time but I feel like I'm coming back
together so so uh let's wrap up the show
guys I'm [ __ ] rambly today um where
is that part that I read oh yeah it says
thanks for listening to another episode
I'll be back in another week uh don't
forget to check out the sponsors I
didn't do much ads because I wanted to
get the show going uh check out our
sponsors this Rocky Mountain worm
company and hyro indoor growing supplies
uh two Colorado based businesses that I
truly support with all my heart uh if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like us to review send me an email it's
grow from yourheart hotmail.com I will
get you all of the information that you
need don't forget get the show is
available on iTunes Stitcher and every
single episode is archived on iry
gentics
colorado.com don't forget that we did
add a donation button to the podcast
page on the website if you feel like the
show is worth a couple of bucks you can
go to my website IR genetics color.com
click on the grow fromy heart podcast
tab at the top right there's a PayPal
logo click on that make a small donation
it goes directly to my Paypal account
because I'm never going to charge you
for the podcast the show is always going
to be free but if you do feel like
making a contribution it would be
greatly appreciated I could use a new
mic phone I could use these microphone
covers this one's all grimy uh yeah no
begging just if it's if it's uh
something on your mind I would
appreciate it uh we are on all the
social media sites just search for us
it's a grow from your heart on Twitter
it's gfyh podcast you can find me on
Facebook uh please you guys follow iy
genetics on Instagram I post a lot of
sweet cannabis photography there um I've
recently joined uh what's it called
massroots but I'm not getting much
response so uh I may quit posting there
eventually but definitely check me out
on Instagram
you guys a huge shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me