[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
681 of the grow from your heart podcast
i've got a great thursday show lined up
for you this episode will include an
update from our previous episode before
we get to that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend girls grow too then let's
send a thank you shout out to my buddy
mister let's follow that up with the big
thank you shout out to spherical
glassworks i want to send a thank you
shout out to my friend josiah w let's
send a thank you shout out and a fist
bump to greenvet 88224
let's send a big thank you to g7 i want
to send a thank you shout out to a local
supporter my buddy uncle adam the uber
driver let's send a big thank you shout
out to terp burglar let's send a special
thank you shout out and a fist bump to
our buddy shakoba let's send another
thank you to new old guy then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend quasi
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include that link in the
show notes and the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends this is of course the part of
the podcast where i do invite you to
join the discord server that's right
there's an irie genetics grow from your
heart podcast discord server there's a
great community of people over there if
you need help growing any genetics not
just irie genetics if you need grow help
we are happy to help you on the discord
server
if you want to post your pictures have a
conversation talk about anything in life
you are invited all of that stuff is
welcome on the discord server there's a
place for that there's a sports tab
there's a yoga tab there's a growing tab
there's a pictures tab there's a just
hanging out tab there's a movies tab
anything you can think of if you want to
hang out with some like-minded folks we
do invite you to join the irie genetics
discord of course there is a link in the
show notes and in the video description
and you are of course invited
i do want to make a quirk a quick
disclaimer here first of all my words
are having trouble coming out today but
also it is a super windy day here in
southern colorado we are having extreme
winds if you hear weird noises in the
background i try to take out most of the
noise with this
processing gear here i will try to do
some more corrections in the computer
when i edit but you may hear some crazy
noises coming through my air
conditioning vents
there was debris and stuff bashing
against the house if you hear noises i
do apologize speaking of crazy wind
tonight is the first cold night in
colorado i've been complaining that it
is getting cold tonight it is officially
cold i think i was just kidding before
when i was saying it was cold tonight
mother nature is serious it's cold as
[ __ ] outside if you had plants outside
they were not in a greenhouse or some
sort of protected environment tonight
was the last night or today was the last
day to cut them down most of your plants
are going to start experiencing problems
they're going to get too cold of course
last year we saw some amazing [ __ ] but
ideally plants would be down by now if
you've got an outdoor environment if
you've got a greenhouse with some
heaters or some tricks you may be able
to keep those plants going but tonight
it is super cold everybody in southern
colorado is in harvest mode plants are
coming down plants are getting trimmed
jars are getting filled shelves will be
filled again soon it's a beautiful time
here in colorado but everybody is in
hurry up and harvest mode it is harvest
time if you've been following around
following along you know that i do have
a greenhouse that had some plants in it
i say had because today was the day we
finished harvesting the greenhouse all
of the plants are gone they're down
they're safely chopped up and in a warm
dry safe place to where the weather
cannot get to them and destroy the seeds
that we made i'm very proud of my uh my
friends and my crew i want to call them
my crew they're my friends i'm very
proud of my friends that did a really
good job growing this crop this year uh
there are a lot of great seeds uh there
will be uh let's see there will be lady
marmalade blue raspberry truffle
restocks very soon we made a bunch of
those uh then there will be machine and
saka souffle seeds will drop sometime i
haven't picked a an exact drop date for
those they were planned for the endo
expo right now once again there's no
update on the endo expo so i don't know
exactly when i'm going to drop the
machine and soccer souffle seeds coming
soon stay tuned you are excited about
those i definitely will keep you updated
but if you don't have some winter gear
going on in your grow you might want to
consider getting all your plants down if
you have not already because it is
frosty cold here in colorado i had to
fire up the heater uh there's a heater
here on this recording space going feels
kind of nice you could probably hear
that thing making noise too got a long
sleeve hoodie on it's for real cold
today nature's not [ __ ] around now i
did mention that i had some friends and
a crew working a greenhouse that kind of
leads me into one of the topics i want
to talk about on this episode of the
show
the reason that greenhouse worked is
because i let those growers do their
thing these people had a greenhouse that
was already set up they've been running
the greenhouse for years we spoke i said
hey i want to make some seeds in your
greenhouse they said that sounds like a
really good idea we were came to a
beautiful agreement uh they did a bunch
of work on the plants i gave some great
guidance did some hands-on work showed
them some things some tricks some tips
gave them a good strategy but for the
most part i honestly stayed out of the
way and let them grow it's their
greenhouse they know the flow they know
uh who is good at what who likes to do
what they've got their systems and their
ideas and their sops in place they were
doing a different design a different
grow because they usually of course
don't produce seeds in their product
they usually have a scentsy bud a
seedless bud but this year they were
making seeds for me so there were some
changes to be made but with very minimal
guidance my crew my team my friends were
able to produce high quality seeds
mainly i think because i stayed out of
the way and let them work with their
style and their flow
i could have gone in and i did of course
i took notes uh on things that i didn't
like and i made suggestions and we made
corrections as we went it was all
friendly it was like hey i see that
you're doing this
what's your reason and they would give
me a reason i would say cool reason i
understand but i've been doing it for a
long time and this is what that is going
to cause i saw one thing they're trying
to do to prevent one problem but it was
going to cause two more problems we had
a quick team meeting and we quickly
agreed let's not do this i'd rather have
small problem a than compounding
problems b and c so there were a couple
of quick meetings a couple of
observations i took notes i thought of
things that we can improve next year
we've already talked about that but
honestly i stayed out of their way and
just let them do their thing because
they are experienced cannabis growers
they have developed their system they've
developed their sops also that's their
greenhouse they know
they knew what weather to expect they
knew where the hot pockets in the grow
was not the hot pockets we eat you guys
the warm spots in the grow some people
right now are getting the munchies
because i said that uh but uh free
advertising there you go eat something
better for you but they knew all the
problems and the niches of the grow they
knew where all the switches all the
bells all the whistles if we wanted to
turn on something they knew where that
button was
so it's their place
what i'm getting at
is i see a lot of people on social media
trying to give people instructions and
they say you need to do this or you must
do this and they give crazy crazy advice
what i want to say is do things your way
and it will work there are a few rules
of growing cannabis basically uh keep
them alive water them give them proper
light and then if you have a successful
harvest that you were happy with you did
it right if the plants don't die you're
doing it correctly you can do things
better you can do things differently but
if you have a harvested outcome you did
it right if you were satisfied with it
what we can always do is work on
improving what we have done the first
time the second time the third time your
first grow allow your first grow to be a
total train wreck that way you've got
some learning and some experience from
it if that first grow comes off
perfectly you're never going to learn
anything your ego is going to get big
you're going to go i can grow we let's
just do it and your next grow is going
to suck because you got egotistical and
you didn't have any mistakes if you have
some adversity you learn a lot more so
let me get back on my notes because i do
have some sort of direction here what
i'm what i'm trying to get to is do
things your way you're learning from me
you're probably learning from books
other podcasters maybe your friends
listen to all of us take all of our
information then turn it into your thing
you're hearing a lot of different things
a lot of getting a lot of different
input kind of translate that interpret
it how you would like and make it your
grow that grow space is yours design it
the way you want grow the plants you
want grow the style you want
these plants do require some love and
some care and some attention for a
top-notch harvest but don't expect your
first harvest to be amazing you haven't
developed your skill yet you haven't
developed your style yet and also don't
expect that growth to be exactly like
mine it doesn't have to be my grow do
your growth the way you want develop
your style
develop your skill set then it will all
come together learn make some mistakes
kill some plants over water some things
over feed some things under feed some
things get all the way to the harvest
and then mess up the dry and cure
experience all of the pitfalls and
mistakes that a grower can make i've
done a full episode about making
mistakes because i've made plenty of
them that's why i'm a good grower i
think that if i had never made any
mistakes i've said it before i wouldn't
be as good of a grower as i think i am
now i can problem solve now i can
correct issues on the fly now i can
anticipate and predict problems like i
said a moment ago we were going to
correct problem a but i knew it would
make problem b and c happen so we just
stick with problem a and try to mitigate
that as much as possible
i can anticipate and predict the issues
that will arise in the grow room from
experience if you stick with your craft
and pay attention and fall in love with
this craft and do it with passion and
take notes and dedication is the word
i'm looking for you will develop the
skills the same skill set that i've got
i'm nobody special i'm just some dude
just like you or you're maybe some lady
some female or maybe whatever spectrum
you find yourself in i'm just a person
and i've done a lot of research and i'm
passionate about my craft there's
nothing stopping you from becoming this
knowledgeable and skillful with this
plant in a grow you can achieve this
just learn pay attention you might not
be growing yet you may be
semi-experienced you may be a better
grower than me but there's always
something to learn and your style is
always developing so don't think that
your first grow has to be the best don't
think that that's your last growth
that's your first grow that's the one
you should make mistakes on if you make
mistakes on like the ninth and tenth
grow that's when we go hey is this
person ever going to learn are they just
going to keep driving into the [ __ ]
wall make some mistakes on that first
second and third grow so that you know
like oops i overfed i saw crispy leaves
i under fed i saw pale leaves i didn't
water one day and i got droopy ass
plants i over watered the next day i got
clawed and [ __ ] up plants then start
learning to identify signs of heat
stress cold stress other stresses start
then you'll start seeing bugs you won't
go what are these spots on my plants and
you wait two weeks to treat for spider
mites because you didn't even know they
were mites just develop that
relationship get in there play with the
plants learn some skills kill some [ __ ]
that's where i was make some mistakes
i've made crucial mistakes in big and
small grows
let's make all of these mistakes early
on so that we can get them out of the
way get them under our belt learn from
them get a little embarrassment get a
little humbling from it and then have
that lesson in your tool belt to move
forward with in the future to prevent us
from making that mistake again also that
may help you predict and anticipate
other mistakes that you may make you may
be like hey i did something similar to
this that one time let me read my notes
and then i'll have a big circle with an
x on it like don't ever do this dumb
[ __ ] again because it made all the
plants go crazy like take some notes and
learn a lot about what you're doing let
me get on my notes because i'm rambling
in stone today uh this should be
enjoyable and
educational when i see people telling
people that they have to do some [ __ ] or
that they must do this or just random
instructions i'm like you're just
sucking the enjoyment out of the plants
let this person grow the way that they
want to grow and develop their style and
their system and their flow of growing
you'll become a good grower you'll have
your own system your style every grower
walks into the grow and we've got like a
routine you do this and then you do this
this is how i mix this is how i feed
this is how i do this this is what i
check on these are the notes i take this
is my clean up procedure clock out go
home everyone's got their little system
you will develop yours that will work
for you
your system doesn't have to be like my
system it doesn't have to be like the
dude system it doesn't have to be scotty
real system it doesn't have to be guru
system it doesn't have to be anybody
from any other podcast system or any
other professional grower you've ever
seen it can be your system make it a
hybrid of all of the systems that you've
seen i always recommend starting off
simple and expanding there but start
with the system that gets your attention
something will get your attention when
it comes to growing a strain that you
want to grow will get your attention a
system will get your attention a light
will get your attention when you do a
little research delve into it all of the
things will come together your setup
your style and your system will kind of
develop itself and it will be a
beautiful enjoyable experience it'll be
your comfort zone once you get that grow
dialed in it will be where you retreat
to get away from all of the crap in your
life you'll be like ah something's
stressful i'm going to the grow and
you'll just go hang out in there and it
will feel good you'll forget about all
the other [ __ ] that's going on in life
sometimes i say i'm going to go in the
grow and just hang out for like 30
minutes maybe pull some leaves see if i
can find anything that i can do just
look for work in there
and then i realize oh yeah i've just
listened to like seven seven podcasts in
here and i haven't really done anything
i'm just like pulling leaves and popping
stems and just just finding light work
to do but time will just go by and there
it's such a beautiful place it smells
good the temperature is perfect the
humidity is perfect the music is perfect
the company is great it's a great place
to be so build your zen space and have
fun in there make it educational and
comforting and relaxing and enjoyable
don't make it stressful because people
on the internet say you have to top that
plant you have to up pot those your
lights are wrong everyone's got an
opinion don't let it bother you do your
thing just do it your way of course if
the plants are dying and if [ __ ] is
failing maybe take some advice but if
it's working and if it's only your first
try do your thing and don't be afraid to
make some mistakes don't let people
intimidate you the internet the internet
tries to scare and intimidate people
making them think they have to do a lot
of [ __ ] that's not necessary don't worry
about that do what you can do
i do my best not to intimidate you there
are a lot of pieces of equipment to be
involved in a grow a lot of skills a lot
of steps a lot of things to be involved
in to grow i try to go slowly and not
scare you away with the cost and all the
requirements i try to go real slowly and
invite you i want it to be welcoming and
enjoyable for you so keep it that way
don't make it stressful let me catch up
on my notes sometimes you will have to
adjust and adapt your space and your
schedule and your budget and your style
and your goal
um just adjust sometimes the things you
tried to do might not work out after
that first or second grow if you're
seeing that something isn't working
adjust and adapt don't be stubborn i've
seen people try to make [ __ ] work if it
doesn't work it just doesn't work let's
adapt adjust and correct things and set
ourselves up for success instead of
spending money
on lights soil uh water nutrients maybe
you wasted seeds maybe you wasted clones
let's quit wasting things i do have
another episode uh planned and prepared
to talk about how to save some money and
budget better in the growth so we'll
talk about that in the future
but uh people make growing really
stressful and i see the internet trying
to make growing stressful on new growers
trying to prevent that let's keep it fun
you guys let's just keep it a good time
it should be therapeutic relaxing should
be the zen zone um i can make a big grow
fun and enjoyable we run large grows
with multiple 100 lights 500 lights and
20 people working and we're having a
good time we got the music up super loud
we're high fiving each other
when we get a row of clones done we all
do the ric flair woo because we're all
excited about it
i try to make a big environment exciting
and all that takes is just building a
flow building a system having a team
that communicates and all knows what the
final goal is and then just having a
good attitude and setting yourself up
for success every day today you're
setting yourself up for success tomorrow
that's not just in the grow that's
everywhere but in the grow you can see
it if you don't do the side work tonight
before you leave tomorrow you've got to
do the side work before you can even
start doing the real work so you're just
rushing to get to the real work then you
got to do the real work in a rush then
you don't get the side work done again
tonight because you [ __ ] up and had to
rush everything then there's always a
surprise in a commercial grow always a
surprise i teach the new guys i say this
a lot when i train a new guy in a
commercial grow i just have them shadow
me for a day and as we walk in i always
say the first thing we're gonna do is
find out what went wrong last night what
pump broke what light went out there's a
lot of moving parts in a 500 light grow
a lot of things can break let's go find
out what happened last night that's
usually the first thing we do
we still keep it fun we still keep it
enjoyable because that's i love the
plants that is that is the main uh the
main part is to have fun and enjoy this
[ __ ] and the plants i think the plants
can feel your vibes do you ever walk
into a grow and you just feel that life
force that presence that energy that is
the plants why can't the plants feel it
from us as well uh if you're walking in
there anxious disheveled nervous rushed
the plants feel that what if you went to
the doctor or the dentist and the
dentist had like
a distracted rushed disheveled feel or
like they felt like they had to just
hurry up and get [ __ ] done you might not
go to that dentist you might be like can
i come back tomorrow
like i'd rather come back when you've
got time to like sit down and look at my
tooth and actually do the stuff instead
of like drill it fill it stitch me up
send me on my way and high five me that
that's not what i need from a dentist i
want some love and care take your time
the plants enjoy that too and they can
feel it from you
all right i'm gonna catch up on these
notes i'm stoned and rambling i want to
make sure i got all the important parts
here
make it enjoyable and educational those
are the words that i have in bold
there's no exact way to grow cannabis
the exact way is the way that's working
for you i've seen it done a billion
different ways and guess what i've seen
a billion successful outcomes so
whatever is working for you do that [ __ ]
don't let anyone on the internet scare
you don't let them tell you you're doing
it wrong don't let them talk [ __ ] to you
uh let them give you constructive
criticism and then learn how to filter
out all the [ __ ] the internet is
full of crap and you're gonna get some
terrible terrible advice always ask why
when you when somebody gives you advice
just say why and see if they can tell
you why if they say because my uncle
larry did it in the 70s and it worked
that's not why that's just because uncle
larry did it maybe uncle larry's plants
are way different than yours maybe
you're growing indoors uncle larry was
outdoors maybe you're in the northern
hemisphere larry was in the southern
[ __ ] could be way different you never
know all right i feel like i got good
and rambly on that i did say that i've
got an update from a previous episode
let's jump into that part here trying to
get myself on some sort of a track all
right in a previous episode we talked
about trellising our plants we had a
listener or a viewer who wanted to use a
by five grow tent they wanted to trellis
their plants or have some sort of
supports for their buds but if they put
up the trellis they were unable to get
to the plants properly we have had some
follow-up conversation from that viewer
from that listener what they have
decided to do is build the trellis
system and an auto watering system and
just suck it up their next question was
about co2 which i will address in a
future episode today let's talk about
the update on the trellis question there
was one piece that i greatly overlooked
there's a grower that taught me how to
take big pots and build an individual
trellis on each pot i think what he was
using was a 30 gallon tote that he would
put on wheels or on casters and then he
would fill the 30 gallon tote with a
soilless mix or a soil put some holes in
the bottom of that for drainage then he
would use that soilless mix bed as like
a big raised bed then he would build a
trellis system out of pvc piping it
would put two four posts one post in
each corner four posts in there kind of
build like a table and then put a net
into the table and then slowly lower
that onto the plants and trellis the
plants out with that net that allowed
him to move his plants around he could
move them around the tent around the
room around the facility and he could
have them trellised out properly so it
is possible to build trellis netting for
individual plants i'm not sure why i
didn't think about that in the first
episode when we talked about this but as
i was listening and editing i was like
oh you didn't even talk about the
opportunity to trellis your big plants
by themselves in a tent so you could
just use like a 30 gallon container i
think it's a 30 gallon like a sterlite
bin or a rubbermaid bin just uh i think
it's 30 gallons i'm pretty sure that's
what it is they're about 30 inches by 20
by about 15. fill that up with your
soilless mix or whatever you want to use
put plenty of holes in the bottom for
drainage put it on casters you can roll
that around then you just build a little
square frame it's a rectangle it's kind
of like a table basically you can get
creative with that as long as you've got
posts in each corner then maybe extend
it so it's wider because your plant will
be wider than that pot if you do things
correctly
but make some extenders make it go
higher longer however you need it then
just use that pvc frame put your trellis
net right on there you can trellis your
individual plants of course those are
gigantic plants those are big but that
does work
recently while shopping at a big box
hardware store i know i shouldn't go to
the big box stores but it was my only
option i did see a 16-inch tomato cage
with a built-in trellis on the top
that's right the top layer of the tomato
cage had a square grid built onto the
top of it so if you want to do a small
individual trellis system that would be
a great way to do it just pull one bud
through each square have a nice even
canopy going on there that would be a
beautiful idea all right that was my
update for the trellising episode i did
want to make sure to include those two
pieces you can trellis individual pots
by building a pvc trellis or you can use
the pre-made circle uh tomato cage with
the trellis on top i've also seen people
put sticks in each corner use a twisty
tie or that garden tape and just build
like a spiral up and use that to put the
branches in place get creative you guys
once again there's no wrong way to do it
as long as the plants are successful as
long as you're happy with it there's
always room for improvement but there's
no wrong way to do it
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pams hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis growers
and smokers out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast this episode is going to be
quick because i don't want to lose the
recordings i don't want the power to cut
out i don't want anything to go wrong i
feel like i got enough material to call
this successful so we're going to wrap
it up thank you again for listening to
another episode uh questions corrections
comments and concerns send those to my
email address grow
fromyourheart.hotmail.com of course
don't forget about the discord server
join us on discord i do invite you
if you missed anything if you have any
questions everything is on the website
at
iregenetics.com all the contact info all
the discord stuff all the vendor links
everything you need at iregenetics.com
all right ladies and gentlemen that's
all i've got for you for this episode
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my buddy ez057
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you