[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me ross to
jeff and this is episode
682 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode we're going to focus on
saving you a few dollars in your grow
room before we get to that part of the
show let's do a few shout outs to a few
of the great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
magic mike let's send a big thank you
shout out to verbal medicine let's send
a big thank you shout out and a fist
bump to a long time supporter my buddy
let's send a big thank you shout out to
nick p i want to send a special thank
you shout out to brohan 78 let's send a
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to blackhawks fan i want to send a thank
you shout out to my buddy mister let's
send a big thank you shout out to
groove2112
let's send a thank you shout out to ivan
m i want to send a big thank you shout
out to my buddy lefty let's send a thank
you shout out to levity love day i want
to send a thank you shout out to single
t then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend pac northwest dan
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www dot
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen and you know i do
include a link in the show notes to make
everything super easy for all of my
friends this of course is the part of
the podcast where i do invite you to
join us on the discord server that's
right i say it on almost every episode
there's an irie genetics grow from your
heart podcast discord server we've got
about 1600 members people are hanging
out right now they're smoking they're
having a conversation they're posting
pictures of ganja plants they're doing
all the things you want to be doing on
discord i invite you to join us there is
a link in the show notes and in the
video description once again join us on
the discord server all right i do have a
couple of fun things to ramble about
before we get to the main topic of this
podcast
i try not to brag about all the amazing
[ __ ] that i get to do but since the
world has opened up and we're having fun
again i want to share an experience that
i had a few nights ago
on sunday doug benson headlined comedy
works in denver colorado of course you
know the comedy works is my favorite
comedy club on the planet i think that
is the best club on the planet the
downtown club in denver uh they've got a
great staff they've got an amazing owner
uh they've got an amazing stage a great
club and the acts that they bring are
always top-notch of course if you've
been listening for a while you know that
doug benson is my homie that should be a
bumper sticker doug benson is my homie
somebody make it happen but doug benson
is my friend we've been hanging out for
quite a while i've seen a lot of doug
benson shows uh the majority i think uh
almost all of them were at the comedy
works downtown uh but doug benson came
to denver and he did a show at comedy
works and he did a great show uh big
shout out to my buddy baker i have a
friend my buddy clint usually goes to
comedy shows with me he's my comedy
buddy we're both comedy nerds clint was
busy that day so i invited my buddy
baker who lives in denver denver is a
baker is a former employee of the comedy
works so everybody there knows baker uh
everybody there knows me because i'm a
regular i'm there every week it was a
really good time walking in with baker
uh my buddy doug benson came out on
stage i did chat with doug a little bit
before the show we did some tweeting we
did some talking he chose not to smoke
with people this time if you know doug
you know he is a big smoker he usually
hangs out with the crowd uh because of
the quarantine conditions because of
kovid he's chosen to protect himself he
wasn't smoking with anybody i chose to
respect that so we didn't hang out
before the show like normal but when he
walked on stage he made sure to wave to
me uh he made me stand up and show the
crowd my dreadlocks that was a little
bit interesting uh he realized my buddy
baker was the guy sitting next to me
eventually and he's like oh hey dude
didn't realize that was you that was
kind of funny but
at the end of the show
i tried not to impose uh on doug benson
i knew he wanted some privacy but i was
invited to go say hello after i popped
into the green room said hello then i
quickly excused myself i knew doug was
trying to protect himself and not try to
get sick and not be around a lot of
people so i threw a fist bump i threw
some high fives and i said hey it's
crowded in the green room i'm out of
here
there was a young man in that green room
who um we're not going to get too
political but he's not into the mask
thing he finds it silly that's not what
he's doing so when i uh politely excused
myself from the green room shortly after
that he came out to smoke with me since
everybody smoking in the green room was
kind of a mask person so the guy that
followed me outside and ended up smoking
a big 14 gram joint of the cream with me
was this comedian you might have seen on
tv his name was josh blue
that was a really good experience
because i excused myself from that green
room and tried not to impose and mix
myself up into that crowd i ended up
smoking a big fat joint with josh blue
sometimes life just works itself out for
you that was a blessing josh blue of
course was just on america's got talent
he is the the comedian with cerebral
palsy not trying to be rude but uh if
you ever pass a joint to a guy with
cerebral palsy be [ __ ] patient trying
to get that thing back had to chase it
down that's just a joke i'd sit in front
of him he makes fun of his palsy arm
it's [ __ ] hilarious but really he had
to chase it down his palsy arm just went
out of control and he had the joint in
the palsy arm i'm like well no i'm never
getting the [ __ ] joint back had to
chase it that was a funny joke i looked
him right in the eye and shook my head
like you [ __ ] you put it in that
hand because he knew better he was i'm
not sure if he was [ __ ] with me or if
his paul's yarn was out of control and
that joint was just going everywhere
anyway big up to josh blue that was a
great experience something i want to
mention a long time ago i did a podcast
talking about seeing doug benson
i said that doug benson pulled out a
bunch of papers called and i called it a
handful of grandpa if you see doug
benson again you're gonna laugh at the
handful of grandpa if he's still doing
one of the bits that i saw him do i'm
not gonna blow his act at all but a
handful of grandpa just go see doug
benson and laugh when that happens all
right that's enough bragging about
comedy i just wanted to share with you
guys what i do sometimes it's fun to
bring you into my world some people are
going to say i'm bragging some people
are going to say thanks for hanging out
big up to both of you thank you both for
watching all right now let's focus more
on cannabis growing ganja production a
cannabis consumption podcast i'm
scrolling through my notes trying to get
myself on track here big shout out to
doug benson big shout out to comedy
works big shout out to baker big shout
out to josh blue big shout out to the
opening acts big shout out to everybody
who made sunday an amazing day let's
keep moving i do have a big topic here
let's talk about cannabis growing let's
talk about a few ways to save you money
in your grow space i do offer
professional commercial cultivation
consulting services
one of the things that i talk about when
i go to a commercial cultivation to do a
consultation those are a lot of words
together but when i go to do that one of
the things i focus on is increasing
productivity or reducing costs by about
30 percent i know i can save some money
i know i can increase cost can i do both
enough to increase productivity and
reduce costs by 30 percent that is a
huge goal in a commercial facility if
you can increase productivity by 30
percent that's 30 percent more money
you're gonna make which will really help
out right now a lot of commercial
facilities in colorado are barely
scraping even so we've got to make every
dollar count this also counts when
you're working in your own home grow if
you've got one light if you've got four
lights if you've got a 12 lighter in
your garage however you're doing it
every dollar counts especially in the
situation we are in i don't know how the
pandemic treated you maybe you made some
money maybe you went broke maybe you're
scraping by it doesn't matter everybody
can save a few bucks if you have money
and you save a few bucks you have more
money if you barely have any money and
you save a few bucks maybe you can use
those dollars to improve on something in
your life or in your garden so let me
get my high ass on track and let's talk
about some ways to save money in your
grow space
first of all in a commercial environment
one of the things i focus on is is your
building the appropriate size did you
buy a big ass warehouse thinking you're
going to load it up with lights and
plants and then you're only using a
small portion of that real estate is
expensive space is expensive every
square foot of your cultivation space
costs you money use it if you're not
using it you're wasting space that is a
big void do you wanna if i gave you a
cooler and i said put weed in the cooler
are you gonna put weed in some of the
space in that cooler are you gonna fill
the whole cooler with weed do that with
your grow environment fill that [ __ ] up
or you are wasting space maximize your
output
of course you do need processing area
trimming area working area but you get
the point if you've got some dark area a
room that's not even being used if
you're storing [ __ ] in there just
because it's empty utilize that room do
something with it make it pay for itself
real estate square footage is expensive
and that matters in any grow if you're
running a commercial grow a five by five
tent a three by three tent be economical
be cost effective with your space use
every square foot of space that you've
got you paid for it even if it's a tent
you bought a five by five tent use the
five by five i see people setting up a
trellis in a five by five and they're
allowed to grow three plants or four
plants in their legal location so
they'll put four plants in there but
they don't veg it out to fill that tent
so even if you're running a three by
three fill it up if you're running a
five by five fill it up veg long enough
to utilize that space i see a lot of
wasted space in a lot of grow tents and
think of it this way sometimes it's
illegal where people are growing are you
going to grow just enough to get by or
are you going to grow enough to [ __ ]
make it worth it because if you get in
trouble you're getting in trouble either
way if you've got a plant and it's kind
of this big or if you've got a plant
it's this [ __ ] big and it's in your
house it's gonna be the same charge go
big or go the [ __ ] home and make it
worth it fill your space so real estate
is one of the number one things that i
see people wasting in any grow fill your
tent fill your commercial growth then
another thing that i see when those
rooms are filled they're only filled
with lights they're not filled with
plants and the lights are running
just like your mama says just like your
dad says if that light isn't on for a
reason turn it the [ __ ] off if you're
not in that room turn the light off if
there are not plants underneath that
light turn the light off why is that
light running for no plants it looks
cool yeah you got the whole room lit up
all the workspace is bright it looks
like a big productivity area but you're
just burning lumens wasting your bulb
running electricity the kilowatts are
just spinning on the meter outside
you're not getting anything from it
except a little bit more heat you're
running lights that are unnecessary
you're creating more heat which means
you need to run more fans which will
also mean you probably need more air
conditioning which are all sucking more
kilowatts that you don't need so think
about the equipment you do not need
that's running right now and turn it off
maybe you've got plants too far apart i
like to plant i like the plants to have
some space they need some breathing room
they don't need to be crowded but do you
have plants too far spread apart
unnecessarily to where you've got extra
lights on can you possibly turn off that
row of lights move all those plants over
and wait for them to grow a little bit
and then when they're bigger then we'll
use more light that may be something
that you're uh not thinking about
something else to think about move the
plants closer together that's easier to
do if you are using smaller pots are you
using the right size pot i like to use
graduated pot sizes which means i start
off in a so you go from a cloner right
you got your clone domes or your clone
however many of those [ __ ] cram those
under a light as soon as they go into
the small pots you can get them pretty
close together your plants are only
three inches tall three inches wide why
do they need a lot of space cram a lot
of those together put them under the
light then as soon as they start growing
spread them out make them comfortable
but don't give them two or three lights
until you need to run two or three
lights
ah this isn't as big of a deal in a
small grow but once you get into a
commercial environment when i'm saying
one or three lights that means 10 15 20
lights that adds up quite quickly
so do you have unnecessary lighting that
is running are your plants in small
enough pots where you can push them
together and save some space until it is
time to add though the bigger pots and
the extra lighting now something that
will save you some more money if you're
running smaller pots is you obviously
don't need as much soil or cocoa as soon
you're going to need it later but you
don't need it now you can save some
money now
money comes and goes it you may not have
all the money right now you may have it
later to buy more soil for bigger pots
so you can use smaller pots for now
until you get that next paycheck maybe
do whatever you need to do to make the
next few bucks then you put them in
bigger pots then you have to spread them
apart further put them under more light
but then you need to water them more so
if you put them in a smaller pot they
don't need as much water they don't need
as much nutrients also that takes less
time and we're going to talk about that
here toward the end of the show so one
quick thing you can think about is pot
size am i using too big of a pot too
early can i keep these plants in smaller
pots keep them closer together and keep
less light on and that may save you some
money that could save you a lot of money
just the water the nutrients the time
the light then that equals more air
conditioning and fans that you can turn
off that is one quick thing that can
save you a few bucks consolidate the
plants under less lights no matter what
kind of lights you're running they do
cost money even if they are high
efficient led lights they they're
costing you money they're generating
heat they're making more equipment run
and the bigger pots if you're using
bigger pots unnecessarily it takes more
water takes more nutrients takes more ph
up or ph down takes you longer to mix
takes you longer to water the water
costs money it all adds up if you really
pay attention and think about it now
let's talk about some of your ancillary
gear how are your dehumidifier and
humidifiers running are they on too
frequently are they on often enough are
they on unnecessarily sometimes i
recommend putting them on to battle each
other uh in a dry and cure environment i
will set them both at 55 and just let
them fight so that it stays at 55 all
day in that room but that isn't a
commercial environment where it is
critical that we keep those conditions
do you have gear running unnecessarily
do you can you turn some of it off now
that we've turned off some of the lights
will that help you out have you cleaned
the filters in those devices because
when those filters get dirty they are
not as efficient that is also true with
your air conditioner have you cleaned
your air conditioning filters if they're
dirty they're sucking up some of your
efficiency you're not getting as much
air flow the motors are running they're
struggling you're wasting money you're
not getting the air in the cooling that
you think you're getting but you are
putting out the electricity and the
stress on your gear which is costing you
money so now that we're talking about
air conditioning let's talk about
ducting are you running ducting do you
have vented lights do you have a carbon
filter that's blowing air out you have
some sort of air coming in
ducting every time you put a bend in
your ducting it becomes less efficient
every time you put a curve a kink a bend
or a twist in that ducting you are
slowing down the amount of air and the
speed of the air the volume of air which
can move through that duct you are
lessening the efficiency efficacy
efficiency of the fan the blower that
you're using to blow that air through
that ducting so if you straighten it out
a little bit you could probably use uh
save a few kilowatts use a little less
bucks use a little less power to move
more air of course i understand ducks
need to be bent that's why we get the
flexi duct [ __ ] does happen but maybe
unnecessary curves and [ __ ] maybe unex
necessary duct length can be minimized
uh one thing you do have to keep in mind
though is if you're using the lights
with the ducted hoods you do need to
kind of keep the light from coming in if
you've got sunshine or another light or
something so you may need those bins i
understand but try to minimize and
mitigate those excessive bends
if you are using the lights that have
the glass between so there's a bulb and
glass and your canopy that way the heat
doesn't get down into your grow you duck
that heat out clean that glass that
glass being dirty will suck up your
lumens if the light can't get through
it's not getting to your plants you are
wasting money you're paying for it the
lights are burning the lights are hot
and you're just [ __ ] blocking it with
your pesticide that got sprayed up on
that glass there not even making it to
your plants something else we can think
about when it comes to ducting that i
almost overlooked is where are you
running your ducting are you wasting
that heat if you're running that hot air
right outside of the house and it's the
winter maybe consider dumping that heat
into the office into a bedroom somewhere
that you want to heat up anyway maybe
then you can turn off the heater and the
rest of the house you can just dump your
grow room heat right into your bedroom
and then you don't even have to run the
heater that will save you a few bucks
use the heat that's already being
created sometimes i will dump the heat
from my bedroom into my flower space
when the lights go off uh because in the
winter the flower room will get colder
but the bedroom stays on so we just run
the heat from there into the flower
space it keeps the flower space nice and
warm so think about where you're running
your heat are you wasting it are you
pulling cold air from somewhere and not
sending it somewhere that it needs to be
really think about where you're moving
your air you're moving temperature air
move it to where you want it maybe you
can use it recycle that air warm up a
room cool down a room i don't know your
environment your situation but there are
a lot of options that will come up where
you can utilize the air the heat the
cool that comes from the grow space now
let's segue back into talking about
space are you wasting space with
unnecessary plants fortunately and
unfortunately i am limited by the state
of colorado of how many plants i could
have
that kind of helps me out because i
could have hoarder tendencies if i were
unlimited on plants i would have a lot
of mother plants being a breeder
somebody who likes to create new
genetics and have a large library of
genetics to create and also a large
library to smoke from i would have a lot
of plants if i weren't limited so it's
kind of a good thing that the state does
limit me every plant in my garden has a
purpose i've got mother plants i've got
father plants and then of course i've
got my plants that are in bloom that are
seeded and i've got my father plant in
there dumping the pollen so i've got
very select plants that all have a
purpose do you have plants that you're
not exactly sure your plan their goal
why are they sticking around i kind of
just like that one because that strain
is cool is that strain worth of [ __ ]
does it produce is it a quality strain
are you just keeping that plan around
for nostalgia because of the name
because of a cool story it's got to meet
goals it's got to meet a criteria it's
got to meet a quota does it give you
enough product when you grow it does it
take too long to flower is it super
potent does it taste right if you're a
commercial grower does it sell because
if you're putting all of this money into
the grow it's got to come back right so
does it sell when it sells does it get
you top dollar or do your clientele pass
on it if they pass on it why are you
growing that [ __ ] grow more of the lemon
jeffrey because the people are gonna buy
that grow the machine grow the soccer
souffle that's what they're gonna buy if
they're not buying it switch it up so
every plant in your grow space should
have a solid purpose and a strategy and
a schedule not just uh it should not
just be a potent plant that pays the
bills but it should also have a schedule
it got cut this day it goes into veg
this day it goes into flower this day i
plan to cut it down this day and then i
intend to have it dried cured and sold
or smoked or processed or whatever by
this time frame have a schedule for
every single plant in the grow or that
plant is kind of wasting space and
messing up your schedule and messing up
your income and your cost effectiveness
now since we're talking about individual
plants in the grow i did mention mother
plants are mother plants necessary for
your style of grow think about this a
mother plant is kept to preserve the
genetics so that when i want uh let's
just pick a plant when i want golden
goat i can go to my go to my golden goat
plant pull off six clones now i've got
six clones of golden goat whenever i
want them and that mommy plant is always
chilling there she grows every six or
eight months or so i gotta cut her down
take one of those best clones and re-mom
that clone and make a new one because
the plant just gets old and big and
spindly and out of control just try to
give it a fresh cut start over but for
the most part that golden goat mommy is
there as a bank as preservation
what is stopping me from just using that
golden goat veg plant and right before i
put it into flour take a few clones and
use those clones as my next veg run move
that plant right into the flower space
if you are not a breeder if you are not
completely dependent on keeping those
strains around that is a very viable
option that will free up numbers for you
so you could just take a plant that is
your lemon jeffree plant take six clones
of it put the big plant into the flower
room and you got six clones growing up
for your next run they're already right
there maybe wait until your clone's root
before you put that plant into flowers
so you have some security but it is not
completely necessary to keep a mother
plant around if you are skilled at
taking clones if you understand how to
keep veg plants healthy and happy and if
you can get the clones to root in a
timely manner before you put the other
plant into flower so keeping clones is
not always necessary and that could save
you a lot of space i don't recommend
that for a commercial environment
because you may need a lot of clones you
need some dedicated plants to give you
cuts from but in a home grow space that
would save you a lot of plants now let's
get back to talking about mom plants a
little bit
why do you have so many mom plants do
you need them or why do you have so many
strains do you need them are they
necessary um do you need that many are
you just keeping them for hoarder
purposes i think i said most of this
already but really think about why
you're keeping each plant and then
possibly minimize if you don't need all
of those if you've got two that are
depend it depends on what your goal is
it's all about the goal but if you are a
commercial cropper find the one or two
that sell the best that way you don't
have to keep clones or moms you could
just keep production going uh if you're
a medical grower find the one or two the
one for the day the one for the night
and then one to switch it up because you
always need that switch hitter i feel
like you get strain lock if you smoke
the [ __ ] the same [ __ ] too long but try
to pick two or three maybe four and
minimize down and make sure that every
strain in that garden has a solid reason
for being there if you fill the grow
with a bunch of sixes how are you gonna
get a bunch of nines in there and if you
got a bunch of nines and you got them
surrounded by six is it just d values
the nines let's get the nines in there
maybe some tens maybe some elevens if
you quit [ __ ] with the sixes all
right another great way to save a few
bucks or increase productivity in a
small space is to add some shelves for
vertical growing if you've got clones on
a shelf what's to stop you from putting
like a three or four tier shelf with the
t5 light with the tray of clones with
the t5 light with the tray of clones
with the t5 light and a tray of clones
or just a one shelf area and you could
put small plants on the bottom big
plants on the top hang your light from
the underside so you got a light for the
small plants then put your big light up
on the ceiling and put your plants up on
the top shelf use that vertical space to
the best of your ability we have a
friend that's been on the podcast before
that does a complete vertical grow so
there are a lot of options to go up if
you run out of space on the floor use
that vertical space
then you can make space for all of your
gear and all of your stuff get that up
off the floor then you've got more floor
space for working more floor space for
plants also i see a lot of walkways and
grows in a small grow and a personal
grow what do you need a walkway for we
talked about this on a previous episode
that is not a walking path that's not
your zen garden that is not where you go
to put your hands behind your back and
walk around like old man and feed the
ducks think about life that is a
productivity space put plants in the
[ __ ] walkway i understand a
commercial grill you've got to get
through there if it's your personal grow
move plants into that space you can fit
another row of plants put them in there
you're ripping yourself off we're not
growing concrete we're not growing
drywall rock growing floor we want to
grow more plants put more plants in that
space that is my theory back to filling
up the cabinet or the box or the cooler
fill it up quit wasting space with the
walkway you can just do some work move
the plants and walk through do the jenga
move do the tetris move do whatever you
have to do to get through there but
let's not waste so much space with
walkways um
where am i i feel like i got a lot going
on shelves for vertical space
how many moms do you have cut and go do
you have a strategy do you have a
strategy for every plant when i cut a
clone i know i think i mentioned this
briefly i know when i cut a clone i know
where it's going to go and i know which
space it will go in the veg area i know
which space it's gonna go into the
flower area i know basically what day
it'll go into the flower area do you
have a plan and a strategy for every
single plant i see some people that just
cut a bunch of clones they pot all of
them and then when it comes time to go
into flower they've got 20 or 30 clones
and they pick the best 10 or 12. what
are you doing yeah yeah that many plants
extra running for that long that you
wasted water soil space newt's time and
energy
get rid of that [ __ ] every plant you cut
should be top shelf give it the best
love you can pay the best attention you
can to it and that way you don't have to
cut a bunch of extras and waste all the
time and space have a goal for every
single plant that you cut everything
costs something everything in the grow
costs something let's start with just
cutting clones you had to use uh clone
gel you had to use clone plugs a clone
dome you had to clean the equipment
which took you time and energy uh then
you had to use water and nutrients
that's just for cutting clones we're
already at a substantial cost you had to
go to the store and drop some money
already then you've got to pop those
clones into something you've got to buy
either soil cocoa something to put them
in then you've got to have a container
to put that [ __ ] in then probably some
plant tags or something then we got to
feed them we gotta give them water that
is material we've gotta pay for and more
time that we are investing everything
costs something uh big pots cost
something soil and cocoa again cost
something the ph up and down costs
something the ph pen costs a lot those
things are expensive and they die you
break them quite often everything costs
cost a lot if you've got a ph pen make
sure you keep the cap on it make sure
you keep it clean and calibrated that'll
save you some money because then you
don't have to buy a new one take good
care of your equipment
the lights all cost money the water
costs a lot of money but something you
might not be thinking about something
you may not have considered what is your
time worth what is your energy in that
grow worth if you're a single person
like myself i'm just a single dude i do
have a daughter she's 18. she wants to
hang out sometimes nowadays but
i'm a single dude so i can dedicate a
lot of time to my garden but if you've
got a family if you've got a lot of [ __ ]
going on people want your attention your
girlfriend's trying to go to the movie
your kids need attention your dog wants
to play the other part of life your
friends on the xbox live or playstation
live want to hang out and blow up
zombies and [ __ ] you got other [ __ ] to
do so your time is very valuable what is
it worth to you how much time are you
spending in there when it comes to
recouping the cost of your grow however
you're doing that
are you considering your time are you
getting paid for the hours that you're
spending in there and then think about
maybe you'll do [ __ ] more quickly if
you're thinking like oh i'm in here this
much a day because time is money no
matter what you're doing no matter where
you are unfortunately now time is money
you could be at work you could be doing
something else making some money doing
another task fulfilling a side job so
let's get this stuff done and think
about how many hours we're spending in
that grow all right now let's talk about
a couple of other things that i think
can definitely help us out if we use
strategy when purchasing what is your
pesticide regimen what is your
integrated pest management plan strategy
goal schedule are you going to buy
pesticides are you going to buy predator
bugs let's think about this before we
get too far into any grow because this
is going to be a cost quality pesticides
are not cheap but if you don't use
something bugs will get to your garden
and that is even more expensive
preventative measures are more
affordable and more effective than
trying to fix a problem because then
you're gonna have to go nuclear you're
gonna have to find specific [ __ ] based
on what stage you're in i think if you
plan ahead start having a pesticide
regimen early it is more cost effective
are you going to use spray pesticides
are you going to use bugs what is your
strategy let's think about it now
because if we plan for this ahead fit it
in the budget when we build the grow
that'll help us out then let's not use
too much pesticide i see a lot of people
when they mix it up they go mix up a
five or i work in a commercial grow so
it's a five gallon thing of [ __ ] or a
one gallon thing of pesticides most of
the time and then i see them dump some
of that let's remember and learn how
much we're gonna use per spray let's try
to anticipate it um you don't always
have to mix up the whole entire [ __ ]
sprayer worth you can just mix up enough
to cover the plants so this time maybe
just do a water spray put [ __ ] half a
gallon of water in your sprayer and see
if that covers the room and if it does
you only need a half a gallon of
pesticide if it doesn't maybe you need a
full gallon give it a dry or just a wet
run it's gonna say a dry run but you
know give it a wet run and see how much
you need to wet the room then go back
the next time and hit it with the
pesticide let's not waste the pesticide
then think about how much time you're
spending applying those pesticides i
always talk about it the cost versus
releasing the predators versus applying
the pesticide which is more cost
effective because you do need the
personal protective equipment you got a
suit up there's a reentry interval with
the pesticides sometimes the predators
are more cost effective but you do need
to have a crew to go put them out on the
plants so think of which one is going to
be more cost effective for you
then when it comes to applying the
pesticides when it comes to just about
anything in the grow get the appropriate
equipment if you get some cheap sprayers
some cheap [ __ ] it's gonna break after
the second or third maybe sometimes the
first use
they always say the most expensive
hammer is the cheap hammer because
you're gonna break it you gotta buy a
hammer every [ __ ] week every month
get a good hammer you only gotta buy it
once then they say uh pay once cry once
some [ __ ] like that i don't remember all
the funny [ __ ] that old people say but
uh buy quality [ __ ]
you're gonna have a better experience
with good equipment if your grow room
equipment is frustrating to use you
can't have a relia an enjoyable uh
relaxing time in that grow part of the
point of going in there is enjoying
yourself and having a good time and
relaxing i always say it's a work area
but it should feel good to be in there
and if it's frustrating if your gear
doesn't work if you're measuring
equipment your ph equipment doesn't work
it's going to frustrate you get good
[ __ ] so you can enjoy yourself and then
cheap [ __ ] breaks it is going to break
you're gonna have to buy it again
replacing a dehumidifier or repairing a
broken air conditioner in the middle of
a grow is a struggle the grove is
running the plants are relying on that
we can't turn off the lights and you've
already purchased the air conditioner
one time spent the time to install it
why didn't you get a good one then we
didn't have to replace that [ __ ] in the
middle of the grow and move the plants
around and struggle and get in there
with the ladder while the lights are
running it was so much easier if we
spent the money early on and didn't [ __ ]
around i think one of my last pieces of
advice on saving you money in the grow
room is to invest in industrial
equipment not cheap walmart [ __ ] not
cheap target [ __ ] skip the stores the
box stores and get industrial equipment
we are building a grow space an
agricultural workspace whether it's your
home grow especially your commercial
grow don't go get the cheap [ __ ] get
industrial stuff designed for
greenhouses for commercial horticultural
production or it will break if you try
to stick just a basic piece of gear that
was made for your bedroom or for your
office a dehumidifier for the office if
you try to put that in the grill it's
not going to keep up it's going to get
funky and gunky on the inside it's going
to get dirty it's not going to keep up
and it's going to die buy something
quality get the good [ __ ] we're building
we're building a workspace we're not
building an office we're not building
just a little it might sound like cutesy
little grow i think of it more as it's a
functioning industrial space so get
industrial [ __ ] that's gonna work and
gonna last
the good [ __ ] works so much better and
then people you're not gonna have as
many problems people always complain
when they buy the cheap [ __ ] they're
like well i spent the money and my
problems still exist it's because you
didn't spend enough and i know i'm
trying to tell you how to save money but
you'll save money by spending money up
front that may sound crazy but you'll
see how it works if you're one of those
people that keeps buying the cheap [ __ ]
buy the good one how many times you're
going to deal with fixing [ __ ] just buy
the expensive one the first time
if you can afford it buy the best you
can buy the first time
uh when it comes to buying air
conditioners uh for a commercial grow i
always say uh don't get one giant unit
get several smaller units that way when
that big one uh when one of them breaks
you've got a couple of backups you can
limp along and keep it growing i've been
in commercial grows where the giant air
conditioner broke and then it's been 110
in the whole grow got to turn off half
the lights and try to make that happen
if we had just three small acs something
would have kept us a little bit cool all
right i am rambling now
um i want to thank my buddy double door
big shout out to matt matt kind of
inspired this episode he's like hey bro
you should do an episode on how to save
a few bucks in the grow i think i gave
you a lot of ideas some of them for
smaller grows some of them of course for
bigger grows
if you have any feedback questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know that i would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy send
me that input um i like the constructive
criticism but don't be a dick all right
i think that is all i've got for you for
this episode if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining maybe you just like to send
me a tip because i helped you out in the
grow all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen of
course there's that link in the show
notes and in the video description don't
forget about the discord server of
course all the links for everything i
read genetics are on the website at
iregenetics.com
check out the website join the
newsletter join the discord server check
out the website have a good time you're
missing out all right that is all i've
got for you for this episode you know
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to send a giant
shout out to my buddy choke norris and
until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you