um
[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rosta
jeff and this is episode 685
of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
starting your own seed business before
we get to that part of the podcast let's
do a few shout outs to a few of the
great folks who continue to support the
show on patreon let's kick it off with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to the hardest
working man in cannabis my friend james
brown let's send a big fist bump to
danny potts let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to alabama man i
want to send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to my buddy maverick let's
send a thank you shout out to a news
supporter our friend terp yuper let's
send a thank you shout out to the larp
knight rises let's send a big fist bump
to a fellow podcaster caribou heart tv
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend crazy hand grows
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
dot www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need is right there on the screen
and you know there is a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it nice and easy for all of my friends
all right i don't want to waste too much
time let's jump right into this email i
got a great email from a person on
patreon let's see if they want their
name said yes they do want to be called
danny potts a big shout out to danny
potts let's jump right into their
message it goes like this it says rasta
jeff you bad [ __ ]
i like it when it starts like that it
says i love the show the girl from your
heart podcast and the dude grow show
keep me learning and entertained on my
two hour drive to and from work dude
that is a long drive are you driving two
hours each direction
big respect that's some dedication
that's a lot of hours in the car it does
go on it says i'm a new grower on my
second season i just ordered my first
batch of irie genetics congratulations
brother welcome to the club if you have
any questions about those genetics when
you're growing them i do expect more
emails i will answer all of those
questions it does say i wanted to get
some a rise to search for a mother plant
and a father plant to breed with however
a rise was unavailable so i picked up
morning dew that is a great uh cross to
pick up unfortunately the rise sells
well i guess fortunately for me
unfortunately for you the arise sells
out quite quickly that strain has been
very well advertised it has gotten very
popular uh that one is all over the
internet so it does sell out quite
quickly i cannot make enough of that
i've made f2s i'm working on the f3s
which i will release eventually but i
cannot keep the arise in stock so uh i'm
glad you understand that i'm glad you
went with the morning dude that is a
great backup plan a good decision it
goes on to say i'll be doing a phenol
hunt and the winner will be breeding
with jinx proof's nine pound hammer
that's going to be an amazing cross
i'm already running strain idea strain
name ideas through my head the first
thing that happened was like morning dew
nine pound hammer let's start naming
this [ __ ] for some reason that's the
first thing my brain wants to go to it's
gonna be an amazing cross uh jinx proof
is a great breeder great dude um
definitely i have some uh i stand behind
my morning dew so that's gonna be an
amazing cross i hope that goes well for
you i cannot wait to get a few of those
seeds to grow out and see what you did
wink wink anyway let's keep going with
the message it says
thank you for everything you do and for
the knowledge you drop on us bro thank
you you are very welcome i feel like uh
i would explode if i didn't share this
knowledge i feel like i was given this
gift of like gift of gab and the ability
to just retain and uh regurgitate
information i feel like this is my duty
and my job uh this is like my service
it's what i was put here to do if i
didn't do it something would go wrong
like cosmically karmically i may just
spontaneously combust or something so
this is what i'm supposed to be doing so
thank you bro i appreciate that
it says my goal is to practice breeding
to develop a medicine that works for my
wife's chronic pain and nausea which is
a result from an infection uh of um a
flesh-eating bacteria he did put the
the damn greek words for the
flesh-eating bacteria here but i'm not
even going to try to stumble through
those words uh it goes on to say oh also
big respect for stepping up to try to
create medicine for your wife that is
true love right there creating medicine
for one person that you love dearly to
treat them because you're watching them
suffer you want the quality of both of
your lives to be better big respect for
taking initiative and for having that
passion that that is often what inspires
a breeder something like this is what
inspires a cannabis grower a breeder an
advocate an activist
this is what gets people on our team so
thank you big respect it says uh third
and i hope your wife is okay also and if
i can do anything let me know
it says 13 surgeries later she lives a
somewhat normal life but the pain and
nausea keep her relying on opiates and
other scary pharmaceuticals
man that is 13 surgeries i couldn't
imagine that surgeries make me uh just
small stuff like i had a tooth pulled
and i had a [ __ ] panic attack all day
for that so surgeries and things are not
up my alley uh she your wife is a
soldier bro big respect to her she is
definitely in the irie army and
something weird
if i take pills i get nauseous i don't
like like uh even ibuprofen or vicodin
or something like that i can't take
pills they make me want to throw up so
it's amazing how our bodies are so
different that your wife is using these
things to combat the nausea and those
things make me throw up immediately
it's amazing how our bodies work
there is a point to this it says i would
like to find a strain that helps reduce
the amount of pharmaceutical
pharmaceuticals needed daily yes
that's such a beautiful thing i had the
honor and the privilege of uh being a
major part in the first dispensary here
in pueblo colorado i was uh one of the
fir i was like the first bud tender to
have a reputation to be i'm not i'm just
saying i was one of the first bud
tenders to develop a bud tender client
blood tender patient relationship with
my clientele here in this area i was
very blessed to be in an area that we
had medical marijuana we established a
dispensary i got to meet sick people i
got to see what it was like when
somebody would come in some of my
favorites of the little old ladies that
were brand new to cannabis the younger
kids they're experimenting they're going
to smoke weed and see what they like and
their hip and their they talk fast and
learn quick but the little old ladies
that would come in and they're like you
know since i tried smoking sometimes i
enjoy this and it's helping with some of
this i would ask them what are you
smoking for where is your like what is
your ailment is it your back is it your
neck is it your back and your neck is it
your knees it's your stomach and i would
give them samples of products to take
home smoke those products and come back
and tell me the results they had with
smoking that product and they'd be like
when i smoked the chocolate chunk i
slept really good and the maui wowie
made my head spin too much and the sour
diesel is too damn stinky like those
were the kind of reports we'd get from
them but developing that relationship
and learning what would help these
people it was the most rewarding
experience that is uh that drove me
deeper and deeper into growing into
wanting to dial in my medicine and
defining specific strains for people one
of the things i really noticed was
happening when i was working with these
older people is that they would tell me
they were able to eliminate some of the
medicines they were taking if they were
taking three medicines for pain and two
to help them sleep the right cannabis
would solve all five of those pills
problems then they don't have to take
the pill that's making them constipated
because of these three pills and then
they don't have to take the pill that's
messing up their vision because of this
one pill they don't have to take their
liver pill because all these other
things are [ __ ] up their liver and
their kidneys like they would just stop
taking so many pharmaceuticals and it
was amazing to see cannabis able to fill
that role just fix their bodies in such
a magical way anyway i'm rambling but
yes it is a beautiful goal to try to
minimize the amount of pharmaceuticals
that anybody is putting in their body so
great goal great passion let me stay on
focus here
i am quite stoned and quite rambly big
shout out to the friends that allegedly
possibly traded me seeds for
concentrates good job bro i know you
don't want to talk about on the show but
you just got a shout out kinda on the
down low it goes on in this message it
says i also enjoy growing and breeding
so much that i would like to pursue the
idea of opening my own seed company that
is quite the endeavor that'll be quite
the task i hope you were in it but we'll
talk about that more in just a moment it
says uh keeping good genetics around and
helping others that need this medicine
is where my head is except i have no
idea how to continue breeding wise then
it says i'm learning and i will get
better and the business side and
marketing scare me how might one go
about setting up a seed company legally
in a medical state all right here's
where the main part of the question
comes in how might one go about setting
up a seed company in a legal state that
may have recreational past in the near
future sorry for the long message keep
up the great work from danny potts so
our friend wants to start a seed company
in a medical state that possibly will go
recreational in the very near future um
our friend straight up said that they
are intimidated or afraid of the
marketing and business side that is not
their forte honestly that was not my
specialty either when i started a seed
company so that is something i had to
learn so my advice if you're really
going to do it uh maybe take a small
business school maybe get some business
advisors uh do that stuff early because
i made
so many mistakes as a small business as
a person starting a business but
i did not know i was starting a seed
company when i started this
i know you asked how this started and
for some advice the best way i could do
that is kind of start off by telling you
how i fell into this let me just kind of
segue into how i fell into owning a seed
company then we'll talk about developing
your seed company and some of the things
that came with me starting mine that's
just the best way to make this episode
happen so one two three here we go i
started making seeds because i was
dissatisfied with what i was purchasing
online i was paying a lot of money for
seeds uh they would come and half of
them would be crushed because the
packaging was terrible sometimes customs
would [ __ ] take my seats they
wouldn't even make it to my to my door
um a lot of times i would grow them and
they would be intersex or they wouldn't
even be what they were labeled i would
order these seeds that said they were
going to smell like gasoline and be
covered in trichomes and they would
smell like [ __ ]
roses and have no trichomes and i was
like that's not really cool of you so i
started breeding i found a few things
that i did like things that did kind of
have some quality to it and then i just
i wanted to make more seeds and see what
i could do and i started breeding for
myself i made seeds i found seeds that i
liked i found plants that i liked i bred
them together i just kept playing around
i was just kind of making seeds for
myself then i made a lot of seeds then i
started posting pictures to social media
a friend introduced me to instagram
they're like bro you should put some of
the pictures of that killer wheat on
instagram you'd get a good following and
i was like i'm not really into that sort
of [ __ ] they're like you're missing out
if you don't do it so i thought i better
post some pictures
started posting pictures of my plants
and my dried buds and flowers to social
media and people started saying bro your
plants are amazing where can we get
seeds and i was like i don't really sell
seeds i don't really sell seeds
and people were like well you need to
sell us seeds i didn't make that many
seeds i was just making enough for me to
play with i would give them and
allegedly possibly um well let's just
said give them to my friends all over
the nation and all over the places
people would have my seeds and they were
growing them and they were having great
results
and so they were asking for more seeds
and so i made
the seeds that i had made for myself i
just went back and made larger batches
and started giving them out to my
friends then i put them in a bunch of
bags and i labeled them with my email
address and just what the cross was and
a couple of hints of what i thought they
would grow like and i went to the very
first high times cannabis cup in denver
colorado the first one they held in
denver i went there and i passed out
probably 500 free packs of seeds just
thinking i was going to give them out to
people because i had a lot of seeds and
nothing to do with them i was just
giving them out i thought it was kind of
fun it was just just a gift to the world
i made a lot of seeds i got what i need
out of it
i have a lot i'm not going to grow them
here are some seeds for the people
shortly thereafter my inbox started
blowing up my friends that i'd been
giving seeds to were posting pictures of
their progress people were impressed by
that so now third party third layer
people i guess were seeing the seeds
that i had made and they said bro where
did you get those and my friend said
this guy ross to jeff and i wasn't even
ross to jeff i was just jeff on the
[ __ ]
jeff there's just [ __ ] jeff on the
internet growing weed
so like my friend ross to jeff made
these seeds and then [ __ ] um they all
those people contacted me then all those
people that i gave seeds to with that
cannabis cup they started growing and
they started having good results
they started contacting me asking for
more seeds then the same thing happened
with their social media people they
started posting [ __ ] then social media
really made it blow up i was posting
quality photos my friends were growing
quality products posting quality photos
giving out probably 500
they were somewhere between five and ten
packs was like five and ten seven packs
of seeds maybe twelve packs of seeds
randomly in a package i'd walk around
the cannabis cup and if i saw somebody
holding like anything that hinted to me
they were going to go home and grow weed
especially if they had clones or grow
nutrients or a grow light i just hand
them a package of seeds now you've got
everything you need go home and grow
some weed
passing out all those seeds really did
very well for me to establish a name in
the industry so i guess i kind of
accidentally started my seed company i
started it out of pure passion this was
the seeds were made this is why i
believe it is successful a big part of
why i believe it is successful it was an
art that i made for myself it wasn't
something i was doing to make money it
wasn't a product i was trying to pay the
bills with it was something that i was
frustrated with what i was buying i
wanted to make a quality product for
myself that was tailor-made for myself
my favorite thing about growing from
seed is i can find the phenotype that if
i'm growing in a commercial grow we'll
find the phenotype for the commercial
grow if i'm going to grow in a grow tent
we'll find the phenotype for the grow
tent that's in a seed pack you can find
variation and find what you'd like so i
started breeding with those uh to find
what i loved and started making stuff
that i thought was great for me that
worked for my grow environment and my
situation
luckily fortunately my situation my
environment was also a large part of
regular the cannabis uh medical
marijuana the regular grower it was
their environment their situation as
well they had a small home grow they
needed plants that would finish in a
certain amount of time they were highly
potent they gave them huge yields that
had a variety of flavors available on
the menu that's what they were looking
for just like me so it just so happened
that i was making a product that fit the
market very well there was a need and a
demand for my product so i kind of fell
into it it was right time right place
lots of passion i feel like if i would
have thought hey man i need to pay the
rent what are we gonna do let's invent a
seed company it would have failed i
would have done it wrong i did this
organically i just i just did it and it
happened so um a lot of my experience my
information here is going to be from
experience most of my knowledge is from
experience i honestly wish i would have
had more business knowledge but since
you're starting from scratch i can say
get yourself a business advisor
accountant and lawyer from the beginning
to get all of your paperwork in line so
that's how i got started let me make
sure i covered all of my how i got
started notes here
i was going to events and giving out
lots of seeds
every event that was possible to go to
cannabis cups we used to have the
cannabis cups here we'd have the secret
cup we had the 710 cup we would have uh
the secret sash
we would have there were so many events
it was when cannabis first got medically
legal and then recreationally legal here
we were doing events once a month at
least and i would go pass out seeds and
then eventually it came to trading seeds
and then eventually it became to vending
seeds
i used to be what i would call the
backpack backpack warrior i would fill
my backpack up with a bunch of seeds and
just go to the events and sling seeds
out of my backpack and then one time i
got kicked out of the cannabis cup
because they're like dude you can't do
that pay for a booth and i realized
that's absolutely correct i should be a
damn grown-up and pay for a booth right
after that a very well-known seed uh
vendor invited me to be a part of their
booth at an event i realized that i
could really do well at those events i
didn't need um anybody to hold my hand
and help me out that i could just get my
own booth and then the next event i
rented my own booth and things went
crazy from there i got
all the things it takes to build a trade
show booth we got the banner in the back
we got the tablecloth all the stuff to
make a booth look professional and from
there it was basically game on built a
website did all that [ __ ]
but uh going to all those events and
passing [ __ ] out and meeting the people
and then continuing to go to the events
and put my face out in the community and
shaking their hands and being there that
helps a lot with the brand and that's a
lot of how it got going just being there
uh being part of the crew just showing
up smoking with everybody and having
seeds and being the guy that's kind of
how it all happened so i do have a bunch
of notes here that we could get into
i wanted to get the organic part out of
the way so i have a couple of questions
you've got a couple of options you want
to start a seed business do you want to
start do you want to sell your seeds in
the retail shops only or do you want to
sell them online i don't think
that doing both is a really good idea
and an option i know there's one company
that does sell their seeds in their
retail store and you can buy them online
there are a lot of legal uh loopholes
and things around that but you should
probably pick one do you want to sell
them in your stores or do you want to
sell them online that's the first thing
to think about if you sell them in the
store you have a lot of licensing to go
around a lot of overhead to cover a lot
of legalities to think about
there is a a lot of advantages you've
got a storefront people will just go
there and buy your seeds that is very
easy but they've got to be regulated
seeds there's a lot of rules around that
um then also people have to go there to
buy your seeds if you sell your seeds
online they can be sold people could be
buying my seeds right now from vendors
while i'm here recording while i'm
editing this show i may be making a sale
i don't even know about it because the
seeds are online they're being sold all
over the place and the vendors are
handling that for me i don't have to
touch them anymore
all that stuff is done the seeds are
being sold that way online
so you can set up a website or you can
set up your own seed brand and then just
send the seeds to vendors and let them
go that way how do you want to do it do
you want the brick and mortar storefront
or do you want the online presence it
sounds kind of like you want to do the
store which is going to be a lot more
work a lot of legalities it kind of
sounds like i keep saying this but now
is the time to get some business
education either get yourself a small
business degree
learn a little bit about small business
or team up with a small business advisor
also you're going to need a lawyer
anytime you're involved in the cannabis
business anything selling anything have
a lawyer have somebody you can call for
quick questions big questions uh
somebody that can help you out a lot of
[ __ ] is going to come up make sure that
all of your paperwork gets filed legally
if you're going to start an llc
uh non-profit organization whatever you
decide to do however you decide to do it
whichever works best for you so your
business advisor and whoever helps you
fill this stuff out will have all that
advice for you um there are things
online that can help you nobody uh
nobody advertises with me for that but
there are websites that can help you do
that but make sure that you get a lawyer
and an accountant and a small business
advisor or something like that to help
you out so you can start off properly i
said it earlier i wish that i had had
some help when i got started i didn't do
everything correctly i took a couple of
years to kind of fix some things that i
didn't do right at the start not a big
deal it's just business [ __ ] that had to
be resolved but uh paperwork and
headaches could have been resolved had i
done it correctly the first time so
if you've already got a commercial grow
or anything you already know all this
stuff i'm not sure if you've got a
dispensary you know you want to start
anyway make sure you get advice a lawyer
and an accountant those things all help
you out and then make sure that they're
not friends uh you don't want your
lawyer and your accountant to be buddies
um and then if the business advisor you
don't want them teaming up against you
make sure that your money is being
watched by everybody make sure they're
all after each other because when they
team up on you that's when [ __ ] can go
wrong so lawyer up get yourself an
account and get that business advisor
then you're going to have to build a
reputation that's one of the hardest
parts about creating a seed company sure
you made a bunch of seeds now what what
are you going to do with them why does
anybody want those seeds what comes out
of those seeds have you built a
reputation you're going to have to give
away seeds people are going to have to
grow them they're going to have to see
what comes from them you're going to
have to grow them that's the first step
make seeds grow them find something you
know is worth putting to market then put
it to market have it tested all over the
place we'll talk about testers in a
little bit have it tested in so many
different environment situations
then if you feel like it's ready to go
to market put it out there but
you're gonna have to build a reputation
why does anybody want to buy your seeds
what do you offer what do you bring to
the table that's not already there of
course if you've got that storefront
people are coming in to buy product
already maybe seeds are an upsell maybe
they just happen to be looking for seeds
maybe you're the only shop on the block
with seeds that always helps but what is
going to drive people to your brand how
do you build a reputation how do you
build the demand and then once you've
built a reputation and built a demand
how do you continue those people to keep
coming back for your seeds how do you
how do you create sustainability you've
always got to be creating new stuff
which means you've always got to have
stuff out testing as a breeder the stuff
that you see being released now i've got
stuff that will come out this fall i'm
not sure if it'll be
late this year early next year but there
are stuff coming out what i'm calling oh
it'll be the winter stuff coming out the
winter the winter release was actually
made last winter so those seeds are
finally being released it took about a
year to get them uh processed i grew
them i made sure they're good i sent
them out to testers the testers are
growing them then i sent out a round of
like secondary testers to people like
hey i think these are really killer you
should try these like to my bros who are
good photographers and [ __ ] like that
they got them next now pretty soon
they're going to make it to market it
takes a year so you've always got to be
producing new crosses
you've got to be testing them and
getting them out and you've got to have
a reliable product it only takes one bad
batch of seeds to ruin a breeder's
reputation i've seen it happen to you
guys if you pay attention to the seed
game you've seen people that were around
for a long time put out one or two bad
batches of seeds then they disappeared
their reputation is shot they're at the
events they used to have a line around
the block for their booth now there's
just a few people coming up because they
ruin their reputation by putting out a
few bad one or two bad batches of seeds
so you've got to build a reputation
you've got to become relevant why do
people want your seeds why how do people
know who you are then once they've got
one pack why are they going to come back
for another pack of seeds you've got to
build longevity and sustainability as a
seed company there's a lot of work to
doing that now let's talk about um
oh another factor it's over saturated
there are a million seed companies out
there if you go to the larger vendors on
the internet and you click on like let's
just say seeds here now.com look at the
the vast amount of vendors of retailers
of seed breeders that are on that
website it is overwhelming there are a
lot of people on there it's over
saturated so how are you going to stand
out from an oversaturated market i'm not
trying to discourage you i'm asking you
the real questions that come up in a
business meeting why does anybody want
to buy your seeds
why do you stand out from the plethora
of other breeders why not to sound
egotistical why does somebody want to
buy your seeds over my seeds i've been
around for my brand has been around for
a while my podcast has existed for six
years the seeds were around for much
longer than that i've got a six year at
least six year podcast head start on you
where people know about my brand have
been seeing my stuff why do they wanna
buy yours i'm not belittling or
criticizing them asking a real business
question what are you gonna do to
convince them to buy your seeds when
mine are right there on the shelf next
to them um that's just a real question
in business so uh now let's work into
part of the the part of the things that
are required from a seed breeder if you
want to own a seed company
it will be a full-time commitment this
will be a a job a business if you've
already got a backup plan you're not in
it to win it there is no way out there's
no other idea if you're gonna start a
seed company that is what you're going
to be doing it is a full-time job it is
a full commitment it is a nine days a
week [ __ ] 32 hour a day job uh
sometimes when i'm recording podcasts
i'm just trying to get them done before
the sun comes up in this window behind
me you have no idea how many hours a
seed breeder small business owner puts
in every week i'm not complaining by any
means i love it i'm my own boss
i work when i want how i want if i want
to take a dab break we take a dab break
that's just how it goes but we get a lot
of [ __ ] done it's how it is owning your
own business
let's talk about just kind of a basic
day of a small business owner you get up
you do your normal morning routine i
don't know what you do get some food in
you probably poop get some coffee i
don't drink coffee but whatever gets
started right then there is garden work
to do the first thing that i do is take
care of the garden the plants need
attention if it's the home grow if it's
a commercial grow always knock out the
plant work first thing
if i gotta go to a commercial grow
sometimes i hit two commercial grows in
a day go make sure that all the plants
are good teach the staff what to do then
get back to my personal grow take care
of the personal grow the plants are done
sometimes there's not much to do to the
plants sometimes there are hours and
hours of work to do to the plants maybe
you have to do transplanting maybe you
have to cut clones you have to keep the
plants alive you have to breed them you
have to do all the plant work you have
to harvest them you have to get the
seeds out of them
that's a lot of work to be done with the
plants then
then after that try to take a little bit
of a break take a shower get cleaned up
get all the the work off of me then we
do emails there are a lot of emails to
be handled there are business emails
there are customer service emails
businesses with vendors i have so many
emails i honestly cannot keep up and
it's giving me anxiety just freaking
thinking about it right now so that is a
full-time job within its own just just
answering emails then on top of that
there is social media if you try to stay
relevant on social media that could take
up a good portion of your day i try to
stay away from that because i can really
get sucked in i'm sure you notice when i
do get sucked in there's four or five
pictures for like 30 minutes just
scrolling and posting then i realize
i've just spent 30 or 40 minutes here on
social media i got to get back to work
so social media is like a part-time job
in its own and we haven't even gotten
halfway through the day yet then um
you have to have i mentioned these
people earlier the accountant the lawyer
the tax guy the paralegal and whoever
else you've got on your team that you've
got to check in with probably once a
week once every two weeks at least once
a month you got to check in with the
lawyer got to check in with the
accountant at least once a month and see
what's going on there
check in with touch all the bases make
sure everybody's still on your team make
sure the taxes have been paid make sure
that everything is current make sure all
the licenses are up to date do all that
good stuff
we're only up to lunch time right now
we're still making phone calls the
plants have already been watered we
haven't even got to uh checking in with
the web guy there are website updates to
be made uh then there's the art guy i'm
having new merchandise made and new seed
packages designed so i've got to check
in with the art guy big shout out to the
art guy i hope you're well bro also fist
bump to the web guy uh then there's the
merch team i've gotta check in with
customstickermakers.com and see if the
stickers are being printed gotta check
on the t-shirts also gotta check on the
mood mats where are they they said they
were shipping those around the 15th here
we are like the 27th and those
definitely have not shipped i haven't
even gotten pictures of the proofs yet
gotta email them again and see where
those things are so there's just a bunch
of things that you have to take care of
then um
testers testers are a big part of being
a successful seed company you've got to
develop a relationship with your testers
if i make a new cross
i know the parents of that cross i know
the grandparents of that cross and
possibly the great grandparents on both
sides i should be able to grow that
plant like a champion uh i'm a a
professional grower with a lot of
experience and i know all of the details
of that plant i've got the [ __ ] cheat
code for those seeds i better be able to
grow it like a pro what i do is send
those seeds out to my test crew big
shout out to the test team you guys know
who you are they're the people who run
the seeds in their specific grow
environments and show me what i really
made
they're the people that are gonna see
what it grows like under this kind of
light with this humidity with this type
of nutrient in a tent in a basement in a
warehouse they're gonna see that sort of
stuff for me you've got to develop a
relationship with your test crew which
again puts you back sitting at the desk
answering emails doing facetime calls
checking the social media checking in
with all of the testers the testers are
a big part of the team without the
testers i would not have success uh i
would be years behind without the
testers i couldn't do all the testing
that they do for me um
probably a thousand seeds went out to be
tested in the past week so the testers
are a big part of the team um if you're
interested in testing people are gonna
start emailing me now there is a podcast
all about testing the grow from your
heart podcast uh tester episode is
available watch that before you send me
a message asking about testing please
check that one out all the details are
there then join the discord there's a
tester tab we'd love to see you there
check us out come hang out but watch the
video first
so we're only like halfway through the
day um and we've only gotten to the
testers then i do have a life i've got a
daughter i've got friends um i've got
people i want to hang out with and talk
to and also sometimes i want to eat
dinner and take a break so uh being a
seed breeder and owning a seed company
what i'm getting at is a full-time job
it's a full commitment so unless you are
in it to win it and fully dedicated i
really wouldn't suggest getting into
that unless you can commit to it
another thing we should talk about is
building a fan base we've talked about
this earlier a little bit uh becoming uh
relevant why do people want to buy your
seeds then once you've got them how do
you retain them if you can develop a
solid fan base of just a solid number i
have approximately 200 patreon
supporters and there's about 500 to a
thousand people that really support me
very strongly there's like a a close
group of 250 people of anything i put
out if it's a grinder a t-shirt a pack
of seeds they'll grab it right away then
there's like a group of about 500 people
the fringe that buy a lot of stuff then
there's like a thousand people that buy
enough and if you can just build
a nice little following like that that
will help sustain you don't work don't
worry about going major too fast slowly
build and have a loyal following try to
try to make some friends that that are
in your fan base and you're i hate even
calling them fan base or following but
you guys know what i mean it's the
people that follow you on social media
that interact with you the most online
start learning some of those people
start building relationships that's why
i go hang out in the discord i've got
friends on the discord you guys are my
friends uh they know [ __ ] about my
personal life that you guys that watch
the podcast don't care about or have no
idea about but we know what's going on
in each other's lives i get pictures of
my friends at other friends houses
trimming iregenetic strains and that is
super cool big shout out to lollipop
farms
but build a relationship with those
people the testers and the loyal fan
base
they keep me afloat they keep life going
they keep the wheels turning so you've
got to be grateful and loyal to them
you've got to show love back to them
it's like a band
that peep those people down in the front
that are in the mosh pit for every
[ __ ] show you gotta throw them some
t-shirts every once in a while and help
them out because they're the people that
make you successful without them you
would not exist without my fan base
without the people watching this
without the people watching the podcast
i would just be some psychopath with two
cameras a microphone and way too many
[ __ ] toys this would be weird without
the people buying the seeds i would not
be successful i would not eat dinner i'd
be skinnier i wouldn't have a nice shirt
i look like [ __ ] life wouldn't be what
it is so you've got to show love to the
people that show you love when you
become a successful business owner don't
forget where you came from don't forget
the people
that make you who you are so remember
that the day you get started with this
idea of making a seed company you are
already working on your reputation as
that seed company the people that
already know you are putting your
character and your reputation into your
seed company so start strong start off
correctly don't cut corners
make quality products uh be fair with
your customers have quality customer
service did i mention that i spend about
uh at least an hour or two every day
answering customer service emails a lot
of people are gonna say no he doesn't
because he doesn't reply to me i've got
about 30 000 emails that i try to answer
and it's overwhelming because every time
you answer them they reply and you have
more emails i love you guys and i'm not
mad about it but i'm a one person
operation i do the podcast the seed
company i've got a daughter i've got
friends like i got [ __ ] going on trying
to keep up with it all
thank you for keeping me overloaded
anyway the main part of this question
was um how might one go about setting up
a seed company legally and a medical
state uh that is a great question the
first advice lawyer up get that account
get that business advisor make sure they
are on your team guiding you so that you
don't make any legal mistakes and get
yourself in trouble then breed high
quality highly tested products that's
what your goal is breed the product that
you are proud to put out to your
consumer if you're not proud to put it
out if you wouldn't be happy buying it
don't put it out to your consumer build
a loyal fan base connect with them and
then stay relevant then think about the
future i don't know the future of seed
breeding in the future of seed
purchasing in the future of cannabis try
to project that and try to stay on top
of it
something that i've done i try not to
[ __ ] with the hype there are enough
people out there doing the hype [ __ ] i
try to dodge that and do my own thing
again that is why i think it works
because i'm not doing what everybody
else is doing what everybody else wants
i'm doing what is working for me what i
love and then my art is showing that i'm
putting passion into it and that makes
it desirable and successful so bottom
line bro grow from your heart and breed
with love do what you love stay out of
trouble i hope i gave you a lot of good
advice because i got super rambly i feel
like this is a topic i could really
ramble about uh get that lawyer get that
account get the business advisor then
breed breed breed test test test then
package them up put them on the shelf
and get them out there to the people bro
always be available for a customer
service questions always be available
for events uh if people want to put you
on shows and interview you be available
for those types of things that camera
just cut out my voice is burning out it
is obviously time to wrap up this
podcast ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters and paul and chuckers
thank you once again for listening to me
ramble on another episode of this
podcast
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy send me that feedback send me those
questions big shout out to my buddy
danny potts for this great question i
hope i helped you out bro um for
anything else check out the website ire
iriegenetics.com everything you need is
right there
iriegenetics.com that's all i've got for
you for this episode i'll be back in a
few days with fresh new content i want
to give a big shout out to all of my
friends at the neighborhood grows
podcast and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]