[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
687 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
germinating seeds but before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend smokey j let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy adhd grower let's send a big fist
bump and a thank you shout out to a long
time friend and a long time supporter my
buddy og purple thumb let's send a big
thank you shout out to dr dendro let's
send a big fist bump to another long
time supporter my buddy mister let's
send a fist bump in a thank you shout
out to froggle rock i want to send a
thank you shout out to my buddy zackson
starker let's send a big fist bump to
jake let's send a shout out to grant m
let's send a thank you shout out to mike
v hill then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy yee
[ __ ] ha
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it nice and easy for all of my friends
all right i don't want to waste too much
time i don't want to make this a super
long episode let's jump right into the
germinating seeds portion of this
podcast a lot of people are buying seeds
a lot of people are trying to get them
started as a seed maker a seed seller i
feel like it could be partly my
responsibility to make sure you have
good luck with these seeds so let's do a
quick seed germinating episode i'm
getting all the supplies i need gathered
here in front of me we're going to start
with a big jar of blue raspberry truffle
seeds these were grown this summer in a
greenhouse these will be a great example
to get us going here on the show
let's talk about the things we need for
a successful germination number one
ingredient for a successful seed
germination is quality seeds we want big
fat healthy seeds any seed that comes
from my brand let me show you something
i do i've never done this on a show i've
never shown anybody this these are the
actual seeds that you will get if you
purchase irish seeds i'm just going to
dump a couple into the lid this is how i
would package your seeds i would as i'm
packaging each one would get set on the
table and pressed under my finger you
can see i'm pressing it is not breaking
it is not i'm putting a lot of pressure
on it's not squishing or popping this is
a high quality seed i pressed so hard it
is stuck to my finger i pressed so hard
i've got a nice indention in my finger
this finger is calloused this is a
soldier finger for testing seeds these
are high quality seeds in my opinion
these will germinate these are very
viable seeds so what i'm going to do i'm
going to take a few of these seeds i
just dropped them right here into the
lid i'm going to make sure they're clean
i don't need any seed holes or any of
that stuff in here we don't need that to
contaminate our mess you won't get that
part you won't have seed holes and extra
junk this is just a jar of uncleaned
seeds kind of unrefined uh unsorted
seeds so these are just seeds i'm
pouring them out making a few selections
we've got enough gonna put these away
try to keep myself on track here but
we've got some seeds that's the main
ingredient here for successful
germination this is honestly how i
germinate seeds that i'm going to run in
my garden this is how i do test seeds
this is how i do dispensary grow seeds
any seeds i'm going to grow this is how
i do it i get this really technical
piece of equipment here this is a paper
towel this is from the dollar store
super affordable everybody should have
this maybe you should have a rag instead
of paper towels but today we're going to
use a paper towel um a lot of times i
won't even use the whole sheet luckily
we got the brand that gives you half
sheets we're going to take a half sheet
be more economical here i'm going to
fold it in half this is really critical
fold it in half and then half again i'm
just kidding this is not very critical
at all as being a smart ass i hope you
caught on to that i'm going to fold it
to this size
then i'm going to move these seeds out
of the way so i don't need them wet just
yet dump those on the table i'm going to
fold it to this size
then i'm going to get
this really
expensive fancy technical substance here
called bottled water so far everybody
should be able to follow along we should
all have these products readily
available then i'm just going to soak
this paper towel i'm just pouring
bottled water over the paper towel until
it is saturated it is soaked it's not
going to take much more water i'm going
to kind of let it sit right there then
i've got a little bowl over here nothing
fancy just a cereal bowl maybe a small
cereal bowl i'm going to pour this
excess water
into the bowl
now i've got a saturated paper towel
sitting on a plate so far we haven't
gotten really technical we haven't
gotten really crazy i hope everybody can
follow along then here's the fun part i
better close up this water with all this
electronic [ __ ] around here uh put the
stuff away here comes the fun part grab
the seeds put them on one side of your
paper towel that is wet pick one side
put them on there just drop them right
in there
and then
really easily real gently i'm going to
take the other side i'm just going to
fold it up so now i've just got a paper
towel folded like this it's really wet
you can see some water coming out that's
too much water i'm going to let that
water drip out but when it quits
dripping right about there
we're basically done we're going to take
this and i'm going to stick this
inside of a baggie
the reason i'm putting it in the baggie
is i want to retain this moisture i'm
going to go i've got places to go today
i can't get this baggy open there we go
i've got places to go today i've got
things to do i know that by placing this
inside of this baggie i've now trapped
this moisture in here we've just created
a little humidity zone the seeds are in
there getting really wet there's
humidity trapped in there i'm gonna set
this in a warm place i've got a grow
light that is on i've got a t5 light
right on top of that grow light will be
perfect it's warm it'll get this seed
going and it will start germinating that
wasn't super technical honestly that is
how i germinate all of my seeds and
we'll take this plate here we're just
going to pour this excess water right
into this bowl that we've got
and then what i will do
usually this would go sit on the grow
light but right now we're just gonna
leave it right here on the table
so now while i'm recording this will
just chill right here it is totally fine
that is going to germinate it will take
probably somewhere around 24 to 48 hours
before you start seeing little tails
that is our goal here we want these
seeds to pop open i won't touch this or
open this for probably 24 to 48 hours
this will go somewhere like i said i'm
going to put it on top of a t5 grow
light i don't want to roast these i
don't want to cook them i don't want to
barbecue them i don't want to ruin them
with too much heat it is cold it's cold
here today you notice i got a long
sleeve shirt on it's been pretty cold in
colorado they would be okay here in this
ambient environment if they're okay
they're okay in the environment in which
you are in but i think in my veg area
right on top of that t5 light they'll
just be a little bit cozier it's just a
little bit warmer i don't generally put
them on a heating mat i'm only doing
that because it is winter time we are
shifting from the cold or from the warm
to the cold season and i don't want to
risk these seeds i don't want you to
risk your seeds so this is the type of
climate when i would use some heating
just that grow light is all i'm going to
use and that will be enough i've got
some notes i want to make sure i got
we're going to fold the paper towel wet
the paper towel put the seeds in there
fold it up put it in the baggie and
we're going to let it sit for 24 to 48
hours then we're going to check on it
through the magic of technology i
planned ahead i germinated some seeds
yesterday i haven't opened this this has
been sealed up for 24 hours we're going
to pop it open now together and we're
going to see what happened
these have been sitting on top of a t5
light
just chilling we're going to pop them
open together and we will see what we're
expecting
and i will take a picture with my phone
and insert this into the video just so
you get a better glimpse oh i am
impressed i don't know if this is coming
up on camera but we have got some
sprouts here i would be very gentle if i
were you uh these are this is a
germination test on a new line for me so
these aren't hypercritical for me they
don't have to go anywhere but this is
what you will see in 24 to 48 hours i
got little they look like spermies it's
a seed with the tail on it i'm trying to
put it somewhere i can't see what shows
up on the camera it's kind of far away
put it right here in front of the mic
maybe you can see the little tail that's
popping up but it's got little tails
coming out of it at this point these
seeds are ready to go into
cocoa dirt hydroponics however you're
gonna grow them now is the time so at
this point i'm gonna snap a quick photo
and try to keep talking at this point i
would get my container whatever i'm
gonna put them in in my experience in my
situation i would take a beer cup a red
solo cup filled with um a
fluffy soil i'm not going to say any
brand names or anything like that but a
soilless mix or cocoa with a lot of
perlite in it so it's nice and fluffy i
would fill my container
i would pack it not tight but semi tight
i'd press it down so that it's in there
so that the seed has something to dig
through i want the seed to dig a little
bit but also don't want it to struggle
so i've got it semi-packed i would water
my medium at this point before i put the
seed in there i would water that
container so i've got my soilless mix in
my cup make sure your container has
drainage holes if you're using cups you
have to put your own holes in it you
don't want to fill the cup up with water
and create a mud situation in there so
poke some holes in a cup uh fill it with
your medium of choice
then water it at this point ph adjusts
the water to somewhere between five
eight and six four you will be just fine
water it i don't add any nutrients i may
add some microbes at this time usually
don't add any nutrients most of the soil
that i buy has already got microbes in
it so i don't need to add a lot so i've
got my container with holes in it it's
got soil or soilless mix or cocoa with
perlite in there now i've watered it uh
at this point i would put my finger into
that mix about to the first knuckle one
knuckle deep is as deep as i would go
right in the center just make a knuckle
deep indention then i would put a seed
right in there let me snap a picture of
these seeds and then i will show you how
i would put them in there you'll see
this picture right here will end up in
the video
boom those are little tails we got
at this point i would take a seed and i
would gently set it right into oh
they're kind of stuck to the paper towel
be careful pulling them off the paper
towel
don't break them there we go all right
this one's got a really long tail i hope
you can see how long the tail is on this
seed i'm getting in front of the black
microphone hopefully that helps you it's
got a really long tail on it this is the
direction in which it wants to be
planted the tail goes down the seed goes
up you want your roots to grow down into
the dirt you want your seed to grow up
and pop out of the dirt this is a
beautiful this is impressive this is a
very beautiful specimen of a seed i'm
really glad that we decided to germinate
these i'm trying to zoom in for you and
do some camera cuts and i'm thinking
ahead but look at the health and beauty
of this seed this is a very beautiful
seed i'm very lucky that we germinated
these very glad that i got to show you
these these are vigorous seeds normally
it wouldn't stand up like that the root
shouldn't hold it up but this root is
acting like a stem already it's so
strong and super vigorous so you'd want
to plant it with the root going down and
the seed pointing up and don't plant it
so deep that it has to struggle like i
said knuckle deep my fingers are kind of
big i'm still going knuckle deep i maybe
maybe a short finger maybe only halfway
to a knuckle but just go knuckle deep
set that seed right in there it's where
it's pointing up and then just scoop the
dirt right back over it don't bury it
just kind of lightly backfill it and
then that seed the tap root will dig
down the top will start popping up and
now you have successfully germinated and
planted your seeds let me make sure
there are more notes that i want to keep
up on
um now you need to keep your seeds in a
good your seedlings in a good
environment the t5 light that these have
been sitting on top of now they're going
to go right underneath there once they
get a little bit bigger i will move them
to the led lights my small veg space is
a t5 right now that's just the way that
things are going so they would go under
a t5 light i would keep them on a
minimum of 18 hours of daylight of
lights on schedule maybe more maybe 20
maybe 24 for a few days so at this point
i would just keep them under a strong
vegetative light cycle they don't need a
lot of light right now uh if you see
them stretching they're not getting
enough light but if you're giving them
proper light they'll stay short and
squatty they don't need intense light
they just need the right light a t5 or
an led will be perfect so i put them
under a light
with somewhere uh more than 18 hours of
light sometimes my veg spaces get 20
hours of light and four hours of
darkness sometimes i do 19.5 sometimes
18 6. somewhere in that area will be
good for your plants keep them in veg
they won't flower until you put them on
12 12. so let's get them under a solid
vegetative schedule if they're
stretching they want more light if
they're staying short they're getting
enough light if they look like they're
kind of roasting on you they're getting
too much light that's something you'll
have to learn to adjust it's going to be
plant specific light specific
environment specific that'll be a trick
to learn that's one of the details
you'll have to learn in your grow
environment i would keep them around 75
to 85 degrees that is optimal for the
seedlings maybe a little bit higher
maybe better the colder will slow them
down higher we'll get them growing a
little more quickly higher humidity is
better i understand that sometimes it's
hard to get high humidity especially
right now we're in winter in colorado uh
it's dry here so the higher humidity the
better uh 75 85 degrees temperature is
good i do not use domes for my seedlings
i see a lot of people put their
seedlings in a dome or put some sort of
cover on it i do not do that
in my opinion that makes for weak
seedlings i want these seedlings to come
out and be ready domes are for clones
when you cut a clone the clone doesn't
have a root source a root zone a life
source to keep it going it's got the
clones have to survive from the humidity
in the environment if there's no
moisture in the air they don't have any
way to sustain themselves they don't
have roots to drink so they need a dome
we have to control that humidity in the
clones the seedlings don't need that
dome i think they want exposure to the
environment exposure to the wind that
makes them tougher then we don't have to
harden them off like we do clones i
think that the dome kind of turns your
seedlings into it makes them weak makes
them little [ __ ] doesn't give them
the vigor that they need from the very
beginning i want these seeds going
strong from day one so i do not use a
dome for my seedlings most of the time i
do not use a heating mat i do keep
saying i'm going to put these seedlings
on top of the t5 it is really cold at
this time of year in colorado i may use
that t5 light just to get them
germinated past that there's not going
to be any heat mat nothing underneath
them i've seen more people cook and
roast seeds i have honestly roasted and
boiled more seeds than i've germinated
when using a heat mat i keep checking my
notes to make sure i'm getting it going
um sometimes the seed shell will get
stuck to your seed let me show you a
good example this seedling will start to
grow it'll pop up out of the dirt and
then it'll go up toward the light this
little shell on here sometimes gets
stuck to the seed and people really
panic your seed may open up you may have
a little plant forming and the little
helmet just might be stuck on there or
it might not even have opened it this is
not a big deal this is not cause for
concern this is no reason to panic it is
very easy to fix if you are careful and
delicate and pay attention the easiest
way in my experience i call it taking
off the helmet the helmet got stuck
that's all you just got to get the
helmet off and get that soldier back
into battle so the helmet will get stuck
the easiest way in my opinion i get a
spray bottle that you could spray like
just a little squeeze sprayer you know
what i mean like you use it to clean the
windows uh get a spray bottle and just
mist it with water just put some water
you don't have to ph you can if you want
i just get some water throw it in a
spray bottle spray the seedling spray
that down the helmet and you'll notice
it softens it up i don't know if i want
to risk doing it to this seed but once
you soften it up you can just grab it
and you can just probably pull it right
off this one doesn't want to come off
yet
but if it were opened up more it would
slide right off if you don't if you've
got big clumsy gorilla fingers like me
i'm a big dude i got big [ __ ] sausage
fingers you may want to use some
tweezers get in there gently with
tweezers and just pull the helmet right
off spray it with some water and just
let it come right off if you're pulling
and struggling let it wait a couple days
nature pushes that shell off it wants to
come off so in time with water with a
little help and a little um
encouragement you will be able to get
that off without causing problems don't
panic and don't freak out don't pull too
hard spray it with water the water will
act like a lubricant it'll uh make
everything separate it'll make it super
easy for you so if that seed shell gets
stuck just moisten it up use some
tweezers pull it right off if you don't
have tweezers if you have confidence if
you got a steady hand get in there just
pull it right off with your fingers
fortunately i've got a lot of seeds so i
could play with them and learn that sort
of stuff and figure out those kind of
experiments for you you do have to be
delicate with these because they're
seedlings they're small little delicate
baby life forms but they're not precious
uh you're not going to destroy them you
can handle them you can see i'm picking
them up i'm playing with them this will
still grow this is going to be a very
viable seed i'm throwing it around and
playing with it the fingers on the acids
on my fingers are probably not good for
this i should probably be wearing gloves
but this is nature it's going to go into
the dirt there's going to be microbes in
the dirt there's going to be rolly
pulleys there's going to be spiders
there's going to be worms as this plant
grows if it were to grow in nature a
goat would piss on it the wind would
knock it over these are resilient plants
nature made this plant very resilient
and then the breeders have definitely
found the keepers out of those resilient
plants and we've made it even better so
don't be too afraid to handle your
plants don't be too afraid to handle
your seeds get in there learn your
plants learn your seeds touch them look
at them like have you ever just examined
a seedling like this it's pretty
interesting started off as a seed it
cracked open and others life coming out
of it and it's going to turn in in 12 or
13 weeks we're going to be smoking this
isn't that crazy
i love it all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
growers out there thank you once again
for watching another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns about germinating your seeds or
any other cannabis cultivation or
culture questions you know i would love
to help you out send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com try that again grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
send me an email you know i would love
to hear from you also check out my
website at iriegenetics.com
all of the vendor links are there you
can get yourself some of these fresh new
seeds get yourself some gear some
merchandise stay up to date at
iriegenetics.com all right i think that
is all i've got for you for this episode
thank you once again for listening to a
quick episode i want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy lemur priest and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]