[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
688 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on a
patreon question that asks about
starting our seeds before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend darius from cerritos let's
send a thank you shout out to stony like
baloney let's send a big thank you shout
out to my buddy purple skunk listen to
thank you shout out to sean clark and
lobster bush let's send a big fist bump
and a thank you shout out to humble
green thumb let's send a thank you shout
out to tad masterson let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to my
buddy stone trout bomb let's send a
thank you to turt burglar let's send a
big fist bump to kojaks let's send a
thank you to single t then let's wrap it
all up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my buddy
dave's not here
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and the video description to make
it nice and easy for all of my friends
before we get too far into this episode
let me remind you about the upcoming
black friday and cyber monday sale on
the irie genetics merch page that's
right if you need a new hoodie a new hat
maybe a new grinder maybe a rolling tray
i'm doing a 25 off black friday sale on
the irie genetics merch page to get to
that page simply visit the irie genetics
website at iregenetics.com
you will see the merch tab click on the
irestore tab that will take you right to
the store when you do check out there
use coupon code gfyh25
to save 25 off your entire order and
that coupon code is good for every item
in the store
all right my next order of business is
to send a big thank you to everybody who
sent me positive feedback and
constructive criticism on the previous
episode of course the previous episode
was about germinating seeds i did get a
lot of comments a lot of messages and a
lot of feedback about that show thank
you i did start that podcast off by
saying that that was how i germinate my
seeds that is exactly how i start my
seeds for my personal grow or for a
commercial grow and i have great success
with that many people told me that they
do it quite differently and that is
wonderful i have no problems no
complaints no issues with you
germinating seeds however works for you
that's one of my favorite parts about
growing cannabis there are a lot of ways
of doing it there are a lot of methods
techniques and styles and they all work
if they work you were doing it correctly
if you were satisfied with your outcome
so a lot of people wanted to give me
feedback and input on how to germinate
and i agree with you a lot of those
methods and techniques and tactics will
work for you there's a lot of great
ideas and some of the messages i got but
i was just telling you how i do it and
if you do it differently do it your way
don't let me sway you don't let me
change your ways do that do what works
for you i do want to go over some of the
ideas and things that people did mention
that i did not talk about on the show
when people are germinating seeds a lot
of the time they will soak their seeds
for 12 to 24 hours in water before even
putting them in the paper towel like i
showed that works that's a great idea
that is a great method sometimes if
you've got seeds that have a thicker
shell or a thicker hole or grew for too
long that will help them germinate that
will soften up the seed before you stick
it in the paper towel and get it going
so many people will do a 12 to 24 hour
soak on their seeds before they do
germinate them that is just filling up a
container maybe a shot glass maybe a
beer glass with water just dropping the
seeds right in the water let them swim
around for 24 hours then do the
germination method which i showed also a
lot of people do add peroxide to that
mix when they're doing the soak and the
germination they'll put a few drops of
hydrogen peroxide in the mix their idea
is to get rid of any uh problems any
bacteria any problem that may be on that
seed
a lot of other growers will add microbes
and add things to that so that is a
controversial topic do peroxide or add
microbes whichever way works for you do
it because i have seen great success
with both methods as you saw in my
germination lesson i do not use any
hydrogen peroxide in my mix i also do
not do the 12 to 24 hour soak for my
seeds i don't find it necessary if you
do that and it works for you keep doing
it another thing that a lot of growers
will do a moment ago i mentioned soaking
our seeds to soften the shell sometimes
some seeds grow if they are grown for
too long and not harvested on time the
shells will become thick those seeds
will get too hard a lot of people will
take something and scuff the outer layer
of that seed shell i've seen a lot of
different methods for doing this some
people will simply get a fine-grained
sandpaper and just rub the seed just a
little bit you don't want to penetrate
or puncture or break open the seed you
just want to scuff that outer layer to
make it a little bit softer so that the
moisture can penetrate that seed and
give it the indicator to pop open so
that's another thing that people do that
i honestly do not do
maybe if the seeds were really old or
something like that i would do that
speaking of old seeds i do not do the
peroxide method because i like to
promote beneficial bacteria and fungus
if i am starting some older seeds that i
know have been sitting around or if i
got them from somebody and i don't know
the health of those seeds or the age of
those seeds i may treat them with a
microbial product during germination
something like herb or some kind of
microbes just to give them a head start
may be the case for older seeds
but in most cases i don't do any fancy
tricks or techniques i honestly just
fold up the paper towel wet it and get
the seeds going if that is not how you
do it that is fine if your method works
for you keep doing your method i do not
disrespect or doubt your method i'm just
telling you how i do things and what
works for me and again there's no one
way to do this as long as the plants are
successful and you're happy with it you
are doing it correctly
now one comment and one piece of
feedback i was getting from a lot of
growers is that they do not even bother
doing the soak and the paper towel
method they put their seeds straight
into their dirt straight into their
cocoa they begin watering and they start
their seeds right in the pot in which
the plant is going to grow that works
like i said before if that works for you
that works for you do that there are a
few reasons why i don't start my seeds
directly in the container first of all
as a breeder as the person making the
seeds i like to observe a little bit
more i can pay attention to i can put a
handful of seeds in the paper towel i
can count them i can open it up every
however many hours i want and i can see
that it's six hours two of them popped
at 12 hours four of them popped at 18
hours i've got six of them popping i can
see that in 24 hours this many popped it
gives me i can see them better if
they're in the soil and the dirt i can't
monitor them as well i can't see the
progress i can't see what's going on it
is a breeder who's making the seeds i
like to see them i like to see the
growth the development the time and the
speed
all right i took a quick drink and fixed
my voice let's talk about a couple of
more reasons why i do not pop my seeds
directly into the soil in my container
first of all seed direction
once my seed is germinated and i've got
a little tail coming out i know which
direction that seed is going to be going
i know which way is up and which way is
down i can set that seed in the dirt or
in the cocoa and have it set perfectly
the direction it needs to go and it is
set up for success
if i just throw it right into the dirt
and i don't give it any direction i'm
not sure which direction it's facing
it's got to pop the root the root may go
up as it pops it's got to reorientate
itself and go down the seed needs to
figure out which way is down and which
way is up that's slowing me down wasting
time and energy if i put it in there
going up and down it's already set up
for success it already knows which way
to go we can save a little struggle
another reason why i don't like to plant
the seeds directly into the cocoa or
into the dirt is because i like to have
better control of the moisture level in
the early stages of my seedlings i know
that if i put that ceiling in a baggie
and a paper towel that moisture is
trapped there it is not going anywhere
i'm a busy person uh sometimes i will go
to a grow thinking i need to be at the
grow for an hour and i will be gone for
six hours and if i wasn't prepared with
my plants properly i would come home and
we would have dry dead seedlings so to
set myself up for success i put them in
the baggie where i can retain that
moisture cocoa dries soil dries if
there's air movement in the room if
there's wind if there's a temperature
change that stuff will dry out more
quickly i know that i can
control and predict the drying rate of
that
sealed baggie with the paper towel and
the moisture in there as long as i
continue to keep that baggie sealed with
the wet paper towel in there that
moisture is not going anywhere as long
as i keep that in a warm place that seed
will germinate and they will be
successful so that is part of why i
don't go straight to the pot i think we
give ourselves a lot of opportunity to
over or underwater our seedlings when we
go straight to the pot we just cause
them a lot of unnecessary stress if i've
got a moistened container a moistened
bed of soil and drop the seed directly
into there once it's germinated i feel
like i'm just setting myself up for
success and the seeds are expensive i
pride myself on making my seeds
affordable i have very competitive
prices you'll notice we are a little bit
lower price than a lot of the other
brands on the same websites i understand
how expensive seeds are i want to make
sure that every single seed germinates i
buy seeds from other breeders and other
vendors as well i pay for those seeds
just like you guys do i want success
just like you do so i do everything that
i can to ensure that success
so that is a quick update on germinating
seeds a couple of other options of
things you can do and things you might
not do things that i don't do but things
that are available to you
we started off with a 12 to 24 hour soak
we also added a little bit of peroxide
to that water to get rid of any uh
pathogens that may be present
we've also done a little bit of scuffing
on our seeds to open up the shells and
then some people may be planting
directly into their medium which is not
what i do but if you want to do that and
it works go for it have fun like i said
that's one of the best parts of growing
cannabis as long as you are happy with
the outcome as long as you're getting
the results you are looking for you can
do it however you want have fun grow
from your heart breed with love enjoy
the garden make that garden your zen
space do it however you want again i'm
just trying to share my knowledge my
info and the ways that i've had the best
success now this does segue me into a
question we have a patreon question this
one came from our friend maverick and it
basically says i started a 10 pack of
seeds i did receive three bonus seeds
you're very welcome thank you for
noticing it says i popped the seeds in
order to do a pheno hunt for some proper
smoke and a possible breeding project i
like where this is going it says i
started the seeds in a cup of distilled
water phd at 6.0 for 24 hours we're off
to a good start here it says then into a
paper towel for another 24 hours making
sense so far
at this point eight seeds have
germinated and a few have tails using
beer cups filled with sunshine mix
number four amended with a bit of kelp
meal and worm castings i planted the
seeds the depth of a pen tip the part
that holds the ink tube to the ball
point yes i know what you mean there's
the tube of the pen and there's that
little uh just the writing part where it
starts to taper that sounds like about
the right depth that is knuckle deep if
you compare that it says i lightly
covered and moistened with a few drops
of water i covered the cups with clear
beer cups all right i like most of this
so far the only thing i would have done
differently i think at this point is i
would not have covered the cups
with beer cups and i think i talked
about that in the previous episode i
want those seedlings to get air i want
them to get maybe even put a fan on them
so they get blown around
the reason we cover clones is to keep
the moisture in there we don't need to
cover the seedlings uh they're creating
a root zone that is where they're going
to eat and drink the reason we create
the humidity environment is because
clones don't have roots so in my opinion
the cup on top is unnecessary however if
it is working for you don't change it do
your thing that's the beauty of growing
cannabis in our own gardens it does go
on though it says three days later i
have two that have sprouted so you've
got some that have popped up that's
always a great feeling
day four i get another sprout and i
lightly water sprouts and add a few more
drops to the empty cups all right so
it's starting to dry you're adding some
water as they're growing on day eight
i have a total of six seedlings upon it
okay so you've got six out of uh either
10 or 13 that you germinate i don't know
how many you did ah got a pack of 10 got
13 seeds either way you've got six total
seedlings all right which is 50 which
honestly as the breeder i would hope for
more you paid for those seeds i would
hope that you get more than 50 success
out of those it says upon some
excavation i found twisted taproots and
unsprung seeds that just kind of
crunched and mushed at the same time
then the question here is did i do
something wrong i made sure the pointy
end was down and all the tap roots were
down as well from looking at the picture
my first instinct is that this plant has
been too wet for too long now it says
you've only been giving it a little bit
of water but it looks too wet in my
opinion the seedling itself looks a
little damaged like it's just funky like
it's just been abused by water like it's
been sitting in water for too long and
it honestly is getting a little bit of
rot also if you look at one section i
see what i think is the end of the tap
root popping back up out of the soil it
looks like it completely made a loop and
it is coming back up out of the soil
which i'm not sure why that happened
maybe the ceiling wasn't pointing the
right direction uh but something caused
that taproot to pop right back up out of
the soil if you look carefully i think
that's what i'm seeing i will circle
that part in the video so that we can
see that
but i really do think that that is the
end of the tap root popping back up out
of the soil so it is curled on itself
somehow which uh tells me a couple of
things again that tells me that it could
be too wet also i think it may be too
cold it's hard to judge heat and cold by
photos but by looking at this soil if
that clump of dirt has been that wet for
too long there is an extreme temperature
happening in there it is probably too
cold or too warm if it's too cold it is
definitely going to slow down all
progress of those seeds if it's too hot
it is going to speed up the rot and the
mildew process for that seed i can't
tell the temperature by looking at it i
do have a few notes here but those notes
of the temperature are going to be the
ambient air temp in the room i don't
know the temperature of the
soil inside that cup it could be really
cold especially if it's sitting on a
cold floor so it could be too cold and
too wet which would be detrimental to a
young seedling the other thing i think
about is how tightly is that soil packed
is that soil stuffed in there is it kind
of fluffy in there if it's too tight
that seedling has been struggling to
grow its entire life you said you've
grown a lot of seeds and you've done
this before so you probably didn't pack
it too tight i'm gonna trust your
judgment on that and also i'm not making
any accusations or pointing any fingers
i'm trying to give you ideas and uh
guidance on what this could be so i
don't think i'm judging you i'm just
noticing what i'm seeing in this picture
and kind of going by this one picture
and this one seedling which i've got
here uh how tightly is that soil packed
is there enough perlite or personality
in there i do see the white stuff
in there i'm not sure how much is in the
entire container a lot of times the
perlite does float so it's hard to tell
how much is in there is there air space
in there that's what i want to know do
you have some air space so when roots do
start to grow are you not going to
suffocate that little seedling the next
thing i want to know is are there
drainage holes in that cup you're using
a beer cup beer cups do not come with
holes in them you didn't say that you
did and you also didn't say that you did
not put any drainage holes in that cup
you've been watering it is that water
going anywhere or is it just evaporating
or is it making a mud hole inside that
cup if it doesn't and again if you're an
experienced grower i hope you did put
the holes in there maybe it's something
you overlooked maybe you didn't even
think about it is there any drainage in
that container because it does again
look like it's been too wet and or too
cold for too long so with the details
from the letter and the photo that i've
got i think my diagnosis is that this
plant has been too wet for too long it's
possibly cold as well i think the
solution would be to water less often
and possibly water less water each
watering and again make sure that you do
have proper draining in that container
because it looks like there's a lot of
water in there it does look like it's
been soaked for quite a while that
ceiling just has that like wrinkled
pruning been in the bathtub too long
vibe going on in the photo that's what i
think so that makes me think too wet too
cold too long now i do have one more
completely logical and rational reason
for why your seeds may not be
germinating this may not be your problem
or your fault or your issue at all those
seeds simply could be duds those seeds
simply could be old those simply could
be non-viable seeds those seeds did come
from me i do pride myself on having
quality products i do thoroughly test
everything before we release anything i
have not had a lot of negative feedback
about the line you were working with but
sometimes seeds do pass through that are
not good i obviously can't test every
single seed because i've got to send
some to you so this is a customer
service issue possibly on my end if you
feel like these seeds didn't germinate
because of my fault to no fault of your
own please send me an email and i would
love to send you a replacement pack of
seeds maybe you got old seeds maybe
those were sitting around at a vendor
for a long time ah maybe you just got
the random unviable seeds out of that
whole batch maybe there were six seeds
in there that weren't good and you
happen to get them either way i would be
happy to send you a replacement pack of
seeds that i know are more fresh and are
quality so please do feel free to reach
out send me a follow-up and we will get
you a replacement pack of seeds and then
i do look forward to that germination
report and that grow report as well so
once again to wrap this up i do think
that those seeds were too wet for too
long is my diagnosis however it could
have been a breeder issue and if you
feel like you were owed some seeds don't
be shy send me an email i would be
honored and excited to send you a
replacement pack all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy you know i
do love that listener feedback also this
is a good time for you to like and
subscribe to this channel and video if
you liked the video click like also
click subscribe that way every time i
put out a new video you will get a
notification you'll never miss an
episode for any more information check
out the website at
iriegenetics.com don't forget about the
black friday sale that does start on the
25th that will go through the end of the
month the coupon code is
gfyh25 you'll get 25
off everything in the irie store all
right that is all i've got for you i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content i want to give a big shout
out to my buddy billy podunk and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]