yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 69 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation
right if you're a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're a
cannabis activist or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host roster Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to the
Mystic Roots band for letting me use
their music on the show big thanks to
cat coup and the entire Mystic Roots
crew what's up guys I'm back with
another solo episode nobody's hanging
out with me today it's me all by myself
before we get too far I do need to send
you guys a huge apology I know that
there was an issue with the last episode
I posted the stitcher but it has since
been corrected I'm drop down that music
a little bit I'm going to repeat that uh
the last episode I posted to Stitcher
went up it went to iTunes it went to
Stitcher it went to the website
everything went perfectly but for some
reason when Stitcher grabbed it it only
took the first uh 14 or 15 minutes of it
so for the first couple of days of the
week you guys were only able to access a
15minute episode right when the grow
lesson came in everything cut off I
apologize for that Stitcher got it fixed
it took him a couple of days but
Stitcher did repair that for me so big
shout out to Stitcher uh big thanks to
everybody who went back and listened to
that episode if you guys uh tried to
listen and gave up because it sucked uh
go back and the whole episode is there
now it's a 30-some minute episode we
cover most of veg growth so now that
that's out of the way let's uh move
forward with the show um I received a
question that I want to answer it'll be
real quick somebody asked me why do you
turn off the lights during your foler
feeding um
when I'm using a bug spray or a foler
feed I turn off the lights because um
when you spray the plants with a liquid
it makes little bubbles on there right
and then you've got these high-intensity
discharge lights right above them and it
works the same way as if you took a
magnifying glass and shown the sun
through it uh it makes that little I
call it a reflector bubble and the
magnifying glass and the sun work and it
makes that little dot on [ __ ] and then
it burns it it'll create you can catch
paper on fire when I was a kid I
remember we used to burn ants and [ __ ]
with the magnifying glass using the sun
uh the bubble on your plants will do the
exact same thing it'll create that
magnifier bubble the light will hit it
it'll intensify the light beam into one
spot on your plant and it will actually
create a little burn mark in your plant
so if you're using a f your feed or a
bug spray I fully recommend you turn off
the lights it's ideal to do it right
before the lights go out if you can but
sometimes uh we have jobs and [ __ ] that
prevent us from doing that so that is
why I turn off the lights when I F your
feed and that's why I recommend you turn
off the lights when you f your feed or
bug spray let's see what's going on in
my world um man I was at the spot
yesterday I spent a couple hours out at
the spot dispensary in PLO West and
things are really moving forward I
should be out there growing cannabis uh
very soon mainly we are waiting for
inspections from the city uh we need a
couple uh small more uh we need n not
important stuff we need a few small
steps to get through before I'm able to
put plants in the spot dispensary and
start growing recreational Cannabis that
you will be able to come try that's
right I'll let you guys know when the
plants are in there I'll let you know
when we put them into flower I'll let
you guys know when they're ready I'll
let you guys know when you can come get
it also before we get to the grow lesson
I wanted to talk about how much I feel
like my head is improving um if you guys
follow the show you know that at the
beginning of April I hit my head I had a
serious concussion um a few episodes at
the beginning of April mid April were a
little bit I'm going to say they were
shitty in my opinion I know they were
not up to uh the standard I've created
they did not follow the format that I've
created
but honestly uh I was not in my head I
was recovering from a major head wound
but the good part is I feel like I'm
getting my [ __ ] together um it's been a
week since I sat down to record and it
came together the recording equipment
came together easily my podcast notes
came together easily uh the notes that I
wrote last week I brushed them up and
made a lot more sense out of them so the
good part is I feel like I'm getting
back together I want to thank you guys
for uh sticking with me through my head
injury while I've been kind of a
[ __ ] I have not been all here and I
know that I appreciate you guys that
have not abandoned me and my show
through that time that's cool of you
also extra huge shout out to all the
people who have sent me love and support
and well wishes uh telling me to get
better telling me to take care of my
head uh several people volunteered to
come do chores for me so I appreciate
that you guys have no idea what that
means to me I'm getting back on my feet
well I've been on my feet but I'm
getting my head back in there while I'm
doing it so let's move on to the grow
lesson you guys I've written a bunch of
stuff and I'm going to try to it all
into one lesson for you so I may leave a
little bit out if you have any questions
just ask and I'll go back over anything
I went to fast on all right I'm going to
take a quick drink and a dab and we are
going to get on with the grow lesson
here we go hey guys while I'm taking a
dab make sure you support our sponsors
the Rocky Mountain worm company if you
need organic soil amendments or
highquality worm castings check out www.
rockymountain worm cod.com
today all right guys in the last episode
I talked lot about vegetative growth and
we got right up to the first day of
flowering and that's where I want to
start off today let's start a flowering
cycle but first let's talk a little bit
about the flowering period I've alluded
that there are three trimesters to the
flowering period now let me explain a
little what I meant by that uh for this
we're going to talk about a 9we plant uh
nwe flowering plant uh we'll use
Grateful Dog as an example because it
likes to finish in about nine weeks so
that's perfect uh the first trimester is
what I would refer to as the transition
phase uh the second trimester is full
flour uh and the finishing and the third
trimester is the finishing and ripening
phase so I'm going to try to talk a
little bit about what the plants want
during each trimester and I'll do my
best to kind of break it down week by
week for you and let you know what to
feed and what you can be doing to your
plants each week uh we'll find like the
main important things to do to your
plants each week and then I'll give you
some ideas that'll really improve your
crops and then in a future episode we're
going to focus all about improving your
crops so
let's get on it let's start a flowering
cycle today would be day one of week one
of flower so you I would start on a
Monday that's just my preference we've
talked about that I would go to that
Monday and I would say day one of flower
week one day one uh then I would go
through and Mark that calendar week two
week three week four week five week six
so that it's easily easily viewable all
right so you want to set the lights for
a 1212 cycle uh that means we want the
lights to be on for 12 hours and off for
12 hours of uninterrupted Darkness every
day and every night uh we can't have any
dark during the night cycle I can't
stress or any light during the night
cycle I can't stress how important it is
to have total darkness for the dark
period of your Bloom cycle the room
needs to be totally pitch black dark if
you can see any light in there it's too
much uh if you can stand in the room and
put your hand in front of your face if
you can see your hand at all you need
more darkness in there uh that's
completely important uh it's also uh
let's see where was I it's equally
important not to interrupt the dark
period uh interrupting the dark period
will cause your plants to possibly Herm
and possibly make seeds uh your plants
are asleep you want to let them sleep it
pisses you off when I wake you up in the
middle of the night it' piss your plants
off too so running a 1212 cycle I like
to keep my metal halide bulbs in for the
first two weeks of flowering for the
first week of flowering all right here
we go for the first week of flowering I
would feed my vegetative base nutrients
and I would start pumping up my pnk
values okay and I would also keep
focusing on root development a little
bit if I were using bottled nutrients I
would uh use a little bit of liquid
Karma some Silica Blast I would use a
little bit of humble honey and some
roots zho or something similar uh some
kind of similar rooting powder or maybe
some uh like uh what was I us before ogt
that works some great white shark Works
anything like that would work for you
and also maybe I would add in some
hydrozyme uh don't expect to see a whole
lot of action from the plants your first
week of flower uh this is the start of
the transitional period like like I said
this is Transitional phase from Veg to
bloom and then in about 6 to 10 days is
where you're really going to see your
changes so let me add something here
while I'm thinking about it your plants
are going to get fed nutrients uh on
every Monday but they're probably going
to get uh thirsty and need a drink
before the next Monday so it's probably
going to be Wednesday or Thursday but on
that day water your plants with just
clean water phed at
6.5 uh you don't want to feed every day
because then your plants are going to
start to get over fertilized and they
are going to get what we call nutrient
lockout all of your bottle nutrients are
salt based and if we keep feeding these
salts to our plants they get salty and
they don't want to take up more salts so
they simply stop taking up nutrients and
that's called nutrient lockout so we're
going to feed clean water every
Wednesday or Thursday and prevent that
nutrient lockout by giving these girls a
fresh drink so that's going to put us
into week two
for week two I would start feeding my
Bloom base nutrients and I would add
some cow mag I would add this is if
you're going to use bottle nutrients and
this is what I would use if I were using
liquid Karma if you're using a different
brand uh all of these products are
easily replaceable just look at your
feed chart and look at your the other
brand and replace the bottles it'll be
that easy so uh for week two I would do
some calmag some liquid Karma Silica
Blast and I would add a little bit of
clex uh week two is where you really
need to start paying attention for m
plants if you started from seeds you're
going to start seeing uh little ball
sacks develop if you've got males in
there get them out uh in week two you
should start seeing pre- flowers and the
plants are starting to stretch by the
end of this week you should have
identified your males and isolated them
if you don't plan on breeding uh
definitely get those males out of there
cut them down uh if you put them in the
garage they may keep going if you put
them somewhere they may keep going and
make pollen kill them cut them down kill
them uh unless you plan on breeding and
if you plan on breeding then I don't
need to tell you what to do with males
you've already got that figured out so
for week two they're pretty much just
going to grow uh you're going to start
seeing flowering Set uh flower sets
start to develop you'll start to see the
sex uh if you're using femin seeds still
pay attention to the sex you may get
some Herm hermaphrodites some [ __ ] could
have gone wrong you may have gotten the
wrong seeds you never know pay attention
don't take that feminized label as the
complete this will be a perfect female
plant that could not be the case all
right so week three week three is a busy
week this is where we really start
getting busy you should have identified
your males by now uh you should have
pulled them hopefully if you had clones
of those you tossed the Clones of the
males also so uh if you don't have nice
Bud sights developing by the beginning
of week three you may have a light leak
or another issue during your dark period
uh if you're not starting to see little
dandelion looking buds sits by now go in
the room at night and make sure you're
not getting a light leak a small light
leak will prevent your your plants from
going into flower so for week three
I would feed my Bloom base nutrients I
would feed calag I would introduce
fulvex I would use Liquid Karma I would
use
hydroplex uh clex Silica Blast humble
honey and hygrozyme this week uh this
will be the basic recipe through
flowering minus the hygrozyme I only
hygrozyme every other feed now I do add
a few other things to my personal mix
but uh this will get you guys through
flowering I don't want to get too crazy
and have you buying a whole bunch of
things when you're not ready for that so
I did get this mix from the Botanicare
website uh if you need help mixing up a
great Botanicare recipe just go to the
Botanicare website go to the Nutrient
calculator uh basically fill it in it
asks how many weeks you want a veg how
many weeks you want to flour it asks you
which bottles of nutrients you've got
you click on those and it'll tell you
what to feed I would recommend reducing
it just a little bit uh feed your plants
a reduced mix and see how they react you
can always feed more but you can't unfed
your plants once they've burned
themselves
so don't overdo it uh they do I like
Botanicare I like the company but they
are a company they need you to buy more
so they kind of tell you to use a little
bit extra is my opinion the more you use
the sooner you got to buy another bottle
anyway let's talk more about week three
um yeah you can go get that on the
Botanicare website is where I left off
right all right if you're using a
different brand they do have a different
feeding chart online for you to follow
uh almost all the popular brands have a
feeding chart right now and you can
easily like I said you can easily swap
out bottle for bottle if you know if you
just read like I said liquid Karma read
the bottle see what's in there look at
whatever brand you're using and there's
the equivalent for your brand is there
it's all basically the same [ __ ] I just
prefer Botanicare if I'm going bottled
NES all right so I also like to add a
nice dose of carbs and sugars at week
three um we're going to start seeing
resin production around week uh midweek
three early week four you'll very little
resin production but it will start and
why not give it some carbs and sugars to
start contributing to that that's my op
opinion and I also think that carbs and
sugars keep the MOs in your root Zone
living and healthy and happy so that is
always a good idea to add those guys so
in week three we should really see Bud
sights developing this is a good time to
start lollipopping your plants what that
means is kind of cleaning up the bottom
uh little mini Buds and the sucker
branches that aren't going to get enough
light to become viable buds just get in
there and clean that [ __ ] right out
don't be afraid um we'll do a whole
lesson on lollipopping if we haven't
already you want to get in there light's
only going to P penetrate your canopy
about 18 to 20 maybe 24 in uh if you're
using regular th000 watt bulbs if you're
using lower wattage you've got even less
penetration so you're going to want to
get in there if your plant's 3ot tall
you don't need a whole 3ft stock you
want to kind of clean off the bottom 12
inches or so and that gives you more air
flow down there those buds that develop
down there are just going to be wispy
[ __ ] anyway unless you're going to make
hash with it clean that up send all that
energy up to the top of the plant
because you don't want to waste time
time trimming that bottom [ __ ] anyway so
we're g to lollipop clean up the
bottoms um also I would recommend
switching from metal HDE bulbs to high
pressure sodium bulbs at the start of
week three week three is the last week
of the first trimester and it's the last
week of the transition and stretching
phase so after this week your plants
will quit stretching so much week three
is really the super stretch and then
week four they'll quit stretching and
start working more on buds for you so in
week three you want a lollipop
and you want to change to your high
pressure sodium bulbs are your main
goals for week three and guys I know I'm
going kind of fast but we got nine weeks
to cover here and I'm only to week four
and we're 15 minutes in already
so uh week four I'm going to feed a very
similar mix that I would in week three
uh week four is the end of the stretch
phase and the start of actual bud growth
you'll really start to see buds
developing by now and if you don't
you've got a problem we need to get in
there and make sure you've got Darkness
make sure you don't have some shitty PL
so uh uh week four is another week to
lollipop you can definitely get in there
and lollipop a little bit more I just
use my thumbnail I don't trim my
thumbnail all the way down I just use
that to pick off those little sucker
buds uh collect them up put them in a
little trash can and toss them those are
or put them in the compost pile if
you're doing that those little sucker
buds are just that they're just little
suckers they all that energy could go up
to the top of the plant if you guys are
growing for just hash you could do
whatever you want with that I get it so
um now it's also a good time to start
adding steaks or some sort of supports
to the branches cuz we're going to get
some Hefty Buds and once we get into
week five and six we're really going to
need Stakes to support everything but by
week five and six it's such a [ __ ] to
maneuver those plants uh your branches
got long sticky colas on there and you
don't want to be playing with the resin
and getting the resin all over your
clothes you want to leave that on the
plant so get in there about week four
and I like to put a stake to support the
middle Cola cuz I know I'm going to have
a big huge fat Cola then I like to put
about four maybe six sticks around the
pot because I'm going to get some big
colas and I use those sticks to strap up
my major colas just right to the stick
and I do it early because like I'm
saying in week five and six I'm going to
have some buds going on that I don't
want to have to mess with so much and if
I got them all strapped up already I
don't have to worry about it when I'm
working with soil plants I usually don't
use a trellis or a screen or anything
but at the uh the dispensary where I'm
running the big row we are definitely
using a trellis and if you're going to
Trellis the you need to get that in
there during your veg cycle that's why
when I was doing the veg lesson I
mentioned that this is the week to do
any type of trellising and [ __ ] like
that that'll have to happen in veg you
guys because those plants are going to
grow up into that trellis and you don't
want to be bending them and folding them
and manipulating them in flower so you
have to be prepared for that that's why
we're making a schedule now before we
put these plants in the dirt or in the
Rockwall cubes so get your staks up you
guys water healthy get your staks up
more lollipopping that's what you're
doing for week four let's transition
into week five now this is when the fun
starts you guys the plants start getting
photogenic the buds start getting chunky
uh since we're getting chunky buds it's
a good time to stop foler feeding I
don't talk a lot about folar feeding I
will in the future um foler feeding can
lead to a lot of problems if it's done
incorrectly or at the wrong time so I
haven't introduced that yet but if you
have gone on your own and started foler
feeding week five is when I would
recommend you
quit uh it's also important to pay
attention to your humidity in week five
high humidity and big buds can be a
great way to create powdery mildew or
other mold related problems I'm sure you
guys that listen to the podcast they've
heard me talk about growing in a new
room I was in a basement I had a um
exterior wall Corner that got really
cold and that corner pocket right there
had a lot of cold air and I had a 5 O
White Rhino plant that I cut down and
discovered powdery mildew on one butt of
it as I was cutting it down and I threw
the entire plant away uh about probably
5 ounces worth of good cannabis
somewhere between four and 6 ounces is
what those plants were averaging so
those 5 ounces that my patients did not
get to enjoy because I let it get
powdery milw so pay attention to the
room don't let your room get too humid
uh my problem was that it was cold and I
was letting cold air mix with the warm
air and that created mildew in my room
um but I learned from it I learned a
whole lot that [ __ ] will never happen to
me again and guys if it happens to you
don't don't feel bad shit's going to
happen you just have to learn from it
it's how you deal with it is what makes
you the the grower so uh do your best to
get the humidity under control you don't
want too much humidity in there you do
not want to start getting mildew um for
week five I would recommend getting your
humidity right around 50% if you can get
it to 40 there's nothing wrong with that
um you don't want it too high that's
when you're going to get problems too
low of humidity your room's going to dry
up kind of quickly and the buds don't
get as sticky I don't think but uh if
you have the option or if you're stuck
with one if you have to go too high or
too low definitely go too low if you
make humidity so let's see we talked
about getting rid of the humidity I'm
reading notes as I do this um oh this is
where I would stop lollipopping you guys
week five don't lollipop anymore uh you
can if you want to but you should have
gotten all that taken care of by now and
you're just going to kind of shock the
plant if you keep doing it uh you may if
you keep lollipopping and [ __ ] with
the plant this far in you may cause it
to stress out and Herm just depends on
what other stress you're giv to the
plant so you should have a room full of
sexy chunky buds by now and they're
going to start falling over and needing
a attention so uh hopefully you've got
plenty of sticks in there you're in
there paying attention every day uh
you're going to go in there one day and
you're going to find a bud that you
didn't notice and it's going to be
straight sideways looking like it's
ready to break Don't Panic just get in
there and support it give it some
support that shit's going to happen to
you uh and you're going to learn all
these things over a couple of grows of
what to look for and you'll learn to
stop panicking when you see a problem
guys don't panic that's I know I keep
saying that but if you freak out you're
just going to make it worse when you see
a problem in the grow room just take a
minute it's a plant we can fix it
hopefully if not we'll just make BHO out
of it you're going to be okay so for
week five I like to add a really strong
dose of sugars and carbs uh one of my
favorite bottled products is humble
honey uh I use that at week three but I
use a nice fat dose of it again at week
five so for week five you want to make
sure you've got your supports in place
if you haven't done it in week four you
may need to add a few more sticks in
place for week five to get those bigger
buds up in place what I do I put a I
think it's a six foot tall bamboo stick
cuz I grow big plants you guys I put a
six foot tall bamboo stick uh toward the
outer edge of the plant because I don't
want to disrupt too much of the root I
just shove it right into there um then I
grab the bud that needs some support and
I use I've used several different things
but right now I'm using they call them
uh fuzzy sticks got them at Hobby Lobby
they had a whole bunch for really cheap
so I bought a [ __ ] ton of them it's kind
of like a uh it's a pipe cleaner
essentially it's like a really long red
tie that you can handle better so I just
take that and I wrap that right around
the stock of the bud that's going to
fall over and maybe maybe I'll do part
of the bud just depends on how heavy the
bud is if I feel like it'll break the
stick but then I take that and just wrap
it around the bud or the stock and wrap
that around the stick itself so that
it's just strapped right up to it like
you got a broken finger just give that
sucker some support you just don't want
it falling over and breaking it's your
whole goal uh maybe if you tip it a
little bit if it's at an angle it's a
good idea because then you can expose
more of that bud to the light and
instead of just having it completely up
and down if you tip it you get a little
more surface area for that light to hit
which will increase your
harvests so week five you want to work
on your supports you want to feed some
sugars and carbs you want to monitor
your humidity get it around 50 to 40%
and keep it there because you're going
to start uh getting chunkier buds and
you don't need mildew and you're going
to stop fol your feeding all right so
that's what's going to happen in week
five that's going to move us into week
six uh in week six I would feed a very
similar recipe as I did in week five I'd
use high amounts of pnk and lots of
sugars and carbs I would reduce my base
nutrients and focus on resin production
and healthy
plants uh week six will be our last full
feeding our Bud should be chunky and the
resin should be starting to cover the
buds and the small leaves uh if you're
growing a strain that purples up now is
a good time to lower the temps a few
degrees during the night cycles I try to
keep my Grow rooms about 77 or 74 to 77°
during the light period during the
period I try to get it down to about 68
69° at this point in week six if I'm
working with something that will purple
up a little bit like the kangi Kush or
the flo or the ghost OG or the Grateful
Dog I would drop the temps down just a
few more to like 65 degrees maybe 67 and
if you get to that 65 at night you'll
see it in a night or two those plants
will start to purple up the leaves will
turn purple for you um higher CBD plants
I think like more cold but that's just
my experience with the torab Bora and
the Night Nurse uh you may have a
totally different plant so don't take
that as a rule that's just my experience
so you might want to lower the temps
just a little bit if you're trying to
pull out the purples if you have more
sativa dominant plants uh th this would
probably piss off the Capleton the White
Widow would not like it lemon Jeffrey
would not like that don't put those in
the cold but cushy plants uh indic
dominant plants give them a little bit
of cold and they'll purple up for you
about week
six um you're going to have to use more
air conditioning so that may cost you a
little bit but I think it's worth it for
the plant that enjoys that so week
Seven's a great week for photography you
guys you got big chunky buds this is
however your last feeding so whatever
your plants are lacking or whatever you
haven't gotten in there this is probably
your last chance to do it we are going
to feed on week seven but we're not
going to feed the entire program we're
just going to give a little bit of stuff
to keep it alive and happy and healthy
so week six
uh basically work on a good feeding uh
lower your temps if you want make sure
you've got everything supported and
staked up make sure nothing Falls over
keep going through every single week you
guys and check for Herms check for males
check for issues uh I should say this
also every day if you can do it every
day go in your garden and grab each
plant and just grab one leaf and flip it
upside down and inspect the [ __ ] out of
it if you see any signs of bugs any
kinds of pests that's when we need to
get in there and really deal with it
hopefully you're not too far into Flower
by the time we discover a pest uh if
you're in flower when we discover pest
that's a whole another conversation
that's when you have to decide are these
pests going to ruin my garden before
Harvest time or can I eradicate these
pests somehow there are a lot of
decisions to make in that scramble mode
we'll talk about that in another episode
I do have a whole Pest Management
episode uh in the works so week six we
have uh lower the temps that's our last
big feeding we got chunky buds hopefully
he took a lot of pictures in week six
because week six is photogenic week
seven in this is when we start what I've
been calling the third trimester this is
ripening and the flush phase uh we won't
feed most of our nutrients this week I
would only use the humble honey for the
yucka extract and the sweetener in there
uh that's really going to make your
plant sweet it's going to make them DSE
up and it's going to make them taste
good and it's going to make them stanky
uh I would also use clex I think clex
really contributes to the aroma and
flavor of a Kush dominant plant a lot of
clex in cushy plants will bring out that
funk that feedy smell I really love it A
Grateful Dog loves
clex uh if you're grow and grateful dog
when you crack it open there's a an
offensive odor that comes out of it it's
almost foot-like it's almost armpit
likee and it has a scent of fuel to it I
think if you pump up the clex or a seelp
based product when you grow Grateful Dog
it will definitely increase that funky
ass turpine you're getting out of it so
we're using humble Honey C hydrozyme
also I like enzymes at this phase to
start breaking down uh dead material
dead roots that have maybe died and need
to be decomposed in there the hyro will
help eliminate that [ __ ] and speed
things along for the flush phase also
add some fulvex if you want to speed
things up and our friend Sean taught us
that you can use ogt to speed up the
flushing phase of your plants because
the rock phosphates make the plant cycle
too quickly it speeds up the nutritive
cycle so that will kind of assist us in
the flush phase if we like to I do not
use any of that [ __ ] like Final Phase or
clearex or any of that um I feel like
that stuff leaves a little bit of a
flavor in the plant and I also believe
that if we are growing properly and we
are flushing properly we don't need that
product that's just another product to
cell there is a science behind it like I
said earlier we are filling the plant
with salts and those flushing agents are
basically sugars and complex sugars
break down salts which would break the
bond of the salts around the N uh the
root base
which would allow uh cleaner absorption
of the roots and everything would just
taste better and it would flow better
but I don't think that they're necessary
unless you [ __ ] up at some point in
the grow so we're very close to harvest
time uh we really need to start getting
the excess nutrients out of our buds
before we cut them down and prepare them
so we need to start getting the nitrogen
the phosphorus the potassium the
maganese the uh calcium the Magnesium
all the [ __ ] that we've been shoving
into these plants we want to get it out
of there now
so um that moves us into week eight
excuse me week eight is the beginning
the official beginning of the flush
phase um what I like to do and this kind
of depends on your setup if you have
smaller pots you can move the pots to
the bathroom or the shower throw a
cinder block put something down so you
don't scratch up the bathtub or the
shower you guys put a towel down throw a
cinder block or a bucket right in the
bathtub or the shower and then if you're
using a three gallon pot I like to run
about 9 or 10 gallons of water right
through that pot I know that sounds
excessive but what you're doing you want
to wa you're washing the dirt you want
to get all of the nutrients that we've
poured into this plant through the past
seven weeks we need to rinse all that
[ __ ] out of the dirt now so and it's
also in the plant the plant has been
eating it so we have to kind of starve
the plant for the next two weeks if
you're using bigger pots it might not be
feasible or rational to drag them to
another room that's fine in a sgon pot I
usually pour about a gallon and a half
of water through it and just let it fill
up in that little tray and then I use a
shop vac a wet dry V to go suck the
water out of the trays I know that
sounds excessive but I really like to
clean out the plants if this method
doesn't work for you what you have to
really focus on when you're
flushing you want water to come out of
the bottom of the pot you need like if I
would like to say at least 10% of the
water I want to see that come back out
of the bottom that's how I know I'm
actually flushing that plant and pushing
something out if nothing's coming out of
the bottom nothing's coming out
you got to get water to flow to get all
those nutrients out and you're going to
want to do that without drowning your
plant you're going to want to flush it
let it kind of dry and then flush it
again as many times as we can until the
end of week nine so the week eight is a
start of flushing you're probably going
to water the [ __ ] out of it on Monday
it's not going to be ready for water
again until probably Thursday or Friday
because you watered it so
heavily um don't be in too much of a
rush to water it again because you will
drown the damn plant so Thursday or
Friday when you water it again do the
same thing lots of water just lots of
water just let it go right on through
just let it drain right on through if
you've got like a floor drain or
something just keep pouring water
through you can't over flush in my
opinion it's ideal to use three
times uh the volume of the pot so if
you've got a nine gallon pot or a three
gallon pot you want to use nine gallons
of water if you got a 5 gallon pot you
want to put 15 gallons of water through
that [ __ ] right is that what I said 5
gallon pot 15 G water three times yeah
just making sure I'm doing good math
here head injuri is coming back all
right so flush really good you guys I
[ __ ] a lot about cannabis because it's
improperly flushed um when you're
smoking a joint if the joint won't stay
lit if you have to keep relighting it
there's a good chance it wasn't flush
properly or I rolled it and I don't roll
with of [ __ ] but if your ashes are black
and chunky there are still nutrients in
there you want a nice clean white ash
that's nice and smooth and soft you
don't want chunks of it if you Ash into
your hand it should feel nice you should
almost enjoy that nice smooth texture of
the ashes if your plants were flushed
properly um one of my biggest complaints
about dispensary cannabis and I am
trying to fix this in my shop uh they
don't flush they do not flush and they
do not cure they pretty much say shit's
done cut it down and sell it and I don't
like that so we're going to try to
change that where I'm working uh
flushing is important you guys I can't
stress that so from week eight you want
to flush run plenty of clean water
through that pot week nine flushing is
in full effect uh week nine ends at day
63 on day 60 here's what I recommend go
in the grow room and start taking off
all of the big fan leaves any leaf that
has a pedial that's a stem you guys any
leaf that has a stem that you can get to
take some scissors and cut that [ __ ] off
really close to the bud just go in there
and de Leaf the entire room you don't
need these leaves anymore this is going
to save you time when it comes to
harvest so day 60 you walked in there
and you took off all of those leaves
boom
now this may sound crazy this is what I
do in my grows I've got three days left
right on the first on day 61 I reduce my
lights from 12:12 to 10:14 I'm on for 10
hours and I'm off for 14 the plants are
going oh [ __ ] he's going to kill us now
the time is near they know it the next
day I'll drop him down to eight hours
and on day three I'll give him 24 hours
of total darkness so day 63 no light at
all I'll leave them off for the entire
day
day 64 wake up bright and early nice and
ready go in and cut down the entire room
and just let them hang that's Harvest
day that's 63 or 64 days you guys nine
weeks of full flow I got through that in
30 minutes I did have to kind of I did
have to kind of skip a couple of details
I'm going to take a drink I'm sorry I'm
trying to talk right through this but I
got a throat thing let me take a drink
here all right that's a little better I
got you guys through 9 weeks and 30
minutes I left some stuff out but I feel
like that leaves me more [ __ ] to teach
you guys and more tips tips to give you
in the future you'll survive a crop with
everything I taught you um something
that I should mention if you do grow a
longer strain I would recommend reducing
the light to 11 hours on and 13 hours
off around week nine this is only if
you're growing something that takes 11
weeks or more um some sativas won't
finish up without a short and day period
the reason is they are from an area that
only have a few hours difference in the
natural day and night cycle so we need
to encourage them excuse me I just
burped right into the microphone we need
to encourage these plants to finish up
by shortening the days uh what happens
when we shorten the days is the plant
realizes that winter is coming and our
plant's main goal is to pollinate and
create seeds and since it hasn't
received any pollen it's kind of being
stubborn about finishing it's like H I
really think it's like a dude at a party
it thinks if it hangs out late enough
there's still a chance of getting laid
so what we got to do is we got to start
messing with the lights and tell these
guys your time's up dude we got to turn
tell the girls actually we got to turn
the lights down and they'll start
finishing on their own otherwise some of
these sativas will just keep on going I
had a Durban Poison strain that went for
14 weeks and then I was getting tired of
that [ __ ] because I needed the room and
it was I was done growing that strain
and that crop and it wouldn't finish and
then I thought well why don't I just
reduce the lights down a little bit and
speed this up and you know within one
week of reducing the lights it finished
I just had to tell it so
so also you may want to feed for a
little bit longer if you're running a
longer plant I would extend the week six
regimen if you have to extend anything
uh just repeat week six uh until you get
to the like if you have three extra
weeks just do week six three extra times
that's what I'm trying to say here guys
my voice is burning out I've got a
little bit more stuff here but I'm
running out of throat so I think we're
going to do another 35 minute show and
wrap this [ __ ] up put a bow on it um I
appreciate you guys for listening to me
if you want more information please
email me grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com you can find me on Facebook
it's grow fromy yourheart you can tweet
me it's gfyh podcast um if you are on
Instagram make sure you follow me it's
IR gentics send me a message on one of
those platforms and say hey bro when you
were doing your grow lesson I needed to
know this and you didn't tell me and I
will make a lesson out of that just for
you in the future guys I apologize that
my throat is burning out here let's just
wrap it up so I don't have to sound like
[ __ ] anymore uh thanks for listening I
really do appreciate it I think you can
tell that my head's getting better I
really can I ordered a product from on
it.com called alphabrain uh if you
listen to Joe Rogan or any of those
other podcasts you've heard about
alphabrain alphabrain is used by public
speakers and um lecturers and folks in
that type of a position that have to
speak right but they say that Alpha
Brain it's a new Tropic and it is
supposed to increase your ability to
recall names and and facts and locations
and it's supposed to uh broaden your
vocabulary so maybe that'll improve on
my head injury and fix all my
problems all right I really don't have a
voice left so don't forget to check out
our sponsors the Rocky Mountain worm
company and hyro indoor growing supplies
make sure you visit naturegreen
remedies.com for all your seeds uh if
you're interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review send me an email I
already told you guys it's gr yourart
hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you need um check us
out on all the social media sites I'd
really appreciate it don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every single episode will always and
forever be archived on iry gentics
color.com don't forget about the
donation button on the podcast page
that's right go to iry gentics
colorado.com go to the grow from your
heart podcast tab at the top right
there's a little PayPal logo that's a
donation button click on that that goes
directly to my Paypal account I'm never
going to charge you guys for the podcast
this is always going to be free but if
you feel like making a contribution to
say thank you I would definitely
appreciate it I do put at least 3 hours
into every episode plus the hour that it
takes to record I do research I write
all the stuff out uh I'm not asking for
anything but some people want to do that
and I'm not going to stop you so throw
down if you want to we are on all the
social media sites I think I already
said that yeah no more rambling dude
make sure you guys follow me on
Instagram I'm almost at 15,000 followers
I really want to hit that 15,000 Mark
I'm not sure why but I do um once again
big shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening you guys until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me