[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
690 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
pesticide drift in our outdoor gardens
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to kim matic
listen to thank you shout out to darion
smith let's send a thank you shout out
to jg i want to send a big fist bump and
a thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter and a good friend my buddy
treestar meadow let's send a thank you
shout out to another longtime supporter
my buddy kurt z let's send a thank you
shout out to a great photographer and a
good tester my buddy zo so j let's send
a thank you shout out to a canadian
supporter tonto let's send a big thank
you shout out to danky dave i want to
send a fist bump to dayron t let's send
a special thank you shout out to double
d then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend all mixed up big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends i do want to start the show by
saying wow i apologize for going through
that intro super fast i smoked a strain
of some flowers of a strain called jack
tripper and it's got me going super fast
hopefully i can calm down and get this
together but my brain is speeding
through it uh jack tripper is a cross of
it is uh lemon skunk and jack the ripper
it's got a flavor of lemon candy and
spiciness and some dryer sheets in it my
favorite part is that it has just got my
brain to suspend and i'm going super
fast in here also something i noticed
most of the time when i smoke flowers my
mouth gets super dry my mouth my throat
my nose my eyes i get that dry
cottonmouth feeling that just crusty eye
feeling from smoking so much flour i do
not have that feeling at all from these
flowers it is quite the opposite my
mouth feels not to it sounds kind of
gross i got juicy mouth from smoking
those flowers it tasted so good that my
mouth is like watering thinking about
the lemon candy flowery spicy flavors
that came from it's like lemon candy
bubble gum dryer sheets there's a lot of
stuff lingering on my tongue right now i
really enjoy it i'm going to try to keep
myself together and do a good podcast
for you but heads up i was smoking some
good [ __ ] today all right let's jump
right into it i don't want to ramble too
much because that is definitely a
possibility in this episode i did say at
the beginning of the show that we were
going to talk about pesticide drift in
our outdoor gardens we are wrapping up
the outdoor season most folks in the
united states have wrapped up their
outdoor grow season if you have not
wrapped up you are a savage or a maniac
good luck but many people have wrapped
up their outdoor grows a lot of people
have gotten their outdoor grows tested
by a lab facility we're testing for
potency and we're posting testing for
terpene content also we're testing for
contamination we're testing for heavy
metals and the presence of pesticides
we're making some weird discoveries i
was having this conversation with some
friends in a discord server and then
just after that we had some flowers not
any of my flowers but a friend another
person that i associate with and outdoor
girl i was checking out a lot they
discovered that some of their flowers
are testing hot for pesticide exposure
now how is this happening because the
people i'm talking about never used any
spray applications in their garden
especially the products that they are
being uh tested positive for so they're
saying how did this happen there's only
one solution that i could come up with
somebody a neighboring garden must have
been applying illegal pesticides or
pesticides that were drifting into our
friend's garden now that is really
important to think about are you
applying a pesticide and this only works
for an outdoor garden if you're applying
indoors that shit's stuck indoors you'd
be very careful think about where you're
exhausting to but for the most part
you're just spraying indoors outdoors no
matter how big your garden if you're
using a three by three plot of land that
is yours and the neighbors are sharing
that land on the other side of that
imaginary fence that imaginary
borderline it is still your
responsibility if you've got acres and
acres it is still your responsibility to
control the products that you apply to
your garden if they drift and travel
outward it is our responsibility to be
responsible pesticide applicators if
you've been trained by the department of
ag if you've taken any training classes
if you're certified you probably
understand the importance of pesticide
drift many people may not understand
that so we were talking about it and
there were a lot of things that came to
my mind and i thought we could do a good
podcast about it so uh did your neighbor
contaminate your grow did you did you
contaminate your neighbors grow were the
first two questions that i wrote in my
notes
pesticide can drift when you are
spraying stuff if it is windy it can
travel to the grow next door it can
travel every direction it could travel
whichever direction the wind is going so
let's be careful when we're applying now
this doesn't only count in cannabis
crops you may have neighbors that are
using uh you may have a fruit and
vegetable crop next door you may have a
hemp crop you may have they may have a
pumpkin patch coming up right next door
think about what they're spraying what
they're using think about what you're
spraying and what you are using is it
going to have detrimental effects on
either side of the fence possibly four
sides of the fence maybe you got people
all around you that means you got at
least four people to think about other
than yourself when it comes to pesticide
applications let's be good neighbors
let's be a good community we're growing
cannabis and a lot of people already
have a little bit of a stigma for us a
lot of people were programmed and
trained that reefer madness cannabis is
the devil we're gonna smoke smoke a
little bit of weed and start raping
ladies and committing crimes and doing
all the worst [ __ ] you could think of
we're gonna become the devil it doesn't
happen that way but they think that so
let's try to be good neighbors we're
growing cannabis right next door to
people that may be afraid of us let's be
good neighbors let's not destroy their
crops because that is one more thing to
make them hate team cannabis let's try
to be their friends we'll talk more
about that a little bit here in the
future so are you spraying your
neighbors and another thing to think
about are your neighbors spraying or
treating and sending their pests your
way when you spray for a pest or treat
for a pest or a problem especially like
if you got spider mites or something
like that i'm just gonna pick spider
mites if you spray for spider mites
outdoors they're going that way in that
way and if your neighbors didn't spray
for spider mites they're gonna get
spider mites if you don't treat for
spider mites in some sort of way maybe
you sprayed maybe you got predators
maybe you got some sort of
electromagnetic mind control that you
can use to control spider mites when one
of you treats for bugs the bugs are
gonna go to the other yard they're just
gonna say oh this guy's sprayed for
spider mites let's just climb the fence
there's no fence or spider mites are
microscopic they're just going to travel
south they're going to go to the next
garden right over there because that
person didn't treat for bugs didn't
treat for spider mites so if one of you
is treating and one of you isn't they're
just going to move around and then when
your treatment wears off or your spray
wears off they're going to go to the
other garden and then the other guy's
going to spray they're going to keep
traveling around a great way to prevent
this would be
farmer unity why not go and meet your
neighbors why not go and talk to each
person around you growing and see how
you are handling pests i'm sure that in
a lot of agricultural
areas there are meetings people have
town meetings people get together in
small towns they like to gather and meet
maybe a church maybe somewhere like that
bring it up say hey are you guys
treating there's nothing stopping you
from going and knocking on the door i
know maybe there is i don't know your
situation uh farmers are different i
don't have a lot i'm gonna be straight
up i don't have a lot of farm life
experience i'm a city boy i'm an indoor
grower i actually contacted a farmer
friend and i said hey is there a
protocol for this and he said not really
so i guess the thing would to do would
be to go knock on their door or send
them a letter or contact them some way
they're people they're facing the same
challenges as you possibly if you went
over there and said hey last year i got
hit with spider mites real bad around
this time of year did you notice that as
well and they're gonna go well holy [ __ ]
so did i and you're gonna go well this
year i'm going to do this to treat the
spider mites what are you going to do
and they can say well that your
treatment was a good idea or maybe
they'll say you know my grandpappy
taught me that for 20 years we did this
and it worked you might learn some [ __ ]
you might teach some [ __ ] so don't be
afraid to make contact go over there
establish some friendships build a
relationship see what you guys are doing
and work together if not like i said you
could just be passing those problems
from farm to farm to farm if you've got
think about if you got four farms
meeting at a corner you got the four
corners they're gonna go from plot a to
plot b to plot c to plot d just in a
circle just gonna rotate if you guys
don't do something if you guys all team
up you'll kill all the pests all the
problems work together you can all have
successful outcomes then if one guy's
growing corn and one guy is growing
soybeans and one guy's growing in
something else and you're growing weed
you're gonna have free coin free corn
free soybeans free tomatoes all year
because you guys teamed up and helped
each other out then you got some new
smoking buddies things should work unity
is the way to do it you guys now when it
does come to treating outdoors for our
pests and preventing for pests my
favorite and most recommended method
would be the use of predator insects i
personally am not i said this before i'm
not experienced and well-versed in
outdoor growing i've done a little bit
of greenhouse growing i've done some
help in outdoor farms but i've never
been in charge of an outdoor grow to the
best of my knowledge from what i've seen
i think that predator bugs would be the
most useful uh avenue and mode of attack
i personally maybe i'm a big old hippie
i don't want to go spray a bunch of
stuff outside
not only am i going to spray the plants
i'm intending to spray but also possibly
i may over spray and spray the crop next
door and that will result in my friends
my neighbors having a pesticide exposure
they were not looking for if they're
growing if i'm growing one product and
they're growing another and i spray it
over here maybe the product i'm spraying
is not allowed to be sprayed on their
product maybe the product they're
spraying isn't allowed on my product and
now we're going to contaminate each
other's product and it has to be
destroyed and we lose our product for
the year so my favorite option would be
the predator bugs also when you spray
stuff what else are you destroying
you're not just hitting your plants
you're hitting the soil you're hitting
everything around then if any wildlife
passes through you're getting that
wildlife also which we may want to keep
the wildlife away but you should have
built a fence or whatever for that we
don't need to get animals bunnies [ __ ]
like that sick let's talk about the
bunnies and the chickens let's learn to
use those sort of things to our
advantage the chickens are around eating
all the small jumping critters i don't
know what the bunnies do like i said i'm
not a farm guy but let's learn to use
our natural uh buddies the chickens and
things like that to our advantage to
help take care of that grill maybe let
some chickens out there maybe one of
your farmer friends already has a bunch
of chickens next door maybe bring them
chickens through your crops to eat all
those grasshoppers that are trying to
take over like i'm saying if we use our
resources and team up together we could
definitely make things better this
applies
side rant hippie talk i told you i'm hi
this applies to just about everything in
life if we talk to the people around us
and say what's your goal what are we
trying to do instead of just doing it
all on our own and trying to [ __ ] do
everything maybe the person next to us
has a goal that lines up with ours and
we can help each other out and we can
all get there together and not leave
people behind not [ __ ] fail because
we didn't ask for help this works with
everything in life team up with the
people around you see who's got similar
goals see who has similar things in mind
let's work together and get each other
where we want to be that way nobody
struggles it's all a community the
community can be a community again all
the isolation all the quarantine that's
coming to an end let's be friends let's
be community again let's get together
try to love one another and feel all
right you guys i'm telling you that jack
tripper is some good [ __ ] now let me uh
segue into i wrote down protect the land
it sounds like hippie [ __ ] but it is all
of our responsibility that land is yours
ah maybe that portion of land is your
land this land is my land but guess what
for now in the future you're gonna die
i'm gonna die people are gonna have to
live on that land after us i've got a
child she hopefully one day not too far
too not too [ __ ] soon settle down kid
hopefully she has children one day
hopefully those children have children
we need safe healthy viable land for all
of our children so it's our
responsibility now to make sure that
that land is healthy when our children's
children's children are there to play in
that dirt to grow their food to grow
their ganja in that dirt also protect
the water i know that's just a side rant
but protect the water if you're growing
cannabis it is your responsibility to
protect the land and the water around
your grow think about it like i said
about the land it's not ours forever
that water is moving that water is yours
and that section but it's traveling
downstream and taking all the
destruction the contamination the
pollution
the bad vibes that you're doing to it
it's traveling downstream quit doing
that [ __ ] to the people downstream be a
good person love the water love the land
it will love you back i do believe that
it will take care of you if you love it
back now this does work us into a little
bit of a recap previously i've done an
episode about bud washing somebody asked
me will bud washing help with the
pesticide situation
possibly maybe that depends on what
pesticide was applied to the flower and
what stage how strong there are a lot of
contributing factors here
was it just a surface application is
what i want to call it if you applied
some sort of oil some hippie oil that
just landed on the surface of the leaf
and made that plant undesirable for
attacking pests or maybe a pathogen
if you applied something systemic that
got inside of the plant there is no
washing that out a product like
floramite or avid that's inside of your
plant you can't wash that out it's
moving around it's in the cellular part
of the plant there's no getting rid of
that that butt is going to test positive
for that whatever the main ingredient is
that is it will test positive for that
no matter what you do even with a bud
wash so bud washing will take off your
powdery mildew your bug poop it may take
off some of your lighter uh surface
sprayed type products but your systemic
stuff is inside of that plant and you
cannot get rid of it so bud washing may
help with some things but it's not going
to get rid of every pesticide that you
used now one more thing to talk about
when it comes to protecting our outdoor
grows and taking care of our neighbors
is pollen i see a lot of people growing
outdoors in the city in in the country
on farmland in urban areas
be very careful with your male plants if
you've got a male plant outside and it
starts to drop pollen the wind will take
that pollen for miles it can go a long
way depending on what's in the way if
you're in the city if you've got a big
city i've got buildings and houses and
trees and [ __ ] here that may block some
of that pollen from getting places but
if you're in a flat landed area with not
a lot of [ __ ] that pollen is going to
travel and it could go quite a ways it
could go very far there's there are
stories of pollen traveling miles i
don't know how true or real that is but
there are legends and stories of pollen
moving for miles so it can go aways it
can go quite a distance at least a
quarter mile so be very careful if
you're growing outdoors pay very close
attention to your plants look for males
get rid of those males very early if
you're going to do any breeding outdoors
be very careful really consider how far
that pollen will travel do you have
neighbors that are growing hemp or
cannabis you may mess up their entire
crop also if they're out there growing
hemp or cannabis and they miss their
males they're going to mess up your crop
too so be very careful learn how to
identify males it is best practice in my
opinion to put tested plants outdoors so
we don't put boys out there i understand
a lot of people are just plopping
thousands of seeds and hoping to find
the boys be very careful with that be
very diligent with your mail search
please please don't ruin other people's
crops with your stray pollen alright
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy let me know
what you think of these short episodes
i've been doing shorter episodes with uh
i'm trying to do a little less rambling
in the show of course i did smoke some
good [ __ ] today they got me talkative
but let me know what you think about
these short episodes maybe i'll keep
doing the shorties maybe i'll start
making them longer again let me know
what you think i do appreciate the
feedback also don't forget to like and
subscribe to the videos click like click
subscribe that way every time i put out
an episode you do get a notification and
you never miss an episode of the grow
from your heart podcast don't forget to
check out the website at
iriegenetics.com
all things irie genetics all things grow
from your heart podcast are right there
on the website if you need a seed vendor
if you need a merch link if you're
looking for the discord server it is all
right there on iregenetics.com
give it a visit check it out tap in is
what i think all the cool kids say all
right that is all i've got for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
little lincoln and until next time take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]