[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode we're going to talk about
my new strain called the machine before
we get to that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to a few of the great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to jessica k let's send a
thank you shout out and a fist bump to
frugal rock and freak fish let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
brian p and double d i want to send a
big thank you shout out to the dad hayes
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to the new old guy let's send
a thank you shout out to blaise
mcconnell let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to rasufa i want to
send a special thank you to my buddy
captain mojo let's send a big thank you
shout out to sacred tree organic farms
then let's wrap it all up with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy trikeman
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and he would like to
learn how to do so all you have to do is
visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends this is the part of the show
where i remind you about the black
friday sale on the irie genetics merch
store that's right if you're looking for
fresh t-shirts maybe you need a grinder
a tray maybe a coffee mug
maybe a mood mat those things are now
available on the irie genetics merch
store all you have to do is go to the
irie genetics website click on the merge
tab that will take you right to the
store when you are checking out use
coupon code gfyh25
that will save you 25 off everything in
the store that sale does start on the
25th and that will end november 30th
once again the coupon code is gfyh25
all right at the top of the show i did
say that we were going to talk about my
new strain called the machine i do have
a great email here from our friend marco
s gondolas big shout out to my buddy
marco escondolas ryrie rocco the
question goes hey ross to jeff i'm sure
you get a lot of requests for podcasts
dedicated to your seed varieties but i
thought i would ask a few specific
questions to help spur your thoughts
this was a perfectly timed email because
i am going to release the machine and
the saka souffle both on black friday
those will be part of the black friday
sale um he does ask about soccer souffle
and the machine this episode is going to
be focused on the machine so i'm going
to skip right to that question it says
the machine uh what is kem de la chem
and which breeder that's a very good
question there is more to this but i
kind of wanted to uh focus on those two
strains for the next two episodes this
episode will be the machine the next
episode obviously will be the soccer
souffle
let's talk a little bit about those so i
do have a bunch of notes here about the
machine let me cut the rambling and jump
right into it the machine if you've been
following my social media you have been
seeing the or my discord even you've
been seeing a lot of posts about the
machine the machine has been um in
testing and it has been showing great
amazing impressive results a lot of the
people testing it have uh harvested
their test crops they're now smoking it
i've actually tasted and smoked some
concentrates made from a test run of the
machine we have all decided that it is
impressive smoke so
i said i wasn't going to ramble but i'm
doing that so let's jump into my report
about a strain called the machine the
parents of the machine obviously marco
escondolas asked if uh let me see there
was a specific question uh which kem de
la chem is it the parents of the machine
are chem daily chem cross to arise uh to
the best of my knowledge the chem de la
chem came from top dog genetics and that
is where i believe this one came from uh
this was given to me as a clone by a
friend who sprouted the seed big shout
out to my friend you know who you are
but this clone really stood out in my
garden we'll talk about that more in a
little bit but this is the kem de la kim
kim daily kim was ah chem d to i-95 or
it is chemdai 95 i don't guess it
changed that is the cam de la chem chem
d to i-95 i love it because
it just stinks it's got such good stink
to it that chem daily kim brings a that
old-school skunky with the new school
diesel funk with that really crazy chem
flavor and the buzz to it is beautiful
and it grows like a savage and it's very
photogenic that's something else i
should talk about which did transfer
into the machine all right so that's the
the chem daily chem which was the female
plant used in this cross that is the
mother plant that got pollinated on the
male side we do have the arise also
known as king solomon my king solomon is
a um
a beautiful specimen of a male i was
going to say a stud is the word that
left my brain there a stud of a male
plant of a an arise cut it's just an
arise male that i have named king
solomon he's just got his own specific
name because he has such a stud
all of the female the rise plants get
labeled a rise and then a number arise
f2 number two or rise f1 number four
things like that sit around in the
garden but the arise male he has simply
named king solomon so the king solomon
arise is golden goat and daybreaker that
was a golden goat female pollinated by a
daybreaker male
my arise is fairly well known there's a
lot of info on the internet a lot of
pictures it is well known for producing
uh very high thc the offspring come out
with very high thc almost anything i
pollinate with that king solomon will
come out with extreme potency almost
like panic attack potency almost like
freak you out psychedelic almost type
potency it's really i call it the fixer
plant king solomon likes to fix and
improve everything also it's known for
making plants grow with what we call
hyper vigor it makes them grow very very
quickly they get big plants that root
quite quite well
that is king solomon that is a rise all
right we know the parents now let's talk
a little bit about how the parents grow
and then we'll segue into how the cross
itself grows uh the chem daily chem it
gets a little bit tall and kind of lanky
but it turns into what i call just
spears of nasty dank it's just long
thick buds with beautiful colors
beautiful aromas lots of trichomes and
it just smells
nasty delicious if it wasn't cannabis
you would make it go far away if it
smelled like that anything else that
smelled like that you would put it in
two or three bags and seal it up and get
rid of it maybe burn it with fire maybe
destroy it but since it's cannabis it is
such a tremendously uh desirable smell i
love it i can't get enough it's like ooh
that stinks i want to smell it again oh
that stinks so bad i want to smell it
again and when you smoke it people
around you they go damn that weed stinks
can i get an eighth like they want some
of it immediately because it smells so
good so that is the chem de la chem gets
a little bit tall kind of lanky
but just [ __ ] gassy and delicious
then the arise i mentioned that one
hyper vigor hyper potency super fast
grow fast growing plant so that's what
we're going to talk about about the
parents now why did i want to make this
cross because i love that kem de la chem
skunk gassy funk i don't have enough of
that in my lineup it's something i'm
really uh it feels like we go in circles
with the flavors of cannabis that are
desired for a while there uh it was
nothing but skunk and then it turned
into diesel and then it turned into uh
kush was popular in the denver area and
then everybody wanted chem and then uh
then everybody wanted garlic and then
everybody wanted candy oh then cookies
was popular and then garlic came around
and now it's all the uh
the dessert strains and the the fruity
flavored candy dessert stuff is what's
popular now like if you got a fruit
flavor and a dessert in your name like
watermelon gelato or something that
shit's what everybody wants right now so
i feel like my terp wheel is coming back
around to liking that skunky diesely
stuff that i used to like uh probably
around uh 98 99 early 2000's that's what
was real popular so i'm coming back
around to liking that i wanted more of
that in my lineup i'm trying not to
ramble too much we're gonna get me back
on track uh so i really love the flavors
and aromas of the camdella kim also i
really i like jj as a breeder and that's
where this cross came from so i wanted
to do some breeding with some of his
stuff just uh you gotta gotta breed with
the people work with the people that you
uh respect and uh appreciate so that's
mostly why i made it and i knew that um
that growth that comes from the arise
and the potency from the arise with that
skunky funkiness it's just like putting
uh two supermodels in a room together
knowing that i'm just going to make a
super super model i knew it was going to
work well so that's basically why i made
the cross as a breeder as a grower as a
smoker i felt like all the right
ingredients were there if i put those
together it was going to work very well
and i feel like we did reach our goal
we'll talk more about that in the future
now let's talk about why i named this
cross the machine a lot of it came from
excuse me a lot of it came from the
flavors and aromas that come from this
finished plant it's got chemicals and
greasy smells and funky stuff kind of
machine shop sort of smells but also i
named it the machine in honor of
bert kreischer if you know me at all you
know that i'm a huge comedy nerd i love
going to comedy shows i love watching
comedy shows i listen to podcasts all
day constantly when i work i'm a huge
fan of laughter one of the people that
makes me laugh the most is [ __ ]
brent chrysler that dude will make you
laugh you're right make me laugh my ass
off i could be working hard i could be
in a funky mood it could be early in the
morning and burnt chrysler will say
something ridiculous on a podcast and i
will laugh until i have to go take a
piss so i had to make a a strain named
after my friend burke kirschner just
because i felt like it was appropriate
so it is named after bert kirschner on
i'm trolling his name it is bert
kreisher ladies and gentlemen the strain
is named after bert kreischer i've been
naming strains after grateful dead songs
after reggae artists after uh mystical
things and motivational things and i
love comedy and i love laughter so i
decided it was time to name a strain
after one of my favorite comedians so
bert kreischer got a strain named after
him the machine comes from a long story
that bert tells in one of his specials
and it is about how i don't want to ruin
his joke but if you haven't heard it by
now i don't know where you have been uh
bert crisher uh learns russian in
college he doesn't learn russian at all
but he gets to go on a free trip to
russia he becomes involved in the
russian mafia and he tells them that he
is the machine and it's a hit so that is
where it comes from it comes from the i
am the machine joke from brent kirschner
that is where the name comes from i've
rambled for a long time about that let's
talk about the actual strain big shout
out to burke crusher by the way that
dude has made me laugh a lot um the
flowering time so we've talked about the
cross we've talked about the parents a
lot of people are going to want to know
the flowering time of this strain let's
get back into grower mode here the
flowering time of the machine most
phenotypes will finish within 63 to 70
days some of them maybe let them go
about 72 days those super chem heavy
gassy stanky ones maybe 72 days but 60
to 70 days is the prime zone about 63 65
days is where most of the phenotypes are
going to be finished aromas and flavors
i've talked about this a little bit this
is part of why i got the name the
machine there are chemical flavors there
are chemical smells there are gassy
smells sometimes there's a hint of like
lemon fuel but it's mostly chemicals
gassy funky dirtiness
there's hints of coffee
some lower notes in there but a lot of
chemically
machine shop greasy kind of smells it's
really kind of overwhelming honestly
sometimes some phenotypes it'll make
your eyes kind of itchy kind of burning
when you're trimming it
let's talk about growth shapes and
structures a lot of people growing this
are going to want to know what to expect
most of the phenotypes are going to make
long branches there are what i call the
chem and the kush phenotypes which are
usually pretty identifiable if you've
grown any chem you know that it kind of
stays a little bit tighter it makes
those long spear type nuggets if you've
grown kush you know it makes kind of
more like popcorn balls and kind of
stretchier plants so let's talk a little
bit about that the chem it is spears and
tighter nodes and earlier in flower it's
got a nasty berries sort of a smell it's
like dirty funky smells like rotten
putrid stuff and berries at the same
time which later turns into a skunky
gassy kind of a thing when you dry it
and cure it that is the chem ah the chem
dominant phenotype that one in my
opinion it smells like the old school
original chem 91 so that is the the chem
dominant phenotype there is a cush
dominant phenotype like i said before
it's got longer branches if you've ever
grown kush you know that some of the
older old-school og kush just it just
gets real branchy and then when you
flower it all those branches kind of
fill in with big popcorn ball nugs and
the top makes a big glory bud that's
kind of what the kush dominant phenotype
does the kush phenotype will be earthy
and
just earthy and dirtier in aromas it's
going to be not as berries not as gassy
more earthy you're going to get an
earthy dirty thing i keep saying earthy
i hope i've made that point clear that
one is going to be more chill more
indica dominant buzz more put you in the
couch more knock you out that one's got
big fat whiter leaves you will notice
that phenotype
the chem is gassier and nasty and also i
wrote down a head killer the chem
dominant phenotype the buzz will make
you forget where you were and what
you're doing while you were doing it
you'll be walking to the fridge to get a
drink and you'll forget that you needed
a drink until you realize you're so
thirsty that your mouth is stuck to your
face
most of these phenotypes come out
distinctly chem or distinctly cush and
it is very noticeable very few of them
show much of the golden goat trait other
than the the fast growth and the high
potency i think a lot of that
is attributed to by the golden goat so
you're getting the
aromas and flavors of the cushion chem
and the speed of the growth and that
high potency is kicking in from that
tropical part of the sativa that's where
i think that comes in but you're going
to find very heavy kush phenotypes and
very heavy chem phenotypes and then
things right in the middle so you'll be
able to find something that's got the
amount of couch lock you want the amount
of head buzz you like and then that
right in the middle beautiful buzz that
i really enjoy that kind of sits you
down and makes you think all you can do
is just sit there and ponder life for a
little bit or you end up staring at a
painting and seeing a totally different
painting in that painting that you've
never seen before that's the kind of
herb that this is here you got the gassy
the chemi the cushy and the potency of
that tropical stuff now within these
ranges of cush and chem i do find what i
believe to be three
not distinct phenotypes but basically
categories of phenotypes there are
probably uh several phenotypes that will
pop up this is an f1 hybrid i do enjoy
the variation but there are three
categories of phenotypes that i have
distinctly identified let's talk about
those three categories there is what i
call the pinecone category which uh that
one is the kush og kush type of category
it's gonna smell more musty more earthy
you're gonna get your coffee or
chocolate your indica dominant
phenotypes are going to be that one it's
going to be more pine cone size and
shape buds
more jaggedy buds they're going to be
your pine cone size and shape buds all
over the plant not as big long spears i
only say that because there is another
phenotype called the spear which we'll
talk about in a minute but these pine
cone shaped buds are going to be the
gassy musty flavors and aromas your
cushy type varieties uh like i said a
moment ago your bigger leaf varieties
these are going to be what i call the
pine cone phenotype that is going to be
og kush dominant then there is what i
call the foxtail phenotype there are
some phenotypes within this line that
just simply produce foxtails that comes
from the chem d and the genetics we
don't see that a lot pop up in the chem
but things that are made with the chem
do make that trait we see that in the
gmo i've seen it in some other chem
crosses that is not your fault possibly
not your fault that very well could be
from the genetics if you get minimal fox
tailing it's not crazy we just see some
bulbous uh calyxes little extra bulbous
uh what do we want to call them brax
they swell a little bit more they stack
up a little bit harder than you're used
to that is just a trait from the chem
you're not doing anything wrong then
there is another very distinct maybe a
phenotype maybe a category of phenotypes
which i call the spears these are the
stinky chem dominant phenotypes they're
just long spears of bud they get a
silvery sort of a tint to them uh maybe
a purple hue with silver trichomes up
and down them they look velvety they are
beautiful plants they stink like skunk
and gas and chemicals those are the
three distinct phenotypes the pine cone
is the gassy one uh the spears is that
chem dominant one the foxtails is very
potent and seems to kind of be the blend
you got that chem in there and then it's
got that uh it's got the chem from the
structure it's got that cushy flavor and
aroma beautiful blend of both so if
you're looking for more of a head buzz
you want the one with the long
spear buds and the longer leaves if you
want to sit down on your ass and be
knocked out get that fat leaf one if
you're looking for that beautiful blend
and with all the beautiful terps you
might want that fox tail phenotype now
if you're looking at my social media and
watching the photos you'll see that zoso
j got one of the plants that i may
actually consider that fox tailey
phenotype it's not extreme foxtails but
you'll see what i mean by the bulbous
calyxes the swollen bracks all over it's
a beautiful plant but it did do a little
fox tailing that was not zozo jay's
fault that is simply attributed to the
genetics then if you look at a lot of
the plants that mobius mobius grows on
instagram
he got the chem and the kush dominant
phenotypes and posted a lot of pictures
of both of them uh the one with no
leaves that is the kush dominant
phenotype and the one with a lot of
leaves that is more chem dominant i can
tell by looking i can almost imagine and
predict the aromas of the two phenotypes
i saw from mobius just by looking at the
photos all right i'm going to check out
my notes see where we are here all right
now we're to the part of the notes where
it says tips and tricks and details this
is where we're going to give the breeder
nuances the breeder tips and tricks on
how to maximize the potential of the
machine
um this one is a very fast vegging plant
a lot of my plants grow very fast all
the way through their life this one
grows very very quickly and veg however
it does slow down when you flip it into
flower
that is quite the opposite of a lot of
plants they usually do go a lot faster
this one will kind of slow down so you
don't have to worry you do have to worry
about the stretch but it is not as
extreme it will probably
double in size by the time you were done
flowering so if you've got a six foot of
flowering space flower it at three feet
of course allow for light space and
whatnot but you understand what i'm
saying
your three foot tall plant will be six
feet tall by the time it's done if it's
two feet tall expect four feet by the
time your plant finishes a lot of the
test growers did report that these
plants do take a lot of nutrients they
will suck up a lot of nitrogen and veg
because they do grow quite quickly and
they do continue to eat a lot of
nutrients throughout the flowering phase
so feed these plants heavy do pay very
close attention to your plants if they
show you any signs of deficiency or
signs of burn adjust accordingly but we
do have reports that they eat a lot so i
can warn you to feed them heavy from the
beginning also myself and a lot of test
growers notice that these plants do tend
to like it a little bit drier you don't
need to water these plants as frequently
as heavily you can let them get a little
bit drier which is often the case with
most cush dominant varietals things from
the cush line
the og cushes the old kush stuff the
tahoe the sfv
that stuff does better when you let it
dry out you're more likely to drown a
kush plant than you are to let it dry so
if you've got a
if you've got a cush dominant phenotype
those plants will like much drier
conditions as you lean more toward the
chem dominant phenotypes they may want a
little bit more but we did notice that
they do tend to like it a little bit
drier witch if you're growing a lot of
og kush stuff that is a trait that the
og kush it's very common across the
entire kush family alright so it does
also this is also a trait that is very
common across the kush family these
plants will eat a lot of cow mag if you
feed them cow mag you'll see the leaves
give you big fat serrations the leaves
will get bold and strong don't overdo it
but they do like cal mag they will get
calmag
calcium deficient
in mid flour if you don't feed them
enough calcium i know i say calmag all
the time together usually they're sold
in the same bottle i try to keep it easy
for everybody they're going to get
calcium deficient as the one that you're
going to see i've also learned that
feeding kush and chem plants kelp
products or kelp really do increase the
potency and that stanky aroma that
skunky gassy cushy earthy [ __ ] that is
really enhanced in my opinion in my
experience by feeding a good kelp
product in flowers so if you can add
some kelp products that will really add
to your stinkiness now let's talk a
little bit about the growth of these
plants i did mention that the chem de la
chem does like to get tall it likes to
grow long branches the arise does like
to make big tall fast growing plants so
i do recommend trellising or tomato
cages or some sort of supports for these
plants these plants will trellis
very well they pop and twist well they
spread out very well when you spread
them and bend them it just makes more
shoots and those grow up as well i do
recommend supports early i would trellis
them out in veg have that trellis all
set up or have your tomato cages or your
sticks ready because when those buds
start setting in they're going to get
top heavy you're going to fill up big
spears of buds they're going to start
toppling over you're going to get sticky
and stinky it's going to be a pain in
the ass if you don't start getting them
supported ahead talking about supporting
our plants these plants really bulk up
in the last two weeks of flower myself
and all of the test growers really
mentioned and really noticed that these
plants beef up and bulk up the last two
weeks of flower that's why i recommend
you let them go the 70 maybe 72 days the
first time you grow them let them go and
see what they do that last 10 14 days
they really might expand bulk up beef up
on you you would hate to cut down at
week nine and week ten they really
exploded and you wasted some growth on
there wasted some weight that really
could have helped you out so let them
finish they really bulk up in the last
two weeks we did notice that temperature
swings really make these plants colorful
these plants acted really really well to
cold temperatures during the night we
had some really drastic temperature
swings here in colorado one of my test
places was getting really hot during the
day and really cold at night some of the
plants we'll talk about that one later
some of the plants did not like the cold
at all the the machine really seemed to
run well in the cold at night it really
brought out the colors made the buds
nice and dense
i really think it reacted responded very
well to those cold night temperatures
toward the end of flower
the machine is now what i would call the
gassiest and stankiest strain in my
lineup that is now available
it compares very closely in stank and
aroma to the double dose and also it
would compete with the dark hollow but
it is now what i would call the gassiest
in my lineup that that camera roma that
chem stank you just can't beat it it's
got it just so skunky stinky
it is gross in a delicious way i said
that earlier it's like you smell it and
you're like
that's gross can i smell it again just
something disgustingly pleasing about it
um that being said
i think it is best to have carbon
filters it is i would recommend and over
recommend and highly suggest again that
you've got carbon filters and extra odor
control i said before when you trim this
one when i trim this one i don't trim a
lot of plants i grow little tiny plants
we did test runs when we would crack
open these plants to trim them my eyes
would get like just it would i'd feel
like there was chemicals in my eyes they
would burn and they would itch it was
almost like i was allergic to it in a
good way uh when you crack open a bag it
makes my eyes itch like it's almost like
a uh it's like a pavlov effect a
pavlonian pavlovian how do you whatever
pavlov shout out to that dude and his
dogs pavlovian i think that's how you
say it it's that sort of effect when i
would open up the jar my eyes would itch
and burn like it does when i smoke it
and i'm not saying itch and burn in a
bad way but it would get my eyes my eyes
would go heavy and droopy and i think
the smell would trigger my body and my
eyes would just go oh yeah you're gonna
get that nice head buzz pretty soon here
but just trimming it made my eyes itch
and burn it is super gassy super stinky
um it will be when you're trimming it
will be some of the most pungent uh
stankiest offensive herb you ever
experience offensive is the word i was
looking for one good thing to mention
these plants are very resistant to mold
and mites people grew this one outdoors
it did not get the mildew that a lot of
people experienced i have a good friend
who got they got some problematic bugs
during their grow and they said that
this plant was basically left alone by
some of their mites so a lot of the
testers did report that these plants
were resistant to mildew and to bugs we
had a lot of people grow these outdoors
nobody uh reported any powdery mildew
nobody reported any bud rot also i did
have a friend who grew this in a room
with mites they did not get mites on
this plant so it is bug resistant that
is always a good thing so we have
learned that these plants are very
resistant to bugs very resistant to
pathogens and mold so knowing that these
plants are resistant to pathogens
resistant to bugs and they also grow
super quickly they smell really good
they're super photogenic they come out
with extremely high potency they
tolerate a lot of problems i think that
these plants would be great for beginner
growers the only thing i would really
worry about is over watering but for
people who may not be able to get to the
grow as often for people who aren't in
there all day for people who may forget
to water these may be great plants uh
like i said other than that uh the
opportunity to over water these plants
and the idea that they don't like as
much water these are great plants for
beginner growers now let's talk a little
bit about the smoke i've gotten to smoke
a few of the flowers from a couple of
different grows
something that i noticed is this cushy
chemi chemical gassy aroma when i hit it
it just feels like chemicals and
cottonmouth coat my tongue and when i
exhale that flavor and aroma just
lingers and my eyes get heavy right away
and i can't get that smell off of my
hands i can wash my hands two or three
times and if you smoke a joint if you
break up a joint and smoke a joint of
this weed your fingers will smell like
it for the rest of the weekend this was
also super thick smoke i smoked two two
batches of flowers that made me say that
reminds me of back in the day when we
used to say we got the chronic and the
smoke expands in your lungs this weed
gave me that lung expandy feeling that i
haven't had in a little bit
i smoke a lot of flowers i smoke a lot
of dabs and there's just something in
the lungs that i haven't felt in a long
time and i enjoyed it reminded me like i
said of that old school and we used to
call it the chronic it would expand in
your lungs and you would smoke it it
kind of reminded me of that feeling i
did have a friend in denver make some
concentrates i've got a friend they are
two friends they're a lovely couple big
shout out they do not want their names
set on the show they made that clear uh
they are a couple they grow and make
concentrates in denver they made some
concentrates of the machine i tried to
smoke some before a podcast one night
and i do not remember writing recording
editing doing that show it was all a
blur uh that concentrates from the
machine it is like the thing from the
guys that men in black have they go
blink blink and then your whole memory
is gone you don't know what happened
that is what this stuff is like i just
emptied my brain i enjoyed it uh but if
you've got something to do maybe if you
got something to do you don't want to do
this would be the perfect smoke for that
because it made me uh it just made my
brain numb i forgot everything also
after that
when i got done recording while i was
editing i ate everything it seems like
when i smoked the machine i get extreme
munchies so if you are if you're a
cancer patient or if you've got a
medicine or something that is stopping
you from eating if you need an increased
appetite the machine may be a great
medical strain for you it may help you
out may increase that appetite may help
you put some weight on uh help you build
bulk up for the winter here uh where am
i i'm looking for my uh my notes here uh
overall this was an easy to grow strain
and top quality um you can grow this one
if you're a beginner grower as long as
you don't over water this plant you can
grow this and it looks like you grew
something that should have been super
challenging to grow this is an easy
plant to grow that will put out
connoisseur smoke as a note that i wrote
down
it handles over feeding it'll handle
under feeding but you've got to pay
attention to it it'll come out better if
you feed it properly every plant will it
handles temp swings well it is super
easy to trim
big fat bag of peel the nugs the dried
and cured nugs look beautiful
big fat pine cones big long spears
beautiful dark colors uh beautiful
layers of trichomes
super frosty gross aromas nice dense
nugs lots of dense dense nuggets come
out of these crosses i wrote down again
easy for beginners low maintenance if
you time it right the biggest issue will
be height and stank and something to
look out for will be over watering you
do have to time it correctly flower
early if you were limited on space
flower early because this one's going to
double in height on you it's going to
veg very very quickly then it's going to
flower and it will double in height so
make sure you are prepared for that uh
it's great plants for quick runs because
it veges so quickly and is ready to flip
early most of the time you may uh you
may be vegging for four to six weeks you
may want to cut that down and just plan
on the four because they're going to go
so quickly it may save you a couple of
weeks which is always a good thing in a
grow that gets more plants more grows
per year
it doesn't require a lot of attention
get it supported pull a few leaves feed
the [ __ ] out of it and i wrote down she
will bang so it's a pretty easy plant to
grow if you flip it early don't get it
too tall if you do get her too tall you
could pop her twister bender
tie her down do what you need to do she
takes very well to that sort of stuff
she does recover very quickly and very
well from popping topping and abuse i
think the machine is a great plant for
quick runs because she veges super
quickly she flowers in about nine or ten
weeks which is great for top quality
product i'm sure you can find a
phenotype that is done in nine weeks it
will suit your purposes all right i do
have one more detail before i start
wrapping up this show if i were going to
grow a run of the machine right now with
what i know about her uh with the
experience i've got with this plant the
way that i would do it is i would
probably run so let me preface by saying
a lot of people are probably growing in
a five by five tent or something similar
uh maybe a small room a lot of us don't
have major uh high ceilings uh we've got
a little bit of space to work with in a
five by five tent or something similar
this is probably what i would do i would
probably do
nine three gallon pots and i would veg
them up until they are about 12 to 18
inches tall then i would flour them if
you want to spread them out if you want
to trellis them i would top them one
time early about 10 to 12 inches tall as
soon as they start branching take a top
out of them then put the trellis net
down and spread them out let that go for
maybe a week because they're going to
veg quickly into that trellis then flip
them because they're going to grow tall
and they're going to fill that area so
that's the way i would do it three
nine three gallon pots veg them until
they're about 12 to 18 inches tall then
flip them and they will fill your space
or veg them till they're about 10 or 12
inches tall top them one time spread
them out with the trellis let them fill
that space then flip them i think you'll
be satisfied with that maybe i would
consider four seven gallon pots in a
five by five space but as quickly as
they veg that may get out of control uh
they may outgrow your space more quickly
than you were prepared for but if i
wanted to run a quick crop of these
plants the way that i would do it again
would be nine three gallon pots in a
five by five veg them until they're
about 12 to 18 inches tall then flour
them let them flower for uh nine to ten
weeks maybe 72 days at the most chop
them dry them cure them you've got a
quick crop of top shelf product in my
opinion you guys i wasn't sure if i was
going to say this but i think i enjoy
the machine so much that it may become
my new concert smoke this may replace
the grateful dog the grateful dog has
been my go-to choice for concert weed
this may replace that we'll talk about
the grateful dog in the future all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts i want to
thank you once again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you made it this far it
is time for me to announce that the
machine and soccer souffle will be
available at seeds herenow.com on the
black friday sale that does start
november 25th they will drop on november
25th so make sure you check that out
once again that is seeds here now.com on
november 25th for soccer souffle and the
machine there will be a special sale
running if you buy both packs you will
get a free 10 pack of unreleased irie
genetics what will it be who knows i'll
label the pack so that i know what it is
i can tell you in the future but at this
time it will be an unreleased pack with
a secret code on it so you don't even
know what it is
all right seeds here now.com on november
25th all right uh where was i i was
gonna wrap it up right uh make sure you
check out the website at
iriegenetics.com there will be a link to
all of the seed vendors there's a link
to seeds herenow.com there's a link to
the discord of course there's a link to
the patreon if you've got any other
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know i'd love to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy send
me your questions corrections comments
or concerns i do love the community
interaction all right that is all i've
got for this episode you know i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a big shout out
to my buddy mobius grows and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]