[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff and this is episode
693 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to feature my
new strain called saka souffle before i
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend kes burton
let's send a big thank you shout out in
a fist bump to redbeard and noah n let's
send a big thank you shout out to
brendan gross and paparoni let's send a
big fist bump to just a smokin i want to
send a special thank you shout out to my
friend north north terps let's send a
big thank you shout out to mr mean green
i want to send a fist bump to guido 7
and brian p then let's wrap it all up
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to dz from
detroit
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends by the time this episode comes
out the black friday sale will be live
if you need a new irie genetics t-shirt
maybe a tray maybe a grinder maybe a
coffee cup those things will be
available on the website simply click on
the web store that will take you right
to the web store where you can get the
merchandise when you check out use
coupon code gfyh25
that will save you 25 off everything in
the store also saka souffle and the
machine will be dropping at most vendors
on black friday so check out the vendor
list on the website and make sure you're
ready for black friday saka souffle and
the machine all right i don't want to
ramble too much here at the beginning of
the show
may already be too late for that let's
talk about saka souffle i like to start
my strain features by talking about the
parents that only makes sense the
parents of saka souffle are biscotti and
arise it is a female biscotti plant and
then a rise male
in this episode and every episode when i
talk about my arise mail uh i will say
arise and king solomon uh
interchangeably they will mean the same
thing king solomon is a specially
selected arise plan he's just an arise
f1 male uh he's my favorite male in my
lineup he's one of the best male plants
i've ever used and work with uh worked
with i have named him king solomon if
you read about king solomon you may
understand why i chose that name that's
not important but the important part is
knowing that arise and king solomon are
the same thing when i say male arise and
king solomon same dude same guy he's got
two names i call him sully i call him
saul but that's king solomon or just
solomon that's the arise male that's who
i'm talking about and another note when
i list genetics
i always list ladies first so when you
hear me say biscotti to arise or
whatever to whatever
girl scout cookies to grateful dog or
banana kush to cherry widow
i'm always listing always listing ladies
first and the one that i say second is
the pollen donor and i'm saying pollen
donor at this time because sometimes uh
that is a reversed cross and it is a
feminized plant it was a female that
gave us pollen it wasn't truly a male
but it was the paul and donor so i'm
going to say that it always is the paul
and receiver to the pollen donor first
but the easy way to remember that is
ladies first so when i'm talking about
crosses when i say right now biscotti to
arise i do mean the biscotti was the
lady in this cross
i said i was going to try to not ramble
already too late for that so the cross
is biscotti to arise let's talk about
the biscotti to the best of my research
there were uh uh different differing
results on the internet i saw a couple
of different things to the best of my
research what made the most sense to me
from the
research online the flavors aromas
growth experience with this plant i'm
going to agree that i believe it is
gelato girl scout cookies and south
florida og if you've got any varying
information or better or different
information and you would like to have a
friendly conversation about it if you
come at me like a dick i'm going to
delete your email to be honest with you
if you're cool and calm and collected
and friendly and want to have a
conversation my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com let me
know what you believe the cross is i'm
open to those friendly conversations i
enjoy and appreciate that sort of stuff
let me get back on track here
i really enjoyed the biscotti the
biscotti came from a friend of mine
he grew it from seed he made the
selection he found a great cut i really
liked it he really liked it he gave me a
cut
it smelled so good and the flowers when
i smoked the flowers it made me super
mellow it gave me that uh we can't say
girl scout cookies anymore but uh from
here out girl scout cookies means our
gsc means girl scout cookies it gave me
that gsc buzz
but it grew so much better than the gsc
and it gave me more of an open buzz gsc
or the cookies i'll call it kind of put
me in a bubble it seemed to shut me down
and put me in my own uh my own zone i
was not very social i wanted to grab a
guitar grab a drum uh write something
be creative search the internet scroll
my phone that's what uh gsc or cookies
kind of did to me the biscotti had that
punch to the face from the cookies but
also kind of made me want to be more
social it made me want to talk and
didn't put me in my own
silent bubble so it's better for being
social better for being outdoors and
active and
in the public which i often have to be
over here on a podcast imagine just
being in your bubble here that'd be hard
to do
so i really enjoyed the buzz it didn't
shut me down as much and it seems to
grow better than the original cookies
that seems to be crossed with it but it
had a lot of cookies traits it was like
uh just turbo cookies better cookies and
i enjoy that because i really liked the
cookies back in the day
so uh that is the biscotti it was uh
gelato girl scout cookies south florida
og smelled good really dense flowers
kind of made me mellow but not too
mellow similar to cookies
better grower but a more outgoing social
buzz now let's talk about the arise i
said before that when i talk about king
solomon and arise it is the same plant
it is an f1 arise
that was specially selected and he is
named king solomon so let's talk about
that that is a golden goat female
pollinated by a daybreaker male uh that
golden goat's got that
tropical sweet kind of flavors it grows
with
kind of an indica structure but sativa
traits and it's got a very sativa
dominant head buzz it kind of gets to
your brain it makes your head spin and i
think that golden goat uh mixes in with
everything that i cross from the arise
that really adds to the potency that is
the golden goat doing the potency on the
other side of that cross we've got the
daybreaker
that is chem d and joseph og so you've
got chem and kush flavors and aromas
that plant had big
wide fat leaves that you could camp
under you could live under those leaves
they were so big
uh it had that funky earthy cushy gassy
chemical sort of smell so i brought the
golden goat that sweet tropical to that
gassy cushy thing and that gave us a
rise uh all of those plants grow with
what i call hyper vigor and great
potency so when you cross the rise to
anything that hyper vigor and potency
comes along so that's why i breed almost
everything to king solomon you see
everything crossed to solomon i cross a
lot of stuff to eject the ripper mail
and i do a lot of reversals but solomon
is my most used male so that's why i've
selected solomon for this cross that's
why he was bred to the biscotti let's
talk a little bit about how these plants
grow the original plants the parent
plants that will lead us into a little
bit about how the offspring are expected
to grow
uh the biscotti grows fairly quickly and
it got fairly tall in the garden quite
early i would have to pop it twist it
bend it over manipulate it some way
because it would take off
but that was a good thing because i like
those vigorous
fast growing plants
some of the phenotypes would make long
branches and it would always make
gigantic tops every branch every top on
the plant of the biscotti was just dense
rock hard nuggets with beautiful
colorings it would make pinks i would go
from light greens to pinks and then it
would fade into like burgundies and
stuff like that but the top color would
always just be a big it looked like a
baseball bat no matter how big the plant
was we were just kicking out baseball
bats out of that one
um where was i now
the golden of the arise i mentioned
before the arise it grows with hyper
vigor super quick grower uh it is super
resistant to mold super resistant to
bugs uh it passes on that super potency
trait so that is the arise and the
biscotti why did i make it uh the buds
from the biscotti were great and the
buzz was super nice but
i say that a rise fixes everything there
was really nothing wrong with the
biscotti but if you could have your
favorite thing and make it better just
make it turbocharged everything why not
it's the new world we want everything
stronger faster louder right now
maybe we could do that if we pollinated
it with the rise i know that a rise is
the champ so i hit it with my king
solomon pollen king solomon pollen could
be a tongue twister if you try to say it
too many times
so i crossed those and it made a strain
that i call saka souffle now this gets
us to uh something that a lot of people
have been asking about and a lot of
people also understand
what the hell does saka souffle mean
where did you come up with this name
what is this
if you know me at all if you've been
following me on social media for a while
if you've been watching the podcast if
you know me personally you know that i
am a huge fan of comedy i love laughter
i love stand-up comedy i love comedy
podcasts i love comedy videos i think
that life kind of beats us down all day
and all the if you got a life bar like
in a video game uh when the boss yells
at you you get a couple of damage points
and the cops get behind you and make you
nervous your damage bar starts flashing
and getting all weird uh i think that
comedy and music a lot of it is comedy a
lot of it is music in two different ways
those refill your damage bar your energy
bar your life bar it makes life better
again it's like kissing the boo-boos you
get told some good jokes and you just
feel better it's like uh it's like soup
on a sick day so i really love comedy
i'm rambling about comedy now i could do
that all day i'm a huge fan of stand-up
comedy the last episode i put out was
about the machine that of course was
named after bert kreischer so this saka
souffle was named
kind of after a combination of another
one of my favorite comedians tom segura
also uh larry king so let me tell the
story of how this name came up tom
segura one of my favorite comedians was
on larry king live big up to larry king
rest in peace right yeah rest in peace
larry king um larry king asked tom
segura one of his guilty pleasures and
tom segura innocently answered chocolate
souffle now larry king at the time was
about 132 years old and he squinted and
looked confused and said saka souffle
and it was funny and that is where saka
souffle came from i kind of took that
sound bite and made it a strain name i
became very popular on your mom's house
podcast that is the name of the show
your mom's house podcast that is where
tom segura and christina pozinski uh do
their thing uh shout out to uh both of
them high and tight what up jeans but uh
if you're into a weird uh if you're
broken like me you would enjoy that
podcast weird great humor check him out
but that is where saka souffle came from
that clip became real popular on their
show i watched that show a lot uh
friends and i would just say soccer
souffle when somebody was uh just doing
something outlandish or if there wasn't
the right thing to say at the right time
i just go suck a souffle and it just
fills gaps it was great
so saku souffle became a strain name i
said i wasn't going to ramble too much
on that
i've done that already now let's talk
about growing uh big up to tom segura
also
let's talk about growing some saka
souffle most phenotypes of saku souffle
are going to take between 60 and 70 days
to flower the darker black leaf
phenotype finishes in 63 days there will
be a phenotype that pops up that is kind
of short and kind of squat and it makes
dark dark leaves very easy
you probably aren't messing it up it'll
look like you're having a problem like
you're struggling in your grow that is a
trait of this plant that comes from the
we're not allowed to say girl scout
cookies anymore so now i have to say
cookies or gsc the girl scout cookies
got mad that somebody made a strain
called girl scout cookies now we have to
say gsc
cookies i'll say random things
culturally it's cookies gsc uh well i'll
say those when i'm talking about girl
scout cookies just know that but the
girl scout cookies would turn black back
in the day there was a hashtag on social
media social media i'm not sure what i
said the first time there was a hashtag
on social media that said hashtag black
leaf society and that was because a lot
of the girl scout cookies
the cookies the cookies crosses plants
we're changing black leaf colors uh in
mid to late flower if you see a
phenotype where the pitials are turning
uh really dark purple really quickly and
the leaves fade to black you're probably
not messing it up that is probably the
plant that is just what these plants do
so that black leaf phenotype does finish
at 63 days the lighter colored plants do
take approximately 70 days it kind of
seems like the darker the shorter
finishing and the lighter plants are the
longer finishing so the lighter color it
could be a nutrient thing also but if
you're growing them right and feeding
them properly the lighter colored plants
are going to take a little bit longer
with this cross let's talk about the
aromas and flavors i really really enjoy
the funky gross aromas and flavors that
come from the soccer souffle it starts
off with that peppery cookie dough thing
and i know that sounds weird but imagine
if you took one of those store-bought
logs of cookie dough and just sprinkled
just a hint of black pepper in it and it
warmed it up it's got a warm cookie
dough with pepper sort of a smell and i
really really do enjoy that
it's got pastries uh sugary pastries
maybe some sort of scones or
maybe the bakery aisle at the store or
maybe just a bakery it's got that sort
of smell also there are some phenotypes
that present a cough syrup sort of a
smell and also a bubble gum sort of a
candy flavored sort of a smell
also there's one that mixes that
remember when you were little sometimes
they gave us a pink cough syrup that was
almost good almost gross at the same
time
some of the phenotypes reminded me of
that good gross pink cough syrup so
there's a lot of pastry
peppery candy flavored then there's a
bubble gum and then there's a cough
syrup funky flavor that does appear um
lots of great aromas and flavors but
those are what the flavors i think you
can expect there are more but i'm gonna
stop there i can confuse you and give
you too many descriptors that's a bad
habit of mine so expect cookie dough
pastries cough syrup and some bubble gum
phenotypes i've noticed that the lighter
colors are more prone uh have more
potential for the bubble gum phenotypes
those dark colored plants aren't going
to have the bubble gum in most cases is
what i have noticed now let's talk a
little bit about the growth shape and
structure of these plants
these plants are they make really tight
buds and most of the phenotypes make a
big baseball bat type center bud no
matter how you train it trim it top it
that middle bud with the center stock
that thing likes to grow a big fat
chunky bud you can almost always expect
impressive top coals from these plants
some of the phenotypes only grow a top
cola if you're a screen or a sea of
green type grower the kind of grower
that just puts a bunch of plants like
small plants in one table or one tray
packs them in real tight just wants one
tall branch there's a phenotype
in this line that does do that for you
if you're looking for that one cola i
call it the spear i just makes one big
rock all the way up it is beautiful that
is a good cash crop there's another one
that is more kind of bushy it grows kind
of even and it doesn't get that super
top cola and it grows real even without
topping it it's kind of bushy uh makes
that minora effect and then there's
another one that does the uh it gets
kind of bushy but it doesn't it gets
real tall and the branches get real long
but it doesn't go out real wide it stays
real and real skinny so you got one that
kind of branches out gets bushy doesn't
make a top one that is just tops and
then one that is a top with branches
trying to keep up basically those are
the three dominant phenotypes that i uh
phenotypical categories i'm going to say
categories because you're going to see
differences you're going to see outliers
these are f1s it's an f1 cross you're
going to see variation but that one big
spear is a common phenotype that minora
type branchy one is a very common
phenotype and that one that just gets
tall and lanky with a bunch of chasers
that is a very common phenotype that one
that gets tall and has all the chasers
every bud along the side and along the
bottom will rock up and be silver and
shiny and covered in trichomes even the
bottoms on these plants are amazing that
one that's just a tall spear all the way
down usable harvestable product that one
that's bushy and spreads out that's a
great plant that's kind of like a
classic plant that'll grow very well and
give you everything you're expecting and
looking for that one may change colors
on you a little more quickly the and
it'll get a little bit woody as well if
you got that more branchy spread out
phenotype that's you're going to get
more colors possibly some woodier type
responses from the branches let's talk
more about some specifics uh these
plants are kind of slow growers uh they
a lot of my plants are known for hyper
vigor and they grow very quickly in veg
i've noticed that these don't grow as
quickly in veg but the minute you put
them in flour
they make up for all of the lost time
they just go shebang kapow they take off
these plants have the potential and
opportunity to triple in size from when
you put them in flour so if they're uh
one foot tall when you put the plant in
flower expect it to get up to three feet
tall by the time it is flowering allow
proper light space allow proper sealing
space these plants have the potential to
triple in size i'm going to say that
again triple three times the size from
when you flower that can get out of
control for some growers so be prepared
for that if you're running a scrog net
if you're bending popping twisting that
will help you out if you've got that
tall stretchy fino that makes the
stretchy branches that bad [ __ ] is
going to triple in size before it is
done so be ready for that uh what else
do we have to mention uh the straight
spear that one big cola the bush the
rocks oh the black leaves if you're
getting black leaves i probably said
this already
that is not your fault that is probably
uh just the phenotype from that plant
that even bushier phenotype is great
that thing will put out great product
that smells great it looks beautiful
the node spacing is super tight
it's kind of a it's kind of not the
super easiest plant to grow but the
smoke from that one is my favorite the
bushier phenotype is my favorite to
smoke all right now i'm going to talk
about the buzz that i experience when i
smoke saku souffle this is what i got
from it i feel like saku souffle is the
kind of herb that you could roll up a
big fat joint and smoke it on the way to
work and when you get to work you clock
in and by the time you clock out you
don't even know you just had a long hard
day at work it's like just get [ __ ] done
weed but you don't even know it like
you're so in this tunnel vision thing
but you're still like uppity and peppery
so you could deal with customers if you
got a social job i think it would be
great work weed if you had to go deal
with people deal with the public if
you're not into the public it would be
good herb if you like to smoke and then
go out in public and go do your stuff
this would be great for that because it
gives you that it just gives you a
little bit of a pep but it also gives
you that like um super high kind of
thing sometimes when you get too high
you get too much into your bubble this
one doesn't put you into that little
that little private bubble does it give
you the blinders that they put on the
horses some of the herbie breed will
give you the blinders and give you a
panic attack this one doesn't give you
too much of that but it does put you in
the bubble one thing i did notice was
every time i smoked it it kind of got me
like above and behind my eyes it felt
like my uh like my hat was too tight it
almost felt like like i was wearing a
headband there's already a strain called
headband but it did feel like i had like
my headphones were too tight i kept like
feeling like pressure or something
around my face
i noticed it and i enjoyed it so it gets
me in the eyes it puts me in that bubble
but i'm also still functional which is a
good thing for me because people like to
talk to me people expect me to be
functional and doing [ __ ] so i can't be
too roasted all the time i've noticed
that those uh the phenotypes they get
the purple pedials the long purple
leaves those are going to give you more
of that that tunnel vision sort of a
sort of a buzz sort of a thing now let's
work into that part of the paper where i
always write tips and tricks i've
already mentioned that this plant is a
slow grower but it does explode in
flower i wrote again triple in size some
of the phenotypes of these plants will
triple in size be prepared you've been
forewarned uh where do we go from there
fat dense nugs even the lowers get dense
and frosty if you don't have your
environment dialed in you may want to
pop and twist and bend and top these
plants and create a bunch of smaller bud
sites instead of just one big gigantic
bud side if you lay it on its side
those smaller buds will grow up and you
don't get one big giant dense bat you
get a row of smaller buds if you tip
that big branch on its side it may help
you out with mold issues but you're
going to get big buds so be prepared get
your environment dialed in
these plants some of the phenotypes i
mentioned i may have mentioned that the
bushier phenotypes will get a little bit
woody later in their life pop and twist
them early because you don't want them
to explode some of the woody phenotypes
will get a little bit crunchy uh they're
going to get big they're going to need
some sort of support even those
single bud phenotypes they may enjoy
some support it may help you out if you
just put down a screen and put one bud
per screen or just put one stick per bud
that would help you out the tall
stretchy one is definitely going to need
some sort of supports the light green
phenotypes are more bendy uh they're
easier to work into a trellis into a
canopy they're more pliable once they
start getting a little bit purple they
do get kind of woody they do kind of
snap you'll break off leaves and
branches much more easily so be careful
with those purple phenotypes that it's
not a nutrient deficiency that's not a
problem that is just something in the
genetics that does happen pop and twist
those gently because you don't want
those to explode top them early let them
branch out to prevent that giant cola at
the end
uh purple stems and purple and dark
colors is common i keep saying that but
that is in my notes a lot uh it fades
hard and late blooming looks sad it's
okay it just does that it looks like a
phosphorus or a potassium deficiency
it's just done
sometimes that purple stock finishes up
it's not a nutrient issue what i wrote
down was sometimes the plant itself
looks like it's done before the
trichomes are ripe just let the plant
keep going the trichomes will ripen up
even if those leaves are black and
turning gold and yellow let it keep
going there will be some very beautiful
photo opportunities
there's not a problem it's just done
that plan is entering what is called
senescence it's like dude i've done my
life i'm only supposed to live a year
i'm only supposed to flower for so long
it had its uh its whole goal was to get
pollinated all of its organs to receive
pollen have now receded and dried up
that plant is done it's in senescence
it's over uh it's waiting for its time
to die it's just waiting for you to cut
it down but until you do those trichomes
will keep ripening so let it keep going
don't cut it down too early let it
finish that trade again does come from
the gsc i'm not sure what trait in the
gsc that what line from that came from
what parent but that is a trait from the
gsc anyone who grew the cookies back in
the day we saw it turn different colors
we got it black we got it purple
environmental factors and pushing it
nutrients would change these plants so
many different colors
eventually just realized that when you
dial it in it will change a lot of cool
colors it's not anything we're doing
wrong
don't try to over feed it to correct a
nutrient issue uh that's when you mess
it up it'll start doing uh usually it'll
stack up and make a good butt if you
over feed it it'll do what i call the
spiral staircase you get the main stalk
and then right up that stem you get
a bud here then a butt here and a butt
here and it doesn't fill in like it's
supposed to if you feed it properly
that'll all fill in it'll be one giant
cola that fills up that whole meristem
just be one chunky baseball bat worth of
nuggets where else do i have to go from
there
these plants handle spider mites very
well we had one tester get hit with uh
regular spider mites and these plants
didn't get touched we had another tester
get hit with the worst of all he got the
russets and he said these plants fared
the best in the room i'm not going to
call anybody out for their russets but
good work for recovering from that they
finished the harvest of this plant with
russets and made it to the end that's a
big challenge
all right my final notes on this one
i've got expect big buds so have airflow
and vpd dialed in possibly water less to
reduce
humidity and to prevent issues if you're
watering less you're going to have less
water in the room defoliate that will
reduce transpiration these plants don't
make a lot of leaves they're super easy
to trim i pull off a lot of those big
leaves with the long purple pedials
that'll make less air in the room less
transpiration you won't have as much
water in the room just because of that
these plants
don't really like cold at all they get
uh purple and they stop growing i had
some plants on a cold floor they just
stopped we had another person report
their room got cold they just stopped
don't get them excuse me
don't get them extremely cold basic
diurnal temperature swings will be okay
your five seven maybe 10 degree swings
don't get them cold at night they'll
stop growing they'll turn purple the
buds just turn into these black rocks
they don't do anything they freeze up on
you don't do that they do not like being
over watered and they especially don't
like cold water no plants really do
enjoy the cold water
they're slightly challenging to grow the
problem is
they're supposed to change colors and do
weird [ __ ] and new growers see those
colors and see the differences that
these plants do and they panic and freak
out and try to fix it grow it just like
any other plant and it will work just
like any other plan if you don't [ __ ] it
up and freak it out uh it won't [ __ ] up
and freak out it's supposed to change
colors and do weird [ __ ] that's part of
the plan i'm trying to find my pages in
order there we go uh the next thing is
they like low ph and medium nutrients in
flour too much nitrogen will make it do
the bud spin i talked about that spiral
staircase a moment ago too much nitrogen
will definitely attribute to the spiral
staircase now i did say low ph a lot of
the time i recommend about six two to
six four stick around that six one six
two i've seen these plants grow very
well in low low ph i've seen them go
five eight and thrive uh you'll make the
dark plants really dark really purple uh
low ph and lots of kelp i think will
bring out a lot of stank that yeah stank
no just stink it's stank all right where
am i going from there i've got another
i've got one last page i do apologize
for the throat clearing i'm not even
sure that i'm going to edit that out
because i'm on such a good flow
the best grows were in soil or soilless
mixes this plant didn't seem to like
hydro as much as the soilless mix is
however the hydro guys did kill it but
the soilless and organic eyes were
crushing it if i were going to grow saku
souffle i would probably grow it uh four
seven gallon pots under a thousand watt
light i would veg it until it reached
the scrog net and then i would put it
into flour and for the first two weeks
work it into that scrog net then it'll
take off and keep growing i may put up
another net to support those big buds
but that's probably how i would do it or
i would find that phenotype that shoots
one main cola and i would do in a uh in
a five by five i'd probably do
depending on numbers if you add
unlimited numbers probably go with 16 of
those uh in a five by five veg them
until they're about a foot and a half
tall then flip them and they'll be ready
to go
that's what i would probably do
it looks like there's a lot of space
when they grow because they get a little
bit stretchy but they will fill in if
you don't over feed them uh veggies like
cookies is what i wrote down but it
takes off in bloom
where are we oh do the sea of green find
a good phenotype that makes the big cola
and just cram a bunch of them in if
you're the hydro guy that grows on cubes
do the 4x4 table with like 64 cubes and
veg for like a week this plant would
kill it with that
i don't know that i would recommend
soccer souffle outdoors for a lot of
people unless you've got a good
environment i said it makes giant buds
those giant buds do put you at risk for
problems outdoors late in the season
this year we saw a lot of people with
bud rot with powdery mildew with extreme
damage in the middle of their buds
i fear that this makes such big buds you
would experience those types of problems
so unless you can control that i don't
know that i would recommend this
outdoors
these plants do make a very great calyx
to leaf ratio so they are easy to trim
if you hate trimming and you like big
fat harvest these may be the plants for
you
very very nice bag appeal the buds have
a silvery purple color that comes from
the cookies some of them get very dark
the others are very bright bright green
so you're going to get very good bag
appeal everything will be super frosty
um
the rosin we made raw i can't say we i
watched i supervised i had my hands on
my hips i was smelling a lot going
smells like you're doing a good job
friends of mine made rosin and the rosin
that came out of the press looked like
velvet it had it was silver and glittery
it looked like a silver sheen with
speckles in it looked like they were
mixing metallic paint uh really
beautiful concentrate
the dab tasted like eating oh that
camera just [ __ ] died i gotta finish
it on this camera gotta finish up
quickly uh tasted like eating a buttery
pastry you guys i gotta go quick i don't
want this to end uh smelled like uh
buttery armpits bad armpits or a hippie
girl who works as a pastry chef all
right that's what i've got i'm going to
wrap it up because that camera died i
don't want to lose this episode uh thank
you thank you check out my website
iregenetics.com
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com what do i have here at the
end black friday sale you know how to
get that shout out to my buddy rosinman
until next time take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for me i hope i got all this
on recording happy thanksgiving you guys
i love you
[Music]