[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
and this is episode 694
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
breeding with feminized seeds before i
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend tart and mike
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to ez057
let's send a big thank you shout out to
pro brewer home grower let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to my
buddy uncle gigi i want to send a big
thank you shout out to noah n and
godfather kush let's send a thank you
shout out to adhd grower and stone trout
bomb let's send a big fist bump to the
larf knight rises i want to send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy
greybeard then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to a friend with weed big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends this episode will come out right
after thanksgiving indigenous people's
day black friday will actually come out
on cyber monday i hope everybody had a
great holiday i hope you had a good
feast i hope you had a good walk with
your cousin i also want to tell
everybody big thanks for all of the
support on the black friday sales that's
right we put out a couple of new strains
and if you were looking for those new
strains on black friday and you had a
problem finding them that is because
they sold out almost instantly that's
right they dropped it 420 on most of the
vendors by 4 30 most of them were sold
out so a lot of people were sending me
messages asking where and how to get
those new drops i do apologize they went
quite quickly they are being restocked
by the time this episode comes out most
of the vendors should be replenished
with the new drops of soccer souffle in
the machine so check the website check
the vendor links you should be able to
find those new packs in stock somewhere
so if you were looking for the machine
and soccer souffle on black friday and
you were unable to get those i do
apologize however they should be back in
stock now so once again check that
vendor list check the websites you
should be able to find soccer souffle
and the machine alright i do have one
more thing to cover before we get to the
main topic of this podcast the show is
approaching 10 000 youtube subscribers
my goal for this podcast for the end of
the year is to reach 10 000 youtube
subscribers also all i want for
christmas is 10 000 youtube subscribers
if you are listening on an audio
platform i do invite you to come
subscribe to the youtube channel come
check out the cool 4k video editing i'm
doing i've got two cameras going they're
both 4k i think it looks pretty good see
my cool background my lighting check out
my fancy table set up here anyway i do
invite you to come subscribe to the
youtube channel and if you're watching
and you haven't subscribed already now
is the time please click that little red
subscribe button click on the
notification bell that way every time i
put out a new episode you'll get a
notification and you'll never miss an
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast all right let's jump into the
main topic of this episode this question
came from the irie genetics website if
you've got a grow question you can visit
the irie genetics website there is a
grow help tab simply click on that tab
it will ask you a few preliminary
questions if you are asking a plant
specific question or a problem specific
question those uh preliminary questions
will help me kind of diagnose your
problem give me some details let me know
what's going on in the grow then at the
bottom it does give you the opportunity
to type out in detail what's going on
and ask your question this was not a
plant specific question this is a
breeding question that came from our
friend laser king and it goes a lot like
this it says rasta jeff when you have
feminized seeds and you make feminized
f2 well you have the same genetic
diversity as in regular f2 seeds that is
a very good question there are a couple
of things to unpack to get to the answer
to that one so our friend is asking
about feminized seeds if you don't
understand femme seeds i've done several
episodes on feminized seeds um there's a
full podcast about it if you type in
grow from your heart podcast feminized
seeds it will come up so that is a good
basis for feminized seeds a good base
education um so our friend has
apparently has feminized seeds or is
thinking about breeding with femme seeds
and they've got so when you make a batch
of seeds that first batch
we're going to call it for the sake of
this question here we're going to call
it an f1 when you take two strains that
are uh non-similar parents and you cross
them you have now made an f1
you probably made a polyhybrid but
that's just details to talk about in the
future we're going to say for this
question you've made an f1 so you've
taken a plant and reversed it and used
that pollen to put onto a different
plant and now we have made an f1 that is
feminized
that may also be called an s1 it could
also be called an r1 we're going to talk
about that it kind of those labels and
people are going to uh those are kind of
made up labels by the cannabis industry
we're kind of bastardizing all of these
labels for the cannabis industry i think
s and r were kind of made up by the
industry to indicate so let's talk about
what an s and an r are because that will
help us out uh when we are reversing
plants when i'm making feminized seeds
we are reversing a plant i'm taking a
female plant and treating it with a
solution to cause that plant to create
pollen which will all be female pollen
then we put that pollen on
a another female plant now
if i take
let's just say golden goat golden goat
is a really good place to start if i
take a golden goat female plant and
reverse it and make pollen out of that
golden goat i can either put that pollen
on another golden goat female or i can
put that pollen on any other female in
my grow
if i put that feminized pollen from
golden goat onto golden goat i have done
what is called selfing that plant has
selfed self-itself this may be crass but
you will never forget it that plant just
[ __ ] itself and made babies you're
never gonna forget that it is a little
crass but it is in your brain forever it
is s self self itself that is golden
goat two golden goat nothing but golden
goat s1 in that genetics you're not
gonna find anything but golden goat you
may find some recessive traits from the
golden goat parents and grandparents but
there's no adulteration it's just golden
goat genetics in that line if i were to
take that golden goat pollen and put it
on any other plant that is going to be
labeled an r plant a r r is for reversal
the number that follows that will be
your generation it can be an r1 and r2
but in this case we're just going to say
r1 the first time i make that pollen and
put it on a different plant the seeds
that come out of that are now labeled an
r1 it's a reversal one it is an f1 but
to be friendly and to give more
information a breeder would like to uh
would be polite if they label that as an
s1 or an r1 which would indicate that it
is feminized and it would let you know a
little bit of how it has been created
and worked that is why we use uh more
specific labels other than f1 s1 r1 so i
think i've talked about the difference b
if it were a regular seat it would be an
f1 if it was not feminized it'd be an f1
since we're working with fems
we get s1s and r1's so let me catch
myself back up on my notes
the original question is are we going to
have the same genetic diversity as in
regular f2 seeds that genetic diversity
will be dictated by a couple of things
first of all was the original plant a
self plant or a reversed plant and now
the second question is are you putting
that pollen on the same plant or a
different plant and the reason i'm
asking that is because that is going to
unlock different potential there are
more ingredients going into the pie
think about it this way if i've got
golden goat and i'm only putting golden
goats a golden goat 100 golden goat i'm
going to get
probably 75 to 80 percent of my
phenotypes are going to be very golden
goat some of those other phenotypes the
other 25 20ish percent are going to look
like the parents that created golden
goat and possibly the grandparents that
created those plants that's a little bit
unlikely but it is possible when you're
working with genetics you do see the
history when you're making things but
we're not going to see any other
genetics other than the ingredients that
were in that pie that make golden goat
but it's going to be very golden goat
dominant now let's talk about if i took
a golden goat and pollinated let's just
say lemon skunk and made lemon jeffrey
now you've got the opportunity to see
the parents of the golden goat and also
the parents of the lemon jeffrey in that
cross we've got two different
ingredients so we've got more options
for more flavors most of the time we're
going to see
a beautiful 50 50 mix of golden goat and
lemon skunk which is a beautiful
phenotype of the lemon jeffrey but
you're going to see leaners toward the
golden goat and you're going to see
leaners toward the lemon jeffrey now
this is going to depend on
which plant is more dominant in the
genetics which traits take over there
will be recessive traits there will be
dominant traits there will be
co-dominant traits which traits in your
plants when in that mix it's like you
just put all these ingredients in a bowl
and you shook them up which one's got
more flavor which one's gonna win in
that mix which flavor and there are so
many other things to think about when it
comes to breeding it's not just flavor
the flavor the aromas the buzz and the
appearance are all things we can quickly
identify but you've also got to think
about how does it grow is it resistant
is there resistance to pests and
pathogens and problems and stress those
are very important things to think about
but i'm kind of getting off topic here
um the main thing we're going to see is
the parents you're going to see the
golden goat and the lemon skunk and then
you may
may see a little bit of the golden go
parents there's romulan island sweet
skunk hawaiian sativa in there you may
see some of those traits pop up in the
lemon skunk ah there's some sort of
skunk and some sort of lemon i don't
even know exactly what made the lemon
skunk uh but you're gonna see traits of
those parents honestly a lot of the
things if i reverse golden goat i see i
can identify the golden goat traits in
it and then i can identify the traits
that come from the other plants very
well the lemon jeffrey
that spacious between the notes that
spacious growth between the nodes that
directly comes from the lemon skunk that
crazy wicked potency that comes directly
from the golden goat so it kind of
depends on the dominance of the traits
in which plant you're going to use now
let me get myself back on track and
focus a little bit because the question
is specifically about s2 or f2 with
feminized seeds and will we see the same
genetic diversity as in as within an f2
in my experience no ah when you make f2s
of regular seeds the f2 is when you find
the wild diversity the wild variation uh
i think it is called transgressive
segregation or recessive segregation one
of those words is accurate somebody tell
me because i just pulled that out of the
sky randomly and there are a lot of
words in my brain one of those is
accurate but it's the uh the segregation
word when we find uh offspring that
outperform the original appearance
that's when you see stuff like that so
uh the f2s will show wild variation you
see a lot of uh you see a lot of things
that look like the mom a lot of things
that look like the dad a lot of things
that are 50 50. then we see a lot of
crazy grandparent traits get brought out
so if you're looking from to find some
of the older stuff in the line you can
kind of find that in the f2s that's
where it will represent itself or
present itself
then you find the f3 and breed those
together and wash all that old stuff out
and start narrowing it down that's kind
of the process for there with the
feminized seed you don't really bring
out all that old stuff you were kind of
locking it in even tighter one thing i
have noticed when you do make the
feminized s2s
sometimes you can make kind of weaker
spindly plants that don't perform as
well sometimes you really lock in super
traits that have very uniform plants
that s2
will come out almost like an f4 and f5
with the uniformity if you've done
proper selection again a lot of this
will be based very much on the plants
which you select the dominance of the
genes which you're using but since
you're using feminized seeds and doing
that the s's the s ones and only and not
doing ours you've got the good
opportunity of locking in the traits
that you really want but it's all about
phenotypical selection something i have
noticed is that different phenotypes of
the same strain will react differently
when they are feminized
i had a plan and we'll just say number
nine and number four were both reversed
and self to each other and number nine
was awesome number four was trash all
the seeds that came out of there showed
me garbage i did not like what they
represented number nine was awesome
the plant my favorite plant that came
out of uh the s ones of number nine i
made s2s of those and that got labeled
uh if i start talking numbers i'll
reveal what it is because it's known as
number 77. uh number 77 had problems
being reversed it was so dominant and so
female that i could not reverse it i had
to really spray the [ __ ] out of it start
spraying it early to get it to reverse
so the original question is will i see
the same genetic diversity in the f2s uh
no they're going to be in my opinion
they'll be much more locked down you're
not going to get i was i was rambling
about how the f2s and regular seeds
bring up that wild genetic diversity the
feminized f2s kind of lock it in really
tight you're not going to see much
diversity at all it's going to be
more like an f3 or an f4 of regular
seeds and it's going to be very very
uniform if you have selected the correct
phenotype like i said number nine was
amazing
number four did not want to be uh f2 in
any way now i kind of hinted at this a
moment ago but think of breeding a
little bit as chefing every ingredient
you put in is going to add to the mix
now think about portions of those
ingredients if i add one portion of one
thing my meal tastes or my mix my final
product tastes like that one thing if i
put in golden goat it tastes like golden
goat it is only golden goat if i put in
some lemon skunk now probably i'm going
to get 50 50 percent lemon skunk 50
golden go and we shake it up you got to
think about like there's going to be the
edges of the pan or the edges of the
cookie sheet or however that's where
your outliers are going to be right in
the middle is going to be your your
regular [ __ ] then the outliers are going
to be out there you're going to find
some weirdos out there but most of your
flavors are going to be 50 50 then let's
think about if we're breeding feminized
plants to itself again you just added
more golden goat to the mix so you're
just doubling up on the golden goat
flavor making it super golden goat now
that one is gonna have that one batch of
pie or that one cake is double golden
goat so now whatever you breed to that
it's going to be two golden goats two
whatever you breed it to technically
just because of the breeding that you've
done you've locked in that golden goat
trait so hard kind of think about it as
if uh we filled the pan with golden goat
you're only going to take golden goat
but if we fill the pan with 50 golden
goat and 50 lemon skunk and blend it
together now right in the middle there
is going to be a beautiful blend of 50
percent lemon scott 5050 lemon skunk and
golden goat maybe on the outer edges
maybe we didn't blend it too well you're
gonna get some that's a little more
golden goat some that's a little more
lemon skunk and the opposite on other
parts that's kind of how breeding works
if you want to be real basic about it
and compare it to chefing i know i took
off on a good ramble on that one but the
short answer is you will not see as much
diversity in the feminized f2 as you
would in the regular f2 because you're
not unlocking that pandora's box
in my experience and in my opinion the
phenotypes do come out much more uniform
much more regular and quite a bit like
that original plant that you started
with uh sometimes though you can create
weak and spindly offspring in the
feminized f2 but a lot of the times you
do make very stable uniform uh viable
crosses when doing the feminized f2
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast this may be a quick episode
after some editing i do want to make
sure to get this episode completed i've
been experiencing some camera technical
difficulties i want to get this episode
done get these cameras checked out see
what's going on i do promise longer
better episodes in the future i do have
two more breeding questions here lined
up we will get to those in the next
episode um if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know that i would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy don't
forget to support the patreon campaign
at patreon.com
everything else you need is on the
website at iregenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy thecanocrat
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you