[Music]
[Applause]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a
breeding question before i get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to roll this nug let's send a big thank
you shout out to growing tennessee let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to justin glosser i want to send a
thank you shout out to jay dutch in
route 305 let's send a big thank you
shout out to big sexy dank and grow man
stan let's send a fist bump to a long
time supporter my buddy know me by my
guacamole listen to fist bump and a
thank you shout out to polo paul let's
send a big thank you shout out to jackie
daytona then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to stoner dave
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends welcome to the show everybody
thank you for joining me this will be a
one camera episode if you're watching
the video there's only one camera today
we are figuring out what the technical
difficulty is with the other camera
we'll get two cameras up and running
pretty soon maybe just purchase another
camera that may end up with sometimes
three angles sometimes two angles i am
already rambling this is going to be a
good show i wanted to start by saying
thank you in the last episode i asked a
lot of people to i asked for people to
subscribe to the channel i'm trying to
get to 10 000 subscribers on youtube
before the new year a lot of people
subscribed a lot of people shared that
message uh thank you to everybody who
subscribed uh thanks to everybody who
already was subscribed and big thanks to
everybody who shared my request for
subscriptions i appreciate that big push
thank you it was noticed there was an
increase in numbers i do appreciate that
also thank you for all of the feedback
in the youtube comments i have been
checking out the comments a little bit
more previously i talked about not
reading those i've been making an effort
to browse them a little bit more
i do see that you guys prefer the longer
episodes i prefer the longer episodes
myself i think um even when the camera
does crap out the longer episodes are
still more fun
it takes a minute to get started i got
to do the ads i got to do the intro i
got to read the patreon stuff once i get
settled in i really like flowing so i do
think that i enjoy the longer episodes
as well so i will do my best to get
longer episodes coming to you but
sometimes short sweet episodes are good
and good good and good i said that not
even gonna edit that they're good and
sweet it's what you need just get right
to the point get the lesson out get it
out there some people say i ramble too
much some people want longer shows i'm
gonna make the show happen the way it
goes do my best to make everybody happy
i'm gonna do my thing we'll see how it
works
i'm gonna be super rambly through this
episode i've been smoking all kinds of
different dabs today we can't blame it
on one dab or the other put a lot of
miles on the car did a lot of things
smoked a lot of dabs saw a lot of people
that's why i'm rambling lots of talking
happened today um let's not ramble too
much i did all the ads i covered all the
patreon stuff i said thank you let's
jump into the email portion of this
podcast i've got a message here in front
of me uh do they want their name said on
the show this one came from our friend
zach big shout out to our buddy zach if
you have any questions the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com i
would love to hear from you that's where
this one came from our friend zach says
hey ross to jeff i started listening to
your podcast around a month ago and i am
so appreciative of all the information
you give out i have learned so much hey
thank you that's all i need is to hear
that people are learning that makes it
all worth the time effort energy uh
knowing that you're learning something
uh that you learned enough and felt like
you should reach out and tell me so that
means you're learning a lot that i'm
connecting with you so thank you for the
feedback thank you for watching
listening i do appreciate it and thank
you for the great question it goes on it
says i've always wanted to do a small
breeding project in my little three by
three tent and i'm still trying out new
strains before i really go in to a pheno
hunt
but years ago my buddy and i grew for
the first time and we got our hands on
some bog genetics big up bog genetics uh
we got some
some bog bubble gum uh rest in peace to
bushy old grower yes big rest in peace
to bushy old grower if you guys ever see
the name bog or the letters b-o-g in a
grow forum or on seed form or wherever
you're getting seeds bog b-o-g is bushy
old grower uh he was a really cool
grower a really cool breeder
kind of a cantankerous old man not as
cantankerous and outgoing and ornery as
subcool but he still had some stuff to
say uh he wasn't as outgoing on the
online on the new types of internet back
in the day on irc and stuff he did talk
a little more uh i'm already rambling
but bog is bushy old grower he taught us
a lot he gave us a lot of great quality
strains he did make a lot of great stuff
big up to mrs bogg let me get back on
track um so our friend is talking about
doing some breeding they're still
searching for some strains they're still
getting their uh their black belt and
growing before they get into breeding
then their first time they grew they got
their hands on the bog bog bubble since
then they've been hooked on all things
bubble gum when it comes to cannabis and
love trying things that are crossed with
it that bubble gum terp and that bubble
gum effect is great uh anything from i'm
not sure if the bog bubble comes from
the old indiana bubble gum i didn't
research that but anything from that
indiana bubble gum or true bubble gum
line is tasty it tastes so good it's got
that super stickiness to it which
actually is why the bubble gum got its
name it wasn't from the flavors or the
aromas it was because it was so sticky
that it was sticky like bubble gums
where bubble gum got its name so our
friend is thinking about or talking
about doing some breeding in the future
uh they're in love with the bog bubble
and all things bubble gum and bubble gum
crosses now here's where we get into the
question part it says i do not require a
large quantity of cannabis and when i do
decide to create some seeds i am purely
looking for that euphoric giggly creeper
uh what's it say creeper high that i
remember from bog my question is what is
the best way to select keepers in a
breeding project if i'm only looking for
specific effects
um that is a really good question you've
got a goal so the goal is the most
important part it says should i take
small samples late in flower or decide
purely based off the smell of the terps
neither one of those you're going to
have to
completely finish your test samples
dry them cure them and smoke them and if
you're looking if you're judging your
phenohunt based purely on looking for
the euphoric giggly creeper buzz you've
got to grow them to full mature maturity
dry them cure them smoke them
all of these things have to happen under
the same scientific type conditions i
understand you're in a three by three
tent which actually kind of makes it
better because that three by three tint
is gives you much less variables that's
only three by three you've only got that
much space to have differences so you
get your 3x3 i would grow as many seeds
as you can fit in there and as legally i
do them small
grow them until you can get a clone get
your clone then grow them all
scientifically feed them all the same
thing
treat them all the same way give them
all the same amount of light air
humidity that's why the 3x3 is cool it's
very limited your variables are going to
be limited in there
you've got to grow it
harvest them
you can harvest them at different times
wait until you see the trichomes look
the way that you would normally harvest
way so you feel like each plant is done
harvest them dry and cure them the same
way
then smoke them
i've got like
i noticed that when i smoke if you guys
watch any of my live shows or if you
know me you know that my office space is
my favorite little smoking spot i've got
a huge computer screen
my favorite music is there my drink goes
right here the dab rig is right here
it's just like my home base that is my
spot when i get home and want to chill
out and take some dabs and put on some
music and relax that is the first spot i
go got a nice cozy computer chair uh
chilling out that is like my my test
zone if i was gonna test new dabs new
cannabis that would be the first place i
would go my favorite smoking devices
there my favorite music is there my
comfortable chair is there my snacks are
within reach i know that that is my zone
i can get i can get wrecked in that zone
and nothing can go wrong if anything
does go wrong there's a couch on the
other side of the room that i just i
just basically crawl to the couch and
everything will be okay i've got snacks
i've got drinks i've got a couch i got
music nothing can go wrong
so that is my desired test environment
if i had new product to test i would
test it all there also i would try to
test it all after a decent meal have
some food in my stomach have some
hydration not be exhausted not be too
hyper not have any caffeinated beverages
not too much sugar just kind of baseline
you know belly full to where when you
smoke it you're not going to get instant
munchies you got some blood sugar to
handle something to handle the blood
sugar then you take a couple of dabs
take a couple smokes whatever however
you bong rips pipe rips
get the cannabis india see what it does
to you give give each sample that same
kind of critical test sample do it in
your favorite device in your favorite
space have you noticed if you smoke in
your little your comfort space you can
smoke and enjoy it really comfortably
you could taste every terp smell every
smell because you don't have to pay
attention to like uh if you're smoking
somewhere perhaps in the car or at
somebody else's house at somebody else's
house maybe the dog is gonna knock over
your drink or spill the bong or you
can't really focus as much on what you
can when you're in your perfect little
bubble that's my opinion so i would say
smoke all of the samples in a scientific
sort of format with the same baseline
sort of starting point full stomach no
sugar no caffeine clear head good mood
nothing to do and see what it does see
if that's the one that gives you that
giggly uh euphoric creeper bud feeling
you've got to smoke if what you're
looking for is specifically that effect
you've got to find the finished product
that gives you that effect that's the
only way to really test it uh taking
early samples won't tell you what you're
going to have in a final product you've
got to
smoke a final finished product that is
my opinion uh if you really want to know
what you're going to get so you've got a
goal uh you've got a long long term
short-term goal is to reproduce that
giggly effect do you want to f2 these
things do you want to f3 f4 how far do
you want to go when you're breeding do
you just want to make a few seeds for
yourself to play with or do you want to
make a whole bunch of seeds it sounds
like you just want to make some for you
to breed and grow out and hopefully you
find that giggly stuff so it says any
advice would be greatly appreciated keep
doing your thing p.s i'm about to pop
some strawberry starburst i can't wait
to see what these are
all about cheers from zach dude uh
strawberry starburst and that bog bubble
would be really great and you will find
similar bubble gum type terps in the
strawberry starburst their strawberry
candy their strawberry bubble gum
there's a watermelon terp in there
when you if you grow the flowers out and
what i have noticed this is my
experience when you grow the flowers and
press them into concentrate or where
they why yeah grow the flowers wash it
and then press the con the wash
concentrates you grow it make bubble
hash then press the bubble hash
that tasted like strawberry bubble gum
that's what i did notice so you may get
some strawberry terps bubble gummy terps
out of that
no um do you have an idea when you breed
with the bog are you going to use a
bubble a bog bubble mail or are you
going to use a bog bubble female what do
you have in mind here i would grow
i would try to use that bog i would
almost just make f2s if you're just
doing this just for fun for your own
personal enjoyment i would make f2s i
would find the bog mail that looks and
smells a lot like the bog female you're
going to find find that perfect so
you're going to grow a pack of the bog
girls hopefully you can get more of
those seeds right that would be ideal
here or hopefully you've got a clone or
something of the female anyway try to
find some of that bog bubble grow that
find a female that gives you the traits
you're looking for you're going to find
one in there it was in the pack the
first time that you grew it you'll find
it in the pack again so find that
phenotype that gives you the giggles the
creeper uh what else is the effect right
there that you're looking for giggles
creeper there's something else but the
my printer kind of messed up around this
euphoric is the other word uh so find
those traits from the female now you've
got a male find a male that looks
similar to that you're going to be
limited on male selection find the best
male out of the pack that's going to be
up to you find the one that looks a lot
like the girl you're working with now
you've got a male and you've got a girl
ah now i would also find a couple of
other female plants to put in that room
something like the strawberry starburst
would be cool but then i would find
something
vastly different than the bog just way
different
just to play with just to see what that
bog is what the bog bubble is
contributing to the mix uh breed it to
um something really cushy or gassy or
garlicky so that you can see what it
contributes does it give it uh does it
change the structure does it change the
aroma does it change the uh does it give
you just a bunch of mutants does it make
it really resistant to bugs see what
that male is adding by breeding it to
other plants now of course you've got to
grow those but that is the best the
funnest part grow maybe i don't know
that is a big debate in my head right
now i want your feedback send me an
email hit me up on twitter however you
know how to get in touch with me on
twitter it's at gfyh podcast i want to
know do you enjoy the phenohunt and
growing more or do you enjoy smoking it
more i really love growing it and seeing
what happens to the flowers like i made
the seed so after you make a breeding
project this is my question if you do a
breeding project and you make seeds are
you more excited about seeing what the
plants do as they grow or smoking the
final product as a breeder i'm torn that
is a really uh that's a really big
question for me
so i lost my place rambling on that one
but i would find that uh yeah then you
get to grow them then you get to smoke
them out find a male find a female then
find a couple of other females and put
them in the room because that dude's
going to be in there skeet skeeting
blowing pollen anyway so just put a
couple of females in there for him to
pollinate make it a party get a bunch of
different seeds keep all of those seeds
separate when you harvest uh then grow
them out mark them so that you know this
is like a strawberry starburst to the
bog and then this is the whatever to the
bog and this to the bog markham grow
them see what you've got and then like i
said identify the trait that that male
is delivering to the mix see if he's uh
if the bog f2s come out bubble gummy and
euphoric and giggly perfect you hit your
goal right there but to the strawberry
starburst what did you get did it make
the strawberry starburst to go super
tall did it make it short and squat did
it make it get a sour
maybe a grapefruit kind of an aroma when
you hit it to an indica or a garlic
plant does the garlic come out more or
does the structure of the original plant
you pollinated come out or does the
structure of that male plant come out a
little bit more you should be able to
identify the traits
when you do the breeding to see which
side which parent came out you should be
able to see that so i would take the boy
i would take the girl uh take a few
other girls and have a party in there
grow them now the most important part
again is to finish them let them finish
i don't know why i stuttered so strong
when i said that but i must have meant
it let them finish then harvest them dry
them cure them just like you normally do
just like you do all of your other crops
don't do anything do it scientifically
but don't dry them and cure them don't
do anything weird no anomalies do what
you know don't do any new experiments
like i tried this because that may [ __ ]
up all of your science if you try one
new thing that can mess everything up do
the familiar [ __ ] that you do but keep
it very regulated amongst every plant in
the grow dry them cure them smoke them
see what you enjoy the best those are
your keepers if you are breeding for
potency and effect that is the way to
find the keepers but also keep in mind
that if you're growing this you're going
to want plants that grow well um
structure is important is it shaped well
does that plant support itself does it
grow in your growing style i don't know
if you grow in three you're in a three
by three tent so you're not in gigantic
pots but i don't know if you grow hydro
do you grow soilless mix do you grow
cocoa do you grow in a six inch net pot
or a three gallon pot do you grow
one big bud and cut off all the branches
do you trellis them out real far do you
use a tomato cage do you use a stick are
using yoyos and hanging them from the
ceiling yes that is a thing it's not as
crazy as it sounds it sounds different
than what it looks like if you're not
familiar with the yoyos but how are you
growing i don't know how you're growing
in there so find the phenotype that is
going to work the best for you also your
environment is it hot is it cold you may
need to find the phenotype that works
best for the hot for the cold for the
humid for the dry uh do you want the one
that takes a little bit longer to flower
are you patient can you handle that are
you freaking out are you like ah this
plant needs to get done already or are
you like man i got all day that's cool
at that plant [ __ ] finch i'm patient
i love letting plants grow for a long
time so do you want the faster finisher
do you want the longer finisher there
are so many variables to think about
what about bug resistance uh do you want
these plants to be really resistant to
bugs or does that even matter to you do
you care if they are resistant to mold
and mildew or do you not even care
because you're the only one growing
those i make seeds for market i make
seeds uh first of all i make a lot of
seeds for myself you guys see these
strains pop up occasionally you're like
where did those come from why were those
never for sale like the garlic goat was
made just for me to play with and then i
made so many of those that i was like
i'm never gonna grow all these so i put
some of them out let some people get
their hands on those but if you're just
making them for you you could breed for
just potency just for flavor i'm
breeding for things that go to the
market they've got to be pest resistant
pathogen resistant definitely no mutants
no intersex plants i've got to be very
careful what i put out but when i'm
making stuff for me i could just be it
could be really problematic and i can
find the keeper for myself to grow and
that's more fun so it depends on what
you're going to do with it it sounds
like these are just for you now
you've got that three by three you don't
have to grow gigantic plants if you find
uh this is something i was talking about
with a couple of friends people like i
just don't have room to breathe i don't
have the space i wish i had room to grow
and breed you can breed in a very small
space your three by three would be
beautiful i keep saying put that male
plant and several females in there you
can pollinate in a three by three you
could probably hypothetically put you i
can fit nine uh three gallon pots and
they're easily in a three by three they
may be the pots may be touching might
not be a lot of space but i'm thinking
uh nine three rows of three three gallon
pots put the dude in the middle surround
him with ladies when he starts
pollinating all those girls are gonna
get it
that's probably what i would do that's
uh eight female plants in there that you
get to pollinate you know you don't have
to grow them very big if you want to go
even quicker and not make a big mess and
get a bunch of pollen and have a huge
project you can breed in small pots i've
done beer cup breeding projects i
shouldn't tell everybody about this as a
seed maker i shouldn't tell you how to
make seeds so quickly so easily but this
is a very easy effective way to make a
few seeds just for yourself to play with
when i make seeds the first time i make
a cross let's say that we're going to
make let's pick a strain let's say jack
tripper this is a real thing that has
happened jack tripper jack tripper is
lemon skunk to jack the ripper uh come
and dance on our floor the song will be
stuck in your head all day you're gonna
be coming knock on our door now it's in
your head it'll never stop that's where
jack tripper came from on the story when
the question gets asked jack tripper
lemon skunk jack the ripper call it jack
tripper uh
amazing lemon terps lemon cleaner terps
uh almost gross overpowering lemon
cleaner terps and the head buzz it's
like a knife just came through the
ceiling and ripped your head off and
opened your brain in half and lights and
fireworks just come out of your brain
for a minute the head high is so extreme
but anyway let me focus um jack tripper
i only made
70 50 something seeds of that maybe just
a small a small drug bag of seeds that's
how many seeds i made you know what i'm
talking about a little drug bag that's
how many seeds i made
not a lot because i don't know i didn't
know i do know now at the time i didn't
know if that was going to be
uh completely intersex plants complete
mutants i didn't know if they were going
to take 74 weeks to flower i didn't know
if they were going to be duds i didn't
know what it was going to do so instead
of wasting time uh vegging a plant that
is going to get real big first of all a
male plant that gets real big makes a
lot of pollen pollen goes everywhere and
not that i'm lazy but i don't want to
clean up a whole bunch of pollen if i
don't have to if there's minimal pollen
that is less to clean so i grew a
smaller male plant uh he was in a six
inch net pot because i wanted him kind
of bigger than the females because i
want enough pollen to get the room there
so i got my male and a six inch net pot
i got my females and beer cups i can
pollinate a bunch of beer cups you grow
them to where they're
just big enough to i don't know four or
five inches maybe three and a half
inches flip them by the time the pollen
hits they're only maybe eight inches ten
inches tall by the time they're done
they're 10 or they're 12 maybe 14 inches
tall you may need to put a skinny stick
in there just to support them but from
that plant you're going to get a lot of
seeds a lot a lot of seeds a lot like 30
to 70 seeds probably and that's plenty
for just a home grower a home breeder to
tinker and play with you guys buy a 10
pack and you spend good money on a 10
pack if you get 30 seeds and you do that
to four or five plants you're going to
get at least 100 150 200 and something
seeds to play with and you can do that
in one very small run if you've got a
small just a very tiny space that you
can control the light to 12 12 for six
weeks nine weeks on
there are some variables in there i said
six weeks because you can put the light
back uh to a vegetative cycle and the
seeds will finish you don't have any
problem with that but um six to nine
weeks that you can control a flowering
cycle three or four two or three three
or four weeks you can control a veg
phase you can produce seeds uh that will
be very viable usable for yourself so i
got rambly on that one uh but you don't
need as much space as you think you
might need is what i'm saying you can
pollinate little tiny plants they don't
have to be super large get them in a
beer cup veg them until they're as tall
as gi joe flower them they'll end up two
or three gi joes tall they'll have 30 50
maybe even 100 seeds in there depending
on the strain some of the og kush stuff
doesn't make a lot of big buds you don't
get a lot of seeds out of that the mac
doesn't take pollen the mac is just
stingy
don't be stingy mac
but then things like strawberry
starburst they'll take a lot of pollen
and give you a lot of seeds blue
raspberry truffle blueberry cookies
they make a lot of pistols they make a
lot of seeds when you pollinate them the
jack the ripper crosses
make a lot of pistols very early and
produce a lot of seed so you can hit
those really early when they're little
and produce seeds for yourself to play
with all right i got rambling let me
check my notes there are more notes on
this page
if you're looking for the effects you
definitely have to smoke it um gotta
find the the potency that you're looking
for there's no other way to tell now
here is the last note that i did right
on this page it says if you find the
right keeper and the one that gives you
that giggly buzz and that euphoric high
and that creeper effect that you're
looking for is it necessary to do any
breeding you've already got the plant
that you're looking for it's perfect uh
you could you could just be happy with
that i understand the desire the need
the want uh just the excitement of
breeding but honestly if you've got the
plant that does what you need it to do
you don't you don't really have to go
any further you could just clone it and
grow it forever and ever and be
completely happy with that you could or
you can s want it you could self it and
make more seeds of it than you've got
those seeds forever uh here's another
avenue um if you don't have a male plant
if you don't have any seeds if you do uh
of the bog if you do have the clone of
the bog you can reverse it and you can
use that as your pollen donor and that
can pollinate another clone of the bog
you can make s-ones of that and while
you're doing that you can also put that
pollen on other female plants and
outcross it those would be ours from the
previous episodes self and reverse
plants you can make some selves and some
reversals using the bog keeper i don't
know if you still have it let me try to
read again i always wanted to breed
years ago buddy grew for the first time
got our hands on bog since then i've
looked uh i've loved all things bubble
so i don't know if you still have it um
if you've still got it you can self it
and then you can make a self cross of it
and you can outcross it if you still
have it if not
i would recommend trying to find another
pack if not you said you're growing the
strawberry starburst you're gonna find
similar bubble gummy terps in there
you'll find creeper you'll find euphoric
the answer may lie in that pack all
right my friend zach i do want to thank
you for the great message you did get me
rambling i do appreciate that i like
talking about breeding i like looping it
back to previous episodes that was a
good chat thank you once again the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me those
questions
i do have one more quick question i'm
going to cover here in this episode this
one comes from our friend kyle what up
kyle thank you for the great question
this one goes a lot like this it says
hey ross to jeff i have a question about
ph this is a good question it says i
know you recommend to be in the 6.2 to
6.5 range i usually would say six two to
six point four but six five in like a
soilless mix and stuff yeah that'll work
for you i said i completely understand
the reasoning but i'm curious why canada
recommend canada is a nutrient brand by
the way it says i'm curious why kano
recommends as low as 5.5 so canna is a
nutrient company they sell bottled
nutrients and on their website most of
the nutrient brands that you buy do have
a website with a nutrient calculator a
nutrient feed chart on there a nutrient
nutrient schedule uh nutrients is
starting to become the new roads in my
head if you know what i'm talking about
big up shout out to chris farley um
nutrients anyway uh so they're a
nutrient company they sell bottled
nutrients and they do recommend as low
as 5.5 that does make sense i did check
their website let's talk minimally about
ph because i am not an organic chemistry
expert our plants are uptaking uh
buffered nutrients in a bottled nutrient
environment they're taking up bottled
nutrients they're taking up uh the 16
elements nitrogen phosphorus potassium
mellitum malebinim wow you say that one
fast calcium magnesium there are more
than i'm going to miss but i'm going to
try to keep on moving our plants are
trying to uptake those things
for those things to be bioavailable to
our plant the ph
needs to be the ph of that feed solution
needs to be around 6.2 to 6.5 those
nutrients are more bioavailable to the
plant at that range once it gets higher
the plant doesn't uptake that once it
gets lower the plant doesn't uptake that
the reason we recommend a six two to six
five is because there's kind of a range
where like some of the nutrients would
kind of take up better at six five some
of them would kind of take up better at
six two so we go right in the middle to
where you get just just kind of the best
for both of those nutrients and we're
using so many things that we just found
that within that six two to six four six
five range you do get a good window
where most things will absorb with uh mo
they'll work best together i don't know
the scientific terms like i said i'm not
an organic chemistry major
but that's where things seem to work the
best now the reason uh that they are
giving you such a broad range in this
proprietary brand uh i did yeah and the
rest of the question says uh recommends
5.5 i do believe they say the highest is
6.2 is this something proprietary to
them yes this is proprietary to them i
did some research on their website
the 5.2 is recommended for hydro for
dirt they recommend a 5.8 to 6.2 and for
cocoa they recommend 5.5 to 6.2 so in
the hydro
there's nothing buffering those
nutrients uh from touching the roots so
they give you just a little bit lower ph
that's just straight to the nutrient
straight absorption absorption so the
lower ph works there's no soil to buffer
there there's nothing to work through
nothing in the way straight to the roots
that makes sense they'll be quickly
absorbable at that low of a ph i
honestly am not super experienced in
hydro but it does kind of make sense for
the little bit i know about uh plant
growing organic chemistry and ph i do
think that makes sense now the 5 8 6 2
in the dirt is because of the buffering
of the dirt the soil the dirt there does
give you a little bit to work with it
does make that range a little bit more
available for the plants it's kind of i
keep saying the word buffering you just
get a little more room uh to work with
that's why that's why we recommend soil
and soilless mix to new growers because
it is a little bit easier to work with
that soil kind of works the soil kind of
corrects your problems a little bit to
an extent don't think you can just go
pouring in a bunch of [ __ ] but it does
kind of help you correct the problems at
that point you fed the soil the soil
will do some work the living [ __ ] inside
the soil will do its things and help uh
correct what you've done a little bit
and make that available to the plants
again i'm gonna get a lot of messages
about what i just said i am not an
organic chemistry major i'm trying to
explain this the best i know how
somebody said i explained things like
people have never grown before uh good a
lot of people never have grown before
and that's why they're here
uh let me keep going then it says uh 5.5
to 6.2 in cocoa uh yeah we're getting
that low 5.5 in cocoa because uh that is
very close to hydra that is kind of a
hybrid of soilless mix uh hydro together
so that's why you can go so low in there
basically nothing buffering uh
protecting the roots just cocoa in there
that's basically hydro the cocoa is
basically inert also we could talk about
i wrote down phase
and medium and plant specific in certain
phases your plants are going to want
different phs
in different medium your plant may want
different phs um
and also it's plant-specific i know that
some of the cookies crosses like a lower
ph some of the more sativa dominant
stuff likes a higher ph sometimes uh if
you're in certain environments you want
to adjust ph to kind of compensate for
some things that may help you out so um
that is why they're recommending a range
let me get back onto the question get
back in track here
all right it goes on to say this run i
followed your range and i feel like my
plants are very happy i have your
testers hitting my flower tent next and
i wanted to get your thoughts i'm
excited to see your testers it sounds
like you're going to pay a lot of good
attention to them it says as a side note
uh for this typically when i mix my
nutrients it hits about six three until
i bump up the feed and mid flour uh then
it consistently sits at five eight until
i adjust uh that's gonna you could
probably feed them that 5 8 and they
wouldn't be angry but if you're liking
what you're seeing i wouldn't change
anything a lot of people want to make
changes because of numbers and [ __ ]
watch the plants the plants are the boss
if you're liking the results
don't change anything it goes on to say
thanks for all you do
you have helped me improve my grow by
leaps and bounds i can't thank you
enough your friend kyle that means a lot
to me knowing that i have improved your
grow leaps and bounds that makes it all
worth it like i said uh those kind of
compliments that type of feedback makes
setting up a camera uh makes having a
frustrating camera that keeps turning
off on me and draining a battery and
doing weird [ __ ]
these comments this type of feedback
makes all that [ __ ] worth it sometimes
that camera makes me want to throw it
i'm not even mad at that camera anymore
doesn't even bug me that i got these
bright ass lights in my face i love the
feedback thank you guys i love knowing
that i'm making your garden better i
love knowing that i'm making your
growing experience better growing should
be fun growing should be pleasurable
growing is like my zen zone i do work in
a commercial environment i do consulting
i do get paid for that sort of stuff
when i'm in my own personal grow i close
the door i put in the earbuds sometimes
i'm just listening to the growth
sometimes i just hear the fans and the
blowers and i love it it's relaxing the
the sound of a vortex fan or a hurricane
fan and then just another oscillating
fan coming by that
and then
ah those sounds it's like what is it
asmr amsr i don't know the right order
but it's like music to my ears sometimes
hearing those [ __ ] sounds in the grow
space and then you hear the air
conditioner kick on that
that's a pretty good imitation of the
air conditioner that'll run for a few
minutes and then it cycles off i just
love being in there and hearing all the
rhythms of the [ __ ] and knowing it's all
working smooth and smelling the plants i
just like being in there that's my zen
space you can't [ __ ] with me when i'm in
there i leave the phone outside it's in
that's on the charger somewhere else
yeah let's go in the grove that is my
zen space so knowing that i can make
your grow that comfortable for you uh
it's your getaway like mine is i don't
need a vacation my vacation is in the
grow it's cool let's go let's do do some
defoliating let's go do some cloning
some topping popping lollipopping
twisting let's just go stare at the
plants that's like my meditation right
there anyway i'm glad i'm making your
grow as enjoyable as mine uh ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes uh newbies and pros smokers and
growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there thank you once
again for listening to me ramble on
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast thanks for hanging out i
really did have a good time on this
episode even though i only had one
camera to ramble into i will get camera
number two repaired we'll figure out
what's going on with that maybe like i
said before i'll buy camera three that
way we've got a backup plan when camera
two decides to be a little [ __ ] again
thanks for hanging out you guys if you
have any questions corrections comments
or concerns you know i would love to
hear from you the email address again is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com make
sure you hit the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart
everything else is on the website at
iregenetics.com
i think that's all i've got for you for
this episode let's wrap it up while it
was nice and tight i want to give a big
shout out to my buddy levity loveday and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you