[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on
another breeding question before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend girls grow too
let's send a big thank you shout out to
blackbird 76 and brendan groves let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to my buddy north north terps let's
send a big thank you shout out to mr
mean green i want to send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to chicago
dabber let's send a big fist bump to
kojaks i want to send a thank you shout
out to jesse gross let's send a thank
you shout out to madewall medicated and
rosta green thumb let's send a big shout
out to stash drop 269. i want to send a
big fist bump to my buddy quasi then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our friend groove two one one two
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends
alright let's not waste too much time
here at the start of the show let's jump
right into some of the emails that our
friends have sent us this one comes from
our friend maritime grower it goes a
little bit like this it says my question
is so far i'm very impressed with the
golden goat bx i've received everything
is working out great but i need to look
at expanding my selection yes that is
very uh a grower thing once you get good
at growing a plant you have fun with it
you realize i want to grow something
different grow more get more experiences
more flavors that is how it goes uh then
you end up filling a room with a bunch
of great [ __ ] i growing is so much fun i
get so passionate about growing i can't
get enough plants i can't grow enough
plants i just want to grow smoke try it
all let me try to get myself back on
track
it says i'm a big fan of sour diesel i
mean it's probably my favorite strain to
date and i've been stoned for over 30
years on all different types of weed
a lot of us that have been smoking for a
long time love the sour diesel the chem
the kush those are three distinct
flavors and aromas and kind of classes
of cannabis that we all enjoy and i
totally agree with you that sour diesel
that diesel turp uh the buzz the flavor
the aroma everything about it is highly
desirable when you got a bag of the good
sour diesel in your pocket you get in
the car with a friend and they're like
oh dude you brought the diesel they know
right away the whole neighborhood knows
right away when you roll a joint and
smoke that [ __ ] good sour diesel is
amazing so i understand why it's one of
your favorites it stands out like i said
it's got its own category that gas that
diesel flavor that's its own thing it
says uh what strain would you say would
be close to that i've been growing
different strains for six years looking
for something like this and since after
uh after 650 plus podcasts i feel that
you your genetics and knowledge can help
with this thanks in advance keep it up
and growers love of course that was from
our friend
maritime grower there thank you for the
great message thank you for the
nostalgia when i read the message about
the sour diesel i could smell the diesel
the way that it used to make my
it would make my my smoke room i was i
think it was my bedroom back in the day
would make that room stink so good
i remembered how when i would get a
large quantity of it maybe allegedly i
had a friend that was growing a lot of
it and i would get a large quantity and
it would make the whole house smell
funky when you would drive with it in
the car you'd be psy would be so
paranoid it was like a gassy skunk dirty
diesel fuel sort of a thing it kind of
burns my eyes in a delightful way the
buzz gives me tunnel visions where all i
can focus on is what's right in front of
me and i can't even barely pay attention
to that i love good sour diesel stuff
now the question here is ah what strain
would you say would be close to that
i would like to make a lot of
recommendations unfortunately there's
nothing like real true real deal sour
diesel there's nothing like that so i
can't make a recommendation for anything
from my line currently that i would say
would be real deal true diesel i don't
want to mislead you lie to you give you
the wrong information i may allegedly
have crossed something with a diesel
plant
but it needs to be tested we need to see
what it does it's still brand new it's
uh just happened it hasn't had time to
be ran at all uh that is in testing but
uh being a good friend somebody that uh
wants to make sure you get what you're
looking for our friend jj from top dog
has been putting out sour diesel bx3 and
i've got a pack of them i do intend to
uh maybe select a mail out of those in
the future i don't have room to run them
right now but if you are looking for
high quality sour diesel seeds right now
to the best of my knowledge there may be
more out there i'm not dissing any other
breeder i'm giving love to the breeder
that i know does have it uh jj top dog
genetics does have the real deal sour
diesel bx3 uh make sure if you are
looking for jj if you're looking for top
dog follow the appropriate
page on instagram if you are following
them on social media i'm going to side
track here
on social media right now there are a
lot of fake accounts posing as your
favorite seed makers seed breeders seed
vendors and you'll notice if you pay
close attention their account is just
one letter off so i'm talking about top
dog right now top dog is top t-o-p
d-a-w-g
they may put two w's in the top dog and
you may not even notice that or they may
throw an underscore in a weird place
ivory underscore genetics is me i
read.genetics is not me so people on
instagram right now are really trying to
scam people who are looking to buy seeds
if a breeder posts a photo and then
somebody says hey where can i find this
there is a scammer that follows up right
away and says hey i've got it message me
here and those most likely are not the
breeders we're not really
the breeders don't do a lot of sales
online i can't speak for everybody but
most of the breeders do their sales
through the vendors most of us have a
website you can hit the website there is
a recommended or a uh
it is a suggested vendor list those
people have been tried and trued we know
they've been vetted as the word my brain
is searching for we know those are good
vendors we know they will not rip you
off burn you scam you uh we know the
seeds that they send you came from us so
make sure you're checking out the real
uh social media pages and that you are
following the real social media and that
you are getting seeds from reliable
sources let me try to figure out where i
was sour diesel from jj uh if you're
looking for the sour diesel i highly
recommend jj that's a good cross that's
a good dude uh he's a new yorker i would
trust and believe that that's the real
deal og sour diesel
get a pack of those seeds be forewarned
they are not the cheapest seeds on the
planet i'm not talking trash about aj's
prices or jj's prices i apologize for
that when i'm thinking diesel i think aj
that's a whole nother if anybody knows
why you'll understand why aj sour diesel
is why um but jj will charge you a
little bit for those seeds but if you
find that sour diesel that you're
looking for it is worth it you do pay
for a premium product expect that i am
warning you no disrespect to the people
charging uh top dollar for their product
out there charge what you want but to
you customers that are gonna go look
right now be ready it's not super cheap
um be prepared all right so the sour
diesel i would recommend that you get
the sour diesel bx i think it's a bx3 a
bat cross number three from our friend
top dog genetics top dog seeds all right
and once again make sure you guys are
supporting the correct social media page
unfortunately we did have a friend um
i'm not gonna say any names but a friend
was scammed out of a nice portion of
money uh somebody on social media was
claiming to be iriegenetics
unfortunately that was a fake account
i saw them on a live feed they said hey
did you send my package and i was like i
didn't send any package uh politely went
and we did some messaging and they sent
me screenshots somebody was pretending
to be me that wasn't me so be very
careful if you're purchasing seeds out
there you guys check the email address
check the uh social media account double
check your uh your dots your dashes
underscores
make sure you're messing with the right
person all right to my friend maritime
grower i wish i had more advice for you
but i don't have something in my line
that is reliably
sour diesel that's going to give you
that nostalgia i don't want to mislead
you lie to you but i do know that it's
available via top dog genetics thank you
for the great message brother i do look
forward uh to seeing pictures of your
grow of the sour diesel when you do
obtain those seeds obtain a acquire
score
when you get them bro i look forward to
the pictures alright i do have one more
message here before we get to the
breeding part of this podcast
this message came from the man with no
name it says hey i love the podcast and
the plants you put out bro thank you
that's a great compliment it says my
question is i have an ac infinity fan a
six inch ac infinity fan i'm using a
three by three tent i used the ac
infiniti and my four by four currently
i'm having problems with nanners really
bad since i got the ac infinity okay so
you've got you're ending up with
intersex plants ever since you got that
ac infinity fan
it goes on to say if the fan outtake is
sucking in the sides of the tent can and
will that cause manners and by nanowrist
he means intersex plants hermaphroditic
plants uh it says i've stopped i've had
the speed control on the lowest setting
thank you and then it talks about some
other strains he's grown now let's talk
about this just briefly the sides of the
tent being sucked in are not a problem
that is negative pressure if you've got
your carbon filter inside the tent
uh then you're sucking in uh it's
working very that's a good thing don't
worry about that that's not a problem
and no that should will not cause
intersex plants if you've got quality
genetics that should not be the cause
i'm thinking since you've introduced
this new fan there is some sort of a
light leak would be my first assumption
i don't know what else got adjusted
during this i don't know where the ac
infinity controller is there are a lot
of things that i would investigate but
my very first assumption would be that
you have now got a light leak that you
have not yet discovered
so i would see where that ac infinity
controller is is that inside the tent if
it's in the tent it is coming on during
your night cycle and that is giving you
your intersex traits um you've got the
new the new blower
excuse me for the throat clearing you
guys i've been dabbing my face off this
weekend uh you've got that new blower uh
how is the ducting ran now is the
ducting going a different direction
where you're getting light through the
ducting or did you open a flap that
wasn't open before uh maybe i just
thought of this while i'm talking my way
through it the tent is sucking in on
itself the tents usually have flaps on
the bottom are they opening up so much
that you're allowing light in through
the bottom it's really unlikely probably
not the cause but uh my main if you're
getting intersex plants now that you
weren't getting before this piece of
equipment i'm going to assume it's a
light leak that is going to be my very
first assumption
i actually like to see the walls of the
tent suck in a little bit when i'm
growing that lets me know first of all
it lets me know i'm getting enough
suction power i'm pushing out more air
than i'm able to pull in right because
it's struggling to get air so it's just
caving in because so much air is going
out that means that all of the air going
out is getting carbon filtered and i'm
replacing that air just [ __ ] as
quickly as possible as it can be
replaced in that tin it's coming i keep
making this motion uh that's air coming
in through the bottom going up going
through the carbon filter going out of
the ducting going out of that tent and
then wherever you've got it directed if
it's out of the house out of uh into the
attic out of a window or just back into
the room which could work if you do that
properly if you recondition that air and
then blow it back into the tent that
would work for you
heat rises lower errors at the bottom
you can figure out how to make that
happen for you
but overall i really don't think that
that suction is ever going to cause you
intersex traits i've been doing that
sort of a thing in uh intense four years
i don't have any tents running right now
which is kind of weird uh i've usually
got ten a tent going somewhere and i
always have it kind of sucking in a
little bit it's where when you unzip it
you kind of hear the tank go ah i was
getting sucked in a lot i do like that
uh negative pressure is what that is
called so that's not a problem that
shouldn't be causing it i really really
think it is you if you've ran these
plants before and you haven't ran into
intersex issues i'm going to assume
there is a light leak so go in there go
in the tent uh during your night cycle
when the lights should be off go in the
tent if you can if you can fit in there
i'm 6'5 it's hard as [ __ ] for me to go
in the tent
but go in the tent uh maybe you can look
around during the light cycle and see
what's in there is there an extension
cord that's got a light on it is there a
piece of equipment that lights up do you
have a do you have a hygrometer do you
have a thermostat do you have any sort
of equipment that is in there that's got
any kind of lighting on it does your
dehumidifier have a light on it do you
have anything in there that is producing
any kind of light during the dark cycle
because i really do believe it is a
light leak so if you can fit in there if
you can stand in that tent
in that space if you're i wouldn't fit
if you can fit in there go in there and
turn off the lights in the grow space
and leave the outside lights however
they would be in that room and see if
you're getting any light in that space
stand in there for three to five minutes
cover your eyes let them adjust when you
open them up do you see any any any
light at all if you can see your hand in
front of your face during the dark cycle
that is too much light also sometimes
those tents are not completely light
proof a lot of times i'll get just a
black sheet and put it over it sometimes
you got to run a strip of duct tape
right down the edge of the where the
zippers are just to cover up some light
leaks a lot of times near the corners
where the seams are kind of pulling like
where there's a lot of stress of one
seam going this way and one going that
way at a corner
you'll get some stretchiness of the uh
the material and you'll get like light
leaks down there that was harder to say
than it looked but you'll figure it out
so check for leaks that is my main
assumption i think i've spent enough
time saying light leaks on this one so
to my friend the man with no name big up
thank you for the message i hope we have
solved your problem if it is not a light
leak send me another message of course
the email address is grow from your
heart at
hotmail.com
all right now let's jump into the part
of the podcast that everybody has been
waiting for the part that i teased at
the top of the show i do have a breeding
question for you we've got a friend who
is breeding with the australian bastard
cannabis plant before i get too far into
this let's talk about the australian
bastard just briefly uh you may have
seen pictures of it you may have heard
about it you may have read about it you
may have seen our friend trey kdgc uh
highly ganginous she changed her social
media name and it threw me off uh big
shout out to trey k dgc she grew the
australian bastard she's playing with
the bastard
it is a very interesting looking
cannabis plant it does not produce
normal-looking cannabis leaves they are
kind of kind of ferny they look like
something you'd find out in a rain
forest or if you're walking along out in
oregon or something it looks like a very
organy
mossy area kind of a plant in my opinion
once again excuse me for the throat
clearing i will just blame that on the
dabs all day it's been a good weekend um
anyway it looks more like a plant that
you would find in a mossy area or
something like that in my opinion it
looks like something uh that grandma
might have in the mix of houseplants or
something like that so it doesn't really
look like a traditional cannabis plant
everybody that i've seen grow it uh it
does produce buds it doesn't produce an
amazing amount of trichomes or anything
like that but it does produce a very
unique looking plant so that is a
preface if you will for this email now
let's jump into the email part of this
question it goes
what's up bro i hope all is well i want
to try breeding out for the first time
this is going to be a very interesting
experiment for your first time breeding
i don't know that i would recommend this
for your first time although uh i'm the
kind of person that wants you to have
fun and do your thing i would recommend
to uh
more regular cannabis plants things that
you're gonna have just we'll talk about
why in the future just because you're
gonna have to breed this multiple
generations to see the results that you
want if that's what you're looking for
that's cool um that may be frustrating
it may be discouraging if you want to
see some results on the first run i
would work with regular plants but i'm
kind of uh no do your thing bro have fun
and do your thing live your dreams live
your best life you only live once all
that good stuff
anyway don't let me discourage you uh
that's just my advice it says i do want
to use humboldt seed company's freak
show it's kind of looks like a fern if
you haven't seen it yes i know exactly
what you're talking about a great plant
there are a couple of people out there
putting different versions of the freak
show out says i'm not really sure what
else i'm going to use anyway my question
is how do i get the offspring to look
like the freak show that is a really
good question
most of the time i would draw a punnett
square and we'll talk about punnett
squares in the future i'm not going to
teach a full punnett square and i would
be able to tell
i would be able to predict a lot of what
the plants are going to look like and a
lot of what the genetics are going to do
based on a punnett square also based on
so when i teach about breeding i say
learn about mendel charts and punnett
squares
learn about the way that the plants work
together when you breed them just learn
about the scientific part of that then i
follow that up by saying uh when you're
breeding forget all of that and use your
intuition because that's really uh i
find that to be super important as well
as a breeder i'd like to say that i'm a
successful breeder i've made some
crosses that are out there that are
paying some bills and people are really
happy with them so we'll call that a
success right um i've got intuition i
can just see some plants it's like have
you ever known two people and you're
like hey you and hey you if you guys met
it's gonna be [ __ ] a match made in
heaven and you introduce two people like
five years later they're married and
they got a family and you're like yeah
i'm kind of happy that i did that like i
feel like i've got that ability with
plants i understand the mental charts
the alien charts i understand that sort
of stuff but also i can intuitively see
the things that are going to kind of
happen with these plants
working with the australian bastard
however brings a lot of variables i'm
not familiar with that plant at all i
don't know a lot about its heritage its
history where it came from which helps
me a lot as a breeder as a grower to
kind of uh predict a little bit it's
like a lot of information it tells you a
lot of things about a plant when you
know its genetics its parents where it
came from on the planet uh what a lot of
it tell it lets you know a lot about
what to expect from it but with the
bastard i didn't know so i wrote um we
would have to find out if that funky
leaf trait that ferny leaf uh there's a
technical word for it we've gotten
what's the word that i found i learned
this word
um i can't find the word in this it'll
pop up when i read this i don't want to
lose my place though there's a word for
that funky leaf we have to find out we
have to determine if that is a recessive
or a dominant trait the way to find that
out basically is by
growing out a batch of it and breeding
with it and playing with it you have to
have experience with it
um
so then we have to decide do you want to
use a male or a female of the australian
bastard
then
from some i talked to a friend who is
grown and bred with the australian
bastard cannabis i'm leading up to that
i was going to wonder if you want to use
the male or the female then it turns out
that you're going to have to do some
f2ing before you even get a good
standard plant to start with
um
something i did want to talk about
before we get too far and i don't want
to discourage you from the bad the
australian bastard cannabis but i've
never seen anybody post pictures of
finished and i'm not talking trash this
is my experience on social media
nobody's ever posted a finished product
they've been like look at this amazing
australian bastard cannabis i've seen a
lot of people post like week five six
and seven photos and they're like look
at this crazy [ __ ] and then the pictures
kind of taper off it doesn't seem like
too many people are blown away ecstatic
super satisfied uh braggadocious about
the final product i'm not really trying
to talk [ __ ] i'm just saying that's what
i've experienced on the internet nobody
seems to the pictures are great but
nobody's like man when i smoke this i'm
on the moon i haven't really seen
anybody ecstatic and in love with the uh
bastard cannabis in that aspect it's
really cool for photos i may be cool for
breeding but i haven't seen anybody
blown away by any of the quality that's
just my opinion if you've got some
australian bastard cannabis out there
that blew your mind correct me send me a
photo send me an email grow from your
heart at hotmail.com i look forward to
friendly corrections and feedback i
invite that if you're just going to tell
me i'm a dick because i just said that
have some photos and something to back
it up i'm all about it let's be friendly
with each other i like that um let's
find my place in this message
okay so um you're gonna have to get
yourself some australian bastard
cannabis seeds that's probably how
you're gonna have to do this then you're
gonna have to grow them out
find a plant with the traits you were
looking for hopefully find a male and a
female with the traits you're looking
for and then you're gonna have to breed
those together uh you can at the same
time while you're doing this you can
pollinate other plants
but um those aren't gonna have the
bastard trait as strongly from some of
the advice i was given you're going to
have to make f2s before you can even
bring out that trade
to get it to pass
um
let me jump into this message that our
friend
i was talking with our friend locomotive
medical has been doing some breeding
with the freak show i just reached out
to a member of the team because i knew
somebody was working with it and i said
what can you tell me about breeding with
the freak show because i have a question
and here's what my friend locomotive
medical had to say it says the freak
show or the pinion leaf trait that's the
word i was looking for pin it
p-i-n-n-a-t-e pin it leaf trait is
recessive or at best and incomplete
dominant when you cross it with
traditional palmet plants the palmett
trait dominates the f1s and the f1s
mostly look normal so if you cross it
with anything one time that offspring is
going to look mostly like a normal
cannabis plant you may see some outliers
that do pop up with the bastard trait
but overall it sounds like most of them
are going to look mostly normal now it
says the f2s have some strange plants
and 25
freaks so this is where you're going to
start finding plants that you can narrow
down and isolate the uh the leaf
structure you're looking for
now you're also going to have to think
about
the terps the potency the structure of
the plant this leaf structure is just
one thing on a big chess board of traits
that we're looking for for a successful
plant that leaf trait is cool but what
else you want it to smoke good smell
good tastes good you got to get high as
[ __ ] from it or it's got to have a lot
of cbd or
a specific
something really high in a specific
cannabinoid or a certain interpreter
it's got to blow your mind in some way
it's got to produce seven pounds of
light or something like that to make it
stand out
make it a good plant overall it's got to
be pathogen resistant it's got to handle
nutrients well it's got to be growable
it's got to be enjoyable it's got to be
a good plant so that's just one trait is
the leaf that we're looking for so the
f2s will have some strange plants and 25
freaks so at this point i would find
another uh a male and a female that both
look like that have the leaf trait
you're looking for that pin it leaf uh
structure and i would breed those
together and make f3 now it says
f3 you can stabilize for that trait by
f3
similar to autoflower and photoperiod
outcross projects work so
by f3 you can lock it down
but
the first cross is going to look just
like normal plants you may find a couple
of weirdos in there but then you gotta
cross it again to start getting more of
that freak trade you're not gonna see it
until the second and then the third one
you can lock it in and my friend says
that's about all the tips i have for the
australian bastard cannabis that he does
so big shout out to my buddy locomotive
medical for having great info on
breeding um let's jump more back into
your message uh you want the traits to
come out you're trying to make it look
like the freak show so you're going to
take the freak to another plant the
first time you do that you're only going
to get about 25 percent freaks find a
freak that you like the one that works
the best for you
find a male and a female do that again
then find another male and a female they
work best for you and do that again by
the time you get to the f3 the seeds
that come out after that
should be quite a bit freak show
uniformity then you can find the
phenotype that works the best for you
out of there
then you can do a lot of things you can
self that you can start back crossing
things once you've got that gem that is
exactly what you're looking for which is
probably around the f3 range
then you can start doing a lot of fun
things with it
so i hope i did not discourage you by
giving you such a long path to success
maybe you're the kind of person that
enjoys a really long project like that a
lot of people
want to chuck some pollen make some
seeds and see what they made that is fun
f1s are great there's a lot of fun
diversity in there if you trust and know
your parent plants you can make some
great things
if you can predict what you're going to
make with an f1 if you can kind of write
down i think like my goal is this and if
it comes out like that that's fine make
f ones that are predictable uh that is a
good uh that's a that's a good product
in my opinion some people are not into
the f1s but um anyway i'm kind of
rambling if you're if you're excited
about having a long project i encourage
you to do this but for my first breeding
project i don't know that i would work
with this uh australian bastard cannabis
i may work with something different if
your goal is to fix the australian
bastard because i did say that i've
never seen one that impresses me when
it's finished i'm really not trying to
be rude i'm just saying uh we see a lot
of people post their grows and then we
see it all the way up to the end and
then we get to see them like harvest it
in the pictures they post a picture of
them holding the buds we don't see a lot
of that with the australian bastard they
all quit posting their pictures around i
don't know right after the buds start
forming and kind of where they should
get chunky and then they just fizzle out
with the photos not being hateful just
saying that's what i have seen mostly uh
so uh maybe you can be the person that
breeds something to it to correct it
maybe you can still get that australian
bastard cannabis leaf structure and the
growth the vigor the potency of some of
the other hype strains popular strains
productive strains that are on the
market now if that is your goal i do
wish you the best of luck if i can give
you any other guidance because i do not
mean to ever discourage anybody i would
just rather set you up for success
in your first run than watch you stumble
and be frustrated so if i can give you
any other guidance any other advice
please do reach out i look forward to
hearing back from you you know the email
address it is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
noobs and pros i want to thank everybody
out there for listening to episode
696 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative maybe it was
entertaining maybe you just like to
throw a couple of bucks our way for
taking some time to help you out all you
have to do is visit patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart once again
all the information is right there on
the screen
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
send me your feedback i do love the
listener interaction anything else is on
the website at iregenetics.com
make sure you check out the website for
uh the discord link vendor links merch
links all kinds of great stuff is on the
website once again iriegenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
big shout out to my buddy choke norris
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you