[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff and this is episode
698 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before we get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to black hippie let's send a
big thank you shout out to alabama man
and jethro earl let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to my buddy
311 let's send a fist bump to crazy hand
grows i want to send a thank you shout
out to spherical glass works let's send
a big fist bump to a long time supporter
a good friend my buddy gramps memel
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to the terp burglar let's
send a fist bump to verbal medicine and
single t then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to brohan78 big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and
you know i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends and yes i will put that
information in the show notes properly
the show notes properly and correctly
this time i will remember to do that
thank you for the gentle and subtle
reminders all right where do we go from
there let's just jump right into it i've
got a message from a previous episode in
the last episode i talked about my
strain grateful dog
i talked about an offshoot of grateful
dog that is known as 77 if you listen to
the episode you know what i'm talking
about if not give it a listen it's the
episode right before this titled
grateful dog you might enjoy it this
question goes like this it came from our
friend old ball coach and it says can we
in the irie army expect anything from
number 77 in the near future
thanks for what you do and then there's
more it says don't read this part on the
air so i won't read that part thank you
for that message i did read that part to
myself big respect nothing but love uh
the answer to your question though is uh
quick nah i don't have any plans for
number 77 for any uh commercial breeding
releases sometimes i do make and create
projects that uh kind of stick around
and they stay for myself for me to breed
with for me to work with 77 so far has
been kept a secret kept in the the
private reserve in the vault if you will
i have to have some things that i don't
release i have to have some things that
i can use as breeding stock in the
future if i release everything
you've got the potential to recreate
everything in my lineup you could
possibly recreate everything that i've
put out there if you acquired the right
strains did a little bit of homework did
some research did some final hunting did
some matching you can make a lot of my
line
however i do have some things that i've
bred that i have never put out there
i've got male plants that i've used that
i've never put out any of the seeds i've
got female plants i've pollinated that
nobody has ever seen those crosses i've
got kind of a secret arsenal my secret
weapons my hidden vault not everything
makes it out so there are some things
that have been played with with 77 but
nothing that will go out uh commercially
in the foreseeable future although the
market changes my ideas change my
opinions change sometimes you notice
that i uh i realize that some seeds have
been sitting in the vault in my secret
stash in my private reserve for far too
long and i begin to feel guilty about
that and i think those need to get out
to some friends and i will put those up
make them available for people in
certain avenues and certain places most
likely the discord server but that is
how i end up getting rid of some stuff
like that sometimes so maybe eventually
one day i'll decide that i've had some
of those number 77 cross too i'm not
even going to say what they've been
pollinated by or
anyway we don't need to talk about i
almost i almost decided to go up that
route but uh maybe one day i'll release
some of those 77 seeds through uh some
of the avenues that we do on discord or
other things like that but right now
there are no plans no intentions that is
one of my hidden gems secret vaults uh
secret weapons private reserves uh once
everybody is tired of all these stuff
that i'm putting out once king solomon
runs his course and gets boring uh once
the jack the ripper mail gets boring
once the blueberry cookies mail gets
boring once the golden goat mail gets
boring so we've got a lot of stuff to
run through
then maybe we may play with some of the
stuff from 77 i've pollinated that with
a couple of things maybe in the future
all right now i'm just rambling at this
point the quick answer nah bro no plans
to put that one out to the public gotta
have some private reserve some secret
stash
all right let me cut myself off from a
ramble and get to the next email here in
today's episode this one came from our
friend how did they sign this one this
one came from brian 420 big shout out to
our buddy brian brian420 thank you for
the great message this one goes a little
bit like this it says hey ross to jeff i
love your podcast you deliver well
structured accurate and free cannabis
knowledge and we appreciate it dude i
appreciate that compliment that's uh
basically exactly what i'm trying to do
deliver structured cannabis content that
uh new growers pro growers that every
grower can understand i want to uh
entertain and educate the guys in the
trim room all the way to the guys in the
lead of the grow maybe even entertain
the investors and the owners maybe even
encourage and educate some people who
are just curious about cannabis so what
was the old phrase uh if you're a new
grower pro grower i don't even remember
what we used to say old school smoker or
new smoker or even just curious about
the current state of cannabis some [ __ ]
like that that's what i used to say at
the start of the show i want everybody
to feel included involved and
participate uh somebody said that i do
talk to you guys like you've never grown
before and i said that's a good thing
because many of you out there never have
grown before but i also try to include
subjects topics and details that will
keep even the most experienced seasoned
veteran growers entertained i'm rambling
once again but welcome to the show if
you didn't know i was gonna ramble you
must be new here thank you for the
compliment brother that's where i'm
headed it goes on it says i've received
a pack of star struck seeds good
selection i believe those are sold out
in most venues i don't have any more i'm
not going to make anymore so you were
lucky to have those it says i've been
growing and just wanted to send you an
update i appreciate that i also must say
that the pheno i have is perfectly
structured a perfectly structured plant
it's beautiful from the aroma to
structure and resistance i can't wait to
oh we're going to skip that i can't wait
to send you some flower picks i thought
you're going to say you're going to see
me flower wasn't going to read that on
the air it says can't wait to send you
some flower picks as well as try to self
and reverse her with my
motivation pheno i've been working with
or i had to change pages here so there's
a lot going on there he says that the
starstruck plant is perfectly structured
uh that is part of why i selected it the
star dog plant they worked with that was
beautifully structured it was one of my
favorite in the commercial grow i gave a
very nice structure very wonderful aroma
beautiful bag appeal and like you said
here it was resistant to problems on a
commercial grow we would experience a
myriad of problems throughout the
seasons we'd get mites powdery mildew
there's always something to learn how to
battle in a new grow and the star dog
just didn't seem to get it that's part
of why i decided to
kidnap that plant and breed it uh breed
with it put it in my breeding program it
was a great plant just the original mom
plant
that's where a lot of these traits are
coming from is from that original star
dog then like i like to say arise king
solomon that it is just the fixer that
is the turbo charger that's like uh
sending it to training camp any plan you
put in the room with that it just went
through a six-week camp and it'll come
out ready for fighting uh it's ready to
make weight ready to tap a [ __ ]
out i am rambling it's been a good day
been smoking all the good [ __ ] let me
find out where i am in this message i'm
on page two
so our friend has found a star dog fino
they love they're considering reversing
it preserving it and crossing it with
their motivation phenotype they've been
working with and it says keep up the
awesomeness p.s a quick question this is
where the fun part comes in does a plant
does a plant's structure change with
maturity and then he says an example
nodes changing from growing across from
one another to staggered node spacing i
ask because i've experienced something
similar with a star struck clone it
looks structurally different from the
parent plant what do you think that's a
very good question brian i've got a
couple of different theories here a
couple of things that could be happening
possibly my first question my first
theory my first idea the very first
thing that comes to mind is where did
you cut the clones from if you cut it
from the main meristem you're probably
going to get the the symmetry the
symmetrical branching
that was harder than it looked to say
symmetrical branching you'll get that
from the main meristem however if you
cut from some of the side branches then
maybe you'll get some shoots or maybe
even the opposite on some plants it kind
of depends on how the plant grows
but
for most of my experience if you cut the
top you're going to get the symmetry if
you come from the sides you may get that
uh the opposites which you're talking
about staggered node spacing is what
you're saying i think my first uh
suspicion is that it would come from
location in which those plants uh those
clones particular clones were cut i have
no evidence of that i wasn't there i
didn't see anything i've got very
little information to go on i've got
about a paragraph about three sentences
here to work with so that is my first
guess
then
then let's just talk about some other
phenomenon uh that could be happening
there phenomena phenomenon things that
could be happening there i try to sound
like a professional sometimes i don't
know what the hell i'm even saying uh
some other things that we should keep in
mind is just phenotypical expression has
the room change is the environment
different that could make a big
difference in the way that the plant
grows i don't know that that would
necessarily change the uh the staggered
node spacing but that is going to make a
difference in the way that the plant
would grow in a different room i just
want to talk about that because that's a
fun avenue to go down phenotypical
expression if we took the same plant and
we cut 10 clones and we didn't take one
out of the main meristem we took it from
the branches all around the size we had
10 beautiful clones we gave them to 10
different growers to put in 10 different
rooms we may see 10 wildly different
results the flowers are going to look
smell taste
and affect us all differently based on
things in their grow first of all we've
got
so there's like lights air water soil
all that stuff to think about the light
is probably our first factor uh one
person a lot of people nowadays will
probably grow under an led some people
are going to grow under ceramic metal
halides somebody will grow under an hps
light somebody's gonna grow still under
a [ __ ] stolen street light that they
got from way back in the day uh
somebody's gonna use some cheap ass
blurple light somebody who's gonna use
the most expensive [ __ ] led on the
market so that's lighting that's right
there we've got so many variables the
guy using that hps that he stole
compared to the guy using the super
expensive led he's got that r switch on
there so he's giving him far red light
way different effects from those lights
compared to these uh the stolen shop
light and way different effect compared
to all of those compared to that ceramic
metal halide maybe someone's running a
t5 the whole grow lots of variables for
lighting that's going to give us
different shapes different structures a
different bud density is going to be
something we definitely notice from that
then let's talk about air it is
definitely going to be a different
temperature and different humidity
different basic vpd in every grow it's
going to be a couple of points off no
matter which grow we go to either the
temperature will be different the
humidity will be different the diurnal
swings will be different it's going to
be different in every grow i promise you
all of the grows you'll have noticeable
differences
that is going to affect plant structure
leaf shape and size bud density bud size
flavor terpenes aroma stickiness of the
overall final product that's going to
have a big role in your whole room the
vpd makes a big difference you got 10
different rooms one guy the guy running
that stolen hps he's probably got a hot
room also his buds are going to get
fluffy he's going to encourage more
limonine production he's going to have
taller more slender plants the guy with
the
the plant with the r switch on his led
his plants are going to be shorter
squattier maybe better node spacing
maybe denser buds there's going to be
differences throughout just because of
the lighting and the way that the
humidity are affecting each other i'm
saying there's going to be a lot of
variables let me get to the point here
because i can ramble on this forever
we've still got nutrients to talk about
we've got soil to talk about it could be
cocoa it could be hydroponic all of
these things are going to make a
difference in how the plants perform
you'll see different growth structures
shapes
the leaves can change size and shape not
completely drastically but they can
show you a little bit thinner leaf in a
higher humidity environment a thicker
leaf and a lower maybe even the opposite
it's all about where the plant came from
and how it is replying or reacting or
responding to the environment which you
have now stuck that plant in that is the
phenotypical expression that you're
gonna see so uh what you could be seeing
the short version of what i'm trying to
say is this could just be phenotypical
expression maybe the room has changed
maybe you're growing it in a different
room than you did before uh maybe it's
just changed also this plant is aging in
life if you're taking a clone from a
plant and taking a clone from a plant
the plant is continuing to age that
plant's as old as that original plant
that you started with so there is age in
that plant maybe it has changed um
it is not
genetic drift that is technically not
what genetic drift is but there is a
technical word that will not come to my
brain right now the plants basically do
change they can change over time uh
everything changes over time that is
very possible that could be happening
so my main three options are going to be
uh where you cut the clone from then
it's going to be phenotypical change
then also it's something with the
hormones and changes of the plant the
plant is just evolving it's getting
older those all three could be very
possible very likely culprits for what
is happening what you are experiencing
in your garden all right brian 4 20. i
think i rambled on long enough about
that one i want to thank you for a great
question if you've got any more
follow-up questions you know i'd love to
hear from you uh everybody the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy reach out i do
love the listener interaction
all right this next message comes from
my friend mud and it goes a little bit
like this it says ross to jeff i
recently purchased some morning dew reg
seeds from seeds here now big shout out
to our friends at seeds herenow.com it
says i would like to breed a plant to my
kim dog variety to introduce the
anti-powdery mildew anti-bud rot
properties to my cam so if you've been
following my brand or my podcast for a
while you know that my line morning dew
has been discovered that is very
resistant to powdery mildew and bud rot
the past couple of outdoor seasons we've
seen a lot of gardens get decimated by
powdery mildew and by bud rot the
morning dew we've gotten a lot of
reports that it withstood all of those
stresses plants next to it we're getting
mildew plants next to it we're getting
rot and the morning do withstood all of
the struggles
so our friend mud here wants to get a
quality morning do mail and breed that
to his chem dog varietal female now it
goes on to say i know it's your indica i
know it's your version of an indica i've
been following the podcast for a while
now and i haven't heard you speak much
about this is there a reason why
um no i just don't uh without being
prompted i don't really talk too much
about my strains i've done full strain
reports i think i've done a full strain
report on the morning dew talking about
the way it grows the way it smokes i'm
not sure if we knew about the uh
resistance to powdery mildew at the time
a lot more people have grown it the
plant has been the seeds have been sold
the plant has been experienced more so i
don't know how much of that i talked
about in that old episode uh there's no
reason i don't talk about the morning
dew or that it's being uh one of my
indicas or anything it's just uh like i
said i don't really talk about the
strains without being prompted you have
to ask a question which you did here so
we will talk about it um
and i talked about the grateful dog in
the last episode so uh the grateful dog
is the uh the morning dew is the
grateful dog pollinated by king solomon
and most of the phenotypes seem to put
off a
more indica type quality than the sativa
type qualities they finish more quickly
than most sativas the buzz is more
indica dominant it grows more with the
wider leaf type of a structure some of
the phenotypes do have skinnier leaves
but the plants stay short and squat and
the buds get dense uh more more like
what we know as an indica or what i
would qualify classify as an indica it
will get you in your head a little bit
when you smoke it but it's going to be
more that
i'm going to say more of an indica
varietal
than it says i haven't ever bred before
but i thought this would be a good cross
my kim has almost uh satsuma hazy funk
super triked out and the yields are no
problem but it does have a problem with
powdery mildew then it goes on to say my
question is two parts
do you mind if i breed with it it's for
personal i'm not selling the beans and
then can you give me a breakdown of what
type of phenotypes to expect in advance
uh you can call me mud as my friends do
and thank you in advance all right mud
thank you for the great message thank
you for the good questions let's answer
your questions about the morning dew and
breeding with it i feel this way about
all of my strains any seeds that you buy
from me
once you've given me or a vendor or a
trader or anybody money for those seeds
they are yours you can do whatever you
want with them and i can't be mad about
it you've paid money my job is to make
the seeds make quality seeds test them
make sure they're reliable get them out
to you at that point basically i got
paid my end of the bargain is up i make
sure you get quality customer service if
you have a problem if you have an issue
i'm here for that but
those seeds are yours grow them have fun
breed with them uh do what you must you
paid your money for them that's like me
telling you ah you can't drive your car
as fast as you want once you bought the
car once you bought the seeds bro
they're yours have a good time also
be respectful about that there is kind
of a breeder's code of ethics there is a
code of ethics you notice when i make a
cross i always list the true genetics of
what that cross is i reveal almost
everything to you guys i like to be
transparent i feel like you guys trust
me and believe in me because of my
transparency so in return whenever you
put out a seat or whatever you do
whatever you post a picture of it just
maybe put in little parentheses this is
ross to jeff's morning due to my uh what
was it called uh motivation i think you
called it or do it correctly uh when you
list genetics list the ladies first it's
always ladies first so girl plant x male
plant in the parentheses there but if
you ever talk about it list it advertise
it promote it if somebody says what is
that just give me a shout out give me a
fist bump give me some credit give me
some love that's all i ask for uh you
notice when i talk about um a lot of
strains that i work with a lot of
strains that i breed with i tell you
straight up who they came from who i got
the cuts from i didn't invent cannabis i
didn't invent seeds
i didn't just fart out a bunch of seeds
and start with those i had to get plants
and seeds from other breeders other
people that were putting out quality
products things i enjoyed trusted
liked
relied on was impressed by uh by
breeders that i like also if i only work
with strains from breeders that i enjoy
also you gotta be kind of a cool person
uh if i find out that you're not super
cool maybe i'll eliminate your plants
from my garden uh things like that do
matter to me at this point and i've got
the opportunity to be very selective and
picky at this point also
ah but i ramble on my point is once i've
sold you those seeds dude you could do
whatever you want with them i appreciate
that you like my seedline enough and you
trust in what i've said and the reviews
and you trust in the product enough that
you've chosen to breed that to your
seeds uh to try to make a better product
to fix the problem in there now you see
what i'm saying by uh saying that king
solomon is the fixer you're going to use
the morning due to try to be the fixer
you found the recipe to make your pie a
little bit better i am rambling so the
overall answer to part one of your
question is yes you do have full
permission to breed with the seeds that
you get from me
just give me give me some credit give me
some respect anybody out there if you
breed with my seeds
my plants my clones whatever just show
me love give me respect maybe
send me a 10 pack if you can not a big
deal honestly i don't have a lot of room
to run a lot of stuff but if it's super
intriguing you may see pictures of your
cross pop up on my social media pop up
in my crosses in the future maybe i'll
send you more [ __ ] and return we can
establish friendships in relationships
like that i try to get seeds back to the
people who give me clones and things i
try to keep the circle going all right
let me keep going because there is a
second part to our buddy mud's question
it says uh could you give me a breakdown
in the phenos to expect from the morning
dew
like i said i've done the full podcast
on the morning do uh if you search the
grow from your heart podcast morning do
there should be a full episode but we
will do a quick phenotype expectation
run down here since you're gonna breed
with it um there are three main
phenotypical categories and i've stopped
saying main phenotypes i'm going to
start putting phenotypes into categories
because
i'm a category kind of guy and it sets a
better expectation you're not looking
for this specific plant i like that
you're looking for specific phenotypes
but also i want you to find the one
that's good for you it's like if if i
say i like this phenotype you may pass
on the one that would have been stellar
for you because you chose the one that's
great for me and you could add something
better and i
i always explain like we went to a
restaurant you narrowed it down that you
want italian food and we sat at the
restaurant read the menu i'm gonna get
something garlicky with white sauce you
might want something with red sauce the
other person might not want any sauce
they might just get buttery pasta we've
all we've all established we want
morning dew but i might want a different
phenotype of morning do than you you
might want the cushy one i might want
the gassy one somebody else might want
the one with the berry funk at the end
of it so find the phenotype that works
best for you as my my bottom line my
best advice now the phenotypical
categories which you can expect from the
morning do
there is the og kush leaner there's one
that has got cushy rocks to it
that one grows it's got a stretchier
structure and it grows a bunch of rocks
that one is going to be great it's going
to be cushy gassy mothballs
real pungent then there's another which
i call the it's the chem leaning
phenotype which you can identify by the
acorn style buds
it doesn't grow real long buds it
doesn't grow real chunky rocky buds but
they're shaped like a pine cone they're
just nice perfect triangles and they're
all over the plant that phenotype tends
to turn a little bit purple a little bit
silver a little bit darker colors then
of course there is the arise dominant
phenotype that is the phenotype that
gets spears that is the one that makes
the long spears so if you've got rocks
it's going to be more cushy if you got
pine cones that's more chemi
if you get the spears that's going to
have a lot of a rise in it
now it sounds like in your situation
you're going to need a male plant so i
would find a male plant with a nice
structure just look for the one that is
shaped the way you want it to be shaped
you're probably going to get a five
maybe a ten pack of seeds maybe more
than that but out of the male plants
that you get the first if you've got a
10 pack you're probably gonna get five
males i would eliminate those first two
super hyper vigorous males just get rid
of them my reason for that is they're
going to add too much to the mix when
we're breeding most of the time the goal
is to kind of combine the two plants and
see the representation of both parents
in your offspring unless you're trying
to lock down one specific trait i like
to see what the male and the female can
do together if you've got a male plant
that is just too dominant in the mix
it'll wash out all of the traits of the
female and you're basically reproducing
that male plant so i like to find a male
that's not a real meat head not just
real
super aggressive super vigorous too
crazy to flower early uh grows real
crazy tall that's not the dude that i
would use if i had five seeds the third
and fourth seeds are probably the
candidates the third and fourth males to
show me that they're males uh to show
their vigor their aggression i guess it
is
those are going to be the two that i
start uh really eyeballing as my males
so find a good male find somebody with
good structure find somebody that
flowers at the appropriate time find a
male that puts out a decent amount of
pollen do the stem rub i like a male
plant so you're going to grow it the
morning dew
look for the one that smells like vomit
i know it sounds crazy male plants when
you rub the stem if it smells like acrid
puke that is always a good trait and a
male plant in my opinion that's just my
opinion that's from my experience i love
that disgusting acrid
vomit puke bar trash can gross smells
that always turns into a good male plant
that good puts out good terps and it's
uh and it's progeny the offspring will
always smell really good if the male
plant smells like vomit
so i would work on finding a good male
plant you're not going to see
the bud structure that we see from the
females because you're going to be
looking for a boy so find a good shape
find a good structure
find one with big thick robust stems
that you can work and bin and it doesn't
explode when you pop and twist it
because you want the progeny to keep
that trait as well find one that puts
out
pollen in the right amount of time
if you can finish this male plan out see
how far they go put a few male plants in
a room isolate them let them flower out
see which one you like the best do a
phenotype just like you do with the
females look at the bud cluster look at
the color do the uh do the male plants
put out any color are the male flowers
turning purple uh do they put out
trichomes do they smell good when they
put out buds then uh do they get
deficiencies do they handle your feeding
well do you have any bugs do those male
plants get beat up by bugs uh later on
in the life of the plant how bad do
those leaves start crinkling up how long
does it last that's going to tell you a
lot about the offspring what you see in
that male plant is 50 of what you're
going to see in the offspring so find a
a good combo a good pairing for your
plant that you call motivation i think
that is that's going to be so i say this
a lot when it comes to breeding
learn about mendel charts learn about
alleles learn about chromosome transfer
learn all of that stuff then forget it
all look at two plants and say those are
the two plants right there that need to
be bred together use the grower and
breeder intuition i think that will work
great for you understand the charts
understand the science understand the
biology
then
understand that you've got to grow from
your heart breed with love that's how i
have the greatest success i draw the
charts i think about the mendel charts i
really envision it in my head and then i
go no you know what that plant and that
plant right there need to make some
seeds and it's going to be [ __ ]
awesome most of the time i am correct so
develop your intuition check out the
plants like i said grow from your heart
the bottom line breed with love you're
making this cross for yourself you're
going to have a lot of seeds to play
with there will be a resistant phenotype
within that first mix you'll find a
couple a bunch hopefully in there you'll
find what you're looking for ah almost
no matter which male you select that
trait will pop up it'll be there it is
in the mix it's in the gene pool i do
believe you'll find that resistance
trait
it could pass on um i think that is all
i've got for this episode uh my buddy
mud uh thank you for the great message i
have got primus songs stuck in my head
now um also i did say there are three
categories of phenotypes i have another
note here there are some weirdos when
you're growing the morning dew you're
gonna see some weirdos some of them
start off kind of strange
be patient they grow right out of their
weirdness a lot of those morning do
weirdos they snap out of it and they
turn into beautiful amazing plants so if
you've got some weird [ __ ] happening
with your morning dew babies have no
fear they will grow out of it sometimes
we just have ugly babies not all babies
are beautiful i'm just kidding you guys
uh they'll grow right out of it though
all right that is all i've got for that
episode i think that's our for that
message and for this episode if you have
any questions corrections comments or
concerns you know that i would love to
hear from you the email address of
course is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy once again i do
love the listener interaction the
comments corrections feedback
constructive criticism it is welcomed
don't be shy also if you have anything
else check out the website
iriegenetics.com there's a link there
for merchandise the discord tab uh
vendors are there there's a contact tab
there where you can click on that
contact me there's a grow question tab
if you click on that type in your grow
questions those go right to my email
inbox it will answer your question here
on the show i look forward to more
questions load me up give me some great
content all right i think that is all
i've got for you oh yeah like and
subscribe this is the part where i ask
you to like and subscribe to the show
i'm trying to get the show to 10 000
subscribers before the end of the year
please click subscribe if you're
listening on an audio server
all you have to do is open up youtube
type grow from your heart click
subscribe that's all it takes you'll be
subscribed maybe watch the videos check
out the fancy 4k action i got going on
4k multi-cam
got a brand new blue shirt on check it
out see what you're missing have fun
with me all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pamps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts amazing cannabis activists
out there i want to thank you once again
for listening to episode
698 of the grow from your heart podcast
i say it all the time it blows my mind
when i talk about
698 episodes that is amazing to me
number 700 is coming up i don't have
anything special planned for number 700
uh high fives and fist bumps all around
however i do have some things planned
for episode number 710 i'm going to do
my best to get a very well-known
hashmaker on the show to answer some
hash questions we'll have some friends
from the discord uh give us some
questions so episode 710 should feature
a wonderful uh kind of a well-known
hashmaker in these parts if you've been
hanging out for a while you might know
who i'm talking about already don't want
to drop any names because it has not
been confirmed but once i confirm
i'll tell you all about who's going to
be on the show here for the 7 10 episode
uh we're going to talk about
concentrates on 710. if you don't know
what 710 is about you've got 12 episodes
you're gonna learn something today all
right that is all i've got for this
episode i'm gonna get out of here before
i keep rambling and make this a nine
hour show thank you again for listening
let's give a big shout out to my buddy
sam heads and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you