[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff and this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of grow questions before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to a longtime supporter our
friend brian p let's send a big thank
you shout out to our buddy triomph let's
send a thank you shout out to bongstein
bear i want to send a big thank you
shout out to blackhawks fan let's end a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
johnny appleweed let's send a fist bump
to nick p and canner reaper 413 let's
send a big fist bump into thank you
shout out to pack northwest dan let's
send a big fist bump to luke let's send
a thank you to frankie let's send a fist
bump to ivan munoz let's send a big
thank you shout out to thomas m then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our friend rut rowe
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends
speaking of making things easy for all
of my friends i got a very weird patreon
message i'm not going to say who it was
i'm not going to say their name i got a
question about i was straight up
relationship love and relationship and
family and marriage advice and i'm going
to say right now at the top of this show
that's not what this is about i am in no
way qualified to give you relationship
advice that sort of stuff this is a
cannabis growing show somebody paid
money on my patreon to ask me a
relationship advice question i asked if
they wanted their money back they did
not want their contribution back i felt
it very weird um i'm not the guy to come
to for that so uh that was awkward
that's all i've really got to say about
that i wanted to address that on the
show because first of all it was kind of
i thought they might be trolling me but
then i realized no this person paid
money for this uh they might be serious
so i contacted them i was like bro is
this for real i'm like yeah i need your
guidance and i was like i'm not the
person dude i'm not a relationship
counselor all i'm gonna do is say i'm a
42 year old single guy not the guy to
ask for relationship advice from uh i
just want to make it clear don't don't
send me relationship questions on
patreon you'll get your money back and
also that's kind of funny i thought it
was funny once i was like this is real i
don't know if i thought it was funnier
when i thought it was trolling or when i
realized it was real either way that was
my laugh of the week i thought i'd share
it with you guys
relationship advice on patreon that's
kind of funny maybe i should have taken
the money and given my best advice it
did not feel right i don't have that
kind of qualification you guys all right
let's jump into some real content here
on this podcast
i do have a patreon question here in
front of me that does come from a long
time patreon supporter who would rather
remain a not a mouse it goes a lot like
this it says hey ross to jeff i've never
heard you discuss the washing qualities
of your strains i plan on dabbling in
some bubble hash production and i've
wondered if you have any reports on irie
washing attributes if no such reports
exist which i restrain is the stickiest
of them all that's a very good question
uh what our friend here is asking is
about making bubble hash they're going
to there's a lot of good ways to do this
but let's just stick to the point
they're going to make some bubble hash
they're going to extract the trichomes
from the plants using
ice water ice probably some bubble bags
and some agitation that's the main way
to do it they're gonna freeze the
trichomes off the buds collect them
through some sort of a sieve bag that's
the way it's gonna happen here so our
friend is basically asking which irie
genetic strains wash the best because
they do plan to make some bubble hash uh
they're going to use uh bubble bags and
ice and water and agitation and remove
the trichomes from the plant material to
make smokeable concentrates some people
from there will press that make it even
cleaner and better uh some people will
just smoke the bubble depending on the
quality that they make there are a lot
of methods to doing that in the winter
time it's a great time to make bubble
hash because the colder uh your
environment the colder the process the
better the concentrate that is an
advantage of being here in colorado in
the winter time let me get myself back
on track our friend wants to make bubble
hash and to make the best hash they want
to know which irie genetic strains have
been known for making the best bubble
and the best wash concentrates i do have
some good feedback for you i can tell
you right away that the cream is
definitely going to be one of the best
washers the cream is amazing for washing
it rinses really easily it puts off a
lot of product it tastes and smells
amazing and most of the time the color
that comes from it is a real light white
color so it makes your washed product
product look really desirable really
tasty and the the buzz from it will sit
you on your ass it's the kind of buzz
that makes you just sometimes when you
smoke concentrates your brain will
wander when you smoke the cream you just
sit right back in your ass you find a
recliner and you lean back and you chill
out for a little bit that's what it'll
do to you so the cream is going to be
my very first recommendation however the
cream is getting close to being sold out
forever once the cream sells out i'm not
going to make any more um
nothing against the cream plant excuse
me nothing against that cream plant it
is just uh it's not something that i'm
going to work with anymore it's time to
move on i make some things i produce
them for a certain amount of time and
then sometimes i just simply move on i'm
only allowed to have so many plants in
the garden you guys know that and so uh
the cream the mom plant that makes the
cream has been eliminated i don't have
that plant anymore couldn't make more if
i wanted to i could have to it i could
s1 it however it is time to move on the
cream has done its thing uh it's worked
its course so i will not be making any
more cream seeds if you can find them uh
if you can get them i would get those
make some bubble hash with those
another line that would make amazing
concentrates is the dark hollow that one
makes more of that real
musky earthy garlicky scented
concentrate it's also real light in
color it washes really well i really
like the dark hollow concentrates now
let's talk about something else i was at
the dude grows cup and my friend kelvin
grew strawberry starburst and they
pressed the strawberry starburst into
rosin the rosin that pedro made out of
the strawberry starburst was some of my
favorite rosin i have ever smoked so if
you're going to press it maybe
strawberry starburst might be right up
your alley for the pressing concentrates
i also wrote down that the blue
raspberry truffle has made some amazing
pressed concentrates then we're going to
talk about the machine recently i was
gifted a batch of the machine so the
machine started off as machine fresh
frozen buds they grew the plant they
chopped it down they took off all the
big leaves and froze it almost
immediately then they took that and they
made bubble hash out of those frozen
buds from those frozen buds then they
pressed that in a press and made hash
rosin that concentrate put me on my ass
it made me totally goofy the entire time
i had that jar of concentrates around
my day was just half done it was like i
was multitasking but i was malta i was
actually multi [ __ ] things up i
wasn't getting anything done properly i
was doing 10 things at a time all of
them were failing it was a good thing
that concentrate was awesome but it made
me
stupid it made me dumb i did a podcast
and i don't really i don't recall that
podcast i know i did it i know i had a
good time and it was a good show
but i was in a bubble for the whole time
that machine concentrate wrecked me so
the machine makes great concentrates
something else i've noticed is that all
of the lemon strains that i breed make
really tall trichomes and those tall
trichomes seem to make good concentrates
so the lemon sunrise the lemon jeffrey
those seem to make really good
concentrates i don't know if it's the
tall trichomes i don't know if it's the
size of the trichome head i'm really not
certain i'm not a concentrate maker or a
trichome head expert so that is not my
area of expertise but i do know that
those lemon strains make amazing
concentrates
now i did say that i'm not the
concentrate maker let me tease an
upcoming episode for episode 710 i do
plan to have a concentrate maker on the
show i will ask them about the size and
shape of trichome stocks and heads and
see how much of a difference that does
make in our concentrate production
because i'm interested to learn that
type of thing too so i've been rambling
for quite a bit about
bubble hash recommendations let me kind
of recap a little bit and then also let
me you should keep this in mind um i do
smoke a lot of flour people are like do
you only smoke concentrates no i smoke a
lot of flour i just tend to take more
dabs when i'm on the go because uh to
get myself the buzz i want with flowers
i basically have to smoke an entire uh
big fat joint about about a two gram
three and a half gram joint i gotta
smoke that bad [ __ ] by myself to get
the desired effect uh and then i'm just
carrying a joint around or hitting a
bowl all day i could take a dab or two
dabs in just a couple of minutes and be
lit for a few hours a couple maybe two
and a half hours if i take a couple of
fat dabs i could be nice and heavily
medicated i would prefer a dab every
hour but when you're working when you're
busy
trying to be productive you can't be
sitting around dabbing all day so i try
to stay on the move that's why i smoke a
lot of dabs but i do love smoking a lot
of flowers i breed seeds i make a lot of
new creations
i like to test grow and test smoke and
enjoy my new creations i really love to
smoke when i create a new seed line and
give it to somebody local and they grow
it and they bring me flowers or bring me
concentrates i love smoking those
flowers i love smoking those
concentrates so i do smoke a lot of
flowers but i primarily have been
smoking concentrates lately since the
whole dab revolution fired up and uh
they're easily available readily
available kind of what i'm leaning
towards here kind of what i'm heading
for is i think i've accidentally been
breeding flowers that are geared toward
concentrate production i don't know if i
was doing it subconsciously or
consciously but i prefer to smoke
concentrate so when my harvest is ready
when all my flowers are done most of the
time if it's not a seeded product if
it's something i grew for myself at
least two thirds three quarters of it
gets allocated for concentrate
production we don't even trim it
not the way that we would trim it for uh
for smoking which we'll talk about our
concentrate gurus in a future episode to
see the difference between harvesting
and growing our buds if there's a
difference between growing for
concentrate and growing for flowers but
i allocate probably three quarters of my
my grow for concentrate making uh
concentrate production because i prefer
to smoke concentrate so i maybe
subconsciously secretly in the back of
my head have been breeding so that i can
have the best quality concentrates if
you think about it i've got strawberry
starburst that makes [ __ ] strawberry
concentrates who doesn't love a
strawberry concentrate lemon jeffrey
lemon concentrates who doesn't love a
lemon concentrated i kind of caught
myself accidentally breathing toward
that avenue most of my stuff is going
toward the most flavorable most potent
concentrates so i said i was going to
recap i don't know if i got to that part
uh bubble hash some of the best strains
i would recommend would be the cream
i've got great experience with the cream
making amazing bubble hash
then i would say strawberry starburst
then i would say blue raspberry truffle
then i would throw the machine in there
definitely dark hollow
then all of the lemon strains that i
make fall in that category for making
good concentrates i don't have good
experience i don't have the education
but i think something with the size of
the trichome heads they come from the
lemon skunk plant that i work with i
think that results in very good
concentrates it just catches in the bags
very well and i guess if there's a big
trichome had there's got to be a lot of
product inside of that trichome head as
well right that's where all the magic
happens
i'm not sure what i'm talking about all
right my friend who would rather remain
anonymous i want to thank you for your
great message i also want to thank you
for the generous patreon contribution
that does not go unnoticed thank you for
that i look forward to hearing more from
you if you have any more questions
please do reach out uh he wrapped this
up with take care bro oh also uh which
is the stickiest eye restraint of all i
think sticky is going to be uh kind of
more about your growing and breeding
environment it's all about uh if your
room is dry your weed won't get real
sticky if your room is kind of humid if
you've got the proper vpd your weed will
get sticky it's got the potential the
opportunity to get sticky then in the
dry and cure process you've got to baby
that weed and keep it just right spongy
gooey but not not juicy you want to kind
of ah that's that's the fine line right
there that's where you get the
stickiness i think that comes from the
dry and cure i think anything out of my
line properly grown properly dried and
cured has the potential to be the sticky
icky all right dude once again thank you
for the great question let's keep it
moving
all right this next message comes from
our friends at cedar city canada and it
goes a little bit like this it says hey
ross to jeff thank you for all the
knowledge and info you drop you are very
welcome thank you for listening and
watching it goes on it says i'm
cultivating indoor hemp because i live
in a prohibition state ah be careful you
still may need uh hemp cultivation
licenses don't think that just because
it's hemp and not cannabis that you
can't get in any trouble uh side rant
random stories sometimes these are
people's favorites favorite parts of the
podcast we had some friends who were
growing cannabis outdoors they possibly
allegedly may have been over their legal
limit of how many cannabis plants we
were allowed to have in the region in
which they were growing the police came
actually uh zoning came it was zoning it
wasn't even the police because in
colorado if you've got a certain amount
of plants over your limit
and you don't seem like you're into a
criminal activity or a criminal
enterprise they just send zoning so far
it's a zoning violation so they sent
code enforcement and code enforcement
comes up and they're like sir it seems
that you have too many cannabis plants
and my friend said what if i tell you
their hemp plants and he said well then
we're going to go get the department of
agriculture and find you for your
illegal hemp plants but if you've got
illegal cannabis plants we're just going
to make you cut those down until you've
got your limit so the options were if
they were cannabis plants we were going
to cut them down until we got to our
legal limit we were allowed to have
explants we had x plus question mark had
to cut down all the question mark get to
x while the while the uh department of
the code enforcement guy watched he
basically was like pick them out cut
them down that's all i care about and so
the plants got chopped down if they were
hemp
we would not have had they would not
have had the option to cut down the
parts the plants in the question mark
those would have been illegal hemp
plants and we would have been fined for
growing hemp without any licensing
that was a weird dynamic to experience
that day that luckily that zoning guy
was pretty cool he was just an older guy
he didn't want any [ __ ] didn't want any
trouble wanted to come out and say hey
the neighbors say it smells like [ __ ]
dank weed out here you got too many
plants i can't really say much other
than cut down the plants and if those
are still here in a few days the law
will come and we're like well [ __ ] we'll
just cut down the plants and the plants
went choppy chop chop into the compost
bin that was that uh we were allowed to
finish the crop with the legal amount of
plants in that area
i told you i was gonna get rambling so
be careful with your hemp plants that is
the main point of that story um let's
get back into this i live in a
prohibition state and i am on the be
careful growing anything in a
prohibition state my friend uh please do
it says i'm on the fence with breeding a
cbd cultivar i like that uh with your
breeding expertise um that might be an
exaggeration but i appreciate that would
it matter for thc sake which was the
male versus which was the female say an
orange gasm let's not say orange
gasoline because orange gasms uh fem
seed and it's got to be uh this will
that it may work in here but i just want
to keep in mind orange gas ms femme and
that bell went off and the breeder
salesman side of my brain say orange
gasm pollinated by cbd cultivar that is
possible so you've got a female orange
gasm pollinated it by a high cbd
cultivar or
pollen from a reversal reversal or a
male thc to the cbd cultivar i see what
you're saying thc male to a cbd female
or the opposite either way
i know you do not grow hemp but if you
add any advice or knowledge on the
pollen donor versus the receiver that
would be helpful thanks again um then
something cut out here looks like my
printer by the way something is oh i
think it says orange jasmine is fire the
emojis did not print here that's what
happened uh by the way the orange gasm
is fire thank you bro i appreciate that
uh let's talk a little bit about
breeding for cannabinoids you're trying
to create a high cbd cultivar by or yeah
high cbd cultivar by starting with a thc
and a cbd high strain so when you do the
first cross
when you make that first cross so a lot
of you're asking mainly if it matters if
we do the male or the female it all
matters um
i don't think it's going to matter which
is the male and which is the female it's
going to work it's going to come down to
your selection the first cross is going
to open up pandora's box um it kind of
depends on which plant also it depends
on which plant carries the dominant tree
which one uh dominates the mix i've
talked about this in previous episodes
when we're breeding a lot of the times
the goal is to mix the plants together
to get two traits of a plant one
traits of one plant traits of another
plant mix those into one plant you hope
to see those traits uh those alleles
express themselves and the progeny uh
sometimes you see weird [ __ ] sometimes
you see stuff from the grandparents
sometimes you don't see what you're
expecting
but it all depends on the dominance
codominance uh and not dominance of the
genes of the traits of that plant
sometimes i've talked about uh using a
male plant that is too dominant excuse
me a male plant that is too dominant in
a mix imagine if you've got like just a
dude that's just
beastly all the time yeah he can't think
real well but he could [ __ ] move a
refrigerator with his left hand and
you're just an ogre just a real ogrely
male maybe you wouldn't want to breed
with that ogrely male because all the
offspring are just going to be [ __ ]
flat forehead narrow eyed ogres we don't
need a bunch of ogres in the offspring
you want to see some of the female in
the cross so i would skip those real
meathead ogrely male plants
because those are going to be due to
dominant if you've got a male or a
female plant that could happen on either
side you could have a super powerful
[ __ ] femme queen on one side or an
ogrely dominant male on one side and
that will dominate your mix and then
your cross is just going to be more
representations of the male or female
the cannabinoids are going to transfer
the same way if the male plant carries
the thc and it's a super dominant plant
you're going to see a lot of thc in the
offspring if the female plant is super
dominant in the mix and carries the cbd
you're going to see that or vice versa
however it works just depends on kind of
which plant is dominant and it's gene
passing a lot of times we'd hope to see
a perfect 50 50 mix which is how it
works but expression you're gonna see
weird [ __ ] so now let's talk about the
weird [ __ ] we're gonna see
um in my experience from my what you
called expertise which i'm not sure i
qualify for but thank you
when we first make this f1 cross with
these varied cannabinoids in my
experience in my prediction and with my
expertise uh what i've seen what i think
will happen is the f1 the first cross
you take your either way i don't it
doesn't matter if you've got a thc male
or a female cbd male or female you got
cbd and thc male or female we're going
to cross them bad [ __ ] the first time
you're going to get very high cbd
cultivars you're going to find very high
thc cultivars then you're going to find
things in the middle and everything in
between you're just gonna open up
pandora's box and get a little bit of
everything at this point i would find a
female that is obviously high in cbd i
would try to do lab testing that's the
best way to find cbd if that's really
what you're looking for find the one
that is the highest in the cbd and
lowest in thc
you also need to find the good grower
the one that grows well so do the phenol
hunt find the one that works best for
you
find the plant that looks like how you
want your finished project to look like
what do you want the plant structure to
be like how do you want it shaped you
want long spaces do you want short
internal structure do you want long
branching do you want short branching
what kind of plants are you into growing
find the plant that grows the way you
need it to grow for your purpose or the
plant that is going to reach your goal
so now you've selected a female
from the f1 progeny find a male from the
f1 progeny that looks just like that
girl if you can similar leaf shape
similar node structure similar
everything find its twin except it's a
boy then cross those two pollinate that
bad [ __ ] now you've made the f2s
in those f2s we're going to find a lot
of crazy [ __ ] we're going to find uh
grandparents and great grandparents
expressing themselves but we are also
going to find
beautiful representations of exactly
what we're looking for for the f2 we
found exactly what we want in this batch
you're going to find that exactly the
one with the cbd the growth structure
exactly what you want in this batch then
you're going to find a male and you're
going to do it again now we're making
the f3
now at this point we're actually
beginning to lock in that cbd dominant
trade we have found the plants so the f1
uh when you make that f1 it's going to
be wild you're going to have a lot of
stuff f2 even more wild but there's
going to be a solid plant in there to
work with then you're going to use that
f2 to make f3
the f3s are going if we selected
correctly the f3s are going to start
showing us exactly what we're looking
for if we did this correctly
at least 50 of the plants we grow should
look like the plant we are looking for
maybe closer to 60 maybe 70 it depends
all about your selection so at this
point here we go again find the plant
that works very well for you the one
that makes the cbd the low thc the
flavor you want that grows the structure
shape time all of the attributes that
you need find those alleles for you find
that plant find the female find the male
here we go again let's pollinate let's
cross them now we're making f4 now at
this point your percentage of your uh
stability this is where the word
stability really does come in here uh
this is where your stability will come
into play you're going to start
increasing the stability every time you
do this if you select correctly if you
don't make the right selection you got
to go back to that f2 the f3 wherever
you were wherever you did see what you
liked go there maybe the step before and
rework that select different plants from
the mix
so just keep working this by the time
you get to f4 you should be really close
to what you're looking for by the time
you get to uh f5 you'll have what i
called what i wrote down as reliable
stabilized phenotypes most of the
phenotypes are going to come out looking
like the plant you're looking for by the
time you get to f6 you've got basically
clones you're growing
probably 95 98 of the seeds you toss out
are going to look exactly the same so it
doesn't really matter uh which plant has
the thc which one has the cbd that first
time you cross it you're gonna you're
gonna get the the whole mix of [ __ ] the
second time you're gonna get an even
wider mix of [ __ ] find the plants you
like keep moving forward and fill your
generation with your goal in mind take a
lot of notes
never be afraid to go back if you messed
up and you're not seeing what you want
in the f3 f4 go back work the f2 again
start there
then take a lot of notes see what did
and what did not work also here may be a
useful tip when you were working with
these plants you've got a couple of
options you can take
the um you can take one male and you can
pollinate multiple females what is
stopping you from taking one the select
male uh from your f2 population and
pollinating three females you got the
tall one the short one and the squatty
one pollinate all three of them mark the
seeds and grow those and see which one
of those you like the best what is
stopping you nothing's stopping you from
pollinating multiple females so
pollinating multiple females each round
will give you
multiple avenues to work with then you
can always cross those lines together if
you get one that has the structure you
want and one that's got the cbd that you
want later on cross those together
that's always a fun work parallel line
should i talk briefly on parallel lines
so in your first project you were
working strictly for cbd right so let's
just breed for cbd on this side all
we're looking for is cbd maybe growth
also because you have to have stable uh
plants that can support themselves
strong healthy vigorous plants is the
word i'm looking for so we're looking
for plant growth and cbd on one side we
just breed for that
you just just just like i said before f2
look for cbd and plant growth f3 for cbd
and plant growth all the way up to f5
maybe f6 on another project we're using
the exact same seeds except we're
looking for different attributes let's
say we're looking for
maybe it puts out a super strong grape
aroma so we're going to breed other
plants over here and we're looking for
nothing but grape aroma so we're going
to grow them and all the plants don't
smell like grapes they get tossed we're
gonna f2 the grape smelling plant gonna
find an f2 that smells like grapes we're
gonna have three that f4 f5 f6 where
every time we grow it it just smells
like grapes every time then we cross our
cbd dominant cultivar to our grape
cultivar and we breed those together and
you get [ __ ] grape cbd out of your
line a true f1 that you've created all
the way from f f yeah that that feels
really fun to do right that's a lifelong
project uh maybe something to think
about that's just what i was saying when
i say parallel lines i said it had to
ramble about it thanks for listening to
that i hope you learned something on
that let me get myself back on track
here because i did freestyle most of the
info coming out of this question here a
lot of this is going to rely on your
selection luckily now we've got science
we've got labs um
you can do predicative testing if you're
looking for cbd you can take snippets or
tissue samples of all of your plants and
send them to the lab and they can say
this plant has got the precursor for a
lot of thc or the precursor for a lot of
cbd and you can toss those high thc
plants and keep those high cbd plants
now you're just breeding out of uh
you've already got half your population
eliminated half your work is done for
you you know those cannabinoids are
going to be there now you can grow for a
structure uh the other traits which you
are looking for you can focus more on
that predicative testing will really
help you out if that is available
affordable cost effective that will
really speed you up in this program you
can identify the presence of cbd
precursors
early and vegetative growth yes i know
that sounds crazy but then you can get
rid of all those thc plants early and
just breed for cbd that will definitely
help you move forward in your
generations all right my friend i folded
up the paper you wanted to be called
cedar city can i make sure you follow
them on instagram it's cedar city canna
big shout out big thanks for the great
message
i hope i answered your question you did
ask uh which mail in which female the
traits would come from but i think i
gave you a good answer to your question
if you have any follow-ups to that i
would love to hear from you the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me those
questions corrections comments concerns
positive criticism what is it
constructive criticism positive feedback
i look forward to all of the above
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers all of you
amazing cannabis enthusiasts out there i
want to thank you once again for
listening to episode
699 of the grow from your heart podcast
it does blow my mind every time i say
that
super high numbers 700 is next 710 is
coming i'm super excited um i think
that's all i'm going to ramble on for
this episode i look forward to seeing
you in the next show make sure you check
out the patreon page at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart uh
what else do we got for you the website
iriegenetics.com
thanks again for watching you guys will
be back in a couple of days with fresh
content let's give a giant shout out to
my buddy smoke what and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you