[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 70 of the
grow fromy heart podcast your source for
Cannabis News education and conversation
that's right if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're
a cannabis activist or even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host roster
Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I want to send a big huge thank
you shout out to the Mystic Roots band
for letting me use their music on the
show thanks to cat CP and the entire
Mystic Roots crew the song you're
listening to right now is called the
doggy dub make sure you support my
friends in the Mystic Roots crew what's
up everybody I've got a great show put
together for you to C for you guys I'm
going to turn that now that's really
distracting just cut that right out
there we go so I got a few things I want
to talk about first I want to give a
huge shout out to everybody that's
helped me out this past week um I was
driving up to Colorado Springs to go see
our good friends hunt and damsel and of
course the Jordans and of course John
randles Jr was headed up there to
Springs was going to go pay them a visit
and uh the [ __ ] transmission went out
on my car about uh a mile from Colorado
Springs I could see the first exit in
Colorado Springs I could see the damn
Circle Drive Lake Avenue sign right in
front of me but I just couldn't get off
the highway my car pretty much exploded
it felt like I was doing a good 75 mph
on the interstate in the rain uh it felt
like my car downshifted uh from 75 I
immediately was going about 45 miles an
hour uh it sounded like uh sort of like
and then it was like is what it felt
like to me uh it felt like my engine was
trying to jump out of the car and into
my lap so of course I hit the brakes uh
signal got over as quickly as I could
got to the side of the road turned on
the hazards C AAA it took AAA they
quoted me 85 minutes to get there they
got there in 65 so uh [ __ ] 85 minute
is a long 85 minute wait is a long wait
65 minutes was less than what they
promised me so I guess that that's a
good job on aaa's part I made friends
with the triple a tow truck driver I
wish I had your business card with me
right now in my pocket but I have said
it somewhere uh you know what it's
actually in the car that's broken down
that is at the mechanic shop so once I
get your card out of there I'll give you
a shout out on the show because the
truck driver was a cool guy uh they did
a great job they were super they had to
tell me about 50 m home get me back to
the house but I'm here I'm safe I don't
have a car for a little bit here we're
figuring that out it's going to cost a
little bit to get that son of a [ __ ]
fixed but anyway trying to move on
trying to have a good week uh we are
going to talk about cannabis here but I
want to talk a little bit first uh you
guys know that I hit my head at the
beginning of April right and it is now
I'm recording this uh the date is May
14th as we
record uh I feel like I'm getting it
back together so much you guys I want to
thank you for tolerating my [ __ ]
while I've had a head wound uh I know
I've been goofy I really do I wasn't all
there I apologize you guys that stuck
with me you're my friends I love you
thanks for supporting the show thanks
for being there while I was kind of down
uh I want to talk about a product I
ordered online I've been taking
something called alpab brain you can get
it at on it.com there's two NS in that
it's o nnit t onit Labs makes a lot of
great products I'm going to reach for my
bottle of alphab brain right here hold
on all right I got the bottle in my hand
alphab brain is a complete Earth grown
neut Tropic with Al GPC and ac11 I know
that sounds like a bunch of [ __ ] to
you guys but um they say that uh
lecturers Educators uh speakers public
speakers radio personalities and folks
like that use Alpha Brain uh the guy
that inspired me to use it is Joe Rogan
when Joe Rogan does his podcast he takes
a couple of alpab brain when he does the
UFC events he uh announces commentates
on the UFC's he does three Alpha Brain
pills for that I've been taking two a
day and I can feel a sharpness in my
brain my vocabulary is stronger um I had
a problem after I hit my head I would
try to recall words and I'd say hey can
you hand me my my and I just couldn't
think of what basic words were like
screwdriver or flashlight sometimes I
would just forget words but the Alpha
Brain is making that [ __ ] come back to
me uh it's making me a better speaker
it's making me remember and recall more
uh it's making me calmer I've described
it as maybe I've said this on the show
maybe I'm full of [ __ ] with my memory
thing but I've described it as a my
brain has the main track that's
happening there's like the you got to
wake up you got to poop you got to brush
your teeth you got to get to work on
time you got to do your chores you got
to call this person you know that track
is playing in your head but there's
always that side [ __ ] that goes on
in your head like taxes and it just
Whispers at you occasionally or I wonder
what that girl's doing or I miss
somebody or just [ __ ] that happens
in your head that you really don't need
to be focusing on right now I feel like
weird things pop up into your head and
the Alpha Brain has kind of quieted that
secondary track so where able to focus
on what I'm supposed to focus on which
gets me to my point the podcasts are
getting much better you guys I'm going
to make the podcast a lot better much
much better so shout out to alphabrain
shout out to onit Labs um I take two a
day and I definitely feel um I'm more
talkative but it's because my thoughts
are more clear and I can put together
much better sentences much better
podcasts definitely oh dude I got the
phone on loud here that's ridiculous me
put that [ __ ] on silent I apologize
that's very unprofessional podcast
Behavior here we go after phone on
silent uh so I want to talk about
another product um you heard us talk
about Floria on a previous podcast
episode Floria is a medicated personal
lubricant which means it is a uh it's a
sexual lubricant that contains cannabis
uh somebody heard that I talked about it
on the show and they gave me a product
called evos and from what I can tell
evos and Floria are very very similar
fairly similar was what I wanted to say
uh they are both coconut oil and fused
with cannabis and they are meant to be
applied to you know the instructions
pretty much say apply it to the female's
parts so I'm going to be straight up
about this I got some uh evos and I uh
sprayed it up on my partner's goods and
uh it made a difference it definitely uh
there was nothing to complain about
before everything was going just fine
but when we added that stuff it made it
a little uh it made my junk warm it felt
like she it's already warm I know but it
felt a little warmer and tingli it made
stuff feel a little more alert like it
was definitely a heightened experience
and she agreed she said that it was
definitely a heightened experience uh
it's just coconut oil and cannabis so I
had no uh worries about putting it on my
body or in her body or whatever uh it
washed off really cleanly and really
quickly uh one funny thing that I said
when I was done and I'm sorry if I'm
being too explicit you guys but it's my
podcast and I'll talk about my dick if I
want uh when I was done uh I was I felt
I wasn't around I was okay I was all
done and soft right I'm all floppy but I
felt like my dick was Fluffy like I've
given somebody a massage with apana
lotion before and I've explained my
hands like feeling like I was wearing
Mickey Mouse gloves my dick felt like it
was Fluffy like to the touch if I would
touch it I felt like it was thicker than
it was that's a weird uh okay enough
about my dong on the show but I tried
the evos and uh if you're looking for
something to add to the bedroom fun and
you want to go to the dispensary and
spend a few bucks uh there was nothing
wrong with evos it worked I would use it
I would do that again if you're
listening let's do that again so we
talked about Alpha Brain we talked about
evos let's change the tone a little bit
this is something that is not good that
happens um I was trying to explain to a
friend something and I don't know the
science behind it but I know that this
is happening when my dab rig gets dirty
my chunk of globby resin in there and
this probably applies to the bong with
bong resin if you're just smoking flower
but I've noticed that when I'm hitting
the dab rig um once the rig gets dirty I
feel like that chunk of res in there is
actually stealing part of my dab I feel
like when you've got a big floater if
you look at my rig right now there is
like a quar gram of hash just floating
in my rig water and it's not old the rig
water's only been in there for three or
4 days at the most we just dab heavy the
seil never turns off you guys it's like
the coffee pot it turns on at a certain
time in the morning and then it goes off
right when I go to bed so I'm taking big
fat Globs right I'll clean the rig and
take fat Globs fat Globs I get super
baked like just like I should but as the
rig gets dirtier I stop getting high and
stop choking and stop enjoying my dab as
much as it gets dirtier I think that
chunk of resin in there collects the
resin that's the smoke it collects all
your canabo and your smoke and your
whatever you're trying to get it sticks
to that ball and it's ripping you off so
my point clean your [ __ ] rig go get
some rubbing alcohol if it's really
super sticky get yourself some kosher
salt fill the rig halfway up with
alcohol put a little bit of kosher salt
in there the salt is working as an
abrasive it's going to scratch all that
resin off of there cover up both
holes go somewhere you got a carpeted
floor if you're a pothead and just shake
the [ __ ] out of that rig and the reason
we're going to the carpeted floor is so
that when you drop the rig you you have
a better chance of living uh just be
careful just go shake the [ __ ] out of
that rig and then uh yeah I know it's
disgusting but just pour all that
[ __ ] reclaim right down the drain and
get rid of it you don't want that I know
a lot of people that use it I'm not
going to hate on you if you do I
wouldn't use it especially if you just
mix alcohol into it but flush that [ __ ]
right down the drain get rid of it and
then rinse the rig out a couple of times
with super hot water let it dry let it
cool down to a normal temp fill it back
up with water the right uh depth what is
that a right amount of water whatever
the right level throw your nail on there
and get down on some clean tasty dabs
and enjoy the flavor of your dabs again
I really think a clean rig is more
important than uh people realize all
right that's enough of that PSA I've got
more [ __ ] written down here what else is
next um somebody was asking me I got an
email or a Facebook message I cannot
recall where it came from right now but
somebody was asking me about rig
selection how do I choose a good rig
personally if you're dabbing uh I prefer
a small rig over a big piece the reason
we used to smoke pot out of a giant bong
is so that you can fill all that space
with a big thick chunky hit of smoke and
then when you pull that carb or you pull
the bull out or you take your finger off
however you carb your B your bong if
you're from the 70s you just take your
finger off that hole in the back if
you're from the future you got to pull
the stem out when you carb it you're
supposed to get all that [ __ ] smoke
into your lungs right at once boom you
just got a big old bong hit that's why
you get baked from the bong that's the
purpose fill that piece clear it get all
your smoke when we're smoking
dabs your dab is just burning up right
when you put it on the nail and you
start smoking and you're getting it I
don't think we need a big ass piece for
a dab I like a little tiny rig to where
when you put it on there you put the
carb cap on there you inhale you get
that smoke right to your face we're not
trying to build a whole bunch of smoke
into one chamber and then clear it we
just want that dab to go through the rig
through the water to cool and then into
your face so my main recommendation is
something kind of small my favorite rig
and you're going to think I'm crazy but
my favorite rig is my Hitman side car
it's just the right height I'm thinking
that's probably 5 in tall something like
that if you go up to the mouthpiece it's
probably s inches tall um it's a little
rig I like my mad Rob rig that sucker is
probably 4 in tall at the most um you
don't need a lot of percolation on a rig
uh if you've got something that gets
plenty of bubbles you don't need a lot
of diffusion all you want to do is calm
cool your dab smoke you don't want it
coming off of that hot nail directly
into your lungs so you put a little
water through there just enough to cool
it like I don't like a lot of water on
my rig and also I think over percolation
on a dab like if you've got too many
sections of water you're kind of
overdoing it I like the Toro cans that
have the the tree perk and then it's got
the little shower head perk in the
middle those are great but my favorite
is the Hitman uh I really do like the
mothership rigs those things hit like a
boss but you're looking at like 2500 to
3,000 for a rig if you're asking me for
advice you don't need advice on a mother
ship uh get yourself a nice Hitman rig
don't be afraid of uh you don't have to
buy name brand glass just keep in mind
that if you're buying Chinese made glass
there's probably some Chinese little kid
making it in unsafe conditions they
don't have good eye protection they're
probably Barefoot just try to if you can
buy some American Glass do that it's
worth the extra few bucks just to know
that you have ethically made glass I
think it's some Karma uh like I said
hitman's a good company they don't
support the show or anything but they're
always innovators they lead the glass
game in my opinion if you want to go
expensive get yourself a uh a coil or
some beer glass or something like that
coil is going to be ridiculous you guys
I'm just talking about my favorite rigs
here one thing I'm going to mention so
get a small rig without without a lot of
percolation uh something that keeps the
nail a little bit away from your face
when you're checking out these rigs at
the store try to put the nail that
you're going to buy right on that rig
and then see how far away that nail is
from your face cuz I don't really like
the nail higher than the mouthpiece or
real right in my face I need it a couple
inches away from my nose so that I can
see where I'm putting the dab I don't
want to go
crossy all right the important part the
most important part when you're buying a
rig is the nail that's what you're
heating up to a couple hundred degrees
that's what you're putting your extract
on it's going to be heated and cooled
and heated and cooled all the time oh
excuse me I'm burping here I'm going to
take a drink right quick excuse me
all right I apologize for the silence I
needed a drink um so get a good quality
titanium nail the only brand I will
recommend for titanium is highly
educated titanium they make a nail for
your rig no matter what you're trying to
do Highly Educated has got the perfect
nail for you I promise if you need
guidance on the nail hit me up send me a
picture of your rig I'll tell you what
kind of nail to
buy um I do really like the quartz nails
if you get a good quality quartz nail uh
I recommend the Halen honey hole if you
do big fat dabs if you're into smoking
solventless and BHO definitely get the
honeyhole it holds a lot of heat for
when you smoke solventless it's got a
lot of room to get a big solventless dab
in there I also like the quave Banger um
the qu Banger is going to be a little
bit pricey but they are awesome they
taste super clean uh who just made the
trough was that Joel Halen that just
made the trough I not had a chance to
try the trough yet but they look amazing
if it's made out of good quality quartz
I bet it's going to be a good quartz
Banger uh there is a company that is
selling uh they call them quartz bangers
it's the nail that uh it's quartz it
looks like a faucet spout kind of with a
little bucket at the end of it you put
your dab in the bucket part um guys
there's a company that's selling those
that's claiming their quarts and they
are glass be careful you don't want to
buy glass and reheat it and let it cool
and reheat it and let it cool it's going
to break you want a good quartz piece
quartz can handle the
[ __ ] also we go back to that stuff
talking about what's made in America
what's made in China try to do that with
your quartz products also uh get a Halen
honey hole get a real quave Banger or
get yourself a real Highly Educated
titanium nail those are the only Nails I
will support on this show so come on
guys send me some Nails not really I'm
just kidding I've got all the nails I
can use right now uh so good nail is key
that's the point here also recently I
discovered something that the people in
Colorado may be excited about
occasionally uh kind love in Denver has
occasionally been putting out clones of
my lemon Jeffrey they were uh they
actually bought seeds from me at an
event they bought several packages of
seeds and they ran the lemon Jeffy and
they found their phenotypes that are
killer I've seen the lab tests uh
they've tested from the 24 to 26s and
they actually said that they could have
grown the herb better but there was an
issue so that means that next time
you're going to see 28 to 29% on the
limit Jeffrey from kind love so
occasionally you can pick up lemon
Jeffrey clones at kind love and they are
beautiful I've seen pictures of them
they're big fat healthy luscious clones
I definitely recommend that call before
you drive uh they will not reserve a
clone for you so you have to call you
have to say do they have this clone and
if they say yes then you got to get in
the car and haul ass over there because
they will not reserve a clone for you
but they might have
it all right I feel like I'm talking a
million miles an hour um I'm going to
press pause take a dab and then we're
going to get into some news I'll be
right back guys the organic portions of
this episode were sponsored by my
friends at the Rocky Mountain worm
company visit the Rocky Mountain worm
company in Colorado Springs for fresh
worm castings African nightcrawlers red
wigglers and all of your soil amendments
Rocky Mountain worm company has
dragonfly Earth medicine products in
stock right now the Rocky Mountain worm
company will ship to your door you can
get the same worm castings that I use
plus many of the same amendments I use
in my garden through Rocky Mountain worm
company.com check that out
today all right guys I'm back I want to
give a huge shout out to task in lus
thanks for letting me use the music on
the show guys um so I want to talk about
some news like I said but to lead into
the news I want to talk a little bit
about a comedy show that I went to
recently uh Clint and I were bragging
that we got to go see the taping of Doug
Loves movies which is one of my favorite
podcasts uh Doug Benson is a weed
comedian he does a show called Doug
Loves movies where they play games uh he
usually brings three uh comedians or
some level of superstars to the show
with him and they are his contestants
and they play for the audience and the
audience will win the prizes based on
who wins in the crowd so Doug Love's
movies came to Comedy Works in downtown
Denver you guys know how much I love
Comedy Works big shout out to Baker big
shout out to Comedy Works big shout out
to the entire crew
there excuse me for that Giant Cough I
felt that coming so uh Clint and I
actually shout out to Clint Clint drove
me up there because like I said my
transmission is [ __ ] so Clint drove us
up there and got us to the Mellow
Mushroom shout out to the mushroom they
always feed us well uh got us to Comedy
Works we got to see the
show um we talked about Doug's last show
not being up to standards this time we
laughed our asses off he completely
completely made up for the lack of funny
in the last
show so I'm catching my breath after
that cough I
apologize took some pretty gnarly dabs
while we were off the air there oh yeah
while you guys were listening to that
commercial about the worm company thanks
for that all right I really am going to
read this article here I'm just trying
to catch my breath before I do it you
guys um Doug binon he pulled off a great
show a great podcast you can listen to
the exact episode if you go to uh it
search for Doug Benson it's Doug Loves
Movies the episode actually is titled
something about I'm going to look in my
phone right here just so that I can tell
you accurately what it is we're going
there got this iPhone takes a second it
is holy crap he does a lot of episodes
bro it's titled Jeff Tate Julian Maka
and Ricardo Baka guest and it was uh put
up on Monday so check that out if you
want to you guys I was sitting in the
front row shout out to my friends at
Comedy
Works uh I I owe somebody an apology wow
I got to fix that sound equipment I got
this [ __ ] spiked up I owe so many an
apology at Comedy Works a patron I was
uh gifted the the luxury of kind of a
lifetime VI pass for comedy work a VIP
pass for Comedy Works as long as I call
ahead and let my friend know that I'm
coming uh I can get a VIP seat in the
front row let them know how many of us
there will be and they'll put me in the
front row as long as I've got tickets so
I called ahead I made arrangements to
have my front row privileges I was told
that's that's cool uh we got to the club
and when it was time to seat us the
seating people kind of looked at each
other with some concern and the one guy
said you [ __ ] up you go tell him so
the one seating person I don't know what
he's called I'm going to call him an
usher that sounds about right but the
one Usher dude had to go tell two people
that they had to move because the seats
that they were sitting in up front had
been reserved for Doug's VIP special
guests um I felt bad for that because
those people probably waited in line for
a good hour while I was at the Mellow
Mushroom eating pizza or in the car
taking fat
dabs um well I'm thinking about it shout
out to Claud the candy man I ate a sweet
Stone candy uh CLA bear before I went
into the show about two hours before the
show and by Showtime woohoo I was sweet
stoned for sure so they had to go and
move these two people because I've got
this VIP pass so they sit Clint and I in
the most Prime [ __ ] seats in the club
right up front and it's kind of awkward
I could feel hatred people were staring
at us like we were huge dicks uh and
then eventually the guy sitting next to
us got tired of the tension and he just
said so who the [ __ ] are you guys and
Clint said nobody I'm with him and
they're like who are you and I was like
we're just friends of Doug and they said
yeah they moved our friends because you
guys are Doug's special guests and I
felt kind of like a [ __ ] for that so
I do apologize but I had a great ass
time up front that was a good ass show
um let's go and read this article I've
been talking for a long time about it
and I've just got an article written um
I was excited because what doug does
dude excuse all the coughing and throat
clearing I just took some gnarly dabs of
some Gorilla
Glue hopefully that was the last one of
those not the not the dab the throat
clearing uh I was excited because when
he announced his guests he said Ricardo
Baka and I knew who that was right away
and a lot of our news on this show is
written by Ricardo Baka so this says
Comedia podcast listen to marijuana
editor Ricardo Baka on Doug Loves Movies
comedians Jeff Tate and Julian McCulla
join weed editor Ricardo Baka on Doug
Benson's popular movie podcast of course
this came out May 11th and it was in the
Cannabis it's written by Ricardo Baka it
says talk about nerves as as 4:20 p.m.
Denver time approached on May 10th AKA
Mother's Day I was sitting in com Comedy
Works green room with some insanely
talented stand-up comics getting ready
to take the stage for a taping of my
single favorite podcast in the world
comic Doug Benson also a legit weed hero
had generously asked me to be a guest on
his movie podcast Doug Loves Movies
after seeing the marijuana journalism
documentary rolling papers at the South
by Southwest Film Festival too fun um
I'm going to jump in right here uh I
mentioned Rolling Papers a movie a
camera crew followed um what's his name
Ricardo Baka around for a year and
followed members of his staff and part
of the newspaper they followed him for
an entire year and recorded and made a
documentary about the journalism
marijuana journalism that is developed
in Colorado and and they've dubbed the
movie Rolling Papers um it was purchased
after its first showing at the South by
Southwest Festival so that's coming out
in the future um I'll keep you guys
updated when that comes
out excuse all the coughing I apologize
it's a weed show you get it I hope
you're coughing with me uh then the
article goes on to say and then the
nerves came on lots of people listen to
this I thought but after my Mee after
meeting my fellow guests whips smart
comedians Jeff Tate and Julian Mulla and
seeing Benson again I knew we were in
for a good time the podcast taping was a
blast the soldout cow crowd at Comedy
Works was Super Rad and Benson's team
took less than 24 hours to launch it and
he means the podcast and now everyone
can listen via the embedded uh
douglovesmovies site or iTunes so yeah
if you go to Doug gloves movies.com or
go to iTunes you can listen to it it was
a great great
podcast Ricardo Baka did quite damn well
he was on stage with three uh witty top
level Comedians and he held his own he
did not try to step up and be a comedian
he remained Ricardo Baka and I respected
him for that he let the comedians comedy
and he did his job and was the person
that they invited you guys my throat is
tickly I'm going to press pause for a
second and I'll be right back with
another news article excuse me and I
apologize oh my gosh you guys wouldn't
believe what I just spit up I should
have took a picture of that for you man
I should have recorded the sound of that
hitting wherever it landed oh that was
thick um here's a side note on the
Cannabis the strain of the day is Golden
Goat thought that's cool people often
credit me for making the Golden Goat I
did not invent the Golden Goat I simply
put it into femin seed for the world to
enjoy uh Golden Goat was created by Mr
dank in Topeka
Kansas Shout Out Mr dank oh I'm catching
my breath I'm sure you could hear that a
little bit but we are going to read
another news article I'm going to fix
some recording equipment I'm blowing
some [ __ ] up um I've got the air
conditioner next to me and I don't think
you guys can hear it but the uh the
recording equipment is struggling to
keep me and this [ __ ] air conditioner
separate in the recording here it's
pretty neat watching the lights light up
anyway this one hits close to home
because I do live in PUO Colorado uh I
am actually the grower at a very popular
dispensary in Pueblo West Colorado uh
peblo West is like a sub uh development
just outside of the city of Pueblo it's
about 10 minutes to the West obviously
it's Pueblo West it's a little nicer uh
well I don't know that it's exactly
complete a little completely a little
nicer it's newer so it doesn't have Old
Town problems it doesn't have the old
rickety parts of town so it looks lot
nicer uh we also have a part that we
call the county which if you drive
outside of City Limits there are a lot
of uh stores and shopping areas in the
county and the county and peblo West are
allowed to have dispensaries but the
city of peblo um has not been allowed
dispensaries I'm going to read an
article that came out May
12th dude I really do apologize for this
throat uh I just took some gnarly dabs
I'll quit taking so many dabs on the
show so that you guys can hear me also
come be on the show talk to me talk
while I'm clearing my throat and you
guys can give me a break uh this article
says poblo pot shops voters will decide
whether to allow retail sales in
November it's only by the AP is who gets
credit for this peblo peblo lawmakers
are letting the voters decide whether to
allow recreational marijuana shops in
their City the PUO Chieftain reports
concerned residents filled the city
council chambers Monday night many
wearing yellow shirts that said voice
your choice and urging their elected
officials to put the issue to
voters councilman Bob Schilling was the
only vote in favor of Licensing retail
pot shops but said that he hasn't
opposed a vote in November several of
the six council members who voted
against adopting the ordinance had been
in favor before the public hearing
including President Steve arachi excuse
me guys I'm sorry he said there isn't uh
the issue isn't worth dividing the
public over uh they did vote and uh they
did uh decide to push back the vote
there will be no recreational or medical
marijuana shops in the city of peblo
uh until they vote
again which will be in November so you
guys if you live in poblo you have to
drive 15 minutes to the county or to
Pueblo West to go purchase your cannabis
and then drive back and then the city
that you live in isn't getting your tax
money for the Cannabis that you're able
to purchase because of these stupid
[ __ ] regulations that Pablo's been
juggling
with I've been in the legal medical
marijuana industry in this city uh since
sh we had the first shop I think I think
that was 9 years ago when we had meamar
downtown and since that is closed uh
there has not been another medical shop
or a recreational shop in the city that
was legally licensed there have been
places that popped up randomly and were
closed but I think it's kind of [ __ ]
I shouldn't use the word [ __ ] that's
mean to the [ __ ] people I think it's
ridiculous and stupid that we are not
allowed to have a recreational cannabis
shop within City
Limits they need the tax money this town
is broke and hurting bunch of weed money
would really help this city all right um
here's another news article that I found
interesting it says Castle Rock man
pleads guilty to mailing Colorado pot
across the country this one is written
by Anthony cotton of the Denver Post it
was published May 12th and here's you're
going to you're going to catch on right
away my point when I start reading this
it says a Castle Rock Man pleaded guilty
on charges that included sending more
than a 100 packages that included
marijuana to locations across the
country and receiving several
100,000 through the mail in return
according to to the according to the
United States District Attorney's Office
Brian Daniel Evans age 42 began mailing
pot packages in April of 2014 and
continued through that fall Evans
pleaded guilty this April officials said
Evans first came under suspicion on
April 2nd 2014 when a US Postal
Inspector came across a suspicious
mailing that may have contained
narcotics or narcotic proceeds the first
package in question came from Missouri
and it contained
cash that package was sent to a
commercial mail receiving agency mail ma
box and was addressed to an individual
in Lone Tree an ongoing investigation
traced the car under surveillance to
Evans who was also seen mailing Parcels
from post offices in the metro area
officials said inspectors also conducted
search a search of elvin's apartment
that uh that search recovered 580 gram
of bagged marijuana 800 gram of
marijuana extract or hash oil wow that's
a lot of hash oil bro that's close to 2
lbs um
5,480 G of marijuana edibles for a total
weight of
6,860 G of marijuana wait a minute you
guys heard that stupid [ __ ] in there
right uh 5,480 gram of marijuana edibles
they're [ __ ] weighing the brownies
and charging him with the weight of the
[ __ ] brownies for the grams of
pot that's [ __ ] whack bro that is
inaccurate that's not cool that's like
weighing the baggie too man you can't do
that man you're a shitty drug dealer
that that sucks that this whole article
is [ __ ] up this guy should not have
done that but that part right there is
wrong um I'm going to continue the
article a search of his vehicle found an
additional 78 gram of liquid marijuana
he probably had some tincture you guys
uh he had previously mailed two
additional packages that were seized by
law enforcement those packages contained
3,654 G of marijuana in total inspectors
learned that Elvin sent 11,026 G of
marijuana law enforcement also had
seized during the investigation more
than
$53,000 in cash which was the proceed
proceeds from his illegal narcotics
transaction that money was forfeited to
the government as part of elvin's ple
agreement Elvin pled guilty to three
account three counts of possession of a
controlled substance with the intent to
distribute he now faces more than 20
years in federal prison and up to a $1
million fine per count so my point here
people is quit mailing weed out of
Colorado unless you want to end up in
federal prison doing 20 years and facing
up to one million dollar in fines per
count there are several reasons we
shouldn't be mailing cannabis out of the
state you
guys first off it's illegal and you're
going to go to prison and you're going
to get butt raped doesn't sound like fun
to me doesn't sound like the [ __ ]
profit I'm making from it not at all
second of all in Colorado the people
that have fought hard to legalize
cannabis medically and recreationally we
did it for here and you're [ __ ] it up
by mailing it somewhere else it's their
respon wherever you're sending it
they're responsible for legalizing
cannabis in their area not us and by
sending it out you're [ __ ] up what we
worked hard for we're making something
shiny we've got a system that works we
have created laws and we're playing by
the rules and then you're going to be a
[ __ ] [ __ ] and take the rules that
we've made you can grow and smoke all
the weed you want you can hustle weed in
Colorado quit sending it out of state
you don't need to do that that's [ __ ]
it up making everybody look bad and
you're going to get caught and get butt
raped and go to jail you get to be I
I'll read about you in the future keep
sending that [ __ ] I will proudly read
your name and laugh at you on this show
don't send cannabis out of state that's
[ __ ] my point you guys get it right
legalize cannabis everywhere do your
part contact your local Congress people
go to City Council meetings do that [ __ ]
where you are and get it legalized in
your area so that you don't have to get
and there's not enough herb here people
are hurting for herb there are patients
that want cannabis that don't have any
medicine here and we're sending that
[ __ ] to other states to make a profit
that's [ __ ] up take the money out of
cannabis put more compassion into
cannabis that's what I'm saying all
right yeah what else do I have for you
we've gone 30 minutes let's uh let's
just chat for a minute I have promised
you a uh scheduling episode I told you I
was going to do an episode about
scheduling your grow for a Perpetual
cycle uh I am writing it but I'm having
an I had an issue I had a stumbling
block I don't know how many lights you
have so I don't know how to write a
Perpetual cycle for your room but I have
found a solution so I'm writing it based
on that uh we'll get it together that'll
probably be one or two episodes away
um the other episode I have been teasing
about is improving your Gardens I was
going to say top 10 ways to improve your
garden I've got about 30 ways written
down that could be a long episode that
is definitely
coming um I don't want to talk too much
about any of that stuff because we'll
just save it for the actual show I want
to give a huge shout out again to Clint
and Baker uh also a big shout out to
Comedy Works big shout out to everybody
who has helped me deal with not having a
car this week or this weekend that's
been a real pain in the ass you guys if
we had some plans that I had to cancel
or rearrange range I apologize I've got
a blown transmission uh my Cheval legs
will get me so far but the weather has
been shitty and uh I'm stuck so you got
to come to me if you want to take some
dabs or if you want to be on the podcast
you got to come to me I'm going to wrap
up to show you guys you pay a lot more
attention to a 35 40 minute episode than
you do those hour shows let me know what
you think um yeah uh go to uh Stitcher
or iTunes or Twitter or Facebook or
email me and tell me if you prefer the
30 minutes episodes over the hourong
episodes um I think it's better when I
do two 30 minute episodes instead of the
long hour and you guys really listen
more my throat doesn't [ __ ] up as much
if we have a guest we'll go an hour but
when it's just me I'm going to try to go
about 30 and try to do two episodes a
week it's better for everybody that way
in my opinion let me know what you think
the show isn't just for me the show is a
lot for you so uh thanks for listening
you guys I'm going to wrap it up I'll be
back in a few days with another episode
probably about ways to improve your
garden
don't forget to check out our sponsors
the Rocky Mountain worm company if you
guys are interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review send me an email it's
gr yourart hotmail.com I'll get you all
of the information that you need guys
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes uh go to the iTunes Store search
for grow from your heart find the review
section give me a festar rating and then
after that type in a comment and let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comment on a future
episode uh Stitcher keeps changing the
way the comments are handled so leave a
comment there and I will do my best to
find it if you have something to say and
you're not into the social media thing
uh you can email me like I said earlier
scart hotmail.com if you want to find me
on Twitter it's gfyh podcast or at rosta
Jeff 420 that also works make sure you
follow iy genetics on Instagram we just
hit 15,000 followers big up to everybody
that follows us on Instagram I
appreciate that also don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every single episode is forever
archived on iy genetics
colorado.com uh we did add that donation
button on the podcast page guys my
transmission blew the [ __ ] up so to tell
you the truth as of what episode is this
this is number 70 um that Adventure that
we were talking about for my daughter
the deadline for that was the first so
the new uh PayPal button that goes to my
transmission from here on
out straight up honest about that
[ __ ] um so yeah go to the website
it's IR gentics colorado.com click on
the grow fromy heart podcast tab top
right there's a little PayPal logo click
on that throw in a dollar throw in $5
throw in $500 transmission is $2,600 so
we're working our way toward that uh
we'll get there don't worry guys I got
it um I'll never charge you for this
podcast it's always going to be free but
if you uh feel like making a
contribution saying thank you that is
definitely appreciated I feel like I'm
begging now let's get away from this uh
we're on all the social media sites I
already said that you guys thanks for
listening to Me Clear My Throat a bunch
of times the next episode will be more
educational um yeah shout out to my
ninja Spence shout out to Maddie shout
out to the Garden of Weeden sloppy big
shout out brother I read about your
medical issue and I need to visit with
you I don't have a car uh we need to get
together to dab and smoke bro I want to
talk to you about that uh big shout out
to sloppy love you sloppy love you like
family so until next time you guys take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
your life what's it like living my life
because my lifestyle lifestyle lifestyle
because my lifestyle
lifestyle what's it like living my life
because my lifestyle lifestyle
lify what's it like living my life
because my lifestyle lifestyle lify
waking up next to a top-notch female all
out the bed and click the button check
in my email well friends and fans from
across the land prated pay extended the
Mystic root man and man I got to thank
the Lord up above all the letters that
I'm getting connect with your music dog
it's been years I've known you what's it
like to be Co from his dick boots up in
California what's it like living my life
rocking mics every night smoking purple
and white is tight I can't lie I'm
loving how I'm living since birth I've
been giving aition plus the gift is spit
I'm hot now all with that my beat Can't
you stop now see me on your block now
got it on lock down on lock down like a
My
Lifestyle what's it like living my life
because my lifestyle lifestyle
lifestyle what's it like living my life
because my lifestyle lifestyle lifestyle
I'm the type of guy that gets around
alarm's going off cuz I'm smoking
pounding all night no matter the town
rolling up CH I'm always down