[Music]
here we go welcome to the show podcast
world i'm your host my friends call me
ross to jeff this is episode number 700
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i am joined by by my buddy
white mike of course we've been dabbing
pre-show a little bit so words are
harder than they should be today i will
introduce white mike in just a moment
before we get to that part of the show
let's do some shout outs to a few of
those great folks who have continued to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to a good
friend tree star meadow let's send a big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to a
longtime supporter my buddy kurt z let's
send a special thank you shout out to
ez057
i want wanna send a fist bump to zoso j
and tonto let's send a big fist bump to
danky dave i wanna send a thank you
shout out to sacred tree organic farms
listen to a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to seven one six vibes i
wanna send a big fist bump to uncle gigi
shout out to jg and bongstein bear big
thanks to my buddy chicago dabber then
let's wrap it all up with the big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to pro brewer home grower big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen of
course i do include those links in the
show notes and the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends i made it through the intro
let's get to the part of the show where
we intro my buddy white mike why mike
welcome to the show brother
thanks man thanks for having me what's
up everybody
welcome to the show bro this is a good
opportunity while i catch my breath from
spitting out that intro so loud and fast
uh would you like to tell everybody how
they can stalk you on social media plug
any uh stuff you'd like to plug right
now
um if you're looking to find me on
social media you can follow me on
twitter at
nemopunk15 or you can find me on
facebook at pueblo for sensible cannabis
laws
nemo punk 15 you guys nemo punk 15 and
pueblo for sensible cannabis laws mike i
think i've asked you a long time ago and
if this isn't appropriate for the show
we can edit it out where did nemo punk
15 come from what the hell does that
mean bro so the 15 is the age when i
came up with the handle wow i was
creating my first hotmail account like
that's how old that is
so i i don't necessarily want to say the
number of years that account has been
around
but that was my first hotmail account
way back in the day and it has just
survived and when i first created a
twitter handle i did it as a joke so
that i could hassle a huffington post
live personality
on twitter
and like i never thought it would go
anywhere and then here we are i don't
know a decade later
all right that's the story 15 comes from
well that's the 15. what what's nemo
punk
um just nemo is known for latin and that
movie wasn't out yet and um i was a
little punk
i know you still are complicated you're
a good dude now you're an adult now but
if we would have known each other
in our teens we would have gotten in a
lot more trouble than we did uh without
being friends with each other yeah yeah
i'm glad we met in our adult lives once
we got that [ __ ] out of our system all
right that's nemo punk 15 go ahead dude
i don't mean to interrupt you i talk a
lot from it
uh it's just one of those things that's
stuck around and every now and then i'm
like i should
retire that but it's attached to
everything at this point yeah what do
you do my email addresses
my email is iriegenetics hotmail.com i
just came up with that one day i needed
an email address i hit hotmail and i was
like oh and now when i tell people
they're like really bro you're gonna are
you gonna ever gonna upgrade i gotta
develop hotmail like it's not exactly an
aol address but it's close
i i i do check an aol address
occasionally
anyway
my niece has ridiculed me extensively
for having a hotmail account we're
telling people how old we are bro you
didn't want to reveal how many years ago
you made that uh email account but we're
telling people time we're hinting at
them yeah mike mike wears jenko's still
you guys all right now pueblo for
sensible cannabis laws is another good
place to go support mike that is a great
place mike post great stuff there uh
good friendly cannabis debates a lot of
good cannabis info uh so check him out
at pueblo for sensible cannabis laws
dude you haven't been on on a long time
the people have been asking for you it
is good to see you would you like to
plug your patreon page while i'm
thinking about it
sure it's a patreon.com forward slash
white mic um find me at uh probably a
link in the show notes
make it easy for the people there you go
as i'm editing and i hear that i'll go
type that in the notes that i create
i'll put that in the notes shout out to
some of my supporters real quick she
gave me a chance to plug it easy um tree
star meadow uh big thank you farmer z
always appreciated locomotive medical
love you guys lemur priest thank you so
much for the support
and grow from your heart podcast
really appreciate the support brother
yeah dude i gotta i gotta pay it forward
[ __ ] rolls downhill something like that
you're welcome bro thank you for coming
on the show taking time uh you mike
might not be on the show uh as many
episodes as we would like him but he
does contribute sometimes i'll just
message mike a couple things like hey
bro what's the answer to this and it'll
just trigger my brain and so there you
go patreon funding i feel like it's the
right thing to do behind the scenes
action but yes i've been missing being
on the podcast i've been dragging my
feet getting
the new office space set up and getting
all the podcast equipment reassembled
and
episode 700 was the motivation i needed
to get her done i like that yeah mike
was like 700 is coming up dude what are
we doing i was like we're going to zoom
chat what do you think we're going to do
i like the new background it's nice and
uh i like the dark set up there it's
just dark enough to you're not a
floating head but you are still
mysterious i have no idea what's
happening three feet behind you
yeah one of the one of the kids needed
my other light source ass
so i am shy one light source right now
but everything else is up and running
and still functional after
like so much stuff has happened since
the last time i was in the podcast there
was major construction in the space we
had to tear concrete out with a
jackhammer and install
when you say there was a flood everybody
just goes oh like anybody that's had a
basement flood they go oh they feel
empathetic or sympathetic or they get
feelings and they understand like yeah i
know what you mean brother so yeah we
understand that flood sets you back
quite a bit
there's nothing like fighting four
inches of water come pouring out of your
concrete floor
that was a fun night
uh you said something about equipment
and i do want to reassure the people
that this is the uh a rare zoom type
video for me usually i do have the
multicam four camera 4k
camera there were words in there that
were meant to make sense multi camera 4k
camera setup that was really hard to say
4k cameras yeah usually i have that
going this is a rare zoom occasion i'm
using the the macbook camera here looks
pretty good in my opinion uh but uh the
other night camera two i recorded a full
show on it and camera two did not record
so i'm having both of those cameras uh
they're they're in timeout right now and
then once they get fixed we'll be able
to do the episodes on those and maybe
just maybe there may be time uh funding
for an upgrade here because the patreon
folks have been helping us out so much
for so long that it may be time to add
another camera a better camera so i do
assure you i do promise this zoom thing
this uh one camera thing is not going to
be forever i know i've set expectations
and i will deliver those um yeah
speaking of that that's a good way to
segue into this uh big shout out thank
you to the patreon crew dude how about
the evolution of this podcast that's a
great segue my next note is evolution of
the show the way to the evolution of the
show i was gonna say we uh
while you were talking about getting the
new cameras i was gonna say i was just
over in the new recording space and it
is looking
amazing thank you
yeah sitting here at episode 700.
we've come a long way from that old
coffee table
when you put your arms down you'd almost
feel like you got letters imprinted on
it because people had written so many
things that had just like hieroglyphics
like melted into it
yeah there was a lot of dabs stuck to it
on top of it yeah there was a lot of
burn marks on that table
that table got a lot of use
the
dab stuck to the top of that table we're
felony weight in some states yes you
could probably scrape up enough enough
residual concentrates off that table to
take a couple of fat dabs the table did
go through hell uh big shout out to oil
slick one time i was on a live show on
an instagram live an oil sling came on
and they're like why don't you have a
big
excuse that that's from the dabs before
the show
they're like why don't you have a big
oil slick pad for that table and i said
because you didn't send it yet
and he said give me your p.o box and
check that [ __ ] in a couple of days and
seriously five days later there's a big
table sized oil slick pad in there so
that was pretty awesome
covered the entire table was perfect so
couldn't get i just cleaned it real easy
wipe it down with a little alcohol it
didn't mess anything up it was great but
yeah so we went from uh crappy recording
i used my old uh that first episode with
you and kevin is hilarious i listen to
it like at least once a year just to
remind myself where we the show started
when people tell me that they're a new
listener and they've gone back and
they're like i've listened to the whole
catalog i'm like oh man i'm like thank
you for the clicks and thank you for
liking the show but also dude don't
don't don't judge me like i'm so much
better at this by now i wasn't sure
i wasn't sure what we were doing yet i
didn't know that what the goal was i
wanted to have more of a hangout smoke
party vibe but also i like teaching so i
kind of narrowed it down to me just
giving you a good lesson i feel like
it's more uh more what i was trying to
do
but i started using the old that
equipment i used came from when i was a
drummer on the road i had an independent
mixer for the drums i used to have a big
mixing board all kinds of [ __ ] i had
compression because wade was blowing out
the mic on the old show we were on i had
compression
uh i had a giant rack of equipment yep
yeah and now
uh well then uh then we upgraded to the
zoom h6 which was fun i could get four
mics on there
um and i remember times we had like nine
people on the show there were the whole
table was full and the little side table
over there had people at it that was a
good time now i've got room for four
mics on one device i'm just using the
dry dab that day oh the dry dab that day
was sloppy big shout out to our buddy
shampoo sloppy shampoo i call them
shampoo but a shampoo sloppy uh yeah it
was sloppy uh what were the numbers in
his name nine sloppy's i don't remember
the numbers sloppy always has numbers in
his name but big up to slop bizzle uh he
took a big fat dry dab in a podcast
might have been episode 200 or 500 i
don't recall of course the brain injury
makes things wonky but i had a bunch of
people over garden of weed and crew was
over spence maddie uh joe buzzy was here
sloppy was here and sloppy sat down and
took a fat dab out of a rig with no
water in it that was a that was an
experience the email it slow baked all
the water out of the ring yeah it
evaporated everything cold glass rig the
glass was warm enough to slowly bake
water out of itself
yummy dabs
man
this time
yeah so we went from all that wonky
recording equipment to the
zoom h6 now i'm using a zoom pod track
four during the pandemic i got inspired
to i don't remember what around 560 i
think i started doing videos and i was
using the macbook and just using the
screen on the mac
uh that was fun but it didn't seem
as good as it could be i knew i could do
better and just having this weird frame
of view was different so i bought a
camera and a real camera and then i set
up 4k camera then i bought a i learned
how to do that i learned how to edit in
final cut pro so i bought a camera which
resulted in buying a new computer
because the camera uh i dumped that file
into the computer and the computer went
that's funny yeah so i had to go buy a
brand new computer that could handle the
editing and processing i was trying to
do i was like well if i'm gonna spend
the money on that let's [ __ ] get
another camera and so i went to cam and
now i'm running two sony uh hd cameras i
got this mic going on i feel like i
upgraded a long way i got the the joe
rogan mic i can't forget about the
everyone i just called the joe rogan mic
it's the sure sm7b
uh upgraded to that multicam i feel like
we've come a long way
uh we have nearly still sound guy at
heart though
you can't shake that the sound guy part
of me
yep oh no that's always gonna be in me
yeah that was yeah i've got a sound guy
ear uh i'm not trained in sound guy
stuff i've just done enough sound guy
stuff to where it's ingrained in me
i'm curious after the show i want to
know what what where you what makes you
think that what you see that or my sound
guys no it's
uh like
right now for a hundred dollars i
couldn't list a piece of equipment you'd
named off other than like
because that [ __ ] failed on you like a
hundred times i remember the old
headphone amp that i wanted to throw
through the wall several times yep
there was
i'm trying to remember which piece of
equipment had the lights that would
hypnotize me when i got too baked oh
that's funny that would probably with
the compressed audio lights that would
bounce
and they would get real hypnotic when
when the show got
rambly i love it but then yeah then you
would just get more rambly and it would
get more hypnotic um dude we're close to
10 000 youtube subscribers uh for a
little show that yeah 10 000 subscribers
700 episodes i had no idea uh i i
thought maybe when we started like 100
episodes would be the goal and when we
hit 100 i was like 250 would be fun and
then at 250 i was like yeah 500 seems
like a cool goal and then at 500
something was like yeah just do it dude
it's it's working don't stop
yeah by 500 i think everybody knew it
was on like officially this was just
going to be a steady
every monday you could count on it i
can't believe you haven't missed a
monday and 700 episodes dude dude
haven't missed a monday on the podcast
and i don't think i've missed a monday
on the instagram live uh that's false
because there was a time period where my
instagram account was deactivated
yeah and then sometimes they block me
from going live uh sometimes they close
my inbox right i can read the messages
but i can't reply instagram and they
like to toy with us a little bit but uh
yeah for the most part for
700 episodes like six years-ish i have
not missed a monday and i do my best to
put out a show every thursday as well i
think this actually comes out on a
thursday so yeah
thanks for noticing that bro i
appreciate that uh
sometimes it's a struggle and sometimes
people are like you wanna go do this and
i'm like ah i know i gotta record a
podcast and like do that tomorrow and
i'm like oh no no no no it's tuesday
it's podcast day the whole world might
erupt
yeah your inbox would never recover if
you missed a monday that's that is the
damn truth uh and then the whole flow of
everything would just be wrong
um i feel like i'm working my way
through the notes here pretty good the
evolution of the show has been great um
the only thing left to do is like learn
how to podcast better and then get more
guests on i need to get uh more people
on i need to be on more shows uh and
maybe possibly some camera upgrades but
i think everything else bro evolution is
slowly happening pretty well i am
excited for the 7 10 show i've been
hyping up the 7 10 and i said 7 10 show
earlier and mike was like 7 10 it's not
july dude it's the middle of winter it
was right after a big dab
he like exhaled and started talking
about being hyped for the 710 show and i
was like the
poor guy dabbed himself six months into
the future yeah no uh number seven ten
not not the date of seven days for the
july show yes in november hey you gotta
be prepared brah uh if i don't start
planning ahead
episode number 710 is coming up uh i
find it uh maybe it's odd that i'm more
excited about episode 710 than i was
number 700 because 710 it's like uh
that's like the new 420 so for a week
broadcasting through the prop release
the proper celebration episode yeah this
is the milestone episode i have a good
idea i'm gonna have some friends from
discord send us some great questions and
i have a concentrate maker or two in
mind i'm gonna try to do this type of a
setup with them uh so there will be
another zoom uh podcast coming up for
710 but it will be worth it if i get who
i'm really trying to book onto the show
i love it good hash content is so rare
and there's still a lot of
just confusion in non-exposure when it
comes to the modern hash so yes
content the person i hope to have on i'm
hoping that they can kind of teach us uh
how to take our garden
from from seed or clone all the way to
smokable usable hash without breaking
any laws without using any uh illegal uh
solvents because they've made if you're
making butane hash at home you're
technically breaking the law so he's
gonna teach us i'm hoping they can teach
us how to wash it possibly press it
maybe find one person that washes one
person that presses maybe the same guy
will do both maybe two guys that do both
and let them just give us a rundown of
what they do i've got a bunch of good
questions lined up i'm sure the discord
server my friends on discord have a lot
of good questions patreon will have a
good questions coming uh patreon guys if
you're watching this and gals patreon
supporters uh if you're watching this
and you have good questions for a
concentrate maker go ahead and send them
up on patreon to do my best to get those
on the show for you but that should be
the gateway to getting me more people on
the show i've been hesitant shy of uh
i'm not a good interviewer dude i just
uh i don't know
it's a weird time for it
and like everything's just hard right
now travel and
getting people around places and the
video chat's gotten substantially better
than it was four years ago but oh yeah
yeah
i'm just uh
it's not the technology honestly all
excuses it's me dude i'm uh i just i'm
not the best interviewer like you could
send me questions and i'll have the list
of questions i just can't figure out how
to [ __ ] answer my better just having
a conversation but i don't know maybe i
just need to do that with the
interviewers uh i'll get good at it but
hopefully this 710 interview sparks my
inspiration to get some more people on
to the show if you guys out there have
guests in mind uh or you'd like to be a
guest send me an email or a patreon
email is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com send me a request to be on
the show or a guest recommendation if
you send me a guest recommendation send
me two or three questions to go along
with that guest so i have something to
ask them something to get the
conversation flowing if you are trying
to be on the show tell me what we're
gonna talk about uh tell me why you
stand out why you are uh why you're
qualified i know that sounds maybe uh
conceited or something but tell me why
you're qualified to teach my audience
your knowledge why would i put you on
the show it's a platform so i can't just
let you come out here in your underwear
and talk about crazy [ __ ] gotta kind of
qualify you that's my job
whoa
that's why i don't take people live on
instagram with me dude i'm on the
instagram live show every monday and
people are like can i jump in your live
i'm like there's no way to preview this
i just hit live and you're with me and
you could be you'd be in your underwear
or not in your underwear you could be
wearing less than your underwear you
could be naked and doing done
regular insane like this yeah there's
perfectly clothed insane and then you're
right there and well i can hit the x and
get rid of you but if you're naked
everybody already seen you naked and
then it's too late but that's why i
don't take people live with me if
anybody was wondering all right
and we do need to get you on more mike
um i'm talking about guests and such oh
you're just so funny right as you say we
need to get you one more i hear the
audio monitor go off behind me oh are
the kids cool everyone good
one of them is talking in his sleep i
think
nice let's hear what he's saying dude
put him on the show
i'm not going to edit this out
all right yeah
he's wondering where i'm at like what
just happened is where i'm at yeah
mike's got two uh 7 30 in the morning as
early as [ __ ] studly handsome [ __ ]
cool little guys those are you're making
cool little men dude i'm proud of you
for that uh they're gonna be cool man
yeah yeah like i
like even i noticed that like i'm doing
a pretty awesome job with it it's just
it's exhausting like it's a 16 hour a
day job yeah yeah
when it's like let's get three hours to
podcast it's like i just
there's no energy left there that's all
right we'll fire you up we'll get you
moving for a podcast big shout out to
the boys for letting dad podcast also
big shout out to the wife i don't know
if she'll watch this or hear this but
fist bump to the wife for a watch and
also fist bump for the help you're
giving me on that other thing i asked
for help i appreciate it
they get older
breaking away gets easier
yeah so sure we're getting there little
by little by little i can edit this out
if i'm crossing any lines you just tell
me but i never know until i ask um
when
uh and i know there's not a number but
when do you think it's going to be time
to
um explain to them and talk to them
about cannabis
well sort of
already have started and like the oldest
ones six and the younger ones three and
like right now it's just dad disappears
into the garage
like for dad time
and uh
the
the older one like he goes and takes a
load time in his room he goes and takes
personal time just like i did
the thing people do and so i've kind of
talked to him a little bit like very
kind of
surface level
you know no details like it just i'm out
there doing stuff that like it's for
adults not kids
like
it's just
that's where we're at with it right now
like the three-year-old's just like he
wants to do everything with me and he
doesn't get away yeah i just appear from
time to time
but you're a six-year-old i'm going to
interrupt you uh you're a six-year-old
dude that's he's not sick but he's
[ __ ] 16. like when i talk to him i'm
like what how did who am i talking to
over here this is not somebody's little
kid this is somebody's like uncle or
somebody over here
the the combination of um
all of the medical procedures and stuff
that he's had to go through in his uh
six years and
kovit just being home with me for a year
and a half
like just hanging out with me i was it
was playmate like i was the the daycare
kids i was the teacher's aide like all
of it
like that [ __ ] had an impact like the
way
the world is directly
um framed by those two things yeah that
makes a huge difference yeah he's not
hanging out with a cartoon watching
booger picking kids he's hanging out
with dad all day long that's kind of
cool dude i see it i'm not trying to
talk i've been trying to make this the
fatherhood podcast but uh it was a good
opportunity to ask like when do we start
talking about our kids about smoking
herb like just because i like your uh
your your uh your model of parenting
we're very much um like my wife and i we
uh we sort of helped raise two of our
nieces already they're in their 20s now
um but we were
not parental but like parental adjacent
figures for them for their whole lives
and we just went with
brutal honesty was the whole point
like you have to put it in the context
that's age-appropriate
but
um
just we don't lie to him we just
we frame it appropriately and so it's
not daddy's outside doing dabs
his dad's taking personal time we're
going to give dad 15 or 20 minutes and
then
that'll line right about up with dinner
being ready and
all right let's roll right through it
we do the same thing with wine or
alcoholic beverages you know it's adult
juice don't worry about it you don't
need to
okay
they don't like the smell of it they're
not interested in it or anything
my daughter is 18. and i don't know
oh dude yeah i was gonna say i know she
dabs she dabs with her friends she dabs
at
the house um i don't necessarily
buy her flowers or concentrates but if
she needs something
like i'll give her a ride to the
dispensary but i won't go in and get it
for her like i don't like
i'm not against it or anything and if i
really had to i would but there's got to
be some like when i was her age dude we
had to go find weed like you had to find
somebody with weed and then you had to
have money to get weed and then you had
to buy the weed and pick all the [ __ ]
seeds out of it before you could smoke
some of it like i don't care that she
smokes happy go for it dude chill out
have a good time but i'm not gonna make
it super easy like you gotta do some of
it like i'm not gonna show up with with
a bag of weed for her but
if she spends some of her birthday money
on a bag of weed i don't care like
that's kind of how i feel about it like
part of me wishes
the
the current generation had to go through
some of the [ __ ] that we did when we
were teenagers to
acquire herb
and part of me is really glad they don't
have to
because like
yeah we got lucky kind of
yeah but it only got ugly and scary a
couple of times right i wouldn't want my
daughter messing with a couple of my
weed guys from back in the day oh yeah
right but like yeah i don't want my kids
driving three hours
because
that's where the weeds the best price
like the three hour drive is worth the
75 savings yeah now she goes to the
dispensary down the street and she's 18
and got a weed card so she can go in
there and get get plenty like all the
crap
like if there were rocks and stuff in
the pound like what was sprayed on it
yeah no i always troll her i'm like
you've never even picked seeds out of
weed like i always want to just like get
our weed and throw a bunch of seeds in
it like now dig that [ __ ] out of there
before you smoke see that's what it used
to be like
but she's ready to remember
smoking with somebody and they would
scissor stuff off a brick into a metal
colander and then grind on it with
like a pedestal from a mortar and pestle
oh yeah yeah nerves and so you'd have
the little colander and you just grind
around
this lump of compacted herb
yeah yep and then one day somebody
showed up with real weed and i was like
woody what do you have like this is kind
bud not compressed brick weave and i was
like well let's smoke that and my brain
went
yep and then it was everybody at the
party slept for seven hours yeah yeah
well then i had to learn where to get it
and then i had to learn how to grow it
and then i had to learn how to breed it
and that's bad too that's where we are
today yeah somebody showed up with some
really good weed and it blew my [ __ ]
brains
yeah so that was a weird segue from
asking when you're gonna uh talk about
cannabis with your kid i can't wait to
uh uh smoke a fat one with both of them
like i can't the time will come
a long way but like it's it's an event
i'm desperately looking forward to i
gotta beat the older one in a foot race
uh he thinks he can run faster than me
you guys that are happening
this is so funny every time i mention
you or he sees something uh with your
face on except i irene merch all over
the place
um he's like i still have to race him he
owes me
i do i owe the kid a foot race yep yeah
i do
um yeah but damn no i can't wait dude
he's super rad all right we've been
talking about kids a lot i don't
remember what i was rambling about i had
a segway it fell out of my brain
um parents is an excellent little sort
of little piece to show that we can do
when i'm on yeah it definitely is
because it's why you're never here so it
correlates very well like it's an
interesting balance that i think
i get it from older people in my family
that are like so how are you the pot guy
and like the good dad and it's like well
it's it's the you just said it
is it the kids like it's not complicated
grow rooms locked and secured and in
another place and the kids are
up there doing their thing it's like two
different yeah two different segments of
life
how do cops
yeah and it's like a gun safe but it's
cheaper
[Music]
oh you cut out mike so
nobody can hear what you're saying but i
don't even think you can hear me so
right now in the podcast it'll just be
me talking over for you
um now you totally froze i'm just gonna
keep talking for a couple of seconds
guys because it looks like mike is
totally frozen uh we'll give him a
minute to recover he's stopping his back
there you go brother welcome back uh
we're talking about gun
you get a thing online called a gun
cabinet and like it's like a gun safe
but it's way lighter
and mine came perfect it's got a little
section for my little two foot bong and
it's got little shelves for my weed and
my hash and my gummies and it's got a
nice easy key system super simple right
that's perfect keep everything away from
the little ones that's all you got to do
in the house is not at all complicated
yeah yeah it's a big house and even if
it wasn't there's more than one room
yeah well that's
it's one of those things like when
you're thinking about laws is you gotta
have a place to go smoke if you're in an
apartment like
and that was how i got people to make it
legal to smoke on porches down here as i
just pointed out like what about
apartment smokers
you really want parents sitting and
stuck in an apartment because that's
where it's only legal to smoke like let
the parent go outside very true yeah let
the parent go outside let's
immediately change that in the law
before we pass it
uh did you hear the grateful dog episode
mike
i did i greatly enjoyed it i've been
waiting for that episode for years i
kind of wanted to get you on it but also
knew that that episode would have been
three times as long if i put you on
there so i just did it
yes yes so i just did it by myself um
what what uh what would you have
contributed bro you got a big smile on
your face when i asked you about it it
was just such a fun episode to listen to
because
so when he's talking about like i got
seeds from such and such like i remember
sitting in his his basement
um smoking or bagging up weed and him
sitting there should i get this this
genetic or that genetic well they have
these five on the website like which
three should i order
um
these ones got seized i had to order
them again
which one thrived
what dumbass merch was sent with the
seeds like i remember oh yeah it's
like there was a line in the episode
where you talk about uh rolling up
joints before going to red rocks
for ray guy on the rocks and i
distinctly remember sitting at your
kitchen table grinding herb for utero
joints with
knowing that you were going to reggae on
the rocks and me not at all being
interested in ray guy on the rocks but
we were hanging out smoking and
recording that night so i'm sitting
there with the grinder for hours
well you roll up 40 dubs yep
like
yeah we used to uh i remember the easy
cloner showing up and you hit that part
in that episode too like yeah all those
fun little evolutions i was there for
just a fun episode to hear cool plus the
grateful dogs still my favorite of your
genetics i'm glad you said that before i
had to ask you if it was your favorite i
love hearing that that's your favorite
mad there's not a grateful dog shirt
like
i don't know what that shirt would be
but it would be a picture of jerry
garcia and david grissman because it's a
band name so
i can't really make my own shirt of a
banana it's my favorite shirt
or my favorite strange shirt i don't
want to wear
yeah well i can't do it i can't make it
because i probably get sued by whoever
owns the grateful dead stuff
jerry's stuff
david grissman's stuff yeah
but if anybody out there wants to make a
bootleg grateful dog shirt i wear an
extra large and mike's probably into a
3x at this point
give or take the pandemic's been rough
smoking hey he quit smoking so we'll
give him that credit
yeah right at the start of this [ __ ]
thing too now it looks like he just
smoked bacon
in
march we cook that's what we do it's
like it's part of the routine with the
kids is we cook all goddamn time yeah
delicious wonderful food that there's a
lot of
[Laughter]
oh i really want to go off on a grubhub
ranch but we'll keep the show positive
today
i don't have a lot more notes i do have
one more good question for you um and i
should have thought about my answer
before i asked you this because i don't
have an answer to this question right
now um do you have a favorite product of
the year we're wrapping up this year uh
it's almost christmas time as we're
recording here uh it's been a good year
do you have a favorite medical or
recreational cannabis product from this
year
the wreck products i buy the most i
don't know
oh you just completely cut out that's
really funny
i'm trying to get his attention you guys
i'm waving at him there you go
we'll i'll just talk till he comes right
back in
um he's leaning toward the mic he's
shaking his head but you guys right now
send me a tweet or an email and tell me
what your favorite product was there we
go we're getting him back tell me what
your favorite uh medical or recreational
cannabis product was this year what got
you zooted what worked best medical or
recreationally for you and i will let
mike continue on with his story of his
favorite product of the year so the the
stuff i buy the most often is either
taste buds gummies
taste product
that is spectacular
um
and then uh
green dot black label stuff the
the batters and the cartridges
bro
yeah
that would be my favorite product of the
year as well they do not pay me i pay
cash for these products straight up
um
this particular dispensary gives me a
discount the deal has nothing to do with
green dots because i was the first
customer to shop in this dispensary when
they open for recreational cannabis
sales so i've got kind of a vip hookup
there
but honestly that's full disclosure they
give me the vip pricing i don't get
these for free green dot does not uh pay
me promote advertise anything
i picked [ __ ] retail and i'm still
shouting them out yeah that's delicious
and uh the funny part is you're like
well ross to jeff you get that fat
discount why don't you go get some for
mike because i buy my damn limit
i buy the limit and mike knows i'm
getting eight of them when i go the
limit is so funny we uh we can't find
the time
to get on zoom for an hour like if we
could get to the dispensary together oh
yeah cause uh you don't get your lemon
i'd have you get me some flowers so that
i could try that a flower there that i
wanted the other day but i was like i'm
not gonna
miss a gram of concentrates to try those
flowers
the limit's tight now especially with
edibles and i've been going through a
boatload of those gummies so i've
like i walk in and like give me two of
those two of those two of those two of
those and then like please stop saying
things so that i don't have to
cut you off right yeah then they
realized when you stopped like oh this
guy knows what's up big shout out to my
buddy ricky one of the best blood
tenders in town i don't often shout out
blood tenders big up ricky
yeah you know what i'm talking about
it's a good dude i'm not just a good
butt tender but a good dude
um yeah dude the green dot black label
is probably my product of the year
anything with
the uh what did i have just the other
day damn i just finished at the fatso
did i add a jaw four gram jar of fatso
anything with the gmo the garlic the han
solo burger anything in that realm from
them uh
[ __ ] i'll take it dude i love it i
love the i think you had a jar of the
holy [ __ ] i love it
had so much of it i've had so much of it
i'll pass like i'll buy something
different if they got the holy [ __ ]
something else probably take something
else just because i spawned so much of
it that gram i i just held up i've been
saving and i saved until tonight i
rewarded myself by finally getting my
podcast stuff set up with a gram or a
nice little dab out of that and it was
that's what i was coughing on when you
uh when you let me into the meeting
[Music]
nice i love it when i opened up the zoo
meeting mike hits the uh the let me into
the damn zoo meeting button and i look
up to let him in and i click accept and
then all i hear is just kill my hand
mike's just taking a big old fat bong
rip yeah he's got his hand like one
moment sir
i got you buddy i got
you shout out to the little blue rig
yeah dude
i don't want to jinx myself this rig
uh
this rig has been around dude i need to
clean my banger i need to clean the rig
but this thing uh
this that little sidecar has been
people talk about their favorite reagan
should i like it's just the right size
it's got the flared mouthpiece so i
don't have to like put my mouth on a
phallic shape thing it's nice and short
all the smoke goes down the stem and to
my brain dude i love it love it love it
love it
yeah
all right bro we've been going for like
30 minutes um at the end of these
podcasts when i've gone through all of
my notes i like to give you the mics
moments it's been a long year you don't
get to be on here very often and if i
need to edit this out i can if i gave
you a microphone and some time to
yourself and i was like mike go ahead
and ramble about whatever you want to
get off your chest today what kind of
[ __ ] would you have to say
that's so tricky because uh one of my
my hesitancies uh
get my setup going one of the little
procrastination tools i've been throwing
around in my head is like i just
try not to bring random politics stuff
to the show but um
the safe banking act if you follow stuff
going on in congress they were going to
give legal cannabis access to banking
some people were all for it others are
against it um even in the community
there's there's word resistance because
everybody's afraid of the corporate
takeover
which will be hastened by full access to
banking but that failed again which is
disappointing the community's still so
fragmented that
they can kick our issues down the down
the street for decades and nothing
happens fear of the bank being able to
be involved is what is keeping your
business afloat your business plan is
wrong you got to re-strategize if that's
what's worrying you realize your
argument for not being able to use the
banks uh that's that's a uh it's a
insecurity that's a weird fear
that's a poorly planned before you can
fix that like it's
yeah a a major
kind of
i don't know stumbling block in legal
cannabis right now is an access to
capital
um we can't go to the bank and get a
business loan you have to know somebody
with private capital or you have to have
um private investment and it's just a
brutal system to survive
i mean it's cut throat it's why owners
are
so
stereotypically douche baggy
like it's
it's that's who's who's funding it right
now it's not somebody trying to pay off
a business loan over 40 years it's right
somebody looking to to triple their
investment quick and get out of the new
hot thing
that explains a lot of a thing that i
talk about on this show often um
the commercial industry can beat the
[ __ ] out of a grower with passion
because
i became a lead grower and this has
happened in more than one environment
and once you're in the commercial
industry you realize it's kind of a joke
it's kind of a trend
there's an owner who
has finagled some money out of somebody
some people a group a person with money
he's gotten an owner has investors maybe
multiple investors
then the owner has
probably two investors then they've got
a lead grower and a grow team and
they're telling different stories to
everybody because that investor every
day wants their money back the growers
telling them i need nine weeks to get it
done they're telling the grower that
they're gonna they're just so it's that
pressure from that investor that's all
of a sudden their weirdness
all of a sudden they're asking the
grower if they can shorten the flowering
time to six weeks and it's like that's
not how [ __ ] nature works yeah they
tell the investor will have it done in
eight weeks the grower says nine they
tell me i gotta have it done in seven
when it doesn't reach the harvest goals
because we took it down two weeks early
because the [ __ ] owner of the place
was getting uh ridiculously overzealous
it doesn't reach the goals or the
potency then the investor gets mad about
us not making the money we should have
made like it's a weird dynamic if we
could get those real bank loans uh and
have
people like
different everything would be different
with a decent [ __ ] apr and actually
just get a loan know that we got to pay
this back over this time because we have
to sell this much product that means our
first year we could struggle by year two
and three we could be going by year five
we're banging by ten we're all paid off
like you can make that kind of plan but
when you got crazy investors
uh it goes kind of weird sometimes you
don't get to do all the things that you
were hoping um sometimes they dangle
more money over you they're like oh
we'll give you more money after your
first harvest and you harvest and they
don't give it to you and you've promised
people bonuses and then there's no
bonuses to be given because you didn't
get the money
anyway that's everything's so tight
because it's all private capital and
it's just it's just one of the one more
thing that's
it's
how many different things we have to
overcome
yeah right and there's so many of us
it's it's one in three americans so
there's 120 million of us
and if we could all just get together
for 45 minutes on one wednesday
everything would be different you know
it's just the random stoner thought of
the night i like it no that's what i
gave you this uh this mike's moments
this open platform that's what it was
for uh any of the people that don't like
listening to the politics uh they got to
listen to a good 30-minute show and then
they can uh not uh not hear this part if
they're not into it and we don't have to
listen to their comments
yeah they need to start
like everybody gets down on politics but
it's like how everything functions like
i was just scanning headlines and i
don't have the time right now that i
used to have to really keep up on like
every state's path through legalization
but i saw that new york just had a whole
bunch of counties or i think they call
them counties in new york
a whole bunch of geographical squares of
space uh
borderlines opt out or refuse to opt in
to legal cannabis so they're gonna be
like colorado where
you can buy urban in manitoba but not
colorado springs or you can get urban
pueblo but not in
um wallsenberg i think you can get wheat
in wasselberg but yeah
60 some counties in colorado where you
still can't buy herb you've got to drive
to the next county over
in some counties it's made ridiculously
rich because it's a small county next to
a big county
and the big counties refuse to opt in so
the little county's never seen more
funding like trinidad
yeah um
but uh
if you're not involved especially at the
local level like just weird stuff
happens
and
you don't want to miss out on this you
know especially if you only go to the
dispensary a couple of times a year you
don't want to have to drive three
counties over right and pay ridiculous
taxes
plenty of people drive to another county
just to avoid 30 32 35 taxes on cannabis
when you're buying a product that costs
200 bucks that's 60 bucks in taxes if
you didn't have to pay that imagine how
much more product you could leave with
it uh
the taxes right now are incredibly
brutal because it's still illegal
federally so federal tax rule 280e
applies and you can't deduct
all the normal expenses from your
business taxes
like that's where the industry's health
insurance is right there
oh yeah that's the health insurance
money that's the bonus money that's the
raises money
it's
just one of those things
i still love legal cannabis i wouldn't
go back for anything
like i laugh at people pretending that
they'd go back to illegal herb oh no we
don't know if you were a home grower
back then like everybody else is way
better off and then you should have
evolved by now you should be leading a
dispensary or at least being a top-notch
grower at a dispensary or a consultant
he should have evolved and adjusted and
adapted because those times are changing
uh maybe that's a good heads up to
people who are in
markets which are about to change or
have recently changed bro if you're an
illegal grower and you're just doing the
black market thing there will always be
a demand and a need for the free market
but a lot of those are going to go away
you may want to re-strategize you may
want to come up with something new
because eventually a lot of those gray
market free market opportunities those
disappear when the legal market comes so
be ready yeah and then the squeeze comes
quick i mean i remember and it doesn't
seem like that long ago but like me and
jeff said earlier we're old now
older now
um
you used to be able to make a perfectly
respectable living with four or five
lights
three or four lights even
if you ran a tight ship you could have
three or four grow lights in a house
and to have a
set of regular customers and make a
perfectly respectable living oh yeah and
that went away about an hour and a half
after legalization landed
and you started to see
do you remember all the people who
tried to make a dispensary in their
living room oh yeah nailed shelves to
the wall and had jars up and yeah
for a minute there that was how half of
our town survived we're going to talk
about that a lot more mike i've got
another episode planned i should give
you a heads up now um my goal is to have
episode 719
about our city and the cannabis oh
that's beautiful
episode yes we'll make it about our area
code here is 719 folks so we're going to
do 719 we'll be about cannabis in the
719. we'll talk about how many jobs
we've provided uh and how things have
gone like that and something i'll let
mike talk about so mike let me get down
here
start writing you just gave me a bunch
of homework so mike we were talking
about some greedy people uh in my
opinion it would just be greedy people
would be the people that did not want
legalization to happen i would never
undo legalization people in jail for
cannabis is like [ __ ] that that is
that's a word that we're not supposed to
say
yes yeah there's a word we're not
supposed to say anymore in this time
time of the year and this climate and
this culture is how i feel about that um
yeah people should be able to consume
cannabis and not have fear of getting
locked up just for smoking a plant
people can do we should be able to do
most of whatever we want if it doesn't
bug anybody so i'd never undo that
that's not something i would change i
changed a lot of my uh a lot of my world
it made me grow dude it made me it's
funny it made me grow i didn't even mean
it that way it made me grow as a person
it made me grow it made me grow
business-wise in a lot of ways made me
grow commercially but it made me grow uh
as an adult as a person as a business
person otherwise what what what are we
gonna do what was i gonna do just sell
weed forever grow weed and sell weed
forever i had to evolve and move with
the times i couldn't just have a that
couldn't be my hustle forever i had to
learn other things and evolve yeah at a
certain point that would have gotten
really old yeah
um i was tired when it was ending i was
done with it when it that's why it yeah
that's why we evolved it by the time it
went away yeah
watching all the different different
evolutions has been really cool um
still wishing more people would get
involved it uh
um if we could just come together for
like five minutes community
because we got 10 000 subscribers to the
show like everybody tell two friends
about the girl from your heart podcast
yeah that's that's a good segue uh this
is a good time to like and subscribe
mike's mike's high and running out of
steam i can see it on his face uh but
dude yeah it's like one in the morning
and seven a.m was a long time yeah it's
all right i pumped some energy back into
it mike is saying like and subscribe
right now and then have two friends like
and subscribe also like i gave you uh
your mike's moments uh it is getting
pretty late here you are correct i still
do have some editing work to do we got
to put some fanciness at the start and
end of this show polish up this video a
little bit yeah they like the sparkly
stuff big shout out to everybody who uh
gives me comments about the musical
selections and the cool [ __ ] that i've
been trying uh to do at the start and
end of the show i appreciate that it's a
little bit of work so i like that you
noticed
um i gave you your moments uh you got
any final things to add to this show
number 700 bro before we start wrapping
it up um just again the show's been
looking and sounding great the the
investments you're making in the tech
are paying off the
hours you spent learning to edit the
video are paying off um
i'm digging the music in and out but i
missed the original
like uh the mystic roots song yeah i
missed that too but i'm tired of getting
flagged by youtube every time i use it
mystic
like i know why it's not a thing but
like
every time i go to click on an episode
there's a little piece of my brain that
goes play the song play the song
oh that's not the song
then i get excited to hear what's in the
place of it okay because it changes all
the time now yeah i try to rotate i've
got a few songs that are about 22
seconds 18 to 22 seconds to 50 intros
try to play those little clips and
things uh big shout out to the people
that send me music make music sometimes
i make a lot of those myself i'm not
trying to too many horns but uh yeah
thank you bro i appreciate it i can't
play the mystic root song they're
friends of mine i've got like express
written permission and youtube does not
give a [ __ ] youtube's like we don't care
that they give you permission yeah it
doesn't matter the record label has
given me permission and youtube just
does not care um
it's kind of funny i'm like hey look
they're giving me a warning for using
your music and he's like sorry bro
there's nothing he could do about it
sitting across the room from me it just
doesn't matter right
weird music industry stuff all right
we're i am rambly i don't know about you
you look like you've had enough of
podcasting today so it's time to wrap up
this show make sure you guys follow mike
sending thanks and love for uh being on
this episode we'll get him back more i
won't be midnight when we start
recording we'll give him some more
energy we'll put some coffee and some
red bull and might keep him fired up
uh follows pueblo for sensible
candidates laws on facebook check him
out on twitter nemopunk15 dude
um you haven't been on the show lately
but the show would not have made it to
700 episodes without you so i do
appreciate you ah thank you man thanks
for being on number 700 thanks for
making a fun cool show thank you and
congratulations again man 700 is a huge
milestone hell yeah bro i look forward
to getting you on uh at least 7 19 you
write the 719 show uh and then we'll put
you on 750 800 an episode a thousand and
1500 we're gonna keep on trucking you
guys so uh keep checking us out make
sure you follow mike on patreon
patreon.com forward slash girl from your
heart i think i'm gonna do all the wrap
up part of the show unless you've got
something to say mike
wrap this up bud wrap everybody
uh thank you mike um everybody else if
you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns uh once again the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback i love hearing from the
listeners the audience i consider you my
friends thanks for the updates the info
i can't improve if you don't tell me how
to improve um also patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart all the
information you need to support the show
will be right there on the screen for
any more links details information make
sure you check out the website at
iriegenetics.com that's all i've got for
you for this episode once again big
thanks to mike big thanks to you
listening uh i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my friend billy
podunk and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you