all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 702
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of quick emails before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to cano organic illinois let's send a
big thank you shout out to orrick i want
to send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to my buddy b bala let's send
a big thank you shout out to doc grows
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy up north caribou heart tv let's
send a thank you shout out to lots of
trichomes who doesn't love lots of
trichomes let's send a big fist bump and
a thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter my buddy glenn jeroni let's
send a thank you shout out to double d
and frugal rock let's send a big fist
bump to a longtime supporter our buddy
brian p let's send a thank you shout out
to the dad hayes let's send a fist bump
to guido7 then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to stoned trout bomb
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need to support the show will be right
there on the screen of course you know i
do include that link in the show notes
and in the video description to make
that nice and easy for all of my friends
once again thank you for the patreon
support oh i am so excited that the
holiday shenanigans are over i am done
with the christmas rush i'm done hearing
christmas music everywhere i go i'm done
with the traffic uh my favorite part
about christmas i love the family i got
to spend time with my two favorite
people my mama and my daughter at the
same time uh they live a distance apart
it was great to have uh to spend time
with both of them my favorite part
though might be other than the family
the the part about side there is the
christmas lights i do enjoy the
christmas lights that's kind of cool but
everything else
other than the family and the christmas
lights i'm glad it's over
i'm glad that it's a year away until we
have to do that crap again it is time to
settle in i'm glad i hope you had a good
time is where i'm headed i hope you had
a great christmas i'm glad that crap is
over it's time to settle in get back to
business get back to work get back to
normal schedules uh less of the hustle
and bustle for the christmas holiday
stuff i hope you had a wonderful time i
hope you got to spend time with your
family whoever it is like i said in the
last episode if it's not your blood
family maybe it's your ganja family
maybe it's your other kind of family
whatever you're into i hope you had a
good time hope you got to spend it with
some people uh if not join us on the
discord you've always got a family there
the discord link is in the show notes
and the video description i'm obviously
nice and rambly you guys i was hanging
out on discord earlier taking dabs with
the friends um i think i smoked some
stuff called a rainbow cheddar i don't
have the jar with me or i would show you
got me well lit well medicated nice and
talkative so this will be a fun podcast
i don't want to stretch it out too far i
want to wish everybody a good holiday
good safe happy new year that will be
the next holiday then we settle in with
a fresh start
let's get into an email because i do
want to answer at least one maybe two
emails here in this uh short one camera
episode yes we're only recording with
one camera today
still trying to figure out a tech issue
we'll get it figured out you guys aren't
concerned with that i do apologize it's
only one camera tried to deliver a
two-camera show let's get to this
message it comes from our friend who
calls themselves they did not even sign
it there's no name this one comes from
anonymous anonymous says hello irie
unfortunately my last paper towel and
seeds went dry for a few hours i sprayed
them around six and found them dry
around two the tap roots generally still
seem healthy then the question let me
kind of talk about what happened here
our friend is germinating some seeds
they're attempting the
fold up a paper towel and stick your
seeds in their method put some water in
it keep it moist those seeds should
sprout unfortunately our friend got
stoned got tied up in a video game got
distracted i don't know what happened
i'm making [ __ ] up our buddy got
distracted and those seedlings went dry
the question is should i start over or
will these plants be stunted in the
future and or offer less yield less
ideal plants to breed and clone in the
long run or will they somehow recover
and be worth keeping thank you irie uh
this is a pretty good question
i don't have any scientifical input or
evidence based on uh what i'm gonna to
support what i'm going to say this is
just what uh i think and what i've
experienced and how i think that uh
the will to survive excuse me if you
heard me get all choked up
talking about the will to survive and
life must go on it got me all choked up
there
so uh you say that the tap roots
generally still seem healthy your
concern here is should i start over will
these plants be stunted uh will these
plants not offer what they could have
um i don't think you if they keep
growing if they survive i don't think
you cause them any problems i think they
will recover i think they'll bounce back
they will give you their full potential
possibly they may be a little bit
stronger i think anything that goes
through a little bit of a struggle a
little bit of adversity and survives it
comes out stronger better i think the
phrase is what doesn't kill me only
makes me stronger i think you may have
done that to these plants if they didn't
die
during your little drought period if
they didn't go too dry they're fine
they're going to be
great plants i would not start over i
would keep growing these i would
proceed as usual
business as usual on with the regularly
scheduled program i think you're going
to get good viable usable plants they
will live up to their potential their
full outcome
you can
clone breed keep a mother plant i think
you're going to do great so nothing to
worry about there as long as you keep
them going as long as they're still
healthy as long as they look happy if
they do give you any problems um once
you get them past that tiny delicate
seedling stage if you do have any
problems don't blame it on yourself for
this issue you do have to get them past
this they've got to recover they've got
to get cotyledons and turn into plants
if you have any issues after the
cotyledons form and they're actually
plants
that is not from this so don't use this
as like a uh
a reason later um this isn't the uh the
sprained ankle and training camp is not
why you lost the fight six weeks later
don't blame this this isn't why so if
you do run into trouble it wasn't from
this i think you will have success i've
rambled on more than enough about this
episode or about this question anonymous
thank you for the great question i hope
i helped you out i hope you keep those
seedlings going i hope they look good
hope they're healthy uh if they're
anything from my line i hope to see
pictures of the kids as they grow up i
do enjoy uh people usually send me a lot
of flower picks i get big chunky bud
shots trichome shots love all that [ __ ]
also i do appreciate
veg picks clone flower seed i love the
whole stage let me see your stuff
especially if there's something weird or
interesting happening in your grow i
like baby pictures i like adult pictures
that sounds weird when you say it like
that
baby pictures of my kids i like that my
seedlings i want to see them in all
stages you guys let's get my high ass
back on track because obviously i'm
rambling up a [ __ ] storm over here
let's focus this message comes from our
friend as i
am i supposed to say your name um
this one comes from our friend dave in
ontario i'm going to cut out part of the
details but big up to our buddy dave in
ontario thank you for the great question
it goes a little bit like this it says
ross to jeff it's your friend dave from
ontario uh it says you and i both have
brain injuries which may be why i'm so
rambly today it says i love we both love
growing cannabis and we love comedians
bro we could be friends did we just
become best friends we grow weed we got
brain injuries and we like comedians we
could get along we could work well on a
car trip together it says you are a
cannabis hero um
i'm not going to argue if you think i'm
your hero but i in no way consider
myself think of myself as a hero that
felt weird to read
but i can't belittle or discredit your
label so i am a [ __ ] hero thank you
bro i appreciate that it says as well as
a general hero to me uh i will
definitely take credit if you call me a
hero i've got to be your hero be
disrespectful not to take it it says i
was that guy talking about a doug
stanhope strain one time uh that's funny
in my instagram lives we chat about
strain names and random chaos i like to
name strains after uh people that
inspire me things that make my life
better uh things that just are great and
i named strains after tom segura and
bert christopher uh burnt chrysler brant
chrysler how do you say it bert
christopher that's the guy's name i made
strains after those guys uh the soccer
souffle and the machine are named after
those two uh tom segura and bert
kreicher and we were joking that there
should be a doug stanhope name
and uh i can't come up with a strain
name for doug stanhope but that'd be
funny because doug stanhope is one of my
uh favorite comedians he is great i got
to see him at the oriental theater here
just a couple of months ago honestly
frustrated myself i caught myself too
high and zoning out during the show i
took a vape pin into that show because
it was a theater show and i was hitting
the pen
the opening act wasn't my favorite no
disrespect to uh i won't even say his
name the opener was boring and i was
just hitting my pen to pass time and by
the time doug came out i was way too
high for a comedy show so i missed i
feel like i missed part of it i realized
this i was like you're zoning out you're
looking around at the crowd and like
paying attention to the wrong [ __ ] i had
to lock myself in and pay attention to
stanhope but he was great i did enjoy it
once i kind of snapped out of my coma
but uh doug stanhope's [ __ ] awesome
if you guys haven't heard digging up
mother listen to that bit it's a comedy
bit um
it's dark it's dark so i hope you're
into dark comedy anyway doug stanhope's
strain name would be great i digress
this message says anyway i have a couple
of your strains in my veg tent from seed
i've got sun kiss and raphael they're
about four to five weeks oh that's good
info it says i want to determine the sex
of my sun kiss
so i turned my veg tint to 1212 to get
the plant to show sex so in five to ten
days i expect to see signs of it being
male or female that will work that's
going to do what you're thinking it's
going to do it says now my question is
how long do i have to run or how long do
i have to run 18-6 again before
determining the sex of the plant
after determining the sex of the plant
sorry i misread part of that i thought
it sounded kind of weird it was my fault
not yours so then he does follow that up
with an example that says my example uh
day one i switched from 18 6 to 12 12
day 55 i determined sun kisses a female
so i switched from 12 12 back to 18 6.
now what day would sun kiss be safe to
go back to 12 12 and go through its
normal flowering cycle
that is a very good question
um
i like the idea i like the strategy i
like the approach however i would have
done this a little bit differently i
would have put these plants into flower
when they were a few inches tall i would
not have done this at wood are we 45
days in
now the hormones in those plants have
spread and developed so much more
and when you put it into flour those
hormones are going to take a little bit
longer to switch over to flower to show
you that the plant is in flower
depending on it may it may be it may
have reached a sexual point in its
growth that it could have some
pre-flower into it it may be ready which
also could be a problem
because then it's not going to want to
go back to veg as quickly so i would
have done it much earlier your plants
are 45 days in when you put them into
flour it is going to take you that 10 to
12 day period to find out if you've got
a male or female
then you can put it back into veg but
it's going to take a little bit longer
because you've got a plant with much
more hormones much more stuff to work
with that you've got to return all the
way back to veg i would give it two
three at least three maybe four weeks to
veg before i went back into flower at
this point you're gonna have a big-ass
plan
what i would have done and i'm not
saying you can't do your method you can
do this
but it's going to be slightly stressful
on the plant and on you what i would
have done what would have been better
next time what you can do is either flip
these plants when they are much much
smaller like i said when they're an inch
tall
i determine the sex before they find
their forever home so i don't waste
space i don't waste soil i don't waste
even waste the time up potting them i
don't waste the electricity
they go from seed into a beer cup i get
some cotyledons i let them grow i put
them into flour they'll show me in when
they're that little they'll show you
pretty quickly if they're male or female
and then you can toss them really
quickly then you don't even transplant
the boys they don't even make it to that
stage so i would have done it much
earlier
then you're gonna vet you're gonna take
your small plants veg them for a week
then flower them for seven to ten days
put them back into veg and now in like
10 to 12 days those plants will go back
into veg because they're so little but
we're gonna grow them out for weeks
because we're just starting them so
they've got all that veg time to recover
uh they're gonna continue to grow while
the hormones go back into a vegetative
stage and it won't take long depending
on how deep into flower you got them 10
or 12 days isn't too far they should
revert fairly quickly if they're little
plants without a lot of a lot of changes
in hormones so that should work better
for you what i can recommend that you
can do with these plants since you're
already at this point i do have a great
recommendation for you to minimize the
stress on yourself and these plants what
i would do at this time is i would take
a few clones from the plant that you're
trying to sex and sex the clone you've
got these big fancy plants they've been
going for
45 days you should have pretty big
plants by now they should be a couple
feet tall they should be nice and
branchy
you should have
at least two or three maybe four or five
viable clones available off of each
plant i would get a clone dome and a
tray and some clone plugs or an easy
cloner if you really want to make an
investment if you've already got it set
it up get it running i would invest in a
cloning setup then i would take a clone
from each of these sun-kissed plants i
don't know how many you have in there
um
a couple of them so it sounds like just
one i would take two or three clones
from the sun kiss plant
one of them if you can turn it into a
mother plant that way you've got a
proven female for next time you already
know it's a girl you don't have to sex
it this is how we uh do a see i would
have done a proper phenohunt first is
kind of what i'm getting at we're gonna
get you a pheno hunt out of this uh to
find out if you've got a plant that's
even worth growing after 45 days what i
would do let me get my ass back on track
here i would take a clone i would get
the clone and a clone dome uh you've
probably got four or five clones off
there take four or five clones maybe
designate one as a mom keep that around
i would put this clone dome into flour
right away get four or five clones put
them into flour you can cut the clones
dip them stick them put them under 12 12
lighting while they are rooting they
will also flip to flower they will then
show you in 7 10 12 maybe 14 days if
they are boys or girls those clones will
be boys or girls just like the plant
they came from you've only got one plant
so if it shows you boy that plant's a
boy if it shows a girl that plant is a
girl so i would cut clones
oftentimes i like to lolly pop my plants
right before they go into flower
that means taking off the bottom stuff
if you can get a couple of good clones
off the bottom pull that stuff off there
you can clean the plant up and create
clones at the same time
if your plant is getting tall and it's
getting unruly you can always take that
center top right out of the middle and
use that for a clone i love cloning that
center top i top my plants anyway so
that topping that just becomes a
beautiful healthy hearty clone i label
that one clone a plant a put that clone
in the clone dome put it under 1212
lighting right now in my area i'm in
north america i'm in colorado we're
experiencing less than 12 hours of light
per day i think we're headed back up in
daylight hours at this time we might be
going more but still currently
we do experience [ __ ] about six hours
of daylight it feels like i think we
might get seven and a half eight hours
of daylight right now if you put a clone
dome in a window silla just provided it
daylight it has to stay warm don't get
it cold uh in colorado it might [ __ ]
freeze to death right now oddly it's not
cold enough but it will get cold for the
plant um
put that clone under 1212 lighting if it
gets 12 hours of darkness every day it
will go into flower and then in 10 12
maybe 14 days you will know if that
plant is a male or female and you won't
have to stress out your big plant by
putting it into flour putting it back
into veg at this point
i would almost just put that depending
on how much space you've got you've got
the uh what's your size i think you told
me the size of your tent no it doesn't
say the size i would just put that [ __ ]
in a flower and grow it at this point
and then find out if it's a male or
female 45 days uh what are you waiting
for that's about how long my plants veg
they don't get that much more veg time
that [ __ ] would be running turn it and
burn it at this point um
so you do have an option you do have a
couple of options i wouldn't i wouldn't
recommend putting the big plant into
flour and then bringing it back i would
just veg for two more weeks and then put
it in the flour and send it don't even
bring it back just let it go if it's a
boy it's a boy you cut it down if it's a
girl finish it let it go all the way or
your other option is to take a clone and
put that clone under 1212 lighting right
away and it will show you sex within
just a few days uh in the future i would
recommend to either get a clone from it
much earlier as soon as the plant is big
enough to clone cut a clone sex the
clone or sex that plant when it is real
tiny so we don't get 45 days in um and
not know if that plant is a boy or a
girl i i couldn't handle 45 days
wondering is that a dude or is that a
chick that i've been hanging out with
like i'd really want to know by now so i
find out much earlier that way it would
have never even it's probably in a three
maybe a five gallon pot do you tell me
in this message you don't mention that
but it's in a pot big enough to sustain
it for 45 days it's probably a three
gallon at least which means you got
three gallons of dirt which means it's
taking up at least a one by one maybe a
two by two square foot space in your
grow space um it is definitely taking
what's most valuable to me in that
equation
is the plant number i'm only allowed so
many plants so if that's a dude that i
don't need that's a wasted [ __ ]
number i could have done something way
better with a plant that i do need what
sometimes i need a boy sometimes i need
a female but if i don't need a boy and
it's a boy uh get rid of it so i can
replace it i can have 12 and every one
of those 12 counts when you're a seed
breeder trying to create new [ __ ] trying
to discover things final hunt keep moms
it gets hectic it's a fun juggle so
let me quickly recap because that is my
style what i would have done is i would
have flowered it much sooner and then
put it back into veg when it was six
inches tall it would have gone into
flour maybe even three or five inches
tall would have gone into flower we
would have discovered if it was a boy or
a girl then put it right back that way i
don't have to take a clone i don't have
another plant count that's a way to
dodge another plant in the count just
flower that one then it's still there
the other that clone just doubled my
plan account if i clone everything to
sex test it i just doubled my [ __ ]
count so i would do that or uh there's
another option i almost looked over sex
testing you can do the mail-in sex
testing order a sex test card rub your
weed plan on the card mail it in the lab
will tell you if it's a boy or a girl
let me get back on track where i was
what i would do what i would recommend
is the early sexing from a small plant
or grow it get a clone sex test the
clone when you do the clones also you
can revert the clones they'll go back
quicker and you can keep a mom that way
um or you can put this bad [ __ ] into
flower and see what it does at this
point i know it sounds uh
it may sound crazy but dude you're 45
days in how long do you really plan on
vegging this plant how big do you want
it you're already 45 days in i would
just turn it and burn it send it see
what you got if it's a boy you've wasted
45 days if it's a girl you're gonna have
a decent harvest
if you want to keep vegging it it's
going to get big
but in in
i think quicker veg cycles and more
cycles per year is more productive in my
opinion i don't know your space i don't
know your situation
but my advice [ __ ] send it get her
done get that [ __ ] out of there get it
going get more plants in
i would already flower the crop by now i
would have been i would have been ahead
of you anyway that's just what i would
do uh my buddy dave from ontario i hope
i did not break your heart by giving you
by saying that i wouldn't do what you're
planning to do it will work but it will
be stressful there are better ways to do
it what i did do was i set you up with
strategies and ideas for the future we
set you up for success for next time so
i hope something was helpful something
works out for you ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers real people figments of
my imagination virtual reality the
metaverse this beautiful universe we are
in together i want to thank you once
again for listening watching joining me
for another episode of the grow from
your heart podcast this is a quick
episode we're at that time between
christmas and new year's everyone is
taking a break i'm going to take a
little break too and just give you a
quick episode thank you for hanging out
i do appreciate it make sure you support
all my social media stuff on instagram
it's irie underscore genetics follow the
show i don't post enough from the show's
instagram account if you give me some
follows maybe you'll encourage me to use
that account it is
the grow from your heart podcast what is
it grow from your heart podcast i don't
even know what it is find it on
instagram search grow from your heart
podcast give it a follow maybe that [ __ ]
will pop up on twitter it's gfyh podcast
of course there is a website
iriegenetics.com don't forget about the
patreon at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart that's a lot of
information at the end i don't expect
you to remember any of it i hope one
thing stuck in your head support the
show
all right um i think that's all i've got
for you for this episode i'll be back in
a couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a giant shout out to my buddy
carl woodward and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you