[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls and
everything in between i'm your host
rasta jeff and this is episode 704
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
adjusting our grow spaces for the winter
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
the kind of folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to romy1
kenobi let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to grow bandit i
want to send a special thank you shout
out to our friends fiscals organics and
uncle adam the uber driver let's send a
big thank you shout out to stash drop
269 and grow man stan let's send a fist
bump to kojaks and polo paul let's send
a thank you shout out to shakoba and
terp burglar let's send a big fist bump
to magic mike then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to the hardest
working man in cannabis my friend james
brown
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www dot
dot
forward slash grow from your heart of
course all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen and i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make that
nice and easy for all of our friends i
do want to take a brief moment to send a
big shout out a big uh big some love
some energy to everybody in boulder if
you've been watching the news uh the
boulder area of colorado has been
experiencing suffering from some extreme
fires many people have lost their homes
their properties their businesses their
belongings a lot of [ __ ] has burnt down
it is devastating to watch on the news i
know people personally who have lost uh
homes items uh animals a lot of [ __ ]
went wrong up there so big shout out
lots of love and energy to all of the
people in boulder that entire area
suffering through those fires that is
terrible to watch their houses got
burned down and then the next day we got
a foot of snow so they got their asses
kicked up there lots of love to those
folks if you need some help if you need
anything reach out i'll do my best to
help you out any way that i can alright
big shout out to everybody in boulder
big shout out to everybody uh going
through some rough stuff at the start of
the year that's a struggle start the
year with some problems all right this
is of course the first episode of the
new year let's shift gears happy new
year everybody thank you for joining me
let's kick off the new year strong what
can we do as growers as breeders as
cannabis consumers to kick off the new
year strong we should start goals and
journals that's right if you're growing
you should have a grow room journal
inside of that journal you should create
some goals what are you going to get
better at this year what did you [ __ ] up
last year in your grow that you didn't
like the way you did that you know you
could have done better what are we going
to improve on this year set some goals
set some ways to improve set yourself up
for success in this year if you don't
have any goals if you don't have any uh
objectives any notes how do you know if
you're improving how do you know what
you did then in the second part of that
journal let's start taking a lot of
notes so that when the grow comes out
better or worse than last time we know
exactly what we did so let's start off
this new year by starting a journal in
that journal let's set some goals and
some objectives then when we're working
in the grow room let's write down
everything we do when you mix up a feed
solution write down how much water you
started with sometimes it's a 5 gallon
container a lot of people have a 10
gallon container i rock a 30 gallon
reservoir in one space and another room
i've got a 250 gallon reservoir just
depends on where i'm working but write
down the amount of water you started
with and then write down everything that
you put into it if you mix up 100
milliliters of this nutrient pour it
into your 250 gallon res write that down
i started with 250 gallons of water i
poured in 100 mils of this 150 mils of
this uh this much of this nutrient uh
this many grams of this some of the
stuff i feed is in a powdered form uh
then i phd to this after i put in the ph
down or the ph up to get it to the 6.2
to 6.4 range i would approve of then i
checked the ec and i wrote down the ec
also so i know every nutrient that went
in and exactly how much i know what the
ec of that total solution was at the end
i know what the ph was now when i feed
those plants i can watch and if some
[ __ ] goes wrong in a few days i've got a
note i can say well it's because we gave
it a thousand milliliters of this
instead of eight fifty uh we know not to
give it eight not a thousand just to
stick at a 50 maybe 900 next time we
push that [ __ ] a little too hard she
got a little bit fried that's the way
that you can learn we uh
we're cannabis consumers not only if
most of us who are cannabis growers and
breeders we are heavy cannabis consumers
i really enjoy there's nothing like
taking a couple of fat dabs or smoking a
big fat joint on the way to the grow
place wherever you're going to grow uh
maybe you don't smoke in the car while
you're driving smoke uh right when you
get there we just got to be safe with
what we say you know what i'm talking
about uh don't smoke in the car don't
smoke while you're driving follow all
the legal laws but uh smoke right before
you go into the grow space if that's
legal it's like a zen feeling i just
like to get [ __ ] stoned and go in
there and work i'm in the zone i got the
music going i'm in my bubble my element
that's where i feel super comfortable on
the stage behind some drums and in a
grow room and obviously behind this
microphone doing a podcast or some of my
comfort zones so i like to get a little
blazed and go in there unfortunately
when you get blazed and go in there you
get in the zone you just start doing
[ __ ] like mix up nutrients adjust the ph
test the ec water the plants catch some
runoff test the runoff sometimes a lot
of people do runoff reports we're not
going to delve into the runoff reports
right now but a lot of people will also
test the runoff of the feed solution the
plants are going to have a little
drainage gather that test it check the
ec and the ph of that document that if
you understand how to decipher that code
later in the future that may help you
solve some problems but uh you're going
to be in there doing your routine and
then you're just going to do stuff
you're going to get in the flow and then
you're going to run into either great
success or great problems in the future
and you're not going to remember what
you did to cause that uh success or that
failure if you would have just done a
few things taken a couple of notes do a
few things take a couple of notes the
bigger the grow the more notes i take
which uh i guess that's because it's uh
it's a lot more of an investment but
i'll carry a clipboard around and a big
grow and just write down what i did all
day and if i've got a couple of guys
doing work i have them report to me at
the end of the day and i fill out just a
big report of everything that got done
in every room i tried to compile all of
the ec reports uh the feed reports all
the what got defoliated what got
lollipopped and twisted if there were
any equipment issues that were noticed
if any bugs were issued i noticed in the
room write down everything that you can
in that grow space that way like i said
if you have good success or big failure
you can repeat those results then you
can create what is known in the
commercial industry as a standard
operating procedure you know that on day
one we do this on day two we do this you
can write a book and then every time you
grow you can follow your own instruction
manual and you can nail that [ __ ] then
you can learn how to improve until
you've got some sort of standardized
sample you don't know that you've got
evidence that you're proving that's why
we want to keep notes see what we're
doing all right i've been rambling let
me check on my notes and see where we
were
write down everything that you spray if
you are spraying food a pesticide or a
foliar application whatever you're
applying to the plants write that down
in colorado we're required to write down
any pesticide application uh the
pesticides have to be approved by the
colorado department of agriculture the
colorado uh department department
department of public health and
environment that's a lot of letters to
remember uh they have to be on an
approved pesticide list you have to
write down the pesticide you applied how
much of it per gallon of water how many
gallons of that solution were mixed up
and applied the epa number of the
pesticide you used the time you applied
it the plant numbers of which got
applied there are a lot of notes to be
taken in a commercial environment why
not just start doing that in your own
personal grow that way there are a lot
of advantages to writing down these
pesticide applications if something goes
wrong in the future you've got that
paper trail you know what you sprayed
you know what you applied you know why
you've got that weird rash on your arm
when you go to the doctor you could say
on five days ago i applied this uh
here's the bottle don't bring the bottle
bring the label peel the label off take
the label to the hospital with you when
you go see the doctor show them what you
used explain how it happened tell them
you didn't use proper protective
equipment you got a little rash from it
but write down so everything we do in a
commercial grow has to be written down
and marked get in the habit of doing
that now because what if you end up
working in a commercial grow why not
make it a habit and then you can tell
when you go apply for the job you can
say i'm already documenting pesticides
to department of agriculture colorado
department of public health and
environment standards i'm already
practicing that standard in my personal
growth so i'm comfortable doing it in
the commercial environment just set
yourself up if you want to work in a big
grow that'd be a good thing to do so i
think i've rambled on for the first part
of this podcast long enough start a
journal you guys let's set ourselves up
for success in this new year we got a
brand new calendar year you just turned
the page how many harvests are you going
to pull off this calendar year can you
get six harvest can you get 5.5 harvest
can you stagger them out what is your
goal do you just want four harvests you
have enough rooms to get sick harvest
that's another issue uh what is your
goal what are you going to improve on
what did you really suck at before what
are you not happy with
many people their clone game sucks many
people aren't exactly sure how to sex a
plant many people are afraid to pop
seeds because they don't know how to
tell the difference between a male and a
female let's jump in if you're afraid of
that i'm here to help you out we've got
a lot of resources that will help you
out my discord server my website me
personally the podcast the irie army we
will definitely help you identify your
males and your females so pop some seeds
maybe that's a new new goal for the year
start from seed let's just have a goal
expand or grow you're not going to get
any better if you keep doing the same
thing maybe you're cool maybe you're
satisfied with your grow but
don't you want a little bit more for
your money maybe you can just learn how
to save a little bit of electricity and
still put out the same amount of product
maybe we can save you a few bucks
somewhere and that will help you out
even if your product is as good as you
think it can be maybe we can save money
on lights air water soil maybe a little
bit of labor there's going to be a way
that we can improve you this year all
right i've been rambling set some goals
write down some details write down what
you feed what you mix what you did
have a schedule write down a schedule
and a plan and a goal get some sort of a
flow how long do your clones live in the
clone machine how long do your seedlings
stay in that small section when do you
put them into smaller pots and have
small veg how long do they go into the
bigger veg how long do you veg those
plants then when do you put them into
flour when they go into flour how often
do you defoliate when do you lollipop
when do you pop and twist when you start
adding your bloom boosters based on your
specific feed schedule have a plan let's
set some goals and routines based on
this new schedule we've got for a brand
new year let's set ourselves up for
success you guys write everything down
all right i've been rambling about that
part for long enough i want to segue
into the second half of this podcast if
you will um it finally snowed
that may not be a big deal to you
here in colorado we've been getting very
worried about uh drought like conditions
because we're not getting any snow we're
into january i always say that we get
snow on halloween i make a big joke that
we arrange our halloween costume in
colorado
around the weather because it always
snows on halloween you see people out
there uh the girls in their tinker bell
costumes and the guys in there whatever
costumes i don't even know what dudes
wear anymore uh they're out there in
their costumes little tiny uh just
little walmart outfits because you don't
buy expensive [ __ ] for halloween they're
just freezing their nuts off i always
joke that you got to set your costume up
around a jacket or some long sleeves
that's why i was always chewbacca you
get that long just a big fur suit i
don't even wear anything under it and
i'm nice and warm all night
sorry i gave you that detail anyway uh
we didn't get any snow it's been too
many months without some snow sound like
an old guy talking about that but that
brings drought-like conditions so we
don't get any water for the summer which
leads to uh forest fires which leads to
[ __ ] like what is happening in the
boulder uh superior area right now which
is devastating um if the weather would
have been a little bit more moist a
little bit more snow a little rain we
may not have had such devastating fires
all right i sound like an old guy sound
like a two old guy sitting on the porch
we don't get no water soon but that's
really how it is but we finally got some
snow and when it snowed boy did it snow
it is deep out there i drive a ford suv
and the snow is up to about uh at least
halfway a little bit past halfway from
my tires which is a lot of snow for my
area i live in the city here i usually
don't get that much so it dumped on us
nature is confused my point is you guys
it is cold now it just suddenly went
from uh really nice to super duper cold
here if you are in colorado if you're in
north america now is the time if you
have not already now is the time to jump
our grow rooms into winter conditions
winter preparations i don't know your
grow space i don't know your grow
environment i don't know where you're
growing at all but if it gets cold
outside now is a good time to make some
adjustments we can learn a few things we
can save some electricity we can move
heat around to the right places may not
have to duct as many things let's talk
about a few things to adjust now that it
is winter time because uh being growers
being indoor growers this is mostly
going to apply to the indoor growers
we do have to learn to adjust and adapt
we can't expect the exact same things
that worked in the summer to work for us
in the winter we may need to make some
gear changes some room changes uh just
some basic adjustments just to uh
maximize potential for our garden we
want our plants to still do the best in
the winter as they do in the summer
honestly my fall crop when i grow
indoors in my personal grow my crop like
around halloween is always the best
because it's not super hot it gets hot
here in the summer i'm in southern
colorado we'll have 102 110 days he gets
negative 17 in the winter so that fall
crop when it's like actually tolerable
conditions for plants and humans and you
don't have to fight the sun and the snow
in your grow space those crops are
always the finest in my opinion for me
those are the most successful
but we've got to learn to adjust and
adapt due to seasons now let's talk
about a couple of adjustments that i
make automatically when the winter comes
i usually run in the summer spring time
the warmer part of the year i run led
lighting you guys know that i recently
fell in love with the led lighting i've
been running the canon leds from black
sail big up to our friends at black cell
market
uh whatever else their slogans are these
days keep up with our friends black sail
market give them a follow good lightings
uh good lighting i've been using the
canons i love them they make my plants
uh bushy and dense and they do all the
things i need them to do now that i've
learned them it was a learning curve
figuring out how to use the things but
in the winter
those lights do not provide enough heat
to keep my grow space warm so to keep
that room warm i simply replace the led
lighting with hps lights i put up uh i
take down a few uh leds and i put up
three hps lights and those keep that
small space warm very efficiently i
don't have to duct the air out too much
i do run a duct out to get the humidity
out but i don't run it as often as i
used to during the summer uh so i switch
those lights out to create some heat i
don't want the cool leds in the winter i
actually want the hot hps lights in the
winter now here's another thing that i
do i put those lights on a different
schedule i will run the hps lights
during the night times so instead of
having the lights on from 9 00 am to 9
pm now i will run the hps lights from 9
p.m till 9 00 a.m i do make sure to
carefully adjust my light cycle if i've
got plants in flower uh but i'm
experienced in doing that and i've also
done a full podcast on how to do it uh
just be careful if you're adjusting
plants that are in flower don't just uh
don't give them a long day give them an
extended night to get back on schedule
as the tip there but i will run the the
lights during the night because it gets
colder at night it gets colder at night
naturally the sun goes down it's colder
i use my grow lights to keep the space
warmer during the day the heater's on
the sun is up that grow space will stay
ambiently warm it stays the same
temperature as the rest of the building
the rest of the house which is ambient
temperature because there's central
heating so the the place stays warm
during the normal part of the day but
when it gets cold outside that sun drops
everything gets colder and so to keep it
a little bit warmer in there the lights
do come on during the night cycle uh
during the night time it's not the night
cycle it is the night time for us when i
would be asleep the lights are on it
works out that way for me very well some
people can't do that i understand that
that is one quick adjustment that i do
make another thing that i think about is
moving and ducting my hot air those warm
lights are creating hot air i've got a
veg room which is also filled with warm
air i used to duck that air out of the
grow area it used to go outside so that
it would just get away from the grow now
that it's warm i utilize that heat maybe
sometimes i'll dump some of that heat
into a bedroom and just warm up the
house with it if the rooms are right and
conditions work out sometimes i'll dump
the heat from the veg room into the
flower room during the night time so
that that flowering room will get some
heat during its dark cycle and not get
too cold while the lights are off these
are all small adjustments that you can
learn to custom tailor for your grow
space what do you need to do where are
you getting too much heat where would
you like that heat to go where is it too
cold where would you like that cool to
go learn to manipulate and move that air
around and save yourself on electricity
and ducting make your grow room as
sufficient as you can make it the winter
time is a good time to learn that it's a
completely different struggle than
during the summer so learn to move the
air around instead of dumping it
outdoors don't waste that hot air in the
winter here you heated up that air let's
put it somewhere useful if nothing else
dump it into the house and keep the
house warm you've already paid for the
electricity to warm that air up let's
keep that heat in the house in somewhere
in the facility to at least warm up a
grow room maybe warm up a bedroom warm
up something that is my point don't
waste that hot air now let's think about
something else if you are dumping that
hot air out somewhere are you melting
the snow in a weird section to where
your whole neighborhood knows that that
is a grow think about where the heat is
going we've all seen that photo from
canada where the guy's got the apartment
building and his apartment is the only
one with the snow melting off of it and
they busted him for growing weed in
there are you doing that in the winter
are you snitching on yourself is your
blower melting snow in an awkward place
or does your roof the only roof that
attic space the only space in the
neighborhood without a bunch of snow on
it because your grow is up there melting
that snow think about how you're going
to bust yourself here in the winter
because the snow could give you away
beware of the evidence is what i wrote
all right another thing i want to talk
about is warming up our water which we
use to water our plants in one of the
commercial grows that i used to run the
water would come from a well basically
outside into the building in the winter
that water would be extremely cold we'd
have to put heaters in the reservoirs to
warm up the water i don't know where
your water comes from if the water is
coming from outside in the winter the
pipes are outside it's got to come from
somewhere if it's coming into your home
into your commercial facility it's
probably really cold my advice fill up
your reservoirs whatever you're holding
water in fill those up the night before
and a lot of the commercial grows where
i work we will just get trash cans on
wheels a big rubbermaid or a brute trash
can a 50 gallon trash can on wheels
we'll fill those up with water then we
will move those into the veg room under
the veg lights to stay there overnight
when you come back they have reached
room temperature they're safe to use
don't water your plants with extremely
cold water i wouldn't go less than 70
degrees maybe 68 at the very lowest but
you don't want cold water watering your
plants just think about putting your
toes your balls your hands and some cold
water it's going to piss you off it's
not going to make you want to drink or
eat just going to make you angry that
we'll do the same thing to the plants
let's not piss them off
just get that water nice and warm the
plants will thank you for that also
another thing we could do is get the
plants up off of the ground if the grow
room is cold if you're growing in the
basement or a commercial facility with a
concrete floor let's not have the plants
on the floor that floor is very cold if
you aren't comfortable walking around on
that floor barefoot the plants are not
comfortable there either we're going to
put that water or that plant on the cold
floor then we're going to pour water
into it and that cold floor is going to
make that water really cold the roots
are in there they're not going to feed
properly your ph is going to get all out
of whack things are going to go really
wrong so if you can get those plants up
off of the floor raise them up off the
floor it doesn't take a lot you could
get another pot whatever size pot you're
using buy another one flip it upside
down it'll raise your plant up a couple
of inches set the plant right on top of
that it is off the floor you could use
pallets i don't like pallets because i
kick them i trip on them uh and they're
wood i don't like adding that wood into
the grill but if that's what you got to
do that's what you've got to do i would
prefer you get uh make a get a table
with a hydro tray in there and put the
plants in that and put a drains where
they could drain into something
underneath and you could pull out the
drain to get rid of the water that's
spinning some money that's going in on
it but get those plants up off the
ground for the winter because like i
said if you can't put your bare feet on
that floor and walk around and some of
you [ __ ] got those chewbacca
feet you can't feel anything you've been
at the festival for your whole life you
do not count get those plants up off the
ground set yourself up for success
maximum root growth maximum potential if
the roots are nice and happy all right
podcast world it looks like i've covered
all of my notes i think i'm going to
wrap up this podcast i want to thank you
once again for listening if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know that i would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy send me your feedback send me your
constructive criticism wish me a happy
new year whatever you've got to say i
look forward to hearing from you one of
my new year's resolutions once again is
to be better at answering my emails i
really try to answer all of the emails
that come in i've got patreon messages
discord messages multiple email accounts
i'm not making excuses but it is just me
i'm the only one answering all of those
emails doing these shows living a life
building a dream uh it's just me one of
my resolutions however is to get better
at answering those emails and answer
more of them but when i answer them you
guys reply so i just got to answer that
again and then you reply and then it's
like it's it's i'm just kidding but
we'll catch up we'll get more emails
answered uh if you want to support the
show
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart everything else is on the website
at iregenetics.com
there's a link to vendors there's a link
to the web store you can get your
merchandise there there's a link to the
discord server and of course there is a
patreon link there there's a newsletter
link anything you could imagine if it's
not there let me know we will put it
there ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pollen chuckers island
boys hippie girls everybody out there i
want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast i'll be back in
just a couple of days with fresh new
content let's give a big shout out to my
friend tree star meadow and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
so
bye