[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode
705 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
some of the labels we see on seed
packages what does that s1 mean what
does rbx mean what do all of those crazy
letters mean on our packages before we
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend quasi let's
send a big thank you shout out to
spherical glass works i want to send a
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to my friend danny potts let's send a
thank you shout out to the new old guy
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to g7 let's send a thank you
shout out to brohan 78 let's send a big
fist bump to a long time supporter and a
good friend to my buddy vacanocrat let's
send a thank you to gramps memel i want
to send a big fist bump to girls grow
too let's send a fist wump and a thank
you shout out to blackhawks fan let's
send a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you to groove 2112. let's send a
big thank you shout out to my buddy
lefty and his wife and then let's wrap
it all up with the big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to pac
northwest dan
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends i want to start off by
sending a big thank you to everybody who
has helped get the show closer to 10 000
subscribers that's right all i asked for
for christmas was 10 000 youtube
subscribers we didn't quite reach the
goal but we got very close i've been
noticing a lot more subscribers
i've been noticing a lot more
interaction a lot more likes and a lot
more comments a lot more comments right
away on the videos when a new video
comes out you guys are watching it you
are commenting right away big thanks i
do appreciate that thank you for all the
support the interaction the words of
encouragement all of that stuff does
mean a lot to me i do appreciate it so
please do keep subscribing and keep
leaving those comments on youtube also
if you have more questions corrections
comments or concerns of course the email
address is grow fromyourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy send me those
questions those corrections the comments
the concerns i will get that into the
show thank you once again for all of
that interaction i do appreciate it all
right i don't want to ramble too much
here at the start of the show i feel
like we could talk for a long time about
this topic so let's jump right into this
email this one came from patreon it came
from our friend luke and it goes a lot
like this it says hey ross to jeff i
just finished the podcast the podcast
about back cross would you do another
one on the same topic just go a little
further like talking about an rb x1 and
keep crossing it to itself or better yet
crossing it back to its mom or an rb x1
s1 to a p1 or crossing that to an s3 to
an s1 it looks like you just grabbed a
bunch of seed packs and saw those
letters on there and just decided to
throw a bunch of those in the email i
know what you're saying i know what
you're asking for we can delve into this
it says i love the show and all of the
knowledge it brings us you can say my
name say my name say my name big shout
out to my buddy luke61 uh thank you for
the great question and for the continued
patreon support this is a good question
we see this on a lot of seed packs i am
a seed maker
seed seller i try to label my seed packs
quite clearly i see a lot of other
seed makers and seed breeders and seed
sellers
creating
really confusing seed labels and i see a
lot of arbitrary things out there so
let's try to talk a little bit about
some of those letters and labels that we
see on our seed packages
now luke did ask about some very
specific lettering in here but i do want
to start with a little bit of a
foundation what can we learn without a
foundation so let's start from the
beginning most of the time we're going
to see things like f1 or f2 if we see
the letter f in there that means filial
generation most of the time if you see
an f it is going to be a regular male
female
non-feminized c that will not always be
the case but most of the time a f1 and
f2 will be a regular male female seed
we will talk about s1s and r1s in a
moment those are also f1s we'll talk
more about that in a minute but i wanted
to just throw that out there and s1 is
also an f1 but an f1 is not always an s1
that will that will make sense in just a
minute but i wanted to make sure to put
that out there
so when we take two plants that are
vastly different and we breed them
together we are now making an f1 hybrid
if those plants are too close together
we haven't done our proper breeding that
is a polyhybrid that is a whole other
podcast conversation that we could talk
about in the future i would love your
feedback and input on talking about the
difference in f1s and poly hybrids that
can be a fun conversation so most of the
time if we see the letter f that is
indicating filial generation and f1
means it is the first time that that has
been crossed that golden goat and
daybreaker have been crossed we just
made a rise f1 it is the first filial
generation now if i were to find a male
and a female from that first batch of
seeds we take the daybreaker and the
golden goat we breed them together it
makes seeds that is an f1 if i grow out
those seeds and find an awesome male and
an awesome female and cross those
together we have now made f2 we are
making filial generation number two
as long as we keep repeating that
process we are moving forward and in
what is called the filial generation we
take the plants that come out of f2 we
grow those we find a solid male and a
solid female we breed those together we
have now made the f3 repeat that process
all the way up to f6 and you will make
totally completely stable plants that
look like clones of each other if you
have done the selection process properly
so that is moving forward in filial
generations f1 f2
that should make sense i'll just keep
going number wise as long as we're
pulling from that batch of seeds and not
adulterating and going backwards or
bringing in new plants anywhere you were
moving forward with the filial
generation you take a male and a female
you make new seeds that is f1 you take a
male and a female from that batch and
now you breed them together you make f2
you take a male and a female from that
batch you make f3 i think i've made that
clear now let's talk about where do we
go from there let's jump into the back
cross i did talk about back cross in a
previous episode we will talk about that
the bat cross if i were to take the
golden goat and the daybreaker and breed
them together we have now made an f1 if
i were to take the male plant or we
could do the female but we're to stick
with the male for
my topic here if i were to find a male
plant out of that f1 batch and pollinate
the original golden goat girl again that
is a bat cross if you use one of the
plants that you used in the original if
you go backwards if you cross back to
one of the original parents you are back
crossing the reason we would do that is
to stabilize and isolate the traits of
that original parent plant that is the
focus of the back cross podcast so you
can listen to that to learn all about
back crossing so an f1 is when we make
new stuff uh f2 f3 is when we breed that
further down the line uh with itself not
back to another plant but forward with
itself bat cross would be going back to
one of the original parents no matter
what generation you're using you can
always back cross you can do an f3 back
to the one of the original parents you
could do an f4 back to the parent it
would still be a back cross you may
label that
golden goat how would you label it
golden goat two uh a rise f4 back cross
that's how that would be because if you
use the f4 you'd want to indicate that
the f4 was used in there a lot of people
just want to know that information a lot
of this is just a lot of it isn't
important if you're just growing this
and enjoying it a lot of this is
important if you're going to make seeds
and sell or share them or if you're just
really trying to document history of
cannabis a lot of this won't be
important to a smoker or a consumer it
wouldn't matter to you at all but if
you're kind of nerding out and creating
things and wanting to know history and
how to make labels and how to understand
the labels better this would help you
out all right so we've done f1 i feel
like we've covered back cross now let's
talk about r and s rns is when people
get confused
i've talked about this before the
easiest way for me to explain this is
reversal is when we are making feminized
seeds we will take a female plant and
treat it with the solution now we have
reversed that plant to become a pollen
donor we're not going to label we're not
going to label that plant as a male
we're going to label that plant as a
pollen donor because it is not a male it
is also not a hermaphrodite when you
guys talk about
feminized seeds and feminize plants and
reversing plants stop saying
hermaphrodite because it is not a
hermaphrodite if it were an intersex
plant i would not use it i am using a
solid female plant that is treated with
a solution to create pollen it is not a
hermaphrodite it is not intersex that is
my rant on that let me stay on focus
i would take a female plant and treat it
with a solution now it will create
pollen that pollen is now feminized
pollen what i do with that pollen
dictates if i am creating s or r
generations now let's talk about that an
r generation would be a reversal if i
reverse that plant and put that pollen
on any other cultivar other than itself
we have just made a reversal that is an
r1
let's talk about lemon jeffrey as an r1
lemon jeffrey is a reversed golden goat
pollinated pollinated a lemon skunk so
we got a reverse golden goat took the
pollen put that on lemon skunk the
offspring from that is the lemon jeffrey
that is an r1 i used reversed pollen put
it on a different plant we made an r1
that is the that is an s1 that is an s1
because it is the first creation the
first filial generation of this plant
but i would use r1 to indicate to my
customers my consumers the people buying
these seeds the people looking at the
website that this is a feminized
creation that is why i would go with the
r in that indication to show you it's
been reversed pollen and it is the first
time we have done that it is an r1 now
where does the s come in you'll never
forget this it sounds crass but i
promise you'll never forget
the letter s in that indication stands
for self which means that plant
basically [ __ ] itself if we were to
take golden goat reverse the golden goat
pollinate another clone of the golden
goat we are making golden goat s-1 that
is a golden goat self-plant there's
nothing else in that golden goat to
adulterate those golden goat genetics i
took a golden goat plant i reversed it
put put another golden goat plant up
there and it basically [ __ ] itself
that sounds crass but i promise you're
going to remember that that is a self
plant that is when a plant is flipped
reversed pollinated itself and [ __ ]
itself and makes seeds of itself that is
a feminized golden goat s1
also an f1
so basically when we make feminized
seeds if it is a reversal if the pollen
from the donor plant is used on any
other plants that is an r1 that is a
reversal if that feminized pollen is put
back on the same plant that it was
reversed from the same cultivar it would
be a different clone but it's the same
plant basically you see what i'm saying
that would be an s because it is selfing
itself you'll never forget that it just
selfed itself it's either it's been
reversed or self so let's talk more
about some of the details which you
asked oh uh you said p1 you included the
letters p1 in here p1 p means parent so
p just stands for parent is what p is in
that equation now let's talk a little
bit more you said can you talk about
taking it further like
taking an rb x1 which is a reversed back
cross one let's talk about what is a
reversed back cross one let's uh
decipher this code
all right so i'm going to pick a plant
to give an example with this rbx1 i'm
just going to pick blueberry cookies
because i work with that a lot it does
make great reversals great fem seeds
great outcrosses let me try to explain a
little bit about what this rb x1 is
without having the actual seed package
in front of me i don't know uh what they
did there and i don't know where you got
the idea so i'm going to try to explain
this to the best of my knowledge i have
a good idea uh who you're reading these
uh letters from rbx1 the r indicates
that that is a reversal so this will be
feminized bx1 indicates that there was a
plant that was selected and bred back to
its parent for a desired trait without
knowing a little bit more history of
this i don't know exactly which order it
happened but it sounds like we took a
plant and reversed it and put that
pollen back on one of its parents is
possibly what happened here because you
were it's a reversal which is an r so i
would assume we've got the plant we
treated it with the solution that plant
made pollen then we put that pollen back
onto one of its parents would be my
assumption here again without the uh
without the seed pack without more
details without more of the story all i
can do is make assumptions and try to
decipher this code here but rbx1 would
be
if you took a plant and reversed it and
put that pollen from that plant back
onto one of its parents would be an easy
way to explain that one
so let me try to think of how that would
go we would take a blueberry cookies
plant and then we would uh reverse that
and we would pollinate another plant it
doesn't matter which plant that is uh
we'll say that we pollinated strawberry
fields and we just made the raphael
so now we've got blueberry cookies to
strawberry fields makes raphael now at
this point we've got to do a back cross
so i think we're going to take the
raphael plant which is the blueberry
cookies and the strawberry fields we're
going to treat that with a solution
which will make that plant make pollen
now we can take that pollen and put it
back on either the blueberry cookies or
the strawberry fields plant or we could
do the opposite we could reverse the
blueberry cookies or the strawberry
fields and put that to the raphael but
i'm not sure which order they did it
because i don't have more details but
that kind of gives me an idea of what
happened there was a reversal and
something went back to apparent without
more of the equation i can't really do
the math uh there's algebra to be done
here and i don't have the other letters
all right
so that is rbx1
all right then you wrote s1 crossed to
p1 if we selected a keeper from that uh
batch of feminized seeds and put it back
to one of the original parents is what
it sounds like that would be that would
have to be feminized right because we're
making a reversal in s1 that's a
feminized project back to one of the
original parents that would be a fem
project that uh that's kind of almost is
that an s1 bad that's kind of a back
cross right there you're doing a
feminized back to one of its parents
that's a really good way to lock in
certain traits if you find a feminized
seed with the trait that you're looking
for cross it back to one of his parents
that is a her appearance that is a
really good way to lock in and isolate
traits that you're looking for that
would work really well or crossing an s3
to an s1
um
if you're doing an s3 to an s1 that is
the same line that is a back cross if
you're doing an s3 to an s1 like a self
plant let's just say that we got a
golden goat uh where are we
s3 s3 just sounds weird i don't think
anybody even does s3 yeah i'm not
familiar with anybody that does an s3
i've seen s2s i'm not sure that colin's
going to s3 or not
but so let's just say that we took a
golden goat and selfed it and then
golden that golden goat and selfed it
and did it again and did it again to the
third generation and then if we just
took a different plant there was an s1
like a lemon skunk s1 across those
you're just making another f1 that is
just another poly hybrid uh it would be
an s1 an f1 or a poly hybrid probably
fit in all of those categories
but honestly technically most of these
labels don't really matter unless you
are the breeder unless you really want
to know the details about how these
plants were made what came from these
plants
if you're that passionate and that
curious about the crosses and the
history i'm sure that a little bit of
research on the website of the breeder
that made those seeds will give you a
lot of clues of what they've been doing
you can see the history of a lot of my
crosses and where things have gone
just if you looked at like the current
stuff you could see what's been crossed
to add up to what we've got going on now
so if you did a little bit of diving a
little bit of investigation you could
probably reverse engineer most of the
crosses that you see on a lot of popular
breeders websites i think i understand
where you're getting these ideas my
friend colin at the ethos collective at
etho seeds likes to use the rs the s's
the bx um
and honestly
these labels are kind of being uh
bastardized and readjusted and
reinvented to suit the cannabis industry
we're not really using them the
technical way uh that they were meant to
be done in agriculture and horticulture
i really don't even think that bx is the
correct term my friend f1 pete i could
see a little vein in his head his head
tries to rupture every time we say bx
so we may start adjusting and correcting
that to bc because it is back cross
again i said bx
we use that because when we're listing
crosses we put the x in there and when
you go to back cross it you just use the
x because it stands for cross and it's
back cross it makes sense but i honestly
don't think it is correct the cannabis
industry is kind of bastardized and uh
just created and altered this labeling
system to work for us
um
one thing i can say though when we're
listing genetics this may be kind of a
side ramp but this is important always
list ladies first or pollen donor first
because sometimes we're working with
feminized reverse plants i don't want to
call that one a boy that is a reversed
lady in 2021 we've got to use the proper
pronouns that is a reversal not a dude
not a lady that's a reversal definitely
not a hermaphrodite not intersex it's
definitely not a herme hermes not even a
word
that word sounds so third grade to me
herme
just say herm or intersex intersex is
the real word all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimp so's friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters pawn
chuckers my voice is cutting out really
quickly here i just felt it tell me hey
bro it's time to wrap up this show i'm
going to listen to my body and quit
rambling i want to thank you guys and
gals for listening to another episode of
the grow from your heart podcast if you
have any questions corrections comments
or concerns i would love to hear from
you once again the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy also support the show on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen if i
said all of that too quickly and you
can't find it everything you need is on
the website at ire genetics
all right that is all i've got for you
for this episode i want to thank you
again for listening i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend bongstein bear and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
you