[Music]
yeah welcome to the podcast everybody
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff this is episode 706 of the grow
from your heart podcast in this episode
i'm going to talk about king solomon and
how i select male plants for breeding
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to stoned
trout bomb let's send a big thank you
shout out to roll this nug in growing
tennessee let's send a big thank you
shout out to romy one kenobi and mr mean
green i want to send a thank you shout
out to noah n and jay dutch let's send a
fist bump to daniel an adhd grower let's
send a thank you shout out to nomi by my
guacamole and polo paul then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
shoetrader101 big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends all right i don't want to ramble
too much here at the start of the show
let's jump into the main topic of this
episode we're going to talk about king
solomon and selecting male plants i got
a message from our friend darcy and it
goes a little bit like this
it says hey ross to jeff let me start
with how much i love your work the
podcast has kept me company for years
and i have learned a lot from you that
is a great compliment i love knowing
that people are learning from me and i
love knowing that uh the podcast keeps
you company i listen to a lot of
podcasts myself i listen when i'm
driving when i'm working uh when i just
need some entertainment and it is like
hanging out with some of your best
friends you get to pick and choose who
you listen to uh sometimes it's better
than having your friends around because
you can just press pause mute next skip
whenever you want you can hear good
entertaining [ __ ] so i'm glad and i'm
excited and grateful that you were
choosing me thank you for choosing me to
be in your ear rambling at you all day i
do appreciate that
and also i'm glad you're learning from
me that is the goal here let me keep
going because i can get rambly quite
quickly it says i am also a huge fan of
your breeding work thank you it says i
was also lucky enough to score some
lemon jeffrey a while back and they were
beautiful plants that grew the most
amazing daytime weed super energetic
social and she was a beauty that's a
great compliment thank you it goes on it
says
i now want to start making some seeds of
my own yeah that is the natural
progression a lot of people start
growing they get good at growing then
they realize i want to breed and see
what i can create that is a very natural
progression that's kind of how we ended
up where i am today it says after uh
after years of hearing you speak about
king solomon i thought your genetics
might be a good place to start i could
not get any arise seeds in my area but i
was able to score some dark hollow that
will still be great that'll be a great
project so many people are breeding with
the rise that you will set yourself
apart by breeding with the dark hollow
so that's a good start it says my plan
is to search this pack for a breeding
male
then hit that pollen to some proven
females that is a really good strategy
there are a couple of things i want to
touch on before i get too much further
a lot of breeders in this industry in
this game in this community do not like
it when new growers or growers or
breeders work with their stuff for
breeding purposes they find it they're
territorial they're possessive they want
to have some control over their plants
i don't feel that way if you have
acquired seeds or plants of mine if you
paid for them if you traded for them if
you didn't steal them even if you did
steal them i can't stop you um you have
permission rights um my blessings to
breed with the seeds that i have made i
did not invent cannabis i didn't pull
seeds out of the sky i didn't fart out
some seeds and breed with those i used
seeds and plants that were bred by other
breeders before me so i find no problem
in breeding with my stock if you find a
male or a female in a pack of my seeds
that you want to work with i highly
encourage and promote you to do the
breeding work the only thing i can ask
for is credit if you sell those seeds if
you post them anywhere if the pictures
of those buds get any recognition when
you do list the cross give me some
credit put that that was a dark hollow
mail from ire genetics that was used for
the pollen donor or put that it was a
strawberry starburst or a orange gasm or
a sun-kissed female whatever you use
just give me credit that's all that i
really want also a few seeds would be
cool if you want to send me beans that
would be polite however i don't have
time or space to run them right now
anyway so that wouldn't be too much of a
setback if i didn't get that pack if you
did send them i would find time to run
them and when i do run them i would send
you a clone of the keeper is usually how
that works anyway
i wanted to make sure that people do i
know realize and understand you've got
full permission to breed with the seeds
you've acquired from me once you pay for
those they're yours it's like if you
bought a ferrari and the car dealer
tried to tell you now you can't drive
this car like an [ __ ] what is the
point you bought a ferrari you want to
drive like an [ __ ] go have fun i feel
the same about my seeds now i said there
was a couple of things i wanted to
unpack in that statement one more thing
i want to talk about you have got a pack
of dark hollow seeds and you are looking
for a male
one thing i always say is when we get
seeds when you get a seed pack we're
probably going to get you've probably
got a 10 pack you're probably going to
find approximately five males five
females something i want to mention is
when it comes to breeding i never use
the first male plant of the bunch that
shows me it's a boy for my breeding
project that first plant to display male
traits in my opinion is going to be too
much male for the mix let me try to
explain what i mean
that first dude to show you that he's a
boy is just too much testosterone
maybe he's he's there's nothing wrong
with that plant but i wouldn't use him
for breeding he's going to put too much
of himself into the offspring
a lot of times my goal when i'm breeding
is to
mix or blend the male and the female and
have traits of both parent plants show
in the offspring
if we use a male plant that is too
dominant we're just going to be
reproducing that male plant in all of
the progeny so if you cross
that male plant to strawberry to orange
to bubble gum you're going to wash out
the orange and the strawberry and the
bubble gum and just recreate more of
that male plant because he's got too
much of his genetics into the mix so a
lot of times i completely skip the first
and second male to start showing me that
they are male plants oftentimes those
are really tall really stretchy really
fibrous plants and we don't want to
breed tall stretchy fibrous offspring we
want to make vigorous potent offspring
so get rid of those tall stretchy dudes
that are just going to make tall
stretchy offspring we're not trying to
make hemp here we want to make cannabis
so
i would get rid of the first maybe even
the second dude to show me that it's a
dude i usually work with that third or
fourth male out of a group of five
honestly i would rather have more seeds
to choose from but if you've got quality
seeds you will find a keeper in that 10
pack you will find a boy worth working
with now i think i've unpacked the two
things i wanted to talk about in there
let's move forward and read more of this
message
it does go on to say i've always been a
fan of the strain specific episodes and
i was wondering if you would consider
doing one on king solomon to help me
find a boy with similar traits to help
me understand what makes him special
compared to other male plants all right
that is a great question i love that you
appreciate these strain specific
episodes sometimes i feel like those are
uh bragging or tooting my own horn or
advertising or whatever but i love that
you guys appreciate those so thank you
so in this episode what i'm going to try
to do is kind of a mash-up we're going
to talk about solomon we're going to
talk about his traits what he is why i
selected him why he works so well for me
in that same process we're going to talk
about everybody else selecting a male
plant for a breeding project what we
have to keep in mind here
is we've got different goals or possibly
different goals i don't know your total
outcome goal here you said you want to
cross the dark hollow with a few proven
females and then we'll see what that
does
i don't know your ultimate goal my goal
is to make seeds for commercial
production and for retail sales there's
i've got a goal my seeds have to work in
a variety of grow spaces they've got to
germinate well they've got to give us
what we're expecting i don't know your
goal so we've got different goals we've
also got a different male plant to work
with here so it's all about the goal
keep that in mind that we've got
different goals and different starting
ingredients but i'm sure that you can
follow along so let's jump right into it
and talk about what is king solomon king
solomon is a specially selected male
plant from a batch of arise f1 seeds
what the heck does that mean i took a
golden goat female and a daybreaker male
and i pollinated the golden goat female
that made a rise f1 from that batch of
arize f1 seeds i found a male that stood
out to me in many ways for many reasons
that male has been named king solomon
i've got one plant that is a dude with
his own specific name that's how much i
like him that's how much i rely on him
that's how successful he has been and if
you're curious about the name uh that is
some torah biblical stuff research king
solomon uh king solomon was a king he
could have had anything he wanted his
weaknesses was that he loved the ladies
so i named my male plant solomon because
he has pollinated a lot of ladies he's
doing work spreading his generations so
king solomon is in a rise f1 male just
in a rise male selected from a batch of
seeds i love the way he grew i knew he
was gonna stick around i gave him his
own name he is king solomon i call him
saul i call him sully
he gets a lot of names around here he
gets a lot of love so that is king
solomon an f1 arise male now let's talk
about uh why i chose that male why did i
choose him i grew out a bunch of seeds
and i ran a bunch of male plants side by
side and this is the one that stood out
why
i really liked the vigor this plant has
got hyper vigor he veges super quickly
he flowers super quickly a lot of people
tell me that they have to adjust their
scheduling differently because they are
growing a rise crosses in their grow and
the plants veg so quickly they can cut
off a week or two weeks of veg time so
that is how quickly a rise grows that
trait from that male plant that passes
on to most of his offspring so he's got
great vigor that is one of the main
traits that i like about him he's also
known for having good resistance many of
his progeny the offspring he makes are
resistant to pathogens powdery mildew
mold and also bugs like spider mites you
see a lot of these plants don't get as
badly affected by bugs as many other
plants in the garden i also really like
the shape and the structure of king
solomon he's got a good shape and a good
structure and that translates into the
plants that come from him his progeny
have a good shape and a good structure
and hyper vigor so that is really
important for a male plant now let's
talk about one of the most obvious and
most important traits that come from
king solomon solomon is known for
passing on extremely high potency
everything solomon touches turns to gold
in my opinion it comes out vigorous it's
got good structure it grows quite
quickly and it is super potent sometimes
i call king solomon the fixer or the
corrector plant because i'll have a
female plant that i really like the way
that it grows but it's just missing
something maybe it's not putting out
enough harvest weight maybe it's not
putting out enough potency maybe it
doesn't grow quickly enough so i will
pollinate it with king solomon and that
seems to improve and put other plants
into turbocharged whatever i pollinate
it with the offspring is the female
plant plus turbo it is the female plant
plus more trichomes more potency and
more vigor and more harvest weight so
that's a big part of why solomon is a
great male he adds resistance he adds
vigor he adds potency and he doesn't
disrupt the flavor too much if i have a
female plant that's got a great flavor i
know that saul is going to go in there
and fix the structure the potency and
he's going to leave that flavor that the
females got so i can find that good
balance that's why i like to cross it to
you've seen it across to a strawberry
plant not a strawberry but a strawberry
flavored plant an orange flavored plant
a blueberry flavored plant because i
like to keep those terps and those
flavors in there but i want to add that
vigor that potency i think it's really
coming from king solomon so that potency
is a main factor that everybody relies
on we love that potency i also love that
it is a fixer like i said if there's a
plant that's just not performing the way
that i need it to pollinate it with king
solomon the seeds that come from that
will be that original female plus turbo
plus bonus plus diesel plus super charge
because we hit it with king solomon it
gives it that potency and then it
doesn't ruin the flavor but it gives it
it just turbocharges the flavor it kind
of adds a little gas to it a little funk
to it and who doesn't love a little gas
a little funk added to almost any strain
you're smoking so that's a big part of
why we chose solomon let me take a look
at these notes here
it does not ruin the buzz and it doesn't
overpower the crosses it lets the female
shine that's something i find important
if we're trying to make a cross i like
to see the male traits and the female
traits in the cross so i want that
potency the vigor the aggression from a
rise but then i still want those
strawberry terps and that plant
structure and i want to see both of them
in the mix and arise tends to not over
dominate in the crosses
so that is basically why i have chosen
king solomon uh he adds vigor he adds
aroma he adds potency uh he adds
resistance he fixes things if you've got
a plant that is not living up to par
that is doing a lot of great things but
it's missing something king solomon
likely will add what it is missing
that's why i've chosen to breed almost
everything in my garden gets pollinated
by king solomon and then we see what it
does now let's talk about your breeding
project your project is different than
mine it starts off different because
you've got a different male we can't
make the same thing because you don't
have the same male as me which is good
i'm already making a rise crosses a lot
of people are already making a rise
crosses you're going to make some dark
hollow crosses which will be great but
we've got to i want to help you select
your mail and give you some ideas of how
to select that dude um what is your goal
the most important part of any breeding
project is knowing a goal what do you
want to do what do you want to create
what what are you lacking what is not in
your garden maybe you've got a female
plant that you want to fix what is that
female plant not giving you
before you do this cross before you
chuck any pollen
write down the male plants you're going
to use the male plant you are going to
use and the female plants you're going
to use list the females then make kind
of a prediction a hypothesis a theory
what are these crosses going to be like
once you make them if you cross this
dark hollow male to female number one
what is your predicted goal what will
the aromas and flavors be like how will
it grow what phenotypes are you looking
for why did you do this list that for
every cross you're about to make
then make the cross then the funnest
part is growing out those seeds to see
what you did the only way to find out
what your male plant is doing
to the crosses is by pollinating several
females and then growing those out and
looking at the differences in those
crosses when you cross it to strawberry
does it still taste like strawberry or
does it taste like strawberry or did we
wash that out when you cross it to
blueberry does it taste like blueberry
or did we wash that out did it get the
vigor of the male plant the terps of the
female what's it doing find out what it
is contributing to the mix if you just
cross it to one plant you're only going
to see one set of traits it's hard to
identify what the male is doing unless
it's really obvious if you put it to
several females we can really see what
the effects are on all of those
different female plants so i would start
off by looking for a plant with the
structure you are looking for how do you
want your future plants to be shaped i
like kind of taller plants because i
like those sativa dominant plants with
big colas because i like a lot of herb
and i like a uh a really head ripping
head buzz and i think sativa dominant
tall skinny plants give me that head
buzz i'm looking for so i would look for
tall skinny plants with long skinny
leaves maybe that's not what you want
find the leaf shape and plant structure
that you want we know that bigger whiter
leaves are usually more indica dominant
skinnier leaves are going to be more
sativa dominant find the leaf shape and
plant structure that suits your goal
what are you looking for then one thing
to think about is aroma and flavor what
does this plant smell like give it a
stem rub smell your fingers does it
smell like vomit does it smell like
trash can does it smell like fruit does
it smell like berries what are you
looking for i really like a male plant
that smells like vomit if the male plant
smells acrid and gross that's probably
going to translate into good stuff in
the offspring keep in mind this is one
ingredient this isn't the total equation
you're going to add that dirty stinky
socks gasoline and bar trash can to
other things and see how they mix
together so i really like a male that's
got a nasty gross acrid putrid vomit bar
trash can kind of aroma now another
really important thing to think about in
my opinion is flowering time do you want
plants to take a long time to flower in
my opinion longer flowering plants get
better potency i just like that longer
flowering plant i feel like it can do
something more with the potency the buzz
is better or do you need a rush plant
that gets out of there in eight weeks
then i would find a male that finishes
the flowers in eight weeks if you need a
plant that finishes sooner i would find
a faster flowering male the only way to
do that is to let the males flower out
in the test room so let me talk about
that for a little bit i might not even
pollinate with the first run of growing
this male plant i might grow out five
male plants and finish them let them go
nine weeks let them go ten weeks and see
what they do at week ten you may watch
one plant bulk up it may stop making
pollen it may keep making pollen those
are things to look for how does that
plant act at a few weeks into flower
seven eight nine does it do weird [ __ ]
does it give you nutrient issues does it
start doing does it explode with growth
does it stop putting out trichomes it
start putting out trichomes pay
attention to that grow that male plant
out as long as you can
then the next time you run it is when
you want to collect the pollen and do
the pollination i wouldn't collect
pollen if you've got multiple dudes
around because who knows uh it's going
to be a mori situation we won't know who
the baby daddy is if you got multiple
dudes around so grow those dudes out
flower them see what they do see how
they perform how do they handle
nutrients how do they handle light
what's going on laid in flower a lot of
people don't even know what a male plant
is going to look like at week 10.
get your boys to week nine week ten see
what they do pick one from there then do
the pollination in the next run that's
what i would do so then that is the main
part you get to do pollination pollinate
the plants then finish those seeds then
that is when we really get to do the
test germinate those seeds do they
germinate if they don't germinate i
wouldn't really continue too far making
more of those seeds then after
pollination is the fun part you get to
wait for the seeds to finish then you
get to harvest them pull the seeds out
of each plant that you pollinated keep
them separate make sure they're labeled
so you know what you're growing then
grow as many as you can i don't know
your legalities i don't know your
limitations but i would grow at least 10
of each one and take a lot of notes see
what they do compare similarities and
differences between each cross then we
can see what that male plant is doing to
the mix if you don't like what he did
don't be afraid to throw those seeds
away give them away flush them whatever
you want to do just let people know that
that wasn't a winner don't sell them as
winter seeds that'll mess up your
reputation but try again don't be afraid
to try again i have thrown away a lot of
seeds don't be shy to throw seeds away
feed them to the birds use them as
compost don't put out shitty seeds to
the community please but the main way to
find out what you've done the only way
really to find out what you've done is
to grow those seeds and it's really fun
in my opinion growing a male plant
finding a male then pollinating some
multiple female plants then growing
those and seeing the similarities and
the differences in all of those plants
if you've grown
anything of mine that's been crossed to
a rise if you've grown more than one or
two of those crosses you can see what
solomon is doing and what the females
are doing to that cross
after a lot of growing and breeding it
will become very obvious to you what the
male plant is doing and what the female
is doing you'll start to identify that
very quickly it's like learning your
children you can say oh you got that
from your father or you got that from
your mother you'll start to see that and
it becomes very natural very obvious
very quickly i think that is called
developing an eye for breeding and it
took me a long time to do that but now i
can just look at plants and i go man i
need to pollinate that girl with solomon
and it will make this and then 90 of the
time my predictions in my head come out
exactly how i expected them all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers my friend
darcy thank you guys for listening to
this episode my throat is burning out my
voice is going to be completely gone
here pretty soon so it is time for me to
wrap up this episode i hope you learned
a lot i hope i answered your question um
i choose my mail
based on the goal then i check for a
certain criteria how is it shaped how is
it smell how does it grow does it give
me enough pollen to make seeds how long
is that pollen window does it make
trichomes does it make colors how does
it smell
dj short smokes is male plants he dries
out the buds and smokes the flowers i
don't do that dj short does that maybe
that's something you will do see if that
male plant gives you a buzz then once
you have selected your male plant that
you find appropriate pollinate your
female plants then pollinate multiple
females is my advice then grow out as
many of those as you can compare notes
see what that male is delivering to the
cross if that male is doing what you
want it to do pollinate a bunch more
plants continue with filial generations
if it's not doing what you want get more
seeds find another dude start over take
a lot of notes don't ever be afraid to
scrap a breeding project or go backwards
sometimes that's how it works we don't
always make the right selections it is
always about selection all right that's
all i've got for you for this episode i
feel like my voice is about to be
completely gone i'll check in with you
in a few days i want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy billy bong smokin
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
hey