[Music]
all right let's do this here we go
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
this is episode
707 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
breeding before we get to that part of
the show let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to pack northwest dan let's send a thank
you shout out to levity loveday and
jessica k let's send a thank you shout
out to rutro and ivan m i want to send a
thank you shout out to single t and
canner reaper 413. let's send a big fist
bump and a sidekick to choke norris i
want to send a thank you shout out to
thomas m and rasufa let's send a thank
you shout out to captain mojo and the
larf knight rises i want to send a thank
you shout out to 716 groves then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
greene county grower 401 7. big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends all right i don't want to ramble
too much here at the start of the show
uh recently i was on my instagram live
feed that's right every monday i do an
instagram live at 7 10 p.m mountain time
i'm in colorado i'm dealing with the
mountain time zone so every monday 7 10
p.m mountain time i do an instagram live
i'm on my instagram account i re
underscore genetics that is me on
instagram irie underscore genetics i use
that one for the live feed there is a
podcast uh instagram it is the grow from
your heart podcast i don't post enough
there i try but i don't i re underscore
genetics on instagram i do an instagram
live show every monday on a recent live
show we started talking about labeling
and going deeper into labeling and
somebody asked me the question about f1s
and then they asked me the question
about what does v mean somebody noted
that the letter v was on a seed pack
recently we talked about the bx we
talked about f1 we talked about s now we
are going to talk about v and we're
going to lead that into further breeding
down the line we're going to talk about
parallel breeding in this episode so
let's start the conversation off talking
about v if you buy a package of seeds
and it's got the letter v marked on
there somewhere that can be very
confusing what does the letter v mean
i did not see the package that my friend
was talking about i'm not exactly sure
but i have a good idea of exactly the
breeder probably the line of seeds that
it came from so i can give a good
example of what i expect and i assume
this v means the v
means it is version so let's just say
hypothetically that i made a rise f twos
and the uh there were different
phenotypes that i liked i would run a
bunch of seeds and i would label them
probably number 1 through 25 or 1
through 100 or maybe they would be
letters a through z just kind of depends
on how i'm feeling when i label make the
labels that day in this case we're going
to say they were labeled numbers 1
through 25 and then i'm going to grow
those out i may find two that i really
like that have two totally distinct
traits features two different phenotypes
that really
they're both keepers in totally
different ways so i may work more with
those plants in the future and to
indicate that i chose uh maybe i got on
a rise plant that was super sticky and
super potent and then maybe i got
another arize plant that tastes really
good and grows really fast i would
indicate those by saying like version a
and version b and then on the website i
would go and indicate very clearly the
differences between version a and
version b
so i think the v just means version it's
either
version a or version b possibly version
2.0 is something i've also seen the way
that i have indicated that is i've just
simply given the plants different
numbers you may see a rise f2 number
four a rise f2 number eight there's a
rise f2 letter e that is the way i did
it those are different selections of the
arise phenotypes that i chose to
continue breeding with that is all that
indicates is a v4 version all right i am
back after a quick technical adjustment
i hope you didn't notice through the
magic of editing you will not notice a
thing let's stay on track here i talked
about versions i did say i was going to
talk about
poly hybrids f1s and breeding parallel
lines i'm going to try to unravel that
ball here we go oftentimes in the show i
talk about f1s and f1 is known as when
we take two plants and cross them
together for the first time if i take
plant a that doesn't even need a name
and plant b and i breed them together
the seeds that come from that that's
called the progeny that is an f1 that is
the first filial generation now my
friend f1 pete his head just completely
exploded because unless we've done some
uh work before that or some very careful
selection that is not really nf1 it
could be labeled in f1 technically what
we just made is a polyhybrid we're just
pollen chucking we're just grabbing
plant a plant b putting them in a room
because
that one was called something cookies
and that was called something cake and i
think that something cookies and
something cake would be a cool [ __ ]
strain name that will sell me a lot of
seeds so i put them in a room and i let
them [ __ ] and now i got a bunch of seeds
and those are just poly hybrid hype
seeds
if you're into poly hybrids there's
nothing wrong with that if you've done
if that's what you want that's your
thing but that is not an f1 let's talk
about what would make an f1 and what the
difference is between a poly hybrid and
an f1 the main word is um breeding two
the main thing is breeding two
heterozygous plants together to create
an f1 if you're taking something that's
really uh og kush dominant and a lot of
kush on this side and a lot of kush on
this side you're just kind of pollen
chucking and putting kush and other
ingredients together let's do some work
do some building blocks let's talk about
how to do this and this will also take
us back to the versions so the main when
i'm breeding one of the things i really
look for is breeding plants that are
different why would i want to take
two strawberries and make strawberries
together and get double strawberries
that doesn't make any sense to me i want
to take strawberries and blueberries or
strawberries and chocolate or
strawberries and not even bananas
because that's too cliche how about
strawberries and garlic let's just [ __ ]
it all up let's do things weird and
breed that and try to complement both
plants and see what they both do also
that helps us get to that f1 stage so
in my example again i'm going to go back
to making a rise we're going to work
with a golden goat female and we're
going to focus on a daybreaker male
that's where we're going to go i'm going
to flower them out and i'm going to get
pollen from the daybreaker i'm going to
put the pollen on the golden goat female
i have now made a rise f1 that is a real
thing that i've done i've called that a
rise f1
that could be debatably an f1 depl
debatably you could deflate it if you
want to also that may not be a true f1
it may be um those plants were so far
apart i think in appearance in genetics
and everything that i think i made in f1
maybe people would argue that and i
would accept your argument um they could
be a poly hybrid if you want to call it
that let's talk about what i could do to
further turn this plant into a true f1
if we want to really fit that label that
our friend fp f1p would like to see this
plant fall into shout out to my friend
f1p you're a very inspiring a very
knowledgeable dude and you did inspire a
lot of this and i learned a lot from you
brother so thank you let's keep going so
i've got my first arize f1 or my poly
hybrid stash of seeds from there i'm
going to find a male let's go back to
talking about the versions this is where
the versions are going to come in let me
keep myself on track from there i'm
going to grow them out and i'm going to
find traits that i really enjoy this is
just what you do when you get seeds a
batch of new seeds you grow them you
look for the traits what are these new
uh what is is what does the progeny
express you grow as many as you can and
through that population you take a lot
of notes and you say this is a common
trait this is a common trait this is
really common 25 percent of the plants
show me this 25 show me this 50 percent
of the plants show me this ten percent
of the plants did this weird [ __ ] over
here ten percent of the plants did this
amazing thing over here take a lot of
notes and see what you have created put
that plant in different environments
stress it out run it as many times as
you can see what you can do with this
plant how it reacts to different things
then
then if you really want to go further
find uh there are going to be two
different traits that you like two
different plants that you're looking for
i'm going to pick two very specific
traits once again we're going to say on
this side we have found a plant that is
super potent every time we smoke it i
said this before your brain flies out of
your head you got fireworks going off
every time we're gonna stick with a
super potent plant on this side on the
other side i'm gonna stick with
something we all enjoy terps flavor
whatever your favorite flavor is that is
on this side so i've got one line of
plants that are nothing but potency and
one breeding project that is nothing but
flavor an easy way to achieve this one
way we can do this is to use the same
male or two different males if you found
two males that you really like you want
to run two totally different breeding
projects that is acceptable that's a
great way to do this you can run one
male or two males this will work however
you want as long as you have found the
plants that meet the criteria and reach
the goals you were looking for uh you
can do two different males or the same
male that won't make a difference uh in
my opinion so what we're gonna do we're
gonna find that female super potent find
another female super flavor then we're
going to pollinate them with our male of
choice it's either it's got to be the
same filial generation is the most
important part here it could be the same
male uh could be two two different males
as long as they came from the same batch
of seeds so now we are going to find
that perfect male uh that perfect
perfect male if it's one or two find our
perfect females we've got our female a
and female b now we're going to
pollinate at this point we have made two
separate batches of f2 seeds we have
made f2 batch a and f2 batch b you can
do this at separate times if you've got
uh if you're doing different males you
might want to do it in separate rooms at
different times so you don't cross
pollinate if you're using one male you
can do this in one room you can
pollinate plant a and plant b as long as
you don't mix up the seeds when you're
done that will work out beautifully so
what you would do what i would do
you've made the f1 or the poly hybrid
generation find a solid male in this
case i found king solomon then i would
find a female nothing but potency a
female over here nothing but terps i
keep saying nothing but uh that's wrong
i shouldn't be saying it that way we
want structure vigor uh pathogen
pathogen resistance bug resistance uh
all of the other things you desire in a
plant that you're going to breed to it
needs that but also let's focus
90 of your focus is going to be on the
trichomes on the potency over here i
don't know about 90 i'm exaggerating
that that's hyperbole most of our focus
we're breeding mostly for potency over
here the other side breeding mostly for
flavor so you're going to get your
you're going to select that you're going
to have your male then i would take that
male and pollinate both of those
now i have now made the f2 or i guess
it's the f2 but not really the true f2
working toward our real f1 is where
we're headed we'll get to that so i'm
going to make new seeds i'm going to
take this batch over here that i'm
breeding just for flavor and i'm going
to find another boy and another girl out
of there in this selection process i am
focused once again on structure vigor
resistance to problems but i am focusing
mainly on flavor once again then guess
what once i found that perfect male and
perfect female out of my f2 batch of
this batch of seeds out of batch a i
don't remember which side was batch and
which side was which b batch b but we're
just gonna act like this is flavor batch
over here we've got our f twos we're
gonna make f3 we're going to find a
beautiful flavored plant again we're
going to make f4 we're going to go all
the way to f5 or f6 i want to go until
these plants come out every time i grow
them they are stable stabil stability
means that all of the plants are uniform
uniformity among phenotypes we're not
going to find a bunch of different
phenotypes in the in the population not
going to be any differences they're
going to look like we put a bunch of
clones out there that's how far i'm
going to breed it if i do my selection
properly f5 should get me there f6 will
really lock it in so what are we going
to do with these other plants that we're
focused on the potency side same thing
i've got my f1 seeds i'm going to find a
boy and a girl across those make f2s
find a boy and a girl that are highly
potent cross those i keep going up like
this like like there's a chart in front
of me but there is in my head so i'm
going to do that to both lines this is
what i'm calling parallel lines it's the
same genetics it's the same cross it's
the same genotype but i'm choosing
different phenotypes with different
goals in mind for my breeding once again
i'm just breeding for potency just
reading for flavor in two separate
projects i've got to use
the same batch of seeds over here to
make this work and the same
the the batch of seeds over here that is
allotted for this project over here the
potency seeds have to stay in the
potency rain the flavor seeds have to
stay in the flavor rain and run right up
that side of the chart so we're going to
f f2 f3 f4 f5 f6 both of them right up
each side then once we get to that f5 f6
level and we feel like we've got exactly
what we're looking for from our
phenotypes we're going to find a
beautifully perfectly structured
pathogen resistant bug resistant not
problematic plant that is ideal for our
grow room that is got the most amazing
[ __ ] flavor you could ever find
whatever flavor you think of when you
close your eyes and you inhale that
imaginary joint or imaginary dab or
imaginary bong rip and you go
whatever flavor that is that hits your
tongue this plant tastes just like that
times five it's almost overwhelming
almost overpowering because we've bred
it just focusing on that delicious
terpene content then we're going to find
one over here on the other side on the
potency side then when you open the bag
you don't even have to light it you
don't even have to put fire on it you
just go oh [ __ ] i'm too high to drive
somebody else has to drive the car
that's how high i want you to get from
that weed we're going to find a
phenotype that is perfect you got to
trust now which one which one do we
choose for the male i would say choose
the potency side for the male that would
be my idea but now what we're going to
do we're going to cross these together
we're going to take our f sixes from
each side or f5 from each side and pick
your potency male and your flavorful
female and cross them let's breed those
together now my friends we have made a
true
f1 cross we've taken uh these uh parents
that were golden goat and daybreaker and
we made the poly hybrid version uh part
one and then we selected version a and
version b and we bred them to f2 f3 f456
then we found our crown jewels out of
those we bred those together and we made
[ __ ] super arise the true f1 um that
would be a baddie uh that's like a
lifeline lifelong project for a lot of
people don't think that that's something
you should get done in just a few years
if you rush it you [ __ ] that project up
and if you ever have to go backwards
if one of your selections wasn't what
you thought it should be if you liked
the filial generation before never be
afraid to go back and crack more seeds
from that generation before find the
phenotype out of there you know when you
mess up you you'll see it it may be two
generations back but you'll know which
generation once you're breeding uh
filial generations and you see a problem
pop up you go oh yeah that was in two
generations back and i was too stubborn
to get rid of that i should have tossed
that plant i picked that plant because
it did that other thing that i liked and
i accepted the crazy thing uh just
because it had that other cool trait so
get rid of that um don't be afraid to go
backwards
always keep seed stock from every filial
generation
if you're making f2s f3s f4s you should
have f1 two three and four seed stock
just on reserve like i said just in case
you did not make the appropriate the
correct selection every time maybe later
on you want to take that uh f6 or f5 and
back cross it to an f2 or something
you'll once you start doing this you'll
see why breeding becomes so
i guess addicting as the word and then
you'll see how it also becomes very uh
predictive we can kind of once you do it
a lot you can almost anticipate what's
going to come out if you learn the
plants if you understand what's
happening um
you have to breed with the plants a
couple of times to see how much of that
male goes into the mix and how much of
that female goes into the mix and then
you'll see that different males and
females interact differently but the
only way to do that really is to breed
some plants so um man i guess that is my
quick wrap up i hope i covered that
correctly and appropriately um
i am going to get roasted on something i
said there and honestly i look forward
to it because that is how i learn my
audience holds me to a high standard and
i do appreciate that so don't be shy let
me know what i messed up the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com send me your corrections
corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism criticism that
also uh but send me your constructive
criticism please be polite about it uh
that i don't have any notes in front of
me i'll show you i'll tell you what my
notes have they have the letters p and
then a graph that goes like this and it
says poly slash f1 and then a b and then
f1 all the way down to f6 is what i
wrote and then a circle f1 i'm not going
to show you my chicken scratches of
notes because that's my brain and it's
embarrassing but that's how many notes
i've got so i hope i got that correct
you guys
i've got faith in myself i think that
came out right but again um i am not
afraid to be corrected and educated
that's what we're all here for um ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers um all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
truly thank you for listening to another
grow from your heart podcast i feel like
i was going super fast in this episode
i'll take a couple of more dabs before i
record the next one i smoked some lemon
wreath from green dot they don't pay me
to advertise but that's what got me
talking seven thousand miles an hour big
shout out to our friends at green dot
labs nothing but love also nothing but
love for our friends at superior seeds
check them out they did get a restock
recently superior seeds i think it's
superiors.com i just wrote down superior
seeds check them out they are on my
website iregenetics.com there's a link a
list of vendors you'll find superior
seeds there big up to our friends at
superior seed company support them help
them out
all right also patreon.com forward slash
girl from your heart i think that is all
my stoned rambling ass brought for you
for this episode thanks again for
hanging out for a short episode i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a big shout out
to my buddy kurt zee and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you