[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode
709 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
the evolution of dabbing before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to a longtime supporter and a
good friend my buddy thecanocrat let's
send a thank you shout out to lefty and
godfather kush let's send a big thank
you shout out to kes burton and magic
mike i want to send a special thank you
shout out to my buddy jesse gross let's
send a big fist bump to a long time
supporter my buddy gramps memo i want to
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy ryven waters let's send a thank
you shout out to greene county grower at
g7 then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to rasta green thumb big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen and
you know i do include that link in the
show notes and the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends all right we made it through the
intro part uh the next episode you guys
will be the 710 episode we're going to
talk about uh live rosin about making
rosin about pressing rosin at home about
growing specifically for rosin i do have
our friends uh pedro from pedro's grow
room uh mr rosin's neighborhood rosin is
legal [ __ ] uh also we've got another
amazing concentrate maker our buddy
rosin ryan will be on the next episode i
thought since the next episode is the
710 show this should be kind of the
warm-up for the 7-10 episode i focused
mainly on making concentrates on the
next show this one will be about how we
got to this point in the concentrate
world i'm in colorado here i guess i'm
going to evolve right into it i'm in
colorado here and i feel like i was kind
of uh
on the forefront excuse me i was on the
forefront uh in the scene if you will of
the evolution of concentrates i was
there um when some of the very first
concentrates were put out first first
things were made i got to try some of
the very first new products uh that
people had never seen before um some of
my friends were making live resin they
were the the innovators of the official
uh inception of live resin and from
there they were pulling the live resin
out of the uh the obi dose machine uh
and smoking it before it was even purged
or completely processed and they had a
special name for that i was smoking that
stuff but i started by smoking uh some
funky brown goop so i feel like i've
been around since the and a part of the
evolution of concentrates here in
colorado this new dab evolution of
course there is that old uh the old
bubble hash the old stuff that the older
uh the pressed hash the funky hash the
older guys like the old clientele that
come to the dispensary always ask for
old bubble hash
there's always been bubble hash around
but since the evolution since
legalization and medical cannabis
concentrates and dabs have really
evolved now let me uh step in and
correct myself i
need to talk about proper terminology
here before we get too far i keep saying
dabs um a dab is actually a verb dabbing
is a verb a dab is kind of a unit of
measurement the the phrase dab came from
uh i would get my dabber the little tool
on which i would scoop up my concentrate
onto my dabber so i could put it onto my
nail to consume it the amount of
concentrate that it would take to get me
properly medicated was a dab so when the
phrase dab came into this whole game it
was basically a unit of measurement now
the term the word has been used very
broadly it's like it's like a coke any
kind of a soda a carbonated beverage in
a can is now called a coke
that's kind of how dab has been
bastardized into the community into the
industry it's okay but i just want to
clear up some things here so that we're
all on the same page we all know what
i'm talking about what is a dab a dab is
basically a unit of measurement or an
amount of concentrate to be smoked i
want to take a dab hey do you have any
dabs i haven't taken any dabs today
that's how we would say that i could use
a dab
i like to take dabs that is kind of the
way it should be said
people say can i buy any dab from you uh
that's not really the way that would go
uh do you have any dab that's not the
way that would work a dab is kind of a
unit of measurement multiple doses would
be some dabs i think you get what i'm
saying uh what we should really be
saying is dabs are concentrates or
basically hash a lot of the older
audience will be more familiar with the
word hash that is hash is a cannabis
concentrate we have taken the valuable
the useful the medicinal part of that
plant we have stripped it from the green
leafy vegetable the green part the
flower part ah that is a carrier that is
what grew the trichomes the trichomes is
where the uh the potency is hidden the
trichomes are where the potency is
hidden maybe i should have said it that
way the trichomes are what we want we
have discovered methods and ways to
remove those trichomes from the plant
and now we are concentrating those
trichomes that potency that uh the
terpenes uh the other things are esters
palettes a lot of other things happening
but mainly we're going for the the
potency the trichomes uh the
cannabinoids and the terpenes are what
we're mainly after in there we're
concentrating that into a smaller form
and removing the leafy material that we
do not need to consume we're not horses
we're not rabbits we don't need the
green leafy matter like that we want to
smoke trichomes resin glands uh
cannabinoids terpenes that is what we're
after so we've discovered how to remove
that there are many ways to do it a lot
of people do it through uh you can do it
through uh just uh what is it agitation
you can not when the crystals those
crystals the trichomes when the crystals
fall off the weed and your grinder you
are making dry sift hash basically not
really but kind of that is trichomes
those are trichomes that is a
concentrate that is concentrated
trichomes if you press that into a puck
or roll it into a ball or simply scoop
it on top of your bowl that'll get you
extra buzz because that is a little
concentrated trichome a little
concentrated thc on those trichomes it's
going to get you extra buzzed there are
also fancier ways of making dry sift
hash i've seen people use bags you put a
bunch of trim or a bunch of weed and a
sieve bag with a certain size micron
screen beat the [ __ ] out of it for hours
all the trichomes fall off the the green
leafy matter is left in the bag also
another very popular method to do this
is by using water we've all been uh
educated we will be educated in the next
episode on using ice and water to remove
trichomes from the green leafy matter in
that case water is not being used as a
solvent is being used as an agitator as
a mechanical separator uh not as a
solvent so that's a different when they
say solventless yes that is still
solventless concentrate a lot of people
have discovered how to do it simply by
squishing a bud you can squish a bud and
you can make concentrates out of that a
lot of people will make bubble hash out
of the bubble bags take that and then
squish that and that makes really nice
rosin we'll talk about that in the next
episode then another very popular way
another thing that has evolved rapidly
oh let me touch on co2 oil also we can
make concentrates with
hexane propane co2 all kinds of other uh
gases i don't know the technical term
for what i'm trying to say here but it's
possible to make concentrates with many
other gases the one i am most familiar
with what i think is most commonly used
is butane i will not teach you how to
make butane concentrates we will not
talk too much about that because it is
dangerous and probably illegal where you
are i do not need to lead you down that
rabbit hole there are plenty of avenues
for you to learn how to do that if that
is your preferred method of making
concentrate so let's talk about i'm way
off of my notes i don't know where i am
but we're going to talk about oh i was
talking about the actual terms here
wasn't i
[ __ ] uh the most popular is butane
concentrates uh now in my in my opinion
uh the most popular here in colorado is
probably the butane extracted
concentrates if you get shatter uh if
you get batter if you get diamonds if
you get sauce most of the time those
were extracted with butane the other
most popular is the uh the fresh frozen
the live rosin people really love that
the price differences in butane hash and
rosin are astronomical we'll talk about
that in the next episode uh i was trying
to cover the uh the terminology here so
a dab is a dose a a hit of a concentrate
of some hash
um when we take those trichomes and we
pull it off of the plant and we use
either water agitation butane heat
however we achieve that process we have
now made hash or a concentrate is
basically what we've made we've
concentrated that potency into one
smaller uh amount and now you need less
of that to achieve the recreational or
medical dose which you now desire so
that is basically
a dab and what a dab is and what a
concentrate is now the act of taking a
dab is known as dabbing if you called
and i had a dab on the dabber and i was
putting that on the nail uh into the rig
i know that's a lot of terms we'll talk
about that if you called me right now
and he said what are you doing i'd say i
am dabbing or if i had some people over
and were just sitting on the couch
watching videos and taking dabs in a
group and just called me or texted me
and said what are you guys doing we are
dabbing so i think we've got the
terminology down pedro will touch on
that also in the next episode but i
wanted to make sure to cover that so we
know where we are we're all on this
podcast together we're going to talk
about concentrates dabbing dabs and the
evolution of such so here we go let's
talk more about that
i think i should start off kind of by
talking about how i got into
real concentrates real uh bho
concentrates my first dab maybe i'm
going to talk about my first pre-dab and
my first real dab and then i'll talk
about my first uh group dab i got to
change my notes because i just got an
idea not even gonna edit that i will
edit the change give me one second all
right my notes have been annotated i
will not forget one of the stories i
wanted to tell one detail i wanted to
put in this show one more avenue of
rambles i needed to add to the notes
here we go let's talk about uh one of
the first times i got real dabs of
course i was smoking concentrates with
friends uh before then we all would get
random [ __ ] that we thought was hash or
bubble hash or whatever people would
sell us or give us when we were younger
until this time period i had never been
stoned or high or ah dtfo that stands
for dabbed the [ __ ] out i have never
been dtfo like i was on this occasion so
let's talk about my first experience
acquiring some bho some butane honey oil
some butane extracted concentrate and my
experience
right around the time that medical
marijuana was becoming super popular in
my area this had to be uh 2007 2008
maybe 2006 i've got a brain injury
timelines are weird i'm getting old
shit's all blurry now anyway around that
time frame
i was doing um
business well this happened a long time
ago i was doing business with a friend
he had uh the most amazing sour diesel
that money could buy that [ __ ] was so
good you'd get in the car with it and
everyone would be like boom
and you light it up and your eyes would
itch and [ __ ] this dude
i was getting some sour diesel from him
this is like a weekly visit i'd go get
an ounce of sour d from this guy and try
to make it last a week it would never
[ __ ] work so one day i get some sour
d from my buddy and he passes me just a
little folded piece of parchment paper
it looks like a half a dollar sized
piece of parchment paper folded in half
inside of that parchment paper
was some goopy golden stuff and he gave
it to me he goes hit that when you get
home and let me know what you think so i
got home and i had time to look at what
i got i unfolded it and i realized this
is that bho stuff i've been hearing
about this is that butane honey oil that
i've been hearing about like in
magazines and hearing other people in
denver and [ __ ] talk about i heard
somebody talk about this recently and
they said they got so high they couldn't
handle themselves i was like i'm really
curious about this and it was just a
little teeny tiny bit it wasn't very
much now it would have been
maybe maybe a fat dab back then it was
several dabs but now that would have
been maybe one fat dab for me i take
pretty monstrous dabs that wouldn't have
been much now but back in the day
that was a lot so i took i got a little
scraper tool like a pipe cleaner tool
just something to scrape it up with and
i gathered some of it off the parchment
and i didn't have a proper way to smoke
it i didn't really have there were no i
didn't have a dab tool i didn't even
know i was going to be dabbing so there
was no dab equipment so i got a little
tiny pipe that was brand new it was a
gift from a dispensary i spent some
money at a dispensary they were nice
they threw me a glass pipe as a gift i
put a little tiny chunk of weed in the
bottom of the bowl just to cover the
hole like a screen
if you ever get any pipe that new hole
is too fresh in there i just took a
chunk of weed uh maybe one calyx maybe
it was one bract uh i stuffed that in
the hole to work as a screen then i took
half of that little glob of it wasn't
even glob it was half of a a big dab of
the bho concentrate and just smeared it
on top of there and then i sat at my
desk and i was supposed to go somewhere
i had that new sour diesel in my pocket
i was gonna go smoke with friends and go
do some [ __ ]
but instead
i took a lighter and i hit that bho just
a little bit just
i just took one good hit to where i got
like a nice lungful and as soon as it
hit my lungs my brain went oh
oh
oh oh we're gonna get high high i
thought we're getting high but we're
gonna get high high so my lungs went
on i blew it out and a cloud came out
and i changed colors
and i went from my desk chair
zombie mode to my bed face down just
and my body turned off i remember having
the most vivid dreams i was super high i
woke up my eyes were still bloody red
and i was hungry as [ __ ] i had to text
my buddy and i was like bro
was that bho or did you give me drugs
and he's like bro that's bho and i made
that
i was like
how much more do you have
i i was so high i had to share that with
some friends i had to share that
experience so for a little while there
we were smoking bho on bowls we were
doing it all wrong it was working i got
i got high as [ __ ] but we were not doing
it right we needed to find the proper
equipment so that leads me to my second
dab i'll tell you that after i adjust
this camera all right the camera has
been corrected hopefully through the
magic of editing you don't even notice
you only notice because i just told you
let's talk about my second dab i was at
the cannabis cup again i cannot recall
which year this was this was the first
year of the cannabis cup in denver in
colorado at the uh the little tiny place
what was it called ex-dough little tiny
tiny place it was tiny it was so crowded
in there not the first time it was
pretty open the first time several years
later it got super crowded uh this time
it was perfectly packed we had to park
down the block a little bit it was
pretty hyped up because it was a
cannabis cup a high times event they're
always huge
um
we walked around that event we smoked
weed with everybody people are offering
dabs so
i we saw it i had a person with me and i
was like you want to go and hit a dab
and um she was like sure let's try that
so we got in line for the booth at
broadway wellness big shout out to my
buddy big d daniel desai uh the secret
cup uh top shelf extracts broadway
wellness uh big d was pivotal and the
people are good that's a controversial
statement d i love you guys nothing but
love and respect for you d was pivotal
pivotal that's a good word say it a
couple times it becomes the new roads uh
d was a huge part in the evolution the
pioneering of concentrates in colorado
especially the denver area
he revolutionized pioneered concentrate
making selling dispensary operating the
way [ __ ] was done he had a lot of uh
influence on the industry in my opinion
if you don't agree with that that's fine
send me an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com dieselconf con controversial
dude and i got nothing but love for the
big guy keep taking care of yourself
brother but uh we're at this cannabis
cup event and we're walking around and
we decide that it's time to take a dab
so we get in line for a dab at the
broadway wellness booth
at that booth a guy known as big d was
working there i've seen him several
times uh in magazines on social media
social media was banging for the weed
scene at this time this was before they
took down all of the weed content we
used to do dab wars on social media uh
we would tab it uh hashtag it uh dab
wars uh attack of the dabs and [ __ ] like
that a few of us were taking gigantic
dabs and being being silly on there i
digress and i kind of lost where i was
where the [ __ ] was i big d at broadway
wellness i knew we'd get back on track
we get in line right i know who big d is
and he's like do you want a big dab or a
little dab and i was like uh no i didn't
even hit it first uh the girl that was
with me she got in front and he's like
big dab or a little dab and she's like
little dab so she takes a little tiny
dab deheats up what is known as a
swingarm skillet at this time he's got a
little piece of titanium that swings up
and you heat that and then it swings
down and it attaches to a piece of glass
that looks like it goes into the bong
and comes out like a bong stem would but
then it comes down it curves downward
and has a bell that would flare out uh
it's shaped like an umbrella or a bell
and a swing arm swings underneath the
opening of the belt to absorb the smoke
so that you could inhale through the
smoke uh the smoke through the bong
which this piece is attached to that
makes sense he had a little like a 10
inch tiny bong with not a big thick uh
stem on it so you didn't get too much
smoke in there at once it just went
straight to your head so he heats it up
ah way too hot back in the day we didn't
know yet heated it up way too hot uh put
the dab on there the girl that was with
me hit it and she went wobbly numb for a
couple of seconds i had to reach
underneath her arms and support her kind
of reach underneath her and hold her up
for a minute because she went wobbly uh
she went kind of frog leg kind of
fishing a little bit she blew out this
cloud she looked back at me she goes i
need to go sit down and i was like well
let me let me get she's like yeah yeah
you get one of those but i'm going over
there so she kind of bust out of the
crowd she had to go sit down get her
[ __ ] together take a drink catch her
breath and i'm like wow this looks like
a good [ __ ] time so i line up it's my
turn i got the rig right in front of me
big d drops a fat dab on there cause i'm
a white guy with dreads i look like i
know what i'm doing and i got
skyrocket high from that dab when i blew
out that smoke
my brain it felt like fireworks went out
one side a rocket ship flew out the
other but then it also felt like i [ __ ]
my pants at the same time a lot of
things were happening i was in it was
heaven and hell at the same time because
i was so high that i was like am i am i
having a stroke am i coming am i dying
is this living like i wasn't sure what
the [ __ ] was really happening from that
dab
but i know that i loved it because
before we left that event i went back
and bought one of the exact rigs that i
hit and i bought one of the exact
torches he used to heat that [ __ ] up
and i bought a bunch of concentrates
from everywhere i could find at that
event so from then we started dabbing
heavy now that will lead me into another
great story part of my evolution of
dabbing this is how it all began you
guys this is one of my favorite stories
to tell uh this may be a short podcast
actually because this camera is telling
me that the battery's low and it was at
100 when i started 22 minutes ago you
guys don't care about the tech issues
third dab story
on the 709 episode here we go ross jeff
telling stories to today gather around
you guys it's story time with roster
jeff all right who is in this story this
story starts off with pops uh big shout
out to our friend pop's rest in peace
brother miss you love you
uh also kevin was there big up to kevin
i haven't seen kevin in a minute hope
you were well brother mike may have been
there i'm pretty sure mike was there i'm
not sure wade may have been there uh
there were probably six or seven people
in my basement i called a bunch of
people over i was like hey guys i got a
new rig i got a torch i've got some dabs
i want to show off and i want to get
everybody skyrocket high like i did at
this event so the whole crew came over i
think my girlfriend at the time might
have been there also and i got a bunch
of concentrates on the table i lined up
dabs for everybody we all took a dab we
all leaned back in our chair for about
10 minutes
everybody kind of one at a time decided
i gotta go home our friend tony was
there also big up to tony i haven't seen
you in a while brother everybody decided
man i gotta go and they all just got up
they just left quietly people like i
gotta go take a nap i gotta go get food
people just disappeared off the couches
i honestly laid the [ __ ] down it took
about a six hour nap uh when i woke up
everybody started texting about the same
time like bro did you fall asleep bro
did you eat all of the food like i woke
up so we wrecked everybody that day and
that was the first time we got the whole
group over here super super baked the
whole irie crew the original irie
genetics irie army crew got lit so big
up to that day i'll never forget that
day pops i'll miss you forever you're
always gonna be in that story um
but that was when i killed the entire
crew
all right so that gets us into my first
second third dab story three good
stories is enough for this one let's
talk a little bit more about the actual
evolution of dabbing uh when we started
this uh the bho concentrates we were
open blasting in enclosed places with
pvc tubes if you're a concentrate maker
or a concentrated consumer
all of those things are completely
absurd you should not be open blasting
which is if you don't know what that is
that's fine if you do you're going oh
man i remember those days uh that's just
blasting cans of butane haphazardly
through a pvc tube stuffed with
concentrates to make or stuffed with
weed to make concentrates out of it
don't do that
don't do that that is terrible the pvc
leeches you get gasses and [ __ ] from the
pvc in your concentrate you shouldn't be
open blasting and i said in enclosed
spaces
that's how [ __ ] blows up i know several
people that are scarred from head to toe
uh don't have any hair on their body
don't have any eyebrows and eyelashes
because they were making butane
concentrates incorrectly so we've gone a
long way we went from doing that in the
backyard with shitty equipment into
having professional amazing labs
but let's not overlook a bunch of the
steps that it took to get there we went
from like i said open blasting inside we
finally went outdoors we learned how to
get better equipment safer more sterile
equipment people started learning about
science and reading science and
chemistry papers
we started getting vac ovens when we
started getting vacuum ovens and
learning how to properly purge the bho
concentrates the game changed forever
people can make better concentrates more
quickly batches could be larger
production stepped up quality stepped up
quite a bit
then it became an art the term extract
artist became super popular everybody in
colorado everybody in california you
were either a grower a breeder or an
extract artist some people were all of
the [ __ ] above um
making extracts and concentrates was
huge for a little while there when those
vacuum ovens became popular
uh then uh does anybody remember mystery
oils i've got mystery oils written down
i have to go fast here because that
camera is losing battery rapidly uh we
need to get another camera and figure
out some [ __ ] here um
remember mystery oil you guys if you're
around for mystery oil we started making
butane and we started purging properly
we started discovering a weird layer of
oils on top of our concentrates we
didn't know if it was coming from the
plants itself pesticides or something
applied to the plant or the big question
was is it coming from the butane cans
which we are buying and then later we
discovered guess what it was coming from
the cans of butane which we were buying
nobody knew what it was it was never
identified uh people were curious about
it a lot of us probably smoked a lot of
that [ __ ] didn't know it didn't realize
it still have no idea what it was maybe
that's why i twitch when i wake up in
the mornings you never know
um so we got much better we learned to
purge we got vac ovens
we discovered mystery oils mystery oil
was a good time our concentrates went
from black poop soup i used to call
things poop soup and tane soup uh butane
soup you'd get dabs you'd get
concentrate you'd take a dab of it and
you'd put it on somebody's nail or your
nail and it would sparkle and it would
make a stain now concentrates they burn
smooth and does they vaporize and they
disappear cleanly here's a quick trick
random side notes from ross to jeff if
anybody ever offers you a dab a puff of
a concentrate or even some flowers that
you don't want to smoke my way of
diverting that conversation and politely
avoiding that is i go oh man that looks
pretty good you want to try some of what
i got and then i bust out mine and it
always diverts the conversation you
don't have to smoke their dabs or their
flowers if it looks questionable i
understand sometimes i don't want to
smoke
certain concentrates that i see that
certain people bring around no offense
to anybody but some of your concentrate
looks like complete [ __ ] and i'm not
gonna smoke it i'm not gonna put my
lungs my health my body at risk um also
ew i just don't wanna smoke it so ah you
can avoid smoking other people's nasty
poop soup their tang crap uh their their
butane batter just by saying ah check
this out bro and show it to them and you
both take a dab of that and then you
still have a friend and then if they're
really insisting you'd be like oh man
i'm high after the dab i took and you
could just keep making excuses all day
but you could politely tactfully dodge
it got a couple of excuses for you let
me get my high rambly ass back on track
now we went from poop soup to the stuff
that we have now you guys we had um
stuff would come out liquidy and goopy
on the wrong color and then it started
to shatter we had concentrates called
shatter they used to say if it don't
shatter it don't matter and then we
realized a lot of the shatter was lipids
and things that we don't really want to
smoke and then we started learning that
you could whip it and turn it into a
batter i really like a nice batter
especially a live batter that's when you
fresh freeze it then extract it then
make a batter out of it but i like a
batter i feel like it's very terpe uh
has a lot of terpenes a lot of flavor
and i really think that the feeling in
the lungs is great uh so we had uh goop
and then we had shatter then we had
batter uh then we had wax people learned
how to make it into a waxy texture
sometimes i really liked the wax you'd
get a big old glob of wax and heat up
the dab nail and just press the wax
right into the dab nail and smoke as
much as you want all in one big rip that
was pretty fun to do
um we had crumble stuff that would just
fall apart and crumble there are so many
different textures of concentrates and
so many different names i got regionally
a guy known as a lot of different [ __ ]
also you could go from pueblo to denver
up to boulder and the same [ __ ] would be
called something different you'd find
earwax in different places it'd be
called crumble in a different place uh
you can tell why it's called earwax pull
out a chunk of goopy earwax and look at
it there was a concentrate that looked
like that whatever color that [ __ ] is
that came out of your ear there was a
concentrate that looked like that
somewhere
so now
we've gotten better and cleaner
concentrates now we've got diamonds and
sauce and live rosins and live batter
now we can basically i'm not a
scientologist i'm not a concentrate
maker i'm not an extraction nearest in
any way but now i understand that we can
basically extract and divide uh any of
the components of the plant which we so
desire we can pull out the terpenes in
one container uh we can pull off the
cannabinoids in another container we can
pull out the pesticides in another
container and isolate all of those
components of the cannabis plant is
where this evolution has gotten now we
are making uh big diamonds out of
straight thc a it's 99.9 percent thc and
that one percent is just atmospheric
allowances there's got to be oxygen and
some moisture and [ __ ] in there
now we can also make the same thing with
cbd crystals and isolates it's amazing
to me
you can buy 99
cannabis derived terpenes and you can
mix your own crystals and your own
terpenes together and make your own
ratios to the amount that you like i
don't i used to really love the diamonds
but i feel like they're uh i don't i
like the buzz but i feel like when i
smoke those diamonds without enough
terps the thc just makes me go real high
for a minute and there's no fun to the
buzz it's like i'm really high but nah
no i'm not it's just weird i feel like
the terps really give a color to the
buzz if my buzz was a firework the thc
makes me fly up in the air and then the
terpenes are the color of my buzz and
those crystals don't have any color to
them in the buzz bro they get you real
high make your chest feel weird get your
heart racing make your blood sugar do
weird [ __ ] but i'm not a big fan of the
high without some sort of backup into
there
um
i feel like i feel like this is my
prediction i don't know if i've ever
said this on a podcast i know i've said
this in previous uh instagram live
videos and other weird rambles where i
have appeared but here is a prediction
that i do see coming uh in the future if
it doesn't already exist and there uh
babylon's just keeping it from us it's a
big conspiracy but really this is what i
do see coming
in the future ideally i think that each
uh patient consumer uh either
recreational or medically will be able
to walk into uh maybe a dispensary it
might just be your normal store who
knows you may be able to do this at
starbucks but i would like to be able to
walk into a place um and i can hand them
my card and my card has my preferred mix
now hear me out this sounds crazy but
when we get there together you're going
to go i want this card
imagine when you go when we were a kid
and we would go to um
round table pizza is where i went bro i
just had a crazy flashback did you see
it happen in my face
round table pizza was the pizza place
near me and they had all of the soda
machines in a row you could get coke
diet coke cherry coke um [ __ ] vanilla
coke pepsi tea
uh sun kiss um what's the [ __ ] other
one maybe some fanta some dr pepper uh
maybe even some lemonade um who knows
what the [ __ ] else they had on that row
of [ __ ] sugary diabetes drinks but um
you could go make your we call it a
suicide right you could put um if you
put sprite in the suicide you're [ __ ]
it all up why would you do that you want
to put all the darkest colors the cherry
the dr pepper i'd make the most
disgusting concoctions of sugar and
syrup you could out of that thing
what if you could walk into a dispensary
a terp box a dab box whatever you want
to call this place and you could hand
them your card and that card said my
preferred slurry is this and you drop
that card maybe you just swipe it in
there's no people you put it into a
machine and the machine says oh rosted
jeff is here he wants a concentrate that
is this let's say
50 thc a because i like to get real high
then let's put uh and i'm just making up
numbers i don't know the numbers here
this is i'm creating this as we go this
is my dream come live it with me my card
says that i want 50 thc a in my slurry
zero cbd because i don't [ __ ] with cbd
that ruins my buzz i want some limonene
i want some linalool uh i want a little
bit of pinene in there and let's put
some mercing in there just to kick it
off and then i don't know what other
cannabinoids paleocene esters we can add
to that yet but in the future science
will know what things we can add to that
maybe we're just going to put some
caropholine in there uh maybe we'll just
add weird components of other [ __ ] in
there that are organic compounds it will
help that buzz affect me the way that i
need to for my medical or recreational
desire
maybe i've got uh two or three recipes
on a card that i can just swipe this
card maybe i can set my settings on my
phone and say i want to get high as [ __ ]
torah when i smoke this concentrate
fireworks go off in my brain and i can
levitate and then maybe i've got another
one that i can go to my phone and say i
need to take a [ __ ] nap knock me out
put me down i can make two different
concentrates swipe my card it spits both
of them out puts a label on them this
one is 50 thc a bunch of limonene some
linalool you're going to get high as
[ __ ] this one over here is all sleepy
time components i don't know what that
would be for my body but that's in this
one it spits them out charges my card
sends me home i get to go take dabs of
rosted jeff's custom slurry concentrate
just imagine walking around with your
own vape pen with your custom slurry or
your own dab rig and hitting your own
custom slurry and then your friends got
their own uh it's like mixing jelly
bellies and finding your flavors or
mixing up [ __ ] sodas all day i really
think that's the way of the future
that's what i want to see in cannabis in
concentrate development improvement
because right now i love the textures
the batters the butters the sauces all
of that i love it
the terpenes cannot be beat
cannabis concentrates the flavors are at
an all-time peak
i've got some gmo concentrates and some
garlic banger concentrates that when you
open the jar it is almost disgusting
it's almost vile it almost makes you go
and then you wanna you take a dab of it
and you blow it out and your mouth has
this like
burnt rubber rotten eggs gas and skunk
thing on it and you go
that's disgustingly delicious can i have
another dab of that terpenes have never
been stronger we're learning how to
preserve the terps in the grow and the
dry and cure or the harvest process even
if there's no drying cure and then also
in the concentrate production and then
in the preservation of those
concentrates the transport those jars
have to get from uh one facility to
another and stay fresh and then you have
to buy it and get it home like we're
learning a lot about preservation of
terpenes and these concentrates
all right we got enough battery to keep
talking we can make a podcast out of
this uh the evolution of the gear and
the actual dab i mentioned before that
we had this swing arm skillet before we
were just stuffing concentrates on top
of weed and smoking it like that i
didn't have a real dab pen or a real
concentrate device then we got the swing
arm skillet that was pretty cool
except sometimes the dabs would roll off
the skillet onto your [ __ ] leg or
onto the table or you got hot oil and
you're like that [ __ ] sucked that time
period everything was sticky and [ __ ]
sucked torches have come a long way you
got to torch the nail you got to torch
the skillet torch companies and torches
have come a long way big up to all the
torch companies that tortured us and
helped improve us along the way
nails dab nails have come a long way
back in the day we used a big-ass
metal nail some crap metal then it was
titanium they got big shout out to our
friends taskrock and highly educated
titanium tasks changed the game then we
went from titanium everybody switched
over to quartz bangers then from the
banger everybody switched over to the
new terp slurper things have really
changed quickly there
also there are e-nails oh let's talk
about the torch and the temperature you
guys uh do i have that written down
that's coming up yeah we'll talk about
that next uh then we got e-nails instead
of heating up the nail all the time we
found an e-nail we could set it the
right temperature and hit that [ __ ] all
day long
uh then we got a puffco we started
getting electronic devices the puffcos
uh dab pins then things went crazy from
there now the options for smoking are
[ __ ] endless
one thing i forget to talk about is the
atmos raw vape uh there was this little
device that i watched ruin people's
lives you would put concentrates in a
one dram or a half dram glass vial it
sounds like drugs already it looked like
[ __ ] drugs you'd screw it into this
little metal pipe it was an aluminum
apparatus that basically was big enough
for your hand to hold and then you would
slowly heat that glass vial that had the
concentrates in there with a small torch
and you would inhale
it looked and felt a lot like you were
doing drugs you really don't want to get
caught doing but the dabs or the dry
dabs it wasn't a dab because it was just
a straight dry vapor rip from hot hot
concentrates through a metal pipe and a
glass vial the rips you would get from
that could ruin your weekend you would
cough so hard your lung would come out
of one side your esophagus would pop out
snot would come out of your eye and
tears would come out of your nose it was
a [ __ ] up delicious experience i watch
people throw up from that thing i watch
people pass out from it i got so high it
was beautifully uncomfortable that thing
would ruin people so the atmos i think
it was called the admin no that was a
different device that was this was not
the atmos raw you guys i was wrong when
i said that what was that [ __ ] thing
called it was metal i've got one
somewhere um i don't know what it's
called that thing would just [ __ ]
ruin people's days it was metal
uh might have been the cloud v it wasn't
that either there were so many apparatus
and devices we went there i did say
devices is on purpose i was trying to be
bobby lee um
if you think what that metal [ __ ]
thing is called it a vial screwed into
and you heat up the vial and smoke
concentrates through that i'll try to
find mine it's in a box somewhere i'll
post a picture of it if i can find it um
that thing used to [ __ ] me up how are we
doing on battery all right we're doing
good uh we are well um
eventually we learned not to heat the
dab nail uh into oblivion like we were
trying to reshape the [ __ ] thing for
a long time there we thought the hotter
the dab nail the better the dab
then we learned uh the term was you
gotta waste it to taste it we developed
a thing called a carb cap we did not
shout out to my buddy taskrock
taskrock is who i know for pioneering
the carb cab it was a device that would
go over your dab nail that would trap
the heat and oxygen inside the dab nail
and limit oh man we used to have domes
too we didn't even talk about domes on
the dab rig we skipped that how old
school are you
if she doesn't know what a dome on a dab
nail is she's not old enough for you bro
anyway we're going to skip right over
the domes you guys know what those were
it was a dome to go over the dab nails
so that the air didn't get old the smoke
didn't get away or trapped the air uh
eventually we went to a domeless nail
then we went to a carb cab when we
started putting the carb cap on it would
trap the heat inside the nail and it
would trap it would minimize the flow of
oxygen which would create a vacuum on
the surface of the nail and give you a
much larger smoother burning dab a
better concentrate a better vaporization
if you will without as much heat which
gave you a bigger better dab without
roasting your lungs which got me higher
it got me less lung pain and it tasted
so much better so we learned the term
was taste it to waste it because the
cooler dabs low temp dabs tend to taste
a little bit better because you're not
burning off those terps so over time we
learn to adjust and control our
temperatures a little bit better
i still go a little hot i kind of like a
little bit hot but we have learned quite
a bit the word used to be glowies uh we
used to do red hot dabs and call them
glowies it'd be glowies for harambe uh
glowy's for jesus whoever it was for
that day but we would do globbies back
in the day
and they would [ __ ] hurt my lungs are
probably still burned up from a couple
of hot hot glowys then i forgot about
ninja dabs bro ninja dabs are not on the
notes but a ninja dab um if i'm taking a
dab right nice and peacefully right
we're gonna act like this is my dab tool
i'm gonna take a dab on the microphone
here i'll look into this camera as i do
it right got my dab i'm nice and ready
right
as soon as i get my dab to the device
one of my [ __ ] friends reaches in
with guess what another dad and doubles
up my [ __ ] dab now i'm doing two dabs
didn't expect to do two dabs that's
called the ninja dab now i'm gonna be
double high i'm gonna cough twice as
hard
it's kind of a dick move but also thanks
for the dab bro another thing that i
used to do
i used to set time bombs what the [ __ ]
is a time bomb i would put another dab
underneath the carb cap so that i
wouldn't even have to ninja dab you you
would ninja dab yourself you would take
a dab and then you'd grab the carb cap
and you'd set the carb cap on the nail
this is my nail right here for now for
this the sake of movie magic here you'd
be doing your dab
and then you'd set your carb cap on
there
and you'd get more dabs and you'd be
like what why is it smokier than ever
and now you got to do two dabs and you
only expected one
you just got time bombed or booby
trapped what's wrong with the dab booby
trap who doesn't want an extra dab maybe
sometimes you don't want an extra dab
but sorry dude you were at ross to
jeff's house
you got another dab you're gonna be okay
we got cookies and cable everything will
be all right all right let me get my
hi-ass back on track i do have some
notes and we're running out of time the
battery is descending quickly um
bro we went from smoking goop and crap
and questionable [ __ ] [ __ ] that i was
like oh i paid money for this at a
[ __ ] dispensary i bought this dark
brown [ __ ] that smells like burnt sulfur
and it tastes like fish guts when i
smoke it to now we're smoking live rosin
live batters the best concentrates on
the planet through high end quartz at
the correct temperature with the [ __ ]
thermometer in the dab nail tell me it's
just the right temperature we are
spoiled now things have come a long way
i've got to say how grateful i am how uh
that's the word dude i am so grateful i
am spoiled i love i really enjoy taking
dabs the act of dabbing is something
that really uh that seems to keep me
calm and fulfilled the day so i really
enjoy dabbing i'm really great that we
have evolved so far i hope wherever you
are you are evolving as much as we are
if you've got any questions corrections
comments or concerns about dabbing about
concentrates about uh any of the above
the cannabis concentrate community the
scene whatever equipment use how to do
it i'm not going to teach you how to
make it but let's talk about it the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy please do reach
out a lot of this uh knowledge and
science has come along because of the
legalization of cannabis so fight to
make cannabis legal where you are if
recreational cannabis is what you need
make that happen if legal cannabis is
the only way to make it happen make that
happen but let's get cannabis legal
nationwide so we can all understand
cannabis uh the growth of the plant the
process to make the concentrates and
then the enjoyment of dabbing with our
friends let's all do it together you
guys let's legalize cannabis together
let's take some dabs together this was
episode 709 ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
flower smokers and you dab heads out
there
i want to thank each and every one of
you for listening to another episode of
the grow from your heart podcast
this was a great show i had a good time
making it i hope you had as much fun
listening if you feel like the episode
was educational informative entertaining
maybe you'd just like to throw me a buck
for my time all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart once again all of the
information is right there on the screen
if i said that too fast or you'd like to
find any other links or information
simply visit
iregenetics.com there's a lot of info
there there's a link to seed vendors a
link to merchandise a link to the
discord and of course
a link to the patreon ah what is it a
patreon page a patreon campaign is what
i think we call it ladies and gentlemen
that's all i've got for this episode i
feel like i'm rambling to drag this out
let's wrap this up before the battery
dies all i can do is ruin a great show
from here so it's already happening i
knew it was coming let's get out of here
while we're still winning ladies and
gentlemen i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new contact content what
is wrong with me here it goes already
ladies and gentlemen i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
danny potts and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you