[Applause]
all right here we go welcome ladies and
gentlemen it is time for episode 710 of
the grow from your heart podcast i do
have some wonderful guests with me today
before we get to that part of the show
let's do some shout outs to a few of
those great folks who support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to our friend daniel let's
send a big thank you shout out to david
w let's send a fist bump to a long time
friend jesse groves let's send a big
fist bump to oreck and lots of trichomes
let's send a thank you shout out to the
dad hayes i want to send a big fist bump
to guido 7 and double p let's send a big
fist bump to a great supporter brian p i
want to send a thank you shout out to
froggle rock and all mixed up let's send
a thank you shout out to the larp knight
rises then wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shadow to elders garden big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
stoned friends all right i got through
that intro super quickly right after a
dab i'm trying to catch my breath i am
excited to get started here on the show
today we do have some wonderful
concentrate makers let me start off by
introducing my friend pedro welcome to
the show brother yo cheers brother how
are you thank you very very much for
considering me on the show uh i'm blown
away thank you oh man it's great to have
you i posted to discord that i wanted to
have concentrate makers on the show and
pedro and ryan just were the top two
recommendations everybody was like get
pedro get ryan get pedro get ryan i was
more than obvious that this was the show
that had to happen so it's great to have
you brother thank you for being here
again thank you
uh before we get too far oh yeah brother
for sure before we go too far pedro
would you like to uh do some plugs and
let everybody know how they can stock
you because i do know you have a lot of
avenues for people to find you yeah i
sure do uh i i guess first and foremost
the main instagram account is mr
rosins.org
mr.rosens.neighborhood kind of a play
there but mr rosen's neighborhood
all of the
passion rosin pressing that i do takes
place over on rosin dot is
so rosin is legal [ __ ] uh that was a
little kick for instagram when they shot
my first account down uh i have my glass
sales and everything is over on the
heady vault uh so there's a bunch of
glass sales over there we've got page
rows grow room dot com
www.com for glass sales for discounts
for education for information to contact
me
um and there's a discord as well but
just contact me through those avenues
and we'll get you hooked up i think
that's probably about the best ways yeah
hopefully that instagram is still up by
the time this episode airs it's getting
people brother yeah
i apologize
there's wood around here somewhere yeah
yeah i knock on some good one bro thank
you for the great that's a lot of stuff
to plug also find him on twitch i think
you do some twitter i do i am i'm on
twitter too uh twitch.tv forward slash
pedro's growing thanks man uh every
wednesday night man we're on a street
240 some weeks in every tuesday night um
just kind of a little stoner session
about 9 30 on tuesday night so if you're
down come come get high with us yeah
check him out smokes uh he smokes great
concentrates through beautiful glass so
make sure you check that out follow him
on twitch uh thank you bro all right
let's move on and introduce uh the
legend uh mr rosin ryan thank you for
being here bro well thank you i'm glad
to be here man uh i don't really i guess
uh have as many plugs as pedro that's
for sure uh i guess you could pretty
much for the most part catch me on uh
our army discord man uh i hang out there
quite a bit i've got helva a crew a
community over there that we're building
i'm glad that everybody kind of pushed
me to be here and that's about it man
well thank you bro i'm glad they pushed
you i hope it didn't take too much
not at all not at all glad to be here
for sure brother this is the 7 10
episode before i go too far into it uh
let's briefly talk about what 710 is and
mean so that people understand why we're
doing a hash episode on 710 then we'll
delve deeply into making concentrates
what i want to focus on in this episode
is i want to get the audience the
listeners uh basically self-sufficient i
want them to be able to grow uh from
seed or clone however they're growing uh
manage their grow all the way up to
getting that dab onto the nail and
taking a fat hit of their product pedro
got excited he's about to take that fat
rip right now cheers brother enjoy that
uh so let's uh briefly talk about what
710 is a lot of people might not even
know why we are celebrating 7 10 uh the
710th episode uh so let's give them a
quick update uh since pedro has taken a
dab ryan do you have any input on what
710 means i'll let you talk for a minute
because i feel like i talk a lot on the
show
well 710 to me is kind of a newer thing
i mean it's you know it's oil backwards
uh it's for us dabbers these days that's
the new 420. that's exactly what i would
have said it is the new 420 it's
upgraded 420 420 for big kids
absolutely
upgrade your tolerance all right so
basically that is uh what i would have
said it is the new 420. i agree
we're all agreeing it is the new 420 if
you turn the word oil upside down it
does say 7
7 so when that clock strikes 7 10 we
used to smoke a bowl at 4 12 i still
smoke a ball at 420 but now also i'm
taking a dab at 7 10. so today's just
another excuse that's like we needed it
i was just going to say we actually did
take one on 710.
yes oh we actually were we didn't even
really yeah beautiful seeing the
laughter itself out that way so 710 is
dab time so this is the seven tenth
episode uh i want to teach everybody how
to make their own dabs at home we're not
going to talk about bho um no uh
solventless stuff here because i don't
want to uh encourage anybody or teach
them how to hurt themselves there's a
lot of [ __ ] that can go wrong in that uh
no offense no hatred if you're doing
that do your thing but stay safe and
don't call me when you get blown up by
your own mistakes so i'd like to step in
there if i could for a second i want to
hear it brother that's what you're here
for it's good because you said something
that i hear a lot of people say and it
just it's like it's like sticking
something underneath my skin it just
just drives me nuts it's like a little
mosquito buzzing around your head i want
to show you i want to show you how to
make dabs
i want to show you how to make dabs it's
not dabs dabs are
a dab is like a like i'm gonna i don't
know it's a verb right
um so it's it's not a noun but we're
gonna show you how to make hash and how
to make rosin that's we're gonna talk
about today perfect thank you i
appreciate that live hopefully yeah
right yeah and we'll talk about the
differences yeah we'll talk about
differences let's jump into it now that
we're uh we're here this is the good
part to just jump off on uh let's talk
about the process i want to start with
kind of like uh
i'm hoping that a lot of the people
watching are growing their own product
as well they've got to get the product
to to wash the press from somewhere so
let's talk about are there any uh
significant differences in the grow if
we're gonna grow for flour when i grow i
grow for seed so my grow's way different
than most people most people are growing
for flower you guys are growing for
concentrate is there a big difference in
the way you treat the grow other than
most people
i would say i would say minimally
strained selection yeah i would agree i
would say randomly as far as
as far as like technique um the only
thing i can come up with would be
scrogging excessively so that you don't
get uh main big colas you want a very
consistent bud size um so
so you know it's a big scrog is
something that i really really strive
for my plans grow horizontally not
vertically
and that's what most people should be
doing now anyway no matter how you're
growing that's kind of the ideal way to
do it
it's a good way to maximize your space
really especially for us homegrowers i'm
a stronger i'm a four by four strokes
perfect all right let's let's step back
for a second can we explain
just as an overview
what
hash and rosin are and what we're trying
to achieve and why we're doing what
we're doing absolutely let's do it okay
so i like to explain it in a in a broad
sense um kind of like hash for dummies
right um try trichomes are the plants uh
a defense mechanism um for uv light and
for other and for bugs and pests and
whatnot you have to think of them as
well i think of them as millions and
billions and billions of little beach
balls on your plants right and those
beach balls are on top of a stock and we
don't need to get into technical terms
because that's just advanced classes
so you've got a billions of beach balls
on top of a stock what we are after from
a hash standpoint is those beach balls
all of those little beach balls they're
a little waxy cuticle filled with oil
hopefully filled with oil right and that
oil inside that waxy cuticle is what us
rosin heads are after we leave the waxy
cuticle behind in the hash and we
extract the oil which is where the 710
the oil comes from so
there's spots you can stop along the way
but that is kind of ultimately what we
are going after and everything that
we're going to be talking about
subsequently eases our access to those
trichome heads
okay
that's a perfect explanation yeah thank
you you yeah i don't even need notes
after you that's perfect
that was perfect i don't even have
anything to say after that
yeah
yeah case dismissed um so you said
trichome heads that's i'm going to jump
back to a conversation that we that i
interrupted before the show do trichome
head sizes make a big difference in
trichome shape
i would say yes absolutely we're after
those big trichome heads and we want
that weak neck that we can kind of break
off and get those beach balls as pedro
just explained yep yep and uh and it and
does the size the size not so much
but the uh shape you know if you've got
uh heads that are stuck together two
three four heads i mean you can have a
stalk with two three four heads stuck
together um they're going to collect in
different bags and whatnot so a
uniformity is also desirable as well in
size uh that being noted as i said
in a couple seconds ago the trichomes
are the plants uh protection against uv
light right so if you're if you're not
giving them uv light they have nothing
to create a protection against
um a lot of sun grown cannabis has big
juicy bulbous trichome hits because of
the extra uv light from the sun
so that that i did not i did not did not
know that so you're teaching me stuff
right now ryan i feel like keep that in
mind
yep and keep that in mind you're making
your led selections as well for your
lighting absolutely beautiful all right
so you guys if you're going to make
concentrates uh let's upgrade and get
some of those uh those leds with uv
lights in there that may help you out
bigger trichomes the better
um so the strain selection that was one
of the things that you mentioned that
it's all about a lot about strain
selection do you uh find a difference
back in the day dr dre taught us that we
want a sack of rocks everybody wants
dense buds if you go to the dispensary
all the buds are super dense you're
already i think you know where i'm going
is does the bud density really make a
difference for you concentrate makers
are those fluffier buds going to be more
ideal for you
yeah yeah it makes a huge difference all
right a lot easier to watch that's for
sure i was actually just talking or
somebody was i was reading through
discord and somebody was giving someone
a suggestion upon lights and this and
then i said if you don't give them
enough light you're gonna have airy buds
and they were like you're like oh that's
a bummer i don't want airy buds and i'm
like i do like i'd much rather have a
bud that the first wash just falls apart
rather than go in on the third wash and
see
dense nuggets that i still haven't
broken into you know i've always
explained it as if i took my fist and
moistened my fist and dunked it in
powdered sugar i get my fist worth of
trichomes on the outside here if i open
up my hand and do the same process i get
my palm all the insides of my fingers i
get that much more space for trichomes
and also like you said easier to wash i
don't have to wash inside of my fist i
got fingers open you can wash that i
really i thought that would be a thing
of the future some of what i breed isn't
super tight and super dense but i know
that it you press some strawberry
starburst and uh pedro and that was some
of the best rosin i've ever smoked that
changed my mind on raw and honestly nice
good yes sir uh big shout out to our
friend kelvin who grew that and then you
pressed that at the dude gross cup
um that was a hell of a freaking thing
wasn't that a good time
i missed those events that put a smile
on my face all these times come back
right hopefully these times come back
soon yeah oh yeah it's coming back
around now we're talking about making
concentrate making concentrates out of
trichomes from plants that were growing
one of my main questions was do we treat
them any differently it seems like we
just grow them like normal try not to
scrog them take good care of them how do
we manage pests a lot of people are
putting pesticides on plants i don't
want to smoke pesticides especially
pesticide concentrates in my concentrate
how do you guys manage pests in your
your garden wait who's spraying
pesticides
wait a second what are you guys doing
nothing gets sprayed in my flower room
period nothing no foliar no nothing in
my flower room um and that's just the
way it is i'm i'm just sacrilegious
about it it doesn't happen uh if i have
pests in my flower room we cut we start
over
wow that's dedicated i'm pretty much the
same way so uh same way no no sprays or
anything like that in my flower room if
i do have any issues uh for me it's
generally thrips up here we get thrips
quite a bit um i usually do grease green
lacewing larvae they work really good
simple cheap one round usually takes
care pretty much right through flour and
uh that does it man other than that i'm
a big doctor's arms person pretty much
uh through veg
cockney and green cleaner enzymatics i
will agree with the beneficial bugs
greatly i generally try to stick with
them in veg but of course they carry
over in front of the flower so yeah i
agree with that i concur big time i was
hoping that that would be the answer was
the beneficial predators there and i'm
glad you said lace wings those have been
some of my favorite in a commercial grow
especially in colorado because they
tolerate uh all types of environments
they don't die off as quickly as your
swarovskis and hypoaspis and they stick
around a little bit
all right and those those larvae are
hungry
oh yeah those little crocodiles they
they go crazy
cool as hell
oh really they'll bite the [ __ ] out of
you yeah i think that i'm pretty sure
that's what was biting us right they'll
bite the [ __ ] out of you all right so
we've talked a lot about the grow
process grow it don't spray it uh try to
get the even sized buds we want bigger
trichomes that seems to be a thing let's
get into the process of actually making
the concentrates here um i don't know
the first thing about making any sort of
rosin
any live rosin so
let's say we are right to the day of
harvest uh what do we do if we're going
to make concentrates i know a lot of us
are going to freeze it some of us are
going to press it right away what are
the differences that we're going to run
into can you teach me how to harvest for
concentrate production
yeah the first thing that comes to mind
is cold
cold cold cold
all right and then it comes down to yeah
are we doing fresh are we doing a half
dry are we doing a full dry as far as
i'm concerned that's kind of the three
things that we can do um and i'll let
rosin take to take the fresh because he
says he likes fresh so go live bro i i i
really like the fresh stuff uh pretty
much uh uh you know most of my my top
buds and stuff for the most part i
pretty much generally keep for smoking
i generally do it all for myself so all
my larf anything that doesn't have any
kind of bag of peel pretty much goes
right to my hash bags uh i fresh freeze
it that night
and then i pretty much try to process it
as soon as i possibly can um if i tend
to store it i do vacuum seal it and keep
it frozen that way um the longer the
storage obviously the worse terpene
preservation is everything obviously
um so other than that like pedro said
cold cold cold um i'm a strong believer
in distilled water i like my water super
super cold i don't like to wash unless
it's winter time generally
you know garage is a perfect place for
that this time of year
i've got the words washing weather on my
notes here i was going to talk about
that it is beautiful washing weather it
is i don't touch anything all summer
long really you don't even mess with it
in the summer
i don't personally know what's the uh
what's like the temperature threshold
when you start going oh it's washing
season what gets you excited
oh soon as i see that snow fly okay
that's all i can think about pedro's got
a big silly grin
yeah i was just like i was just letting
him go i'm just thinking about where i
can fill in here and where
snowboard kids and the hash washers get
excited at that first time
i have a cold room i built myself a cold
room
so i can make it 32 degrees in my room
when it's 100 degrees outside
um and i always wash in 32-33 degree
weather if i can
um
especially with fresh frozen my god
especially with fresh frozen that's some
of that's one of the nuances that uh
that that doesn't get talked about
enough
is people you know fresh frozen fresh
frozen have you ever touched a [ __ ]
plant
you ever seen how sticky a plant is
now collect all those sticky balls
right so that's why we do it in the cold
the cold takes away a lot of the
immediate stick right and it also
brittles the trichome heads um and if
you're doing fresh frozen that's
immensely more important to to get it
cold and to have them break off and to
remain cold
if you have if you have fresh frozen
hash that gets above
goodness sometimes 50 degrees it's
already starting to congeal it's already
starting to melt together it's already
starting to lose its beach sand
consistency
so fresh frozen is not a beginner game
fresh frozen is an advanced player game
cold cold cold is immensely important
anything again anything above 40 degrees
and you're starting to get problematic
with your with your bag your collection
bag stuff sticking to them um trichome
sticking to spoons uh just being a
nightmare um
absolutely kind of one of those do you
even keep going i was just going to say
i even like to keep a a bucket of cold
water right next to me as i'm washing so
i can put my bags right in it yeah my
bags going up my spoon goes into a
little
cup with ice water in it absolutely yeah
like when i say cold
i hope i'm not being underestimated
30 degrees that if you're not if you're
from the coast one of the coast 30
degrees doesn't make sense to you uh but
30 go in the walk-in cooler or wherever
if you work at a restaurant go in there
that's not 30 degrees it's colder than
that at 30 degrees yeah it's probably
not 30. yeah walk in your starting water
stand in your walk-in cooler for eight
hours and tell me how you feel
yeah i was going to ask if you can get
dizzy in there not physically get dizzy
your wife's name is dizzy can you get
dizzy to even walk in that walk-in
cooler yeah she'll walk in and bring me
lunch or something that's about it
yeah i don't i can't keep my like i
can't keep my dab briggs in there it's
too cold you know
yeah i can't dab in there i can't go you
can't water would get frozen oh because
i was gonna mention
do you keep your your water ice cold too
like do you keep uh like i use distilled
water and i always keep it in a beer
fridge before i generally use it keep it
right at that 33 degree mark i have
three 44 gallon drums as my res is in my
room underneath my my cabinets and those
get ice
i mean dude when i go why when i when i
wash i'll bet i'll go through
a couple hundred pounds of ice
yep wow it's just a lot even though my
room is that cold even though my room is
sure everything is ice cold period
you're using at least 25 pounds usually
per 5 gallon wash yeah yeah oh yeah and
then and four gallons of distilled cold
cold water yeah i don't use distilled
for the wash um i'm over that i will use
ro for my final rinse um i will say that
the
the higher quality water that you're
going to use in minimal increments are
going to be higher quality concentrates
for sure
absolutely
for us we use well water so you don't
want that trace yeah yeah definitely
that taste to kind of transfer through
agreed agreed mineral flavor let's go
back real quick though to the to the
fresh and then half and then and then
the other dry because i think i covered
it real good with the fresh but there's
other options you know if you can't
achieve 32 degrees you know you got
outside it's got 40s the best i can do
bro or
there's a bunch of different things um i
i highly recommend a half dry like it's
one of my like go-to's i feel like i've
kind of underlined that in the industry
right um and i and i say half dry
anymore because people want to [ __ ]
tie you down they want to be like what
is it four and a half days bro like you
know it's
you know it's that half dry it's that
when the outside of the bud just starts
to get crunchy but the inner side of the
butt is still is still uh
hydrated you know that's about when i'll
hang my flowers you know 50 50 60 60. 60
and if i brush over that 50 degrees 50
humidity 60 degrees 60 humidity in that
window
dry for the half right your eight days
your seven days your whatever your half
dry is
then buck that off here's another thing
that i think we do we don't underline it
when in techniques is again millions of
little trichome heads millions of little
balls filled with oil right be careful
with that [ __ ] man don't don't molest it
at all you know people want to use
trimmers and they want to bounce their
[ __ ] and they want no as as easy and as
careful as you can
each trichome head is another little bit
of oil that you're trying to that you're
trying to extract
and then and then there's the full then
there's a full dry and as we progress
through the from the fresh to the half
to the full dry
the trichome heads get more brittle they
get less sticky less terpene content um
so they're a little bit easier to handle
yes i said less terpene content not to
the point of degradation necessarily but
to the ease of handling you know um so
there's definitely some uh tricks you
know when you're when you're they're
half dry you can probably wash in 40
degree weather when you're full dry you
can maybe wash in 50 degree weather
that brings me to the conversation are
you a wet trimmer or dry charm
so when i harvest i'll take off
everything with uh with without trikes
everything without trikes goes away and
it brings me another thing to fill in
one of your blanks you said you keep
flour
we don't
we we have a couple plants that i grow
mimosas specifically um and a couple
other very few ones that will actually
keep for flour i don't personally smoke
flour like hardly at all um dizzy smokes
a lot more flour than i do i'm just i'm
a straight hash head
um
so yeah we're 50 50. so we keep uh
you know
flour and good hash in the house
absolutely and the hash just hit me in
the face and i forgot where i was going
with that
i just took a dab and stumbled over my
words
you don't save any of it uh what doesn't
have trichomes comes off you don't save
any of it for flower production perfect
and then and then it just gets bucked
straight into a bag you know from from
fresh if it's fresh it gets bucked
straight into a bag straight into the
freezer if it's half dry it gets dried
halfway get bucked straight into a bag
into the freezer if it's dried it gets
dried fully bucked into a bag put into
the freezer
i'm starting to understand why i see the
rosin's twice the price of other
concentrates on the shelf i didn't
understand but now now that i see that
you're getting you said like a few
pounds of herb gave you a very tiny
amount i was like that's all you get so
now i kind of i understand there's a lot
of work to go into it as well that's
funny it's definitely a lot lower to me
that uh that number is astronomical
uh what i what he's referring to is
earlier in a podcast i said that my
critical cush on average gives me if i
push the limits gives me two and a half
ounces of rosin per pound of flour
and if you think about the the market
prices on the on the recreational market
price right now flowers and the
wholesale prices for flowers in the 300
range
you know so uh wholesale pricing for
rosin is in the 15 to 30 dollar a gram
range so you can do the math and you can
see it quickly adds up all right i see
good rosin on shelves for eighty hundred
and twenty dollars a gram for the top
shelf [ __ ] i see that that's what it
sells for out here too
massachusetts and
our surrounding states are 80 to 100 a
gram for good rosin yeah yeah and i was
i was referring to the wholesale side
the yes not the purchase price yeah
absolutely yeah you guys don't come here
thinking you're gonna get it for the
price page that is wholesale yeah that
is whole that's that's wholesale on the
recreational market that's why i said
that because i i'm starting
i didn't i didn't mention that in the
intro and because i don't
we're still in kind of the infancy
phases and everything i'm busting my ass
putting in crazy hours but we are
entering the recreational and med market
um we as in pedro i guess i say we and
it's
like looking who the [ __ ] behind me um
it's a grow grow up it's a grow up in
parachute it's eden extracts it's eden
supernatural gardening
our supernatural gardens uh and uh yeah
we're moving into you know every people
have been asking me for years if they
can purchase my rosin and the answer is
resoundingly no i'm sorry you can't um
but soon to be you will be able to
purchase rosin that i've actually made
excellent the world the world will look
forward to that
very cool hit the rec market with that
pedro rosin all right i love it people
can come talk about what i've been
talking about the stuff that changed my
opinion on rosin that's that's crazy to
hear that's that that's crazy as i say
he's gonna have to send me a little bit
so i can sample that possibly allegedly
well
allegedly we'll all meet at the denver
airport yeah there we go there we go
just for the sake of recording purposes
you know um so we were in the middle of
talking about the half dry uh process
um we got to uh i don't even remember
where we got to because i'm not a
concentrate maker i don't know if you
were done with that part
i don't think you remember either uh no
i was pretty much done with that i think
um it's it's literally just differences
in climates well not literally just but
it's differences in climates that i
wanted to kind of underline and i wanted
to underline the point um that people
that are just starting to do this should
absolutely not start with fresh frozen
and that is just an underlying do not do
it period um start with start with dried
uh if you want to get crazy and think
you're somebody then go ahead and do the
half frozen but pay attention to what i
just said or they're not the half frozen
a half dry but pay attention to what i
just said i would highly recommend
anybody that's starting to wash their
first wash washes dry material
uh how dry like cured or just dry just
dry just dry just dry yeah yeah i i
always when i'm processing for rosin
it's either fresh
bag freezer
half dry bag freezer or dry bag freezer
and that doesn't mean dry and cure bag
free it's dry then freezer
agreed and that freezing process from
what i understand that's like uh and
this is scary to say just because i'm a
guy with dreadlocks it kind of thinks of
if you get gum and your hair or
something you used to freeze the gum and
it would come out of your hair it's kind
of the same idea i get when you talk
about breaking those trichome heads off
in the freeze is that correct yes which
is why we which is why we underline
being careful with it when i take it out
of the freezer i don't throw the [ __ ]
over my shoulder and i can walk into the
you know it's very delicate process
because i want to collect those
trichometes i thought a weed said same
thing when you're trimming it
definitely saw weed santa
and he said it right there and when
you're trimming when you're handling it
when you're everything you know when
when i bring someone into my grow to
to harvest or to to help me with the
process of pre you know basically
harvest
if i see a lot of ras a resin all over
your gloves and [ __ ]
we're gonna have a little bit of a talk
yeah a little why is that what are you
doing to those pods yeah stop molesting
my [ __ ] bro exactly there's at least
half a gram on your fingers right there
yeah so if super cold is one go ahead
ryan i don't mean to cut you off as i
say that's what i i feel like wet
trimming honestly there's you got a
little bit less handling and those
trichomes are a little less brittle i
think when they're wet too i feel like
uh those everything's more intact and
just better overall if you're doing a
wet trim if you're going to watch see if
that makes sense for me trimming is only
a flower thing if i'm going to if i'm
going to rosin there's
trim doesn't happen
if that makes
you don't but you probably don't trim
your lowers right you just throw that in
the bag no yeah
so so for your rosin you're not trimming
correct yep all my lowers larv anything
that has zero bag appeal dude right to
the hatchback yeah for sure literally my
entire heart my every bit of my harvest
go right in the freezer it's pretty
crazy
i want that freeze dryer too brother
ryan just segwayed for me we're trying
to keep the stuff cold uh is freeze
drying this bud an option is that
something that's useful
you got excited about that yeah all
right it's something that has been
talked about a lot
um
controversial as well and and maybe not
enough uh i think yes it's true super
controversial
i think that for smoking flour freeze
drying your buds is not applicable
um you're locking a lot of stuff in in
the plant you're just removing moisture
but you're locking a lot of stuff in the
plant that you that would otherwise
off gas and and dry and you know
chlorophyll yeah chlorophylls
was the one big thing i was thinking
about chlorophyll exactly chlorophyll it
tastes like green bug
that being said if we're not smoking the
flower we're just collecting the
trichome heads
is that a viable option you get very dry
dense or not dry dense very dry brittle
buds and trikes
it's it's viable but god damn think
about the price man it's 36 hours for a
freeze dry session and you can probably
put a half a pound in a big freeze dryer
so
would you it's very interesting you guys
want to spend 300 a gram you know like
man
so no uh viable but possible
with the with the tools and freeze
dryers and stuff that we have right now
no
for freeze drying flour now freeze
drying the hash
as far as i'm concerned that's like the
big step up in
in in question absolutely
definitely next level and uh that's
that's another thing we can talk about
is how you actually uh
try and process afterwards after we wash
uh for me i'm a homegrower freeze dryers
are expensive so that's that's a tough
thing for me so for me uh that was a big
uh a step uh to learn
as well just to preserve those terpenes
so for me uh i like i don't even press
it right out of the bag pretty much on
the pressing screens i keep it in a ball
i fresh freeze it and i got microplaned
the crap out of it um and that's the
only way i really can do it just flash
freeze it microplane it make it that
sandy material pretty much scattered
across a piece of parchment paper and
dry it as fast as you possibly can in a
24-hour period but at a cooler
temperature pizza box pizza box tech
i just i just i microplaned it put it on
a big piece of parchment paper and i
just set it on a counter in a garage at
40 50 degrees and it's pretty much dry
by the next day it's a very uh
low relative immunity here so sure it's
pretty much ready to rock by the next
day a lot of people also use uh they'll
put that parchment inside pizza boxes um
the car the cardboard makes it
when you turn it into dust basically
right you use the little file and turn
it to sand
yeah yeah so he's like like a lemon
zester he
breezed over that that is a
much more arduous task than he said
um
do you have a big
frozen ball of stickiness
okay that you're trying to microplane
before it gets too sticky so back to
cold right um yeah how many how many
times you put that freezer or that thing
back in the freezer while you're
microplaning
five four or five times at least exactly
how many minutes between those times all
depends it'll take me probably an hour
to microplane it okay just because i
have to keep re refreezing it yeah and
then and and with the air drying you got
you have oxidation you're losing terpene
content you know the whole nine yards
color color absolutely yep degradation
but that freeze dryer man two grand
that's a hard bite i know it's it was it
was a tough buy but one of the best i've
ever made you can get you can get by
with a small one you can get by with a
small one so don't don't feel like you
need a big you know expensive ball you
can get by with a small one it'll change
your game like oh trust me yeah that's
that's on top of the list buddy it's
awesome it's really nice
next christmas yeah right
next three christmases
[Laughter]
so we've gotten through the frozen the
half dry i think it's time to kind of
explain the process of harvesting and
turning our dry product into a smokable
concentrate uh yeah into a smokeable
rosin
trying to use the right words now that
i've been educated yeah yeah no worries
um cold cold water where
this is the fun part
we are if some people will say oh water
is a universal solvent so how are we
solvent-less right blah blah blah blah a
solvent is only a solvent when it's used
to dissolve
let's say we're using it mechanically
we're not using it we're not using the
water to dissolve our extract we're
using it as a carrier right we're using
it just just literally as a medium
um so so we're solventless and we're
using that cold that the the brittleness
properties of that trichome head
hopefully at least we discussed a little
bit in
the pre-show uh regarding a stalked
trichome head and and a bulbous trichome
head where it's literally just a bulb of
a trichome head on the leaf itself where
there is no stock
um that does that doesn't wash well at
all
you definitely need stocked trichome
heads that's what's going to give you
your better yield
um
you literally
dump your flower into water
agitate it
and collect the water
and
in the simplest form you know now we can
get into ice content in the water we can
get into a temperature of the water we
can get into agitation practices whether
it's mechanical or hand we can get into
time vegetation we can get into
collecting techniques there's a lot
there's a lot a lot to it um but for
this for the simplest dumbed-down
explanation it's in water it's agitated
cold and we collect the trichome heads
that have collected in the water at the
end
and those trichome heads will be in the
different size bags with the different
uh micron screens in the bottom of them
okay uh ryan said don't over agitate it
i've made bubble hash before i was
taught by uh the legendary sub cool i
used his bubble bag method
subby taught us to agitate the [ __ ] out
of it some beat the [ __ ] out of this out
of his father's
a lot of guys used to use paint mixers
on drills
[Music]
that makes me cringe i did it once and i
was like holy [ __ ] what is going on me
too is that what i bring i looked at my
bags and everything was green
okay chlorophyll that's exactly what i
expected yeah chlorophyll
so when we get into this um it's
definitely a look of feel a touch it's
it's definitely doing it multiple times
uh watching that water watching what's
actually going on it's it's not the same
time every time it's not the same time
with everything it's different for every
strain every female exactly it's it's
it's definitely a look a feel it's it's
something that you got to know
just by doing it
absolutely
um
yeah i agree 100
i think i understand the process of the
sieve bags the bubble bags now i've got
bubble i called it bubble hash back in
the day because we use bubble bags to
make it bubbles when you make it or when
you burn it uh it melts when you light
it up what do i do if i want to turn
that into rosin
what i this is the part where i am lost
what do i do to turn my bag wash into
rosin how do we press this stuff i have
no idea how to do that part
so after after i get my my hash out of
the water i put it uh in a best
consistency i can say is a pancake type
consistency so my when my hash comes out
of the bags let's step back a little bit
more and talk about those collection
bags yes um
there's yes bubble bags bubble man uh as
a matter of the funny thing is why i did
an interview with uh with bubble man
himself and
the first bags that i purchased
some 20
20 years ago were hand stitched by his
wife which is just
freaking cool as [ __ ] she was hand
stitching them in her in her in her
living room at the time
um so there's bags there's a 25 micron
now this varies with manufacture but as
for the most part yeah for the most part
there's a 25 there's a 45 there's a 73
there's a 90 there's a 120 uh there's a
160 there's a 190 there's a 220.
that's like the general you know and
they'll they'll be off on a couple
different a couple try or a couple of
micron sizes on different manufacturers
but that's about
a round ball um
as as as a whole
most people
and most phenos
will collect somewhere in the 45 to 159
range that might be 73 to 159 it might
be 90 to 159 it might be 90 to 120 you
know
the essentially what the micron size is
is it's a whole size in the bag it will
let through anything smaller than 73
microns than 93 microns and it will hold
everything
bigger than that
you can use all eight bags you can use
four bags you can use really whatever
you want i've taught a lot of people in
the past to use the 25 the 45 the 160
and the 220 that's it you can collect
your your 45 through 159 and have a
beautiful
um
i call it broad spectrum i never call it
full spectrum that's a whole nother
conversation full spectrum of smoking
flower
uh you can have a very broad spectrum uh
concentrate but you know and then as you
pull it down into the 90 to 120 you've
got a way more isolated spectrum
product
my 73 and my 120 are my sweet spot yeah
usually it's about the right for me
notice the 90 and 120 sell the best at
the dispensary yeah if you and now
here's the other thing when you start
when you start isolating heads in a 90
bag like let's say you're using all all
of the eight bags right and you're gonna
isolate the 90 to 120
you're no longer getting that two and a
half ounces per pound of the 90 to 120
that that two and a half ounces is all
of your rosin right so now if you start
taking just this little bit now you've
got what eight ounces of or eight grams
or whatever whatever the numbers is
right of high quality and that's why the
shit's costing you 150 a gram
you want me to burst
that's why we don't sell it and we don't
share it yeah you want to only burst the
bubble i think the the
120 the 73 the isolated bags is hype
can you tell me why can you tell me why
yeah because everybody started this
smoking flower right it's a broad it's a
that's your full spectrum that's getting
the can every cannabinoid that the plant
has to offer well i don't want to say
every cannabinoid but that's getting the
vast majority of the cannabinoids that
the plant has to offer in your system
when you start isolating things
and not even burning plant material
you've lost full spectrum you've just
went down to broad at best and every
time you take a step into
a smaller uh
size you know 90 to 120 a smaller bag
size a smaller pole you've isolated
cannabinoids you're no longer getting a
broad
you're no longer getting that full high
you might only get a heady high you
might go to sleep
it's going to be different for every
plant
um i am i i am of a
i started to do the 45 to 159 i do
believe there's value in pulling the 45
out and going like the 73 to 120 or 73
to 159 like i do believe there's some
subtle nuances and benefits to doing
that
but i think the more that we isolate the
heads when we isolate the cannabinoids
we're stepping away from that full body
high
i couldn't agree with that i can agree
with that that's already great i noticed
that some concentrates uh definitely
make me super droopy eyed and super lazy
and then some will definitely give me
bug-eyed and moving and i notice that
there's not the full experience that you
get from some other uh delivery methods
for sure
and some people like want that and
that's a great thing to know and to
desire yeah but just be educated
so we've got uh so we've done our press
let's get back to our yeah we've done
our wash how do we press this stuff
sorry we're no no you're good we're all
stoned here i'll get us back on track
that's my job you ramble all day i like
the info
i'll never cut you off you keep going
seriously i can listen to them all day
long yeah yeah when i cut you off the
listener from one hatch bigger to
another absolutely appreciate it
um so we've isolated our bags whatever
bags we have right we've got hash that
we're ready to press whether it's your
73 whether it's your 90 whether it's a
broad spectrum whatever i'm going to say
we've got beach
beach sand quality hash sitting in front
of us whether it's been microplaned and
it's the the sand particles are a little
bigger whatever we've all got beach sand
in front of us right
um for me everything i use is rosin
evolution sorry it's a plug i use them
all day long every day
uh i'll use the two
or the other two by four and a half inch
bags
and in a two by four and a half inch bag
i will put 20 grams of hash
that's in a 25 micron bag boy there's a
whole other story the bags have micron
sizes too
the the the rosin filter bags have
micron sizes right
double your bags as well per hour i
triple them actually
i double mic i do 37 micron doubles i do
trespass 225s in a 160.
um and i'm and i'm actually and i'm
actually i just ordered and have them
sitting over here right next to me uh 15
microns so i'm gonna play around with
some 15 microns as well i'm figuring man
if it's oil if it's oil
why do we want a micron size anyways
you know this is true so take out the
lipids for the most part right that's
that's the main
yep so so if we're getting down to 50
you know 15 microns instead of 25 we're
potentially even removing it more
undesirable more absolutely so
that being said there's different micron
sizes back when we used to press flower
price we used to press flower in a 90
micron or a 120 micron and
those days are funny to think back on
um now we'll take 20 grams and we'll put
it in a 25 micron bag i'll slip that in
another 25 micron bag double filtration
double uh blowout prevention um and then
i will always put that in a 160
the 160 is extra blowout protection
there's no filtration with the 160
whatsoever
um the thing that it does that people
don't
give enough credit to is bag slippage
when you put your uh your bags into a
160 and put them onto parchment they
won't slip anymore and what i mean by
that
anybody that's ever pressed hash has had
a blowout if your bag is not centered on
your plates or at least within the
square inches of your plates if any part
of that bag comes out
of that press area you will have to blow
out all of your hash will go to that
little spot and it will literally
you will have hash shoot at your face
it's not a great won't be the nice same
color as the rest of it no it's it's
pretty horrible so when when i do it in
the in the 225s that's double blowout
prevention double filtration and then
the 160 is blowout prevention but also
slippage the bag stays put
and um and man that's just i've been
doing it that way religiously for a
couple years now
that's a good tip man i like that
and then
time temperature pressure that's what i
just wrote time
time and weight
[Laughter]
so now we're uh usually again
depends depends depends depends depends
right this is where we're this is why we
are who we are i guess strain dependent
again yep yep so somewhere between the
some people get crazy some people go
down to 150s 160s you know some people
are
170 180 for me that's where i'm at 180
almost almost religiously 180 uh 170 180
sometimes if the hash
is looking weird i'll bump to 190 just
to see what the hell's going on
but i just man
i see people pressing at 2 2 10 220 i'm
like whoa bro you see the bubbles
do you understand what bubbling rosin
means unless we're talking flour that's
a different talk yeah right that
bubbling should happen after i paid for
it yes yeah the bubbling is literally
that's where it should be happening the
bubbling banger if you're bubbling on
the press
you're degrading your rosin
horribly horribly if you're pressing
above 190 you're degrading that's
awesome that's where you get that burnt
popcorn but yeah one of my notes is how
to avoid the burnt popcorn flavor
don't go above 190 don't go above 190.
don't go above 180. try to try to stay
below the 180 190 mark market
and then temperature or time uh time
if you really want the very specifics
this is one of the things that i've done
since the beginning that's kind of
underlined who i am when you go to the
rosin dot
league
account
i tell you all this i pressed at 82
degrees celsius for two and a half
minutes at this amount of pressure at
the back
um
man bag pressure is another thing too
yeah i said that and it's just like
it's slow pressure when you're pressing
cash that's really another thing we
should talk about get that get that slow
pressure don't freaking squeeze the hell
out of it you're gonna blow those bags
out that's why we're double tripling
them up uh big thing and same thing with
flour if we're talking about flour uh i
press it to 37 as well for flour and uh
if you're pressing wetter flour or
something that's just dried go slower
you're going to blow those bags out if
it's fresh
that makes sense
is that why a lot of the rosin that i
smoke and i'm not trying to be a hater
here is that why a lot of the ross and i
smoke taste like straight popsicle
sticks and burnt popcorn or uh yeah what
is it a popsicle stick or burnt popcorn
or are you smoking flour rosin yes
that's probably what i'm assuming i
don't because i don't make it i don't
know people bring me gifts people i've
got a lot of friends that will bring me
gifts and i could tell sometimes as soon
as i open it it's got that just that
woody terp that i do not appreciate
sorry guys i don't love it but yeah i
think that i would honestly say that is
probably well not necessarily
flourishing like he just said it was
probably pressed it was yeah it could be
bubble hash just pressed at a high temp
that's where i really get that popcorn
taste to me yeah you know and here and
here's the other thing too is
you know he's just ryan said that he'll
he'll only press the buds that don't
have bag appeal right
well the buds that don't have bag of
peel also aren't the best buds
right your trim isn't the best material
to run your best material to run is your
your your bag appeal
that's your good hash that's your good
rosin gold and gold out yeah absolutely
so so you you might be getting trim run
rosa which is
a polished dog turd you know it's in it
and it's and that's not a a a a negative
thing if you could polish a dog turd
[ __ ] you've done a great job but it's a
hell of a task
you know
you could have done it correctly if you
started off properly with the right
absolute mind absolutely all right
um
they don't expect gold from trash
exactly no you can never expect that in
the cannabis industry especially
solidless
and i'm learning why this stuff is so
pricey you guys you guys have explained
it now i don't walk in and stare at it
and go why sure sure people some people
can make funny things out of bho yeah i
mean all the pretty buds that you see
they don't get small but they don't get
put in a bag they're washed and thrown
into my garden in the in the in the
backyard you know like
yeah the shit's there's a lot of work
that goes behind and the money holy
christ i bet i've got 15 or 20 000 in my
cold room like it's just it's it's crazy
you know so i mean it's it's it's tough
man it's tough it's all about that
dedication a lot of people don't realize
what somebody in your position ryan's
position my position uh when you have a
niche product like that they don't
understand the dedication to it the
commitment to just the equipment and the
room and the space and then there's the
work after that which we'll talk about
yeah for sure um i wanted to keep on
this uh we got through temp how about
how about time how long do we press this
stuff once we've got it in the press we
bring down that weight how long does it
take for the goop and the gold to come
out of there take it ryan
well for the group and gold to actually
start come out pretty much when you
reach full pressure uh i usually hit my
timer button once i hit full pressure uh
for hash um minute and a half to two
minutes generally oh quickly
all right that's fast uh how much
pressure should we put on there
uh i i'm using a seven ton press but i
don't have actual pressure gauge where
my bag is
okay
so i will hit my timer uh when my bags
hit the press uh and i usually do a 30
minute warm-up again or minutes jesus
christ 30 second warm-up 30 seconds
again so you've just put 20 grams of
millions of little beach balls with
filled with oil into a bag right and now
we're gonna put that bag and we're gonna
we're gonna extract the oil that's in
all these million little beach balls
right
but i don't want to extract the cuticles
of the beach balls i want them to melt
and then to give me the oil right i
don't want when i press out of the bag i
want oil to come out of the bag not hash
so i i allow it to melt for that 30
seconds and i very slowly and very
methodically very system
systemically that's not the word i want
to use but systematically systematically
thank you um it increase the pressure
uh and that's why man so i do give
classes
because this gets very detailed quickly
tell us how we can find those people
want to know um pedro's grow room uh
patreon gmail.com or go to uh
so trying to do that so you get a hold
of me um there's a big difference
between uh um
pressure at the gauge
pressure at the plates and pressure at
the bag
um
so let's just use ryan's here for
example for a seven ton right seventh
the ton if you're if if you're pressing
at full pressure seven ton is fourteen
thousand pounds right and now fourteen
thousand pounds
i i think we all understand that if i
come up to you and with an open palm in
your chest and push
it's probably not going to do much right
it's going to push you back right but if
i walk up to you with a really sharp
stick and stick it right in your chest
and push with that same pressure
things are going to happen right so
there's a difference in pressure over a
square over over your your uh your
square for your square inches
so let's just go with that two by four
and a half inch bag right by the time i
i fold it over and everything is maybe
two by four inches
eight square inches okay
fourteen thousand pounds
divided by eight
is where we're at right so what are you
about that's about two thousand pounds
yeah we'll go close enough you know okay
roughly 18 parts
that's about actually perfect at the bag
that's where right where you want to be
literally right where you want to be
so at the end of your press not
straight into it
butter it down let it when you see the
pressure i said it's feel you really do
got to go slow what do you do especially
when you see the presses on my rosin as
legal [ __ ] they're they're sped up in
four times so they're four times speed
um um but what that allows you to do you
can aside from seeing me over there
pumping it
every time you see it
just know i'm over there
giving it more pressure that's why more
is coming out you know
makes more sense
i don't think i realized that it was
sped up either i don't think i did yeah
there you go they're all four times
man some of those presses uh some of the
latest ones that i've been doing when i
waterfall them on top of each other uh
each press
you know from into the plates to set up
for my next press is four minutes
so if i've done if you see me doing 10
15 presses on one piece of parchment
do the math i've had that camera sitting
there recording that entire time and and
putting that together
i've i've realized now that people are
going to have to straight up ruin a few
batches of presses a few presses yes how
many how many do you think they're going
to ruin before they uh actually get and
do washes
and a couple of washes okay i didn't
yeah putting that into consumption sad
stories on the washes but isn't that how
you get good at [ __ ] that's how you guys
got to be the people that are on the
show right is by [ __ ] up a bunch of
times oh yeah oh definitely oh my god i
washed fresh frozen in my freaking
bathroom one time
it was a nightmare talk about wasting
[ __ ] product dude oh my god yeah
because by the end it was just
especially when it's flower it was
horrible horrible um yeah the the
variable there is how how soon did you
stop the bleeding and call me for
classes
literally because you will ruin some
[ __ ] it's it's just inevitable yeah i
expected that just like growing up yeah
what's an art you're not going to be
good at it the first time and if you are
then you're not going to be good at the
second and third time and if you're not
passionate you know if you're just in it
for the dabs
wink wink then you know you're probably
not going to want to put through the
effort to sit in the fall or that cold
room for for eight hours and do the work
that it's going to take to require to
get the good rosin and a lot of home
growers really let's let's face it are
really going to probably press flower
yeah probably it's easy you know it's
it's you can buy a press for four or
five hundred bucks decent press and
they're gonna make dabs i will tell you
to not don't expect to be blown away
with by your flower rosin
just expect to get high
for some people to be self-sufficient to
be able to go from there i have i take
great pride still at this point in the
game to grow something from seed and
harvest it and put it in the bong and
take a rip i still go yeah i did that
you did that it's my billion time of
doing it and i still feel like yeah i
did that yep absolutely there's got to
be another feeling once you've taken
that from that flower to that frozen
product to that pressed product and then
put it to the banger that's got to be a
whole other step of of relief and pride
right there yeah absolutely and the only
reason that i say don't be i don't that
you know i don't want to stomp on people
that are pressing flower go ahead and do
it i just don't want you to smoke flower
rosin and be like well this is [ __ ] and
we're pedro's what the [ __ ] were they
after like this is horrible
just know that there's a lot of battery
i just had yeah flower rosin is the
bottom of absolutely maybe not the
bottom of the bucket but it's towards
the bottom of the bucket of rosin and
unfortunately that's why for a couple of
years i had a literally a bad taste for
rosin in my mouth because i was being
given uh probably flower rosin that was
probably too hot and then uh you started
coming around a little more you live far
from me we're in colorado but we are
hours and hours it is like four and a
half hours it's crazy yeah so we meet up
in denver and then you change my opinion
and then green dot green dot doesn't pay
me they don't even give me any discounts
green dots started putting out rosin
that really blew my mind and that's good
same color same texture as yours so i
had to buy some and i approve i'll buy
more when they have it but it always
sells out you rosin nerds but how do you
know it's there already how do they the
rosin nerds are like following around
the delivery guy they're like stopping
they pay attention um just like i hope
they pay attention when i make my rosin
come to the market the first time uh
yeah they pay attention
that's it they've been watching
there is no good rosin here that's
that's why i make it there's nothing
here man it's it's it's rough up here
our selection is very minimal uh like i
said we're a very new legal state so our
surrounding states it's the quality is
very rough and if you find anything
decent you are paying very big money for
it
i wasn't going to bring it up on purpose
but big shout out to new york for uh
recently legalizing i know you're up
there in upstate new york uh big up for
joining the team legalization sure
absolutely that should make your your
work a little bit easier going to get uh
parts and supplies definitely not as
much of a sketch yeah absolutely
hopefully a career change someday too
i'd love to see you running a facility
doing pedro's job pretty soon oh it's
crazy man it's it's
i i always have to remind myself that
it's
it's not even a dream come true it's
monumentally more than a dream come true
i i you almost can't put into words dude
when i go
this [ __ ] was illegal when i was growing
up yeah and i'm now getting paid to
extract
concentrate it's mind-boggling dude i
i never want to ever i hope to god i
never take it for granted i hope you got
into particular granted i'm working no
longer working i'm so dead and and
beyond exhausted but i hope to god i
never take it for granted i'm right
there with you brother so uh you remind
me i'll do my best to remind you
beautiful we'll do we'll do for sure all
right guys we've been going for close to
an hour i think we've covered most of
the things i had written down i do have
one question i think you guys can answer
it quite quickly i did ask for uh
questions from the viewers this person
just said what is with the foam that
forms when making bubble hash why does
it increase with each run i find that i
have to stop and change the water and
material after 25 minutes
and then it says after my fourth run he
says i would sometimes i feel like a
fifth run would be worth it but with the
all the foam i just say [ __ ] it he does
have a lot more to the question but any
idea why the foam guys surfectants
surfactants yep surfactants uh very
potentially spraying in flour
um dust dirt dander anything like that
um any oils
can all be leading towards uh towards
foaminess in the wash over agitation can
be leading towards foaminess in the
water that sounds that's what i was
gonna say beating the crap out of it
sounds like very possible when he's
talking about forts and fish fourth and
fifth washes i would immediately start
firing questions back to him asking how
long he's agitating what he's agitating
in how much volume he's putting in his
if he's using mechanical washers and
only filling up halfway it's a way over
agitation like there's a lot of missing
variables here but in the most instance
it's either over agitation or
surfactants so
i'm sure that's one of our agreements
that you guys gave a lot of info on that
i'm sure he'll he'll find an answer to
that and dude if we didn't answer your
question properly send me a follow-up
question all i've got to do is text
pedro yes i'll get the answer absolutely
these guys are great they're on my team
they're really close good resources um
all right gentlemen i think we've
covered a pretty good podcast do you
have any things that you would like to
add here at the end that i didn't ask or
that you just want to put out to the
universe
big cheesy grin from pedro yeah i i mean
[Laughter]
i i hope people people find some value
in the concentrates um i hope people see
the see the passion um and understand
the pricing a little bit more like you
just said that you do and it's worth the
work it really is it's worth the work
and you know if you enjoy quality
concentrate it's worth the work yeah and
and me with the
the headiness if you will the new the
new term the headiness um to me
it all kind of goes hand in hand right
like i want if i'm smoking out of what i
consider one of the best glass pieces i
want the best concentrate to go through
it you know so i hope there's just an
appreciation and an understanding um and
and and and i guess another thing is is
it is achievable it is achievable by
everyone uh it's not something that's
out of the realm and it's safe to make
you guys there's no there's no boom boom
that's the best part absolutely get out
there and mess up a few batches you guys
don't be afraid you've got to mess up a
lot to get to the level that these
concentrate makers are at you've got to
mess up a lot to get good at anything in
life if you keep doing anything and you
don't make a few mistakes you're going
to get a big ego then you're going to
find a bigger problem so make mistakes
in the beginning get humbled get
corrected and then most importantly
reach out to pedro for concentrate for
uh extract for concentrate making
classes for sure for sure all right ryan
any final moments any final thoughts
from ryan i'm gonna give you a jerry
springer a moment here
not too much uh like like i said i mean
i guess
cold cold cold don't don't over agitate
uh really pay attention to what you're
making and uh just enjoy it guys uh do
it at home it's safe that's i think the
bottom line is enjoy it and it's safe
that seems to be the most important part
that came from both you guys enjoy it
enjoy what we are doing you guys this
isn't supposed to be a headache uh the
headaches that do come from it should be
learning lessons so enjoy it all right
gentlemen i want to thank you guys once
again for hanging out on the grow from
your heart podcast maybe we'll have you
back thanks for doing episode 710 um
don't sign off but i'm going to wrap up
the podcast here and then we're going to
[ __ ] and take dabs after this oh
yeah so i'm going to do a wrap up here
we go all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers new concentrate makers thank
you for watching another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me all those questions
updates positive feedback constructive
criticism i look forward to it also hit
the patreon at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart any other uh info
you need is at
iregenetics.com that's all i've got for
you i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content let's give a big
shout out to my buddy taskrock and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Applause]
[Music]
you