[Music]
yeah here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 711
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
munchies before we get to that part of
the show let's do a few shout outs to a
few of the great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to a long
time supporter a good friend and a great
tester my buddy mobius grows let's send
a big thank you shout out to luke i want
to send a big thank you shout out to
curbside gardens let's send a big fist
bump and a thank you shout out to
another great friend girls grow 2. let's
send a thank you shout out to 716 grows
and single t let's send a fist bump and
a thank you shout out to my buddy from
discord danny potts let's send a thank
you shout out to pack northwest den and
levity love day i want to send a big
thank you shout out to paparoni then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to ivan m
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make that
nice and easy for all of my friends all
right let's not waste too much time the
last couple of episodes were quite
intensive episodes uh 709 was all about
the evolution of dabs and dabbing and
concentrates then of course we had pedro
and roz and ryan on for episode 710 we
learned a lot this episode we're going
to relax we're going to cool down a
little bit we're going to have a good
time we're going to talk about something
we all enjoy something we all indulge in
something that may be a little bit of a
personal weakness maybe a point where we
spoil ourselves and treat ourselves
today we're going to talk about munchies
what's better than having some munchies
after you smoke honestly this may be a
weird side note and this may derail the
whole show here but
i like to get super baked and not eat i
like to fight those munchies sometimes i
feel like those munchies you get super
baked you take a few fat dabs and then
you start eating cookies and the next
thing you know not even stone anymore
you got to eat more cookies or you eat a
bunch you take a bunch of dabs and you
go to out to dinner and halfway through
dinner you're like oh i just ruined my
whole buzz don't get me wrong i love to
go to dinner go to thai food order two
entrees super blazed and eat them both i
digress i'm just saying sometimes i like
to fight off those munchies i don't
always go right for it like to fight
that hunger enjoy the buzz however when
i do let those munchies take over
sometimes they win if i let those
munchies kick in i will eat everything
so let's talk about munchies let's talk
about this what do you like to eat once
you are stoned once you've had however
you like to smoke you took a few bong
rips smoked a fat joint maybe you took
too many dabs maybe you ate some edibles
which is something else we're going to
talk about here in the episode what do
you enjoy to eat
i often talk about trying to take care
of myself i try to be
it's 2022 we've learned how to take care
of ourselves we should be treating our
bodies like our temples i'm not super
young anymore i'm in my 40s i'm starting
to get older i do feel it when i eat
junk food when i eat unhealthy crap my
body does say hey bro don't eat as much
of that or don't eat that again my body
does have ways of letting us know as you
get older pay attention your body will
tell you that is terrible for me stop
[ __ ] doing that there are a lot of
things we put in our bodies we shouldn't
be when i get blazed and i do get the
munchies i try to stick with healthy
food however sometimes i will allow
myself i'm human don't get me wrong i
try to eat healthy most of the time uh
vegetarian 100 of the time vegan uh most
of the time i do at least one vegan day
every week you guys don't care about my
diet i try to take care of myself when i
get blazed i will allow myself to slip
on the diet have some crap occasionally
especially in the car if i'm on a road
trip um and i have to say if i'm the
passenger on a road trip just you know
for legal and safety reasons and i do
get blazed and we stop at the gas
station or somewhere small like that to
get some munchies i definitely will
use that as a good excuse to indulge in
some crap food we'll talk about what i
get from the gas stations in a moment
here
i do prefer honestly to stick with
healthier snack options if that's
possible
available affordable effective if i
prepared properly and also if that's
what my high mouth wants sometimes my
stoned mouth wants something sugary and
terrible for me sometimes i'll treat
myself also i smoke a lot and i do
podcasts i constantly [ __ ] talk i
never stop talking i get it i do know
that about myself i apologize if you're
sick of hearing me but that also brings
in a lot of dryness a lot of dry throat
a lot of dry mouth so i need snacks i
prefer snacks that are juicy and not uh
dehydrating and drying something
people hate the word moist but guess
what i need a nice moist snack something
with some moisture
not something that's going to induce
more cottonmouth more dryness more
phlegm i try to stay away from crackers
like i definitely don't want a cracker
i definitely don't need dairy products
it's going to make me sound all
in the throat i don't need sorry for
doing that that was [ __ ] rude i don't
eat all that kind of snack so i try to
stick with like healthy stuff what is
healthy stuff fruit a lot of people
think that fruit is uh it's kind of a
hippie snack it's great it's what i was
put here for it's got enough sugar to
keep you going it's give you some energy
it's got all the right components to
make that sugar not unhealthy it's got
fiber and vitamins in there depending on
the fruit or vegetables you choose but
fruits and vegetables are great for when
you're blazed uh what's better than
biting into like a juicy orange think
about how good that is we have forgotten
we go to the store and we get all that
[ __ ] on the shelves it's packaged and
processed we forgot how good a [ __ ]
orange is bite into an orange a
nectarine a clementine something like
that let that juice run down your chin a
little bit let it absorb into your
tongue feel how good that [ __ ] is we
forgot how good basic fruit is so when i
get blazed i like fruit watermelon
strawberries stuff like that that's
delicious
if it's available like i said sometimes
you don't prepare sometimes you're not
where that stuff is sometimes you hit
the gas station and you just eat crap
that is when i allow myself to eat crap
um i did i'm going somewhere with all of
this i did post a question to instagram
to twitter i also posted it to my
discord that link is in the show notes
and video description but i asked a lot
of my friends what they like to eat and
consume once they get blaze that's where
i'm leading with all this we're going to
read the responses to those surveys i'm
just rambling to set it up real good
here
i asked about um do you allow yourself
to eat crap or do you prefer to eat
healthy snacks once you get blazed i
also asked uh do you have road trip
snacks that you let yourself eat then
also i asked about regional snacks
because i live in colorado uh here in
the summer we have a chili festival so
chili's are kind of our regional thing
i'm sure there's other regional stuff
i'm not thinking about but chili's are
kind of our regional snack depending on
where you go people are known and areas
are known for their snacks here we have
cantaloupes we have a lot of cantaloupes
in our area
the rocky ford cantaloupes are super
delicious
things like that regional stuff then we
talk about seasonal stuff are there
seasonal snacks that you enjoy
i've got a dear friend somebody i care
about a lot who loves a peppermint
cheesecake and we have past the holiday
season and she is going to go crazy
until december because we can't get a
peppermint cheesecake that's a a
seasonal snack she wishes she could have
how about some fast food do you guys
indulge in fast food when you get the
munchies i really try not to eat fast
food i've talked about how healthy i try
to be honestly if the time is right if
we're on the road if i'm blazed if
things come down to it i grew up in
southern california and there's nothing
like some taco bell just a couple of
bean burritos from taco bell don't tell
me what's in there don't talk about it
just let me enjoy that [ __ ] with a bunch
of hot sauce and just let me enjoy it
when i'm blazed that's one of my
weaknesses one of my guilty pleasures if
you will hashtag soccer souffle
um i guess it is time to share some
feedback i also like some chipotle too
give me nice and blaze then let me eat
some chipotle that's always fun but then
don't be around in like an hour i guess
now is a good time to start sharing the
feedback that i have collected i've got
a lot of screenshots here i basically
asked what do you like to much when you
get blazed let's jump into the
screenshots the feedback part of the
show uh this one came from our buddy
onezilla on twitter it said my favorite
fast food is bojangles for awake and
bake a cookout for late night munchies
my seasonal snacks would have to be the
peppermint pretzels i love that another
peppermint person uh peppermint's not
for me but i have a deer person that
loves the peppermint cheesecake so i get
you seasonal and peppermint i'm trying
to figure out where to put the mic and
my phone at the same time if you're
watching the weird
uh posture struggle here that is what's
happening ah here we go more comments
let's fix this [ __ ] mic standing
regroup here all right uh the next one
says i love uh this person must be
canadian big shout out to my buddy b
bala says i love poutine when i'm stoned
i live in canada my favorite fast food
when stoned is dairy queen i'm always
getting a pineapple mango smoothie for
the bots it's for the pasties i'm not
sure what you mean by pasties but um oh
maybe you mean pasty mouth the
cottonmouth that could be the canadian
version of cottonmouth there's the
pasties i got you bro you got the pasty
face truck mouth cottonmouth i get you i
wish i could have eggnog ice cream all
year round i'm all about a pineapple
mango smoothie that sounds [ __ ] great
uh when you start [ __ ] with that
eggnog bro i'm out dude that that just
uh i'm not against your eggnog but to me
it tastes like snot or similar and i am
not in dude i'm checking out at the
eggnog you enjoy it buddy i don't want
any that means you get more are you
spiking the eggnog that's what i want
are you whipping some booze into that
bad [ __ ] uh sprinkling it with whatever
you put on top of eggnog i've seen
people sprinkle [ __ ] on it is it warm is
it cold i don't know about your eggnog
buddy you're canadian you could be doing
some crazy weird [ __ ] uh big up to uh
norm if you're eating poutine and you
don't know who norm is
you're missing out on live
ymh we've got more feedback this one
came from discord
this one is from our friend
reaper6628 it says i love to sit down
and munch down on chips and salsa then
i'll finish it off with some sweet ice
cream and pie but sometimes i love to
munch down on fruit i'm seeing a thing
here a lot of people all the potheads
all the stoners need some sort of food
with some sort of refreshing moisture in
it that ice cream that fruit i'm getting
that i catch that a lot uh what else is
another thing that i noticed oh
something i caught in this pie um i was
in a group conversation the other day
and i've always said that pi is for old
people and a couple of people just said
randomly pies for old people so some
people supported my statement pies for
old people bro that's just a joke don't
get offended we're going to keep moving
um it says uh from mary j wanis says my
favorite munchie to eat when i'm high is
probably apples and peanut butter that
sounds [ __ ] great dude uh apple's fat
crispiness that juiciness and then
peanut butter just to give you some
protein and some texture in there don't
have me do a podcast after that but that
sounds great
favorite fast food is dunkin donuts i
absolutely love their bagels smothered
in cream cheese that sounds pretty nice
uh again we've got that coldness from
the cream cheese that is a trend here
amongst the stoners we gotta have
something cold and delicious in our
snacks
however i do crave twizzlers every so
often and beef jerky has to be peppered
of the beef jerky that has to be
peppered all this talk about munchies is
giving me the munchies yeah i'm sure
there are several people right now that
are pulling over the car uh stopping to
get some snacks on the way to work
because we're [ __ ] up their day sorry
guys i love you
uh be nice to the people in 7 11 early
in the morning get it the 7-eleven show
have you caught on yet 7-eleven talking
about munchies big cheers let's keep
going this one comes from my good friend
billy podunk what's up you bad
[ __ ] hope things are great by
the time you hear this uh it says my
favorites are something crunchy and
savory i understand that bro i'm in that
same boat uh garlic and parmesan
anything
those boulder chips the parmesan boulder
chips those are [ __ ] delicious uh
crunchy savory that's my sort of stuff
it does go on to say i do also like some
healthy snacks one of my favorites is
veggies and that hidden valley ranch dry
mix with the sour cream this dude's got
a specific
dressing that he loves it says i
definitely eat way too much food when i
get stoned there's no stopping me i know
that feeling bro i know that feeling he
said for regional snacks uh of course
billy is in alaska he's in a beautiful
region of alaska i've seen where he
lives up there it says for regional
snacks smoked salmon bellies are one of
my top choices we don't really have fast
food where i am
cheers let's get stoned and eat way too
much food cheers billy podunk thank you
for the great feedback also bro thank
you for the great friendship um we've
become really good friends over the
discord over social media over a short
period of time got nothing but love and
respect for that dude billy podunk so
that's a good dude thank you for the
feedback bro
uh pay attention that dude's gonna be
doing a lot of [ __ ] in the future
then we move our way through the discord
we get some feedback from a guy known as
graybeard i owe a big shout out to my
buddy greybeard he built the discord
that's right if you were on the discord
server you a greybeard a fist bump a
high five a shout out maybe a little
kiss on the cheek however you want to do
it great kid good dude giant hog he
built the discord server and his comment
says candy is my weakness sour gummy
candy to be specific i like savory to
salty to sweet if i could have all three
um sour gummy candies and then savory
salty and sweet so i'm not a fan of the
gummy candy sort of stuff i don't like
digging that candy [ __ ] out of my teeth
i'm not into that kind of stuff but
salty and savory hell yeah bro and sweet
there's a chex mix that will fall right
into that it's like salted honey
something chex mix bro that is salty
sweet crunchy savory it's all of the
above
that one will definitely uh scratch that
itch if you will then he says i hate
spending money on drinks i drink water
and i love crunchy but not much of a
cake guy i get that
i do really enjoy being a stoner being a
talker i love drinks we're going to talk
about the things i love in a little bit
but i do spend a lot of money on
delicious drinks perhaps that's why i
stay
i'm a skinny dude i'm 6'5 and
under 200 pounds because i don't eat a
lot of junk i think most of my snacks
are drinks which means i get to just pee
out most of it then he goes on to say
crunchy but not much of a cake guy
sometimes bro
birthday cake cupcakes the cupcakes with
[ __ ] sprinkles on them at a gas
station that is one of my weaknesses oh
yeah uh healthy snacks usually peanuts
or almonds dude i love
pistachios especially the pistachios
that have been uh cracked already and
they're coated in the top the roasted
thai chili seasoning oh man i'll eat the
whole bag like the whole bag
uh it says
also some kind of fruit or almonds or
peanuts i eat crap food when i get
stoned when not stoned something i'm
trying to get better at oh let's see i
eat crap stoned oh he eats crap when he
is stoned and not stoned i get it bro we
live in america where they feed us and
offer us all of this [ __ ] that we should
not be eating and something you will
notice this is a weird political rant
i'm not going to go too far on uh the
cheaper the food the worse it is for you
like the worst [ __ ] is more affordable
until you learn how to shop and eat like
vegetarian shopping is cheap once you've
figured out fruits and vegetables and
things to sustain rice is cheap but yeah
they make they really make it seem
expensive to take care of yourself
let's stay on track japanese and south
korean candy is the best candy in the
world yes one of my notes later is
exotic terps
cheetos used to come out with the
cinnamon sugar puffs during christmas to
eat a whole bag of those in one sitting
i haven't ever seen those bro but ah
that sounds like a great idea that makes
me think of the taco bell uh the [ __ ]
cinnamon twisted taco bell probably
similar but better then he said subs
jersey mike's jimmy john's penn station
i love subs bro um not to be a hater but
i'm a vegetarian and jersey mike's ah
just [ __ ] sucks there's i can eat
grease and cheese that's basically what
i get offered in there would you like a
grease and cheese sandwich and i'm like
i'm gonna hard pass on that [ __ ] i can
go get diarrhea somewhere else but i get
it if you're into subs uh if you want to
be shaggy and scooby about your life you
go ahead and do your thing and enjoy it
um it does go on there is more from my
soil guy
you guys i do have a lot of feedback so
we're going to get through these kind of
quickly because i feel i realize i am
taking a long time uh it says my
favorite fast food when i'm stoned is
the one someone got for me uh against my
wishes uh but because i can't think of
any fast food i like it's there and it
fits me so this person basically my soil
guy friend here uh this dude is
indecisive refuses to think just wants
food delivered and since he's knows he's
so indecisive you shut the [ __ ] up and
eat what is delivered i can appreciate
that bro you'll take whatever i'm having
i'll just order two and pass you one and
hopefully you like it that's easy enough
for me bro that's adventurous uh you may
end up with some [ __ ] you don't want
this one i was waiting to run into a
note like this a reply like this because
it says
there was this sour tangerine homemade
weed gummy that someone gave me once i
should never be allowed around those
when i'm high
it says they were so good i would
probably never come down so i guess sour
sweets infused foods fried snacks dude
fried [ __ ] is good you could deep fry
anything and i might eat it um stacking
different flavors of pringles that's
magical right there dude uh spicy
jalapeno barbecue ranch or whatever most
asian food boogers but i said boogers
and it says burgers uh if you eat your
boogers i'm down but please don't invite
me um sushi dim sum soda bro you'd eat
just about [ __ ] everything hard cider
pasta carbs comfort food this guy is
down to eat everything oh maybe this is
not a guy this could be a galler called
arya sin
era sin i can't read and i uh i
apologize for uh assuming your gender
it's 2022 i should have known better i
do see the rainbows
and the icon i'm confused uh it says
there is nothing seasonal that i won't
make any time of the year if i want it i
do appreciate that the thing i wanted to
talk about is those damn edibles uh i do
the same thing i'll have some delicious
edibles there's a company called koda
that makes chocolates they're way
overpriced but they're
decadent medicated chocolates i also
have some peanut butter cookies over
there that will [ __ ] ruin your life
um you eat these coated chocolates and
you're like that was really good i don't
feel high i'm gonna eat more of those
chocolates and then guess what you're
[ __ ] up but the chocolates are so good
you just keep eating more of them
shout out to my friend karen uh karen
passed away a couple of years ago love
you karen rest in peace karen would made
uh would make fudge and carrot cake that
you could not get enough of they would
have to put electrodes around it because
i would constantly be reaching into the
fudge and taking little bites of it and
i would forget that it was medicated and
by halfway through the day my eyes would
be so heavy that i couldn't function i
would have the munchies and a lot like
our friend here i would keep reaching in
and going back for more of that
medicated fudge i would just be goofy by
the end of the day things would be hard
to handle uh but i worked at a
dispensary where the owner made
medicated fudge and encouraged me to eat
it so it's her fault love you karen
sorry for uh being so high at work all
the time it was your fault dude all
right let's keep going i thought that's
funny though when you get high and keep
eating the edibles and you keep getting
higher and you keep eating the edibles
and you're like what's going on here man
you fall into that loop i love it the
the weed edible matrix all right we do
have another one that came from snazzy
sneakers big up to our friend snazzy
sneakers that last message came from era
sin i apologize for assuming your gender
ah big up much respect you can correct
me politely let me know who i'm talking
to if you care
it goes on it says uh from snazzy my
wife's cookies dunked in a hot cup of
coffee is going to give me diabetes but
i will do it with a smile on my face bro
isn't that how it is sometimes snacks
are so good you're like yeah taking
[ __ ] six weeks off my life with every
cookie but guess what i don't want to
get old anyway
then it goes on it says uh sweet and
spicy pickles are probably the only
thing resembling healthy food that i
reach for when i'm high that's such a
good debate is a pickle a spicy snack
who cares it's so good and we're back to
the trend cold and refreshing i noticed
the potheads like a cold and refreshing
snack all of that cold and refreshing
snack talk makes me need to hit a drink
of this cold and refreshing kombucha
here we'll talk about that in a minute
i'm gonna take a drink not edit this you
guys hang out drink something while i'm
doing it
i really love the feeling of
carbonation going down the throat when
i'm good and blazed
i feel like what's that soap with the
scrubbing bubbles i feel like it just
gets in there knocks out the uh what do
you call it earlier the pasties just
gets in there and scrubs out the pasties
the cottonmouth
nothing like some good kombucha bubbles
uh i was i used to be an avid dr pepper
addict uh i would drink a ridiculous and
embarrassingly gross amount of dr pepper
every day i was doing a uh
kind of a battle how high can i get now
i need to battle it out or even it out
with caffeine and now i'm too
caffeinated let's dab more now let's
drink more caffeine and by the end of
the day i'd be [ __ ] anxious and shaky
and i called it blown out my mind
couldn't [ __ ] focus i couldn't make
eye contact with anybody because i was
so high and so caffeinated that i wasn't
either one and my body was just fried
i haven't had caffeine and dr pepper uh
and probably two and a half nearly three
years i think if i've got my time right
something i've noticed is in that time
period my thoughts are more clear i have
less anxiety my panic attacks are uh
almost gone much less frequent
so that high fructose corn syrup is a
high fructose corn syrup i apologize for
that i got high fructose corn syrup and
the caffeine in there i'm just
exaggerating now we're definitely
[ __ ] up my mental well-being my body
my physical i feel better i've got more
energy with less caffeine um now i'm
just talking about weird health tips
with ross to jeff but that is something
i definitely noticed
so if you're eating like crap and not
taking care of yourself
it could definitely help you feel better
just to make a few minor adjustments
just take out some of the crap you don't
even have to add anything you don't have
to do anything just take out some of the
crap replace the dr pepper with a bottle
of water something like that all right
let's get back onto it that's enough
preaching you didn't come here for the
preachy [ __ ] you came here for the the
munchie talk our friend snazzy also says
bacon wrapped cream cheese stuffed
jalapenos
that's a hell of a snack right there bro
that's uh i don't eat the bacon part
but that sounds good it says there's
this snow cone and frozen custard place
down the street from me where i used to
live called s j's that has the best god
damn concrete sundays i could smash all
day
it sounds like you fell in love bro
uh what's in there i might try one it
goes on it says those strawberry hard
candies with the chewy center that are
always in grammy's candy jar dude i know
exactly what you're talking about i talk
about that that's what strawberry
starburst smells like those candies are
delicious that gooey texture in the
middle oh yeah now that i'm getting
older i can't eat [ __ ] like that i feel
like those candies are actively trying
to pull out my teeth as i'm eating them
so i don't need that kind of [ __ ] but ah
yeah then he said uh plain ass ice water
is my drink of choice but i understand
that i try to drink a lot of water uh
water is super refreshing uh for a guy
that talks so much i definitely need a
lot of water a lot of voice lubrication
i understand that so big up on a lot of
water you guys drink a lot of water you
will feel better your brain will
function your body will function better
water is good for you and there it is
again that cold refreshing snack for the
potheads all right
these next few replies i'm gonna burn
through it says responses these are from
uh from instagram i did post the same
question what do you like to eat when
you're blazed on instagram i'm quickly
gonna go through a lot of these i may
skip some then we're going to talk a
little bit about what i like i feel like
this episode has gotten longer than i
had anticipated and preferred not a big
deal you guys like the long shows
um what do i have up here that i want to
make sure not to miss oh before we go
that far let me miss this let me cover
this last note so i can scroll uh
something i've noticed is super popular
um and this is just a side random branch
here i have uh i've been frequenting
sneaker shops i go to a lot of sneaker
stores i buy a lot of hoodies and
sneakers it's just something i enjoy
while i'm there i notice that all of
them have a small section of what
they're calling exotic snacks they've
got a little refrigerator with a bunch
of crazy looking sodas and drinks and
exotic snacks is exactly what it is
exotic terps
there are like cheetos and doritos and
lace chips from other countries with
crazy exotic foreign flavors we've never
experienced ah there are candies cookies
um what did i try the other day it was a
fago rocket popsicle soda
it gave me the most tremendous burps and
i haven't had anything with that much
flavor in it in a long long time but
that [ __ ] was tremendously delicious so
this exotic imported chinese candy
chinese terps thing seems to be really
popular right now and at the sneaker
shops i frequent they're charging like
18 to 25 for a bottle of beverages that
is the size of this water bottle just a
normal maybe a little bigger you know
it's your uh 16 maybe a 24 ounce soda
bottle for 18 or 24
they got some doritos in there that
flavors i've never seen before uh
flavors that are summer i buy some of
them and try them out sometimes my
friends own the shop in a couple of
locations so uh we'll all just throw
down a couple of bucks for a bag and
we'll open it up and i'll just try a
couple of doritos some of them are
amazing there's one with tacos it's got
i think it's chinese writing i really am
not sure it looks chinese to me
um and it's some kind of doritos and
they've got a taco on the picture it's
taco flavored doritos right but not the
taco we get here
uh this one tasted like i was like
crunch and i was like okay it tastes
like a taco then i was like nah bro
there's beef in there and i kept chewing
up the dorito and i was like there's the
lettuce
and there's the cheese and there's the
salsa and there's a little bit of
cilantro coming in right now like i
tasted every component of a taco in
these [ __ ] doritos so these exotic
terps are getting real popular it's
really fun i like just i'll buy a couple
of random things and have a few bros
over and we'll come take some dabs and
dab out and then like anybody want to
try some [ __ ] chinese doritos we
can't even read what it says on the
label and we'll try it and see what it
tastes like fun times some cookies some
other weird snacks and things with
pokemon on the label i had no idea what
they were but they were delicious anyway
that [ __ ] is super popular now that i've
rambled about that part let's get into
these instagram responses our friend not
thrilled said fruit i like to taste the
life contained in it i'm not sure if
that is beautiful or um if you're psycho
either way i like it
my buddy lobster bush said i like to eat
cereal and we're noticing both of those
trends something refreshing and moist
for the pothead mouth uh my friend look
at that pink mustang said i like to eat
the blood of my enemies yeah i knew you
were twisted hashtag go fast ah big lose
420 crew said the nemo brand carrot cake
and 7-eleven brand orange pineapple
juice that's an interesting mix carrot
cake and pineapple juice
i'm in let's do it uh gramps420 said
anything sweet we got a tater tots with
salsa and queso bro that's a unique
reply i like that a lot now with some
[ __ ] tater tots dude uh we got a bowl
of cap and crunch that sounds great but
go slowly don't [ __ ] up your mouth or do
you let it get soggy uh chips in queso
but i'm not in texas anymore and nora
cal has been sleeping on this delicacy
for far too long bro if you can't make
chips at queso you're sleeping
uh we got a torchies as one reply uh man
that makes me think of my daughter my
daughter will eat all of the takis you
got some takis she'll eat those up
lately it's got to be green olives
stuffed with garlic cloves that's a good
snack but that's something that would be
very limited how many of those can you
eat
them i know what you're talking about
them big green olives with a nice garlic
clove in the middle two or three of
those and i'm done dude that's enough ah
fried plantains [ __ ] yeah let's get it
we got a pb and j here is magic i'm
gonna give you
the tip of a lifetime i've given a lot
of free advice on this show i've said a
lot of great things i've improved
people's gardens and their lives of
their incomes here's the thing that is
going to make the most impact in
everybody's life ever the next time you
make that peanut butter and jelly
sandwich
get some some butter right just regular
old butter butter the outside of both
sides of that sandwich you got bread
bread peanut butter jelly in the middle
right now you got butter on the outside
both sides is buttered up now heat up
your pan just like you're gonna make you
a grilled cheese sandwich but put that
peanut butter and jelly sandwich in the
pan and pan fry that [ __ ]
grilled peanut butter and jelly sandwich
will change your life that's right
oh that jelly and the peanut butter
mixes in together and that bread gets
all nice and toasty oh my goodness
change your [ __ ] life you guys all
right now let's keep moving go do it i
promise you and then send me messages
about it let me know what you think
don't burn yourself that shit's gonna be
so good it's gonna be hot and sticky in
the middle let it cool down a little bit
before you dig in don't burn yourself
don't message me about that
uh we got trying not to burn the house
down while making quesadillas big shout
out to my buddy stone trout bum we got a
red pepper and hummus with quinoa and
chia seed grain chips um yeah bro i'm
coming over uh invite me that is right
up my high healthy alley
somebody said at 7 11 the question
wasn't necessarily from 7-11 but that's
a good answer i will accept your answer
it said cheesecake the turtle cheesecake
specifically i open it
inside down because the dome becomes a
bowl so we've got a genius here
i like some cheesecake i'm a little bit
uh my body doesn't like all the dairy
products it's not so bad for me it's
more for the people that have to be
around me an hour later after i consume
dairy products i'm used to it but i
apologize for torturing you ah but
cheesecake is [ __ ] great dude i can't
eat a lot of it but cheesecake
cheesecake cheesecake is marvelously
delicious i've got one here i'm gonna
take a screenshot of we're gonna save
that because we got that response a lot
we're just gonna delay that one and read
that last gonna move forward we do have
another screen worth of responses cheeto
puffs that's a great answer i like cool
ranch doritos over cheeto puffs but i
feel you uh chips and french onion dip i
would crush it every night if i didn't
care about my health i hear you bro
uh nerds rope bites
also love uh mountain olive
pepperoncinis that is a [ __ ] wide
variety there bro nerd ropes are so
sweet they make my teeth hurt i cannot
eat that [ __ ] i'm not into like smarties
nerd ropes nerds that crunchy kind of
candy no thank you that's not for me uh
my buddy love for the plant big up love
for the plant he said buenos i'm not
sure what those are sounds great uh we
got a takis we got popcorn we got
chocolate we got gardetos bro when i was
in high school
i don't know if we got in trouble or if
the teachers were pissed off they were
all eating snacks in class but they took
all the good [ __ ] out of the snack
machines we were left with like gardenos
and [ __ ] but those gardetos this person
said the mustard uh the mustard pretzels
and rye chips bro hell yeah that used to
keep me through the morning and i had an
astronomy class early in the morning at
south high school in pueblo uh those
gardetos would keep me the [ __ ] alive we
got a chips with salsa and hot sauce bro
we got a pizza rolls why did it take so
long to get to the answer pizza rolls
[ __ ] yeah shout out to totino's for the
pizza rolls and those pizzas but also
totino's what's up with those pizzas
getting [ __ ] smaller and smaller
every weekend dude i'm on to you
[ __ ] make those pizzas big again
i know they're four for a dollar or some
[ __ ] like that they're cheap as [ __ ] but
dude come on it's it's insulting that
you're making them smaller every weekend
acting like i'm not gonna notice what
the [ __ ] is that
um
cereal three bowls minimum
all right bro uh we got a pizza cold
pizza or warm pizza that's what i want
to know uh we got organic pizza and ice
cream once again we're getting that
refreshing fried chicken fingers and
honey mustard i'm down with that salt
and vinegar chips and kombucha
i'm gonna get you some breath mints my
dude ah we got a kale chips or vegan
jerky that sounds tasty blue corn chips
and mango habanero salsa that sounds
good uh white chocolate kitkats that
sounds nice watermelon simply i don't
know what that is but anything
watermelon is delicious uh or homemade
cookies dude my mama make some chocolate
chip cookies around christmas time that
are [ __ ] divine they smell up the
whole neighborhood people are knocking
on the door probably some cheddar
jalapeno cheetos that sounds interesting
we got another pizza iced oatmeal
cookies uh crunchy anything somebody
replied with you well thank you i'm glad
to know that i would be your favorite
snack when you're blazed
that's not awkward at all um then we got
crunchy anything
chicken and biscuit crackers that's
pretty interesting uh dunking chocolate
chip cookies into nacho i hope you're
trolling me but let's read this just in
case let's see what this person is doing
let's try to imagine this
dunking chocolate chip cookies and nacho
cheese or brown gravy
chocolate chip cookies and i hope you're
trolling me we're going to scroll on
because now i'm going to throw up all
right that does wrap up the responses
portion you guys i got one answer so
many times i'm not even sure how i feel
about it i have to be 100 honest i
expected it but i did not expect it um
as many times and from some of the
people i got it from you guys are creeps
and i love you for it and
i quietly agree with you but i got a lot
of answers where people said their
favorite thing to eat after they got
blazed was their girl's box uh big up
for being a good boyfriend good big up
for being a good dude also big up for
being an open pervert i appreciate it
and i love you for it team box eater
also sounds so weird when you say eating
box more than once or twice but enjoy
your snacks ladies and gentlemen now
let's scroll on i do have some more
stuff written down here i'm going to
talk a little bit about what i like to
eat when i'm blazing there we're going
to wrap up this show because it has
gotten much longer than i had
anticipated and prepared for you guys
have heard enough but thank you for
hanging out talking about munchies
i hope you ate a whole bunch of snacks
during this show type in the comments
right now what you have been snacking on
also while you're there click like and
if you haven't already please do
subscribe to the show now let's talk
about it i already mentioned i like
kombucha for the bubbles i talk a lot i
gotta keep the voice fresh i gotta stay
hydrated i gotta keep moving i like
kombucha a lot
people have asked me a lot about
kombucha and advice about kombucha
kombucha is a very acquired taste there
are lots of different varieties flavors
types of kombucha this one i'm showing
to the camera here is kavita brand
nobody pays me i buy kombucha at the
store uh just like everybody else kavita
k-e-v-i-t-a master brew kombucha this is
a ginger flavored one of my favorites i
really enjoy the tart cherry from this
brand
this is what i kind of call gas station
kombucha this isn't real um
real high in probiotics real fermented
flavored this is kind of a kombucha soda
entry level amateur kombucha um if i'm
at the gas station if options are
limited if the stores are low on
inventory these are refreshing they
taste good it's not a soda it's a good
snack it's a good drink for the day i
like the bubbles a lot when i'm blazed
but if you want to be healthy and if
you're drinking kombucha for health
reasons i definitely prefer
gt's brand kombucha they make a lot of
different great kombuchas
there's the raw and unfiltered
this one's organic and unpasteurized a
lot of them say synergy here you'll see
a lot of different words this blue
flavor is one of my favorites they said
it was going to be seasonal
we kind of demanded that it was not
seasonal i think they heard us this one
is called sacred life this one has
without reading i do remember i think
it's got kiwi juice coconut water and
ginger and then all the probiotics from
a kombucha in there
this is more of a
potent fermented pungent sort of a
kombucha this one uh it takes a little
getting used to if you're not into that
if you can drink a good beer if you're
into fermented things you will enjoy
this it may take some getting used to
some adjustment this is more of the
entry level brand
if you try one kombucha and you don't
like it that doesn't mean you don't like
kombuchas every brand does it
differently different flavors dilution
styles some are real bold and like dark
beer kind of flavored some taste like
[ __ ] bum wine and fruit juice there
are a lot of options don't let it turn
you down turn you off also don't force
it if you don't like it you just don't
like it but i really enjoy a good
kombucha after all that talk i'm going
to take a hit of this ginger kombucha
just because i can't resist anymore
oh yeah those good bubbles
good refreshing ginger bite it's got
like a nice bite to it and that
fermented flavor um i got some german
blood in me there's got to be some
norwegian some dutch in me something
like that maybe some scottish i got a
red beard
i don't know exactly i haven't done the
23andme yet but those people uh from
those regions tend to enjoy fermented
type foods so it only makes sense that i
would like a kombucha also i don't drink
because i have a problem um regulating
my alcohol content i have a drink in
years but i love a good dark beer so
it's only likely that i would enjoy a
kombucha
let's move on um what do i like to eat
for snacks bro lately i've been munching
uh pistachios they're healthy i don't
feel like i'm eating [ __ ] they're not
super sugary they're not bad for my
teeth they satiate hunger they give me
energy i'm sure there's like some sort
of nutrient some sort of cellium or
selenium or some something's got to be
good for my hair teeth nails and eyes
and all those pistachios the thai chili
pistachios are divine i can eat the
whole damn however big the bag is i can
eat it all on a drive on a road trip
during a movie let's crunch down on some
pistachios
i like depending on the mood the
environment the situation i really like
spicy snacks if i'm hanging out the lady
watching a movie obviously i'm not going
100 spicy i'm not gonna do the garlic
and oniony type stuff that i would enjoy
if i'm hanging out with the lady if i'm
at the house by myself like there's
nobody here i'm gonna crunch down on
some garlic and parmesan boulder chips
later but i like spicy crunchy savory
sort of snacks or something i mostly go
for something that makes me feel i said
a moment ago full and satiated but not
like a piece of [ __ ] like i'm just
eating useless calories and feeding my
body crap
now with that being said um sometimes if
i'm on the road i've talked about this i
like to get cupcakes and [ __ ] like that
that's my excuse uh just driving from
boulder to pueblo or
denver to pueblo or where i'm wherever i
might be going that weekend coming back
from a concert or something all the
restaurants are closed i didn't plan
ahead uh chiba hut was closed i love
some good chiba hut when i'm blaze shout
out to chiba hut
but if i didn't get some chiba hut if we
missed the opportunity for chiba hut or
fuzzies tacos or something ah that's
when i'm gonna go to the gas station get
some cupcakes or i like to try like
different kind of energy bars and stuff
but those are overpriced and they're
still that's just a candy bar you're
just eating [ __ ] anyway so you'll often
see me get like some cool ranch doritos
maybe some kind of garlicky spicy
crunchy potato chips or something like
that and then i'll grab like a cupcake i
mentioned earlier i like those birthday
cake cupcakes i really like the orange
cupcakes i may sound crazy but the
orange flavored cupcakes are great the
cake is good it's always nice and moist
to get that creamy center and then the
frosting has got like a little just a
texture that i enjoy that's really nice
for me i don't do candy stuff i've said
that i'm not into like the sweet tarts
and crunchy candy
gummy candy suckers that's not for me no
nerd ropes none of that [ __ ]
sometimes uh you may see me much a
brownie if the brownies are right a
brownie corner with a little bit of
crunch in that texture i'm down with the
brownie but i really try to stay away
from that stuff
um drinks i said that i drink a lot of
drinks a lot of my
snacks are drinks
i cannot drink blue stuff if you have a
sonic where you live sonic is a place
where they serve drinks and food and
it's fast food
people like to get a blue coconut slush
or they have blue coconut drinks i am
allergic to the blue food coloring or
something it will make me projectile
vomit like a [ __ ] dragon can't do
blue drinks
i try to avoid caffeine like i said i
cut out the dr pepper years ago
i do spoil myself when i go to comedy
works they have this bottled root beer
it's caffeine free
but that is as close to drinking like a
sugary shitty soda that i've let myself
get in a while um varieties of kombuchas
and teas um and coconut water you guys
coconut water i love
the vitacoco pressed coconut the other
coconut water is good the pressed
coconut water is [ __ ] delicious
there's nothing more hydrating more
refreshing than coconut water don't
drink too much of it it can have uh it
may come out the other end a little more
quickly than you anticipated if you
drink too much but the coconut water
[ __ ] divine super delicious when
you're blazed and just like that cotton
mouth is all right and you hit the
coconut water it's just like your mouth
goes
you're just refreshed i love it
um
coconut water kombucha's random teas
drink a lot of yogi tea a lot of
celestial seasoning teas just to keep
the throat in line to get some herbs and
different sort of supplements into the
body things like that i think it's good
for you to drink tea especially when you
talk as much as i do the weather is
crazy here i smoke a lot of cannabis and
i'm around a lot of people so vitamins
teas things like that just try to keep
myself boosted up there's a place near
me that sells a peanut butter chia
banana smoothie
[ __ ] oh my god dude if they weren't
nine bucks i drink two of them a day
those things are [ __ ] delicious i
love that we're going to talk about fast
food and food and then we're going to
get the [ __ ] out of here you guys i know
i've been going on for a long time i
really like to eat um when i get blazed
i like food that i can just shove in my
mouth there's something primal something
just [ __ ] rar about me that when i
get good and blaze then you're like it's
eat time and i'm like is it eat time or
is it like eat time like no it's eat
time let's do this um i can murder a big
ass vegetarian chipotle burrito like
it's nothing we could do qdoba if that's
the option i like burritos vegetarian
style burritos that i could just pick up
and shove in my mouth the more food in
my mouth at one time in that situation
the better kind of become a savage a big
dog a mountain lion a bear whatever you
want to call me at that point love that
sort of stuff something like chipotle or
some kind of good tacos or burritos
something like that i'm down with it a
nice savage burrito
that [ __ ] quesadilla from savage
burrito i'm in
um thai food i love asian food thai food
indian food
chinese food korean food all that sort
of stuff
love all of that sort of [ __ ] i like to
go to a thai food restaurant and order
two maybe three maybe four entrees and
just put them if i got a date and where
we know each other uh we'll just put
four meals on the tray on the table and
we'll just experiment and see what's
good and we're gonna like something
we're not gonna like something love
ordering multiple entrees and just
finding out what i like and then um i
can eat so i'll just finish it all if
you don't like it bro i'm not [ __ ]
eat it don't worry
all right so i think that kind of wraps
up my rambling episode about munchies
this was much longer than i had
anticipated i don't think there's much
editing to be done gonna leave it just
like it is i hope you enjoyed this
episode hope you got some good snack
ideas thank you guys for the great
feedback it's great to know that people
are out there trying to take care of
themselves it's great knowing that a lot
of people out there are also uh having
that good box as a snack you're taking
care of yourself and your partner that's
good to know good to hear keep that up
big up thumbs up for that one um yeah
that's all i've got for you let's wrap
up the episode if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions
corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism friendly feedback
i'd love to hear all of it um i do take
it all with a grain of salt don't worry
about my feelings or my ego i've done
this enough i know people are gonna be
um aggressive send it all my way
um patreon check out patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart you can
support the show all the info is on the
screen anything else check out the
website at iriegenetics.com
before i wrap it up i want to give a big
shout out to a friend who
started off as an irie genetics
supporter turned into a strong member of
the irie army joined the discord and has
become a friend he makes artwork for me
he makes artwork for the brand for the
show for the podcast for the company it
makes a lot of great artwork for the
discord the dude is a hell of an artist
he's an amazing dude he's a good friend
uh he's a fish fan uh you can excuse him
or accept him for that however you like
uh fellow fish fan big up fish fans um
he's a good dude my friend's name is
riven waters he's a great [ __ ] dude
he's got a youtube channel called made
while medicated um
i don't even need to tell you a lot
about it i just want to invite you to
check out my friend's youtube channel i
think you'll enjoy it
he's a great dude the least i can do is
give my friend a shout out and invite
you to check out his channel so check
out madewell medicated on youtube give
him a subscribe check out his videos
tell him that rasta jeff sent you show
him some love because he is a friend of
mine and i want to spread love to spread
love to my friends that do deserve it
all right that's all i've got for you
ladies and gentlemen thanks once again
for listening to me ramble about
munchies i hope you enjoyed the 7-eleven
episode 712 will be much more uh grow
focused more garden-centric i do have
mike working on another project for us
maybe i shouldn't announce that until we
get it going
but mike if you hear this this is a
reminder do your homework for that
episode that we talked about all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers vegans
vegetarians carnivores omnivores all you
hungry [ __ ] out there i want to
thank you once again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast i want to give a big shout
out to my buddy billy podunk and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
you