[Music]
is that working this is working that's
working
i think it's time for a podcast here we
go welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
this is episode 712
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk a little
bit about male plants before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend fiscals organics
let's send a big thank you shout out to
uncle adam the uber driver i want to
send a thank you shout out to frogman
420 and spherical glassworks let's send
a big thank you shout out to blackhawks
fan and choke norris let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to groove
2112. i want to send a big thank you to
brohan 78 and captain mojo let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
rut ro and rasufa let's send a big thank
you shout out to canner reaper 4-1-3
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to rasta green thumb big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends all right i feel like
i got all the business out of the way
where do we go from there let's jump
right here into this part recently on
social media i saw something that kind
of bothered me a member of the irie army
a friend made a mistake in the grow room
they actually had a an equipment failure
and a lot of people uh they jumped on
that person and they gave them a bunch
of negative uh feedback a bunch of
negative criticism the feedback was kind
of 50 50. some people said you can do it
ah just try again grow harder but a lot
of people were very uh not super kind
about that you guys people are going to
make mistakes this person took it to
heart when you guys talk trash to them
kind of messed up their day people are
going to make mistakes you're going to
make mistakes in your grow don't be
afraid to make some mistakes ah things
are going to happen equipment is going
to fail you're going to mess up
schedules you're going to mismeasure
some stuff plants are going to die but
guess what life goes on the key is to
grow again so that you've got some good
weed to smoke next time when [ __ ] goes
wrong so don't be discouraged don't give
up if you make mistakes i've done a full
episode about making major mistakes and
grows i've destroyed entire crops i was
halfway through a flowering crop one
year
maybe last year maybe the year before i
was trying new lights i was halfway
through a flowering crop it was fully
seeded i would have been a great market
run you guys would have really enjoyed
those seeds i was not satisfied with the
quality of those plants i cut them down
i made mistakes i cut my losses cleaned
up regrouped started over it hurt it
hurt my uh it hurt my little ego it hurt
my feelings it hurt my budget definitely
but i learned a lot from it i learned
not to use that lighting in the winter i
learned not to switch lighting in the
middle of a grow i learned how to use
those lights eventually it was a great
learning experience so you guys when you
do make mistakes i'm not going to say if
i'm going to say when you do make a
mistake because it's going to happen if
if you're not a robot if you're not a
machine and still then those things make
[ __ ] mistakes if you make mistakes if
you make errors if your plants die it's
not the end of the world that is just
the end of those plants life goes on
[ __ ] happens grow more weed let's do it
again all right big shot it's my friend
that made me some mistakes uh they
actually ended up with some fresh seeds
they were well taken care of they're
going to give it another run they have
been re-encouraged and revitalized you
guys don't let mistakes uh scare you
away there's a full episode of the grow
from your heart podcast about mistakes
uh i talk about the things that i have
done to destroy plants ruin full grows i
encourage you to check that out i'm not
perfect nobody's perfect uh killing
plants and ruining [ __ ] is how i got
good at growing you don't get better at
anything by getting it right the first
time you have to make a mistake then
take notes of your mistakes and now you
know exactly what not to do and of
course sometimes equipment is just going
to fail you can't help that all right
where do we go from there i do have more
notes um
also yes thank you for the great
feedback you guys i got some amazing
awesome feedback from the past uh two or
three episodes from episode 709 when i
talked about the evolution of dabbing i
got quite a few uh comments responses
emails and feedback from that then of
course episode 710
oh my goodness big shout out to pedro
once again big shout out to roz and ryan
and big thanks to the audience out there
everybody for watching uh the feedback
the the corrections the comments the
concerns all of that stuff uh the
comments are what i was gonna say ah big
thanks for all that that episode got a
lot of responses the youtube comments
are uh they're flooded there's a bunch
of comments there the emails are coming
in the questions are being asked you
guys are watching the show thank you i
do appreciate that
then episode 711 i had a lot of fun
doing the munchies episode i talked for
like 40 minutes about munchies i did not
mean to go on that long it was a super
easy show i got rambly you guys seem to
enjoy it thank you for the first of all
for the feedback to make that episode
that was a very uh audience generated
episode so thank you for giving me the
info to make that show and then thank
you once again for the feedback coming
from that episode
also i'm still getting feedback from
that people are listening to it and now
they're messaging me saying this is what
i like to eat
mangoes have been real popular lots of
fruit and still
that box has been popular so you guys
keep doing it keep smoking keep eating
keep sending me great feedback i do
appreciate it it has been great all
those comments all those uh all the
feedback even the the concerns the
constructive criticism all that stuff it
does kind of recharge me it refuels me
it gives me uh like a little bit of
energy it keeps me going it refreshes me
uh it's like a a good job anytime you
tell somebody they did a good job it
encourages them that means a lot coming
from you guys i know that i'm helping
somebody and it makes me feel like i'm
not just talking to myself into this
camera with this expensive mic because
that would be a sign of mental illness
if i was just doing this for me anyway
i'm getting rambly i'm kind of baked
today it's been a great day
let's uh focus a little more you guys i
went to the dispensary today big shout
out to my friends at doctor's orders
stem beach at the south end of pueblo
colorado if you're down there check them
out let them know that rasta jeff sent
you
they will take extra good care of you
they'll take good care of you no matter
what at that dispensary it's a small
little spot
there's hardly ever a line hardly ever
away you can usually walk in get the
products you need and be on your way in
just a few minutes
they've got marvelous flowers and
they've got my favorite they've got the
green dot batters and green dot rosins
and green dot h c f s e the high uh what
is that the high cannabinoids the fse
the full spectrum extracts is what
they've got there so many letters and so
many things what i normally buy is the
batter to be honest with you i get the
batter occasionally i get the pens uh
right now they've also got a bunch of
incredibles edibles they did not pay for
this ad they're just good to me shout
out to my buddy ricky over there always
taking good care of me bud tender of the
year i was there today stocking up on my
green dot concentrates uh the one that i
bought named um it is named after an
artist it is called dali that dolly bro
get you a gram of that that will kick
your dick in the dirt it'll get you
rambling on a podcast
uh anyhow
while i was there my good friend ricky
uh shout out to ricky growing that
orange guys i'm like a champ gave me
this uh propaganda paper from the
dispensary the marijuana enforcement
division is now passing out uh this
paperwork when you buy concentrates
you're supposed to pass this to a
customer that buys concentrates in the
dispensary the top of it says
colorado department of revenue marijuana
enforcement division
use of regulated marijuana concentrate i
just thought this was interesting so i'm
going to share this with you we're going
to kind of mock this a little bit is
what's really going to happen here uh
they gave this to me which i thought was
funny he laughed when he gave him he
said i have to give this to every
customer who buys a concentrate and i
was like oh good because i'm new
of all people that needed some dabbing
advice it is definitely me this is the
medical and retail marijuana stores are
required this says that medical and
retail marijuana stores are required to
provide this resource to individuals
purchasing regulated
marijuana concentrate i feel like nancy
grace when i say marijuana concentrate
you guys excuse the raspy voice also
that's from way too many dabs but life
goes on we must do a podcast
ah this does say examples of a serving
size for each type of concentrate it
describes the expected serving sizes for
a concentrate it goes on it says
regulated marijuana stores offer various
categories of marijuana concentrates
stores may refer to marijuana
concentrates using different names
including but not limited to terms like
shatter wax butter sugar hash resin and
rosin so they talk about all the
different names then here's where they
get serious
start low
and go slow that's that's real advice i
once heard a guy say you can't unsmoke
that joint can you and he was [ __ ]
right uh but it says start low and go
slow then it says vaping vaporizers heat
marijuana concentrate to release thc for
inhalation the serving size should not
exceed one in inhalation lasting two
seconds per serving so they want you to
vapors the heat concentrate the serving
size should not last exceed one
inhalation
lasting two seconds that's
one one thousand two one thousand
that's what they want you to do that
makes sense bro if you're new that'll
work for you i don't hold in a dab for
very long either i think that you get
what you need i think you just get copd
from holding in smoke for too long
that's all you're going to get i think
you absorbed what you're going to absorb
unless you take a giant dab then i think
some of it may stick to my lungs and i
just absorb it slowly over time as my
lungs eat it up let me get back on track
this says inhalation other than vaping
then it says when consuming regulated
marijuana concentrate by inhalation
other than vaping and this is an example
dabbing the recommended serving size is
a sphere with the diameter no larger
than the dot below and i'm going to show
you the dot here i'm going to hold this
up as close to that camera as i can get
it from my seat without messing
everything up but look at the size of
the dot
i tried to move that around a couple of
times to where i can find an edible
edited edit to edit a bowl do you say
edit a bowl quickly a spot where i can
edit to where we can put that picture in
there really good you can see it maybe
we could blow it up maybe i'll pick a
picture of it and drop it in but that
dot that's on there is not a very big
dot they want you to do a dab that is
that size in diameter like a full ball
of that most people that might get you
high but for me that's that's going to
make me wish that you would give me a
dab is all that's gonna do so they're
telling you to inhale for one inhalation
lasting two seconds and that's uh that's
if you're vaping all right and then uh
inhalation uh the serving size this fear
no larger than the dot below then it
says risks and precautions this is the
part where i got excited here use of
marijuana concentrate may lead to
psychotic symptoms and or psychotic
disorder including but not limited to
delusions hallucinations or difficulty
distinguishing
reality
that's [ __ ] extreme you've got to
what are you dabbing can i get some of
that whatever made that person get uh
delusions hallucinations and difficulty
distinguishing reality may i please i'll
take a gram i'll take a four gram jar
i'll pay cash where do we go from here
mental health symptoms and problems it
doesn't list any of those but it gives
you the
the thing that it looks like there's
more coming after that but there's no uh
stuff coming after that then it says uh
cannabis hyperemesis did i say that
right the fr that might be the first
time i ever said that correctly cannabis
hyperemesis syndrome or chs which is
known as uncontrolled and repetitive
vomiting
i think that's pesticide exposure i'm
not a scientist a scientologist a doctor
i just have a podcast i did stay at a
holiday in one time
but
i really think chs is probably most
likely a pesticide exposure i could be
wrong let's keep moving then it says
cannabis use disorder and dependence
including physical
and psychological dependence so they're
warning you that you may you just may
get addicted to dabbing bro um
i don't i don't see that happening
people i don't think you get addicted to
dabbing you may enjoy it you may want to
do it a lot but it does i don't in my
opinion i don't i don't know anybody i'm
not a once again i'm not a behavioral
therapist i'm not a an addictive
medicine specialist we got to call in dr
drew for that i do however uh maybe i am
addicted since i'm justifying [ __ ] here
i do take breaks and i was gonna
encourage you to take breaks
occasionally um if you follow my social
media if you watch my instagram live you
watched uh last year i took a couple of
one-week breaks and then i took a 12-day
break where i didn't smoke any cannabis
or eat any edibles for a stretch of 10
days and then i was one week it was 7
days and then i went for 10 days and at
the end of 10 days i said well that was
fun let's just keep going i went for 12
days uh then i just wanted to smoke just
because i wanted to but maybe just check
yourself occasionally take a little
break see if uh if that's something you
need to do also i consume medical
cannabis and would you stop taking your
medicine do you need a break from your
medicine the things that make you not
sick or something like that that's kind
of the way i see it but i do take breaks
occasionally it's always fun to clean up
the system you don't smoke for 10 days
and then when you do take a dab
it is [ __ ] tremendous you do notice
that one all right let me get myself
back on track there's more to this paper
we'll wrap this up and then start
talking about male plants here next up
on the paper it says consuming
concentrates via inhalation will cause
immediate effects that is accurate
that's accurate i feel like when i take
a dab if i take the appropriate size dab
by the time i'm done blowing it out i'm
like oh i'm high there it is like booyah
it got me and then i got to let that dab
kind of sink in for a few minutes and
let that immediate part of the dab kind
of wear off because it could be
overwhelming when you take a monster dab
so that is accurate it does come on
immediately then it says marijuana
concentrates and this is in bold
marijuana concentrates are not
recommended for inexperienced marijuana
users
then back to our normal size font thc
concentration amount of concentrate
consumed and frequency of use can result
in both short-term and long-term effects
there's moderate evidence that
individuals who use marijuana with thc
concentration greater than 10 percent
are more likely than non-users to be
diagnosed with a psychotic disorder such
as schizophrenia
and they said ah loose right they did
say
there's moderate evidence they don't
have solid evidence it kind of it kind
of looks like this that's what they're
saying that's not [ __ ] real evidence
then it says marijuana concentrate is
not approved by the fda and claims that
medical benefits are not supported by
the fda that's that makes good sense you
got to put that in there for legal
[ __ ] uh marijuana concentrates are
not recommended for anyone under the age
of 25 except if recommended by a doctor
people under 25 may be at greater risk
of potential harm because the brain is
not fully developed so they don't want
you dabbing until you're 25. sorry kid
you got to quit dabbing you got to wait
a couple years
keep doing your thing then it says
regulated marijuana stores cannot
provide medical advice i actually
uh i like that um they're not doctors
they're bud tenders most of them are
just 20 something year old chicks and
bros that definitely have no
qualification to give any medical advice
don't go in there and ask them what to
smoke for your seizures
don't do that do your own research find
the strains of work for you don't rely
on those folks don't put that pressure
on them don't do that don't put your
devil magic on me ricky bobby then it
says any questions related to the health
or safety of marijuana concentrates
should be discussed with a patient's
recommending physician or an adult
consumers primary care physician and
then as a little disclaimer on the
bottom this will be what we wrap up with
the risks are these risks are based on
colorado department of public health and
environment evidence statements where
there is either moderate or substantial
evidence where moderate means strong
scientific findings that support the
outcome but these findings have some
limitations and substantial means uh
robust scientific findings that support
the outcome with no credible opposing
scientific evidence that's a lot of
scientific gibberish that means uh we
did a study and nobody challenged it
that's why what i think no credible
opposing scientific yeah nobody
challenged it that's what i think that
says um on the other side it says uh the
following statements must be included on
every container of marijuana and it
shows you some regulations and some
other things and um some other stuff
that doesn't really matter on this one
then on the back here we have a bunch of
reporting agencies uh the rocky mountain
poison and drug center uh suicide
prevention line um youth and marijuana
just weird propaganda phone numbers on
the back here if you do have some
problems with something like that please
do reach out to somebody take care of
your mental and physical well-being and
if somebody you know is in uh
immediate imminent danger please do
reach out and get them the proper care
that's a responsible thing to say as an
adult with uh a show but um there's a
lot of stuff here on the back that i
really honestly found this to be
entertaining when he handed it to me
he's like here bro i have to give you
this when you dab and i was like bro
we've been buying dabs for years and
they just now realized we needed a
little propaganda pamphlet uh pretty
funny pretty cool hope you guys enjoyed
it i'm gonna take a quick drink then
we're gonna talk about a male plant
question that i got from our friends on
youtube
all right as promised i took a drink and
now i am back to talk about a mail
question that i did get from youtube
most of the time i don't check a lot of
the youtube comments and answer a lot of
the questions from there because i
prefer them to come in an email it's
easier to print and manage however this
one did get my attention
it goes a lot like this first of all it
came from be real but not the original
be real it is be real the other be real
and it says how do you measure the
potency of a male plant that's a very
good question uh with a female plant we
get buds we get flowers you dry them
cure them smoke them enjoy them and then
you go that one's good that one's not as
good that one tastes good you get your
own judgment your own opinions or you
can take it to the lab that's always an
option but
you don't get that option with the mail
plan there's a different process with
that i do have a bunch of notes here let
me keep myself on track because i do
like to start rambling talk over my
notes so male potency question how do
you measure the potency of a male the
first thing i do when i'm growing a male
plant and looking to work with the male
plant is it's always a visual inspection
you got to look at it what does it look
like does it have the traits you're
looking for does it re reach the
criteria meet the criteria which you
have set for that male plan what's your
goal what are you trying to do now
potency um if it makes trichomes it's
going to be potent that's one of the
visual cues for potency probably the
main visual cue but make sure it's got
all the other criteria potency isn't the
only thing that you're looking for when
it comes to a male you need structure
vigor shape resistance to pathogens
resistance to bugs
appropriate flowering time
amount of pollen that it dumps there's a
lot of other things to think about i've
done a lot of shows about that so
visually look at the plant make sure
it's something you want to work with do
you see trichomes that is going to be a
good indicator of a nice potent male now
the next step since we don't get to
smoke the male plant i mean you can but
uh dj short does it that's not my style
i don't want to smoke the male plants i
don't want to dry them out smoke them i
instead i do this i find multiple female
plants i've got one male plant a dude
that i think is going to be good this is
why breeding takes a while that's why
selection takes a minute so my seeds are
expensive you find one male plant that
you want to work with this is at least
how i would so i'd grow a few males i'd
grow a few males and i'd look look
visually and i'd pick one out of those
and that one that i selected all the
others would be gone all the pollen
would be cleaned up now if you've got a
fresh room with one male plant i would
introduce multiple female plants of
different genetics there would be like
in my case it'd probably be a strawberry
starburst plant a sun-kissed plant a
blueberry cookies plant a lemon skunk
plant those plants are all different
enough in growth flavor aroma
leaf shape plant structure that i can
tell what the male plant is going to add
when i breed to those
so i would pollinate several female
plants that are different in lots of
ways visually aromatically buzz wise
flowering times
so that we can kind of what we're trying
to do is we're mixing this paint with
other colors to see what other colors we
create that's really what we're doing
but we want to be able to see
the other colors and we want to see what
mixes what these two colors mix like so
we're trying to put reds and blues
together to get purple if you put a
bunch of purple together you're just
going to get more [ __ ] purple and you
won't know what happened so try to find
reds try to find blues try to find
things that are opposite so we can blend
those breed those together and see what
we've created so the first step
pollinate no first step selection
select males select females do a
pollination one male to several female
plants finish them gather the seeds keep
the seeds separate the seeds that came
out of the strawberry plant they're
staying over here the seeds that came
out of the sun kiss staying over here
seeds that came out of blueberry cookies
staying over here same with all the way
down the line i think lemon skunk was
the other one i said we're gonna keep
all those seeds separate labeled sealed
safe secure then i'm gonna grow as many
as i can of each one of those batches of
seeds in the same uh as close to the
same environment as i possibly can i'm
going to try to get somewhere between 10
and 100 seeds we're just going to say
the blueberry cookies to our new mail
i'm going to bust out a hundred seeds of
those and grow them and see what i get
i'm gonna take a lot of notes i'm gonna
talk about i'm gonna note the growth
structure the speed of the growth the
leaf shape the shape of the plant uh
different phenotypes that i see i'm just
gonna make notes are there any weird
anomalies is there are there any weird
mutations or strange things that i
notice in that batch make all of the
notes you can think about then once
you've grown that batch run another
batch of something different i said the
blueberry this time let's do the
strawberry next time cause that's gonna
be way different you got blueberry and
kind of funky skittles and you got sweet
strawberry bubblegum watermelon let's do
that one so we run the strawberry to our
new male once again look for anomalies
look for growth structure look for shape
look for any sort of things that stand
out document everything that you can
we're going to do this with all of the
seeds that we have made with every batch
the strawberry blueberries uh sun kiss
and the lemon skunk and now what we're
going to start to see is what that male
adds to the mix with each plant because
if you only pollinate one plant then you
only know it's kind of a what is it a 50
50 crapshoot maybe that's what it does
but if you pollinate multiple different
females then you can see
what that male uh does what it provides
what it offers to other female plants
when you breed to it because it's all
about the combination what comes out we
want a new plant that uh outperforms the
original plant in a couple of ways but
we also need vigor structure
resistance potency aroma we need all of
that stuff and it needs to be better
than the original plant we started with
or we're not doing the plant any good
we're moving backwards in the evolution
of cannabis so pollinate a bunch of
females grow them out then take a lot of
notes and see what you've got then
compare your notes as the grower as the
breeder this will start coming to you
naturally as you're doing it you'll say
oh i added let's just say that you're
male maybe i'm going to say that it had
chocolate we're just going to guess
chocolate chocolate's a good flavor a
good trait something we would all enjoy
we're going to say that male adds
chocolate we don't know that yet but
we're going to breed that male 2
blueberry strawberry orange and lemon
powder it happened now we grow it now
we're starting to get in the blueberry i
noticed like a chocolate dark chocolate
blueberry peanut butter sort of a smell
going on that's kind of interesting some
of the phenotypes have a lot of
chocolate in them i grew the strawberry
out got a lot of strawberry terps
there's some watermelon terps like we
expected but then some of them have
chocolate hey guess what i wonder if
that male is contributing chocolate
terps is that what it's doing also i
noticed that they all grow super wildly
tall is that what the male's doing
you'll start noticing commonalities
amongst the different crosses that
you've made and that's how you identify
what the male is doing you'll start
noticing when i cross it to the lemon
skunk that i get chocolate and lemons
and that's how you say oh maybe that
plant puts out chocolate turps or maybe
it makes i said a minute ago it gets
really tall or maybe you'll notice that
everything you bread it to
flowers super quickly also there could
be negative traits sometimes the male
plants if they don't get enough light if
they start to get root bound if they get
thirsty if they get over fed they'll
just start auto flowering without you
telling them to that's a problem for a
male plant because that trait will be
passed on to its progeny those plants
will start flowering whenever there's a
problem and your customers or you or
whoever ends up with those seeds will
not be happy with that if they're
looking for a regular photo period plant
so the best way to do it
pollinate them pollinate a bunch of
females keep the seeds separate grow
them observe take notes then find
commonalities to see what that male
plant is doing i know it sounds like a
lot of work and it is
each pollination is going just to veg
and flower the plants you got a hundred
days right there then you've got to grow
out those seeds there's another 100 days
right there depending on how many you
can grow you've got to do multiple
cycles so that could take you quite a
while that's why seeds are expensive
that's why breeders
charge money for our work that's why we
ask for a compensation for the seeds we
give you that's how we build a
reputation is by doing that work and
putting out seeds that we know will be
reliable that you have shown a track
record that we do make good selections
with um let me get back on my notes
let's see visually pollinate grow the
seeds find the females finish them oh
yeah here's one of the best parts smoke
them you get to grow out these plants
these female plants that you just made
and you get to smoke them that's how we
find out uh what is really the best did
you now here's here's what you have to
do next once you've got a bunch of seeds
and you've grown them and smoking you
have to do it again with a different
male and see which one's better that's
that's a whole another what did i say
300 days worth of research now we're
already at two years into this project
just finding a mail plan that's why
seeds get expensive so
you get to grow them then you get to
smoke them and then you get to find out
what those traits are that were passed
along there are some other options that
you can do you can send your male plant
to the lab and they can test your male
plant for the presence of cannabinoid
precursors you can also test your
finished plant if you've got a male
plant that kicks out flowers you can
send it to the lab for testing for
potency that is a thing
you could
get uh precursor plants from multiple
male plants and send those to the lab
and test for the presence of cannabinoid
precursors and your males and that may
help you speed up your selection process
uh you could do precursory tests on
males and females um that'll definitely
speed up your process should we talk
about that a little bit does that make
any sense what we're able to do um
let's just say we're looking we're going
to breed plants and i'm looking for a
female plant that is super i'm looking
for only plants that are super high in
thc that's that's a silly goal but with
this project it will work for what i'm
going to talk about
um
we would grow these plants until we were
big enough to get a leaf sample i only
need two true leaves once these plants
have two true leaves i take a sample
that is the size of the the back end of
this pin the parts you click the
annoying part i need a sample that big
from each plant we send that sample to a
lab they test it that lab can identify
the presence of the precursors that will
later turn into thc so it knows that the
uh precursors to those cannabinoids are
available in that plant so they will say
uh this plant shows markers that are
high in the precursors this plant's not
so high in it this plant is super high
in it so at that point if we were
breeding for potency what you would do
is just eliminate all of the low testing
number plants at that time and if you're
looking for boys looking for girls you
can run the test at the same time to
find male and female so if you're
looking for that highly potent female
you got her if you're looking for that
highly potent male you got it now what
you would do what i would do since i've
already eliminated the low number plants
i already know that my high potency
plants are in the batch now i will look
for structure vigor growth uh aroma
color
resistance all of the other things that
may be desirable at this point
for the plant we already know that
they're super potent so now i'm pheno
hunting backwards now i don't have to
smoke it i've already eliminated a bunch
of plants through science through what
is known as predicative testing through
looking for the presence of cannabinoid
precursors i would assume you could do
that with the male plants i don't know
anybody that is doing that yet you would
be revolutionary you would be the first
uh send that [ __ ] in get it tested see
what pops up um breathe the mail read
the same email to several females and uh
experience and see what that mail does
take notes and have fun that is the last
of my notes that i've got down uh the
most important part is that you have fun
if you're not having fun with your
breeding projects if you're stressing
yourself out if it's driving you crazy
take a big breath and step back smoke
some good weed take some dabs dive
yourself into a state of which where do
we want to use cannabis use disorder or
maybe get yourself some psychotic
symptoms or psychotic disorder walk
around the block giggle a couple times
think about it snap out of it then go
back to the grow room back to the
drawing board and have fun grow from
your heart breed with love that is what
it is all about
the goal here is to create plants that
were better than the plants we started
with it sounds like you are uh you're
very interested in breeding this is a
great question i hope i gave you some
good information here my friend be real
thank you for the youtube question
everybody else out there this is a good
reminder please do like and subscribe to
the youtube channel that's right go to
youtube search grow from your heart
podcast you will see the little
subscribe button you know how to do it
also click on that notification bell
then every time i put out an episode you
will get notified you'll never miss a
moment of my cannabis psychosis
ramblings all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers flowers smokers and dab heads i
want to thank each and every one of you
for listening to another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast if you feel
like this episode was educational
informative entertaining uh maybe just
like to throw me a couple of bucks
because you learned something or had a
good time all you have to do is visit
dot www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need to support the show will be
right there on the screen big thanks to
everybody who does continue to support
the show also if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know that i would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy if i said that
too fast if i did any of that too fast
all of the info is on my website at
iregenetics.com all right that's all
i've got for you for this episode you
know i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
big shout out to my friend anything
grows and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you