[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode 713
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode we're going to talk about
mother plants before we get to that part
of the show let's do a few shout outs to
a few of those great folks who continue
to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to frankie let's send a big thank you
shout out to stash drop and thomas
mcginnis let's send a big thank you
shout out to a.d viking let's send a big
fist bump to a fox i want to send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy madewell
medicated let's send a fist bump in a
thank you shout out to mr and noah n
let's send a big fist bump to a longtime
supporter my buddy alabama man let's
send a thank you shout out to smoke what
let's send a big fist bump to zoso j and
elder's garden then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to greenvet 88224
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends
i do want to take an extra second to
send a special thank you to everybody
who supports the patreon especially the
past two months because the past two
months have been record setters uh we've
got a record number of patrons and a
record number of patronage of funding
coming in i do appreciate that that does
not go unnoticed so big thank you to
each and every one of you who continue
to support the patreon especially the
past two months i do appreciate it uh to
show you a little special thank you uh
in the month of february this episode
should come out february 1st if i timed
things correctly
in the month of february i will offer a
special discount code for the merch
store for the patrons at the 7 and 10
cent a month level or higher so if
you're contributing 710 or higher you'll
get a discount code i will try to do the
higher levels you're contributing the
higher discount code you will receive so
check for that discount code on patreon
that will be for the merch store where
you can get the uh the t-shirts the
stickers the grinders the rolling trays
and of course the sweet new grow from
your heart podcast hemp hats i don't
think i've talked about these on the
show quickly let me ramble about these
this piece inside here this is just a
protective piece so that when i ship it
to you it doesn't get crushed and
destroyed keeps the hat supported what
we've got here is the grow from your
heart podcast original logo i call it
the eq logo it's got that eq bar on
there we've got a i should mention these
are made by alpine hemp company these
are a hemp hat made by our friends at
alpine hem company big shout out to
alpine hemp got the grow from your heart
podcast logo on the front on the bill
here we've got the red yellow and green
stitching i'll hold that up closer to
the camera there i'm sure it's picking
it up i can't see what's happening it
does have the alpine hemp sticker that
does come off when you're ready or leave
it on there if you're that guy we've got
the alpine hemp hang tag here we do have
the red yellow and green stitching
across the top of the hat
then we've got the
says gfyhtv on the side here on this
side we've got the alpine hemco tag
which is also ladies and gentlemen that
is a joint caddy that's right you can
stick a joint and then i've got a pen
here i can show you with the pen i don't
have a joint handy but you could stick a
pen right in there and that would work
also as a joint caddy you could rock a
fat spliff up there always have a joint
ready to smoke uh please be careful if
you're uh only do that in legal
locations but we got a joint caddy up
there also we got the cool red hemp tag
back here let everybody know you're
rocking the hemp hat that you care about
the world about the planet uh we're
using hemp now on the inside you
probably already saw it i haven't spoken
about it this is printed with a
sublimated image of blue raspberry
truffle seeds if i remember correctly
that is an image of blue raspberry
truffle seeds made to look like you've
got seeds inside the hat of course red
yellow green liner got to keep it rasta
for the rosta jeff style here these hats
my friends my my fellow smokers and
growers these are available on the web
store simply hit the website
iriegenetics.com
click on the merch store that will take
you right there if you are supporting on
patreon you've already got the link go
check patreon i'm not sure where it will
show you but you may get an email
it'll pop up go look for it thank you
guys for the continued support that went
longer than it was supposed to also uh i
will blow out some of the other merch uh
when you go to for the coupon code that
will be valid on all of the merchandise
shirts stickers grinders rolling trays
dab mats a lot of stuff will be getting
blown out then we're going to add more
merch we got to blow out some of this
merch here's the deal here's what i'm
trying to do i've got a couple of boxes
with like random [ __ ] in it and there's
not enough stuff in those boxes to make
those boxes sitting there
want to uh liquidate and consolidate
some merchandise so that we can get new
merchandise spring is coming i'd like to
order some new merch for the spring if
you have any merch ideas for spring uh
grow from your heart podcast i read
genetics merchandise i would love to see
your uh your designs if it's a certain
merch piece that i haven't offered
i like to offer things that are useful
and practical to the community as
merchandise the grinders rolling trays
things like that i'm sure you're using
those exactly as anticipated hats are
cool you can wear them shirts are cool
what am i missing if you're part of the
merch marketing team let me know what
else i should make also
if you've got some designs uh if there's
a strain that i put out that doesn't
have cool artwork and you make some
artwork let me know maybe we can use
your artwork also keep in mind we have
to be careful with some of the strains
that i've created we can't make art for
all of them because that may get us in
trouble if the strain name is uh derived
from something famous already we
probably shouldn't make artwork for it
but some things we could definitely use
artwork for now i feel like i'm begging
for art begging for your help out there
i like crowdsourcing uh you guys told me
design you my friends on discord help me
design this hat here it seems to be
working i like the crowd help you guys
going to be wearing it rocking it using
it why not get your feedback where do we
go from there i think we've talked about
all the stuff on the notes here let's
get into
the topic of this podcast which is your
mom your mom plans to be more specific i
do have an email here this one came from
our friend used to be cool used to be
cool has been listening to the podcast
for a long time has not emailed with a
question in quite a while which makes me
feel like uh our friend is learning
quite a bit they've gotten confident in
the grow they haven't needed my help
which makes me proud i do appreciate
that
i left the mechanic shop the other day
and i said it was good seeing you bro
but i really hope i don't have to see
you for a while and he understood he's
understood exactly what i meant every
time i see him something's wrong with a
damn car didn't want to have to see him
for a while uh i think that our buddy
used to be cool is doing great because
he hasn't messaged me with the problem
in a long time this one i will quit
rambling and we'll cut to the chase i
goes a little bit like this it says if
you read this on your show please don't
use my real name brother we i've read a
lot of your messages i know you as used
to be cool when i see your real name it
just translates into my brain there's a
switch i get it by now bro big love big
respect thank you for being around for
so long
it says i have a question about keeping
a mother plant i have never kept a cut
beyond a few runs mainly because of
space restrictions that is completely
understandable i'm here in the state of
colorado if you've got recreational
cannabis you're allowed six plants if
you've got your medical recommendation
you're allowed an additional six in most
cities and counties uh most places limit
you a lot of people talk about their
extended plant count a lot of cities and
counties don't give a [ __ ] about your
extended plant count you are limited to
6 and
12. it says however
i found a plant i want to explore a
little my dude fell in love
congratulations brother i know that
feeling trust me uh it says i was it was
the only female from a pack of freebies
well that's cool that the the female
freebie was awesome the female freebie
was [ __ ] fantastic it's fabulous to
found her you say that five times fast
i'll send you a pack of seeds
and so she can't be replaced yes i know
that feeling i've got a lot of female
cuts that cannot be replaced especially
my male cut imagine if we had to find
another king solomon it goes on i'm
rambling today you guys i must have
smoked some good [ __ ] thanks for hanging
out with me says however i realize i
don't really know how to keep a mom my
specific question is whether i should
multi-top the plant to increase branches
so i can harvest more cuts or simply let
it grow naturally and let the cuts i
take also count as topping i would also
just like some basic information about
how long to keep the mother before
flowering it out and starting a new mom
and any other
it looks like my printer just [ __ ]
gave up at that point i was like nope
i'm done printing so that's what we got
here it ends with and any other i'm
pretty sure you can ask for any other
information that i can provide to help
you out keep a mother plant happy set
you up for success let's get into that
because i do have a lot of useful tips
being a breeder a long time cultivator i
have kept cuts around
excuse me for having to hear that for a
moment i've cut kept cuts around for a
long time i've talked about a flow plant
that i had for
uh 2008 i probably had that [ __ ] for
10 12. um
man i probably had that plan for 12
years we're just going to say 12 years i
don't know exactly uh but 10 or 12 years
i had a flow plant by keeping a mother
plant of it when that mother plant would
outgrow the pot or outgrow the shape
sometimes they just you cut them and
take mom like take clones off when they
start getting unshapely and unruly i
would just take another fresh cut and
rejuvenate and start fresh that's a
thing as a breeder with a selection of
mom plants that's something that i do
routinely it's about every six months
sometimes sooner depending on the cuts
uh the congo grows too fast she has to
be remomed too early um but i try to
remom my [ __ ] occasionally just to keep
the genetics fresh just to keep them uh
ruley the shape that i want so you
started with a very good question let me
get back on track here um let me back up
into something
that we should that you should have done
further you didn't make a mistake you
didn't know this was going to be a
champion so you did not know to keep a
clone but this is why i say
always keep a clone of every plant you
grow i'm a breeder i run a lot of tests
seeds it is hard to keep a clone of
everything so what i do in that a lot of
times i'm willing to just let it go
because i've got enough seeds where i
can run it and find it again i found
i've seen what i wanted to see that can
go i'm not too attached a lot of the
time sometimes i do wish i had a keeper
i wish i would have kept it in that case
what i will do is re-veg a plant it's
never too late to cut a clone off of a
plant if you've decided that that plant
is [ __ ] fire you want it cut a clone
keep that around or re-veg that plant
after you harvest i've done uh full
episodes on cutting clones re-veging
monster cropping i've done episodes on
all of that that's all available so
always take a clone because you never
know um
if it's going to be fire you never ever
know just like this case it's the only
female and it needs to be kept so if you
would have had a clone um
if you have a clone then you can keep
this going on so hopefully you've got a
clone um but always keep it calm that's
something i talk about then where are we
or learn to re-veg um i have re-veged a
bud i may have talked about this on the
show before i was at a friend's
greenhouse and he had plants that were
pretty far along
it was almost smokeable but not quite
and he thought it would be nice and
clipped me off a little bud like a
good-sized bud and toss it to me and
he's like go home and smoke that and let
me know what you think and i was like
well it's way too early i'm gonna think
it's crap but that was super nice of you
because our buddy white mike had the
brilliant idea he said if you don't
clone that you [ __ ] up and i was like
dude i think we're thinking the same
exact thing so we drove straight to the
house put it in some clonex put it in a
dome uh got it go put it in a clone plug
put it in a dome got it going as a clone
and that [ __ ] rooted and it revenged
and i had a clone on my friend's plant
that he didn't know that i had kept it
around to me
maybe
maybe i've bred something to it recently
that we can't talk about yet here on the
show because people don't even know that
that's what they're testing let me keep
myself on track here
uh so you can clone it's never too late
to clone something re-veg it and rescue
it so now let's talk more about keeping
a mom plant your first question is how
do you shape it
to provide clones that is a very
good question it is all about your goal
i don't know how many clones you need i
don't know how your gross style is so
the main thing i always take that middle
top right out and make that a clone
because all the other branches are going
to grow to a certain height and that top
is going to keep going and [ __ ]
everything up it's going to you're going
to have to adjust the light and
everything because of that top bud that
top node that apical dominant node just
take that out use that as a clone now
you've got a nice even canopy now you've
got a lot of options for cloning once it
starts to grow as a home grower you're
probably i'm assuming here you're
probably not going to need more than six
12 maybe 20 i don't know your state your
limit uh what you're doing you're not
going to need a lot of clones so one
mother plant any three to five gallon
pot can provide a lot of clones but you
have to learn how to
shape it to provide those clones and
where to cut from to keep the plant
active and growing to give you even more
clones once you've cut it so it's kind
of learning learning the plant if you've
got a plant that is squat and stout
and it makes a lot of branching it's
easier to get more clones more
frequently if you've got a tall stretchy
plant like the congo um
there aren't a lot of places to clone
from but there's a lot of plant material
because it's so [ __ ] long but it's
one big main with like eight side
branches so if i were to clone from it i
could get nine clones maybe but i've got
some uh let's talk about the chernobyl
plant that i've got that [ __ ] grows
real short real squat and makes one main
top that takes off but then a lot of
side branching i could get 40 clones off
of a plant the same size as i could the
congo just because the shape and
structure of the plant so that's going
to have a lot to do with it the main
things are the shape and structure of
the plant the size of the plant and then
how many clones and how frequently do
you need them so i always start with
that main top take that out let them
grow evenly and then as they get taller
take those as your next round of clones
and they'll start catching up eventually
you'll have like a hedge then you can
you'll learn when i cut here always cut
at the node when there's another node
sticking up so you got your main branch
and you got another let me come down let
me adjust this mic and get my [ __ ]
together that was awkward the way i did
that uh you got the main branch coming
up this is your main branch right these
are leaves whatever my fingers are
leaves you got a node right here
sticking off top it right before that
and that new one will make another
branch if you do or there's one coming
up here and one coming up here you just
made two tops where there was one and
now the next time you cut you got this
sticking out and now you got two tops
and you can those will make more tops
it'll do the same thing and you can cut
the tops out of there and then you'll
make four out of it and if you once you
figure out that art you'll get really
good at it keep in mind
that
you can reclone this plant get a clone
of it grow it out keep it as a mother
plant
then once it gets unruly unshapely use
one of your clones as your new mother
plant and keep practicing to achieve the
shape you need uh you desire the shape
that reaches your goal all right i do
have a bunch of notes here that i didn't
even talk about i've been going for
quite a while um mom question uh
selection it's all about selection what
works best for you sounds like you found
one you want to play with you've got a
plant that you want to turn into a
mother plant i would recommend keeping
it under a veg
light
i don't have this note written down so i
want to talk about this quickly
if you don't up pot your mother plants
sometimes some plants do have the
potential to begin to autoflower or show
you problems once they get root bound so
keep it in a big enough pot for it to
grow wide and strong have a healthy root
zone that we can branch out bush out and
provide you the clones you need so pot
size is very important then
after that i'm going to say that veg
light is very important light cycle um
the same with the pot size if you don't
give it enough light if you don't give
it enough air enough space
if the vpd is off if this plant gets
stressed out and you keep it around for
a while it may try to flower on you so
give it enough light depending on we're
going to talk about daily light integral
in a very soon upcoming episode here but
depending on the kind of light you're
giving it the intensity and the amount
of hours pay attention to that light pay
attention to the plant give it enough
light to where it will not go into
flower i sometimes i run 18-6 for my
moms often if i've got full control of
everything it'll be 20 on and four off
for my mother plants give them those two
hours extra of light
just makes them grow stronger prevents
them from flowering they don't even get
the idea that it's dark enough to think
about flowering and then they get four
hours for the plant to sleep a lot of
the root cycles a lot of the stuff
happening down there in the rhizosphere
happens in the night a lot of the growth
stuff
happens in the night uh also i want my
equipment to get a four hour rest that's
four hours of electricity i don't have
to pay for four hours longer my bulb
will last every day uh it doesn't seem
like a big deal in a homegrown a small
cultivation but if you're running a
large-scale commercial cultivation
facility uh your mom room can be i've
been in a veg room a mom room with 50 to
100 lights just vegging and mom i've
been in much larger but i'm just saying
it can be
50 lights just for mother plants just
for keeping genetics and small clones
around can be a lot so if you can
minimize the amount of lights that are
on the time give your equipment some
rest that will save some on the bill
also time on your equipment less fans
running less [ __ ] happening uh
everything costs a little something
right now everything costs a lot more we
don't need to talk about that but um
lights think about lighting we want veg
lighting blue lighting um if you've got
the options for switching if you're old
school you do hps and metal halides you
want the blue metal halides right now if
your uh led light has a switch for veg
or flower switch that [ __ ] to veg
that's where you want to be the most
blue light you can give it i'm not an
expert on lighting but we do want veg
lights at this point also to go with
that veg light we do want vegetative
nutrients i focus mainly on that
nitrogen phosphorus potassium of course
they're going to need a little bit of
calmag they're not in flour they're not
in high performance mode once they get
bigger and the soil burns out whatever
you got them in you will need to feed
them calmag and other things but think
about the basics uh just basic veg newts
i like to feed them a lot of microbes i
feed everything that shits on the
microbes just because i think that keeps
the soil moving we're going to talk in
the future about over feeding of
microbes uh but feed it veg nutrients
basically uh your basic vegetative
nutrients you don't have to give it all
the boosters and [ __ ] because you're not
trying to make it uh grow grow grow
we're just trying to make it a big
enough plant to provide healthy happy
cuts
um
then we're gonna touch on something i
already talked about shape it to offer
the amount of clones you need at the
frequency of which you need them
um
maybe some people keep a one gallon tiny
bonsai mother plant that they take one
clone off of and it grows a little bit
bigger and they take two off of they let
it grow a little bit bigger next time
they get three then they up pot that
into a bigger pot or maybe they just
abandon that one and use one of the
other clones and keep going because they
cannot have large plants or maybe you
grow gigantic [ __ ] plants that you've
just got hedged up and trimmed up as
much as you can and you're just taking
thousands of cuts at a time it's all
about your goal i talked about shaping
it
shaping the plant will become an art
once you realize when i cut here
this branch will grow this way when i
cut here these two split this way you
kind of have to do it to learn it and
you'll experience it and you'll figure
it out very quickly on a couple of
plants so shape it the way you want
mother plants can be small they can be
huge it depends on how many you want to
keep around and how many cuts you're
going to need
i generally keep my mother plants in a
three to five gallon pot i keep them
fairly far apart so the wind can blow
and they don't get any issues and when i
apply a sprayed pesticide or foliar feed
that was harder to say than it looked
they're far enough apart that i can get
all the plants carefully and
individually
i keep them in the three to five gallon
pot i veg them out or i keep them i
guess
i try to keep them around 18 inches 24
inches tall sometimes they'll hit about
three feet tall once they get about that
three feet tall they start getting
unruly out of control i have to make too
many adjustments that's when i'll take
as many clones as i can get from one
plant i'll get as many clones as i can
get from that one plant so i'll make
sure that i'm gonna get a keeper i'll
have a row of all of my mom plants in a
clone dome temporarily um
we'll get roots as soon as i see roots
and as soon as i know i've got security
i will toss that big mother plant or
maybe i'll put it into flour we're going
to talk that about that in a moment
maybe i'll drag it out to the greenhouse
uh i point it right there it's not right
there it's way the [ __ ] out there but
we'll take it out to the greenhouse out
in the middle of nowhere put it out
there make some seeds out of it you
never know what could happen but
oftentimes once they get big and unruly
uh i whack them down it hurts mike's
feelings mike has been here and helped
me put giant plants and trash cans and
he just shakes his head and he's like
buddy i wish we could put these outside
i'm like bro it's [ __ ] december like
we could but they're just gonna freeze
and it's gonna be like it's
heartbreaking a little bit to chop down
giant plants but once you realize uh
those plants have given me a hundred
clones and they've served their purpose
they've made a thousand seeds and 500
other plants and 40 pounds of weed and
you start thinking about all the other
[ __ ] they produced it's okay that that
big mother plant goes bye-bye so some
people are going to keep big mother
plants some people are going to keep
small mother plants i think i keep
medium-sized mother plants two to three
feet tall uh they're about uh probably
i'm a drummer that's probably 18 inches
around i'm thinking about the size of a
good floor tom 16 18 inches 18 inches
around at the top i can get plenty of
cuts from those
then sometimes let's talk about this is
this on my notes in this direction um
occasionally i will just drag that
mother plant in quotation marks into the
flower room and bloom it out if you were
using this mother plant as a clone donor
while it veged and you used those clones
to shape that plant
i always talk about when i'm running a
new plant i take that main top out and
use that as a clone when i'm lolly
popping i take two of the bottoms off
and i use those as clones now i've got
three clones
i could do that with a mother plant and
then flower it just as easily as i did
with my new seedling so sometimes if you
don't have space
for a full-on dedicated mother plant or
an arsenal of mother plants let's say
that you're limited
to only 12 plants and you want to keep a
genetic around but you can't dedicate a
mother space or a mother room
i use your veg plants as a mother plant
just perpetually have let's just say we
want to grow let's say lemon jeffrey
you've got a lemon jeffrey plant you
want to grow it over and over again but
you can't keep a dedicated mom you've
got a plant of it grow it up like you're
gonna veg it take the top out take a
clone of that take the two bottoms off
of it because you're gonna clean the
bottom of this plant up anyway take two
bottoms off of it create clones out of
that now you've got three clones
one of them should root if you've
watched my clone tech video
there's a full podcast about cutting
clones i cut clones in the video if you
watch that follow that sop you will have
success one of those three clones will
root if you do this so
get the three clones now once you've got
your three clones and you're sure that
they're going to root you can drag that
big plant into the flower room and just
take good care of those clones maybe
wait a little bit longer if you're not
super experienced but you've got secure
cuts you can keep vegging also if your
veg time isn't up if you're still
vegging waiting longer you can cut those
clones get them rooted put them into a
small pot let them grow and you've got
three of them over there now you've got
mother plants for backup
pick the best one keep that as your
growing plant or keep those three for
veg for the next run you've got plants
for the next run and then guess what
when it's time to run the next run
you've got those three plants take the
three tops as clones you could probably
pull a [ __ ] nine or twelve off the
bottom of those now you got at least
three to 12 clones to [ __ ] with again
drag those big plants into the flower
room you got your clones pot those pot
them again veg them get them stronger
repeat the process so you don't
necessarily need a dedicated mother
plant as long as you remember to take a
clone or as many clones as you need from
your crop before you flower it out most
of us are topping our plants cutting the
bottoms off anyway so why not if you're
doing three big plants in the flower
room four big plants in the flower room
you've got four tops [ __ ] what is
that eight bottoms you could take off
there that's gonna give you however many
what that is eight was sixteen twenty
four some number and multiples of four
as a drummer i should have followed
along it's probably twelve is probably
the number i'm [ __ ] up and i'm a
drummer is why i didn't think of 12. um
you can get your cuts off of those
plants the amount of plants you're about
to flower is the amount of cuts you need
probably right if you're keeping a cycle
going so you got three big plants take
three big clones and do it all over
again you don't need a dedicated mother
i hope i made that clear because i
talked about it for a really long time
veg the plant cut a clone
veg that plant while that one's vegging
throw the other one into flour as soon
as that one's ready cut more cones from
it throw it into flour you got clones
they're right there as long as your
clone tech is solid or as long as you
wait until you can get that clone into a
pot and get it grown big enough to where
you're secure that you've got it if
you've got two or three copies you know
you've got it there
then throw it into flour and if all else
fails
we can re-veg the one that's in the
flower room we can take a cut from that
one so that is an easy way to keep the
mother plants you don't have to keep it
dedicated mother plant god i went on for
way too long about that um rotate your
mom's occasionally if you're not going
to do the rotational move like i just
talked about
uh refresh renew and rotate your mother
plants occasionally i said i do it about
every six months once a year depending
on the genetics the situation the size
of the room sometimes that goes more
quickly sometimes it takes longer and a
commercial grow
i may do it sooner because the plants
grow so largely under all of those
lights now here's something people are
going to talk about
the word you're going to try to spit out
throw at me
use for controversy type in the comments
is the word genetic drift and right now
i'm gonna go
wrong nope genetic drift is not possible
in this situation uh if you listen to
the full episode i did call genetic
drift that will explain why this is not
genetic drift if you do notice that your
plants are getting weaker over time
genetic drift is not the cause of this
if you keep a healthy mother plant and
you take healthy clones in a clean
environment and you grow those clones
properly and love them and take care of
them and feed them and don't let them
get any pathogens or problems you can
perpetually keep those plants forever
you will not face any problems if you
keep them clean don't let them get any
viruses any pathogens no bugs everything
like that will degrade the quality of
your plants that will give you weaker
plants
less strength less vigor you'll start
seeing changes also different
environments will give you different
changes so if you think that the plant
is changing your clone tech or the
environment possibly are changing from
that plant maybe your humidity
your warmth anything could change will
give the plant a little bit different
expression i noticed that my winter
crops and my summer crops are different
in the same room with the same cuts
just basically because of the
environmental factors i cannot control
can't dial in because of the extremes we
face here in colorado we get a negative
17 in the winter and [ __ ] 117 in the
summer so i've got a lot to work with i
see a lot of different conditions it's
my responsibility to dial them in i get
as close as i can trust me but it's a
lot to work with sometimes however
genetic drift is not the word you may
see problems some degradation but in my
opinion in my experience healthy plants
make healthy clones for generations i
told you i kept that flow clone around
for at least 10 years when i decided to
get rid of it it was just as beautiful
and healthy as the day i got it i cut a
bunch of clones of it when i was done
with it and i spread those clones out to
my friends i felt that was the polite
thing to do i was like hey you guys love
flow i've been growing her for years i'm
done with her instead of just taking her
out back and shooting her maybe i'll
give you guys a bunch of cuts and you
can let it live on just don't let me
[ __ ] smell it smoke it i don't want
to be around it anymore nothing wrong
with that plant you guys i'm just done
with it i've smelled so much flow i grew
so much flow smoked so much flow that uh
i'm done i don't want to smell it taste
it look at it i woke up every morning
smelling flow then i would go to the
dispensary at which i worked and we sold
flow and guess what just smell sell
smoke more flow i got sick of it
shout out to flow from progressive
nothing but love also a big shout out to
dj short
and everybody involved in that flow
story you guys know where the flow came
from if you know you know big up and
thank you much respect all right healthy
plants make healthy clones i don't think
genetic drift is a thing it's definitely
not a thing when we're cloning plants do
some research i've already explained why
in a full episode all right my friend
used to be cool i think i've rambled on
for long enough about mother plants feed
them veg nutrients give them lots of veg
light keep them in a big enough pot to
where they don't get root bound because
they will get root bound and they may
give you some problems there
shape them the way you need them
to give you the amount of clones as
frequently as you need rotate them out
you don't need a keeper mom all the time
as long as you've got a veg plant of
that mom you have got the genetics
stored cut a clone of it get that clone
rooted put that big plant into flower
perpetually keep that bad [ __ ] around
that's how you can do it all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i want to thank you once again for
watching and listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast i did have a good time recording
this one felt super comfortable tonight
sometimes this microphone just sounds so
good in the headphones
sometimes it doesn't let's hope it edits
as well as it recorded big shout out to
this camera
for holding on camera number two could
kiss my ass
we'll talk about that later anyway uh
let's wrap it all up if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you can send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback also don't forget about that
grow tab on the website the website is
iriegenetics.com irie
genetics
iriegenetics.com there's a grow help tab
if you click on that tab it'll ask you a
few preliminary questions about your
garden you can send me grow help
questions you can send me podcast
questions through there let me know
what's on your mind i'll do my best to
answer those keep in mind it is just me
answering the emails don't get
frustrated or discouraged if i haven't
answered or replied or read your message
here on the show immediately i've got a
stack of shows lined up i've already got
shows programmed ready to go your
question may be coming up so don't get
annoyed with me also it's just me
answering thousands of emails thank you
for your patience uh website email
uh grow help tab oh subscribe now is a
good time to remind you to like and
subscribe click like on the video also
subscribe to the video
or the what is it subscribe to the
channel that's better there you go like
and subscribe i forgot what the [ __ ] i
was even trying to say uh patreon.com
forward slash go from your heart if you
feel like this podcast was educational
informative and or entertaining all you
have to do is check out patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
the information you need to support the
show will be right there on that screen
that was a mouthful to get out so
quickly all right that is all i've got
for you for this episode you know i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content i want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy tonto's garden and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
you