[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
ganja farmers i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 714
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
growing feminized seeds and working with
feminized plants before i get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to danny dave let's send a big thank you
shout out to our buddy bob let's send a
thank you to alabama man and jg let's
send a big salute and a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to the captain and
commander of the irie army my friend
lemur priest let's send a big thank you
shout out to billy podunk holding it
down in alaska let's send a big thank
you shout out to brian p and ez05
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy og purple thumb i want to send
a special thank you shout out to my
buddy guyudy gross let's send a thank
you to blackhawksfan and matt h then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to triumph big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
dot www.patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen and you know i do include a link
in the show notes and in the video
description to make everything nice and
easy for all of my friends i do want to
make one quick update maybe an
announcement a lot of times when you
sign up for patreon you type in a name
and that is now your patreon account
name some people put their regular name
some people put their full name some
people make up a cool name and put
gaiuty grows in there uh some people
have lemur priest in there some people
however are just putting their real full
government name in there i don't know if
you want me to say your real legal name
on the show
i understand that that could get you in
some trouble uh maybe your co-workers
your boss your friends maybe your wife
finds out that you're contributing to
the patreon and she doesn't want that i
don't want you to get in any trouble so
if i'm saying the wrong name or if i
haven't said your name and you're
concerned simply send me a message on
patreon and let me know what your name
is under on the account and let me know
what the corrected name i should say on
the show is i do have an update from one
person here i've been possibly saying
the wrong name but they do want me to
give a shout out to oh cannabis six one
three so big shout out to oh cannabis
six one three you're getting a shout out
i'm not sure from this message i'm not
sure if that was uh the message was from
oh cannabis or if their friend paid for
this shout out honestly by the looks of
this but either way if i'm not saying
the correct name uh because i've called
a couple of people the wrong name for
several episodes just update me correct
me send me an email i do
this is a cannabis podcast that means i
do consume cannabis before after and
possibly during this show if i have
forgotten if i have failed to make the
adjustments and corrections simply send
me another email sent me a nudge uh
we'll get it corrected i'll say the
right thing on the show all right so
once again big shout out to our buddy oh
cannabis 613 i'm not sure if that came
from you or your friend either way big
love thanks for the support to both of
you or you i'm confused i do have a real
topic for this podcast here i've got a
screenshot here in my phone i'm going to
grab the phone no i'm not flirting with
anybody i'm not scrolling instagram
looking at butts and boobs i am actually
reading a message here on the screen i'm
looking for it this one i found this on
youtube
i've said this before i prefer not to
take the comments from the youtube
channel it's much easier to capture them
and print them and use them here on the
show when they come through either an
email or the grow help tab on the
website let's talk about that before we
even get to this on the website
iriegenetics.com there is a grow help
tab there's a tab that says grow help if
you have questions or need grow help
with your plants all you have to do is
fill out a quick uh it's like a
questionnaire it's like basically asking
your blood pressure height and weight
but we do it about the plant what are
you growing are you indoors are you
outdoors are you growing under led hps
ceramic metal halide or using campfire
and flashlights
what kind of soil are you in are you
using hydro what are you doing i want to
know some questions and then i give you
an opportunity to type in your question
and ask what you need help with the
reason i ask so many preliminary
questions is because questions is
because people say
why are my plants yellow and i'm like
well that could be a billion things with
that little questionnaire that little uh
preview that little uh survey that helps
me get an idea of what's going on with
your plants in your grow room it answers
all the questions i was going to reply
with anyway it saves us a step so if
you've got grow questions if you need
grow help i do recommend the grow help
tab on iregenetics.com that goes
straight to the phone when you send that
message it goes to my phone my phone
jingles i will check that then i will
print it it'll end up in paper that's
the best way to get it on the show i've
got papers piled up i know which episode
they go to their paper clip together
that's just my organization it's easier
that way however i did like this one
this one came from youtube i'm not going
to read a lot of them from youtube
because it's harder to find them it's
harder to print them keep them access
them file them but this one was good
[ __ ] high and rambly but it's going
to work out this one goes a little bit a
lot if not just like this it says can i
do this with feminized seeds and then
they ask a question clone a p1 so that
basically means grow a plant you've
grown your parent your p1 so we're going
to clone the p1 which was feminized
we're going to we've assumed this was
feminized they're asking about femme
seeds clone the p1 use colloidal silver
on one clone and use that to pollinate
multiple plants so far yes you can
absolutely do that that's what i do that
is what is commonly done we're going to
take a p1 plant and we're going to clone
that we're going to reverse one and then
we're going to do what i call pollen
chucking we're going to put that pollen
on a cut of the same thing and a cut of
other things and now we've got a
breeding project you're off to a good
start here so far makes sense i get it
it goes on though it says now i'm going
to take another p1 clone and spray that
across that with the seeds from the
first batch and that should give me f2
seeds right thanks buddy i've been
watching you more and more lately big
shout out to our friend sean cross from
the youtube i'm not sure
um there's parts of this question that i
have questions about
so i'm going to clarify that right here
when you say
then take another p1 clone and spray
that
if that p1 so what you have to do now if
you want to make the f2 there's a
specific step because you could mess
this up let me try to clarify the
question and then i'm going to of course
ramble on rose about this um if so
you're going to take a plant and it does
not matter if it's feminized or
non-feminized i'm going to talk that's
going to be the main chunk of this
podcast here let me scroll up and get
myself to that part of the notes
we're going to talk about that part a
lot here but um let me get myself back
on track so we're going to take a
feminized plan it doesn't matter at this
point if it's regular or feminized it is
all the same that's what i'm going to
ramble about in a moment here we're
going to take a plan we're going to
clone it and then just like i said we're
going to reverse it you can use silver
thiosulfate you can use colladial silver
uh whatever works best for your
situation your experience go ahead do
that reverse it chuck some pollen now
you're gonna make seeds
now to make f2
which is the second filial generation
you have to take seeds a batch of those
seeds that come from the same plant so
let's just say
you took a golden goat and you
pollinated lemon skunk now you've now
made lemon jeffree it's an r1 also
technically can be an f1 for this case
we're going to call it an f1 to make an
f2 you would have to take a batch of
those lemon jeffrey f1 seeds or s1s it's
the same thing
or r1 is what a technically it's an r1
and an f1 at the same time you have to
take seeds out of that batch and find
you're gonna have to reverse that and to
make that again with
the same male and female out of that
batch because that's how you make the
filial generation if you go back and use
one of the males or females from
previous notice i said go back that is a
back cross if they came from the same
batch of seeds if that's a this is a
philly so when you make seeds what comes
out of there is the filial generation if
they are the same filial generation that
you're crossing then you move forward in
filial generations if you cross to
anything else you are making a new f1 or
a back cross so i think that will sum up
that part of the question if you make
seeds
take if you only cross one plant to
another plant and then you get those
seeds and you find a male and a female
out of those or a female that you
reverse out of those and cross that
again that is f2 because that's a filial
generation moving forward if you move
backwards using a previous parent or a
previous mom now you are going backwards
to a back cross i hope that makes it
clear now the chunk of this i want to
focus on is something you really said at
the beginning was a feminized plant you
said can i do this with feminized seeds
there's a lot of myths misconceptions
misunderstandings rumors falsities
[ __ ]
um what is it wackness uh [ __ ] around
feminized seeds there's it's a lot of
rumors and [ __ ] that people don't simply
do not understand around feminized seeds
and that is understandable if you only
learn from the internet if you only
learn from what your cousin's uncles
told you that he heard from his brother
in vietnam that they met at a boot camp
one time like that info is old and who
knows what the [ __ ] that person really
said and somebody heard one thing
because we only half pay attention when
we [ __ ] listen to each other anyway
so
a lot of people have misinformation
misconceptions bad info about femme
seeds
feminized seeds are no different than a
regular seed other than the fact that
the pollen the pollen is the difference
the pollen was the part that was
feminized the plants are the same exact
thing as a male female plant except you
won't find that male chromosome which
would have been transferred in the
pollen i'm going to borrow a lesson from
my friend mr soul big shout out to mr
soul ah mr solon is amazing dude puts
out some great seeds puts out the cindy
99 and some other great [ __ ] big shout
out to brothers grim seed company mr
soul made the greatest analogy that i
can ever think of i can't come up with
anything better than this but i want to
give him credit because give credit when
credit is due you've got to honor and
credit your teachers your masters
something mr soul taught us
the best way i can explain it when we
make feminized pollen we are reversing a
female plant this is a full here i'm
going to go on a side tangent of my
tangent we're walking down alleys
holding hands come with me let's do this
together
a lot of people say that when we make
femme seeds we are using a treatment to
make the female plant become a
hermaphrodite that is not true that is
not accurate
these plants are not intersex or
hermaphroditic plants if they were i
would not be making seeds with them i
stress test them and make sure they are
not intersex plants what i'm doing is
not causing hermaphroditism or intersex
so this is hermaphrodite intersex that
is not the right word here these plants
are reversed they are treated and
reversed to make pollen they are not
male plants uh they are female plants
creating pollen so they're reversed
they're treated they're not intersex
they're not hermaphrodites let's get
that correct now the part that mr soul
taught us when we make feminized seeds
we're treating the female plant a fully
female plant i touch on that again fully
female
we treat that with a either silver style
silver thiosulfate or colloidal silver i
prefer the thiosulfate i can't say it
today i [ __ ] promise i know what it
is i prefer the silver thiosulfate
method myself if you do the other way or
any other way have fun power to the
people do your [ __ ] thing
so we have learned how to make female
plants produce pollen mr soul says uh
taught us that basically we have learned
to put up a filter imagine your male
plant your pollen donor or in this case
our reversed female plant is right here
it's over here it's making pollen it's
it's [ __ ] it's busting a load it's
doing its thing you're gonna sneeze
that's the [ __ ] that's what it's doing
it's making you [ __ ] sneeze over here
we've got female plants they've got
their their hairs like you guys like to
call them they're they're ready to go
they're ready to get pollinated their
female parts are sticking up these
plants are horny we got dudes blowing
loads or a reversed female blowing a
load we got ladies over here ready to
get it right somehow through the magic
of science basically what we have done
by reversing these plants mr soul says
we put up a screen that works as a
filter that only sucks out male pollen
because the sex is determined through
the pollen that pollen is going to hit a
female plant those chromosomes then are
going to mix if there's male chromosomes
in there that's when the plants will
decide if it'll be a male or a female
plant we've already got the female
pollen going over there no male pollen
so the only difference is we basically
found a filter or a vacuum and we're
sucking out the male pollen out of the
sky before that male sperm ever lands on
the plants it's only female sperm female
pollen getting over there we're only
making female babies that is not the
scientific method but that is the
easiest way to explain it that most
people will understand once again credit
to mr soul for that explanation because
that is the most uh reliable teachable
explanation i've ever heard we have
found a way to suck out the male paul in
so the only big difference in these
seeds in the offspring is that there
will not be any males now this is
science and nature coming together and
nature always has a way i have seen
full-on male plants pop up from
feminized projects that is not
impossible it is highly unlikely and
highly uncommon but it does happen that
is just because this is nature and
science and we cannot control everything
you guys have seen jurassic park life
does find a way [ __ ] does happen but if
we do this correctly we should come up
with
99.9 percent pure female offspring now
with that being said there should not be
any significant difference in the
performance of a feminized or a regular
seed they should both germinate the same
they should veg at the same rate of
course you're going to have strain
dependent variables i've got some
strains that simply veg slower than
others and it doesn't matter if they
came from a femme seed or a regular seed
that's just the vigor and growth of that
specific plant i truly do not think that
regular or feminized has anything to do
with it because sometimes
the slower growing plants honestly can
be those regular seeds so they germinate
the same they veg the same they flower
the same the potency will be the same
the per okay here's something that i
will say can be different i found two
variables as i'm thinking about this i
find less intersex plants in packs of
feminized seeds than i do in regular
seeds
now since we've got feminized seeds
dialed down and breeders are doing the
work i do find more problematic seeds in
regular packs so that is something i do
notice that i will testify to as
something who pops a lot of seeds grows
a lot of plants works with a lot of
seeds i do see more anomalies more
variables more freaks from the regular
seeds now another thing i can testify to
is
there is likely and commonly less
variation in feminized seeds why is that
because if we're making a self plant if
we're making let's say golden goat self
seeds a golden goat feminized plant i
cut a clone of golden goat i cut another
clone of golden goat i treat one with
our silver if it's thiosulfate or
colloidal silver whichever we treat one
clone we use that pollen to put on what
golden goat what genetics are in there
golden goat that's pure golden goat
you're not going to find anything but
golden goat you may see some
grandparents some parent traits of
golden goat but you're not going to find
adulterated golden goat the other option
is golden goat bx which of course you've
got another plant in there another line
of genetics which adulterate that which
give you
way more phenotypical options so in my
opinion in my experience in my testimony
i see and find less variation amongst
feminized seeds so that's a pro to the
fem seeds i was going to try to say that
there's no difference in that they're
even but we have found a solid
difference here in the regular seeds i
do find more problems more mutants more
weirdos more intersex plants in the
femmes i see less variation more
reliability which is what we are calling
stability in the cannabis space
so let's elaborate on this a lot part of
this question was about breeding with
femmes i often get asked can you breed
with feminized seeds can you keep
mothers of feminized seeds and the
answer to all of that is
yes they're just like a regular male
female plant except you did not have to
[ __ ] with the male plants when you were
doing the sexing if the breeder did the
work that feminized seed will be
everything the same it'll have the vigor
i've said this before it will be
all the traits all the qualities all of
the abilities of a regular plant except
you don't have to worry about getting a
male in that pack oftentimes there's no
way to get a certain strain like real
gorilla glue people talk about they've
got gorilla gorilla glue number four the
only way you've got it was a clone only
unless you got the clone
if you bought seeds they had to be
feminized seeds because there was
nothing put out there were no seeds put
out of the gorilla glue so if you wanted
seeds of it you had to get feminized
seeds it had to be the gorilla glue cut
a clone cut another clone reverse it put
it on the gorilla glue make feminized
self seeds that was the only way to get
it otherwise you had to adulterate it
and cross it to whatever i was working
with was it king solomon maybe i did
that maybe i hit the gorilla glue with
solomon maybe i've got something in the
works right now with a feminized gorilla
glue project coming up that i don't want
to talk about yet but the reason that we
do a lot of femme stuff is because it is
simply not available in the regular form
and we've wanted really we don't want to
put out misrepresentations of our lines
out there i put out
golden goat femme seeds and i don't want
to ruin the reputation of golden goat by
putting out [ __ ] so we did i did
work hard at making sure that those
seeds were correct so um
i got on a big ramble there i think
there are uh less very you can use here
i am i'm back on track you can use uh
feminized seeds for anything that you
can use a regular male female seed for
you can make a mom out of it you can cut
clones with it you can breed to it you
can do anything and it will work
beautifully if you have done your
selection properly also that goes back
to if the breeder did their work
properly did they select female plants
that did not show any intersex traits do
they select plants that handle stress
well handle bugs well uh possibly
pathogens well abuse well
i really try when i'm making fem seeds
that are going to market i try to find
plants that you can beat the [ __ ] out of
because i want uh i want my clientele to
be able to have a product that they can
beat up i want to set them up for
success so i find plants that can take
abuse can handle pests pathogens
problems that's really what i'm looking
for so did the breeder do the work did
they stress test their plants did they
sex test them do they intersex test them
and put them through the ringer before
they bred to them so if they did all
that part then you did your proper
selection if you selected your females
and you ran them through a few stress
tests a couple of times did the proper
phenol hunt then if you're going to
breed with them they will work just like
any other seeds i made lemon jeffrey
let's talk again about lemon jeffree
that is a uh it's a lemon skunk plant
from greenhouse seeds i got it uh in a
pack of seeds as a gift it is a champion
lemon skunk i came from seed so nobody's
got the one that i've got that's one of
the best parts about growing from seed
i've got this phenotype that you don't
have so i've got the lemon skunk i
reversed golden goat i put that reversed
golden goat pollen onto the lemon skunk
we now made lemon jeffrey i have got the
prized keeper of lemon jeffrey i've got
the champion it's amazing this cut of
lemon jeffrey does everything you would
want it to do it tastes amazing it hits
in potency it hits in weight it grows
quickly it's a perfect [ __ ] plant so
i took that plant and i pollinated it
what did i pollinate it with i've hit it
with the grateful dog i've also hit it
oh the grateful dog is also feminized
what that's a great thing to talk about
grateful dog is feminized lemon jeffrey
is feminized i have reversed the
grateful dog and put that pollen on the
feminized lemon jeffrey and that makes
amazing what feminized offspring what
yeah i've never released those too many
people i put out some testers and then
my social media accounts got squashed
right as i put those out and i lost
contact with all those testers and i've
only got a few seeds left i can make
more but that's not what i'm gonna do
right now also uh with that what else
have we made we have made lemon sunrise
that's lemon jeffrey to the arise
that's a regular king solomon regular
mail to a feminized plant that makes
amazing offspring so yes i do keep a
lemon jeffrey mother plant it's been
around for a long time the grateful dog
is a feminized mother plant which has
been around for a long time which has
been bred to regular and feminized stuff
so i've done it both ways you guys
i've done regular male plants to
feminized females and i've done reversed
females to regular uh
females which sounds weird i've done
everything you can think about doing
reverse to regular regular to reverse
reverse to reverse i've done it all and
they all work because their plants and
that feminized factor only makes a
difference when it comes to making the
seeds and ensuring that the consumer the
customer the clientele the grower ends
up with a feminized seed a feminized
plant all right i've been rambling i
think i've covered my notes here i think
i covered all the bullet points i wanted
to touch on i don't know how long this
episode was i feel like i was going fast
it feels kind of quick but once again um
i don't need to ramble and make this too
long it would just get worse from here
so let's start wrapping it up um ladies
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers grovers clone cutters paul
and chuckers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there i do
thank you once again for listening to
the girl from your heart podcast also
thank you for a great patreon month in
january we did hit records uh high
numbers of patrons and high numbers of
contributions i do appreciate that big
thanks i'm going to offer more discounts
and coupon codes try to find more ways
to make it up for you i'm working on new
merch uh i've talked about this already
stay tuned because episode 719 is coming
that may not be significant to you my
area code is 719. we're going to focus
on my city the way that cannabis
legalization helped my city i'm doing my
best to get mike on that show
mike if you were listening i'm going to
order another microphone and some more
equipment to have you right here at this
side of the table to make it a group
show we'll do two guys on the show it's
been a long time since i've had anybody
on the show since this whole ah the
pandemic has happened so mike
get prepared get some notes buddy uh
we're gonna let mike talk about numbers
because mike's the numbers guy uh talk
about growth and stuff here in pueblo
because of the legalization of
recreational cannabis mike will be here
for that um if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know i would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com also don't forget about the
grow help tab talked about that at the
start of the show go to the website
iriegenetics.com
find the girl help tab send me your
questions there's a lot of great [ __ ] on
there there's a grow help tab there's a
link to the discord if you're not on the
discord
you're missing out join the discord lots
of great [ __ ] happening over there i
hung out on the discord group chat last
night for probably two and a half hours
took a bunch of dabs talked a bunch of
[ __ ] with the crew good time shout out
to all my friends on discord love you
guys always a good time hanging out with
you also there's a link to the merch
there's a lot of great merchandise on
the ire genetics merch page um
everything else check out the website
don't forget patreon.com forward slash
girl from your heart my voice is burning
out i'm getting thirsty and i want a dab
so it is time to wrap up this show i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
shiz khalifa and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you