so
[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode
716 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read more
listener emails before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to kanna organic illinois let's send a
big thank you shout out to levity
loveday and yannick bucci let's send a
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to a longtime supporter our friend know
me by my guacamole let's send a big
thank you shout out to my good friend
dave's not here let's end a fist bumping
a thank you shout out to learning and
burning let's send a thank you to smokey
j and stone trout bum let's send a big
thank you shout out to redbeard i want
to send a special thank you shout out to
a fellow podcaster my friends caribou
heart tv then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to terp burglar
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need is right there on the screen and of
course i do include a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it nice and easy for all of my
friends all right i don't want to ramble
too much on this episode and the last
show i got going pretty good we didn't
answer very many questions let's get
right to it i've got a grow question for
you if you have a cannabis culture or
cannabis cultivation question i would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy the first message in
today's episode came from our friend
jamie and it says in the subject line i
heard you say thc percentage doesn't
mean anything i would like to learn why
can you point me to an episode there is
not an episode yet but now there will be
an episode to teach you why i feel odd i
don't mean the thc percentage doesn't
mean anything but there's more to this
message let's just read it says i do
believe you and i'm not challenging you
in any way i just want to understand why
you said that then he does talk about
some more stuff
which we don't need to discuss here on
the podcast just talking about branding
and other things uh but our friend jamie
asked the question um apparently
obviously somewhere either on instagram
live on social media or perhaps right
here on this show i did say that thc
percentage does not matter um it does
matter a little bit but it is not the
deciding factor it should not be the
deciding factor when it comes to buying
your medical or recreational cannabis
products whether it's your uh your
flowers your dabs uh whatever you're
buying the thc percentage should not be
the number one factor i do have a few
notes here and we'll talk about why
um the main reason why
um being immersed in the industry being
uh deeply involved in the industry
having experience i know that the tests
themselves are very easily manipulable
manipulative
you can manipulate those tests very
easily you guys can translate that
however it should have been done um
i know how to make a lab test come out
better it has nothing to do with the lab
many people say they just pay the lab no
they don't that everybody would just be
paying the lab everybody would have 45
thc that's what everybody would do
that's not a thing you cannot pay the
lab what you can do you can manipulate a
lab test i know how to do it i'm not
going to teach you how to do it here
it's very easy to increase the potency
of the samples which you were sending to
the labs you're supposed to do it in
colorado there's supposed to be a very
strict guideline
a standard operating procedure of how
the sample should be taken however
there's nothing forcing you to do it
that way you can if you're smart if
you're smooth
if you don't follow all of the rules you
can make the lab tests appear much
better than what they are so the first
reason why i don't trust a lab test is
uh they're very easily manipulated
easily manipulated and that doesn't that
doesn't work well for me if i know that
i can easily manipulate it and teach
employees how to get better lab tests
then anybody out there can do it we can
all figure it out um
it's all about prepping the sample if
you take the sample certain ways certain
spaces do certain things to it you can
definitely manipulate that test
then
also thc is not the only thing that
matters when you are smoking um
i've smoked what matters is the
combination of cannabinoids terpenes and
other compounds that all work together
to give you
the desired effect i can go right now to
many dispensaries ah there's a
dispensary 10 miles that way four miles
that way they're everywhere where i am
right now
i can go just a few miles and i can buy
thca diamonds that's just straight up
thc they're available
right next to them for half the price is
green dot batter uh green dot full
spectrum diamonds and sauce plenty of
other company stuff i prefer the green
dot batter because uh i prefer the other
stuff in the mix i don't just want the
thc the thc is a small part of it but
those other things in there really so
i've described it as this before when i
take i've i've hit the thca i've hit a
lot of it i bought a big old they used
to sell it in carrots when the stuff got
popular there was a dispensary just
selling big diamonds of it they thought
we thought we all thought it was awesome
i'm bored with it now because i've
realized
that when i take a dab of that no matter
how big it is i get super high my my
high goes up think of it this is how i'm
gonna describe it think of it as a
firework when you smoke thc or thc a
that's your liftoff from your fireworks
you're going to go up of course you're
going to go up that's what your thc is
going to make you do the more thca the
more thc probably the higher up you're
going to go but you're just going to go
up now the terpenes the esters the
paleontes the flavonoids all of those
other things that are in there are the
things that contribute to the color of
your fireworks another way i'm gonna put
that is
that's what gives you the munchies
that's what gives you the giggles that's
what gives you paranoia that's what
gives you pain relief that's what gives
you uh sometimes when i dab i gotta poop
sometimes it makes me hungry
lots of different things happen from
different strains sometimes the same
strain will have a lot of different
effects on me but i think a lot of that
is from the other compounds not just the
thc the thc is great in there that's
what's going to make me go up but i know
i can mess with the lab test to make it
look like there's a lot of thc in there
and i know that i need all those other
things we've called it the entourage
effect uh the synergistic effect uh the
full spectrum effect we need all those
other components to actually make the
buzz uh more enjoyable more medicative
more medical more for me it's just more
it's a recreational enjoyment i enjoy uh
so i could you could give me all the
diamonds and set them right here pure
thca crystals and you could give me a
bunch of green dot labs batter give me
some of that gmo batter maybe some of
that picasso or the dolly the dolly's
the one i really like give me the dolly
batter
or maybe some of their live rosin even
and i'm gonna smoke that over the
diamonds ninety percent of the time i
may take some of the diamonds over here
the thca crystals and maybe crunch them
up and sprinkle take a dab of the batter
and just coat it like put sprinkles on
the outside of it with the thca diamonds
the little crystals the shiny parts
that's going to make it taste better
that's going to give it a better buzz
and it's just going to increase the thc
a or the thc i'm not sure i keep saying
a or a thc i don't i don't i didn't
write it down but i feel like when i
smoke that i can only get so high i
start getting the sweats i start to get
a headache but if you put the other
stuff with it you give it some some
terps mainly you give it that flavor
that other stuff then you get a really
nice buzz you can really achieve
something
it's almost harsh and too much too much
thc by itself
the dabs they burn my throat they burn
my lungs it's not a desirable dab
you have to get it hotter than a normal
dab so that's also a little bit
uncomfortable then on top of that it
kind of burns your throat on the way in
burns the lungs and then it gives me a
headache when i uh i feel like when i
come down from it it gives me it's not
desirable it's like a headache it's the
best way i can describe it maybe not be
like the worst headache but i can feel a
lingering thing that it was like my
body's going yeah where's the other part
you need the other part to make this
work
so
that's my opinion on the thca diamonds i
think that that is what i meant when i
said the thc is not the only thing
it matters
but it shouldn't be
what happens is so i said the tests i
can manipulate the test what's going to
happen is i run a commercial grow i take
the samples or i manipulate the samples
we send them to the lab they come back
with impressive results we put that on
the jar or on the advertising at the
dispensary that draws a clientele the
clientele that just shops for thc
percentage since we know that's gonna
work we just mark that one up five more
dollars an eighth or whatever i don't i
don't work in that department but i know
that that's how it works i go to the
dispensaries and i see uh the flowers
and i see the [ __ ] that's marked like 18
percent thc and below is one price point
18 to 22 is another and then 22 and up
that's the top shelf stuff they charge
you more for that and
it's kind of just a who knows if that
number is even accurate they tested
so you're supposed to test a couple of
buds out of the batch but you might be
running a two pound batch you could be
running a 50 pound batch of the same
product and the tests are going to be
very inconsistent among that whole
spectrum of all that flour and that big
ass bin
i really do love lab testing
i love a lot of it
uh but also
the labs are allowed to have a plus or
minus ten percent threshold so when i
say that this flower is 30 thc
it could be 20 it could be 40. so
when especially when most of our samples
are coming around the 25 to 30 percent
how do i know they're not 15 to 35 to 40
percent that's something that we well i
should keep in mind so i'm gonna check
my notes uh we are all machines the
machines love thca they love that the
high liquid high pressure liquid
chromatography machine loves to show you
that it's got a lot of thc in the test
our bodies aren't machines we need all
of the other components to make that
more desirable in my opinion also um
this is
this is a joke i love to make
machines never buy another eighth i've
never had a machine come back and say
bro that hit really high numbers can i
get another quarter a machine has never
done that i've had a lot of people come
back and say dude i smoked that bag so
fast can i get another quarter that's
stuff that has happened so the machines
i like the machines i love the testing
it's great uh
they're great uh what are they called
markers uh yeah it's like a marker like
a like just a marker a data point is
maybe what it is but it's not that i'm a
body i'm a person we're all different
the machines don't care if you like
more thc more cbd
more limonene more immersing the
machines don't care they go lots of thc
and that we're not a machine you need
all the other stuff all right i think
i'm rambling let me check my notes uh
thc percentage is a good selling point
it's a good guideline it's a good idea
it's something to keep in mind when
shopping but it should not be the
definitive end-all be-all decision maker
when you are buying your medical or
recreational cannabis products i've done
another episode i'm going to get on a
side tangent here another episode i
think it's called follow your nose i've
done a updated episode on it i'm sure
follow your nose when you're buying
smell the [ __ ] um
and that's a good comment right there
smell the [ __ ] also smell the flowers
when when you smell things ninety
percent of the time when you smell
something and your body goes oh that's
bad you shouldn't consume it when you
smell something and your body goes oh
yeah you should be consuming that
oranges smell good because they're good
for you poop smells bad because you
probably shouldn't eat that somebody
already ate it that's all their waste
that's nature did that on purpose for us
uh that's that's a blessing and a trait
and a skill that we were given uh when
you drive past the restaurant and
they're cooking whatever whatever your
favorite restaurant is and you smell it
out there and you go
oh i need some of that your body craves
it because it's good for you it's going
to nourish you it might be some fast
food or whatever whatever but it's going
to satisfy your body you've been
programmed to think that's good for you
but still your body smells good stuff
that's good for you that you're supposed
to eat that you smell that pie bacon or
that cake bacon those cookies being
baked and you go i need to eat a hot
cookie i'm going to burn my mouth with
that cookie it's so fresh out of the
oven but it's so good i'm going to burn
myself with a chocolate chip i cannot
wait that's the kind of stuff your body
does and then somebody farts and you
want to walk away because you go that's
gross it stinks bro your body is trained
to do that so when you go to buy
cannabis when you go to buy concentrates
try to give it a smell smell a few
things don't be shy take your time at
the dispensary you're going to give them
your money and that's what they're there
for they're there to help you you're not
bothering anybody you're doing your job
at the dispensary which is finding the
product that is proper for you take your
time don't ever let a bud tender i'm on
a way big tangent now don't ever let a
bud tender or a patient behind you a
customer behind you make you feel like
you need to be rushed at the dispensary
treat it like you're at the bank write
all your notes you need to write write
down the numbers cross your eyes dot
your t's sign your name in the right
spot make sure all the zeros and
decimals are in the right place get what
you need at the dispensary leave
satisfied you're spending your hard
earned money money is expensive that bud
tender's there to do their job which is
to help you they're there on the clock
no matter how long you take they're
getting paid also
tip your bud tender if you can afford it
if they help you out if they take good
care of you tip them i've got a bud
tender friend i don't need to say his
name because ah he knows who he is i
take good care of him when they get
drops at my favorite dispensary he
messages me and he says hey bro i'm here
we just got this and i get a picture of
all the new cool [ __ ] that came and i'm
like you know i'm gonna need this and he
sends me a picture he's like bro i
already knew what you were gonna need
it's already stashed don't even worry so
big up to my friends who take good care
of me like that if you tip your bud
tenders they will take good care of you
and stash the good [ __ ] for you take
good care of you um don't rely on those
numbers when you go to the dispensary
that's what i think i was getting at
be sure to smell the jars
look at all the buds look at the shapes
the smells are the shapes the colors the
textures of the buds something's gonna
get your attention just like when you're
looking at the menu at your favorite
restaurant or at a new restaurant you're
looking at it and you're going oh they
got this for me it's just a bunch of
random vegetarian [ __ ] you guys have
never heard of but vegetarian item one
with this vegetarian too spicy
vegetarian that's my style savory
vegetarian ooh that's my style right
there one of them will jump out and then
you'll decide the cannabis will do that
if you go and smell the jars follow your
nose because your nose knows what you're
going to enjoy if it doesn't smell good
you're not going to want to smoke it and
if you don't want to smoke it how are
you going to enjoy it if it smells
smells delightful you're going to smoke
it you're going to blow it out you're
going to squint your eyes you're going
to smile it tastes so good and you're
going to get a nice buzz from it because
your nose
knows just like our old friend toucan
sam used to teach us follow your nose it
always knows your nose is right the
terps are there that's what your nose is
for follow your senses follow your gut
how long have we been going not long
enough let's go for another question my
friend jamie i hope i've answered your
question uh thc numbers are great
but also what about the terps bro and
i'm gonna go on a really quick side
tangent terps somebody sent me a lab
report and they said bro there was this
much percent terps in your uh and your
flowers they're trying to say there's
like 25 percent mercy in my flowers let
me translate those terpene reports for
you quite quickly a lot of times when
you get a terpene report they're showing
you uh the
uh when it says 25 mercene 10 limonene 5
other terp i don't want to get ahead of
myself they're not saying that the
overall
sample you gave them contained 25
percent limonene or mercine what they
are saying in that report is that there
were was a sample out of all of the
terps derived from that sample 25 of the
overall terps were this component i
don't remember the terps i named because
i'm ahead of myself again but
so don't get confused it's there when
they do the sample they'll say this much
of the overall product was terpenes it's
going to be low it's going to be like
one to four percent probably like that's
that's good terpenes about like that's
run do or that's impressive that's good
um but of those four percent
now you've got 100 of your terpenes
four percent of your to overall flower
was terps now you've got that now 25 of
that
is where your limonene is going to be
your 10 mercene so don't get confused
and say my sample was 25 percent
limonene and 35 thca because then what
else do you have you just got like 40
sludge to carry that in it's got to be
bud it's got to be chlorophyll and green
leafy matter at that point so uh read
those lab tests correctly now let me
move on i do have another great question
i got a big pile of questions in front
of me is this the one that i wanted to
read for this episode sure this one will
work very well
excuse me for all the throat clearing
probably not even going to edit that
this one came from our friend adam and
it says hey rosted jeff what's up adam
good to meet you bro it says hey man i
love the podcast it's very entertaining
and informative thank you that is
absolutely the goal here uh also a
little bit of education says nothing
better than hearing you ramble dude this
is the episode for you i said i was
gonna try to not ramble
fail uh it says it's the best part of
the show so maybe i failed successfully
uh just a heads up i'm a big fan of
growing cannabis comedy and also fish
bro did we just become best friends we
should hang out it says just wondering
if you ever thought about naming your
strains after a fish song or fish
lyrics as a fan purchasing a fish strain
would be a must i have thought about it
there's a concentrate by green dot they
call it reba jam which is definitely
named after of course reba if you're a
fish fan it's a good reba jam which uh
bag it tag it sell it to the butcher at
the store can't go wrong with that uh it
also says also is it possible to buy or
create and store male pollen that's a
whole totally different question so let
me ramble on about the fish part i do
have a couple of fish strain names in my
head but nothing has been
um
man if i'm gonna name something after
the band that changed my life that i
know if you're just listening and you
don't know uh what it's like to follow
fish around the country and go on tour
and see a bunch of shows uh that band
changed my life i learned a lot being
a fish follower a fish fan if i'm gonna
name something after that band or in
honor of that band it's gonna be
something amazing so i haven't found the
right one um maybe soon because i've got
a lot of great testers out there and
some new stuff coming up maybe
um if you've got any ideas but like tila
would be cool there's uh you could
gaiuty might be cool but if you've got
ideas of fish strain names i would love
to hear them send them to me of course
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy i want
to know your fish strain name
suggestions don't send me fish and stuff
send me the band fish it's a big
difference i don't need the uh
the [ __ ] i don't even know fish
refishing references but no fly fish or
og we don't need any of that no big
trout kush which hey somebody out there
use that uh if you've got like a a farmy
wildlife type of vibe a brand use that
bro big trout kush or [ __ ] big mouth
oh gee
[ __ ] there you go wild river kush oh
wait there's already a something coal
creek kush i said i wasn't gonna ramble
i told you i'd [ __ ] fail on that one
um now to the next part of this one is
it possible to buy or create and store
mail pollen i'm a medical cannabis
grower in massachusetts who loves
growing the dank i'm interested in
experimenting with seed making i love
how that evolution happens people get
super passionate growing cannabis and
then the next thing you know they're
making seeds i'm not discrediting you or
doubting you i love that passion i love
when people do that um then it says a
little bit nervous about keeping a male
in the house just wondering if it's
possible to buy or make and store male
pollen for later use feel free to use my
name say my name say my name big up to
our friend adam and my instagram which
is you enjoy my dank bro i've seen your
instagram around thank you for uh
following and supporting irie genetics
and the grow from your heart podcast
let's talk briefly about male pollen yes
um you can buy male pollen i uh
man i'm not a fan of buying or selling
male pollen i feel like if you're going
to breed plants if you're going to breed
cannabis if you're going to make your
own seeds you've got to do some of the
work buying pollen is
i don't wanna it's it's jus that's just
the cheap lazy way nope you didn't do
any selection how do you know that that
male is gonna be fire we know that
solomon is fire because i've tested him
so if you bought that pollen which i
won't sell um if you bought that you'd
know you've got winning pollen but if
you're just buying pollen from somebody
on the internet or some dude you're
trusting their selection process and
that's like letting them that's like
letting them pick your [ __ ] wife or
your husband or your mate and i'm not
down to let somebody else pick that for
me i'm not i'm not in an arranged
breeding project i'm in a selective
breeding project that's why i like to
choose i choose my male plants my female
plants based on criteria what is your
goal you don't know what that other
grower or breeder or selector that's all
they were we don't even know about them
they're a selector at this point we
don't know what their goal was we don't
know their education their knowledge uh
we have no idea what they chose why did
they choose that male plant
their ma made it just been a [ __ ] the
one that could have been the one male
plant they had now they're just using
pollen which that's cool if that's what
you're doing but do you really want to
make seeds out of just some male plant
or do you want a selected uh sought
after plant with traits and alleles and
things that you're after or do you just
want do you want the one i picked or the
one that you picked when we go to the
restaurant you want me to order dinner
for you or do you want to [ __ ] with the
menu and order your dinner that's how i
see it so i don't like buying pollen i'd
rather hunt out my own meals it's not
really that much work you just do it
just like you would females just find a
male ah you and then you've got it once
you've got the meal you've got it there
is more to it uh storing pollen yes you
can run a male plant so
you should have uh you're gonna finish a
seedless crop right you should have a
male plant in the veg and then right
when you finish or right before you
finish that crop put him in there and
let him start flowering out
collect his pollen and it's only going
to take him
14 21 25-ish days to start making plenty
of pollen for you to start catching it
and playing with it by day 26 27-28 he's
really busting a lot of pollen you can
cut him down gather the pollen and clean
up then you can just clean up the room
and can continue back on your normal
cycle so you can put yourself behind a
couple of weeks to get a male or you
can't have a male in another location in
the same grow space if you are careful
and know what you're doing
i've got a grow space
where i keep my main breeding area
inside that breeding area there's a
three by three grow tent that ducks the
ducting goes out of the tent and
directly out of the house so there's no
possibility of that pollen being
reintroduced to the main grow space it
goes directly outside the rest of it is
ducted inside that room but that one
tent ducts all the ducting directly
outside so it will never make the pollen
back into the room when i start
pollinating the boy he goes in there
early i get him ahead everybody else
when it's time for him to bust a nut i
just open up that tent slowly drag him
out sprinkle them all over the plants so
if you're careful about it you can keep
a boy in there depending on how much
pollen you need how long you keep them
around you only need them in flour for
10 i don't know more than 10 excuse me
for about 14 to 25 maybe 26 27 days you
can get pollen from him depending on how
many seeds you want to make how hard you
want to go you can get pollen then you
can store it let's talk briefly about
storing pollen before you store it so
collect it somehow i'm not sure how
you're going to collect it i would say
get a pyrex dish cut down the the top
part of the male plant set it in the
pyrex dish let it dry uh give it a tap
all the pollen will start falling out
pull out anything that is not pollen if
you've got male flowers in there leaves
in there buds in there get all of that
[ __ ] out we just want pollen let it dry
put a desiccant pack in there so it will
dry you don't want a boveda you want the
pack that sucks up all the moisture dry
that [ __ ] out get it as dry i'm going to
say dry about 12 or 30 more times get it
as dry as dry can dry it needs to be dry
any moisture in your pollen will destroy
it it will not be active so get it
what's the word dry pollen get it dry
get that pollen dry seal it up put it in
either a glass container some of those
little glass vials a glass jar or you
can put it in a baggie label it with the
male plant and the date which you
collected it then keep it in a cool dry
dark place i put mine in a brown paper
bag in the crisper drawer in the fridge
that's simply how i store my pollen um
don't open it too often don't take it
out of the fridge too much think about
condensation
think about temperature changes just
leave it in there until you need it then
take it out scoop out what you need do
your pollination you're safe that way be
careful with pollination turn off all
the fans um
if you just want to pollinate one or two
plants in the room take them out of the
room leave the rest in there pollinate
them spray them down a couple hours
later then put them back in the room
spray the rest of the [ __ ] in there
too so no pollen gets contaminated uh
water deactivates pollen so that will
help you out a lot the water will
destroy the pollen i think i've answered
most of these questions here um
uh keeping a mail yeah that's that's a
challenge sometimes just make sure you
don't pollinate the house uh you'll
figure it out that's you'll figure it
out you'll [ __ ] it up once or twice then
you'll figure it out that's all it
really takes uh you can buy pollen i
don't recommend it why not just do the
work why not get a pack of seeds you're
growing seeds or growing plants anyway
get some seeds find a dude that really
impresses you and then you've got a male
that nobody else has why do you want the
the male plant everybody else has got
that's boring to me
um
yeah you can store paul and you can
collect it and you can use it later in
the future i think i've answered your
question here my friend adam big up and
big thank you for the great question um
i look forward to your follow up i'm
sure you're going to have more to ask
after this all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters paul
and chuckers all of you sexy cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for supporting the grow
from your heart podcast could not do it
without you if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know that i would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from your heart
at hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback your constructive criticism i
am not afraid i'm not shy to hear what
you've got to say also if you feel like
the episode was educational informative
or entertaining maybe you just like to
throw me a buck all you got to do is
visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart once again all the
information is right there on that
screen if that was too fast check out
the website iriegenetics.com
everything is there the patreon the grow
help tab the discord link the merch
store the vendor links it is all there
once again iriegenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a big shout out to my buddy
sis 81 and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you