[Music]
so
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
this is episode 717
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to catch up on a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend all mixed up
let's send a big thank you shout out to
black hippie and mobius grows let's send
a fist bump and a thank you shout out to
rasta green thumb and single t let's
send a thank you shout out to dank
groves and just a smokin let's send a
fist bump in a thank you shout out to a
long time supporter my buddy godfather
kush let's send a fist bump in a thank
you shout out to a good friend my buddy
og purple thumb let's send a thank you
shout out to matt h let's send a big
fist bump to another good friend my
buddy dave's not here then let's wrap it
all up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to the red
eyed optimist big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends once again you guys
truly big thanks for the continued
patreon support the past couple of
months have been record setters and it
has been great so thank you once again
for all of that uh once again i want to
do send a big shout out to my friend
terp gooney i gave him a shout out on
the instagram live show i've mentioned
him on a couple of platforms but i want
to do it right here on the podcast big
shout out to my buddy terp gooney that's
right terp gooney got himself an irie
army tattoo and it looks fantastic i'll
try to include a picture of it here in
the show i should get permission from
him before doing so if he granted
permission there will be a photo of an
irie army tattoo that i think looks
impressive uh terp gooney is the third
person that i am aware of to get an irie
genetics or iri army tattoo that is
impressive that's amazing it blows my
mind that
i've created a brand uh community a
product
all of the above a service a vibe that
people would like to tattoo on their
bodies that shit's there forever dude
you can't forget and just scrape that
off one day and change your mind that
[ __ ] is there it's red yellow and green
on people's bodies that's amazing to me
so big shout out to my friends who show
mad support and mad love by getting my
brand tattooed on themselves that's
amazing to me it honestly blows my mind
it makes me rambly and speechless
because what the [ __ ] do you even say
when somebody tattoos your brand on them
you'll maybe you'll feel it one day i
hope you get to feel that sort of vibe
one day but i want to send a shout out
to terp gooney also i owe a shout out to
og purplethom perp tattooed an irie
tattoo on himself he did it to himself
and it looks good big up to our buddy
perp also shout out to uh the captain
and commander of the irie army my buddy
lemur priest has the og irie genetics
logo tattooed on himself that is a bad
[ __ ] uh rumor has it lemur is
gonna come hang out with me for a day or
two we're gonna go check out meow wolf
and have a good time so cannot wait for
that but you guys people have irie
tattoos on their bodies it blows my mind
uh that's tremendous that's amazing that
is brand loyalty that is friendship that
is community right there um i thought
about sometimes getting band logos
tattooed on me i want for a long time i
wanted a grateful dead steely on me
thought about the fish logo never did it
you guys got my logo tattooed on me i
don't even have a tattooed on me so
that's [ __ ] awesome thank you guys
here's where i'm headed if you have an
irie army irie genetics tattoo on
yourself and i don't know about it yet
please remind me send me an update let
me know about that [ __ ] because i do and
will send you gifts if you've got my
logo my brand tatted on you and it's
real don't just go draw some [ __ ] so i
send you a gift you guys i want to see a
real tattoo and i can tell because these
this dude had red and blood and [ __ ] in
his tattoo it was real bro you could see
that you showed me the stencil the
outline and then the work and it was
[ __ ] awesome but if you guys got real
irie tattoos i read genetics tattoos you
can't just say stay irie or be irie on
your butt or whatever it's got to be
irie genetics irie army roster jeff grow
from your heart something in that vein
if it's my brand i will send you gifts
not just one gift sometimes i make new
products and you may just randomly get a
box with new [ __ ] in it ask our buddy
lemur ask perp randomly they just get
[ __ ] in the mail because they've got
irie genetics tattoos
all right i feel like i've talked for a
long time about that this podcast has
been long already we haven't covered a
damn thing let me jump into the next
topic that i do have written down i do
have a psa this is a public service
announcement this is a message from ross
to jeff uh one of those the more you
know except mine would say the more you
grow right that's what i'm thinking here
uh shout out to whatever i took dabs of
also it's got me in the right [ __ ]
zone shout out to whoever put a smile on
my face for valentine's day you know who
you is who you are my psa goes like this
um you guys
a lot of times i get messages and emails
from people who um
have a really cool company name which is
cool if your company name is like uncle
jim's [ __ ] big weed farm that's cool
uh stoner bob's i almost said stoner
dave i got a friend named stoner dave
i'm not singling you out you don't use
stoner dave as your business name that's
your name but uh stoner dave's pot farm
is a really cool name i know what you do
i know who you are
but if we do business i might have to
mail you a package to stoner dave's pot
farm and i don't like that [ __ ] at all
you guys when you're naming your company
let's think about um stuff like that
you're going to have to have packages
mailed to you i don't like putting
stoner dave's pot farm in my shipping
app when i mail things to people if it's
a t-shirt or a pack of seeds i don't
like it um the kid at the post office
the old lady at the post office the old
man the transgendered person working at
the post office that is ageless or
sexless gotta be careful nowadays that
person may see that package that says
stoner dave's pot farm they're like well
i to know what the [ __ ] is in there and
they may they have the ability the
option the opportunity to be a shady
[ __ ] and open it up they may have just
stolen your t-shirt your seeds or both
and i don't want that to happen
so
just a public service announcement from
a guy who's been doing business for a
long time um who's got maybe maybe more
steps ahead of you in business maybe
just some ideas maybe it's just my
opinion let's be more careful about
naming our companies you can name your
company stoner dave's pot farm but you
can also have an llc or a doing business
as name that i can mail [ __ ] to and talk
about more openly in my business affairs
that it's not obvious that we're just
doing weed business i know that stoner
dave's platform is a cool name but it
doesn't look good on shipping it doesn't
look good on invoices and it definitely
here's the other thing i want to talk
about if you start a business
you've got to pay taxes do you really
want to send something to the irs the
government the state and the city with
stoner dave's pot farm written on it
unless it's a cultivation or a
dispensary those are the only things i'd
really do that to and still i don't name
those
obvious [ __ ] pothead things i try to
stay a little bit businessy professional
but naming your company is very
important
i have to put the name of your company
on an invoice i have to put it on a
package it goes on a tax report so that
stuff
uh i'm dealing with right now because
i'm mailing a package to somebody who's
i'm like really bro is that really the
name you want me to put on that package
i'm not going to do that you're going to
get initials is what you're going to get
on your package so just the idea you're
basically dry snitching on yourself if
you put um
[ __ ] dank weed llc and you live in an
apartment building
that may ring some bells that may uh
that may get your apartment building
checked out you know what i'm saying so
just be smarter with the names you're
dry snitching on yourself be careful be
serious also i'm mailing this [ __ ] to
your house uh it's coming to your front
door it has passed a bunch of hands that
have all read stoner dave's pot farm at
this address and i know exactly where
that is i'm putting your address your
name and then possibly taxes on it i've
rambled on enough about that i think you
get the point you guys ah it's cool to
have a business but let's kind of uh and
it's cool to get [ __ ] shipped to you but
let's separate our instagram fame from
our business name uh my company is
iriegenetics i make irigenetic seeds i
do not use that as my uh that's a two
that's a doing business as name that's
not what we're listed as doesn't know
where the business names are there are
umbrellas to keep that stuff a little
bit more careful be careful you guys it
is a fun revolution a fun evolution that
we're coming from the black market the
dark ages too the free market the green
age the revolution the evolution of
cannabis is great but don't get ahead of
yourself don't get overzealous um don't
create a name that's going to get you
noticed in the wrong way by the wrong
people and if you are doing business if
you're creating an llc or whatever be
careful with those taxes get your tax
person your lawyer your account people
get all those people in line so you can
do [ __ ] correctly especially if you're
gonna name your [ __ ] stoner dave's pot
farm if stoner dave's spot farm doesn't
pay their taxes i cannot wait to come
check you out that's that's just [ __ ]
begging for stuff so be careful you guys
that is my public stoner announcement
check yourself when you're naming your
stuff instagram it is cool being [ __ ]
stoner dave's ganja farm that grows the
best weed and smokes nine pounds a day
that's a cool [ __ ] name on instagram
i don't want to put that in my shipping
app i don't want to make an invoice with
that don't want to turn that into the
tax people don't even want to [ __ ] with
that so be a little bit uh let's step
out of that and i'm i read genetics you
guys are paying irene you're not paying
irene genetics it's not what shows up on
anything when you pay so let's just be
more careful that's all i'm getting at
now let's move forward i do have another
uh not quite a public service
announcement this isn't this is an
invitation
advertising um last year i did talk
about the groovy gravy secret stash seed
exchange event guess what ladies and
gentlemen it is happening again that's
right uh march 26th at an undisclosed
location in denver it is an easy to
access location it's a cool place we
just have to be uh can't reveal the
location yet for logistical purposes
however
it is a cool place there will be a seed
sales event that's right irie genetics
and many other industry leading breeders
will be at this event slang and beans
come get some seeds possibly have some
t-shirts there maybe some other merch
depending on what is still left in stock
we've been blowing out the store the
past couple months uh get some merch get
some beans uh there will be seed
breeders food trucks rumor has it there
may be live glass blowing that hasn't
been confirmed i think that was on the
list of things that i read and heard
about but make sure you check out the
groovy gravy secret stash on instagram
check out groovy gravy
super cool name there nothing suspicious
doesn't get you thinking that they're
doing anything weird groovy gravy check
him out but be prepared because march
26th irie genetics will be attending the
groovy gravy secret stash round two in
denver colorado come get some beans come
get the soccer souffle come get the
machine come get some blue raspberry
truffles some lady marmalade i know
there will be sun kiss and strawberry
starburst there could be some femmes
available that we're going to talk about
um on the next episode we'll save that
for the next episode we'll talk about
some of the [ __ ] coming up because i've
been rambling for quite a while here we
haven't talked any about about any of
the emails no cannabis related content
people are going to say this show didn't
start until it was 45 minutes in it's
only gonna be a 30 minute show i love
you trolls on the internet you guys are
beautiful
um let's jump into some of the emails
here because i do have quite a few in
front of me this one's labeled 717
that's this episode what do you know
this episode goes a little bit like this
i found this one on youtube i don't
usually take comments from youtube i
don't read them on the show a lot it's
easier to email me this one was good it
was worth it it says what did you do
with the spider i really want to know a
big shout out to my buddy slim ass
that's a good question that shows me
you've been watching listening for quite
a while if you've been paying attention
a few episodes back i discovered a
spider in my grow room it was a little
fuzzy spider
in california we call them mexican
jumping spiders i don't know the uh the
greek name i don't know the species
[ __ ] i don't know the genotype i
don't know phenotype what we got in
there i don't know the cross i don't
know it's mom and dad phenotype and
parents i don't know the f1 of this
spider i know it was a little fuzzy ugly
[ __ ] spider and he looked like he
wasn't causing any problems he wasn't
making any webs and in my opinion he was
working security he was eating fungus
gnats white flies whatever may have
chosen to pop into that grow room he was
working security and taking those
[ __ ] out cause i didn't see any bugs
in there for a while this question said
what did you do with the spider bro i
didn't do anything with the spider uh
you just quit popping up he quit coming
around he's gone he either migrated or
died or uh he's [ __ ] somewhere else
he traveled somewhere else into that
area and he's just hiding out hanging
out now got bored uh maybe he got tired
of the grow lights maybe he got stoned
maybe he's done i don't know he's
probably dead by now i don't know how
long a little mexican jumping spider
lives but i just disappeared i didn't
kill him i didn't do anything to uh get
rid of him i didn't do anything to keep
him around either it was business as
usual i kept an eye on him he kept an
eye on me or she i just gender assigned
that spider and i have no idea but
eventually it disappeared and that's the
end of the story bro i don't know it
just disappears like a dog it wandered
off and that was it so uh thanks for
asking i'll let the spider know you
asked about it if i see it again i'll
shake his hand for you and tell him you
said what's up big shout out to our
friend i'll shake all eight of his
[ __ ] hands could you imagine shaking
hands with spider doing the the homie
high fives what's up bro shabang bang
bang bang bang bang bang bang bang bang
i'm [ __ ] high i told you all right
shout out to my buddy slim s i don't
know whatever happened to that spider i
hope he's well hope you found a nice
spider wife and had some beautiful
spider kids somewhere the [ __ ] else not
here all right this message came from
patreon patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart that's my favorite place
to find messages this one came from my
buddy midnight samurai what's up buddy
great grow great photos great updates
and a great patreon question or it's
actually a comment it says dude the
fried pb j has been a staple in my life
since college for about 20 years
if you've listened to the episode or the
7-eleven episode that was about munchies
i talked about putting a peanut butter
and jelly sandwich in a pan and frying
that [ __ ] up just like you would a
grilled cheese sandwich the peanut
butter gets all melty the jelly gets all
melty in there it makes this gooey
delightful texture get that bread just a
little bit crispy oh my goodness that's
a stoner snack that you cannot believe
uh this dude said i have not once burnt
the [ __ ] out of my mouth because i can
never wait um bro same i probably got
scars and a reshaped mouth and a burnt
palate because of many numerous fried or
grilled peanut butter and jelly
sandwiches do you guys call it fried or
grilled because it's the same thing
you're throwing that [ __ ] it's
grilled cheese when you put peanut
butter in that [ __ ] but my grandma
always called a fried pb j shout out to
grandma rest in peace love you i miss
you she's the one that introduced me to
the grilled or fried peanut butter and
jelly sandwich and
my lady taught me a lot of things and
that is one of the top of the list
things that i'm gonna remember forever
bro if you haven't done it yet make a
peanut butter and jelly sandwich butter
that [ __ ] on both sides throw in a pan
until that peanut butter starts gushing
out the sides and the bread gets a
little [ __ ] crispy
thank me later
send me an email or patreon.com forward
slash girl from here that's the way to
do it all right i'm stoned i'm telling
you we're through two of the emails
already we're like 20 minutes into this
episode let's jump into this one this
one says hey irie did i give a shout out
to midnight samurai yeah shout out to
midnight samurai this one came from our
friend do they want their name said
let's see i'm gonna call you leo what up
leo this one came from our friend leo
says hello irie what up leo nice to meet
you brother says is it somehow possible
to grow and collect pollen from multiple
male plants and strains in one tent
while keeping pollen separated or should
it only be one male plant per tent then
it follows up with what is the beth okay
we're going to talk about two different
questions here the next part is what is
the best method for growing and
collecting pollen from multiple male
strains um all right so this is a really
good question the question here is can i
put basically can i put multiple dudes
in a tent and collect the pollen from
those and then know what that pollen is
my answer is no bro i would not try that
i would not do that i would not
recommend that
um
there's no way to prevent pollen from
this plant just drifting over to this
plant this pollen drifting over to this
one you have no way of knowing which
pollen is which even if you do go tap
that plant get pollen out of it the
first one you touch that pollen is going
all over all of the plants now everyone
you touch is the first one plus the
second one and then when you touch the
second one now you're just compounding
you see what i'm saying you're gonna
have number one you might be cool number
two you're gonna have number one and
number two number three is gonna be one
two and three and four is gonna be a
[ __ ] of every meal plan in there
so uh i replied to our friend leo and i
said i would stick with one male plant
in the room or you're going to have a
mori povich situation nobody gonna know
who the baby daddy is
if that's okay with you that's fine but
i like to know pedigree and history of
the plants there's a reason a rhyme and
a reason why i'm making the cross i want
that selected male to do a certain thing
if you're just trying to do an open
pollination of multiple plants to make
seeds for fun you can do multiple males
it is not uncommon to take let's say we
wanted to make an arise open pollination
just to make a bunch more arise seeds
show diversity and see what is in that
seed line i would take a pack of males
or a pack of a rice seeds a number 10 20
30 seeds whatever you got room for time
for space
grow them you're going to find a number
of males and a number of females
i would kind of maybe pull out a couple
things that are not not exactly what i
want pull them out take them out of
there but then leave a few males and a
few females in there they're all arise
and just do an open pollination now
you've got we'll just say a rise f3 open
pollination with three or four males and
five females and then when i sell them
or talk about them i would list
descriptions of each male and female and
then we would just see what comes out of
there that's a beautiful open
pollination because that shows diversity
amongst all of those different uh is it
genotypes and phenotypes in that one
because we're gonna see genotypes from
the two different genes crossing and
phenotypes from different expressions
gonna see a lot of different [ __ ] by
crossing that open pollination different
males to different females
but the problem with that in my opinion
you don't know who the baby daddy is so
if you want to make more of those you
don't know which male to grab and which
female to grab to make that happen
but at the same time as a breeder as a
somebody who wants to see a lot of
expression a lot of things a lot of
traits i want a lot of data is what i'm
trying to say i love that open
pollination because it lets me know what
is in there somewhere i may not know
exactly where it is but i know it's in
that pack i know somewhere i can find
that [ __ ] plant and i can breed that
again and create it shows me potential
so unless you're doing an open
pollination to forward one line i
wouldn't do this if you've got like a
male of arise and a male of jack the
ripper and a male of candy store i
wouldn't do that i would have one dude
in there i would get his pollen and i
would work with him otherwise the best
way to say it bro you're gonna have a
baby daddy situation there's no way to
keep that pollen separated i would not
do that if you really want to collect
pollen from multiple males i would
stagger them i would flower one out it
only takes a few days to get pollen
maybe 21 days to get plenty of pollen
out of that dude ah get pollen cut him
down clean it up start over get another
dude you could have the other guy
vegging just have him on standby all you
do is throw him into flour as soon as
you're done cleaning up or
like two days before you cut down
because you're gonna get time there's
time ahead before the pollen starts
coming as long as you can clean up the
old pollen before the new pollen starts
coming you can perpetually make pollen
for yourself
now don't contaminate that pollen don't
cross that pollen there's more to the
question that i do want to cover what's
the best method for growing and
collecting pollen from multiple uh i
wouldn't do that so that answers the
second part there um like you to save
after separating from yeah i just would
not do that uh definitely wouldn't have
multiple dudes in there um
i'm reading this quietly to myself to
make sure i covered it multiple strains
and having a few different males you'd
like to save after seven yeah i just
wouldn't do that dude it's not gonna
work the way that you want it to um it's
gonna be that maury povich situation
just like i'm talking about who is the
father you're not the father maybe you
are the father if you want to make seeds
if you want something to play with that
is really cool that could really work
for you but if you want something uh to
put to market to make f2s with uh to
really work on i would kinda um i
wouldn't do that that's that's the
bottom line there all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers clone cutters
pollen chuckers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there i want to
thank you once again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast this may be a short
episode i'm testing a new sd card and my
device is flickering so i'm not sure if
i'm recording the audio or not let's
hope for the best prepare for the worst
make it a short show that way if it
doesn't work out i didn't waste all this
material we could re-record and do it
again and make a quality show for you
you guys didn't really care any about
all of that but that's what is really
happening
straight up transparency here quick show
good times thank you for hanging out
love you make sure you check out the
email grow from your heart hotmail.com
check out the website
iregenetics.com like and subscribe check
out the patreon patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart i think
that's all i've got for you i want to
make sure i've recorded it i'm going to
go edit this down make sure we got a
good show i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content stay tuned
because my best friend white mike will
be here for episode 719 i maybe have
multiple best friends i should say one
of my best friends white mike will be
here for episode 719
stay tuned check him out we got a good
show prepared for you i bought another
microphone he'll be sitting right here
maybe over here
i haven't decided what side we're going
to put him on i think i want to drive i
want to be on the driver's side that's
over here i'm not sure which side of the
camera makes that look like it may be
flipped who knows but mike will be here
for episode 719 718. i've got a bunch of
emails here in front of me i'm going to
save this one because it's kind of
longer than i was prepared for guys i'm
rambling i said quick episode i
stretched not made it long for no reason
thanks for hanging out i love you more
than fat kids love cake i'll be back in
a couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a big shout out to dave's not
here and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you