ugh
[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode 718
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on more
listener emails before i get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend freakfish let's send a big
thank you shout out to the big sexy dank
and kes burton let's send a thank you
shout out to north north terps and
josiah w let's send a big fist bump to
my buddy don't tread on me420 listen to
thank you shout out to ned denver and
lefty listen to thank you shout out to
girls grow two and pack northwest dan
let's send a big thank you shout out to
adhd grower let's send a special thank
you shout out to my buddy zackson
starker then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to sacred tree
organic farms big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends i do want to send you
a special patreon thank you you may have
noticed on social media i did buy a new
microphone i call it the mic mic that's
right i'm looking at it right now it's
over there on the production setup table
that's what that table is called that's
the official name there's a new
microphone there's a cloud lifter
there's a mic stand there's a set of
headphones we've got mic all set up
ready to record episode 719 and that was
contributed that was supported that was
funded by the great folks from patreon a
lot of people ask where that money goes
what happens to it there's a good
example you guys bought mike hey mike so
thank you for the mike mike
and also big shout out to white mike for
joining me for episode seven one nine he
should be here in just a couple of hours
we've got a great show planned for you
but really thank you guys for the
patreon support that patreon support
does help fund things like the mic mic
the cloud lifter one time the cloud
lifter that's what powers this
microphone uh the microphone runs to a
thing that gives it juice and then that
runs to a recording device uh patreon
paid for the microphone the mic arm the
cords the power uh the recording device
the editing computer uh that is the
stuff that the patreon pays for also
pays for the website pays for the web
service here so that we can post the
show uh businessy things come out of the
patreon account to keep it keep it a
legit business you guys that's what
we're trying to do uh that is my report
for the fiscal year 2021 let's move on i
don't know why i wanted you to know what
we do with the patreon money i wanted to
thank you and let you know what i do
with the funding that you provide i try
to put it back into the show in some
sort of way uh if i need equipment there
is some stuff in an account that if [ __ ]
goes wrong i can buy maybe an ipad a
computer a microphone whatever breaks
like a [ __ ] camera you guys know that
camera two can kiss my ass we may
replace that eventually um but there may
be another camera you never know that's
what happens with the patreon i'm high
on rambling thank you that is the main
point here i want to send another thank
you to all of the people who warned me
that a couple of the audio episodes were
not posting and populating on the audio
server feeds i am posting it the way
that i'm supposed to i did what i am
required supposed to knowledgeable of
doing and for some reason the feeds just
were not catching the files that i was
posting some of the audio services
didn't have uh 7 14 15 and possibly 16
that issue has been corrected all of
those episodes are now to the best of my
knowledge those episodes are now on
apple podcast spotify stitcher radio pod
bean uh all that stuff i cannot get
google to update so if you guys are
watching listening waiting for the show
on google podcast i can't get it to
update i don't know why i've messaged
them contact customer service they don't
give a [ __ ] so that's always gonna suck
and be slow there also somebody asked
why there's only so many episodes on
spotify
that is not up to me i don't get to
decide that spotify
decides how much space they're going to
dedicate to the show guys like joe rogan
they get an unlimited [ __ ] feed you
can put it all up there people with
smaller audiences smaller viewerships
less numbers less clicks they get less
uh room on the feed they don't think you
want to listen to more than a hundred
episodes of my nonsense yet so they only
give me server space bandwidth space
storage space for my most 100 recent
episodes that's not up to me that is a
spotify issue i do believe apple podcast
hosts like 300 of my shows maybe more i
don't go check that the listeners tell
me this sort of stuff but
if you are upset frustrated complaining
bent uh vexed in some way that older
episodes have disappeared from spotify i
do apologize that's nothing i can
control until we get more listens more
viewership uh then they will add our
library will be much longer but until
then that's just what they do uh in the
meantime you can check out all of the
episodes on the youtube channel every
episode uh up till from like episode 20
i think all the way up should be on the
youtube server and the older episodes
are on the old channel agro culture
which has been defunct and that i think
i share them somewhere you should be
able to find everything on the grow from
your heart uh podcast youtube it should
all be there check it out there also
click like and subscribe because that's
where uh the numbers count the most for
me when i'm doing advertising and
promotion and sales people want to see
the youtube numbers that's where i count
so uh do that also the main point here
was thank you to everybody that lets me
know that sometimes the shows aren't
populating i don't know because i don't
watch the show i don't listen to the
show i do make sure that youtube comes
up the other servers i can't check on as
regularly so i do rely on you and i do
thank you i'm grateful for the teamwork
that you guys do provide me for letting
me know that my show did not populate on
some servers all right i do have more
notes to cover
i am almost ready for more testers i
know i'm opening the [ __ ] floodgates
for my email inbox here here it comes
but i am ready i've got more seeds
coming we made more seeds we're making
more seeds we have more seeds in
progress i say we because um i talk
about i make and touch every single seed
that comes from iregenetics i do have
some helpers now um i needed more space
i'm using spaces to make more seeds it
will work out for everybody it's all
rosta jeff touched approved and done but
we needed more spaces we were expanding
the team don't worry quality control
will be everything it has been that
being said i need more testers to
maintain quality control
there's a podcast let me find that
before i even go any further tell you
which episode it is there's a grow from
your heart podcast tester episode i'm
typing in that right now all right check
out episode if you would like to be a
tester the first step to test seeds for
ire genetics number one the prerequisite
you don't qualify until you do this you
must watch and pay close attention to
episode
590 of the grow from your heart podcast
that episode is all about becoming a
seed tester for my brand if you'd like
to test for me that is the very first
step check out episode 590 of this
podcast it's here on youtube check it
out that will help you a lot once you
watch that you'll be given some hints
and tips and you'll know more what to do
the next thing i will require you to do
is to join my discord i would really
like to have all of the testers on
discord in the discord tab that helps me
out tremendously when looking for test
reports for info for details for photos
i can go to one place it is all there
really makes it easy so watch the
episode join my discord post in the
tester tab that you have watched the
videos that lets me know you're paying
attention and following instructions
there are more steps
you will get those steps when you follow
these proper instructions the reason i
make you follow instructions is because
i'm not giving out free seeds to give
out free seeds i expect things in return
for these seeds i need detailed reports
i need feedback i need communication if
you can't follow a few instructions to
get these seeds i can't [ __ ] with you to
give you free seeds that's just how it
is a little bit of work to get you some
beans to show you qualify to be on the
team as all this is so
um listen to the episode join the
discord send the correct email the way
it's been asked for then wait for a
reply
please do not feel like i have ignored
you blown you off discredited you
discredited you if i do not reply
promptly
i am only looking for a certain amount
of testers at this time and i'm going to
get an overwhelming amount of responses
if i don't reply to you if i don't send
you a message
just wait because this is one phase of
testing that is going to happen this
year and i will do many many phases of
testing
if i don't [ __ ] with you this time and
you send me a bunch of messages saying
why didn't you pick me why didn't you
pick me i won't pick you next time if
you're cool about it i may pick you next
time randomly it could be two weeks it
could be two months i may just say oh
listener number 7504 sent an email and
they want to be a tester and i like
their app it's at the top of the list
they didn't qualify the last two phases
because i had my number that's all it is
i reach a number of testers i send them
i wait for reports to start coming once
i'm satisfied i send more it's kind of
just phases timing when i've got timing
when i need it you may be at the top of
the list so just wait you may be on the
next phase i'll send you a message
saying hey bro you ready to be a tester
do you have room and if you do guess
what now is your chance so do not get
discouraged if i don't reach out to let
you test right the [ __ ] now it may be in
the near future you may be at the top of
the list i may be waiting for you for a
specific reason maybe i know that you do
a certain thing maybe i know you don't
do a certain thing and i need that
coming up be patient don't blow your
slot by blowing me up with too many
negative emails i understand we all get
impatient we all get eager i get it it's
just me
i am the one
packaging the tester seeds selecting the
testers reading the email applications
loading up the beans into packages
putting them in shipping checking the
test reports it's just me so be patient
there are a lot of you one of me i love
each and every one of you but we've got
to work together also um i said this is
not the only phase
i may randomly select you next time so
be patient there are a lot of regular
seeds out there being tested now if
you're following the discord tester
group you know that i've got three uh
testers out there right now that people
finally kind of know what they've got i
revealed what they've got i waited a
long time to tell people there's a bubba
kush to arise that has been in testing
it is going to pass that will be
released i have decided the name of that
one there is um a rise f1 number four
across to jack the ripper that will pass
testing i approve i've got a name for
that you guys will love the name i'll
tell you the names of that in the future
and there's another one that people
can't figure out quite what the cross is
um
that one is going to pass testing also
so far it looks like but there's a lot
of regular seeds in testing now i've got
new regular seeds coming soon
that will be released we'll announce the
names of the things i just told you
about pretty soon
i am personally making more of the older
stuff that needs restocks the golden
goats the lemon jeffries the orange gas
i'm making more of that also making more
blue pill and red pill for official
release also more stuff in there there
could be
do i tell you that i put chernobyl in
the room to get pollinated by a reversed
golden goat do i tell you that i did
that do we talk about that anyway we're
going to move forward i will not tell
you the name idea that i have that'll
need to be tested also i'm making new
films in another location that you guys
don't even know about we have pollen
we've reversed a plant and we have
pollinated the gorilla glue 4 the chem 4
possibly blue raspberry truffle quite a
few things with a reversal to make some
great femmes those will need testing
very soon they're being harvested now uh
being packaged up as soon as they're
ready we'll get them out for testing so
there's a lot of great [ __ ] coming up
lots of testing and restocking to be
done don't be discouraged don't get shy
don't send too many hate mails if you
don't get selected to be a tester right
now there are more phases coming a lot
of opportunity this year to be a tester
if you're already a tester and you'd
like to test again if you've done what
you considered a successful test run
reach out on the discord now is a good
time to get yourself in line
if you've already done testing and
you've got a recommendation for another
tester send me that recommendation if
they have applied and you recommended
them and you're already on the team that
does help you out but be careful with
your recommendations don't taint your
reputation
i said taint all right let's keep moving
forward i've been talking about testing
for a long time this was not meant to be
a testing episode but here we are i want
to remind you about the groovy gravy
secret stash seed event coming up in
denver that's right i've got all of the
details right here in front of me let me
pull that up i did not prepare and put
that on my screen okay i magically
remember the date because of technology
march 26th in denver colorado the groovy
gravy secret stash seed event will be
happening once again irie genetics
premium seeds and many other of your
favorite top seed makers will be there
slang in the beans come grab some seeds
possibly get some t-shirts get a hug get
a high five take a selfie with me come
meet irie genetics white mike should be
there if things work out who knows who
else i might bring it'll be a good time
i'll be there high-fiving giving hugs
giving kisses i do not think it is a
consumption-friendly event so i will not
be given dabs but show up let's have a
good time i will have saka souffle the
machine blue raspberry truffle lady
marmalade strawberry starburst sun kiss
and possibly some of these new femmes
that i've been teasing you about to
share
come join the party don't miss it check
out groovygravy on instagram for more
information and uh just follow me on
instagram i'll be posting more stuff
about the groovy gravy event very soon
i'm looking to see where i can lead you
but so far i think groovy gravy is the
way to go don't miss the event you guys
look forward to being there look forward
to seeing you last year was a huge
success you saw the photos people were
mad they missed it don't be mad at
yourself for missing it this year join
the party
all right i think that covers all of the
business and rambles here at the start
of the show i know that was a long time
but we got a lot of ground covered let's
talk about some of these emails that i
have received recently my inboxes have
been blowing up please do not stop
sending me messages like i said before
it's just me so if i don't reply right
away i apologize but occasionally i'll
stay up super late and just answer a
bunch of emails and get a lot of [ __ ]
done i may reply to you don't get mad
don't get upset i do appreciate the
messages and i love that grow help tab
on the website let's get down to
business we've got a couple of emails
here in front of me this one came from
another mouse we don't have a name on
here no signature this one says yo ross
to jeff just wanted to let you know i've
been watching since a little bit before
episode 700. well welcome to the party
bro i'm glad you're joining us it says i
just want to say man i really have been
enjoying the shows i'm a long time
smoker never grown i'm debating on
whether i should do it in my apartment
or wait till i get a house i'd say wait
till you get the house bro wait till you
get a house
but in the meantime i'm loving watching
your show
you're very entertaining and funny as
[ __ ] i appreciate that bro um it's not a
comedy show but i do feel like
i hate learning i love learning i hated
school i hate being bombarded with
information that makes my brain frazzled
and confused and in school i didn't care
about half the [ __ ] they were teaching i
love these kind of lessons but it makes
your brain work better if you get a joke
and some laughter in the middle it's
like a treat it's like training a dog if
i run you through the obstacle course
make you sit stay lay down roll over
jump over this thing crawl under this
thing give you a treat it works a lot
better if i don't ever give you the
treat just [ __ ] abusing you so i feel
like a little laughter a little fun
that's a treat for your brain everybody
works better with a smile on their face
a joke will make everybody smile um so
i'm glad you're digging the the jokes
the funny part of the vibe here uh i do
have a comedian spirit comedy is one of
my favorite things you guys know me i
love to go to comedy shows and see
comedy comedy uh best thing on the
planet one of the knowledge one of the
best things on the planet comedy
laughter is medicine let me keep going
i'm [ __ ] rambling uh funny as [ __ ] my
wife doesn't even smoke but she watches
with me because you're [ __ ] hilarious
keep up the great work man can't wait to
get some seeds from you much love bro
dude and your wife ah mrs bro and dude
thank you i'm glad you guys are loving
the show i'm glad you guys are watching
together cannot wait for you to get that
new house together get growing get [ __ ]
going you guys can both listen to the
show and then get in the garden together
make it a bonding experience with uh do
you say wife or girlfriend where are we
wife make it a bonding experience with
the wife you can bring your girlfriend
too if your wife allows you hey don't
slap him for that i said it um but
make it a bonding experience in the
growth space there you guys can grow
your medicine together maybe grow some
his and hers meds bro maybe i challenge
you to let her grow a couple plants that
you don't [ __ ] with and you grow a
couple that she don't [ __ ] with you guys
have your own and i bet you she'll be a
better grower than you because the women
have a special touch when it comes to
the ganja plants to all plants dude they
just are magical so let the wife get in
there once you get that grow going and
bro thank you for the great compliments
thank you for listening i'm glad you
find me entertaining and funny as [ __ ]
also love it that the wife is listening
and watching i love knowing people are
doing [ __ ] together big vibes big love
keep watching you guys so when you get
that grow going i look forward to all of
your cultivation and cannabis culture
questions they didn't sign it there's no
name here so big shout out to my new
anonymous couple friends all right this
one came from patreon this one is from
our buddy terp gooney we gave turp
gooney a shout out in the last episode
this bad [ __ ] has an irie army
tattoo he's got the cross with irie army
above it i don't even have that so he's
cooler than me right now
he sent a compliment it says your
pendant on the 712 episode is [ __ ]
awesome that is straight fire i'm gonna
move the microphone out of the way kind
of show you the pendant for a moment
then we'll get right back to the podcast
but i agree this pendant is straight
[ __ ] fire i may just drop in a photo
of it because moving the mic might not
do a lot but here's what it looks like
it is
a number of pastel like colors
in what looks to be like a bloom type of
a flower possibly a lotus might have
been what they were going for i just
realized that as i'm looking at it at
this angle uh with an ohm sign in the
middle of it right it says ohm right in
the middle of it um i saw this at a
glass shop i actually saw two of them
and i thought i know somebody that would
love that i'm going to get us those
matching pendants and so big shout out
to the person who has the other pendant
that looks just like this she knows who
she is she doesn't want the shout out on
the show she's kind of shy
but had to grab the pendy there's
another person out there rocking a match
to this and i think it's super awesome
this came from our friend uh glass by
blake on instagram check out glass
underscore by underscore blake on
instagram he makes a lot of great [ __ ]
there's more stuff i'm gonna buy uh he's
got a murakami pindy that i've really
got my eye on i think you may have sold
it that may be a blessing in disguise or
a blessing in the skies depending on who
you are um but big shout out to blake
wingard glass glass by blake for the
pendy and big thanks to my buddy terp
gooney for noticing the dope pendant
also shout out to positively vibes in
denver that's where i picked it up great
place great folks there the owner is
super cool the staff is super cool heady
glass kicking ass
i don't know why i even said that but
the place is cool let's keep going i do
have a question here this is the one i'm
looking for why did i get my notes mixed
up you guys saw it happen
this one comes from our friend andrew
and andrew says what's up ross to jeff i
recently finished my first run of
producing seeds isn't that a fun
exciting project except this ends in
tragedy this is a tragedy i will warn
you it says it was dark hollow or it was
a fun and unexpected unexpected project
and then i jumped ahead of line while i
was popping a bag of dark hollow i
stumbled upon the stinkiest male plant
i've ever smelled that one's gonna have
some stinky [ __ ] in there that dark
hollow male plant was probably a champ
it says great structure vigorous and an
intense garlicky funk that's hard to
describe i love it but i can almost
smell it in my mind because i know that
plant so well
it goes on it says i happen to have an
extra xanadu female and some extra space
i know what's going to happen here bro
you put them on a date quick summary it
says i kept them very small and then he
does go on to kind of describe the grow
a little bit fabric pots soil
synthetic help mars hydro uh everything
seemed to be great very healthy all the
way through i got a ton of very healthy
looking seeds
but here's where we turn to tragic
tragedy strategy i think it's a tragedy
however you want to say it this is where
the [ __ ] up part happens but the seeds
have shells made of vibranium after
several attempts at every method of
germinating soaking scarring scraping
cracking etc i finally got two seeds to
crack through the shell and this was
about after 25 attempts after examining
the other failed tries it appears that
the seed was trying to push the root
through but none of them were capable of
cracking the seed shell yes that does
make sense i've got a reason why and
possibly another tester solution you
could try it says i usually have good
germination techniques any idea what i
may have done to cause this i love your
show i love your seeds love your vibe in
general be well from my new friend
andrew andrew big love big respect thank
you for the great question i do have
feedback perhaps possibly an answer here
let's talk about what i think could have
gone wrong in your grow number one
answer i think you let the seeds go for
too long they should have been harvested
earlier they simply got too thick too
tough too strong because they were there
too long i've seen this happen i've done
this
um there's not much you can do now
except next time cut them down earlier
maybe go through and find the seeds you
think might really germ pull those out
try them
also i've seen a thing called the seed
cracker you could probably deal with a
pair of pliers or whatever else you got
but you're going to [ __ ] up some seeds
doing it there's a little device that
you put a seed in it and you twist a
handle and the seed goes crack and it
kind of pops the shell for you then you
attempt to germ it uh that may work for
you that may help you out but the bottom
line the real answer here straight up
without any [ __ ] without buttering
it up without sugar coating it i think
those seeds grew for too long and
they're all going to be probably
problematic it could be a silicate issue
it could be a feed issue it could be
something like that honestly i'm going
to say that this was a timing issue
those seeds simply uh they went too long
they got too hard and now they're just
too hard and too tough and too thick
that's really what i do think happened
to your seeds i wish i had better advice
i wish i had info on how to correct that
because you've got a batch of seeds i
don't know how many you made uh it
doesn't really say but you bought 25 of
them so you must have a nice number when
you make seeds you guys you make a lot
of seeds so you probably got a lot to
play with it's a bummer that it's not a
winner but it's cool that it was just
kind of a side project that you did
learn from so take this as a learning
lesson how long did you flower did you
take notes were you pulling seeds off
occasionally and squeezing them here's a
way we can correct this in the future
the next time you're making seeds
start pulling them out of the plant and
checking on them a little bit earlier
than you did this time when i know that
seeds are getting close or not even
close when i'm getting antsy and anxious
and nervous and want more beans i'll go
to the plant and i'll just pick a nug
somewhere on the plant i'll just reach
in and pull a seed right out you can see
them you can feel them if you can't
there are no seeds yours were obviously
hard enough start pulling a few out rub
the shell off put in your hands squeeze
it does it explode does it pop is it
crunch does it crack or does it leave a
dent in your fingers if they start
leaving dents in your fingers they're
close to done are they tiger striped are
they the color you want are they solid
start paying attention to that then you
can prevent leaving them for too long
sometimes you could take the tops those
seeds will be ready let the bottoms keep
going that way you only let some go too
long maybe some too early outdoors it's
kind of hard to judge but indoors you
should have pollinated all at once all
that pollen should hit at one time most
of the seeds should be consistent you
should be able to tell by plucking seeds
from two or three spots examining do
that once or twice three or four times
and you'll know how far along those
seeds are so once again bottom line
my prognosis my diagnosis my hypothesis
my thesis my [ __ ] stoner idea my bro
science does say that these seeds simply
grew for too long and they got too hard
too thick too robust
um i would try to crack them i would
work more on the scarification maybe a
longer germ soak maybe soak them for 24
hours uh crack them or soak them no wait
try that again crack them or scar them
then soak them for 24 then try to germ
them that may help you out but it sounds
like you've tried a lot of good methods
you're doing the right [ __ ] they're just
too hard you got the hulk you got the
rock they're made out of uh would you
say vibranium unobtainium yeah they're
made out of [ __ ] steel because they
went for too long all right i hope that
was good advice unfortunately i don't
have a real solution other than uh check
next time a little bit better that would
be my advice pay more attention i'm not
saying you didn't pay attention but pay
more attention next time now you know
what to look for how to correct it
all right my buddy andrew uh thank you
for the great compliments and thank you
for the great message i hope you get
some keepers out of there and i hope you
find a winner out of those beans all
right ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pams hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters paul and chuckers all of
you wonderful cannabis enthusiasts out
there i really do want to thank you once
again for listening to another episode
of the grow from your heart podcast this
was
718 episodes blows my mind that you guys
want to listen to that much of my
nonsense thank you i appreciate it keep
the support coming please do send more
grow questions i like answering grow
questions it does a lot of things it
lets me know that i am helping you if
somebody has that question
there are thousands of listeners to this
show if one person's got the question
the numbers tell me there are probably
multiple people that have that question
there are only so many opportunities and
things to do in cannabis growth so if a
question arises a lot of people were
probably thinking it one person said it
so it lets me know that i'm helping you
it gives me um an objective a mission a
purpose how to help you also uh it helps
me not have to just come up with a show
off the top of my head so that helps a
lot so send in those questions send the
details the comments uh the cultivation
questions the community questions all
that stuff i do look forward to it also
check out the website iriegenetics.com
also patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart you guys already know about
that you guys my throat's burning out
i've covered all the content and it's
time to wrap up the show i'll be back in
a couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a big shout out to my buddy
and the captain and commander of the ire
army my good friend lemur priest and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you