[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 719
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode mike is going to join me
we're going to talk about our city
pueblo before we do that part let me do
a few shout outs to a few of the great
folks who support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to a long time supporter my buddy gramps
memo let's send a thank you shout out to
kojaks and xavier let's send a big thank
you shout out to grant m and dayron t
let's send a thank you shout out to
paparoni and blackbird76
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the painted lady let's send a big fist
bump to groman stan and brian p i want
to send a thank you to mr mean green and
the red eyed optimist then let's wrap it
up with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
stoner dave big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen
now with no further ado i am super
excited to welcome back to my show here
in the studio at the table live on the
brand new mike mic ladies and gentlemen
welcome white mike to the show there are
audience clapping noises in the
background right now brother welcome to
the show dude thanks man that was a big
ass intro for you bro thank you for
being here let's kill it thank you it's
good to be here dude you're the first
guest to appear on the show since the
upgrades
since the uh what happened dude why did
we wait for so long i feel like
something was going on were you busy was
i busy both there was something
happening that we couldn't do a show i
don't remember what happened but anyway
for some reason we weren't allowed to
hang out for a long time and we are back
you guys uh it's exciting to have mike
on the show we got the two mic set up
two cameras set up uh that almost
sounded like a dirty joke waiting to
happen uh welcome back to two dudes
coughing we haven't done this in a long
time i am excited uh bro i've been just
rambling my face off before we get too
far would you like to tell people how
they can find you on social media
because i do do know that you would like
some more stalkers
if you're looking for me on twitter you
can find me at nemopunk15
on facebook it's pueblo for sensible
cannabis laws
and those are the easiest two places to
find me on social media there you go
thank you bro also i hope you wrote down
a list do you have some patreon shout
outs to give for the kind patreon shout
outs i'd like to thank a couple of
supporters tree star meadows thank you
cool uh the grokla homan love it thank
you very much for the support
thank you for the support for the
podcast oh yeah lemur priest farmer z
juan rios thank you guys so much for
supporting me those are some great folks
thank you guys thanks for supporting
mike on patreon check him out it's
patreon.com forward slash white mike uh
very familiar names there so
thank you to the people who support both
of us i recognize all of those names and
dude of course i'm going to send some of
that sorry we're touching knees that was
the awkwardest moment in the show we're
still learning the story we're learning
the setup here but i've got these long
legs and we're both tall but yeah we're
going to knee bump instead of fist bump
i wasn't trying to giants in one studio
uh where was i going with that what the
folks are saying oh famous uh common
names common and said famous but common
names in there i like that yeah that's
really cool
he's
real supportive of course i'm gonna send
mike a few bucks from my patreon down
his way because without mike the show
wouldn't exist he does a lot of uh when
he's not on the show he does give me a
lot of uh supportive emails and behind
the scenes i'm like hey mike i need
guidance on this show and he'll always
answer me and help me out so even when
he's not here he's on the show so thank
you for the support guys got to send
mike some also thanks to all of the
patrons for these uh the new microphone
the mic that mike is miking that has
mic'd up miking mike miked on today it's
fantastic it sounds really good in my
head y'all could hear me for the first
time in two years
oh yeah we try to get the zooms right
but zuma is uh zoom likes to fight dude
i try real hard to get it correct it
looks good on my screen and then i put
it out and i'm like what did we just do
yeah hopefully we sound as good in your
headphones as we do in ours uh and thank
you to the patrons you got mike the
microphone the cable the stand the
little power supply you got a lot of
cool stuff for mike to be on the show
got me a new fancy mic stand here uh so
thank you to the patrons that made that
happen that is where the funding came
from big respect shout out to the
patrons all right mike this is the part
of the show where i usually save space
for chatter some stuff that we can
[ __ ] about we do have a lot of notes
if you don't have anything to ramble
about we could jump into the main topic
but if you'd like to say anything this
is a good chance to open the show with
some chatter no major chatter right now
just
smashing through 2022 already it's what
would be almost the end of february it's
the end of february this will come out
one week toward the end of that one week
left in february when this comes out our
birthdays are coming up spring is coming
yep already it's
first quarter is almost over time to
start paying taxes and prep for prep for
the outdoor
time goes dude we feel i can sound like
a couple of old guys right now talking
about the weather and the passing of
time welcome to two guys coughing it is
the girl from your heart podcast
everybody when mike joins me it's two
guys coughing a little bit of a ramble
cast pretty solid topic though they like
it when we ramble very specific and
researched episode we got notes mike's
got a lot of notes i do have an ipad
full of notes if i look distracted into
the ipad i'm not checking out only fans
very impressive studio if if you're
looking at the video and you're like
what the [ __ ] is mike
why does he look surprised because
everything here is awesome well thank
you brother every time my eyes adjust to
something new i see some new cool piece
that ipad setup is beautiful man well
thank you bro thank you it keeps me uh
this is my focus this is how i know this
is my steering wheel this is the drive
this is driving right right about this
it can all go awry and this sounds so
good thank you bro you adjusted the
lights i watched you adjust to the
lights i didn't press record until i saw
you get comfy so yeah it could be
overwhelming so i'm glad you're used to
it all right yeah the lights are a
little bit strong and i can't see myself
being recorded right now which is a
different experience on zoom that's half
of my attention focus oh now pay
attention to the show you will be cool
all right mike we're going to re-wrangle
you we're going to regroup you i love
the chatter i only want to make this so
long of a show and they know how we can
get um you guys this is of course
episode number 719 why did i want mike
here for 719. we live in pueblo colorado
mike's address is 6'5 just kidding we're
in pueblo colorado um
719 is our area code if you want to call
mike or i the number is going to start
in 719 actually mike you may have that
denver phone number still i'm a 719
number uh most of our numbers around
here are 719 so 719 is our area code i
felt it would be very appropriate to
dedicate a podcast episode to our city
to our area code none other to help me
do that than our buddy my one of my best
friends on the planet mike mike has been
integral in the cannabis evolution
revolution legalization uh medical
movement here also mike has been a big
part of my development and growth as a
cannabis
uh grower what do you whatever you want
to call me people call me a guru a
community leader all those silly words
that make me blush when you say them
without mike's contr contributions to
the legal side the moral side the
ethical side and just his bro ship i i
read genetics the podcast wouldn't be
here so we had to have mike on this show
uh represent our city oh yeah for sure
bro i don't know if i say that enough uh
we talked about earlier he's behind the
scenes the lawyers the accountants the
[ __ ] business guys the uh they all
live in the tiny house is made out of
ticky tacky they all look just the same
and they never get no [ __ ] credit bro
so damn skippy i'm up here on camera
with the lights on my face all the time
getting all the love getting all the
praise
like
it's the
compliment
we complement each other in a way that
makes all of this possible right like 10
years ago
like a spark got lit and like now we're
here that's awesome yeah i i will i've
had these dreadlocks for a long time you
guys i'm showing the camera these
dreadlocks are these will be 17 years
old uh by the time this episode comes
out these dreadlocks are 17 years old
bro i was uncomfortable and unprepared
to go speak at city council and say
legalize cannabis i felt the stigma i
got the expected response i knew they're
gonna be like yeah white guy with
dreadlocks of course you want legal weed
mike was the one with the balls the
heart the education uh the presentation
to go do that for our city our community
mike influenced shaped uh
he was a big part helped right
actual rules and rags were
hammered out in meetings that i somehow
got picked to sit in the dispensaries
and grows follow today
homegrown rules dispensary rules all of
it got like we invented it here so mike
was coming to me and saying hey bro this
is the grow rule they are uh what's it
proposing they want to do this how do
you feel what is the good and bad of
that and i would say oh that would ruin
this because of this or a lot of times
they would try to say that each plant is
going to harvest seven pounds and take
30 gallons of water a day and you can
pull seven of them a week
and mike would say give me the real
numbers and i would give him like square
footage per light how many grams i would
expect and he would take that to the
people that were actually making the
rules and say i know a grower this is
what he really does and so mike was
i wasn't going to go there and say i
grow weed this is how it goes mike was
the uh the liaison is that the word uh
the representative if you will
for me and for for the industry here for
the community here so that's why uh
without mike this industry here wouldn't
be what it is and that's i'm not just
tooting his horn uh he's he's a pioneer
he was here
it's good to hear because
it was a lot of work yeah and to see
where where we are now because of that
work is also awesome like it was fun
researching the show and looking at
um some of the numbers that where we
started and where we are now is just
it's beautiful man
we went from a small we
just we are good examples we obvi i
don't like to we're doing okay that's
the best way i could say we used to kind
of not be as financially okay as we are
today we used to just straight not be
okay
in any way everybody else in
what 20
2010 2011 2012 how many different
economic crashes did we go through in
that short order of time yeah yep um
the cars used to suck and break down all
the time dude i had that white van that
the doors didn't lock that would come
open when you turn it it would run out
of gas because the gas gauge didn't work
oh you'd have to walk through the
sections the engine would just die and
make me [ __ ] my pants yeah oops ran out
of gas dude why didn't you get gas oh
the gas gauge doesn't work so yeah those
that used to be how our life is and now
i know my car will start we built it up
slow and a lot of that was
we carved out a place for ourselves in
in the legal cannabis world a big part
of how we create the legal cannabis
world to carve ourselves a piece out of
there and we didn't [ __ ] anybody over
yep that's a huge part of it we took a
couple of individual [ __ ] and a
group [ __ ] uh but we didn't [ __ ]
anybody over probably we still have the
opportunity but we're not gonna there's
plenty of us just why do business that
way yeah that's part of why why i think
we got where we did because we didn't
[ __ ] the people that needed it or that
could have right yeah we just took in
stride and laughed and walked away and
told other people i wouldn't [ __ ] with
them because they they bent us over
pretty good
ah but yeah so uh mike let's focus in a
little bit because uh we did go from we
we were not doing financially well like
i remember your house on eighth street
dude oh yeah it's uh
yeah there was a minute where we were
living with in-laws and there were like
five adults in this tiny little three
room
spot for a minute while we got everybody
back on their feet and
um that was back before there was a
legal cannabis market right
that was back when i was walking to city
council meetings because i didn't have a
car because we were a one-car household
and my wife had a better job so she got
the car
um and i walked because it was i wasn't
getting paid i was just going to city
council because somebody needed to go to
city council
and i could i uh
i talk about it sometimes on patreon and
other places
for a couple of different reasons uh if
you went and spoke about cannabis
uh
you had to have nothing to lose because
you were risking kind of everything
doing it
and some of that started to change when
i was going i was risking a lot but i
wasn't risking like what cheech and
chong were risking being them back then
and
uh after a while it sort of like a
little protective thing formed because
all of the police knew me and they knew
that i was active in city council and
that
if they came and
tried to raid my house or something that
would make the paper and so that
everything would have to be perfect so
they just never bothered to try
and i never gave them a reason to try i
had to be very very careful
but because i was careful and because
everything worked the way it did
this whole city is different now and
that's sort of what the episode's about
is where the city started and where it
is now yeah that's completely good segue
brother um you like the segway we're
trying to bring it in you got it dude i
was quiet and patient letting you do it
i knew it was coming uh we're called
pueblo is called the steel city uh we
have a steel mill here that's what
forged our city a long time ago we had
the opportunity to either get uh the
university or the steel mill and instead
of a university we chose a steel mill
and so uh that is kind of the mentality
that has been here for a long time no
offense to the people that forged our
city it exists because of you but
it was very
it was like 60 some thousand jobs at one
point and
by the time i moved to pueblo it was
like 5 000.
so just i mean the city was hurting bad
it was 2010. it was dusty it was dirty
it was broke there was nowhere to eat uh
it's still a little funky but it's
getting a lot better now i used to be
just all labor jobs if you were our age
well not our age now but if you're in
the mid-20s 30 you were doing
construction or fast food or crime a lot
of people legit straight up here
we're doing petty crimes just enough to
get away just to survive and there's not
enough law enforcement here to make that
uh dangerous you could do that here and
make a small living doing that don't
come here and try to do that but that's
how you used to live here now all those
people that were living by petty crime
restaurants struggling unemployment uh
just doing whatever kind of hustles a
lot of them got legit jobs in the
cannabis industry a lot of people were
illegal growers illegal dealers illegal
whatevers now they are actually in the
legal industry paying taxes with the
badge being contributing members to
society not having to hide not being in
fear
now that's one less person for law
enforcement to look out for so we've
come a long way
and we've got
restaurants here bro
watching the city transform has been fun
isn't it it uh
the whole place used to shut down at
like 7 30 at night he used to drive me
batty because i'm from denver i grew up
grew up in denver i might did my early
20s and mid-20s in denver
and i i like that you can get a variety
of delicious food at two in the morning
and to move to pueblo and have that not
be an option sucked yeah i'm from
california so i feel like where after 7
30 at night is jack-in-the-box or
something you cook that's just miserable
and
slowly but surely
over the years pueblo's gotten like five
percent better a year
right and it's it's a lot better now
we've got stuff i'd never thought i'd
see here but i'm i've got uh special
diet needs it's my fault you guys i'm
gonna i'm i try to eat you guys don't
care but now there are restaurants i can
eat at like a lot of times it'd be like
you can get a burger but now i'm
vegetarian i don't want to eat a burger
there are plenty of grilled cheese can
you get yeah exactly there are plenty of
marvelous wonderful vegetarian
restaurants around here where i can walk
in and are not specifically vegetarian
but places that offer specifically
vegetarian menus and items and meals and
it's got the v on it or the little
vegetable next to it to let me know hey
bro you can eat this here a few years
ago that wasn't an option you could get
mexican food or a burger and or a burger
with green chili on it that was also an
option here yep yeah
so
i i mean even our mall is dying slower
than the rest of them because uh legal
cannabis
our city council and our less so
but the county commissioners saw the
opening that that that would give
economically and they dove on it hard
and uh we're still i think it was fifth
or sixth largest producing county in the
state
um tax revenue wise so
pueblo's doing really well right now
because of this
and people do like to talk a lot of
trash about us but we're growing we're
expanding it's getting a weird
reputation well there are parts of their
parts of town i will not wear my watch
to that is for damn sure but there's
parts of that part of town
where you don't work where the drip yeah
you take the watch off and you hide the
sneakers and you just don't get out the
[ __ ] car but that's there's that part
in every city it's just you got to be
careful where you go uh but it's getting
better and we're getting a lot more
stores speaking of the drip uh there's a
sneaker shop here now i was shocked when
you're like there's a really good
sneaker shop in pueblo yes myself
like high-end hoodies and high-end
sneakers and like fashion stuff like
luxury fashion items that are not super
affordable for the average shopper but
since we've got a nice thriving economy
here a lot of the people that shop there
honestly are in the cannabis industry i
recognize them we see each other when
we're there it's like what's up bro you
run that run grow like we we all smell
like dank when we go in there like and
that's because of this industry we
wouldn't have no drip to drip if we
weren't working at the grows
it's uh
the impact it had in pueblo we've got
one of the higher unemployment rates in
town and this sort of jeff was talking
about
it
it added jobs at exactly the right
moment and it added
building investment and real estate
investment into just the right moments
and really revitalize the whole county i
mean it's not like a lot of winning it
it didn't change everything overnight
our streets aren't paved in gold most of
them still are full of potholes
but
little things got better and it gets a
little bit better every year because the
whole industry gets a little bit bigger
every year
so like the first year
we paved a couple of sidewalks near some
middle schools
and bought some golf carts for a
golf course
that a lot of senior citizens in this
area use so it was sort of like a senior
citizen tax funded thing i wasn't real
happy they were spending money on golf
carts but whatever it's an old grudge
and then you know three years later
we're not doing sidewalks in front of
schools we're doing a gymnasium on a
school
and then uh five thousand dollars in
scholarships becomes 15 and then 20 and
now it's at like 2 million a year i
think 2 million
a year in scholarships going into pueblo
county
good job pueblo county anybody can apply
if they meet some really basic
criteria and
uh
i mean
it doesn't sound like a ton of money per
student but like twenty five hundred
dollars a year can be the difference
between going and not going oh yeah and
pay for your books right yeah it turns
out that it is for a lot of people
especially because the universities down
here in pueblo don't charge
what some of the major universities
elsewhere do but they
they give you a good education and this
lets a lot of kids locally go to college
that might not otherwise it's
opportunity that wasn't there so yeah
that's great man that's great that's
good to know that we're putting that
much money back into education here
through cannabis and that's just pueblo
county that's from a local tax
initiative
that's not some of the state taxes that
we'll talk about a little bit later
that's just from a local county tax that
they do it all goes into one education
fund
someone we know from the cannabis
industry
that used to work at the retail level
now works in that education fund
that's so great it's it just provided
that
employment stepping stone and that
little bit of extra lifeblood that our
city needed to get back on its feet
so many of our people here were
unemployed and lost and now they've all
got really cool jobs because of this
industry so i've met so many cool people
that's the next thing on my list is the
people bro the quality
of the people has changed here in town
and it's a more
uh it's just a more enlightened more
open-minded maybe a younger sort of a
vibe
when i moved here
the biggest issue that the city council
was talking about was how do we get
not senior citizens to move here
because it was sort of a retirement
community because we just didn't have
a lot of jobs for your average
like 20 to 50 year old
we had a couple of call centers and a
couple of other small time you know 50
job 100 job production facilities and
then the mill had like five or six
thousand employees
and that was sort of it
and little by little
this industry slowly grew like we
watched it back in the medical only days
before the wreck wave of funding and
money really hit
all of the grow shops first there was
two hydroponic shops in town and they
both sucked
and then they both got a lot better
because there was a lot more money going
through them yep and now there's like
15. there's three or four on each side
right and
they all suck but
but most of them are thriving because
growing at home a couple of plants is
something that a lot of people do and
they all need all the supplies for that
and
yeah just the different ways
that legalization has impacted the city
are kind of ridiculous the longer you
think about it the more impacts you see
right um
and then when the wreck wave hit
it was
50 of our construction funding for on my
list that's one of the things on my list
is construction i think it was 2013.
it was like 52 million
um and i know these because in 2015 the
anti-pop people tried to throw the
industry out of town and i had a lot of
other people do the data digging for me
and i just remember the numbers from
then
but uh
uh we had 1300 employees back then it's
about 2500 now
um
there's 30 or 40 different businesses
down here that employ thousands of
people
across the state there's like 40 000
employees across the state 40 000 all
right i can give you exact numbers i
wrote those down
so this is fun before the pandemic
we had 40
267 individuals licensed to work in
legal cannabis you have to have an
employment badge so we know exactly how
many of those are active okay and there
were
1686 businesses currently uh two years
into it we've got forty one thousand
seven hundred and eighty three
uh so a thousand fifteen hundred more
badged people
and eighteen hundred and eighty
businesses so 200 businesses opened
during the pandemic
all right things weren't as bad as we
might have thought
not for the cannabis industry it's i get
i wouldn't call it recession-proof but
it's recession-proof just like all the
other mild vice industries when you're
stuck at home and can't see people what
smoking hang out
yeah sales have gone up every year
colorado's had the industry not
substantially but they do
if you're curious it works out to about
bucks per person in the states i started
to do the math and gave up i was like
i'm good so
uh the way you can do the math
um
is you just take the yearly sales and
divide it by
575 or 5 million 759 000 people in
colorado
um i think i [ __ ] this math up
actually
somebody out there will correct you if i
remember right i might have done the
total tax haul
divided by
the people in the state it would be 355
dollars per person in the states so far
after like seven years
which is a weird way that's not a
helpful number
still fun you don't get while you do
your research folks hey you didn't have
a lot of time to prepare mike so i'm
glad that you that you made a guy shout
out tonight for me
but there was some scrambling today so
i'm going to go fast because we're
already i wrote down here mike if you
see me making check marks this is 30 45
and 60 that's how many minutes we've
been going just to politely let you know
where we are we're almost to this point
um so you've covered this i just wanted
to say uh there are a lot of cool
ancillary businesses that did open head
shops restaurants sneaker shops clothing
places the mall is staying alive just
like the ripple effect is intense
because
like there's the the grows the
transport people
the retail outlets
and then there's the hashmakers of the
processors the edible companies all of
those people need packaging all of those
people need labeling all of those people
need light bulbs
all of those people need plumbers and
electricians and bankers and lawyers
and business executives
yeah all of those people need lunch
um you know all those people need tires
on their cars dude how about so there's
a small subdivision uh west of us
ironically it's called pueblo west out
there in pueblo west there are there are
a lot of groves and a several
dispensaries out there uh there was
nothing to eat out there there are a few
there's like a thai restaurant and some
other [ __ ] this is a thai food place and
a wendy's yeah he's really right unless
you've got all day then you can go to
sonic but that who wants to do that
shout out to not eating sonic uh
eventually a bunch of food trucks popped
up out there and it from like 11 to
about 2 o'clock it looked like a food
truck fair and they were banking money
because you'd see the whole trim crew
out there just lined up and they'd all
be and they'd come back and hold their
gut be like bro that barbecue place is
fire tomorrow we're going to the chicken
wing place and the next day we're having
falafel and like those barbecue trucks
and uh food trucks were killing it out
there so that was a whole other business
just because of the business that was
out there it's
it's been fun watching it grow and
when it started there was that whole
area was just empty warehouses yeah and
now it's all thriving businesses with 5
10 15 employees each all those people
need lunch all the security guards
the gas stations are busy try to go at
lunch and get like something from the
gas station and you got to wait in line
crews out there yeah the traffic on that
area is nuts and it used to be empty
because there were no jobs out there so
the only traffic was at night with
people coming back into town
and now it's swamp all day because
there's just a ton of people out there
do you know the average age of the
people working in the cannabis industry
no okay i just wonder if you have that
because i would assume it's mostly like
24 to like 35s
and then you're gonna have a few you
know there's gonna be some some outliers
but then you're gonna have like
management and stuff is gonna be like 40
to 50 year olds this is sort of
researchable information the state of
colorado one of the things we did right
from the get-go was trying to collect
data
and so you can go on the colorado
department of revenue website and just
google is your friend
just ask google questions you want to
know and it'll it it was real easy to
find the number of people that have
badges
the number of business licenses
you can look up who got fined last year
they make that real easy to find you can
look up taxes by county
they've even got a real uh a tab that
makes graphs for you and you can do pie
charts or bar charts and look at taxes
oh that's too fun that's why i know that
pueblo was like the sixth i didn't have
time to sit there and add up all the
numbers
because you asked me if i could figure
out the percentage of marijuana grown in
colorado that comes from pueblo yeah and
technically i know how to do that and i
know where to get the info but it's
hours and hours and hours worth of work
until i find a way to make it easier and
i'm sure smarter people already know
that way
but with the data that's available to me
i would have had to go for to
january 1st 2014
and just write down um how much pueblo
paid in taxes and hit plus
and go forward a month at a time to
present day and then just
do the math because the the totals are
there
but it's easy to find
somebody somebody get on it start typing
i want to know
what percentage of the legal cannabis
produced in colorado is produced in
pueblo if it's recreational or medical
so there's a hundred percent of cannabis
produced in colorado what percentage is
made here in pueblo count uh a city or
county uh recreational or medical one of
my daily counties the number one way to
let you break it down okay because it's
broken down by county and no one outside
of pueblo county understands that the
city of pueblo and the cit the county of
pueblo are different entities yeah i
tried to explain that to city government
and they got kind of pissy about it
um
but uh
this you can figure it out by county
we're only 160 000 people down here
and puts the state of colorado's 5.75
million
so 160 000 is not that many people our
city's not that big
and we're we're the fifth fourth fifth
or sixth i think it's the fifth largest
producer in the state
so
we're supplying all kinds area around
town around the state that uh
either can't grow their own or can't
grow enough of their own
yeah everybody says go down to pueblo
and get some herbs down there that's
what it's a whole commercial market
knows you're gonna stop down here and
get some pounds for a while if you're in
the commercial market you guys don't
think you're just driving here to get
pounds that's not it's not
we might still be the only county in
pueblo where it's legal for a business
to grow outdoors
i know that was true for a while i
haven't been super on top of other
county's law changes for the last little
bit so somebody might have squeaked that
one in there but i think we're still the
only county where that's legal in
colorado which is sort of insane when
you think about it but
the other counties are dumb and pueblo
week reaps the windfall
unfortunately for a while
the anti-pop people and the powers that
be have a moratorium on new businesses
so we're sort of capped at where we are
right now but
um for a long time it was a boom here
and if you don't have legal pot in your
area by all means use this podcast to
help argue for a legal pot in your area
yeah pay off a lot of the debts in your
town fix the roads fund some schools get
some kids some scholarships
the moratorium here doesn't bother me um
there is plenty of cannabis available
plenty of cannabis businesses it's it's
fine we don't need more uh it's okay
um for now it uh when it goes legal
nationally it it'll hurt us
right now it might be helping
but uh the rest of the planet needs our
herb
and i love that we need to expand enough
to provide that growth enough for the
whole planet um or just get everybody
out there at home to grow their own you
guys exercise your legal rights i can't
tell you to break the law but you're an
adult but if you are in a legal place
where it is legal and safe for you to
produce any amount of cannabis grow your
illegal [ __ ] limits grow that as much
as you can if they say you can have six
plants grow six volkswagen buses
it's almost outdoor season grow em big
grow them loud proud grow them strong if
it's illegal where you are i legally
can't tell you to break the law i also
can't tell you mike michael might he's
calling white mike for a reason but here
i am saying
you're a [ __ ] adult keep your mouth
shut and do what the [ __ ] you think is
right also have a lawyer on retainer um
girlfriends and homies ruin ruin grows
we have definitely talked about that
don't tell anybody keep your mouth shut
uh the electrician doesn't need to see
it don't tip the delivery driver or the
uber drive or the grubhub dude
like they know you got it they don't
even know that you got enough to give to
them they're gonna wonder where it came
from they're gonna come back to your
house they may show up when you're not
there um that episode just took a
turn bro we provide a lot of ganja here
in the 719. we have worked with a lot of
grow facilities and a lot of people here
what's fun like when when i was working
in grow facilities i i purposely never
did the math in my head but since i
don't anymore i went back and did the
math in my head and i just chuckle
um
especially when i do the math and i
pretend like it's the year 2000
uh when it was 400 announced was just
the friend price yeah
um letting you know letting you shop
here was was the friend discount
yeah
um we've made businesses
multi money
yeah yeah rivers literally of money
rivers and rivers and we got paid small
streams the analogy i used to get the
city to finally allow businesses was i
kept telling them there's a river of
money flowing right around the city
because the county was dove in with both
feasts when this started oh yeah there
were a city tiptoed in back in the day i
had to drive either 15 that way or 15
that way to get out of city limits to be
able to go buy medical cannabis and then
um we bro we put one right in the middle
of the [ __ ]
downtown big shout out to tom and karen
for trusting us and having faith in us
to run that business
uh one day i told tom i forget the words
that i used i basically told him i
didn't really know how to run a business
i think i said it more politely than
that because i did respect him you need
help and he reached across the counter
and he gave me keys and he said do it
then and i was like oh [ __ ] i've been
talking [ __ ] and now it's time to shine
and guess what mike and i showing like
some stars so uh big shout out to
zombies
man yeah dude we've been we have we've
been a good team since then bro we've
been going for uh 37 minutes do you have
anything that you'd like to add to this
show because honestly we've gone through
most of the notes that i've got there's
no reason to backtrack on the things
i've got here
um
just
not to put a damper on it but to put
some
perspective on it
colorado state's total budget is like 30
to 40 billion a year
so far to date our total cannabis tax
hall just broke 2 billion which is a
huge record that's two billion dollars
with the awesome stuff we couldn't have
done before that we got to do now
because of this
but it's like half a percent or one
percent maybe of a year a state's yearly
budget
so
like it's not
it's really not a lotto ticket but it's
a hundred percent a lifeline
and for our city 100 it saved us like i
can't even imagine what pueblo would be
like now
if this wouldn't happen i wouldn't be
here um
it got us
national press
it brought in
a lot of people moved here that were
like in their 20s and 30s um
the boom for
the construction industry was hit so
hard back then
and the way that this really revitalized
pueblo has been awesome
and getting to see it all firsthand has
been a lot of fun
um see it bro you've shaped it yeah um
that's so funny i read those homegrown
meetings were really really really
really funny
um
so if you're still listening fun story
ah this is the best part you guys these
are the gems i'm in a i'm in a city
meeting that i was i was randomly
approached after a city council meeting
to attend a meeting about a specific
rule
and other people
officially were invited they didn't know
how to make the rule and how to craft it
and so
i show up to this meeting
and i'm early and excited
because i'm being included finally and
i'm not kicking and screaming at a wall
is what it felt like for a lot of the
work
and we start talking
and the two people sitting next to me
are narcotics detectives who are talking
about shooting a video that i 100 appear
in at least a couple of times
and i just have the biggest smile on my
face and finally one of them goes what
and i go i used to go up and down those
stairs a lot and they just both didn't
have any idea what to say to that they
just kind of looked at each other and
looked at me and looked back at each
other and i just started laughing
and it was a lot of fun at the end of
that meeting they took my suggestion and
my suggestion is still the rule for the
city
so
yeah i win
story time with mike and he won in the
end so that's a good victory for mike
ah man those stairs i remember i know
the stairs are talking about that you
know exactly
uh there was a lot of uh loading of
plants uh loading of product in and out
that was a good time dude i wonder what
kind of footage they got i'd like to see
that footage yeah the
there was apparently a camera watching
the back stairs for the last several
weeks
that is scary yep
that place is gone um we paid them a lot
of tax money and then they decided to
come in and shut us down uh mike and i
that's how it goes we had some friends
that were founding a dispensary and they
didn't quite know what to do they had a
really good idea that's the best way to
say it yeah they needed some young blood
in there and i was young and eager and i
went in there and i was like let's do
this and this so we got them going as a
dispensary i couldn't handle it so i
hired mike in there um and then we took
that place the [ __ ] off dude a moment
ago you were talking about uh people
that came here for cannabis dude i
wanted to give a shout out to uh i'm not
gonna say names you guys know who you
are bro we met and made so many friends
that we would have never met you and i
do so many like we met because of a
dispensary yeah because of a crazy
[ __ ] of a father-in-law shout out to
you crazy [ __ ] uh he brought mike in
there to make friends with me and we we
[ __ ] hit it off dude we became great
friends immediately
uh
that we've got plenty of friends that we
don't even need to run the gamut of
friends because some of you'll feel left
out but we made so many friends guys
girls different ages sexes genders
locations that are all here that we made
friends with uh through the cannabis
industry so i'm grateful for you guys
you know who you are even if we don't
talk if it's been a long time if you're
still here
moved on
shout out thank you for being part of
the journey yep for sure and hit me up
if you miss me yeah be the same dude
yeah even if even if things got weird or
whatever i'm shout out it's [ __ ]
pandy is over if you live through it i
forgive you how's that
yeah feel it through the pandemic we
ain't got no beef no super fair yeah no
we're super fair we're survivors
together so let's do that
um bro i'm through my notes i'm rambling
at this point they like it when we
ramble but that i really like it when we
ramble but we're we've we're limited by
our battery princess
time there yeah yep i'm pretty sure we
could still go technologies
um bro great podcast it's great having
you back on the studio is
amazing thank you brother thank you uh
we got four wall street three walls to
choose from for backgrounds
uh
all the way to this from your iphone
with a little headphone mic
this is just amazing thank you dude it's
come a long way i'm glad that you're
noticing episode 719 in the can this was
beautiful yeah 719 mike will be back you
guys now that he knows that there's a
mic over there waiting for him we know i
know i know that we can record group
shows uh mike will be back this is so
much better than zoom i'm frustrated
recording zoom shows the whole like hey
bro what are we going to say
oh it's my turn to talk
uh go ahead buddy here you go wait what
you're you're muted this is so pleasant
and i
i if you if i sound half as good uh in
your headphones as i do in mine oh the
listeners no more you can finally hear
me again i'm so happy about this don't
jinx us buddy i've worked so hard to be
audible i'm sorry
yeah that like once again zoom has uh
bent us over excuse me the cave does not
work very well you're invited back bro
any time that you can get off the leash
any time you can uh i asked him i asked
mike if he was morally wrong or legally
wrong to kennel the children and he
didn't seem to find that appropriate you
guys so mike's a good person
[Laughter]
i might be a piece of [ __ ] mike's a good
person every day they get older getting
away from them gets a little easier if
you've got kids you understand that
sentiment yeah
yeah but uh for a minute it was tough
for a couple of different reasons
um
part of it is just the routine doesn't
let up
and finding gaps is is getting easier
right now so hopefully there's a lot
more of these this studio is too awesome
to stay away
i'm really blown away bro this is
awesome keep saying studio brother
they'll forget that it's my dining room
so i appreciate it thank you it's a
studio you haven't eaten food here in
three years it's very true it's very
true this this yeah there's no food
allowed it used to be a kitchenette yep
this is where we uh used to eat dinner
here but thank you bro i appreciate it
um bam i've had something else i was
gonna ramble it must not have been too
boring about the kids coming over um
come over bro come hang out dude i don't
even remember
um brambles sure we might edit that part
out guys i totally forgot i was gonna
say i had something cool to say at the
end of patreon i restore there you go
check out the uh so it sounds like mike
is ready to wrap it up uh dude really
thank you for coming uh you're welcome
anytime this was awesome come hang out i
forgot what i was to [ __ ] say if you
enjoyed this
say so on social media that will
encourage me to come back sooner there
you go invite him back you guys um
positive reinforced that [ __ ] and it's
time to wrap up the show it sounds like
we're running out of [ __ ] to say we're
just stretching this one out you guys
719 pueblo in the house
um come hang on pueblo um yeah it'll be
a good time i promise
um that is all we've got for you ladies
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers grovers clone cutters
pollen chuckers pueblonians is that the
word pablonians coloradans
i don't want to say what i say
okay
[Laughter]
dmm for that info um that is all we've
got you guys uh if you have any
questions corrections comments concerns
positive feedback constructive criticism
you know i'd love to hear from you my
email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
you can contact mike on twitter he has
nemopunk15 also check him out at pueblo
for sensible cannabis laws also support
mike on patreon at patreon.com forward
slash uh white mike i almost said my
patreon on accident i'm programmed like
a robot dude thanks for hanging out oh
yeah man thanks for having me you guys
thanks for [ __ ] listening
awkward signs for just a half a moment
because it's fun
yeah uh mike and i are gonna go take
dabs and catch up because he's off the
leash we're gonna have some fun you know
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i'm gonna give a big
shout out to my friend terp gooney and
until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you