yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 72 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a caregiver or if
you're a new smoker or a veteran Dabber
if you're a cannabis activist or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host Rost Jeff thanks again for joining
me guys sitting across the table from me
is my good buddy Mike how you doing bro
I'm doing well how are you man I'm great
man thanks for asking I'm going to turn
this music down I got that real loud I'm
trying to yell over it I just took a dab
and my lungs are doing that fluttery
thing they do I love the intro
[Music]
too yeah uh we got definitely warmed up
before we uh started record today we
just took some monster dabs of some that
was Gorilla Glue number four delicious
extracted by my good friends my great
friends my Champion friends over at the
Garden of Weeden big shout out to those
guys uh those are some dedicated dabbers
at the Garden of Weeden yep they stayed
up and stayed in line outside of
Illusions glass galleries in Boulder uh
overnight to scoop a new Mothership rig
and they got one and it is sexy yeah it
looks pretty dope I was looking that
photos today uh shout out to the Garden
of Weeden that is some dedication right
there yes it is uh people may say that
that uh Mothership rig is a bit
excessive but you know what I think you
guys deserve that [ __ ] [ __ ] anybody
that hates on you for it they worked for
it they earned it enjoy the hell out of
it invite me over for the check it out
uh tomorrow we'll go take some dabs over
there I like it we're coming Spence get
ready Maddie make some uh make some
cheesecake dude we're coming all right
where was I in this oh yeah we got to
send a big shout out to cat and coot
from the Mystic Roots band before we go
too far uh cat and coot from the Mystic
Roots crew let me use their music on the
show that is really cool it should cost
me a lot of money to play music on a
podcast if you do things correctly uh
but they let me have access to their
full Library they emailed me everything
all the instrumental tracks I got it all
it was kind of cool of them so big shout
out to the Mystic rootsband make sure
you check them out I'm going to burp
here we go get it I just had to get that
out of the way I was trying to force it
down I needed it out uh the organic
portions of this podcast are brought to
you by my great friends at the Rocky
Mountain worm company make sure you
check out the Rocky Mountain worm
company in Colorado Springs you guys you
can get African nightcrawlers red wig
and all of your organic soil
amendments um I'm not sure if they still
have uh the dragonfly Earth medicine
products in stock by the time you listen
to this but they have for quite a while
they've been selling them like a beast
get them before they run out uh you can
use all the worm castings I use by
visiting www. rockymountain worm
company.com or if you're in Colorado
Springs they are at 411 Tiana Street in
Colorado Springs make sure you tell them
that you learned about them through the
podcast they might show you the uh the
worm Factory if you ask worm farm it's
pretty cool in there yep check it out
guys yeah I'll take you with me next
time I'll take Mike next with next time
and he can stick his hands in the worm
farm and see what goes on in there it's
kind of cool uh so big shout out to the
sponsor that helps the show happen if
you guys are interested in sponsoring
the show uh send me an email it's gry
yourart hotmail.com I'll get you all the
information that you need uh if you want
to leave some comments on Facebook
Twitter Stitcher iTunes all that stuff
I'd really appreciate that so let's get
to the heart of the matter um actually I
got to say a couple more things [ __ ]
forgot that I've got a whole another
pile of notes damn I'm really excited
Big Show this time yeah I want to get to
the to the beef of the show cuz we've
got some [ __ ] that pissed me off when I
read it and I had to have Mike come over
and kind of interpret it's been uh a
week full of some horseshit I'll agreee
with that yeah yeah well the good part
of the week on Monday my good buddy
Clint shout out to Clint my car has been
broke down Clint called me he's like hey
dude I know you're stuck in the house
let's go to the 420 speak eesy in
Colorado Springs I'm going to do some
comedy and so he picked me up and uh he
took me up to Springs and the 420 Speak
Easy is pretty damn cool you guys it
cost me 10 bucks to get in there they
checked my ID and once I walked in
there's a dab bar that you can you don't
buy dabs you buy credits and then you
can trade your credits for dabs or
flowers that you consume on site or you
can trade your credits for Mountain Dew
or orange juice or uh they had ice
creams o yeah so it was a credit system
which we know what's going on there but
good way around some [ __ ] um I was
welcome to pull out my own rig and my
own dabs cuz I'm kind of a dab snob I
didn't really want to most of those
places there be wo everything yeah yeah
so or rent glass but bring your own
everything to put in they they did have
sweet rigs for rent but of course I show
up I took the uh the Eric Ross 4.0
custom rig so had no need for any other
rig and I brought my own Earl with me so
we sat at a booth and just dabbed out uh
Dustin Drew Clint and myself sat there
and dabbed Clint didn't take any dabs
he's kind of a puss but he smoked weed
with us he had something to do that
night yeah and then he did a set of
Comedy that was uh it was different uh
Clint had a life-changing event that day
and so the comedy really let that event
come out on stage and that was quite
entertaining nice yeah uh shout out to
Ben verc he hosts it's called comedy
Anarchy at the 420 Speak Easy on Mondays
I think it starts at 8 so if you guys
want some comedy you want to go smoke
some weed you want to take some dabs
check that place out liveing up your
Monday people yeah yeah get out on a
Monday go see some funny go support my
friend Clint go support uh comedy and
Ben verbeck yeah uh it was fun cuz you
could dab and see comedy they don't pay
me or anything to say that I just had a
good time wanted to talk about it it's
really cool having a place uh I wasn't
at home and I was with a few of my Bros
and I was meeting new Bros just taking
dabs and kicking back and it was open
mic comedy so there was moments of free
entertainment moments um so go to the
420 Speak Easy it was fun that's my
point check it out folks also somebody
sent me an email asking me they want to
add another light to their room and they
wanted to know what the best type of
light would be in their
situation right now the light I would
recommend would be a gavita for almost
any situation uh other than like a tent
if you've got a room and you're trying
to put new lights in there go gavitas
those are sweet the double-ended bulb
technology will push your plants to
another level so uh I hope that answers
your question there dude get a Gita I
emailed you I hope you respond to the
email also um I want to brag about
something the podcast on Stitcher we
have reached a Peak rank of
748 out of 40,000 shows way to go man
thank you bro that's a lot of listens
you guys that's spectacular especially
through Stitcher yeah just Stitcher
alone on Mondays you guys are listening
you download the show 5,000 downloads on
Monday morning keep it up everybody yeah
thank you guys um I want to thank
everybody that downloads it on Stitcher
iTunes and the website I appreciate that
um we ran we moved up in the ranks on
Stitcher quite dramatically in the
lifestyle uh the health and LIF style
category we were ranked number 59 this
week I think that that is because of
being me being a guest speaker on the
medical marijuana radio show about a
week ago with ls love he definitely
plugged my show heavily so I want to
send a huge huge shout out to LS love if
you don't already listen to it make sure
you go listen to medical marijuana radio
with ls love uh it's on it's on YouTube
I have not found it on iTunes I think
I'm going to help him get his show on
iTunes cuz that's what he really needs
nice step him up a little bit yeah just
teach him about that so shout out to LS
love thank you guys for listening dude
oh my God 5,000 people just on Stitcher
that is crazy dude thanks for the love
everybody that means another 5,000 on
iTunes and probably another half of that
on my website so we're getting right I
download it straight off the website and
so I've just got it on my phone to to
play Whenever when I'm rolling but and
that's just stit it up Stitcher shows me
on Mondays that 5,000 people listen yeah
just on Monday that's that's crazy so
thank you guys all 5,000 of you that
listen on Monday everybody that listens
through the week thank you guys I hope
you're in your garden hope you're
driving to work and I hope I'm making
your garden time your work time maybe
you're stuck in a cubicle if you're
stuck in that cubicle I know you know
who I'm talking to I hope I'm making
your day better so we did that um we're
going to get to the news I promise but I
want to talk about one more
thing I am uh a supporter of a company
called Grassroots California they make
these stylish hats that I wear they make
some pretty cool clothing um they make
I'm a fan as well right on the the
company Grassroots has a store in Denver
we got to get you a Grassroots hat dude
we do yeah get this beanie off my head
people thank you go he's been wearing a
beanie since I met him through the
summer through the winter for like seven
years shout out to Ashley hell of a
beanie and uh I've been promised she's
going to visit here sometime in the next
year and make me a new one so so we're
never going to get another color it's
just going to be a beanie forever it
looks good on you we're not going to
change it so the guys at Grassroots uh
shout out to Ryan uh he's the owner and
founder of Grassroots California they're
a hat company uh they support the
Cannabis movement they host the 710 cup
which is a dab Festival where uh it's a
dab competition but they opened a
business called the break room what the
break room was was a smoking Lounge that
you could bring your own they didn't
sell anything there but you had to bring
your own hash your own flowers and you
could hang out in this building and
socialize and smoke and they had games
and activities to do to keep you
entertained and snacked of course so uh
on
420 the Denver police raided the break
room they weren't the only ones raided
but they were among those raided on 420
there was a huge sweep on 420 which come
on Cops it's a dick move bro come on
yeah our rape solve rate is still at
like 40% people yeah but we're raid and
speak easys yeah so they go in and they
raid the break room and they shut the
place down and in turn they shut down
the Grassroots store but the Grassroots
store is a separate business in a
separate the store is divided there's a
separate staff a separate cash register
a separate entrance right and since the
since it's Ryan's store and everything
they shut down both buildings and now
they are forcing the city of Denver is
kind of Strongarm forcing the owner of
the building to evict Ryan from their
prime location on larer where they've
never had a problem right they've got
such good sales there because of their
location it's a sweet spot they've never
done anything wrong and now this this
dude that has put his life into this
company to make these sweet hats that I
wear and that you guys probably wear if
you're part of the movement and you
listen to the show I'm sure one out of
10 of you guys has got a Grassroots hat
on right now uh he's going to be forced
to move out of that building and find
another building which is going to be
hard because everybody already knows
crazy hard oh they know who he's going
to be they don't want him there now
they're going to say no because you're
going to open another pot business and
you're going to break the rules so you
guys he's got a GoFundMe and all kinds
of crowdsourcing it would be really cool
I'm not going to beg for Ryan but
support Ryan anyway that you can uh talk
to your Council people in Denver talk to
the Denver City attorneys let them know
that you think it's [ __ ] your
opinion does matter and if they hear it
enough it might make a difference this
is the first time we're asking you to
get involved tonight it won't be the
last yes Mike definitely needs you to
get off the couch and help us do things
because it's not just me man every
cannabis consumer needs every other
cannabis consumer to stand the [ __ ]
that's the truth we slept a little bit
on some voting and it looks like we got
[ __ ] by sleeping because I'm going to
read you some [ __ ] in just a minute that
you're going to say wait
there's lots of fugly headed up later in
the show sorry yeah stay tuned all right
so let's get into those news articles
that we've been talking about um I'm
gonna take a quick small drink of this
here you take a drink and then we'll get
into some news chug
it all right I'm nice and hydrated now
I'm looking for this news article I've
got so many things on this screen all
it's been a big NE big week in Colorado
news yeah let's start with this one this
one's from the westward uh the headline
is medical marijuana Crackdown bill now
law more about money than safety and the
article is by Michael
Roberts and it goes like this today
Governor John Hickenlooper signed Senate
Bill 15- 014 which has been
characterized as a medical pot Crackdown
Bill among among other things the
legislation will Empower a board in
consultation with the Colorado
Department of Public Health and
environment to establish guidelines for
Physicians making medical marijuana
recommendations the provision is backed
by those like agular who doubt that most
medical marijuana card holders receiving
recommendations for treatment of severe
pain a group that makes up approximately
93% of the total actually suffer from
this condition now we'll we'll take a
minute to [ __ ] about this there's a
there's a lot of stuff in there I first
the 93% of Colorado medical marijuana
card holders list chronic and severe
pain as one of their qualifying
conditions if you add all of the
qualifying conditions up you get way
more than 100% And it's because a lot of
people list that along with cancer AIDS
Ms the cheia is one of the major ones
right Crohn's there's countless um other
ailments on the list of qualifying
conditions that cause severe pain and so
pretty much everyone with a medical
marijuana card in Colorado also includes
severe pain when they're signing up with
their doctor what the legislature's done
and uh the theory I guess for several
years is has been that that 97% number
is the
fakers and so
when I don't know when people I suppose
Park in outside dispensaries across the
street and watch people come and go
every day like there were all kinds of
people claiming they did this regularly
right after we legalized in right after
the medical expansion you can't tell
what's wrong with me by the way I walk
from my car to the dispensary you can't
see my nerve damage from 20 yards away
you can't see that yeah I don't even
need to talk it's I don't I I have
plenty of medical conditions we could
talk about uh my pain is one of them but
it's I shouldn't even have to say what's
wrong with me I've got a medical
marijuana card and it's really not that
detective or that nosy person's business
what my problem is right so the these
people have decided that that 97% number
is probably all of the fakers in
Colorado which is like 97,000 people cuz
there's roughly 100,000 people on the
registry right now wow so they're
assuming roughly 97,000 people are
basically faking and uh this bill is a
big attempt to push as many of them as
they can back into the re uh the wreck
Market where we're paying let me jump
more more taxes yeah let me get into the
article because you're going to blow
this guy's whole paper this guy wrote an
article and you just [ __ ] shot it all
down for him you just you just buried
the lead for this guy that took time
onto this article no uh it says but is
this new rule more about safety or money
even though uh 15-14 is now law the
debate continues to rise page the
highest profile backer of the bill was
Senator Irene agular whose website lists
her as Senator Irene agular MD and
stresses her own medical background so
what Mike was getting at is they're
trying to make it harder for you to get
a medical marijuana card for your pain
and we suspect that it's to drive you to
the recreational dispensaries where
taxes are higher and you've got to spend
more money and pay more taxes and the
state makes more money because a lot of
the things that we see going on in this
bill are all about the taxes and the
money and [ __ ] the patients and the
caregivers yeah this is a long Bill and
it does several things and I think if
you take a look at it as a whole all of
the things it does are designed to push
people off of the medical registry and
into the wck market the next paragraph
in this article just uh is an excerpt
from this lady's website and basically
it brags and says I'm too cool for you
it talks about all the places she went
to school and her qualifications you
guys don't care uh then it goes on to
say uh will the Bill's new guidelines
make it more difficult for Physicians to
recommend medical marijuana to those who
say they are plagued by severe pain if
so longtime Westward uh marijuana writer
William breeds fears some patients who
really need MMJ will be deprived of the
recommendations and then here's an
excerpt from another uh article he wrote
in March that says studies show that as
many as 100 million Americans suffer
from chronic pain and that it affects
more people than diabetes coronary heart
disease and cancer combined according to
the American Academy of pain medicine
20% of All American adults experience
chronic pain severe enough to disrupt
their sleep at least two times per week
the number of patients on the Colorado
medical marijuana registry who claim
severe pain is around 10
15,500 people just below 2% of the total
uh the total population of the state the
fact that 1.9% of the state's residents
experience chronic pain and have turned
to cannabis to help is hardly surprising
or shocking so breeds also notes excuse
me uh Breeze also notes that the
assorted lawmakers in favor of the
proposal have made it clear that the
measure is a way to improve some medical
marijuana paat oh sorry I read that
wrong a way to move some medical
marijuana patients into recreational pot
sales which are taxed at higher rates
than medical pot sales in order to
generate valuable tax revenue for state
and local governments the difference
between the amount of tax revenue
generated by the recreational marijuana
versus medical cannabis are Stark as we
pointed out last week in a post about
recot so yeah they did we talked about
how much of the taxes are then they show
a graph here that shows state of
Colorado medical marijuana sales tax for
the month of March and then it shows
this is Medical in Adams County let's
see let's find pbl this is where we are
let's go to peblo they did
[Music]
$4,940 10% sales tax brought in
$135,200
yep oh that's rude that's a dick move
they were working on this three years
ago and then they sort of dropped it
last year and the hype was that a whole
bunch of people were going to join the
medical marijuana registry to avoid the
taxes and when that didn't happen they
brought up the severe pain number again
and said well let's push more of those
people out why don't yeah it's part of
the data collection when they saw that
the medical marijuana Market consumed
like 65 or 70% of the $700 Million worth
of marijuana sold in Colorado last year
they kind of freaked what they don't get
is that wck consumers consume
occasionally recreationally medical
consumers consume daily for medical
reasons of course we're consuming the
majority of the meds yeah and that's
what this was designed for that's I keep
going back to this part but we' put
cannabis on the legal Market here for
medical patients that's how the model
started and now that's who we have
screwed over that's who's getting pushed
right out of all of this and that that
sus attacked from every angle the
state's taking money out of the registry
that they're not supposed to access and
spending it on stuff they're not
supposed to spend it on they're M
looking to make it harder to get a
extended plant count to get a a
recommendation for severe pain they're
looking to limit caregivers in a half
dozen different ways we're going to talk
about in a little bit yeah we'll talk
about that in just a second it's getting
tough to be a medical patient in
Colorado if you don't really keep up on
your stuff and it's going to be
especially harder to be a caregiver here
pretty soon all right I've got another
article on the screen it's very similar
to the one that we just read but it goes
on a different direction toward the end
it says it's about the same law it's
just such a big law that it's you know
there's several different news articles
yeah and then we're going to read part
of the new bill uh actually I have the
PDF on my screen we'll read part of that
bill in just a minute too and the
headline alone will be enough to make
you understand why we're so frustrated
and we'll read some parts from that bill
so it says this article is actually
written by Kristen Wyatt and I found it
on the Cannabis I think Mike sent me a
link to this thanks for that that's why
I called you to be on the show thanks uh
the headline is Colorado medical pot new
caregiver limits MMJ and schools okayed
by government what yeah I'll read it
don't worry it says Colorado's Governor
signed into law a Crackdown on medical
marijuana
Mona that's a [ __ ] tongue twister
medical marijuana Monday that's a whole
new we should just make that something
right there medical marijuana Mondays I
like that I'm going to start over though
Colorado's Governor signed into law a
Crackdown on medical marijuana Monday
one of two measures designed to fit out
people improperly using and selling
untaxed marijuana I think that we need
an Oxford comma in this sentence right
here after the word marijuana I think
that would fix this I'm the wrong guy to
ask that question but then it says the
law limits caregivers those who grow pot
on behalf of patients to 99 plants the
change means that some high volume
caregivers will face the same oversight
as commercial Growers paying licensing
fees and under growing background checks
the new rule in Senate 14 uh Senate bill
14 have support from the recreational
pot industry which is complained that
the light regulation on Colorado's
caregivers has invited Black Market
Growers who don't face residency
requirements background checks or
commercial seed to sale tracking used to
ensure pot plants are grown and sold
legally um a lot of those people just
have to grow cannabis either way like
they're going to grow their own Black
Market production people just do they
they have forever yeah they're if
they're moving here to Colorado it's to
hide amongst the many like those idiots
doing those warehouses in Denver but
they stood out like a sore thumb because
they weren't operating legally and it
was clear to everyone around them that
they were about to get busted and then
they were quickly
busted there's so many things I want to
rant about here at least they one thing
that they did that was cool is they left
it at 99 plants uh if you've got more
than that you're doing something weird
anyway but fees and background checks we
would open our own dispensary if we
wanted background checks and fees that's
why we're just a caregiver we're just
lowkey growing a little bit of cannabis
for somebody well dispensaries uh make
money caregivers can't and yeah part of
the beauty of the caregiver system is
there's a huge number of people in
Colorado that can't afford to be
spending $400 or $500 a week on medicine
and without caregivers I don't know a
lot of people that could ma manage their
pain yeah I know several people that
would be [ __ ] out of luck if I couldn't
grow their medicine for them or some
Supply their medicine in some way shape
or form yep that's no it's a huge thing
the cost savings when you go through a
caregiver is significant over trying to
shop and even the medical dispensaries
and getting rid of the caregivers pushes
more people into the medical legal
system of the shops and I don't know I
hate this bill so much me too me too the
article goes on to say we're really
trying to make sure that caregivers are
part of our regulatory system said
representative Jonathan singer from
Longmont who sponsored the bill
caregivers have successfully resisted
such limits for years but the law
includes some con uh concessions that
won their
acceptance for example the law that
eliminates an uh an unfor the law
eliminates an unenforced requirement
that parents of marijuana patients under
18 grow the drug so that means that now
back in the day if you were under 18 and
you were a patient your parents had to
grow for you you couldn't assign a
caregiver you couldn't shop at the
dispensary now that kind of changes the
rules there so that kind of helps uh the
rule had
yeah there's two not horrible parts of
this bill or you could even call them
decent and that's definitely one of them
true yeah uh the rule puts some parents
who move to Colorado seeking cannabis
treatments for their children outside
the law and now those folks will be
legal so that helps a lot uh it also
sets up it sets up a task force to start
work on public access to the state's few
marijuana testing Labs uh so the
marijuana industry has generally opposed
public access to the labs fearing
backlogs but that's some horeshit ain't
it just let that sentence sck for a
minute the industry is fighting letting
caregivers access testing Labs because
it might take them an extra day to get
their test
results and they don't want business
well right why aren't the labs standing
up asking for more business it just
doesn't make any sense yeah and my
medicine needs to be tested just as
badly as the dispensaries does right or
whoever else is gr that dumb rule came
down what after one batch of tests you
got in yeah uh yeah I got one two good
batches of testing in before they shut
that down so that I couldn't do it
anymore yep all right uh there's so much
stuff in this article you guys I might
skip a couple of paragraphs uh finally
this one is good the law allows school
districts to consider allowing medical
marijuana use on campus as long as the
pot is administered by a parent or
designated medical marijuana
professional not a school nurse the pot
in school's allowance would be the
nation's first though it's not clear how
many school districts would participate
nor would it allow any sort of
smoked consumption it's capsules oils
tinctures lotions only but still it's a
huge step in the right direction yeah
well because a kid that's got add or
whatever else that requires a medicine
there are hundreds of kids go nurse pill
well I'm just saying if you take if you
take a pill if you take a prescription
you go to the school nurse after lunch
and she gives you your pill why can't
you just go in there and get your ganja
cookie your sweet Stone candy bear or
something they're skirting federal law
again and being silly but it's a step in
the right direction at least it's a very
tiny possible step in the right
direction I say small steps baby steps
uh it goes on to say Governor hicken
Looper said the law was a compromise
worked out by both political parties and
pot the pot industry and caregivers the
news went apeshit with this particular
Amendment the last couple of weeks pot
in schools the anti-pot people had a big
H with it too even I'm in the Cannabis
industry I've been I've seen this since
the beginning you know we had a shot
Mike was the bud tender and I was the
manager at the very first dispensary in
this little town and I'm still surprised
they're going to let the kids use their
Edibles or whatever in school that's
just that's revolutionary I we've
literally had hundreds of kids move to
Colorado to access this is a medication
and all of them have to go to school
like it's just one of the things that we
need to find a good workaround for I
hope this works it's a big step uh it's
a pretty good reflection of what the
community wants hick and Looper said if
the uh the law doesn't require
caregivers to register their growing
operations instead it encourages them to
register by assuring them that
authorities could verify their number of
plants without starting a criminal
investigation instead of forcing
caregivers to prove in court that their
operation is legal that sort of makes
sense but it also
seems um haven't we seen this move
before like all of you folk of a certain
type need to register so that we know
where all of you are that when we want
to round all of those certain folk up we
know where they are right it's it's a
really backwards provision where they're
saying to to keep from looking guilty
stand up and prove your innocent first
right and any caregiver who's operating
legally answers the cop at the door with
a binder full of paperwork yeah and if
the cop can add there's no difficult
questions we're lucky because of where
we live the cops will come and they'll
say you grow weed here and you go yeah I
got a couple plants and they'll go you
got a medical card and you go yeah and
they go okay I've got so much other [ __ ]
to do you guys have good day don't stab
anybody then they leave but for people
in other towns yeah that maybe if you've
got if you're uh in like a nice
residential area and you stank it out
maybe it'd be a good idea just to go
register just to be proactive now that
this bill has been passed it would be a
good idea and they require it if you're
doing more than six plant minimums you
guys you're going to have to read this
bill um yeah if you're a caregiver you
need to hop online and download the PDF
of this bill and read every word it's
short so don't be intimidated just read
it yep just do it get yourself a little
pen and paper make some bullet points of
what you've got to do now and so hicken
Looper signed the measure at a Denver
Police Station to show Goodwill between
law enforcement and caregivers the
language in the law came after years of
testing negotiations between medical
marijuana groups and police there are
good reasons for all sides to not trust
each other said Terry robnett uh head of
the Cannabis patient Alliance who help
negotiate the language the governor has
yet to sign the other medical marijuana
law that measures Upstate that measure
updates marijuana regulations that were
written before Colorado made pot legal
for adults in
2012 so there's a lot of stuff going on
in this bill like we were saying you
guys I'm going to find the bill I've got
it on my uh got the PDF here I'm going
to open it up there are a couple things
that really got Mike's attention and my
attention it starts off and it
says a bill for an act the headline is
concerning marijuana issues that are not
regulated by the Department of Revenue
so they're basically they're starting
off by saying money this is [ __ ] that
we're not getting money from here's
money Swimming by that we're not
catching that's what it sounds like
they're saying to me these are the
people we can't Monitor and over tax and
here are the ways we found to rectify
that so the first part is marijuana
Revenue okay this bill requires the
Colorado Medical Board to adopt rules
regarding guidelines for Physicians who
make medical marijuana recommendations
for patients suffering from severe pain
they want to find a new way to figure
out if you really hurt or not yep
they've decided that your doctor isn't
qualified to believe you and you're not
qualified to tell your doctor what hurts
and so they're going to come up with a a
little sheet or some paperwork so that
the doctor can verify that you really do
hurt and you can verify that your doctor
is sure that you hurt it's asinine yeah
it hurts trust me yep it wouldn't say it
hurts if it didn't uh it goes on it says
uh the bill requires Colorado Medical
Board to adopt rules regarding
guidelines for no wait I already read
that here we go requires a state agency
to adopt rules regarding guidelines for
primary caregivers to give informed
consent to patients that the product
they cultivate or produce may contain
contaminants and that the levels of THC
are not verified so hey Mike as your
caregiver did you hear all that I did I
haven't tested any of this that's what
the warning label on my last pick up
says I am giving you informed consent to
my patient that the product I have
cultivated or produced may contain C
contaminants and that the THC levels are
not verified uh yeah that's I didn't put
any contaminants on there I I knew that
because I watched the state take away
your right to verify your THC
levels yeah well we got it back now with
this bill at least they're going to put
together a group of people to decide how
and if you get access it's not quite the
same thing yeah if I get access yep can
we let him play that's a big F so the
bill requires all primary caregivers to
register with the state uh with the
state health agency and the State
medical marijuana licensing Authority
any PR any primary caregiver who is not
registered shall register within 10 days
of being informed of the duty to
register if a person fails to register
after such 10 days the state health
agency and Licensing Authority shall
prohibit the person from ever
registering and acting as a primary
caregiver yep they they didn't they
didn't have a stick to whack at you with
with some of their other rules so now if
they catch you as an unregistered
caregiver they're going to give you 10
days and if you don't register in 10
days you can't ever caregive again where
do I do that it doesn't even tell me how
or where to do that the bill you have to
require with the state health if you go
to the me website you can download the
voluntary registry form that they've had
up there for a while I don't know that
they've put a new form up so when this
is signed into action right this is this
got signed Monday so all caregivers you
guys have 10 days by the time this
episode comes out we'll we'll all be
[ __ ] we know the 10day time limit is
like if a cop comes to your door and
goes are you a caregiver and you go yeah
and he goes are you registered and you
go no you go you now you've got 10 days
all right all right or if the me decides
to mail all you guys letters saying you
know this is going to be received on the
first or whatever then you've got 10
days they could fully pull that too and
call that notice wow all right the bill
requires the licensing Authority and the
state health agency to share a minimum
amount of information necessary to
ensure that a medical marijuana patient
has only one caregiver and is not using
a primary caregiver and a medical
marijuana
Center uh that makes sense yep yeah
because you if uh I'm a caregiver and I
take good care of my patients you guys
get you get love and uh any caregiver
should be hooking up their patients a
little bit give them some stuff take
care of them make sure they're not
hurting if they come over like my back
hurts you get out of fat dab a CBD and
you [ __ ] them up right uh and and also
that caregiver or that patient should
not be going to another caregiver and
getting love from two people and
spoiling the whole game right or signed
up with multiple people there were a lot
of shop Hoppers when shops were still
able to do sign with us and get blah
people would just go from shop to shop
and sign up with Aiden a day yep and
then get all kinds of free [ __ ] and each
shop would be under the assumption that
they were growing your six and so it led
to some issues so then here's another
fun bill fund bill it says this bill
permits money monies in the marijuana
tax fund to be used to fund the
implementation of any bills approved by
the marijuana revenues interim committee
so all of the marijuana tax money they
want to now they will be able to use
that to implement all of the bills
approved by the committee that's kind of
some [ __ ] later in the bill they D
out a couple of hundred grand to random
stuff that was never
approved just it's just fugly from here
on out folks sorry for the
downer yeah which uh what do we want to
read there were a couple things in this
which one do you want to hit on um just
a couple of bullet points on caregivers
uh you're limited to 36 plants uh that's
five plants or five patients six plants
per patient plus your own six
36 um unless you special register all of
your extended plant count cards which in
which case you can grow up to 99
uh after 99 plants you have to become a
licensed marijuana business which
requires buying a building and business
permits so keep it under 99 people um
the nastiest little paragraph I saw that
I haven't seen any of the news pickup
yet is it bans caregivers from working
for medical or Rec shops in any way you
can't be an owner you can't be an
employee you can't even visit uh limited
access areas is a visitor or a guest a
on a tour yeah that's uh something I'm
looking for right now looking for that
part I can pull it up on my phone I took
a picture of that
paragraph
yeah right I've got it here yeah go
ahead and give it a read all right um in
order to be a primary caregiver who
cultivates medical marijuana for his or
her patients or transports medical
marijuana for his or her patients uh
here she shall also register the loc
uh is that the wrong paragraph no as a
primary caregiver if here she is a
licensed as a medical marijuana
business um associate director in part
um as listed under article there's a lot
of numbers in
here um a primary caregiver can't be an
employee contractor or other support
staff employee an owner a licensed
entity uh pursuant to article 43.3 or
43.4 of title 12 Colorado revised
Statute or working in having access to a
restricted
or uh licensed premise uh pursuant to
article
43.3 sorry guys I'm terrible at reading
aloud but basically what that says is
primary caregivers cannot work in any
recck or medical shops period uh under
any sort of badge so if you've got an me
badge and you go to work at a dispensary
you can no longer grow your own medicine
you can no longer grow somebody else's
medicine well you could grow your own
but you can't be a caregiver for anybody
okay you can just grow your own but you
can't I couldn't uh yeah there's a
paragraph in here that says they can't
stop you from growing and your wck
plants or your own personal six medical
plants okay but you cannot be a
caregiver anymore nope so if you are a
caregiver right now and you work at a
dispensary you've got to figure
something out how long do they have I
mean this bill went into effect is there
a I mean people had plants growing you
know there wasn't technically it went in
it was signing a law on Monday I'm
pretty sure it took effect on Monday it
might be like a six-month grace period
or something we need some sort of time
you guys you can't just say hey you have
to find new a way of life I honestly
haven't seen anyone else talk about this
section of the bill so I'm not sure the
implications of it and what that's going
to do throughout the industry has really
been considered by anybody but the two
of us can I cut and paste all of this
bill into the notes of this show is is
there some sort of is that legal uh you
could link it I'm sure okay we'll do
that we'll put this into the show notes
you guys so that you can read it too uh
the part that really pisses me off is
the part about being a primary caregiver
and working in a store I've been
bragging on this show for months now
that I have become the master grower at
the spot dispensary and uh the time is
coming it's very near um I haven't uh I
haven't actually can't call myself a
full-on employee yet because they
haven't paid me yet for my salary
because uh it's not time for that
started yet like they don't have the
building done that you're going to work
in yet it's damn close buddy word that I
saw pictures a couple weeks ago looks
real close yeah I've been in there a lot
lately uh giving advice and helping them
set things up and telling them where to
put things and kind of doing this and
doing that and getting ready I'm getting
excited too yeah so I got to figure this
out I know a solution but I hope
everybody else uh has a solution right A
lot of people are going to have to
scramble yeah I'm lucky uh J loves me
I've been blessed I had a solution
before this came up I didn't even know
this was coming so I thought iead on
accident didn't know that was why I had
that idea there's a lot of people that
are going to have to scramble I know a
half dozen people in your position
already that they work in a shop 8 hours
a day and they caregive on their free
time because they have forever
caregivers are what brought this whole
thing to where it is now that's how I
learned how to do what I do so well it's
where the shop wanted me c caregivers
were the medical marijuana industry in
Colorado from 2000 to 2008 period there
weren't shops if you were a medical
marijuana patient it's because you knew
knew a caregiver and it developed a
great relationship yep the caregivers
were the ones back in the day taking a
lot of the medicine to the shops yep
that's part of what our we knew that we
had that's where the inventory came from
up until like 2010 right yeah that's the
most of the inventory at the shop Mike
and Mike and I had was grown either in
my old basement in that house in the old
part of town over there or uh from other
friends of mine that were doing the same
damn thing remember that crazy old guy
that used to come and bring us product
yep as in the short time I was there I
saw half different people walk in with
the shoulder bag and the terrified look
asking to look talk to the manager yep
yep and then they got to come back in
the little back room and show me their
product that's where I met the guy with
the Hindu Kush that's where I met the
guy with the Alaskan [ __ ] we
found a lot of friends I made a my phone
is still full of contacts I made running
that counter like I run into people from
there all over town and there's always
that weird moment of eye contact where
do I why right yeah that's where I know
you from all right guys I encourage you
to go read this bill it's a sb1
15-14 um if you're a Colorado medical
marijuana patient a Colorado uh uh
[ __ ] recreational Cannabis consumer
if you're listening to the show this
this bill applies to you you need to
check it out you need to read it if
you've ever thought of growing plants
this is something you need to read right
now it's going to change everything yeah
if you're far away and wondering what
any of this has to do with you this is
what happens when the community doesn't
stand up and speak for itself yeah is he
gets railroaded and stuff like this
that's what I said at the beginning of
the show right down our on it I didn't
even know that this [ __ ] was coming up
to vote on I didn't know that I had
didn't know no I watched it come I
watched it work its way through the
Colorado process and I watched people
argue and fight I read the articles and
sent the emails and it just there was
some progress the original bill was a
lot worse yeah a lot I remember you
saying that I'm cool Comm and collected
right now but I've got some things to
change in my life because of this bill
oh I half of me wants to scream and
smash cuz this is really really ugly and
it's going to do a lot of harm yeah
don't worry uh there's a solution to
everything on our end I know what we're
going to do already oh I'm not worried
about you I'm worried about the three or
four I mean there's like 4,000
caregivers in Colorado I'm going to
guess that 2,000 of them work in
dispensaries yeah I mean that those are
there's definitely 4,000 caregivers in
Colorado the 2,000 is kind of a guess
but still that's 2,000 people that have
to come up with a sketchy workaround or
quit their job one or the other do you
want to fire the five people you're
providing medication and caregiving for
or do you want to quit your day job
that's your income because you can't
make money being a caregiver right you
can that's how recoup your bills but
that's not the same thing as getting
paid the day job funds the caregiving
right like without the day job you can't
afford to caregive because you're given
you got to pay for the lights if you
need a new gear could your patients come
up with that money no dude do you got
money if I blew a light bulb right now
do you have 200 bucks to replace a bulb
no and that comes out of my pocket every
time I replace the's sell my car real
quick and buy you a bulb I got a
transmission we're trying to replace
right now dude let's not talk about
replacing [ __ ] right uh shout out to
Robert shout out to Dave uh they know
why that's um yeah shout out to darios
getting that transmission fixed uh dude
we gone like 42 minutes you got anything
you want to say let start wrapping up
the show um register to vote and start
paying attention to politics and Hope y
we can stop getting just [ __ ] as a
community like this and then go vote you
got to vote there's uh there's an
election this year everybody's talking
about 2016 and who's going to be the
next president there's an election
between now and then that no one's
really talking about here in Pueblo it's
real important we're going to be voting
on Rec shops in the city hey you told me
that I kind of messed up the last report
I said on that to correct me because I
don't want to be wrong on the show it
was it episode 69 or 70 I don't remember
which when you cover
uh recently the Pueblo City Council
voted uh not to license recck shops in
the city and they punted so now the
voters are going to decide on some
marijuana question or another in
November the city council has no idea
what they're going to ask the voters
it's not going to be the 11 page
nonsense ordinance they didn't vote on
last Monday so hopefully it'll be a
short and suweet do we want Rec stores
in the city yes or no but who knows um
when I ask city council directly I got a
snarky response from from one of them
saying show up to those meetings and
find out you know in uh before I've said
I'm impartial to rec stores in the city
but bring it on we need a Rec store on
our city we need those jobs and taxes
period is a poor City full of poor
people who need jobs yeah and if you can
give us 12 jobs by opening opening a
dispensary that's 12 people and that's
something I've noticed that people uh
our age the 24 to 35 range that's been
kind of [ __ ] for the past 10 years
they finally got something to do the
people that got out of college and
realized that there's nothing to [ __ ]
do with that college degree sorry to
look you straight in the face when I say
that right but my sociology degree makes
[ __ ] less confusing to me personally but
it doesn't do [ __ ] off for my bills yeah
yeah you're going to work in a
dispensary now it's finally got
something for you to do because of this
industry it's helping out so I I do
support uh a dispensary in the city of
peblo if my opinion matters to you at
all uh vote Yes when it comes time to
ask about opening dispensaries in the
middle of town because we need that yeah
make sure you're registered to vote make
sure your friends are registered to vote
make sure your your lady or your man are
registered to vote if you're out here
and you've got a crew and all of you are
in those nice ass hats with those pins
boom make sure you registered to vote
cannabis is a gateway drug gateway to
politics I would have cared about
politics talking points for a while
would not have cared about politics and
voting and gone to city council and [ __ ]
at all had I not gotten involved in
cannabis the community's been gateway
drug man to politics we've survived for
so long by being invisible we had we had
to that was that that was how we thrived
and survived we were invisible no one
noticed us and we stayed out of
everybody's line of sight and now if we
don't all stand up real
soon we're not going to have legal
marijuana in any state anymore you guys
that have uh cannabis legalized in your
Estates be careful pay attention to what
they're doing dude Washington just
[ __ ] up Royal did you read about that
today I I've seen so much news that I
don't know what happened in Washington
and my brain is overwhelmed I was
focused on this show so back uh maybe 6
eight months ago Colorado's they did the
first underage by Sting and they hit 20
dispensaries in Colorado and and up and
tall and proud not one of them failed
way to go boys I congratulated them on
they just stung Washington four of 22
failed [ __ ] you [ __ ] I hope somebody
firebombs your [ __ ] store I hope they
take your license and [ __ ] in your weed
oh yeah um that's that's Mike's opinion
I kind of agree but not not as fiercely
that does suck dude we we give you the
opportunity to make a lot of money they
sent them a letter a week in advance
saying we're going to sting you don't
[ __ ] up and four of them
did you know part of I'm going to give
one of those credit to a stupid ass
employee these people should be
crucified at Hempfest next year yeah
let's get it right you guys we're going
to [ __ ] have this business that
you're allowed to make a billion dollars
with and sell cannabis and they're
letting us play it's like I it's like
Mom's away and your dad's like sure you
could watch Playboy while she's gone on
and [ __ ] now you're [ __ ] it up now
you're jerking off in front of the kids
let's zip it up and do this right just
you're right dude firebomb him I'm sorry
just so ridiculous I mean don't really
don't really firebomb them but if you sh
pull them up their the store names are
in the news if you if you live in
Seattle and you used to shop there don't
anymore if you have to pee when you're
walking past hit up their window [ __ ]
them I don't know that we I can support
that statement on the show because when
the window gets pissed on this statement
is brought to you by white Mike not the
podcast yeah yeah all right so now that
Mike's got us pissing on Windows I think
it's almost time to wrap up the damn
show hey wife yeah uh I did not shout
out to the wife I did not prompt him for
that she don't listen I try to remind
all my friends to say hi to their wives
when they're on the show just get he
baby thanks for dinner sweetie I don't
have one of those so hey girl my wife my
wife I did my wife this
show I made it the whole show I saw Doug
Benson and I was in the front row and he
said my wife on stage or somebody else
said my wife and he went my wife and I
did it too my wife after him and I think
the people on stage heard me it was kind
of awkward for me it was funny nice all
right um yeah follow Mike on Twitter
yeah hit me up uh it's Nemo punk5 n m o
p u n K15 yeah follow him he posts a lot
of cool cannabis related [ __ ] lots of
links lots of news yep I appreciate the
follows guys guys we're going to wrap
this up um this will probably I'm not
even sure when I'm going to put this out
it might be Monday it might be Wednesday
either way I'll be back in a a couple of
days with another episode I did not
forget about that Perpetual grow episode
I told you about like I said I've been
writing that and more [ __ ] keeps popping
up to do shows about it was a big news
week guys sorry and Mike was around and
I was like let's do this he was looking
for something to do um yeah so I'll be
back in a couple days I might have that
Perpetual episode ready by then uh in
the meantime check out our sponsors the
Rocky Mountain worm company if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you've got a product you want us to
review on the show send me an email it's
grow from yourart hotmail.com I'll get
you all the information you need guys it
really helps me out if you go to iTunes
go to the iTunes Store search for grow
from your heart find the review section
give me a festar rating and after that
type in a comment and let me know what
you think of the show and I'll read your
comments on a future episode that
five-star rating moves me up in the
ranks in iTunes and then more people see
the show more people listen to the show
more people grow better cannabis we
overgrow the government we legalize
cannabis worldwide you don't have to
smoke mids it gets better and better the
more we do it so help help improve
cannabis by clicking help us help you
five stars right there on iTunes it's
all you got to do uh big thanks to
everybody who pushed us up in the ranks
and Stitcher that's freaking awesome I
appreciate that uh find us on all of the
social media sites please we're on I oh
[ __ ] iTunes no [ __ ] we're on
Instagram we're on Twitter we're on
Facebook uh you can find this it's all
over the place make sure you follow iy
genetics on Instagram that's what it is
iy genetics I just have one page there
uh like I said don't forget the shows
available on iTunes Stitcher every
single episode is always and forever
archived on iry gentics
colorado.com we did do a few adjustments
to the website it'll be working uh more
quickly for you the downloads will be
smoother I've actually been compressing
the files that I send to Stitcher and
iTunes so that they'll download on your
mobile device more quickly I'm thinking
about you guys we're learning how to
improve the experience for
everybody um I keep talking about the
donation button on the podcast page it's
iy genetics colorado.com click on the
grow fromy heart podcast tab on the top
right there's a PayPal button click on
that you can donate any dollar amount
you would like to my Paypal account I
promise I'm never going to charge you
for the podcast every episode is free
there's no hidden content you can unlock
for money or anything like that this is
all free free free grow weed everywhere
you can with my advice but if you want
to contribute I will not argue with you
I would totally appreciate it like I
said I'm getting a new transmission in
the car it's about 2500 bucks every
dollar you throw down is one less that I
have to dig out of a hole somewhere
right yeah I talked about all the Social
Media stuff I think that that's all we
got to do um hit us up on Twitter and
Facebook and whatnot folks ask questions
send emails I love interactions I really
do questions build good shows guys
that's the truth a lot of the episodes
come out of people's questions so until
next time you guys shout out to my ninja
Spence thanks again for listening take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me stand uple
col say roll up ni say roll up
[Music]
we
tell