[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 720
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
making your own spray to make your own
femme seeds before i get to that part
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
frankie let's send a big thank you shout
out to stash drop 269 and tartan mike
let's send a fist wump and a thank you
shout out to jethro earl and all mixed
up let's send a thank you shout out to
uncle gigi let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to chicago dabber i
want to send a big thank you to my buddy
pro brewer home grower let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to
another good friend my buddy crazy hand
grows let's send a thank you shout out
to a friend with weed i want to send a
big fist bump to sam heads let's send a
thank you shout out to cincy11 then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to my friend tree star meadow big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
dot com www.patreon.com slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to find the patreon page all
right i'm going to do a quick episode
about making your own silver thiosulfate
solution this is how we do make
feminized seeds i'm actually in the
middle of a workday i was doing work
putting stuff together i was like i need
to mix up that solution i should spray
these plants today today is the day and
then i thought to myself what kind of
podcaster would i be if i did not set up
some cameras throw up a microphone here
and get this episode recorded so we're
going to record myself making i'm going
to record myself making a silver
thiosulfate solution this will be used
to make the next batch of femme seeds
that come from irie genetics this is the
solution i am going to use you're going
to watch me make my actual solution
which i use for making feminized seeds
there are a lot of things we should talk
about before we show you how to make
this solution but i feel like i've
talked about those things many times
i've given many other podcast episodes
about the the precursors the
prerequisites to making your solution
and to selecting your plants briefly i
will say this
selection is very important when it
comes to making feminized plants you
want true
female plants if you're going to make a
feminized plant if you're going to
reverse a plant pick a plant that you
know is a true female we want a plant
that has been tested uh give it some
light stress give it feeding stress
maybe not all at once or do but let's
see if that plant shows you intersex
traits i do not and will not make
feminized plants feminized seeds from
any plants that ever show me any type of
intersex traits let's remove the word
intersex herm hermaphrodite especially
eliminate the word herme from our
vocabulary when it comes to talking
about femme seeds and femme seed
production there is no hermaphroditism
happening here there are no
hermaphroditic plants being used if
we're using silver in the correct manner
so now i can move forward let's stop
saying herm let's use the right words
that is not a hermaphrodite that's you
know i would throw hermaphrodite away so
that's not what we are doing now i can
talk about a few of the options when we
are making femme seeds uh there are self
plants there are reversed plants what we
are going to do what i am going to do is
i am going to make a solution of silver
thiosulfate also my chemistry nerd
friend says i say that incorrectly uh if
you think i say it wrong politely do
correct me also i do apologize for the
other rough voice here the raspy throat
i was not prepared to record i was
actually in the middle of my work day so
this is not recording normal time uh my
voice is not prepared i may have been
dabbing i may have been doing other
things the voice wasn't ready so i
apologize free show i love you you're
welcome don't complain uh i may be
silver theo sulfate thiosulfate uh if
it's theothio either way it's gonna do
the same [ __ ] correct me if i'm wrong or
was i uh i'm going to mix up this
solution and i'm going to reverse one
plant i'm actually going to reverse
three different clones of the same plant
we're going to put that pollen on
multiple other females when i put that
pollen on a cut of the same plant i'm
going to reverse golden goat full
disclosure i'm going to reverse a golden
goat female three golden goat females to
make a lot of pollen
um i'm going to put that pollen on
another golden goat of course that will
make golden goat s1 self golden goats i
will also put that pollen on a platinum
tangy plant and a lemon skunk we will
then make orange gasm and lemon jeffrey
there may be other [ __ ] in the room
that we can't talk about they're going
to get pollinated as well but let's stay
focused here the other plants to get
pollinated that are not golden goat will
be what are known as reversals r1s and
s1's we're going to self a plant use its
own pollen then we're going to self that
plant put it on other plants that is a
reversal i've done full episodes on that
wanted to give a little a little
background a little prerequisite now
let's talk more about making this
solution we're going to be working with
chemicals i've got these chemicals here
in my face let me move the ipad a little
bit over i had that mainly for the shout
outs uh let me check the recording it
looks like things are going well should
be a good show it's weird with the new
mic placement uh and the ipad in the
wrong place i'm out of my comfort zone
we're gonna do the best we can with this
new setup where were we let's talk about
this stuff uh we're going to be using
chemicals i do have a
bottle of sodium theo or thiosulfate
sodium thiosulfate i'll show that to the
camera i will zoom in on that maybe that
camera's better i'll get the best angle
for the show i promise you and
we'll fix it in post is what we're going
to say here i'll show you that
we've got this bottle here we've also
got this bottle of silver nitrate i'm
showing that to this camera i'm going to
hold it up here for a couple of seconds
let you take a look at it show it to
this camera we'll see which one gives us
the better view uh in post the cameras
are kind of far away we'll edit that to
be appropriate
these chemicals i do buy them from a
company called united nuclear on the
internet
is how i think i find them you can find
them they're very easy to find i buy the
two ounces of sodium thiosulfate and the
10 grams of silver nitrate uh they're
very affordable one is almost still full
this one's almost empty there's another
bottle inside there's why it rattles
they give you the double seal
um very cost effective very affordable
these are very cheap products however
they could be
caustic they could be dangerous they've
got a bunch of notices written on the
sides of them you've got to be very
careful when you're using these products
something i highly recommend one thing
i'll start off with i like to dab a lot
i like to smoke a lot if you're not a if
you're not a safe person if you're not
comfortable doing [ __ ] blaze don't do
this when you're high maybe get a clear
head maybe wait till after you do this
to smoke maybe uh mix up your [ __ ] then
smoke and celebration that's something i
should mention i'm not your boss bro uh
my rule of thumb at work if i'm the boss
is if i can tell you're high you're too
high if i can't tell you're high do your
[ __ ] job and have a good time
that applies to you right now so don't
[ __ ] this up don't get these chemicals
don't inhale these chemicals don't
ingest these chemicals don't get them in
your eyes be very careful the first
thing i'm going to do to be a good
example to be a good leader i'm going to
put on my gloves you guys ready for your
exam i hope you're ready line up then
after that we're going to make some
solution here so i've got my gloves
coming on
oh i hate it when the hands are all
clammy and the gloves won't go on these
are the right size gloves and they fit
just right we're going to put on some
gloves normally when i'm doing this i
would wear a mask i'm going to do things
differently
i already poured the chemicals i already
weighed them uh there i've got them
stored right here next to me so that i
don't have to waste time doing that on
camera also i would normally wear a mask
to do that however i'm asking a podcast
and a camera and a microphone seemed
stupid to me i don't want to do that
honestly the mask seems silly to me at
this point but this is not a political
show
um i would get the gloves and the mask i
would also tie up the dreadlocks but the
way that i had them tied with the big
hat it didn't work with the headphones
we're adjusting um do as i say not as i
do protect yourself take care of
yourself eyewear may be a good idea if
you're a clumsy [ __ ] but that's not
necessary in my opinion right here it's
a powdered chemical however again if
you're a clumsy [ __ ] at that eyewear
it's dangerous you could get [ __ ] in
your eyes maybe eyewear um rasta jeff
says wear eye protection just because
legally i don't want to get in trouble
bro wear your eyewear dude wear your
gloves where your mask type your
dreadlocks type your hair type your
loose sleeves if you got wobbly sleeves
now's a uh if you get the wizard sleeve
now's the time to get to get the wizard
sleeve tied up sorry about that um where
are we type your dreads also work in an
area where
um if you spill some [ __ ] it's gonna be
safe make sure you've got your ipad your
recording equipment your power supply
make sure all that [ __ ] has scale make
sure that's all on the same table don't
really do that i'm doing that for a
video like i said before do as i say not
as i do
um the podcast area will be perfect make
sure you get a lot of electronic [ __ ] is
what i wrote also i may recommend have
some paper towels or a rag or something
available uh we're gonna have some water
pouring here things could go awry like i
keep saying i'm i'm not a jedi i'm not a
ninja i'm not perfect also not a clumsy
[ __ ] i'm somewhere right in the middle
of that so i do need a rag occasionally
gonna have to clean some [ __ ] up now
let's get down to business let's talk
about mixing this solution what do i
have in front of me we talked about the
uh the two products the silver and the
sodium i've got a scale
because i'm going to weigh these two
products in a very specific amount i
need a half a gram of one and two and a
half grams of another then i'm going to
put those into
500 milliliters of distilled water i've
got distilled water i've got a gallon
jug of distilled water over here i'll
hold that up for the camera i can't find
the handle of the bottle there we go i
got a gallon jug just distilled water
plain distilled water i buy i try not to
let it sit around too long i get a fresh
one most of the time when i'm making the
solution so we've got a gallon of
distilled water over here
i've poured that into two
500 milliliter measuring glasses i'm
just going to slide these closer to the
camera view they're both filled with 500
milliliters of water uh it's the
distilled water hold that up for the
camera here there you go right up to the
500 mil mark so i have a liter of water
here essentially divided evenly i've got
my two powders the way i would do this
and like i said i skipped a step because
of the camera because of the mask
because the technology into speed shut
up probably talked right my way through
speed and [ __ ] up but what we're gonna
do we're going to i used a piece of
paper i just took a piece of paper and i
folded it in half to make it easier to
handle uh sometimes if you don't fold
the paper it arches the other way and
you lose your solution so i simply
took a piece of paper folded it in half
i set that piece of paper on the scale
then i hit tear now my scale is at zero
at this point i sprinkled the product on
there until i reached the desired amount
in this case i was using the silver
nitrate and this is where the recipe
comes in pay attention we've got 500
milliliters of water and i used one half
of a gram of silver nitrate okay we're
going to just set the silver nitrate
right in front of here that is the
silver nitrate container but i'm going
to do it this time so i've weighed it
right i've waited out sprinkle sprinkle
you saw me do it i got a half a gram
right here you trust me do you want to
see the scale or do you trust my weight
bro promise you i tore it i teared the
scale what's the word i tore i teared
prefixed the scale
i don't know the word
someone will tell me um so right here i
do have half of a gram of silver nitrate
i don't know if it'll come up on camera
i'm not gonna [ __ ] finagle it and
spill it uh it's not expensive but it's
it's right here i need it so i'm gonna
dump that right into the water i'm gonna
tap my paper just get that all into the
water it's in there
uh there is a an imaginary trash can
right over there i know i've got some
[ __ ] over there to clean up so we're
just gonna put that over there here i'm
going to use a very technical piece of
equipment this um we call a butter knife
i like this because it's metal nothing
sticks to it it's easy to clean up i'm
going to put that in here i'm going to
stir my [ __ ] gently i almost went too
hard just want this to dissolve it
should dissolve pretty quickly the
product was chunky so it may take a
couple of seconds you got a couple of
fat rocks in there that need to dissolve
it's going it's almost dissolved
completely i can see by looking through
the glass here it's gone it's basically
dissolved in there so that part is taken
care of i'm gonna set that there for a
moment get myself a paper towel
and then i'm just going to fold it up
nice and scientifically and then we're
just going to clean this off
all right the first part has been
handled we've done the first part just
leave that there just because it's safe
there i know where it is it's not
[ __ ] anything up so
the next step excuse me for the throat
clearing we already did this disclaimer
next step we're going to basically
repeat the process with the sodium
thiosulfate for this product we need 2.5
grams so i'm going to set that right in
front of here i'm not sure how much of
that's coming up on camera it's far away
for me to see i did already pre-weigh it
but just for science purposes and video
purposes i'll set it right there uh
actually i'll take it off i will refresh
the scale
it's refreshing it's going to zero
all right it's at zero
it's taking a minute there we go i got
shy on camera it's at zero we'll set it
on here
hypothetically i would tear it right now
right i hit the tare button
because i put the paper on there now i
would sprinkle my product onto there
until it says 2.5 grams i've already
done that so i know it's 2.5 what i can
do now pick up my product this is
container b sprinkle it right into
container b this one slid right off the
paper real well just for fun i'm gonna
set that on there it shows me that is
negative 2.5 so i know i started at the
right point i know that that's the right
amount i'm going to fold this up toss it
into the imaginary trash can
brush this off of the table here we
should probably clean up a little better
if you're doing this at home clean up a
little better don't leave [ __ ] on your
table especially especially if it's like
the family table where a pet a friend a
child could be clean the [ __ ] up also
here's another point that i kind of
maybe skipped clean your [ __ ] before we
start
ah i cleaned this bottle this bottle or
this cup a measuring cup yeah it's a cup
i cleaned the measuring cup i cleaned my
next jar i cleaned everything with rub i
cleaned it real well with alcohol let it
water let it sit dry then i cleaned it
with alcohol let it sit and dry again i
did that about an hour ago then i set up
the equipment i cleaned off my scale
real good everything is clean my spray
bottle is clean my environment's clean
everything will be just as clean when i
leave that's something important to
think about at this point i should be
stirring this product into here this one
won't take very long to dissolve it's
pretty much uh
this one's a little thicker than the
other one it will take a minute it's
pretty much starting to dissolve already
i could see the the cloud at the bottom
is going away at this point we can
remove the scale from the equation we
don't need that i've got my paper towel
here in case i make a mess got more
trash let's just toss that to the other
hypothetical invisible trash can we're
going to keep stirring this
this will dissolve i may fast-forward
part of this
now once these dissolve we're going to
simply combine them i'm starting to see
that the little crystals at the bottom
are disappearing there's just a little
bit left to stir maybe a little vigorous
a little more vigor don't spill it i did
spill it fill it right up to the top
here but i needed the 500 mils and wait
till you see me fit it into the one
liter jar that's going to be the fun
part some of it will get spilled so
we're going to clean this off again we
don't need the knife we don't need the
scale we don't need my little wiper
towel so those are going to go over here
out of my way
make my ocd shine get all the used [ __ ]
that i don't need over there
now where are we we've mixed up our [ __ ]
once again if you're doing this at your
space and you're not recording and have
headphones on get your dreadlocks tied
up get your long hair out of the way
have your mask on at this point the mask
may not be necessary the dry powdered
chemicals are gone this is where you
want to think about your eye protection
always use the gloves these chemicals i
think they're slightly caustic they
could burn up your fingers burn up your
skin i don't want to risk it so we have
got the two things mixed together now
in science you always pour i wrote this
down because i always mix this part up
you always pour part a into part b when
you are mixing things uh this is part a
this is part b
so uh what i think we should do normally
honestly what i normally do is i pour
them in here together so i'm going to
move the ipad over just a little bit
because i am a catastrophe once in a
while i'm going to move the mic out of
the way i'm going to pour parts a and b
in here together kind of simultaneously
at the same time i feel like that mixes
them real well we'll see how they fit in
here and then once i've got that done
i'll bring the mic back and we'll
continue on with our normally scheduled
program just going to move those out of
the way move the mic over and we'll get
to action here we go
[Music]
all right through the magic of editing i
did speed that up a little bit so you
didn't have to watch me try to slowly
pour that in there and then dribble some
onto the table anyway here we go it ah
we got it mostly fit i've got equal
parts left over in both containers so my
ratios are still correct uh close enough
in my opinion that's going to be just
fine there's a little bit left in each
container i don't want to spill it i
don't want to waste it but they're even
uh so there's just barely any left in
each container here but this is as close
to uh that that's going to fit in here
without starting to spill it all over
the table so now we've got our solution
this is our one liter of silver
thiosulfate concentrated mix this is a
hundred percent dilution here we cannot
apply this directly to the plant this
will cause problems this will not be
success if we apply this directly to the
plant at this point we do need to dilute
this product the dilutions and
application intervals are where this
becomes kind of an art kind of an
adjustment the same dilution rate and
application uh times and intervals are
not going to work for every single plant
there are things to learn this is just
like working with people it's just like
taking somebody on a date with work for
your last date may not work at all for
your next date so you're gonna have to
figure this out there will be you'll see
some success but to get this perfect
there will be some dialing in this will
be a little bit of a learning process
the way that i do it i get and i said
earlier i was going to spray three
golden goat clones that's because i'm
going to spray them all differently
let's talk about the ratios i'm going to
spray these golden goat clones because
that is the next step i've got my spray
bottle here i've got a funnel i don't
have the funnel with me so i've already
failed myself i do have a workaround to
where we can make this work i've got my
spray bottle here what i would do
i would spray this i would have two or
three spray bottles honestly or i've got
another method that i do that is that's
going to remain one of my secrets here i
would have three spray bottles i would
mix up one solution that is ten percent
silver thiosulfate i would put uh how
much does this one hold 450 we'll say
just for uh to make this easier we'll
say that i've got a thousand milliliter
sprayer i would put 900 mils of
distilled water and uh 100 mils i lost
track of my math 100 mils of this
non-diluted silver solution so now it is
a nine to one solution nine parts water
one part silver i would mix up a nine to
one ratio so i've got nine parts of
distilled water one part of our silver i
would also do another one that is an
eight to two so i've got eight parts
water two parts silver then i would do
another one that is seven to three so
it's seven parts water three parts the
silver solution basically 10 20 and 30
percent
then i would spray each plant let's talk
about the schedule and intervals of when
to spray these plants i've got my golden
goat plants what i plan to do is i'm
going to spray them
seven days before i put them into flour
so today i'm recording on a monday i
want to put those plants into flour next
monday so i will spray them today give
them a full week put them into flour
next monday when they go into flour that
day i will spray them again they'll get
sprayed again so we're gonna spray them
seven days before and then we're gonna
spray them again on day one now here's
where we've got to pay attention because
now i will spray them every three days
until about day 21 or around 25 or 26
depending on what i see from that plant
some plants are stubborn and they don't
want to reverse if it's not reversing
keep spraying again i'm using three
different dilution rates so i can see
some things we're going to talk about
that in a moment but spray every third
day you're going to spray these plants
about seven to ten times total each
plant over the course of their life now
when you spray spray that plant just
about to the runoff point right when it
starts running off soak it towards just
dripping around be careful because the
silver solution can stain things it will
make things have a like a purple shine
to it or a silver color behind it i
should have stuff on this table honestly
so spray the plants
don't just spray the foliage spray the
stems the stalks the leaves everything
on that plant soak it the entire plant
and then it will absorb more of the
silver what's happening here uh brief
science i'm not a scientologist or a
chemistry major the silver disrupts the
copper movement and the plant which
triggers this plant the that's as far as
we need to go the silver disrupts the
copper movement we're trying to get the
silver into the plant the sodium
thiosulfate works to penetrate the leaf
surface and move that into the plant
that's why they're working together
that's why we mix this up if you want to
know more i've done full podcasts about
that i tried to stop myself from digging
down that rabbit hole because we could
go deep so now let's talk about times to
spray i think that's where i was right
somebody put me back on track i'm the
only one here so i'm going to spray one
week before flip oh we're talking about
uh dilutions and intervals right i
really kind of got lost but we'll fix
this
spray it one day then spray it
every three days stop around day 21 or
24 maybe 27 sprayed about 7 to 10 times
um what was i where was i going uh so
we're going to see things happen
sometimes
the heavier dilution will make the
plants crinkle up and look angry that's
okay we're not going for pretty plants
we're going for pollen here but also
sometimes too much silver can make the
plants angry and they don't produce any
pollen
sometimes not enough silver will make
them not produce any pollen sometimes
just enough pollen but not sprayed
enough or just enough silver but not
sprayed enough times or sprayed too many
times will make it not make pollen
there's so many
variables here we've got to learn how
much and how often with each plant the
only way to really do it is to do it
that's why i say spray three if you can
do five spray five of the same plant
spray them with that 70 80 and 90 and
then spray one of them more often than
the other and less often than the other
set up your own variables and take a lot
of notes and see what works for the
plants that you are working with i've
learned my plants i've learned how to
make the most amount of pollen that i
can get from them so it's just all trial
and error experience experimenting i'm
pretty sure that's where my brain was
going with that part you'll see twisted
crooked bent leaves weird [ __ ] happening
uh don't be afraid of that you're
looking for pollen the plants are going
to start making pollen sacks um you're
going to see these female plants start
doing [ __ ] you've never seen them do
before right where the new flower
clusters are coming out at the top
you'll see these weird little round it
looks like they're growing a crown or a
tip it looks like a pine cone it looks
like a uh like some kind of fruit it
looks like a little baby corn or one of
those little star fruits i can't think
of the [ __ ] name of it a really cool
looking fruit starts looking like that
it's growing out of the top of it um
that's the male parts forming around day
26 those will start opening by day 32 26
ish in that time frame they'll start
making pollen ah that's when you need to
have the ladies ready or be ready to
collect the pollen my strategy i
generally start putting the females in
the flowering room uh so you're gonna
spray these plants one week are you
gonna spray them on a monday next monday
put them in flour 12 12 spray them that
day spray them every three days
around day 26 they'll start giving you
pollen maybe day 32 it's plant specific
dude this is really the part you got to
adjust the intervals the timing and the
plants and the timing it's all [ __ ]
timing yeah so uh get the females in
there when the male plants start showing
you or when the female paul and donor
start showing you that it is making male
parts and you're sure that that [ __ ] is
reversing when you're positive that
you've done the trick drag those girls
into the flower room you should time it
just about right at this point like i've
talked about before my son my platinum
tangy plant that makes sun kiss and
orange gasm it wants pollen early that
plant that makes the strawberry
starburst the strawberry fields i use it
wants pollen much later so
you could probably your first run figure
it out by dragging them all in there the
first time you see the male parts really
significantly forming on your pollen
donor do your first cross that way then
learn the timing from note taking
watching what happens observation
learn from there then make adjustments
on your next crop always keep in mind
this isn't the last time we're gonna do
this project unless things go wrong this
isn't your last run we're gonna do this
again plan to make mistakes plan to make
adjustments this is you're the first
time you're riding this horse you're
gonna fall off of it don't be afraid to
get back up on that horse make some more
femme seeds and do that [ __ ] again i'm
going to review the notes i got lost in
one point but i feel like i covered
everything i'm pretty sure that my point
was talking about dilutions and when to
spray you're gonna have to learn how
often how hard to spray just like
learning somebody got to go how often
and how hard you don't know until you
figure it out um
spray them flip them spray them more
keep spraying drag the girls in there
keep spraying um you'll get pollen stop
spraying once you see pollen you guys
don't keep spraying the pollen you'll
ruin it i'll put the females in there
let them [ __ ] just let those guys
pollinate the girls um
when you're sure that they're done when
the girls are close to their point that
they're not going to receive any more
pollen and you're sure the guy plants
the pollen donors are done uh spitting
out their pollen cut off the tops and
just uh smack them around on the female
plants you'll knock out more pollen into
the room into those plants then i do
something weird i hang the plants kind
of from the lights or from the top of
the canopy
as the pollen donor dries more pollen
will fall out of there you'll get that
last little bit of pollen uh get every
drop that you can because femme seeds
femme reversals don't make as much
pollen as we would hope that's part of
why
all the all the caveats that catches the
tricks you heard are why fem seeds are
more expensive
um
learning the intervals learning the
timing learning how much learning the
dilution rate that all takes trial and
error that all takes note taking skill
repetition so you have to do everything
the same every time and just adjust your
solutions so that's why femi's seeds are
expensive also it doesn't make as much
pollen so i make about when i do a five
by five space i know how many seeds i
expect from rags i expect about half
maybe three quarters of that from a
feminized run if i'm lucky so that's why
femmes are a little bit more pricey
however this sop that i just gave you
honestly
i charge a lot of money for this sop i
have charged a lot of money for this sop
there are many details i did not give
you that included in the written
standard operating procedure but this
was an expensive sop in the past
and a standard operating procedure that
i would charge money for in a consulting
environment people were there are
companies built on this sop you guys
irie genetics uses this this is the
solution that i will use to make more
femme golden goat more lemon jeffree
more orange gasm uh chernobyl to
reversed golden goat what i said that
out loud on the show that is going to be
in the in the room so
this is the solution i'll make i'll show
you how i'm going to get into this
bottle actually i'm going to just dump
this one into here i will set this aside
that is 100 mix right there that's
basically the same thing that's in here
then i'm just going to dump it you got
to go quickly because the way that
physics and science and [ __ ] work i'm
gonna do with the mic in front of me and
see how much we spill but booyah go like
that get that into there now i can dump
this one into here easily that's how
it's gonna work and then we'll do the
dilutions
that's how it's gonna happen i do my own
ways of spraying that's gonna happen now
you guys i'm excited to go spray some
golden goat plants i get to pull them
[ __ ] out of the veg area get rid of
their safe space spray them down let
them dry give them a week then a week
from now we'll put them into flour then
about 25 30 days from there we'll drag
the other girls into the room then about
so many days from there guess what
lemon jeffrey orange gasm
golden goat
red pill and blue pill feminized seeds
coming soon there'll also be chernobyl
to golden goat testers available i'm
excited about that i'm sure you're going
to be excited about that right now there
are a lot of femme testers available if
you guys are interested in testing the
fems watch the femme or watch the tester
episode number 590 then join the discord
let me know send me an email and let me
know that you've done all of the steps
required to uh test and we'll get you
tested i've got a lot of tests you don't
want to get out all right i'm excited to
go spray those golden goats get some
femme seeds going i think i've covered
all the stuff i need to cover that is
feminized seeds simplified we're going
to get this water into this sprayer
we're going to dilute it we're going to
spray some plants we're going to make
some fens ladies gentlemen boys girls
pams hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pollen chuckers
femme seed makers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there i truly
do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast like i said
before this was an sop that i would
normally charge a substantial amount of
money for i give it to you for free here
i'm not begging i'm not trying to tug at
your heartstrings however there is a
patreon campaign if you feel like this
episode was valuable if you feel like
you learned something if you laughed at
something or you'd like to throw me a
couple of bucks just for my time i would
appreciate that the easiest way to do so
is to check out my patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart there is a link in the show notes
a link in the video description that
will get you right there thank you once
again for all of the support i look
forward to that don't forget to check
out the website at iregenetics.com
i r i e
g e n e t i c s dot com i read genetics
dot com
everything you need will be right there
questions corrections comments and
concerns the email address of course is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your questions
corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism positive feedback
or whatever else you've got to throw my
way i'm ready to take it hook me up
irene no grow from your heart at
hotmail.com the ocd is making me want to
rearrange this so the end of the show
looks nice on the screen all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls said
that part that is all i've got for you
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a big
shout out to my buddy rasta bob and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you