[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode 721
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
selecting plants for the outdoor season
before i get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my good
friend rasta bob let's send a big thank
you shout out to terp gooney and route
305. let's send a thank you shout out to
kanna organic illinois let's send a big
fist bump to lots of trichomes i want to
send a thank you shout out to orrick and
b bala let's send a big thank you shout
out to doc grows and peter r i want to
send a special thank you shout out to
our new friend frogman420
let's send a big fist bump and a thank
you shout out to the dad hayes i want to
send a thank you shout out to double d
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to jessica k
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends i do also want to remind you
guys about the groovy gravy secret stash
seed exchange event coming up in denver
on march 26th that's right march 26th in
denver colorado there is a seed exchange
event happening uh that will feature top
dog seeds oni seeds masonic smoker night
owl and of course irie genetics will be
there
if you're looking for that stanky
old-school terp find our friends at top
dog if you're looking for that tropicana
cookies find our buddy oni if you're
looking for some of those wilson crosses
our buddy masonic will be there and of
course if you need autoflowers of course
night owl genetics and seeds will be
there big up to my buddy daz there will
also be a lot of other breeders and
vendors and seed makers there there will
be glass artists live glass blowing food
trucks it should be a very entertaining
event i'm looking forward to it i also
look forward to seeing you there so join
us march 26th in denver colorado at the
groovy gravy secret stash seed exchange
event for more info really easy to
follow them on instagram look at it's
groovy gravy on instagram or follow irie
underscore genetics on instagram i will
tag them i will post their stuff we will
make sure you can find them i'll do my
best to put a link in the show notes and
the video description
i will remember to do that because i
just said so i'll do it while i'm
editing yo rasta jeff put that link in
the show notes while you're editing all
right where do we go from here ladies
and gentlemen let's jump into today's
topic it is a beautiful day here in
southern colorado it was the first super
nice day of the year it's been really
cold it's been a jacket and
gloves kind of season at least a heavy
hoodie season today i did not need a
hoodie when i went out of the house it
was super nice it was super beautiful
that means outdoor season is almost
coming before we get to that also it was
my birthday today so i want to give a
big shout out to all of my friends who
sent me birthday love birthday messages
yes i'm recording the podcast on my
birthday big exciting tuesday here but
uh we did have a great birthday weekend
i got to spend my birthday weekend some
with some wonderful people i got to meet
for the very first time in person i got
to hug and high five and smoke with our
buddy lemur priest big shout out to
lemur priest the captain and commander
of the irie army he's been part of the
crew for a long time he's a heavy
contributor to the patreon he's a bad
[ __ ] a cool dude uh we hung out
we visited meow wolf uh he brought his
lovely partner in crime i brought my
lovely partner in crime also we were
joined by the awesome curtis crosses big
up to curtis also big shout out to my
new friend lennon uh we had a great time
at meow wolf so i had a wonderful
birthday weekend had a the whole weekend
was great we'll talk about meow wolf
that's what we did friday uh saturday
spent some time with some other people
sunday was just me and my uh my lovely
queen great birthday weekend wanted to
say thanks to everybody for the birthday
love the hugs the shout outs the fist
bumps the high fives the gifts all the
social media explosion thank you i do
appreciate that extra thanks to anybody
who spent any moment with me on my
birthday weekend on my birthday this
week whenever it's been a great time big
thanks i do appreciate it thanks for
taking a moment out of your day just to
spend some birthday love on me i do
appreciate that all right let's move
forward enough talking about my birthday
uh i said i was going to talk about
outdoor growing it is the nicest the
first nice day of the year it made me
think i better get my [ __ ] prepared for
the outdoor season yes i may do some
outdoor stuff this year i don't talk
about it because i don't like too many
people knowing you don't need to know
what or where i'm doing outdoors because
that gives people too many opportunities
too many people out there suck so i've
got to keep that a little bit on the
down low until it's done and then i'll
tell you all about it but it is time for
everybody out there if you're going to
grow outdoors in north america i guess
if you're in other parts of the world
you may be wrapping up outdoors right
now maybe done i don't know where you
are but in north america here it is
outdoor time it's time to get the
outdoor season plan it is the first of
march we're going to put our plants out
there probably mid may uh early june
depending on where you are now is the
time to start thinking about it if you
don't have seeds or clones or some sort
of supply now is the time to get on the
hunt start searching start thinking
about it start figuring it out but there
are many things to think about before we
decide what plants to put outside how to
get them where to get them from let's
think about it um selections the first
thing on my note here is selections what
does good in your area let's find a
selection for you a plant a clone a
cultivar um the line the kind of the
strain is what a lot of people are going
to say the strain that will work best
for you in your area
many people are going to try to focus on
hype uh right now there are strains that
are popular i'm not going to say any
because then the breeder of that strain
will get back to me and say hey you said
my strain was hype there are a lot of
things that are just popular because of
social media and because of the name and
maybe a rapper saying about it or some
[ __ ] and it's not super quality it looks
good on instagram it's frosty it looks
nice but it doesn't have
mold resistance it doesn't have bug
resistance think about more important
things other than hype terps potency and
yield
does that plant work in your environment
if it doesn't finish on time where you
are the terps don't matter the potency
doesn't matter the yield doesn't matter
if it's not done before the first frost
comes in your area it doesn't matter how
good that plant was going to be it's got
to get finished if your plant can't
handle heat or fog or drought or
humidity or whatever comes to your
neighborhood your environment throughout
that grow season it won't be able to
survive until the harvest so don't focus
strictly on terpenes production flavor
buzz
weights don't think about that kind of
stuff as much it's important trust me
that does matter but more importantly
the resistance the ability the skills of
that plant can it survive where you are
that's much more important than a lot of
those other things so can that plant
take the uh i'm not sure where you are
that's why i said maybe it's going to
get drought conditions if you're in
arizona it's going to get hot as [ __ ]
and really dry if you're by the ocean
you're going to get humidity you're
going to get air coming off of the ocean
with a lot of water in it you're going
to get windy environment you're gonna
get fog can your plants handle the fog
if you're up in the pacific northwest
you're gonna get different [ __ ] if
you're in colorado different [ __ ]
mississippi different [ __ ] it's gonna be
different wherever you are so get plants
that will work best for you and your
environment then think about where are
we going to grow where is your
anticipated space and think about it
heavily you're going to have those
plants out there for months it's not
just going to be a couple of weeks to
camouflage them you're going to be out
there daily taking care of them tending
them watering them you've got to feed
them prune them twist them lollipop them
check on them i manage bugs manage
problems you're going to be touching
them every single day it's not as easy
to be secretive about these plants as a
lot of people would like to think where
are you going to do this are you going
to do it in the backyard you're going to
do it in the front yard you're going to
do it on the side of the house do you
have a big ass field where are you going
to do it do you have a big field way out
in the middle of nowhere where do you
plan on doing this think this through
very well think about from the day you
plant it to the day you cut it down to
the day you dry it cure and smoke it
what are you going to do with this plant
and the product have a plan now let's
set ourselves up for success we're going
to harvest around halloween and we need
to start thinking about it now in march
i know that sounds crazy but plan ahead
that's the only way we win when we're
growing cannabis don't come to the part
where you're like uh it's day 50 what do
i do on day 50 you should know that
around day 30 so you can prepare
at least be ahead all right where are we
going to grow does your anticipated
growth space get enough sun you get
enough direct sun are there uh slight
interruptions are there dark
interruptions is there a lot of [ __ ]
around there that is going to come on
lights that are going to come on during
the night cycle and possibly disrupt
your photo period is there a lot of [ __ ]
blocking the sun is there a lot of wind
there what kind of environment are you
in are there animals are there pests are
there intruders what kind of ground do
you have there are you going to grow in
beds are you going to grow in pots are
you going to go straight in the ground
are you going to build a greenhouse what
kind of obstacles and challenges is your
anticipated grow environment going to
bring you
do you have regular access to this place
a lot of people think ah there's a hill
a mountain that goes this way if you
take that one hill by the creek and take
a left nobody will ever find that spot
sure awesome can you get there every
single day to apply water to those
plants is that going to be safe also is
that a safe place for you to grow i
think that's coming up on the notes
let's think let's look ahead is that
compliant and legal we're just going to
jump right into it is that location
compliant and legal i know some of us
are going to do our own thing we may
grow where it's not legal we may be in
an illegal area but be careful don't
grow on federal land if you're growing
in a state park federal land land owned
by a lawyer or somebody prominent in the
community you could really shoot
yourself in the foot growing on that
land it could be even worse than just
growing in your own land so be careful
where you choose to grow in colorado an
outdoor grow must be secured and locked
up and inaccessible to thieves or
children or anybody like that it cannot
be available to school kids or
neighborhood kids it's got to be in a
greenhouse with a lock on it where
nobody can get in there that also does
work kind of helps to work as thief
deterrent it will not be the best way to
keep a thief out if the thieves want in
there they're going to get in there
that's something we're going to segue
into before that let's talk about a
lawyer if you're going to grow cannabis
legally or illegally especially an
outdoor crop where people can see it
things may go wrong i highly recommend
you develop a relationship with a lawyer
a lawyer will become your best friend
you don't want to ever need them but
it's great to have a lawyer on speed
dial a lawyer on the team a lawyer in
the crew that's already got a bag of
money with your name on it so every time
you call you go lawyer this is my
problem and they just reach into the bag
they take out a couple of the hundred
dollar bills or a thousand or a couple
thousand dollar bills and throw it in
their stack and they go all right here's
how you solve the problem and they just
check out how much money they've taken
out of your bag and you both know got a
little bit of a balance with you over
there whenever i call there's money in
your desk so you're gonna talk to me get
a relationship with a lawyer this sounds
crazy be a hundred percent honest with
your lawyer about what you're doing if
you're growing illegally tell that
lawyer you're growing illegally tell him
where why how and what your plan is that
way he can prepare for when [ __ ] goes
wrong because there's a good chance [ __ ]
could go wrong that's why we've got a
lawyer let him know what you're doing
that lawyer needs to know the details
because if there's a case built against
you whoever's building that case has
every [ __ ] detail it is 2022 they've
got aerial photos they've got documents
from where your phone was they've got
everything you've posted on social media
all your credit card receipts your car
mileage your gps in your car your onstar
your anti-theft piece
something is tracking you you're being
snitched on by yourself by your
equipment by your technology by your
movement all day every day so if you're
going to do something they are building
a case against you make sure your lawyer
knows every detail of the case as well
so that he can help you when the time
comes i know that sounds sketchy but
you've got to think about what if when
you were entering this type of
enterprise environment activity you do
need to be prepared so shout out to the
lawyers shout out to the people keeping
us safe on the team behind the scenes we
need them just as much as we need the
growers the smokers the breeders the
tremors everybody the lawyers are
essential
all right we've talked about the lawyer
now i'm going to segue into a part that
i don't like talking about but this is
required when we're talking about
growing outdoor cannabis you've got a
big-ass plant outdoors somebody may have
seen it maybe you ran your mouth and
told somebody about it maybe the one
person you told told two people they
told two people now like 17 people in
your neighborhood know they all know you
got that big plan out there they all
know your schedule because we're humans
we're predictable we all do the same
[ __ ] all the time mostly just because
that's how life works
that plant is at risk somebody may
decide to come try and remove that plant
from your grow space without your
permission people are [ __ ] people
are desperate especially now we had a
lot of things disrupt the world people
are struggling people are doing dumb
[ __ ] to try to stay afloat somebody may
try to come get that plant
i don't know what you're going to do
when somebody ends up in your yard
trying to take that plan if you were
growing illegally my advice is just let
them take it
i don't think that anybody's life is
worth a cannabis plant if they're
stealing my plant from my backyard i am
not going to shoot somebody for that
plant if that is what you choose to do
that is what you choose to do but i want
you right now to take a moment and think
about what am i going to do if somebody
comes in that yard to steal my ganja
plant then once you've decided what
you're going to do think about would a
jury agree with your decision if you do
choose to blast somebody down because
they're stealing your ganja plant a
judge and a jury may think that you have
decided that that person's life was
worth less than your medicine now to you
it may be but does the judge and the
jury agree i don't want it to ever come
to that point i really truly don't but
that is something we must think about
somebody may try to steal your [ __ ] how
are you going to protect it how are you
going to deal with it then down the line
how are you going to deal with this for
the next five years if you protect your
crop this could be a legal case that
could cause a lot of problems so think
about that before the plant goes outside
how am i going to deal with this a lot
of people in america are gun happy we've
all got a gun since the pandemic
everybody's ready to protect themselves
are you ready to bring that out and
protect your crop i don't recommend it i
wouldn't shoot somebody for weed plants
in my backyard if you went back there i
don't have weed plants i live in the
[ __ ] city my neighbors could just
[ __ ] reach over and take anything
they wanted basically they wouldn't
shout out guys i love you but they would
see the ganja plants they'd throw a
[ __ ] fix i live in the [ __ ] city
and [ __ ] here um if they were out there
and he tried to steal him i'd just say
hey man don't don't [ __ ] hurt the
neighbors don't shoot any dogs don't
[ __ ] up the fence just get what you need
and get out of here bro just get the
[ __ ] out don't come back that'd
basically be my approach that's why i
don't grow outside cause i'm in the city
and somebody will will steal my [ __ ]
you've got to think now what you might
do i don't want to go on too much about
that let's move forward because i don't
want to think about it um is is hitting
somebody worth your crop is shooting
somebody worth your crop or is i you've
got to think about it now because i
don't want you to be in that position to
have to panic and think about it plan
ahead any sort of thing when it comes to
defense tactical strategy you should be
thinking way ahead so
now let's talk about preparation
let's talk about something a little bit
more light-hearted a little bit less
creepy our whole goal is to grow weed
outdoors this year we want to produce an
outdoor crop we've got free sunshine
we've got an environment out there that
is probably ideal for growing cannabis
if you're in north america so how are we
going to prepare prepare for this what
is your main strategy how do you want to
do this are you going to grow
organically are you going to grow with
salt are you going to grow like i said
before are you going to grow in a
greenhouse are you going to grow in
raised beds are you going to use pots
are you digging holes and going straight
into the ground
do you plan to amend the soil
do you plan to just water every day and
put bottled nutrients into there what is
your goal the next thing to think about
is water how are you going to get water
to your grow space a lot of people may
think they're going to grow out there on
that plot of land their uncle left them
a few years ago how's the dirt out there
how is the soil out there more
importantly is there access to water do
you have a truck you can load up enough
water to take out there as frequently as
needed do you have a place you can get
that much water out there water is a big
thing to think about that people really
overlook when it comes to preparing for
an outdoor grow it's one of the most
essential things but you don't think you
don't realize how much water that plant
is going to need they're going to grow
crazy fast outdoors they're going to get
real tall real bushy it's going to get
100 degrees out there they're going to
want to drink a lot of water depending
on where you are if the earth is real
rocky if it's real damp they may need
more they may need less water but
they're going to get thirsty now a big
thing to think about
and maybe i should have talked about
this earlier but what is your budget
what kind of budget do you have do you
have budget a budget to buy a bunch of
nutrients to amend the soil do you have
a budget for really good genetics do you
have a budget for all of the stuff you
need or you want a shoestring budget
use your budget wisely i recommend good
genetics if you don't have good genetics
to start with you cannot meet the goals
you are hoping for so start with good
genetics like i said the correct
genetics in your environment so you need
good genes whether that's clones or
seeds you need good genetics we're going
to talk a lot more about that in a
moment then i would recommend getting
that soil amended well so you've got all
the things you need in the soil i'd
recommend investing in a couple of top
dresses for later on in the flowering
phase
make sure you allocate a little bit of
that budget for pest management and uh
pest deterrent maybe you've got deer or
bunny or bear or [ __ ] something else
wherever you are i don't know where you
are you're going to have to allocate
part of the budget to mitigating damage
from pests don't forget about that so
think about the budget think about what
you're going to need plan ahead
do you have a helper do you need
somebody to help you how are you going
to pay them don't [ __ ] your helpers over
i know so many friendships relationships
bro ships bromances that are [ __ ]
dead because people have built groves
together one guy had land one guy had
plants another guy had an idea and they
all said at the end of this we'll split
it up three ways and we'll all win guess
what one guy took all the [ __ ] and now
two people are mad those two people talk
[ __ ] about guy number three every time
they get a [ __ ] chance guy number
three doesn't have any [ __ ] friends
[ __ ] goes weird when that happens don't
ruin friendships over growing cannabis
that's not what it is about cannabis is
to unite us to unify us don't [ __ ] your
friends over if you hire them to grow
for you
take good care of the trimmers don't be
a [ __ ] to the tremors because
without them your product looks like
[ __ ] love and respect all the tremors
pay the [ __ ] out of them tip them all
right where do we go from there uh we
got the budget figured out how about
security what are you going to do for
security we talked about your plan for
the lawyer what are you going to do to
keep that growth safe and secure the
number one thing that i can recommend
for keeping a growth safe and secure is
to shut the [ __ ] up if nobody knows
about it nobody can steal it don't tell
anybody about it nobody needs to know
your best friend doesn't need to know
your girlfriend doesn't need to know
that girl you brought over that one
night doesn't need to know that dude
from the dispensary doesn't know your
friend at work doesn't need to know
nobody needs to know but you that way
nobody's mooching off you when it's
harvest time also nobody needs to know
about that plant out there if they can
see it there's a problem keep it where
nobody can see it because that seeing
that plant invites thieves a lot of
people are not thieves until you wave
some [ __ ] in front of their face if you
go hey look 10 foot tall weed plant free
weed free weed free weed for a week for
two weeks for three weeks they're just
watching it get bigger by the end of the
fourth week a motherfucker's gonna jump
a fence and get your weed and you're
just taunting them at this point so
think about security keep your [ __ ] safe
protected uh covered be smart about it
i know people that say nobody's gonna
jump this fence and get that
who what what the [ __ ] neighborhood do
you live in somebody's going to jump
that fence and get that [ __ ] i think the
other way because of where i'm from
where i was raised that shit's going to
get stolen that's just how it is if you
leave something outside where i'm from
that's just like sam it's free it's just
putting a [ __ ] free sign on it where
i'm from so step up your security get
your [ __ ] prepared also keep in mind
booby traps are illegal if you guys set
up a booby trap to protect your grow and
somebody gets hurt you did commit a
crime you can be charged with the
original cannabis crime and an assault
charge and a booby trap charge don't do
that kind of [ __ ] also if law
enforcement were to stumble into that
booby trap that's an extra charge
i don't know maybe some people don't
care about the rules and laws but keep
in mind booby traps are an extra crime
you'll get an extra trouble for that all
right where are we going from here we
have got some of the most important part
is going to start coming up now males
and females and tested cuts is what i've
got written on my list
you guys at the end of the grow season
in the middle of the grow season i start
seeing people post really heartbreaking
pictures i see people posting six foot
tall 10 foot tall plants that are as big
around as a volkswagen and they're super
bummed out because they just found out
that that boy is either interest or that
that plan is either a boy or an intersex
plan this is easily easily preventable
the the key to this is don't run into
untested cuts outside don't put some
[ __ ] outside that you did not run
indoors one time and establish what that
plan is is it a boy is it a girl is it
intersex is it a mutant is it a total
piece of [ __ ] don't put plants outside
until you know what they are
i do understand that it can be
challenging to acquire or obtain seeds
or clones or something to grow this year
i get it you might be new you might be
in a place where there's
limited or minimal or maybe no access
but still you've got to be very careful
if you put a male plant outside and you
don't know it's a male plant that male
plant could flower and pollinate every
crop for miles where i am in the city of
pueblo colorado we've got a lot of
growers here a lot of people like to
grow outdoors there are also many
commercial grow facilities just a few
miles from me that grow outdoors they've
got outdoor grow facilities if one of us
busted out a male plant and let it just
full-on skeet pollen everywhere for a
week we would ruin crops not just a crop
we would ruin crops of crops around here
and that is a dick move don't be that
guy to let a male plant go and ruin
everybody else's crop because you are
not a responsible grower i know it's
hard to get the plants that's what i
started with but
maybe you can trust your friends maybe
you can trust your dispensary but
nobody ever says hey i might have a
disease everybody says no i'm clean and
then guess what one day you find out you
got some [ __ ] everybody does the same
thing with their plants they give you a
clone and they go bro my garden's the
[ __ ] cleanest there's no bugs in
there the people that boast and brag the
most about having the cleanest garden
generally have the worst [ __ ]
problems is what i have learned so be
careful where you get your clones from
if they come from a dispensary if they
come from a friend definitely expect
them to have a problem expect them to
have spider mites fungus gnats thrips
something of that nature maybe powdery
mildew it is your job to treat those
incoming plants for those bugs you are
now the gardener you're now the farmer
it is your job your duty your
responsibility to get this crop from
beginning to end successfully that is
your only goal as the farmer is to
harvest a successful smokable profitable
crop so you've got to get the plant and
it is now your job to treat them for
bugs and for mildew and make sure that
these problems don't expand if they do
come with the plants now when you get
these plants
if you get seeds or plants or clones is
what i'm trying to say i would test them
that's why i'm saying get them now it is
march this would give us time to at
least sex test our plants it is very
easy
you can run a small plant indoors and if
you put it under 12 hours of lighting or
it's 12 on and 12 off in about 10 to 14
days that plant will show you if it's a
male or a female don't put the boys
outside call them chop them down throw
them away only put female plants outside
definitely do a sex test before you put
things outside because like i said we
don't want that male plant out there
ruining everybody's garden
now something else to think about is
that clone may have been tested by your
friend it may have been ran by your
friend but do you trust their selection
i like to grow from seed indoors make my
selections then put those selections
outdoors your first run with the plant
shouldn't be outdoors i understand that
not all of us have an indoor setup we
can't all get plants and clones and test
them but ideally you would get a pack of
seeds do a pheno hunt indoors find the
good one then put it outside and one of
the important things i want to get to is
maybe that clone that you got from your
friend was awesome in his indoor grower
in her indoor grow or maybe in his or
her indoor grow or outdoor grow in
california but where are you outdoors
maybe that plant that was selected in
norcal won't do the best in virginia
maybe something that was selected in
jamaica and grew amazingly there won't
grow as well in upstate new york maybe
something that grows really well in
upstate new york won't grow as well here
in colorado there's different
environments different environments it's
basically it different parameters which
these plants have to survive through
find the plants that work best in your
area if you can find an outdoor grower
who's been growing in your area for
generations they probably have the
plants that work the best for them for
you in that area because they know what
to expect they know that around the
middle of august it's going to get real
hot and then as september goes on it
starts to get real damp and then by
october it gets foggy they're going to
know the [ __ ] to expect and they know
the day it's going to snow and so they
know that this plant will finish right
before the snow usually comes so pay
attention to those local growers and see
what they're growing don't fall for just
hype don't buy [ __ ] just for hype like i
said earlier it's got to be able to take
temperature swings bugs
humidity
heat dryness it's got to handle a lot of
[ __ ] outdoors that it never got shown
indoors so make sure you're getting
clones that are good for the outdoors
not just for an indoor grow environment
so if you're going to buy a pack of
seeds i highly recommend you get i would
recommend if you're going to go straight
outdoors i would definitely recommend
feminized seeds that will eliminate the
opportunity for male plants you do still
have to keep a close eye on them there
still is the opportunity for intersex
plants you can get problems mutants
freaks still pay attention but it will
cut the chances in half of finding a boy
it'll cut the chances probably 99 of
finding a boy is what i should say
so that'll help you out you had a 50 50
chance of getting boys in there you just
cut that part right out of the equation
now you've got girls so if you're going
to get the seeds you're going to grow
them outdoors i would definitely sex
test them before you put them outside
don't just run them outside because then
you're going to be heartbroken or if you
do grow them outside grow extra and pay
very close attention and look for the
boys because like i said you've got a 50
chance of regular seed being a male
plant so pay very close attention to
those plants you do grow outside if you
did not sex test them all right ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts i do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy reach out to me i do love
the constructive criticism and the
positive feedback also if you feel like
the show was worth a buck if you learned
something if you chuckled a couple times
maybe just like to throw me a dollar for
my time all you have to do is check out
www.patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen for anything else
check out the website at
iregenetics.com before i wrap it up i do
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
graybeard graybeard is officially
running the irie genetics discord we
just reached over 2 000 followers
members on the irie army ire genetics
discord big shout out to everybody who
has joined if you are looking for the
discord there will be a link in the show
notes and in the video description i
really did want to take a moment to
thank everybody for joining also want to
send a big irie army salute a big rosta
jeff fist bump to my buddy greybeard for
taking care of the discord that is a big
job it's a lot of work to do and my
buddy greybeard is killing it over there
so thank you for the work brother wanted
to make sure you got some love here on
the show he always says that he doesn't
need love doesn't need fist bumps and
shout out but sometimes you got to send
a bad [ __ ] a thank you shout out
just to remind him that he's a bad
[ __ ] so shout out to my buddy
greybeard hope you're well hope you get
a kick out of this shout out right here
brother also one last thing before we
wrap it up your ad could go right here
that's right if you've got a product a
service something you'd like to
advertise on the show i am opening up a
couple of ad spots here on the show i
only advertise products i truly believe
in so if you got some [ __ ] skip me
but if you've got a product that you
think could help the community help out
the people that are interested in this
show if we can help each other help each
other i would be more than happy to do
that send me a message really easy grow
from your heart at hotmail.com i'll get
you all set up with the advertising
information that you do need all right
that is really all i've got for you for
this episode thanks once again for
listening i want to give a big shout out
to the painted lady and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you