[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode 722
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend frankie let's send a big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
rut ro i'll send a thank you shout out
to dave w and guido's grow room let's
send a big fist bump to thor's trike
factory let's send a thank you to spa
city gardener let's send a big thank you
shout out to luke and rosufa let's send
a thank you to my long time friend and a
good supporter tree star meadow let's
send a thank you shout out to tonto's
garden then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to girls grow 2.
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends this is of course the
part of the podcast where i invite you
to the groovy gravy secret stash seed
exchange event in denver colorado that's
right saturday march 26th there will be
a seed event in denver colorado make
sure you check out it's groovy gravy on
instagram for all of the details you
need check their link in their bio that
will get you right to the ticket link
that will let you know all of the seed
vendors that will be there that will let
you know about the taco trucks the food
trucks uh the uh the glass blowers and
the other exhibits that will be at the
event so check out it's groovy gravy on
instagram for all of the information on
the secret stash seed event i do hope
you hope to see you there in denver i
should have some great things with me
some brand new stuff that hasn't been
talked about has not been released
come say hi all right where do we go
from there i do want to thank you for
all of the great feedback on the past
couple of episodes i have gotten a lot
of emails a lot of feedback in general
on the uh the sts mixing episode i will
do an update there is more to be uh
talked about there were a lot of
questions asked is more discussion to be
had i am compiling all of those emails
all of those questions uh they're coming
on youtube instagram they're coming from
all over the place it is easiest to send
those to me in my email then i can find
them gather them in one place print them
paper clip them together bring them to
the table make it a podcast but uh the
point is there is an update to be done
so in the near future uh hopefully i can
bang out part two of the sts video uh
answer some questions there were
questions about storage um dilution
rates uh just a few random questions how
to collect the pollen so we will discuss
that in a future episode again thank you
for all of the feedback on that podcast
you guys did give me guys and gals
listeners and viewers gave me a lot of
feedback i do appreciate that thank you
that was well received i do appreciate
that and thank you for all of the
birthday love i did mention that on a
previous episode it was my birthday
thank you for all of the love my inbox
has been blowing up it is still it's a
couple of days past the birthday now and
the inbox is still going crazy so i do
appreciate that i do also want to take a
moment to send a big special thank you
shout out to some fellow podcasters some
great friends of mine there is a group
of folks doing a podcast known as the
irie army podcast that's right it is a
bunch of members of the irie army the
irie genetics crew has made their own
podcast uh they've got my blessing my
permission uh there's no competition or
anything like that i love that they are
doing a podcast it's a bunch of my
favorite friends a bunch of my favorite
people a bunch of my community that uh
myself and greybeard and other few other
people have really cultivated a nice
community and they have put together a
podcast
in that podcast they feature a member of
the ire army and interview them in a
real friendly laid-back environment
we're all friends so it's not like a uh
tell me about your grow it's like what's
up bro how do you grow man and it's
we're all just buddies and bros hanging
out talking about the grow i say we
because uh they have cordially and
kindly invited me to be a guest on the
irie army podcast so next week early
next week i will be recording with them
i honestly don't know if that show goes
out live or if it is pre-recorded and
edited i do think it's edited and put
out at a later time i will for sure let
you know when my episode of the irie
army podcast is available so that you
can listen you can watch you can enjoy
that but in the meantime please do go
subscribe to my friends at the irie army
podcast they are on youtube they've got
a great thing started they're getting a
good flow going
i want to give them a shout out and a
thank you because
every episode i get a lot of love i get
a lot of shout outs my company gets a
lot of love a lot of shout outs a lot of
attention comes on myself and my company
from that show i do appreciate it thank
you for the love they talk about how i
got them started how i kind of
inspired people and teach people and to
hear so many people say such uh
wonderful stuff about me was uh it felt
really good especially right around my
birthday to discover that there
are about seven episodes of people just
praising me for an hour it was kind of
cool so i enjoyed that it's not just
them praising me they talk a lot about
their personal growth their life their
style but everybody does make sure to
show me some love and our boy lemur
priest was on the show recently and he
made sure to remind everybody that it
was my birthday also uh greybeard made
sure to remind everybody that it was my
birthday on the show so i've been
getting a tremendous amount of podcast
uh love from the podcast community
birthday love birthday shout outs
birthday inboxes uh the po box was
stuffed with good [ __ ] my mailbox was
filled with good [ __ ] it's been a great
week so thank you guys uh thanks uh once
the part of that was a shout out to
everybody at the podcast over at the
irie army podcast if you're behind the
scenes behind the camera behind the mic
if you're involved good show you guys
i'm proud of you
people were like hey can we do this show
because we're going to use your name
we're going to use your people and i was
like please do that is awesome but i
think that the discord the irie army
discord is a great resource for new
growers for experienced growers it's not
only a place that i go for grow
information and grow advice i go there
for my social entertainment during the
pandemic during the quarantine time we
couldn't go places i would just jump in
the discord and hang out and there would
always be a dozen cool people in there
some of my favorite people are hanging
out in the discord right now a couple of
people that i seek guidance from
real adult advice are in the discord i
go there and hang out so they've
cultivated an amazing community for them
to create a podcast from that community
and share that and express their ideas
their views their opinions their
experiences with the rest of the world i
fully encourage that so i'm proud of my
friends for creating a a podcast it's
not even an offshoot of what i do it
just says irie army it's and it is the
irie army it's my friends doing a thing
they just happen to and i respect the
branding i respect the uh and it's
community i appreciate it and respect it
so shout out to those guys and this all
started with i'm proud of you guys and
thanks for the birthday love i went far
far too long with that uh big up to
lemur big up to graybeard big up to
billy uh big up to everybody behind the
scenes and once again i will let you
know when i'm on that show i am
scheduled to record i think it's a week
from yesterday or a week from today i
know when it is uh but by the time this
comes out i will be no i'll record the
day after this comes out i believe
anyway enough rambling i do have some
questions here in front of me this
podcast is already getting lengthy let's
uh let's jump into this first message
this one came from the man with no name
that makes it easy
this one says hi ross to jeff my
question is have you ever thought about
making and releasing autoflower versions
uh of for example golden goat sun kissy
lis a lot of a uh it says the man he the
man with no name lists several of my
strains which would make great
autoflowers then it says i know
i know that with your experience it
would be a doable task i am fervently i
don't know if i know what that word i
can figure out what it means i don't
know if i've ever heard fervent fervor
fervently yeah that's what it says
awaiting your next new drop i love the
show i literally have listened to
probably four or 500 episodes peace and
love your pal and then he does sign it
with his name which we will not reveal
here on the show shout out to my friend
the man with no name this is a great
question that i do get asked quite often
with all of the new states legalizing
cannabis and all of the new growers
coming on recreational medically and
even illegally i do get an influx of
requests for autoflower seeds a lot of
people teach that autos are the way
but i'm not going to discredit
autoflowers what i'm going to say is
this i am not into autoflowers
autoflowers are not for me the way i
think about autoflowers is there is a
time a place in an and an environment
and a situation in which those plants
are great for what i am doing for my
goals my desires
my needs autoflowers are not for me
uh they're great for other people i
always tell one of my favorite stories i
got some weird echo in the headphones i
apologize if that comes through in the
recording i will fix it maybe i'll just
keep talking i've got one of my favorite
stories to tell about autoflowers
because a lot of people do discredit and
talk trash about autos but this is a
great thing that i've seen happen with
autos there was a an illegal cartel grow
it was a allegedly a mexican cartel grow
they say it was a mexican cartel because
all of the food found at the at the
campsites was all of the mexican branded
products uh it was all uh mexican you
could tell us mexican food and mexican
brands and things like that i'm not even
trying to generalize and be racist it
was a mexican cartel grow so they found
this grow in the middle of the national
forest and they were running large
patches of autoflower plants all through
the warm season here in colorado so they
had i don't even know this square
footage but we'll say hypothetically a
quarter of an acre over here that they
started today then like two weeks later
start another quarter of an acre and two
weeks later start another quarter of an
acre and two weeks later start another
quarter and then if they time it right
every two weeks they're now pulling down
a quarter of an acre of ganja because
their autoflowers they'll grow they
don't have to change the sun cycle the
sun doesn't have to do anything
differently those plants are just going
to grow and flower because that's what
they do
if they would have put photo period
plants up there they would have had to
wait until nearly halloween maybe a
little bit after halloween here then
they would have harvested all of it at
once and it had been a lot of work
instead they threw those autos out got
them going got those healthy threw more
out threw more out got a perpetual cycle
going then i would assume that every
time you cut down a crop you immediately
sew more seed keep that pattern going if
you've got an eight or nine wheat crop
and you can get those seeds reliable at
eight or nine weeks and you can plant
four squares that turns out about every
two two and a half weeks you're pulling
a crop down and if it's um if it's a
mexican cartel pulling down weed they
don't give a [ __ ] about that extra week
they want product to chop up put in a
[ __ ] container and send it to
wherever they're making money they don't
really care too much about that extra
week of ripeness their customer isn't
the guy going ah this is this could have
gone another week that's a different
client that's a different customer
altogether so they're probably pulling a
crop every two weeks out there my point
is autoflowers do have a beautiful time
and place if the environment situation
is right but it is not for me now let me
answer the main part of the question the
question was will i ever consider or
would i consider making autoflowers as
some of my popular [ __ ] like the golden
goat they list the sun kiss lemon
jeffrey blueberry butcher and more and
many more it says
um i do know how to do it essentially
but
that's not for me so the quick answer is
no i will not make autoflowers of my
stuff
let me be clear that i said i will not
that does not mean that in the future i
wouldn't have i wouldn't work with
another reputable breeder big up to my
buddy daz at night owl uh he'd be my
first choice um that doesn't mean that i
wouldn't work with somebody to maybe
kind of make a fem or an autoflower
project really all somebody would have
to do all that dads would have to do dez
you've got my blessing and my permission
bro maybe uh send me a few or let's
collab and well dude but if you've got
the seeds you could do this this is how
cannabis works this is the beauty of it
i couldn't stop dazz and i have no
problem with daz if he does this and i
hope you hear this brother he could take
one of my strains anything he could buy
a pack of seeds he could find a keeper
he could breed it to his autos and he
could make an auto whatever i've got he
could make auto i don't know auto sun
kiss he could do it he's got the ability
the skills he's definitely further along
in the autoflower game than i am so he
would know how to breed it what to look
for how to select it and get it there
more quickly and be a marketable product
if he wanted to do it he totally could
do it and i'm gonna say that i'm okay
with that i don't even need to be
involved if you wanna cut or something
bro i'll send you something good so that
you could work uh cut out some steps but
it wouldn't hurt my feelings it wouldn't
bother me because i don't make
autoflowers it's not as a business it's
not gonna take away from my business
because i don't make autos my customers
don't maybe they do want autos but
that's not i'm not going to make them
anyway so i'm not going to lose any
sales if somebody makes an auto of my
line because i'm not going to do that
if i was making autos and somebody else
made an auto of my line and just copied
my [ __ ] that that's a dick move but i'm
not going to do it so if somebody else
does that's that's fair game another big
factor of that is i'm not into
autoflowers so i couldn't do it my
theory the name of the podcast is grow
from your heart i always say grow from
your heart and breed with love i'm not
in love with autoflowers so i would just
i wouldn't care it would just be is this
good enough can we just put these out
and that's not what my brand is known
for irie genetics is known for putting
out top quality [ __ ] that has been
thoroughly tested my testing is
transparent if you follow my discord
server there's a tab that says irie
genetics testers and i encourage
everybody that gets a test pack of seeds
from me to go to the discord and post
every picture you can on that server in
the tester tab that way we can see how
many of your seeds sprouted what they
look like when they're little how long
you veg them what they flower like how
long they flower the colors the shapes
the textures the trichomes like i
encourage you to post everything if
you're a tester so everything that comes
from me is bred with love it's
thoroughly tested i know that it is top
shelf top quality if i were to make auto
flowers it would just be some [ __ ] that
i slapped together so that all the
people asking for autoflowers could send
me their money and that's not how uh
that's not how i operate my company to
be successful i make things that i know
are top quality it doesn't go out unless
it is going to be a winner unless i want
to grow it again and again and i'm proud
of it i want to show it off and when
people talk about it they beam and they
light up it doesn't leave here it
doesn't become a product in the catalog
it gets tossed it gets forgotten about
so
my favorite way that i could describe it
is if i were going to make autoflowers
it would be like playing in a country
band i could do it i could hit the drums
and it would sound like country music
but it wouldn't feel
like good country music if you got me
playing some reggae music if you got me
playing some some jam rock music or some
straight funk we could get down and it
will feel like reggae music it will feel
like jamrock music you got me playing
rock and roll music in a rock and roll
band it will feel good and it will feel
right but if you want me to play real
country i'm not into it my heart's not
into it i'll do it for the money
but i'm not going to do it a long time
and it's not going to be the best it
could be there's somebody else out there
that should do that job that's how i
feel about autoflowers
country music is cool if you're into
that it's just not for me and that's how
autoflowers are in my opinion i often
use this analogy
cannabis breeders and selections are
like music i would obviously be the
[ __ ] reggae side of that coin and
then you got other breeders out there uh
maybe one of those breeders has more of
a uh a death metal vibe and maybe
another one of those breeders out there
has like a b52s kind of a vibe and maybe
somebody out there is full on got that
country music vibe we all find a breeder
that kind of speaks to us that kind of
connects with us that talks in a way we
enjoy and makes plants that we enjoy and
if i if i was making autoflowers i
honestly would be lying to you and
ripping you off and i'm i'm not the uh
the autoflower band if that makes any
sense i've talked enough about that uh
big up to my buddy the man with no name
i do appreciate that long story short
brother i will not make the autoflowers
myself but that does not mean that
somebody on my team somebody in the crew
will not make them and we may one day if
they're thoroughly tested and they
qualify and the consumers approve we may
put the ire label on them it will be uh
transparent and well known that i didn't
do it that they were bred by a qualified
certified auto flower uh
constructionist i'm trying to find a
fancy word for that a breeder is where
i'm going all right i'm gonna stop
talking for a minute take a drink then
we're going to read the next email
all right i am back i am hydrated my
voice is lubricated i'm ready to get
this ramble fest going again i've got an
email here in front of me from somebody
that uh who's become very uh familiar to
me i see your name in a lot of places if
i'm online i probably see your name
there big up to my buddy dave from
ontario this message goes a lot like
this it says i was just watching the
thick shells episode i did an episode a
while back about seeds having too thick
of a shell it says i thought i would
contribute a question in case you
thought it might make a good episode
this is a great question for the show i
do like this it says my apologizes if
there's already an episode on this
subject
i'm gonna ramble on that there's like
700 episodes and i often forget what
i've done shows about so uh if you have
a question and you're like you probably
talked about that don't be afraid i may
have learned something my opinion may
have changed i may have forgotten to say
something on the last time i talked
about it
send me your question don't be shy
because there are 722 episodes i'm not
gonna make you search all the way back
to episode five to find the answer and
if it's like a hundred episodes back
that's a year right that's yeah that's a
full year my education my theory my
practices may have fully changed so
re-ask your new question and i may give
you a completely different [ __ ]
answer than what i gave you last time
you can call me on it you can see the
growth experience
don't be afraid to change but um
yeah so don't be worried if somebody's
already asked the question that you've
got that's cool because most people i've
learned don't really search through the
catalog to find the old stuff they just
ask the question hope for that i'll
answer it now let's get myself on track
here this question from my buddy dave
goes a lot like this it says i am
growing raphael and sun kissed together
my first irie genetics run and i cannot
wait until harvest
that's a great lineup together bro
that's gonna smell so good in that grow
room that's gonna smell like a smoothie
it's gonna smell like a smoothie shop a
fruit stand ah it's gonna smell like a
good fruit jungle it's gonna be
beautiful in there and you said i can't
wait until harvest bro please wait until
they're done which is a good part of
this uh the question here but a lot of
people say i can't wait bro just wait
set your mind too i am going to wait uh
make it a game that you're going to wait
even longer than you should and then
the psycho the psychology will work out
to recut it down at the right time
a lot of people get too eager and cut
down too early and disappoint themselves
and they say next time i'll go longer do
it right the first time we'll figure it
out all right there is more to this it
says sun kiss says 50 to 60 days raphael
says 65 to 70 days my question is and i
like this question how accurate would
you consider your flowering times also
if you could comment on the flowering
times versus flowering times of other
breeders are yours more accurate in your
opinion this is such a great question
and a good topic
it says i would be harvesting sun kiss
on day si or would i be harvesting sun
kiss on day 60 uh would it be
approaching over ripeness what about
harvesting in the 65 70 day range uh and
then similar question here with
harvesting sun kiss on day 50 considered
harvesting too early even though it is
in the range
um all right we've got enough of the
question figured out i know exactly what
you're asking this is a really good
question
there are two parts to the question so
let me jump up and get the first part
how accurate would you consider your
flowering times and i think that'll
segue us into a good ramble to answer
this whole question here uh my flowering
times the flowering times which i print
on my website and my official seed
packaging and you will notice that
sometimes i do go and update the website
because we learn
uh through
uh let's say i put out a hundred test
packs that means i'm gonna get 80 to 90
reports back and if those people tell me
it took nine to ten weeks we're going to
put that on the package but over time
people will buy the product now that
we've released it and now 500 people
will grow it and we'll get the ratio the
options grow now that our test sample is
larger the options for more anomalies
and outliers start popping up and so
sometimes with more test samples with
larger test batches we get more data and
we do have to adjust our flowering times
but i do really think that the flowering
times i list on my website are mostly
accurate
that comes from a few things that comes
from me growing the seeds out that comes
from like i said a second ago sending
the seeds to testers when i make new
seeds when i have a new batch of seeds
i'm doing it right now you guys have
heard me i'm looking for testers i'm
auditioning testers if you want to test
seeds let me say this again make sure
you listen to the seed tester episode i
think it is number 590 find that episode
listen to that then the next thing is to
join the discord and let me know you're
serious because i will require you to
post photos on the discord server
if you are a tester where the hell was i
oh testers everybody likes to test
things i send a lot of test seeds out
i've got a lot of test seeds out there
right now when i get new stuff i send
out testers i'll probably send
somewhere between 25 and 100 i know
that's a random number but it just
depends on honestly how many of the
seeds i've gotten um
sometimes i can see what i want right
away sometimes i know exactly what i've
made sometimes and sometimes i'm like i
better run that a few more times we've
got one right now that i'm testing that
i had about 20 people say it was looking
good one person came up with a weird
anomaly that i've never seen before and
so i sent out 25 more packs just to see
like i said numbers maybe maybe somebody
will see that again and then i have more
research more data so we do a lot of
testing
my testers all have different levels of
experience uh different environments
different lights different soil
different uh maybe not even soil
different cocoa different hydro
different nutrients different air
conditioners different filters
they've got different combinations of
different setups so i let different
people run the same seeds and then i put
all of that data together i get all of
these grow reports and i'll put all of
the uh we're just going to say that
right now people are testing let's talk
about one that finished testing just
recently that'll make it more easy for
me to talk about a strain i recently was
testing bubba kush cross 2 arise it's
the pre-98 bubba kush the female
pollinated by the male arise king
solomon uh that's it past testing it has
been officially named uh that is the
moon tower so people were growing that
we sent out a bunch of packs of moon
tower nobody knew what they had they
were growing that i i got a lot of
feedback people sent me like uh just a
list of people sent me all their grow
reports i've got it all on uh in an
email all on discord and i just open up
a little file that says moon tower and
then i'll put your name and then i'll
put all the details that you send me in
a list and then i kind of can do um it's
i can just see commonalities like oh
tall smells like pine cones smells like
gas makes me lazy gives me the giggles i
can find the commonalities in there and
that's kind of how we list our
descriptions that is also how i come up
with flowering times cannabis is mostly
going to be eight to ten weeks sometimes
rarely less than eight weeks sometimes
10 12 14 16 weeks just depends on what
you've got so i let a bunch of people
run it most of the time they give me
very common reports i get like this one
was done at 63 or this one was done and
a lot of times getting a tester to go
past 70 days is also a challenge so
that's something that i've got to do
i've got to run those on my own
sometimes
i get a lot of reports and then i kind
of just see like i watch the the flavor
reports the growth statistics and charac
characteristics i watch for flowering
times just like i do all those other
feedbacks then i kind of do a lot of
averages if a lot of people say this
takes nine weeks i will tell you that it
takes nine to ten weeks i try to give
you that extra week because
like i talked about earlier people get
eager and anxious and they cut [ __ ] down
too early and if it takes nine weeks
i'll put ten weeks on that package just
sometimes to encourage you to go that
extra week also sometimes that extra
week is where some of the stuff really
bulks up and beefs up so how accurate
are my flowering times in my opinion in
my experience they are fairly accurate i
do offer a two week range on most of the
packages now let's talk about something
very important
these plants are being grown in
different environments they mean they
may be grown in a dry climate they may
be grown in a wet climate they may get
over watered underwater overfed underfed
abused loved cherished insulted they
could get a lot of different [ __ ] every
one of those things i mentioned can
alter the flowering time also phenotype
maybe you got the let's talk about sun
kiss because sun kisses one that could
really this could really happen
that tangy leaning phenotype that's done
in 56 55 days um if you get that more
golden goat leaning phenotype that's a
65 dare so you could have both of those
from the same pack of seeds it's just
phenotype dependent and a lot of people
really like finding that golden goat
dominant phenotype it's golden goat with
oranges on it a lot of people like
finding that tangy phenotype because
it's tangy with golden goat potency and
then somebody's gonna want the one right
in the middle so it's all about finding
the one that works for you but the point
is
um the phenotypes are going to make a
difference and a lot of people
don't like the f1s because of the
phenotype variation i love it a lot of
people like that you can find the plant
that is for you so that is why i give
you approximately a two week window
within there are always outliers there
this is nature this is science and
nature coming together uh there will
always be outliers if i say 55 to 65
days there will be 50 day flowers and
there will be 90 day flowers that's just
how genetics are going to work i'm
giving you the best idea that i can
uh always pay attention to the trichomes
always go in my opinion if i told you 70
days if i told you 65 days
in the first run always go to that last
number that's what i encourage i want
you to see what it does let's watch it
see why are you going to cut it down too
early it might bulk up it might get more
potent it might do some cool [ __ ] might
get some cool colors always go to that
last part so
how accurate do i consider my flowering
times to be i like to think they're
accurate because i do a lot of testing
a whole lot of testing
i'm making it very transparent i'm
having a lot of fun making the testing
transparent because you guys can already
see what's coming and it makes people
super excited about it and it builds a
little bit of hype and a little bit of
mystery i don't tell you what you've got
when i send you testers but i know i've
got a legend and i'm like oh um our
buddy dave over here is testing product
number five and then i know that you've
got bubba kush to arise and you don't
know it and i'm just watching you grow
and comparing yours to lemurs and
lefties and [ __ ] whoever else is
growing whatever i'm just throwing out
random names don't think i just told you
what you've got i made [ __ ] up just now
but i'm comparing notes and watching
pictures and just getting excited for
you and then when everybody's close to
finishing i start telling you what it is
i'm like everybody in this group has the
same stuff and everybody in this group
has the same then we reveal what it is
it's a lot of fun i love the testing so
that is how i determine what to write on
the packages i watch what the testers do
i use their feedback kind of average
that and i know by the male plant and
the female plant what to expect in
flowering time also so i have some
anticipation there
i don't tell the testers how long to let
it flower i tell them let it go till
it's done sometimes like i said it's
hard to let them go past 70 days for a
tester all right so i've answered the
first part how accurate are my flowering
times where do we go from there
um
my flowering times versus other breeders
i can't i'm i don't know
honestly what the other breeders type on
their packages unless i'm buying that
seed pack and running if that's not my
business
literally not my business i'm going to
focus on what i read genetics does and
we're not going to praise or bash any
other company
um
yeah we'll just leave it at that i don't
know what other breeder i don't know
what they're doing it's not my business
quite literally um so then you're
talking about would harvesting sun kiss
on day 60 be approaching over ripeness
all right
this is where
i'm going to say
this is going to be plant-specific i
don't know your grow i don't know what
you're doing i don't know how hot cold
dry wet humid overfed underfed abused
loved kissed lollipop defoliated
overheated
um stressed
dark interrupted i don't know what
you've got going on in there so i really
would say
watch every single plant you can't just
so if you've got a pack of sun kiss and
a pack of strawberry starburst you can't
just say the strawberries are done at
one day and the sunkists are done at
another you've got to watch every single
plant in there and pay attention to each
one i know that is probably not the
answer you want but that is it's the way
it's got to be done if you want
perfection now in a commercial grow
environment um
i would take all these to 65 days
probably six about 60 65 days and then
just chop them because in a commercial
environment it's in a commercial
environment most of the time we go uh
nine weeks 63 days unless it's uh unless
the owners are really cool then you go
seven we are 70 days the 10 weeks but in
a commercial grow these would probably
all come down at the end of week nine to
be honest with you what i would do
um i would find if you want to run these
together
this is the inaugural run this is your
first date i would find um find two that
work well together something just went
wrong with that [ __ ] camera we're
gonna have to finish the whole episode
on this one we're gonna wrap it up quick
that camera just took a [ __ ] [ __ ] you
camera one um i hope i got this so let's
keep going um i would find phenotypes
that work well together and grow them
together or find phenotypes that are
completely opposite that complement each
other and run them you can grow them at
the same time that's not a problem
you're just gonna have to time it when
it comes time to flushing which will be
cool because uh that will save you on
the headache of trimming if you've got
the raphael that comes down closer to
day 70 and the sun kiss that comes down
closer to day 50 that's hypothetical
that gives you nearly three weeks of dry
cure and trim time you could almost get
one down
dry it trim it get it in the jars to get
cured then get it into wherever it goes
for storage before you even cut down the
other batch you could have a nice
perpetual harvest without having one
harvest at one time and a perpetual grow
all right this podcast got shorter than
i intended it for it to be because i
don't know what happened to that camera
honestly you guys it's plugged in
everything should be rocking it flashed
some [ __ ] on the screen it went out no
excuses we're gonna make this work thank
you for watching um the next episode
will be better because this one was a
[ __ ] train wreck big shout out to my
buddy dave uh where are we if you have
any questions corrections comments or
concerns please send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com everything else is on the
website
iregenetics.com i'm going to wrap it up
because i don't want to ramble if this
isn't even recording guys thank you for
watching i love you every day big shout
out to my buddy billy bong smoking and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you