[Music]
so
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff this is
episode 723
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to do an update
on my recent silver thio sulfate episode
before i get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to our
friend daniel let's send a big thank you
shout out to adhd grower and jay dutch
let's send a big thank you shout out to
just a smokin and know me by my
guacamole
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to shoetrader101
let's send a big thank you shout out to
polo paul and grow man stan let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
kojaks and chicoba then let's wrap it
all up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to grow
bandit big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make it nice
and easy for all of my friends to
support the show this of course is the
part of the show when i invite you to
the groovy gravy secret stash seed event
in denver colorado on saturday march
26th that's right irie genetics and many
other great seed vendors and breeders
will be at the groovy gravy secret stash
seed exchange event at an undisclosed
location near downtown denver in denver
colorado saturday march 26th
make sure you check out itsgroovygravy
on instagram at it's groovy gravy is the
one throwing the party give them a
follow on instagram all the information
you need will be right there there is a
link in their bio so check out it's
groovy gravy on instagram check the link
in their bio that will get you tickets
when you check out make sure to use
coupon code rosta jeff that will save
you 10 off your tickets to the event i
look forward to seeing you there pop by
the booth say hi can't wait to see you i
should have packs of blue raspberry
truffle strawberry starburst sun kiss
saka souffle the machine uh there will
be some new stuff what will we have the
new stuff there will be some of the moon
tower will be available moon tower what
is that what we recently talked about
the moon tower that is the bubba kush
female pollinated by the arise we call
it the moon tower the name's inspired by
of course the movie dazed and confused
i'll rat alright alright party at the
moon tower that's enough about that join
me the groovy gravy secret stash seed
event in denver look forward to seeing
you there once again if you need more
info send me an email or make sure you
do follow it's groovy gravy on the gram
all right where do we go from there
um i was recently on i've talked about
this on a previous episode i was
recently on the irie army podcast i want
to give a big shout out to all of my
friends who support the ivory army
podcast big up to billy for the
co-hosting skills there big up to
graybeard for the co-hosting of tech
skills there uh very good questions very
well done show
very interactive show we did 30 minutes
of uh kind of structured material they
asked me pre-written questions then
after that they opened it up to the uh
the chat audience and they got to ask a
bunch of questions that was a good time
i think it was a well done show i got to
uh showcase my brand i got to talk a lot
about my history and who i am and got to
answer all the questions that some of my
friend friends and supporters have
wanted to know that was a great time so
make sure you check out the irie army
podcast if you're not already subscribed
go to youtube give them a subscribe also
if you're not subscribed to my show
please do click subscribe now is a good
time
once again big shout out to my friends
at the irie army also uh not just thanks
for the podcast but thanks for the hang
that was a good time then after we
wrapped up the show we hung out on the
on the server and we chatted for a solid
hour and that was a good time those guys
were my friends my family that's my crew
so thank you big salute rasta army irie
army thank you for being i was gonna say
part of the team you guys are the team i
may be the team captain but without all
you uh you maniacs all you irie army
members out there i'm just a one-man
army and i do need to support the crew
of the team so thank you each and every
one of you do mean a lot to me the irie
army we take more dabs before 9 a.m than
most people do
all day all right let's keep moving with
this podcast because i do have a lot of
stuff i want to cover i have a lot of
notes here i'm trying to get the notes
lined up so i can read them and not get
distracted all right i want to do an
update on a recent silver thiosulfate
episode if you haven't been following
along recently i did a show about making
our own silver thiosulfate that is a
solution which we would use to reverse a
plant to make feminized seeds i don't
want to do a full recap because i've
already done the full episode scroll
back a couple episodes it is available
watch that one this is the follow-up
apparently um i missed a few things
which that's not uncommon for me i try
to talk and be uh what's the word
succinct might be the word i don't know
text me email me let me know if that's
even a word
i try to get it right the first time but
i'm human and i'm also a stoner i'm not
a robot some people say i'm an alien 100
human i'm going to make some mistakes
and thank you for giving me the
opportunity to do updates and
corrections and also forgive me when i
do make more mistakes in the future
because i promise i'm gonna [ __ ] up
again but for now i do have some updates
some corrections uh some more info for
the silver thio sulfate episode let's
jump into it here goes the update silver
thiosulfate part two
most of these questions came from emails
from the youtube channel uh through the
irie genetics grow help tab on the
website check out the website there's a
tab there that says grow help if you
have questions about anything you can
reach me through there just skip the
grow help part type in your question at
the bottom i'll still get that i will
still answer that if i have not answered
your email or your tester application
once again i do apologize it's just me
going to stay on track
a lot of the questions were about
storing the solution we would mix up
part a mix up part b then mix them into
a solution then we would dilute that
there were many questions about storage
here is the straightforward answer it is
best to okay it will last longest i
think is the way that i should say this
for best preservation of the product it
will last longest in the powder form
once we mix it into the waters we are
the water uh we are now reducing the
shelf life of that product once we
combine those two sources together we
are now even greatly more reducing the
shelf life of that product once we
dilute it we have even more drastically
reduced the shelf life of that product
so every time we dilute it every time we
mix it we're kind of reducing the shelf
life and the viability of that product
so what i recommend is i mix up one
liter i know that one liter is going to
get me through my multiple days of
spraying my multiple applications i can
spray several plants several times
several days by mixing up one liter that
one liter recipe is really easy to make
the recipe is simple the amount of water
you need the measuring equipment 500
mils uh the half gram two and a half
grams the math works out very well and
that's about how much i need to get my
reversals done so i make that one liter
that one liter stores long enough to get
me through the 21 days worth of
application without having any problems
if you do see uh discoloration or
coloration i guess any sort of color
happening in there sometimes you'll see
dark granules or black chunks at the
bottom of the the mix that's probably
bad you need to pour that out and remix
so i don't have a tried and true shelf
life for this product what i do know is
that when i make that leader and i throw
that leader in the refrigerator that's
something we're going to talk about here
is storage
i keep it in a refrigerator and it is
clearly labeled it's a big jar and it
says silver thio sulfate solution on it
to where nobody in my house it's just me
here but i make sure that nobody that
shows up comes over is going to drink
out of that maybe mike comes over takes
a giant dab maybe clint pops by uh he
doesn't dab because he's kind of not
that cool yet but maybe he hits the dab
pen and he gets a little fuzzy and he
goes to the fridge and needs something
cold to drink i want to make sure none
of my crew none of my friends none of my
family reach into my refrigerator and
drink the silver thiosulfate solution i
don't think it would cause them drastic
health problems i don't want to find out
so it is clearly labeled in the fridge
keep it in a cool dry dark place if you
can put it in a brown paper bag like
some bum wine just put your clear jar in
a brown bag that will protect it from
the light uh the light is off in the
fridge when you close the door the light
goes off i don't [ __ ] with the fridge a
lot i'm a single i'm not a single dude
i'm a bachelor living alone um
here by myself the fridge doesn't get
opened a lot so uh it stays nice and
cool dry and dark in there so honestly
it is uh it's effective for me over that
course of 21 days it does not lose its
strength it does not lose its uh
viability it does not lose its
effectiveness over that 21 day period
while it is kept in my fridge so what i
do is i'll take the the one uh the
leader i'll take out the amount that i
need put that in my spray bottle dilute
it
usually i can get two applications from
one spray bottle worth i'm using just
the spray bottle that uh you probably
use to put cleaner in and spray the
windows or some sort of just a basic
spray bottles i think it's 450
milliliters is what it's marked up to on
the side of the bottle i can get two
applications of three semi-large plants
out of that one bottle so
i mix it i dilute it i mix it i fill
that bottle i shake the [ __ ] out of it i
spray i leave that bottle sitting in a
cool dry dark place it's honestly in
just my mix area when i'm not in there
the lights in the mix area are off it's
cool it's dry it's dark
it's a comfortable environment for a
person i think that would be a decent
environment for that solution it sits
there ah three days later i shake the
[ __ ] out of it again apply it to the
plants know my spray bottle is empty at
that time i'll clean it out uh when it's
time to make more i will make the
dilution i'll pour my 10 or 30 whatever
percent into the container uh then i'll
mix the 70 or 90 percent dilu distilled
water into there shake the [ __ ] out of
it then i can get once again two more
applications out of that uh by the time
that jar that mix is getting empty i
have my plants are done they're reversed
they're getting cut down it's already
done the magic so
um
the storage they store best as powders
they store a little less longer every
time you mix them and dilute them they
start to lose their um their shelf life
is i'm not a scientist i'm not a
chemistry major to be 100 honest with
you but in my experience uh from the
best of my knowledge from what i've been
taught read and learned
they do last longest as the powder
shorter as they get wetter and more
diluted more dissolved so um keep them
in the fridge i keep them in a cool dry
dark place clearly labeled make sure
that once again if you have family if
you got kids especially if you've got
kids this may be
a weird detail if somebody if you if
somebody in your house drinks alcohol
that's when we make a lot of silly
mistakes we do a lot of weird [ __ ] maybe
put it somewhere that you cannot
accidentally drink it if you're drunk
put it in the bottom somewhere in the
crisper drawer in the bottom somewhere
you just won't get to it set yourself up
for success is what i'm saying we don't
want to be that grower that breeder that
seed maker that that [ __ ] getting
somebody sick because we didn't properly
label and or store the things we're
using for our grow so put that in a safe
designated place make sure it's labeled
also keep in mind drunk people young
people uh sometimes old people sometimes
normal people can't [ __ ] read so set
yourself up your home up for success
i've seen people take a ring of duct
tape and put it right around the top uh
just because when people grab they're
going why the [ __ ] is there duct tape
around here that'll slow them down make
them think not to drink the silver
sulfate solution i don't keep mine for
very long i use it and i make more i
keep that 100 percent solution in a in
the refrigerator and i dilute it as i
need it i apply it usually i can get two
sprays out of a solution out of a mix
and that is basically the storage of the
silver thiosulfate solutions now let's
move forward i spray with the lights off
one of the questions was when do i spray
i try to spray any spray application
with the lights off this doesn't matter
if you've got to turn it's best if you
can hit it right when the lights go off
in the grow space if you can time it to
where like you know the lights go off at
seven you're in there at like 6 59 you
start spraying those lights go off and
then you can finish spraying close up
and get out of there real quick that's
not a problem that couple of minutes
worth spraying those uh plants with
silver won't disrupt anything if you
could pull the plants out just before
night time take them to another location
and spray them then right as the lights
go off return them to their home and
then let them sleep that is probably
best so i always spray with the lights
off if the plants are removed from the
grow lights or you just don't want them
under those intense lights for a couple
of reasons
um
remember when we were kids some of us
did this some didn't you could burn if
you watched beavis and butthead you saw
this you could burn ants with a
magnifying glass if you get a bubble on
your leaf when you're spraying with the
big grow light on and that intense light
hits that bubble it could make a little
burn mark on your plant also there's a
thing called photo toxicity sometimes
the things we spray on our plants may
have a photo reaction with the light
with the heat something may cause an
interaction to cause a problem on your
plants so let's not spray with the
lights on if you can drag those plants
out of there spray them right before the
lights go off right as the lights go off
put them back in the room so they're not
getting hit with that big light while
they're wet that would be ideal be
careful not to get the silver solution
on other plants you only want this on
plants that are going to get sprayed if
you're putting them in a room with other
plants make sure that those plants that
the sprayed plants are dry before you
introduce them back to the population
another thing is i usually spray and
then
that first time i spray is about seven
to ten days before a flower so that one
i just spray lights go out i spray we're
in veg not a big deal once i go into
flower i will wait so my i've got my
room set to 12 12. it's going to come on
at 9 00 a.m or 9 p.m however you're
living it comes on right so that light
will come on whenever you've got it
scheduled i don't know how your setup is
going uh the lights come on boom the
plant's in there this is its first day
of 12 12. when i know that that timer is
about to go off maybe 10 15 minutes
before that i'll go grab that plant pull
it far from the light and spray it now
this is day one for that plant so i'm
going to spray it with a silver solution
let it kind of dry up then when the
lights go off i'll just move it back to
its normal spot so that tomorrow when
the light comes on it's back in its home
that is its first day i like to spray it
right before the lights go off then put
it into darkness give it that first day
of darkness right after that spray that
seems to work for me that seems to be
effective that is the way i've been
doing it so that is when um so we've
covered storage of the solution we've
covered when to spray spray with the
lights off
spray in the dark make sure not to spray
the other plants if you've got to pull
these plants out of the room and spray
them that may be ideal
that should be what you're doing anyway
because you want to flower these plants
a little bit ahead of the females we're
going to talk more about that that may
be getting close to where we are um so
you want to get these male plants in a
room by themselves if you can or the
pollen donor plants i should say in a
room by themselves if you can and get
them ahead of the girls when making
femme seeds let's talk about one of the
big questions we got was pollen
collection and storage of the pollen
that is a really good question our main
goal here is to create feminized pollen
what are we gonna do with the pollen
once we've created that
um what i do
i've got two separate areas
i've got a main room with a three by
three tent inside of that room so my
girls are in one area they're vegging uh
they're under a light they're getting
vegged then i will move my male plant
into the tent or my pollen donor i
should correct my nomenclature my worded
cheer my verbiage uh this is a pollen
donor it's a female being moved to a
tent three of them get moved to a tent
uh they are on their own light now i'll
put them under 1212 and spray them um
they're going to start making pollen
you've got a couple of options what i do
i grab those pollen donor plants uh when
i know it's about time i grab them and i
move them strategically throughout the
grow space one goes right in the middle
of all the females one goes on this end
of the females because there's an
extraction fan on this end so i wanted
to kind of pull the air right over there
and the other one kind of sits off to
the side because i'm saving that one i
want that one to make a bunch of pollen
so that that's my back up my second
pollination so um you can just put one
at the edge of the plants at the edge of
the canopy and just let that pollen dust
in or you can collect the pollen if you
want to collect it keep the males in
their own area the pollen donors in
their own area and as the pollen starts
coming out you can tap it i use often
times i'll get a pyrex dish it's going
to be heavy a pyrex dish is much heavier
than you anticipate get a good grip on
it don't drop that bad [ __ ] in the
grill you'll break some stuff maybe even
the dish it will suck so i've got the
pyrex dish i've got a grip on it i'm a
drummer i've got a drumstick handy i'll
grab a drumstick and just tap that plant
and it'll tap the pollen right into that
into that pyrex dish just give it a few
taps you can do this every few days it
will start giving you pollen it'll make
more pollen just know that every time
you touch this plant pollen is going to
go all over the place there's going to
be pollen everywhere you're going to
sneeze it's going to taste gross it's
going to get in your eyes it'll be funky
so you can drag that
pollen donor over to the rest of the
plant over the population when you're
ready or you can collect the pollen by
tapping it or you can take that pyrex
dish and you can straight up chop the
tops off of your plant your pollen donor
plant and lay it in that pyrex dish and
the pollen will fall out as the plant
dries pollen will land into your dish
you could tap it you could tap it with a
drumstick with your fingers smack the
plant onto the dish carefully gently
don't blow the pollen everywhere it's
sensitive the wind will make you go
crazy tap it tap that plant onto the
dish the pollen will fall out
one of the most important things about
pollen is let it get dry moisture will
destroy pollen that's something we're
going to talk about a lot here
moisture destroys pollen if you have got
a desiccant pack not a boveda pack you
want the opposite boveda helps you
retain moisture we want to eliminate
moisture that thing that comes in food
like beef jerky and [ __ ] to suck out the
moisture it'll come in your vitamin
package it comes in sometimes if you buy
a new bag or something it'll come with
this little packet that is to suck out
moisture that's what we want moisture
will destroy pollen it'll make your
pollen clumpy it'll make it dark yellow
it will not be viable so let's get it
super dry
also before you store it pick out all of
those male flowers you're going to see
little male flower clusters in there get
all of those out because those
have moisture and they will harbor
moisture which will uh attribute and
contribute to moldy conditions in your
storage container so gather up that
pollen you can use the drumstick and the
pyrex dish method you can just bend that
plant over and shake it into your dish
if that's what you want to do but pollen
is going to go every direction when you
do this turn off the fans
help yourself out because that fan is
going to blow dust everywhere or if you
think that the plant has gone long
enough you can cut the tops off and put
those tops in the dish and let them dry
get it bone dry before you seal it up
then store that pollen i don't know how
long your pollen will last i've done a
few experiments i don't want to lead you
astray and say that it will last more
than six months i've had pollen for six
months i've had pollen for a year and it
worked i had pollen for two years it did
not work so i'm gonna say gather your
pollen get it super dry seal it keep it
in a cool dry dark place dry dry did i
say dry enough times get the pollen dry
all right now we've got pollen let's
talk about actually pollinating our
female plants like i said before you
could drag your uh your reversed plant
your pollen donor over to the canopy you
can give it a shake or you can let it
naturally blow across the canopy let it
pollinate that way
or you can select a couple of branches
for your female plant and pollinate just
a few branches if
you're very careful
i would have the pollen in a small
container maybe like a glass vial back
in the day we would use a black film
canister we've evolved since then but a
vial a container of some sort with
pollen in it
if you can remove the female plant that
you're going to pollinate from the room
once you've got your female pollen
receiver in a safe place get the pollen
out of your container you can use a
q-tip you can use a paintbrush i've seen
a lot of different ways to do it i've
seen people simply take a vial of pollen
and sprinkle it right over the top of
the plant like if this microphone was a
plant and this uh i'm gonna use the pen
it's the easiest thing i've got this pen
cap was a vial of pollen they just took
it and went tink tink tink tink and did
a few circles around it and then went
lower or you can just pollinate one
branch if you're super careful you can
grab a branch of the plant bend it over
this way get it right here and just go
and then you know that this branch right
here is going to make a bunch of seeds
you can make plenty of seeds from a
really small bud a really small branch a
good idea at this point maybe to mark it
if you got a bread tie a ribbon
anything you can put on this branch and
say this is where i pollinated now you
know that your seeds are going to be
there when it comes to harvest time you
could possibly harvest the rest of the
plant if you were careful it won't be
seeded and this one branch will have
seeds for your next project you can grow
your own stuff have a little bit of fun
with that so you can use a paintbrush a
q-tip you could dust it you could dip
the paint brush or q-tip into the pollen
and paint it onto the bud paint the
pistols watch the pistols is that where
we are um yeah watch the pistols
when those pistols get
you can identify that the plant has been
pollinated by the pistols or stigmas
being brown and shriveled
that part will become a seed and then it
says you can make a lot of seeds with
tiny tiny plants don't waste a lot of
time and space making seeds for your
first time we don't know if these seeds
are going to be any good so the first
time you make seeds maybe only make 20
30 maybe 50 of them to test them out see
if they're worth a [ __ ] don't seed up
your whole crop and then they got a
bunch of seeds that aren't stellar our
job as a breeder is to make seeds that
are better than both of the parents if
you didn't improve upon the cannabis
line or if you didn't reach a goal that
you were trying to reach then we didn't
do ourselves any justice we didn't do
any good for the plant we're moving
backwards so um you can make yourselves
a lot of seeds in a very small like a
closet or a micro grow space you can
make a lot of seeds i've bred seeds in
six inch net pots all you need is a big
enough plant to receive pollen and a big
enough plant to drop pollen you can make
seeds so pollinate some plants let the
pollen take
then here's a useful tip i keep saying
water deactivates pollen when you are
tossing pollen around if you don't want
all of your plants to get pollen spray
them with water before you get the
pollen out just moisten them up make it
damp in the room wet those plants get
the other plants do your pollen chucking
let the pollen take maybe rinse that
plant off after the pot just mist it
with water kill any excess pollen that
didn't get absorbed by the pistols or uh
by the female plant get the pollen off
of there then spray the other females
then put everybody back in the room
together and then you should prevent
pollen contamination on the plants you
did not want seeded
water deactivates pollen there are so
many useful tricks to use water to keep
your other plants safe so you can spray
the other females
you can spray anything you don't want to
get seeded that may help you out so
rinse them off before you put them back
in there spray the other girls you
should be safe now here's something i
want to talk about
don't harvest the seeds too early how do
we know when they're done the seeds will
probably take
about six weeks to finish i usually
harvest around day 70 sometimes 77 when
my plants are seeded what i like to do
to make sure that my seeds are ready is
i start doing what i call a squeeze test
i seed up pretty large plants so i've i
can risk a few seeds what i do uh right
where the uh the nodes are kind of
intersecting right at the bottom you can
see the bracks the uh the pistols or the
cat you can see the bracks of the calyx
all swell swelling up and there's a seed
in there just reach up and pluck a seed
out you're not gonna ruin too much you
might pull out one or two seeds pull out
a seed give it a squeeze roll it around
in your fingers knock off that hole or
the husk of the seed examine the seed
what color is it is it white is it light
green is it turning brown is it tiger
striped is it gray does it look like a
seed that you think would be viable then
here's the next test give it a squeeze
that seed should not break under the
pressure of your fingers if it cracks
it's not ready if it does not crack
you're getting very close i like to pull
the seeds when they're good and hard and
i can push them on the table and they do
not rupture under the pressure of my
finger i've got a nice i almost have an
indention and a callus on this finger
from pressing so many seeds onto this
table that's how i test them i really
pull out a few and i'll do this from
multiple locations on the plant i don't
just pick the top because that's obvious
right that's getting the most light the
most energy let's do a few spots on the
plant sometimes just like trichomes the
tops of the plant the seeds are ready
and the bottom needs to keep going
sometimes in the greenhouse in the grow
space some of the plant seeds are
already earlier than others the seeds
that come from the platinum tangie are
always done sooner than the seeds that
come from strawberry starburst i always
know that that will be a thing that
saves me
the headache of having to cut down those
two plants at the same time i know that
if i run a large crop of platinum tangy
that i can cut that down seven to ten
days earlier than anything made with the
strawberry fields i said strawberry
starburst earlier sorry i may have
transposed those but i do mix that up in
my brain a lot but i know that the
timing that i can help myself out by
staggering those because they won't be
done for a week apart so i can get the
one down dried get it chopped up into
small pieces and then move the other one
in and they can change places they can
rotate in my process in my processing so
i don't have to do it all at one time
so pull the seeds out see if they're
ripe that's what i'm getting at there um
you'll start developing the eye and the
feel to know if the seeds are ready if
you leave them too long they'll get too
hard if you take them too early they
won't be viable
find some some of your seeds are going
to be done earlier than others in one
plant find that law of averages do you
have enough that are done that it's time
to cut down the plant or do you want to
wait longer and let some get too hard
that's the timing to be done if you're
only making 30 or 40 seeds cut them down
around day 70 they should be ready now
let's talk a little bit more
specifically about the timing of using
our spray solution
i'm going to say it one more time
because i may have gone too fast in the
last episode i like to spray my pollen
donor 7 to 10 days before i initiate
flour i do not initiate flour on my
pollen donor and pollen receiver plants
at the same time that's the next thing
we're going to talk about but i start
spraying seven to ten days before i flip
my pollen donor so a week to ten days
i'll give it a good spray
then i will give that plant day one of
flower my schedule is set nine to nine
a.m or p.m depends on which room i'm in
what i'm doing 9 a.m that light comes on
about 8 45 i go grab the the pollen
donor plants and i spray them for the
first time then the light goes off at
nine o'clock this is day one of flower
so we get sprayed seven to ten days
before flower
then we get sprayed day one a flower now
here is the schedule that i follow i
spray my silver solution on
day one
day three
day six
day nine
day 12
and 21
at this point i will start making uh
game time decisions do i need to spray
again on 25 do i need to spray again on
27 and i have never sprayed after day 30
to be honest with you sometimes the
plants are stubborn uh if you've got a
stubborn plant you may need to go longer
by now we should start seeing pollen so
let's talk about that um you the male
will start making pollen around day 30
or 35
ish this is going to be plant specific
light specific phenotype specific
environment specific so i'm saying ish
um i'm gonna say day 28 to 37 ish is
when you'll get your pollen now the
females will be ready for their pollen
around day 25 to day 30. so there's a
word problem there's some algebra to be
done there let me tell you again expect
pollen between days 30 and 35
expect females to be ready around day 25
to day 30. now there's more stuff to
talk about don't bump your pollen donor
plants
when they're making pollen because that
will knock the pollen out early uh they
won't have as much they won't have as
much stuff to knock up your females also
that dust may travel to the females and
pollinate them early if they get hit too
early you won't make as many seeds as
you could have now one piece of advice
that i use to set my rhythm um i say
that the females are going to be ready
for pollen around day 25 to 30. the dude
is going to start making pollen around
to 35 the way that i set my rhythm when
i see those pollen donor plants showing
me that they are truly reversing uh this
is a kind of a fail-safe way sometimes
your silver solution isn't perfect
sometimes your spray intervals delusions
ratios timing aren't right for the
cultivar you've chosen to reverse so
what i do i wait until i see that female
plant showing me true signs of
successful reversal before i drag my
female plants into the flower room this
does a couple things
first of all it sets up the timing i
know that once i see that part start
developing i know i'm just the right
time away for that plant to give me
pollen to where the girls are going to
get timed up just right also this helps
me not put female plants into flower
when i don't have a pollen donor coming
if i failed if i didn't make my silver
solution properly if i didn't reverse at
the right time spray correctly if i'd
done [ __ ] up i've got a backup plan i
still have my females and veg i can get
that pollen donor plant and do other
tricks and methods and tactics to try to
reverse it that way i don't just have
plants in there flowering not making
seeds scrambling trying to figure [ __ ]
out because i've been there won't do it
again that sucks i'm better than that at
this point and so are you so set
yourself up for success wait until you
see that pollen donor plant showing
successful signs of reversal then drag
those female plants in there then here
comes the next part we're going to
harvest our seeds around day 70 or 75
maybe day 77
i'm going to do a full episode in the
future about harvesting seeds this will
account for feminized seeds regular
seeds autoflower seeds this is universal
however you're going to harvest seeds
this will work so uh get those female
plants get the male plants the pollen
donors about 7 to 15 days ahead expect
pollen around day 30 to 35 get the
females ready for pollen around day 25
to 30.
pollinate i don't know if you're going
to do an open pollination where you're
going to drag that pollen donor in there
and just let it skeet i don't know if
you're going to cut down the top and
walk around and beat the females with it
i don't know if you're going to gather
pollen and then get the girls going at
another time and sprinkle them i don't
know your tactic but
do some pollen chucking get in there get
that pollen going on the girls then be
patient and wait um
let's talk briefly about feeding i don't
have any notes about feeding i didn't
write that down we should talk about
that the seeded plants are going to want
more nutrients i feed my seeded plants
basically
a souped-up veg mix i feed what i'm
feeding my veg plants i do add amino
acids i had a liquid amino product from
what's that company called it'll come to
me you know who they are all right the
company my brain would not bring to my
mind is called microbe life hydroponics
they make great stuff they make an amino
product that i use i also like that
photosynthesis plus
good [ __ ] so i add aminos to my seeded
crops i also step up the calmag and a
little bit of the nitrogen i don't focus
on bud boosters
i will shift later on to the uh the
flowering feed but i don't focus on bud
boosters like we do when we're making
buds because i'm not making buds i'm
making seeds i'm focused on making uh
the building blocks for life and i do
believe that a little bit of those amino
acids a lot of nitrogen basic nutrients
will help us out with that um somebody
asked what kind of thiosol of the uh i
am using the anhydrous version the
crystalline anhydrous is what i am using
i honestly think that answers all of the
questions that i had written down in a
future episode i am again going to talk
about the harvesting of these seeds so
you've got some time to go let your
seeds grow the next time we check in
we'll talk about cutting down your
seeded cannabis plants if they're
feminized seeds regular seeds
autoflowers maybe it's just hemp we'll
teach you how to cut them down get those
seeds out of there that is a tedious
task if you're not prepared properly all
right that is all i've got for you that
is the update to the silver thio sulfate
episode thank you once again for
checking out the grow from your heart
podcast
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy if you feel like the
episode was educational informative or
entertaining
maybe you just like to throw me a couple
of bucks for putting out such quality
content all you have to do is check out
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information of course
is right there on the screen if you need
any more information check out my
website at ire iregenetics.com
my voice is starting to burn out my
jaw's getting tired that's all i've got
for you i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
big shout out to my buddy root3o5 and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug
[Music]
you