[Music]
so
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
this is episode 724
of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
harvesting our seeded ganja plants
before we get to that part of the show
let's do a few shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend all mixed up
let's send a big thank you shout out to
roll this nug and larf knight rises
let's send a thank you shout out to
brian p and mr mean green i want to send
a big fist bump and a thank you shot
it's a stone trout bum and godfather
kush let's send a thank you shout out to
noah n in growing tennessee let's send a
big thank you shout out to romy one
kenobi then let's wrap it all up with
the big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to elder's garden
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends
this is the part of the show where i do
invite you to join me for the groovy
gravy secret stash seed event in denver
colorado on march 26th that's right
saturday march 26th we are doing a seed
event featuring irie genetics top dog
oni masonic and many other great seed
breeders and vendors join us all you
have to do is follow it's groovy gravy
on instagram there's a link in their bio
all of the info you need will be right
there you can get tickets you can find
out exactly who will be there make sure
you get tickets now because it is almost
sold out check out itsgroovygravy on
instagram for access to the seed event
in denver all right no more advertising
let's get right to the point of this
podcast i've been doing a talk about uh
feminized seeds i taught you how to make
your silver thiosulfate solution uh we
talked more in depth about storing the
solution more about application i did
two full episodes on it now we should
have made some seeds by now let's talk a
little bit about harvesting seeds this
episode is going to be about harvesting
seeded cannabis plants this doesn't
really matter if the seeds are regular
seeds if they're femme seeds if they're
autoflowers if they're even hemp seeds
this will work for just about any sort
of cannabis seeds if they are ready if
they're mature if they're ripe this will
be an effective method so big up to
everybody who asked me for advice on
harvesting seeds this is how i
personally harvest my seeded cannabis
plants and i'm going for maximum seed
harvester i want as many as i can get as
many healthy seeds so this is how i do
it for commercial one thing i do is i
start checking for the ripeness of the
seed we don't want to just chop down a
plant if we don't know it's not ready
most of the time we would get a
magnifying glass and we would look at
the trichomes we can't do that here
we're not
concerned about the trichomes the
trichomes honestly do not matter at this
point all i care about is the seeds are
the seeds ready so what i do is i start
pulling seeds out of the plant usually
around day 65 or 70 the plants will be
ready so about day 60 65
i try not to get too impatient but i do
pay attention to each cultivar i will
just start pulling seeds out of the buds
i like to get the top of the plant the
middle of the plant and the bottom of
the plant
don't go for those obvious seeds that
are sticking up right at the edge of the
bud go for something kind of deeper into
the bud that's not protruding out
showing you that it's almost ready get a
seed that you actually need to
investigate something that hasn't been
getting all of the light something
that's a little deeper into the plant
something not prime not ideal that one
will be ready if you find the right seed
it's ready let's find a surprise seed
one in the middle uh one in a million
and see what that seed looks like so i
will pull the seed out of the nug i'll
just reach in there and you can you can
feel it if it's hard enough at this
point you can feel it just work its way
out of the bud pull it out get the
casing or the hole or the shell whatever
you want to call that part get that
right off of your seed
now we need to visually inspect our seed
what color is the seed is it pale if
it's still pale if it's white and pale
or grayish it is not ready yet uh
there's a there's two different kinds of
gray there's a gray where it's not ready
and a gray one it's almost too done so
if it's light colored uh still soft and
squishy obviously not done is it
starting to get some color to it is it
getting tiger striped is it getting
green is it getting brown is it getting
is it getting moldy let's pay attention
to all the things that could be
happening to the seeds we do have
potential of getting powdery mildew bud
rot all those things are still possible
when we're breeding with four seed so
let's pay attention make sure we're not
getting anything on the seeds and the
plants so let's pull the seeds out see
if they're ripe see what they're looking
like
when they start feeling hard i give them
what i call the pinch test
when they start feeling hard is when it
is time to harvest when most of the
seeds within that plant feel hard i'll
pull a few out i'll roll them on a hard
wooden table this table is fairly hard
you can hear me knock on it
that's a hard sturdy solid table a table
a countertop something that with no give
that's what i would take the seeds and
i'd spread a bunch out on the table and
press them with my pointer finger and
just roll them around crush them if they
crush they're not ready if they don't
crush they're probably ready if they
super don't crush you may have gone too
far if you let these seeds go too long
they will get too hard so i reach into
the bud pull out a few seeds ah roll
them around crush them see what they do
when they don't crush anymore when the
majority of the seeds don't crush it is
time to harvest
it will be hard
excuse me it will be hard to achieve a
point where every seed in that plant is
optimal
just like trichomes we want to go when
the majority of the plant is done so we
want as many seeds as we can get some of
the seeds will not be done some will be
over ripe but the majority will be
perfect if we take this plant down at
the right time so we find out the seeds
are hard we find out they're the right
color they got their tiger stripes
they're not crushing it is time to cut
them down i usually chop down around day
70 72
in an indoor flowering run that's if
pollen happened around the right time
i did a previous episode to tell you
about that so um chop when they're ready
that's what it says here chaplain ready
before i chop i do a heavy defoliation i
go in and i pull off as many leaves as i
can possibly remove
because this is going to help speed up
the drying process this is going to help
drastically speed up the sorting process
we don't want to sort through a bunch of
leaves we're going to turn this all into
a powdery dust eventually and get the
seeds out so um pull off all the leaves
that you can defoliate heavily before
you cut the plants down
then after they're naked i will cut them
down i've got a couple of different ways
to do this depending on space uh where i
am the environment uh sometimes if i'm
working with a bunch of plants of one
strain and all of the seeds in there are
going to be the same seeds i will lay a
tarp on the floor maybe some panda film
on the floor
one time i just used a big trash can lid
and let that catch any seeds that may
fall out then i just hang the plants
from the ceiling i use either fishing
line or one time i was in a basement i
just used a bunch of little eye hooks
and screwed them at the basement ceiling
into the rafters down there but uh
hang the plants up that's the point here
get the plants hanging so that they're
going to dry don't let them hang too
long because they will get dry and seeds
will begin to fall out
if you've got sea if you've got plants
they will fit in rubbermaid tubs i've
got these rubbermaid tubs they're
approximately i'm going to guess they're
three feet long by two feet wide by 18
inches tall they've got a lid on them i
do not put the lid on them but they do
come with the lid sometimes i'll chop
down the plant and just put the entire
plant right inside of that tub just let
it sit right in there
i'm not really concerned about drying
and curing this product this isn't going
to be weed i want seeds out of here so i
don't put it in a beautiful environment
a nice condition or anything it goes
wherever it can go sometimes it goes in
the grow room in the corner so that it
gets warm and dry i just need these
plants to dry up quickly that's all i'm
worried about so i cut them down hang
them off the seeds start popping out
then i'll drop them into that tupperware
container or that rubbermaid or sterlite
bin i've got them in there you can do it
a lot of different ways as long as
your plants are isolated if you've got
more than one strain if you've got more
than one female that has been pollinated
keep them separate so you don't cross
the seeds up and get those confused i
make very uh strong efforts to keep all
of my seeds separate because my seeds go
out for commercial use i want people to
get what they think they're getting i
want the packages to be labeled
correctly
and that takes effort from the beginning
so i've got my plants down they get into
their bins they get dry dry dry
to speed up this drying process i will
take the buds off of the sticks i put on
some gloves they're not super thick
gloves they're just thin leather gloves
sometimes i can do it bare-handed if the
buds are just moist enough just dry
enough it'll work beautifully
bare-handed but here's what we're gonna
do grab the stick and just put your hand
around that stalk and just pull and
knock the buds right off the stick into
your uh five gallon bucket your sterlite
bin your rubbermaid tote just get those
buds right off of there we don't need
that stick in there we're not gonna dry
and cure anything we're not making
smokeable flour we're after nothing but
seeds at this point
now some of you out there may want to
make concentrates or edibles or
something with the material that comes
from the seeds
i do not do that i am focused on
strictly seed production seed movement i
don't care about all the stuff that
comes out all the material the chaff is
what i think we call it the junk the
trash
that honestly goes in the compost pile
or in the bokashi bucket and it gets
reused it gets turned back into minerals
for plant growth for compost uh goes out
in the yard gets the plants outside not
the ganja plants but the
the normal yard looks real good because
of that stuff so um i honestly beat the
[ __ ] out of it it's so beat up by the
time i'm done that there's any
concentrates we've made with it come out
green and funky and gross and i don't
make edibles myself so it's not worth my
time i throw it all away so i pulled the
buds off the sticks i got a five gallon
bucket or a tote filled with just little
tiny buds and they're getting drier by
the day my reasoning is i want to get
these seeds dried i want to get them out
of these buds and i want to get them
packaged and get them out to either
testers or vendors basically as soon as
possible there's no good in them sitting
there no product does you any good
sitting in a garage sitting on a shelf
sitting in a room we got to get it
somewhere so i want to get this going as
quickly as possible so i get the sticks
out of the buds i get the buds as small
as i can get them occasionally when i
walk by i'll just put my hands in there
and just break up those buds even
smaller because smaller buds more
surface area they will dry more quickly
give them a stir
mix up that stuff get the air out of
there get the moisture out of there
speed them up get them dry dry dry
once they are completely dry this is
when the fun begins i want it dry to
where if it was weed you'd be mad that
it got that dry but said this before i'm
not worried about the weed at all i'm
only worried about the beans which are
inside of those flowers so we're gonna
get it bone dusty dry
now we've got a couple of options uh
sometimes i'll use a five gallon bucket
and i just put on gloves and it depends
on how much material there is i may just
get in there with my fingers and my
hands and just do this remove and just
rub the buds and just grind it all up
and crush it up with my hands until it's
a fine dust i'm not gonna go hard enough
to crush or break or disrupt or rupture
or destroy any of the seeds that are in
there but the herb is so dry that i can
just rub it with my hands and it'll
start crumbling up into dust you can
hear the seeds land back into the bucket
ding ding ding ding ting ting it sounds
like it's raining into the bucket if
you've done it right you get a bunch of
seeds out of there another method that
i've seen people do and somebody's gonna
say this is crazy but i learned it from
a crazy person big respect to my buddy
who showed me this uh at this store at
the hardware store they sell what is
called a paint paddle for your drill you
can get a power drill and they put a
thing on there that is meant to stir
paint it looks like a propeller for a
boat or something similar to that and
it's supposed to get down into the
bottom of a bucket of paint and stir it
and then you move it up and down and
stir your paint i've seen somebody put
that on a drill and stick it in the five
gallon bucket of buds with seeds in it
excuse me for the throat clearing you
guys i took a couple of monster dabs and
it's got my throat choked up but uh we
take the uh the paint stirrer put it on
a medium-low setting you don't want to
get in there and full-on like destroy
the seeds but like a medium-low setting
to where it's spinning and let it hit
the buds and if the buds are dry enough
they basically just crumble under that
drill under that flower bit under the
stirrer bit it just crushes them not bad
enough to destroy the seeds that's
something we need to focus on if you're
going to put a drill bit in there if
you're going to use something mechanical
do not crush the seeds be gentle be
pay attention is the word i'm trying to
say so the main objective is to get it
super dry and then crumble it up into a
dry
dusty mess you've got a bunch of weed
with a bunch of seeds in it now we've
got a container with weed and seeds now
we've got to separate that here is the
funnest part of the game in my opinion
this is almost the same as trimming i
don't have to trim because i just turned
all my weed into seeds and dust this is
my version of trimming and then
packaging seeds is also my version of
trimming can't complain about that but
this is the next step we've got to
remove all the beans from all of that
weed luckily gravity will work for us
for a lot of this if you've got a the
right kind of container you can tip it
to one side and most of your seeds will
roll to the corner that you've tipped it
to if you've done it right if you've
used a container that is tall enough
wide enough deep enough and not if it's
the right shape you may be able to reach
in with your hand and pull out most of
the material and leave all of the seeds
at the bottom help yourself out and just
start scooping it out the best you can
then we've got a couple of options
the most affordable and effective way of
course is that old school way just get
an album cover or something a lot of
people have no idea what i'm even
talking about get a magazine something
flat and just tip it up on one edge and
let the seeds run out and let that
heavier material stay if you tip
something up and if you put the seeds on
a tray or a magazine or something and
you tip it the seeds will roll down and
the weed will stay there you can do that
a couple of times and clean it up that's
the old school way if you've made a lot
of seeds that will drive you crazy i
possibly could never do that i would
never ever finish sorting seeds um
there's another way to do it you can get
a flower sifter from your local grocery
store or the mart down the street
it's a sifter it looks like a net with a
plastic ring around it and a handle but
it's a mash net a metal net you throw
the material and the seeds in there and
gently rub it around over another bowl
the material will fall out of the bottom
the seeds will remain in the top you've
got your seeds that way wear some rubber
gloves because your fingers are going to
get all chafed and all funky from that
it's going to take a while that's a
frustrating process if you don't have a
lot of seeds that will get her done
if you have a lot of seeds this is when
the job does get harder i've seen uh
shout out to masonic smoker i haven't
seen this method in a long time it
wasn't the first one that i saw do it
but i forgot all about it
mace took a container that had herb and
seeds in it and he just gingerly turned
on the shopvac and just kind of
feathered the top of the the weed and
the material and pulled out the weed and
just kind of gingerly tipped it around
and moved it to where none of the seeds
were getting sucked up but the weed was
getting removed from the container he
got most of it out that way then went
back just kind of hand clean it that's a
super easy way to do it the other way to
do it is a seed sorting machine there
are numerous seed sorting machines
available on the internet my favorite is
the small device it looks like a white
shoe box it's got two drawers on the
front of it it's got a spot you pour in
the material but the [ __ ] seeds come
out on one side the material comes out
on the other it's [ __ ] magic inside
there i love that machine it's great
there is another one that is much larger
it hooks up to a shop vac it's a little
bit cumbersome if you're making a bunch
of seeds that one is effective for you
that's overkill for me and i make a lot
of seeds it just takes up a lot of space
and you need the shopvac also
the little white square piece it's a
standalone unit it's got a computer fan
in there it works beautifully the best
part about both of those seed separating
devices is there are very simple
blueprints and plans all over the
internet so if you need a seed sorting
machine there are blueprints plans
guides all over the internet i think my
friend cascadian groan for a while was
making seed sorting machines i do
approve of those those are quality
devices check out cascadian grown on the
social media uh if you're in the weed
scene the cannabis crew you know how to
find them if you're new uh follow my
social media let me know you need to
find cascadia and we'll get you in touch
honestly don't know if he's still making
him but he's a good dude and i want to
give him a plug if i've got an
opportunity because he would give me a
plug if he had the opportunity because
that's what family does all right where
the hell are we i got rambly
you can definitely make your own seed
sorting machine uh sorting seeds um
counting seeds sorting seeds that's
another thing that i would recommend is
buy yourself a seed counter i think
they're about 350 to 450 bucks depending
on the quality
that you get and of course how quickly
you get it shipped uh find one that'll
ship it to you for free if you're
spending that much money um but a seed
counter is ideal i love just putting the
seeds in the seed counter and watching
it turn it doesn't spin it looks like it
spins its vibration i love watching the
seeds spin up the little thing and into
the shoot and show me how many seeds
i've got so much better than guessing uh
once you've done it a lot of times
you'll get a good guess but it's so much
better then i can do inventory like this
beep and they go
and then it tells me how many seeds are
there so awesome uh so get yourself a
seed sorting machine or get yourself a
um a sifter or an album cover or some
way to get the seeds out have a strategy
there
maybe if you don't destroy that weed so
badly by using the sorting machine and
all the [ __ ] that i do to it you may be
able to make something out of that
leftover weed i never intend to i never
plan to
i just straight up pollinate everything
destroy the whole plant get all the
seeds out then uh since i have a seed
company i guess i just use the funding
from the seed company to buy the
concentrates and the edibles which i
would enjoy that's my strategy there
um so let it get real dry crumble it up
uh once it's crumbled up that's when
you've got some decisions to make are
you going to use the sifter or how are
you going to crumple it you're going to
use a drill you're going to use your
gloves i've seen people put it in a
baggie and just stomp on the baggie a
lot or mash the bag you with their hands
as long as you get that weed real dry it
will work then
figure out how you're going to get the
seeds out you're going to use the sifter
the machine you're going to use gravity
you're going to use a vacuum get those
seeds out
wear gloves i recommend gloves also if
you're going to use the seed sorting
machines maybe a mask because it blows a
lot of dust around you do get the green
boogers from that which are never
pleasant
then very important once the seeds are
out of the material label them whatever
baggy jar whatever it goes into make
sure that gets labeled properly i like
to label it what the male plant was the
female plant was what the cross is
called and the date of the harvest that
way i kind of have an idea how old those
seeds are when they came out of the
plants lets me know what's going on now
if there's a problem i know that it came
from this batch uh just helps me out
with a little bit of uh just helps me
out that's all um then the best part
grow the seeds grow these seeds you've
made some cool seeds you've got them out
of your buds now you've got to grow them
before you sell them share them pass
them along grow them make sure you
didn't just make total garbage don't ask
for money for seeds that you haven't
tested because who knows what you've got
uh could be all boys it could be all
intersex it could be mutants or
or maybe you just made the new hottest
fire on the market store your seeds in a
cool dry dark place by now they should
be super dry
if you followed my method the seeds are
dry they're ready to be stored but make
sure they're nice and dry before you do
seal them up if not you do risk the
opportunity for mold and pathogens in
your seeds so let them go let them get
nice and dry then label them correctly
and store them in a cool dry
dark
place i think that does wrap up my seed
harvest episode um if you have any more
questions about harvesting seeds maybe
we should talk a little bit about seed
storage let's write that down storage
may be an upcoming episode because that
seems like the next logical step all
right ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters pollen chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts every
member of the ire army i want to thank
each and every one of you for listening
to the show and of course for supporting
the show if you feel like this episode
was educational informative entertaining
maybe you just want to support the show
because you learned something maybe i
rescued your garden maybe i made you
giggle all you have to do is check out
www.patreon.com forward slash girl from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
of course that link is in the show notes
and the video description to make a nice
and easy for all of my friends if you
have any questions corrections comments
or concerns i would love to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy let me
know what you think of the show let me
know if i made any mistakes or send your
constructive criticism and i will take
it kindly i think that's all i've got oh
yeah check out the website the website
is
iriegenetics.com everything else you
could possibly need will be on the
website that's all i've got for you for
this episode i'll be back in a couple of
days with
for fresh new content i'm going to give
a big shout out to my buddy billy podunk
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you