[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff this is
episode 720
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to jimmy limmer i want to send
a big thank you shout out to stoner dave
and sam heads let's send a fist bump and
a thank you shout out to james brown and
new old guy let's send a thank you shout
out to g7 and green country grower let's
send a thank you shout out to magic mike
and quasi let's send a fist bump to
spherical glass works and uncle adam the
uber driver then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to kes burton big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show of course
this is the part of the podcast where i
invite you to join me for the groovy
gravy secret stash seed event in denver
colorado on march 26th that's right in
denver colorado on march 26th at an
undisclosed location we are doing a seed
event it will feature food trucks glass
blowing and seed vendors and seed
breeders i do invite you to join the
party check out itsgroovygravy on
instagram for all of the info there is a
link in their bio once again check out
itsgroovygravy on instagram and use
coupon code rasta jeff when you get your
tickets all right where do we go from
there let's talk about this voice
it sounds like i've got a head cold or
something but i do not i was doing some
work and i got a bunch of just a bunch
of junk in my nose a bunch of dust a
bunch of dirt been cleaning up some
stuff and it made me sound like total
[ __ ] if that's coming through on the
microphone and your headphones and your
equipment i do apologize it won't sound
like this in the next episode i've been
trying to blow this junk out of my nose
out of my head i'm just gonna sound like
[ __ ] for a few minutes that's how life
is gonna be we'll accept it we'll have a
great podcast together uh you may not
even notice it as much as i do i didn't
notice until i put on these headphones
how strong it was but i do notice
there's some crap in the nose from all
the dirty work i was doing today nobody
cares about that what else did i do
today i went to the weed doctor that's
right i live here in southern colorado
uh in colorado we do have the uh what is
it the right the privilege of medical
cannabis we are offered medical
marijuana here we do have recreational
cannabis here so many people may say why
do you have your medical marijuana
recommendation your medical marijuana
card from a doctor that's a really good
question there are a couple of reasons
for that first off is it's another layer
of safety it's just uh i do grow we can
grow legally here but
also having that medical card gives you
another layer of protection for growing
also it increases your purchasing power
at dispensaries you're limited uh
certain amounts of milligrams at
recreational dispensaries at a um a
medical cannabis dispensary the edible
dosage is much higher that is available
so you can get different products in
different places you can buy more i can
buy more at a medical shop than i can at
a wreck shop there are a few advantages
of it advantages to it mostly i do it to
keep my garden safe it does allow me so
one of the things i was going to talk
about we are allowed recreational and
medical cannabis we can have six plants
here recreationally you're allowed to
grow six cannabis plants in your
residence if you're an adult and you've
uh if you want to grow that's well
you're illegal right here you can have
six plants
plus if you have your medical marijuana
recommendation you are allowed six more
so i do have the medical marijuana card
for these six extra plants that does
help me out gives me a total of 12.
not a lot of plants to play with but
twice as many as six i'm grateful for
that it helps me out lets me do what i
need to do
supply my medicine my product that i do
need so
i did go to the weed doctor today
because every year we do have to renew
our medical marijuana cards here in
colorado we do have the recreational
cannabis anybody 21 and up is allowed to
have cannabis they can shop in the store
uh if you've got a medical cannabis card
you can be 18. most of the patients are
21 and up it does require special
paperwork more doctor visits extra steps
if you're uh 18 but if you're 21 then
you can get that medical cannabis card
then you can go to the medical
dispensaries and you can have the extra
plants uh i go get the medical marijuana
card once every year you have to have a
qualifying condition uh mine is that i
was in a car wreck in 2003 my knees hit
the dash they make a lot of terrible
noises uh my shoulder came out of the
socket from the seat belt you guys don't
care about medical stuff but that is how
that's my they call it your claim to
fame for your medical marijuana
recommendation so today i had to go to
the weed doctors what i'm getting at and
when i used to go to the weed doctor you
would schedule an appointment and if
you're not watching the video i did air
quotes on the word appointment because
uh back in the day when you would make
an appointment to the weed doctor you'd
schedule for it seemed like everybody's
scheduled for 10 or 11 am
sometimes you wouldn't get to see that
weed doctor until five six maybe seven
pm and you'd have to just hang out all
day wait your turn wait for your name to
be called people would sneak off and go
smoke bulls in the car or sometimes just
wherever we could find a spot to go
smoke
but the weed doctors were rare and they
would just see a lot of patients in one
day they'd show up so this is totally
illegal now and you'll understand why
once i talk about it the weed doctor
used to come to the dispensary and set
up shop in the dispensary so we just
have the weed doctor all day sign in
weed cards he would charge you so much
the dispensary would make a cut off of
every card that he sold so if he sold
250 weed cards today at a hundred
dollars each is what i think they used
to be we would make 10 bucks so we just
make 10 10 of his whole day right there
just for letting him be at our
dispensary then as soon as he signs that
paperwork and gives you the stamp from
the uh what's it called a notary now
you're allowed to shop at the dispenser
you're already there why not let's spend
some more money at the dispensaries so
uh they quickly once they made some
rules they quickly banned doctors being
on-site being present at the actual
dispensary they had to do it at an
off-site location they couldn't be
attached to the store it was making a
little bit too easy um
but you have to go sit there all day and
then you'd have to bring a file of
paperwork with you and explain what was
wrong and why you thought cannabis would
help you out and back in the day the
list of qualifying conditions was a
little bit vague it is still a little
bit vague i think we kind of they kind
of did that on purpose
i like the fact that chronic pain is on
there how can you prove that i don't
hurt if i say this hurts can you look at
my hand right now and tell me if it does
or does not hurt look i'll pull it up to
the camera right there that hurts am i
full of [ __ ] or not as a doctor you've
got to take my word for it that it hurts
so now you're going to give me my
medical cannabis card right i'm gonna
say this hurts all the time i don't know
why it just does and you're gonna say
did you do anything about it no i smoke
weed and it feels better and you go oh
and the doctor just writes your card uh
so that's pretty much how easy it was
today i went in there i had an
appointment an actual appointment for 11
o'clock i'm that guy i showed up 10
minutes early i was like hey i'm here
for my appointment they said oh great
we've got your paperwork ready to go
sign a few things scribble your name
date some [ __ ] you know the doctor goes
when you check in
it took me
uh maybe five minutes to fill out some
paperwork just because i know all the
info i don't have to go digging through
[ __ ] i know my info my social security
number how old i am i know all that [ __ ]
you gotta write that down uh i turned in
the paper they said the doctor will be
right with you the doctor came out with
the previous patient and said have a
great day it was great helping you out
and then she called me back and she said
you look familiar it seems like i've
seen you before and i said i've been
getting my medical cannabis card from
this office since 2008. and she
basically said okay here you go and just
started writing she asked me of course
uh what hurts how do you use it and i
said oh my knees hurt and my shoulder
hurts and i take a lot of dabs and she
said
the state wants me to type in how much
you dab and how you use your product and
i said i'd probably dab somewhere
between depending on the day somewhere
between one and two grams of
concentrates per day and she said that's
an acceptable answer i look forward to
seeing you next year my whole
appointment probably took me maybe 20
maybe 30 minutes total with like
checking out and paying there is a
process where uh once you've seen the
doctor you do have to go on to the
colorado medical marijuana there's a
bunch of [ __ ] letters it's the
department of public health and
environment some random [ __ ] website
where you have to go there and fill out
your recommendation from the doctor and
put in some info after the doctor does
their part and once you do that you're
good to go the whole thing uh from
parking to back in the car uh the entire
appointment was maybe a 30 minute
process today and it cost me 80 bucks to
the doctor and 30 dollars to the state
of colorado somewhere around that is 80
bucks 85 maybe to the doctor and i think
it was 30 or 32 to the state of colorado
so we've come a long way uh to register
with the state used to be a lot more to
see the doctor used to be
depending on where you win it could be a
lot a lot more and now it's really it
was quicker
my stuff was ready within an hour once i
filed that paper with the state of
colorado i pushed the go button i got an
email an hour later saying you're
approved here's your new [ __ ] so you
used to have to wait in the mail
that was the hardest part for a while
there they quit allowing us to have
temporary cards so when the doctor would
sign your [ __ ] that used to mean you're
good to go then you have to mail it to
the state and wait for your card to come
back at one point they said the
paperwork the tent paperwork is no good
you have to have the actual card so
people would see the weed doctor and you
have to mail your [ __ ] to the state and
everybody got a weed cart at the same
time
so nobody was getting their uh their
actual card returned to them for like
six or eight weeks it was supposed to
take three weeks like it'll be 21 days
but everybody sent in their weed card it
felt like everybody saw the weed doctor
at one day they all sent in their paper
it took so long for people to get their
cards so everyone's like i did it i paid
the money i sent my [ __ ] to the state i
want my weed card it just took them so
long to get their [ __ ] back that was
frustrating for a little while there i
was amongst that group at one point i
was like my card should show up any day
now i'd love to go buy some weed
luckily
luckily dude i got the hookups anyway
i'm rambling the weed the weed card went
super well super easy today the doctor
was really cool um this was
every time i feel like the doctors are
evolving and it's been two or three
three or four different doctors for most
of my medical cannabis run there was a
guy an old guy an older doctor dr
reimers he had a couple of dogs who was
super cool we developed a great
relationship i saw him probably 10 or 12
years in a row he passed me off to
another doctor who has now passed me off
to this other doctor who i believe i've
seen two or three times the doctors are
getting
more savvy more educated more hip to um
cannabis to cannabis usage to cannabis
verbiage terminology dosage the doctor i
saw today actually knew what she was
talking about she hinted and implied
that she smokes medical cannabis as well
um so it's kind of nice to see the
doctor actually knowing what they're
talking about now before i would go and
i would actually end up educating the
doctor and the people in the room and
this time she was on our level so that
was kind of cool uh the process was much
easier as the big note that i've got
written down they do not pay me to say
this you guys they did not give me they
don't even know i've got a show they
probably don't even they have no idea
who i am but i'm going to give medical
alternatives a shout out they're the
medical cannabis doctor that i saw in
colorado springs today
the process was painless and streamlined
the visit was great the doctor was great
the parking was easy the location was
cool to get to so if you've got the
opportunity or the need i would
recommend medical alternatives in
colorado springs just google them it
will pop up um it does cost a few bucks
uh if you are a new patient you may need
some medical records you may need to
bring some uh some proof that you are uh
sick or injured and or have a qualifying
condition that will qualify you for
medical cannabis keep in mind
those rules are quite flexible
some paperwork will help you out though
something else i want to talk about
they do offer what is called an extended
plant count um
in many counties in colorado you are not
allowed to even honor the extended plant
count if you pay for that what's an
extended plan account let me talk about
that extended plant count it sounds just
like what what what it is uh earlier i
said i'm allowed to grow six plants for
my recreational rights i can just grow
six just because we're in colorado i
also said i can grow six more because of
my medical rights that gives me six more
my doctor could if i of course pay them
more money that's the whole thing here
if i give the doctor more money and it's
tiered uh if i want to grow um i'm given
six if i want to go like and i'm just
hypothetical with the numbers because i
don't remember if i want to add another
10 to 12 plants it's like another 100
bucks if i want to add 20 to 30 more
plants it's like 250 more bucks if i
want to go up more and more plants it
just tears it's like 350 500 1000 bucks
depending on how many more plants you
want to grow
which back in the day that was awesome i
used to i used to rock the [ __ ] out of
those extended plant counts those used
to be my best friends we built
dispensaries and businesses off of
extended plant counts i basically say uh
we'll give you a fat discount at our
dispensary if you let us have your plant
count because you could assign your
plants to our dispensary it was a big it
was just paperwork that we used to jump
around through and play with back in the
day so the extended plant counts used to
be awesome in my opinion now
unfortunately um in pueblo county where
i do live they don't care about an
extended plant count counties have been
allowed to make their own caps on plant
limits they can cap plant counts they
can cap grow size they can make the
county can decide they can override they
can supersede any rules that your state
has made
regarding your cannabis so pueblo here
we're allowed to have 12 plants most of
the counties in pueblo are limited to 12
total so if you're paying for that
extended plant count and you're growing
that extended plant count i would do a
lot of research on your location and see
if your location does honor or if it
bars that extended plant count some
places are limited to six some are
limited to 12 some give you 24 if you're
in one of those properly zoned areas
they don't give a [ __ ] how many plants
you grow as long as you're following uh
your card limit which could be up to 99
in some cases um once you cross that
hundred plant threshold uh then you're
in that federal zone and once you have
so many plants i'm sure of it because
you have to send in special paperwork
and [ __ ] you're in a computer system
that says [ __ ] roster jeff has 12
plants grover down the street he's got
99. who do you think they're going to
come looking for when some [ __ ] goes
wrong who's on the radar first
that's just my opinion i'm going to grow
12 mind my own [ __ ] business just fly
by the the what's it called fly under
the radar that's what i'm trying to say
all right i'm high and rambly i feel
like the [ __ ] out of my nose is starting
to work itself out now that i've been
talking a little bit mike sounds better
in my head
um so the weed card went super smooth
today basically um what hurts and i said
my wallet and she said yep it's gonna
hurt more give me some money and i said
here you go so let's move forward i did
get a reply from a previous episode i
did an episode talking about growing
seeds and i said that if you leave the
seeds in the plants too long they can
get too hard and they will not germinate
properly i do have a screenshot of my
phone the battery is almost dead so
let's see if we can pull this up super
quickly here it does say
seeds don't over ripe it's not a fruit
it's a seed i've never heard of them
getting too hard can you explain that
yet really quickly nice and easily uh
they get too hard if you leave them in
the plant for too long and you let them
grow for too long
that shell that outer husk the whole the
the [ __ ] shell dude the seed the bean
becomes too hard and they simply have a
hard time germinating you can soak them
in water you can uh scarify them you can
rub them on a matchbox you can do all
kinds of [ __ ] to them and they don't
germinate very easily sometimes you got
to put them in a seed cracker which i
really don't like to do but if you let
the seeds go for too long they do have
the opportunity just simply to get too
hard that's there's not a lot of
explaining to do they get so hard they
don't germinate and it's from letting
them grow for too long this is most
commonly done with outdoor seeds because
i'm learning to grow outdoors now and
the outdoor seeds excuse me for the burp
i'm going to talk right over that excuse
me the outdoor seeds seem to go from
like that's almost ready almost ready
almost ready to [ __ ] i should have cut
that that down yesterday like that's how
i feel like the outdoor seeds went so uh
some of them did get really hard really
big really fat some of them did not
germinate on a couple of the plants
those never went anywhere i tested those
i'm not happy with that so those seeds
will just end up on the back burner uh
you never know what those will end up
doing but um yeah some of the seeds
simply got too hard that's the best uh
best description i can give you bro they
got too hard they won't germinate and uh
those are the seeds that you gotta soak
in water overnight or you gotta put them
in a matchbox and shake them up to where
they get the the shell gets a little
scratched a little scarified on the
outside or i've seen people put them in
a seed cracker so that's what i mean by
the seeds getting too hard another thing
that can happen that we've seen happen
in outdoor grows if you leave the seeds
in those plants too long or leave the
plants out there growing too long the
humidity and the moisture from the
outside environment or just that
moisture inside the buds can trigger
those seeds to germinate inside of the
plants it's really an interesting site
to see it's also terrible because i know
how many seeds are being wasted
but they're just sprouting right there
inside the buds you got a bud that looks
like this microphone right and just
little germination tails coming out of
it it looks like worms climate little
caterpillars or worms climbing out of
your plant so um that is what happens if
you leave them in there too long that is
also a sign we're going to keep rambling
here because we're on a thought process
here that is also a sign to me that the
seeds do not need to be wintered a lot
of people talk about when the seeds come
out of plants they need to be cold or
they need to be preserved for a period
of time before they can grow nah bro
they're ready right now they're ready
they would just normally fall into a
cold environment with some snow or
non-ideal conditions they'd need to wait
a little while to get proper environment
then they'd sprout up but no they're
ready to go when they're in that plant
we've seen them sprout inside the buds
and ruin the entire [ __ ] project so
um yeah the seeds can go too long
they'll get too hard and if you leave
them in there way too long they will
germinate all right let's keep this
school bus moving the next thing i want
to talk about is flowering time i do
want to send a big shout out to my
friend who reminded me to talk about
this on the show i was talking with the
bro today and he's like you know what
this and i was like i should say that on
the show so big shout out to my friend
for reminding me to say this on the show
you know who you are i wouldn't be where
i am without you bro so
something i should talk about i am a
seed breeder i do make seeds on the back
of my seed packaging i do list a
recommended flowering time a lot of
those times are generally nine to ten
weeks what i breed generally takes 9 to
10 weeks i know that's a general time
frame but most of my plans will be done
within that time frame
when i say 9 to 10 weeks i don't mean
cut it down at the beginning of week 9.
when i say nine weeks i recommend you
finish that ninth week don't shortchange
yourself by cutting down your plants way
too early i am recommending nine to ten
weeks and i see people cutting their
plants down at the beginning of week
nine you're ripping yourself off by
potentially 14 maybe 21 days of
potential growth and improvement you
could have gotten from that crop
imagine how much more weight you could
have gotten from 20 14 to 21 more days
of growth out of that plant
imagine how much potency imagine how
much flavor if that plant had that much
more time to go so hypothetically if
you're cutting it down at the start of
week nine what is that that's uh 50 59
days right 56 57 days
you should be cutting down at least day
63 is the end of week nine right that's
the end of yeah 56 is eight weeks 63 is
nine weeks let it go so technically
you've only gone eight weeks on day one
of week nine you've gotta finish that
week what i'm trying to say what i'm
trying to get into your head is when i
say nine weeks
finish the ninth week if i say you've
got to go to this class four nine weeks
you don't go to the class for eight
weeks and don't go to the ninth week
then you don't graduate you fail that is
the same way with growing ganja you've
got to finish the ninth week sometimes
you've got to finish the tenth week
sometimes even though i wrote nine to
ten weeks on your package sometimes you
may need to let that bad dog go 11 weeks
there are anomalies there are outliers
uh sometimes those longer flowering
plants are the most potent the most uh
heavy hitting the most delicious the
most impressive plants in the grow so
when i'm saying 9 to 10 weeks i
definitely mean 63 days or more
and if you're running the first run with
that plant definitely go 70 days i
always recommend going longer on your
first run it's the inaugural run we want
to see the potential of that plant how
do you know that and a lot of times
plants will do special [ __ ] on the last
10 to 14 days of their flowering cycle
they'll change colors they'll change
terpenes they'll change everything it'll
just go totally different right at the
end there that's how you know it's done
it goes into senescence and it expresses
the end of the plant sometimes we never
see that how do you know that maybe at
the end it just doubles in size maybe at
the end it doubles in potency maybe at
the end it puts off this crazy gassy
terp you never noticed so again i highly
recommend that you let the plants finish
when i say 9 weeks that means 63 days
often when i say 9 weeks that means 70
days in breeder talk i do talk in ranges
and in terms keep in mind there are
anomalies in these plants i said it a
moment ago you're going to get outliers
there will be phenotypical differences
your grow room is different your lights
your environment your feed your
temperature your humidity your vpd your
co2 all your abuse your love your care
that you cuss the plants out did you
give them hugs all of that stuff is
gonna make a difference in the flowering
time of these plants so i highly
recommend once again that you let them
finish when i say nine weeks again that
is finish week nine when i say ten weeks
finish week ten don't get too excited
don't get overzealous don't get eager
and ruin everything you've edged for how
many days probably 30 45 days something
like that then you flower for seven
weeks when you should have gone for nine
don't sell yourself short don't cut
yourself off short don't rip yourself
off set yourself up for success and
reach your potential by letting these
plants finish let them finish
everybody's happier when you let them
finish all right where do we go from
there i've got one more question we're
going to cover on this episode somebody
asked me if it would be possible to
reverse one branch of a plant and
pollinate another branch of the same
plant and i said yes that would
absolutely be
possible you can do that um another
thing i should mention is do not smoke
reversed plants i don't know if that
needs to be said i'm not sure if that is
something that needed to be pointed out
or talked about but do not smoke the
plants that have been treated with
silver let's not do that it's now it is
technically a pollen donor plant there
are not buds on there that's not
smokeable bud you want to smoke female
buds anyway but many people have said uh
that that is a problem it's dangerous to
smoke weed that has been sprayed with
silver bro it's you're not don't smoke
that if you're thinking about it
correctly you're not gonna smoke that
don't do that that's my disclaimer never
smoke weed that has been sprayed with
silver what's the next thing oh is it
possible to reverse that one branch yes
if you've got one plant you can grow it
and create two tops on it or two
branches however you want to do it you
can isolate one branch and treat that
one branch with a silver solution at the
proper timing dilution uh schedule all
the right [ __ ] treat that one branch it
will make pollen you can let that pollen
fly wherever you want it's likely going
to go in the whole room but you can't
hit specific branches if you try hard
enough and you can pollinate the
opposite branch on that plant i've done
one plant where i topped it low let it
grow two big tall tops i reversed one
side i kept the other side pure female
and i just let those two dance around
together and it made femme seeds out of
one plant that is definitely possible
you can do that have done it do that
make some seeds have some fun all right
i think that is all the time i've got
for this episode there's some editing to
be done here i got to do some processing
to make this voice sound magical ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers comb heads and
dread heads i want to thank each and
every one of you for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast i had a good time
recording the show it felt good getting
on the microphone and just talking for a
few minutes if you feel like this
episode was educational informative or
entertaining maybe you just like to
throw me a few bucks for taking some
time out of my day to make a show for
you all you have to do is visit www
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need is right
there on the screen of course there is a
link in the show notes and in the video
description if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
anything else check out the website
there are links to seed breeders there
or seed vendors there there are links to
the discord server there's a link to
patreon there to make it easy everything
you need is on my website
iriegenetics.com
all right i think that's all i've got
for you i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content let's give a big
shout out to my buddy route305 and until
next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you