[Music]
so
what
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me ross to
jeff this is episode 726
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
storing our seeds before i get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend brohan78 let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to my
buddy lefty i want to send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy thecanocrat
let's send a thank you shout out to turt
burglar and blackhawks fan let's send a
thank you shout out to levity loveday
and choke norris let's send a big thank
you shout out to pac northwest dan and
gramps memel i want to send a big thank
you shout out to single t and curbside
gardens then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend samurai
garden big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you want to
learn how to do so all you have to do is
visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends all right let's jump right into
this episode i want to talk about
storing our seeds in a few previous
episodes i've taught you how to make
silver thiosulfate solution i taught you
when to pollinate how to pollinate how
to pollinate uh how to apply the pollen
how to store the pollen we've gotten all
the way up to making seeds we have
harvested seeds now let's talk about
what do we do with those seeds the first
answer is going to be grow them as a
seed breeder my favorite thing to do
with new seeds is to grow them as a seed
breeder who made new seeds and sent them
out to my friends i want you to grow
them the worst thing for a seed breeder
to see is seeds in a box in a vault in a
drawer not getting grown not getting any
attention we want those in the dirt on
the websites on the packages it says
that it may be illegal to germinate them
in your area it may be a souvenir but
deep down inside we really wish that you
would grow the [ __ ] out of those and
send us a bunch of pictures that's what
we want so
after you've made seeds the next thing
to do is to grow them of course
sometimes you can't do that i make more
seeds than i could possibly grow in my
lifetime i've got an army of testers a
gang of friends out there just growing
seeds for me so the most uh the best
thing to do is to grow them i understand
you can't grow all them you've got to
store some of them let's talk about
storing our seeds let's back up to the
point of uh just before getting the
seeds into packages we'll talk a little
bit about harvesting them before we can
even think about uh
storing these seeds in any way they need
to be completely dry i've said the words
dry so the dry dry dry i've said those
words so many times while talking about
storing pollen while talking about
harvesting while talking about storing
seeds dryness is very important when it
comes to storage we don't want our weeds
super dry we don't want our buds dry
that's why we do a slow drying cure but
for seeds for pollen we need that stuff
super dry moisture is your worst
nightmare for seeds and pollen so keep
that in mind throughout this entire
process that moisture is your worst
nightmare also seeds don't like drastic
temperature changes we will talk about
that more but let's talk about getting
the seeds from the buds just in case you
missed the harvest episode let's get the
seeds from the buds we want the buds
super dry
a lot of people have this idea that
seeds need to be wintered or frozen or
cold over a season or something like
that that is not accurate i talked about
in a previous episode that i've seen
seeds germinate inside the plant which
tells me they don't need any time to
wait once they're ready once they're
ripe they are viable they're powerful
seeds they're potent they're vigorous
they're ready to go so moisture can
cause that to happen inside of the wet
buds
if we were to store wet seeds or wet
buds or wet pollen into a container and
seal it up and just ignore it it will
definitely create a moldy environment
which will ruin your product so let's
get this product super dry i like to get
the seeds dry i like to get the product
to bone dry before i start packaging it
up in any way it sits out wide open
until i'm confident in the dryness i'm
going to say dry a lot i'm also going to
talk about
desiccant packages i'm looking at some
on my table i've got a little bag of
them over there do not confuse the
desiccant packs with a boveda pack we're
trying to suck out moisture the boveda
pack the other humidipacks those add
moisture we don't want to do that we
want to remove it all we don't want to
regulate it we want to eliminate it so
don't get confused on the packets get
the appropriate packet
desiccant pack dryness pack that's what
we're looking for
not a moisture packet once again so get
the bud super dry the way i like to do
it i've talked about this before i get
my plants my buds are completely dry and
i'll put them in a bin uh maybe a five
gallon bucket maybe a stir light bin
i'll put on gloves i'll crumble it up
maybe i'll use another method i've
talked about this get it dry remove the
seeds from that material we want it
super dry this is where we're going to
start talking about storing the seeds
they are super dry put them in a
container
if i've got a lot of seeds i will use a
small mason jar if i've got just a
number of seeds that i know won't last
very long i put them in a 3x3 uh jewelry
baggie it's just a baggie i get them
online they come from hobby lobby or
amazon a 3x3 square bag if you buy seeds
for me in the
regular packages that's what i'm talking
about one of those baggies
so depending on how many i have i either
use a glass jar maybe i'll use a smaller
glass vial or often times that three by
three baggie so get the seeds dry then
put them in the container which you wish
to store them in
eventually they need to go into
something that is light proof i just
said i put them in those baggies they
also go into another container for
storage which is dark so your container
uh you may want to choose something that
is opaque or what's the word that is
dark that will uh keep the light out you
want something colored or tinted or
eventually it should go into that we
want to store our seeds
in a package that we can make try to
make airtight and keep the light out
then we want to put that in somewhere
that is cool dry and dark we don't want
to get uh temperature swings we don't
want to get light on these plants we
don't want extreme heat we don't want
extreme cold so put your seeds in a
container whether a jar a baggie a vial
then a huge piece of advice label them
very
excessively clearly i put the cross so
let's say that i'm going to package up
some arise f1 seeds i would label it the
top would say arise f1 then it would say
golden goat to daybreaker then it would
have the date that those seeds were
packaged up so today is march something
fifth uh we would put march 17th on that
package so that it would say a rise f1
so i know which filial generation i
remember what the cross is there just
for a backup plan in case i don't
remember what a rise was or if i was
high when i wrote something down i have
another backup plan then i've got a date
so when i know when those seeds were
kind of harvested when i put them in
that baggie is a good enough time frame
for me it lets me know which batch they
were from that way if you guys have a
problem if i discover a problem i know
that this jar this bag of seeds is where
the problem lies we can crack that open
germ a bunch of those and see what
happens in there so clearly excessively
label your seeds
i like to put like i said the name of
the cross
the cross the date sometimes i know how
many seeds are in there sometimes i'll
do that if it's got some special notes
on it maybe i'll write that on the
packaging so label them
put them in a jar put them in a bag put
a desiccant pack in there something that
will suck up the moisture i'm gonna keep
saying dry you want the seeds dry
moisture is a nightmare for a seed
moisture will ruin the seed moisture
will make the seed grow and until you're
ready don't get it wet so
put it in a jar put it in a bag with
your desiccant pack now let's keep the
temperatures consistent cool is better
frozen is not ideal hot is not good at
all i like to store my seeds in a cool
dry dark environment i don't want the
seeds really cold i don't want them
really hot basically if i am comfortable
those seeds are probably comfortable as
well maybe a little bit colder than room
temperature maybe low 70s high 60s would
be good for storing your seeds some
people like to keep them in the
refrigerator let's talk about that for a
little bit cool is good but i don't like
to freeze them the refrigerator would be
cool uh put them in your jar or a baggie
then i put mine inside of a grateful
dead lunchbox i know that sounds [ __ ]
cliche the white hippie with dreadlocks
keeps his magic beans in a grateful dead
lunch box in the refrigerator yes it's
one of those metal lunch boxes
it's got the little metal clasp on the
front you pop it open there's a [ __ ] ton
of seed packs in there close it back up
throw it in the fridge it stays in the
crisper drawer that's mainly where i
keep those seeds don't come to get it
they are well protected uh but the seeds
my seeds tend to stay in the crisper
drawer they marry all there may also be
a safe somewhere that is in a cool dark
place that does not get a lot of
temperature swings a lot of the seeds
stay in the safe the safe is always dark
the temperature there is basically
always the same because of the location
keep it in a place where you can keep
the temperature kind of regulated let's
talk about why uh the temperature is
important and why why i don't like the
freezer and why possibly the
refrigerator may not be the choice for
you
if you are the kind of person that likes
to
uh open and close your seeds and show
your friends all your packages the
fridge or the freezer is not the spot
because think about what happens if you
put a food product in the refrigerator
and then you take it out it develops
condensation on the outside of the
package i was looking at one of my
drinks here to see if it was it's too uh
the temperature is just right in this
room there's no condensation
so when you take a drink out of the
fridge right there's no condensation on
your bottle you take that bottle out of
the fridge you crack it open take a few
drinks you go to grab the bottle again
it's got condensation on it
maybe possibly that could happen to our
seeds if we put them in the fridge get
them nice and cold pull them out show
them off to your friends they may be
getting exposed to condensation or
moisture within that packaging there
could be moisture in the package i don't
know how dry your seeds were i don't
know who sold them to you who packaged
them i don't know the moisture content
of your seeds before they were packaged
in the fridge that moisture could
could become condensation when you take
it out that could be detrimental to your
seeds in the freezer that moisture could
rupture your seeds if there's enough
moisture with inside with the inside of
that seed and it does freeze if it
reaches a certain temperature that could
explode and pop the seed
i have seen seeds get allegedly get
shipped from
colorado to new york in the winter they
exploded in the bay of the [ __ ] cargo
plane all the seeds were ruptured uh
they had too much moisture in them it
was winter they popped inside there like
[ __ ] bubble wrap and popcorn most of
those seeds were toasted they were
toasted they were opposite of toasted
they were frozen to [ __ ] so if you're
gonna put the seeds in the fridge leave
them there until it's time to grow them
don't be the person and it's it's okay i
love to marvel at my seed collection
i've got some seeds and i'll pull them
out and i'll look at them be like oh
there's my i've got all of the sub cool
stuff all of the tga stuff from before
subcool passed i'll pull it out just
look at it and just read the names and
look at all the cool [ __ ] that i've
gotten miss my buddy sub and it's like
looking at your baseball cards or your
sneaker collection or whatever you're
into your video games or your hats or
whatever you're into your purses if
that's your thing
a lot of people like to look at their
collection and share it show their
friends and the bros come over and
you're like i got this and i got oh yeah
i got this from this company and i got
this and you just show it off and maybe
you're doing trading or whatever if
you're going to do that bring them out a
lot don't put them in the fridge because
then you do run that risk that
opportunity that potential for
condensation every time you move them
every time you take them out put them
back in you do give them that
opportunity also you're making heat and
cold fluctuations that's going to cause
problems that's a living organism that
you're trying to preserve when it gets
warm it's probably going to start
thinking oh we're going to germinate
we're going to go in then you put it
back in the fridge and confuse the [ __ ]
out of it i don't know if that's real i
don't know if it's got that kind of
memory but that is something that i
would think about try to keep your
temperature consistent no spikes no
humidity spikes definitely no
condensation no moisture again i would
not recommend freezing them but a lot of
people do that and it does work i have
stored seeds for
years in this method uh in a baggie
in the lunch box in the crisper drawer
the fridge i've had seeds in there for a
long time i bust them out they germinate
very well so that seems to be a good
method for me
um if you are one of those people that
insists on showing your seeds to all of
your friends and you want to store them
in your refrigerator this may be a
better way to do things anyway just
because um
just adds a level of security to
yourself and your collection and also it
keeps your friends honest and it doesn't
allow for any questions maybe consider
just taking all of your seeds one time
and making a fat list of them and saying
like categorize them i read genetics
i've got all of this ah miss jill i've
got all of this whatever other brands
and breeders you're into make a strip
make a breeder and then list all the
[ __ ] you've got from them and then maybe
put regs and fems and then how many
seeds are in each pack you're real ocd
about it if you want to then when it
comes time to show off your trading or
your seeds or talk about trading you
don't have to bring out the stash and
show everybody you just show them the
list
or take pictures of all your cool [ __ ]
and show everybody your pictures
that way once again when it comes time
to trade or sell seeds you don't have to
bring it all out
things can't disappear things can't walk
away people can't accidentally take a
pack that they didn't trade for if you
only give them a picture of what you've
got available i'm not saying your
friends are going to steal from you but
who knows one time somebody stole some
seeds from me i know who you are
[ __ ] guess what i don't call you
no more i didn't say anything about it
we just don't hang out hope the seeds
was worth it because in the long run
dude you would have made so much [ __ ]
more money than stealing a [ __ ] pack
of seeds from me but guess what
you're not on the team all right so
where do we go from there um i really
don't have a lot more notes i think i've
covered the basics of storing seeds keep
them in a cool dry dark place somewhere
secure somewhere safe seeds are valuable
you guys work hard for your money i
recommend a safe if you've got a metal
gun safe or something like that
that is a great spot lock them up under
lock and key is the best place
don't bring them all out don't tell
people where you're keeping them that is
my advice take a lot of pictures of your
seed packs that way if you want to share
it with your friends you got all the
pictures there you remember what you've
got you don't have to pull it out of the
stash all the time document what you've
got write down on the seed packs maybe
if they're packs you bought if they're
seeds you made write down the date on
that package when you got it if you're
making a spreadsheet when you got those
put a date on there so that you know how
old those seeds are also maybe write
down where you got them
there are some uh vendors that do have
older seeds some vendors with newer
seeds unfortunately there are some
vendors with fugazi seeds people are
buying uh just buckets of seeds or
people are just making seeds they
wouldn't stop anybody a seed company a
seed bank uh the banks are the people
that sell the seeds the breeders are the
people that make them all right so a
company makes them the the banks sell
them nobody would
there's nothing stopping from somebody
making a bucket of seeds and just
putting them in packages and saying that
these are this brand seeds we've seen it
done
there's a company that's done it to miss
jill they've done it to myself they've
done it to a lot of the people in the
industry they claim to be selling ivory
genetics or miss jill genetics and it's
honestly just [ __ ] that they made and
they have no idea what the seeds really
are they just package it up and they
sell it then the consumer buys it and
they send me an email saying hey i
bought seeds from this company i grew
the plants and they look like [ __ ] and
i'll say well that's funny because i've
never sold any seeds to that company
they must not have sold you real irig
genetics and i do apologize so uh pay
attention to where you're getting the
seeds
so write down where your seeds came from
write down the date which you got them
that way if you run into problems you do
have some sort of history some sort of
timeline to go back on a lot of us are
consuming a lot of cannabis a lot of us
are just late night internet shoppers we
buy our seeds at random times we don't
remember exactly when and where we
bought some [ __ ] so write down on the
package a lot of the packages are fairly
large or if you've got your spreadsheet
going put those details in the
spreadsheet when did i buy these seeds
who did i buy them from
if you're really ocd write down what you
paid for them just for fun because you
can watch uh i'm watching the seed
market move up and down right now some
seeds that were worth a thousand dollars
last year are not worth much this year
and then seeds that weren't worth [ __ ]
last year are worth a lot this year it's
great watching the market the breeders
the trends um
what is it weed x stock weed the stock
market of cannabis it's fun watching
that move up and down all right i really
feel like i've rambled out this episode
this could have been a longer episode
but there's no need to stretch it out
i've covered the topic keep your seeds
in a cool dry dark place i put them in a
jar or a baggie i throw that jar or
baggie into a grateful dead lunch box if
you're into pokemon if you're into
powerpuff girls if you're into the x-men
if you're into wolverine
whatever kind of lunchbox you've got
that will work for you i've seen a lot
of people use a tackle box or something
similar put it in a box that is going to
keep the light off of the seeds put
those in the crisper drawer of the
fridge or if you live in a cool place
where it doesn't get too hot too cold
you can keep them in a drawer i prefer a
safe tour it's nice and locked in
colorado the basement stays great here
if you've got a safe in the basement in
colorado i'd recommend putting your
seeds in a safe in the basement they'll
be great year-round the temperatures
should stay pretty nice all right you
guys i feel like i'm just rambling at
this point to make the show longer
there's no need to drag this out let's
wrap up this podcast if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know i would love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
let me know what you think of the show
if you have any topics you'd like me to
like me to cover any grow questions
you'd like to ask i would love to hear
from you also check out the website
iriegenetics.com there's a link to the
discord a link to seed vendors there is
a grow help tab there on that grow help
tab i do ask you a free a few
preliminary questions we ask what's up
with your temperature your humidity uh
what you're growing is it indoors is it
outdoors a few basic questions so i know
what's going on with your grow scroll
down to the bottom i do give you the
opportunity to explain what is going on
in your grow and ask for help let me
know if you have problems if you don't
have grow problems or grow help if
you've got a basic cannabis culture
question a cultivation question skip all
the part above put your question right
in there i will answer that for you on
the show if i haven't answered your
message already please be patient i've
been doing a lot of focused episodes on
uh the silver thio sulfate and other
things i will be getting to more
listener emails very soon i save them up
and make big episodes out of those keep
the messages coming don't forget about
patreon at patreon.com
forward slash girl from your heart my
throat is done my add is firing up that
is all i've got for you for this episode
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content let's give a giant
shout out to my friend adhd grower and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug
[Music]
you