[Music]
so
highly ho podcast world i'm your host my
friends call me rasta jeff this is
episode
728 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on
more listener emails before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to our friend oreck let's send
a big thank you shout out to lots of
trichomes and b bala let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to doc
rose and caribou heart tv i want to send
a big thank you shout out to a long time
supporter my buddy glenn jeroni let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to frogman420
let's send a big high five and a fist
bump to double d and spa city gardner i
want to send a thank you shout out to
froggle rock and david w then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to the
dad hayes big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends who want to support the show pay
attention to patreon because in the
month of april i will do a big discount
code for the merchandise store that's
right you will get one of those updated
coupon codes i'm going to try to blow
out the merch store clean out a bunch of
stuff so that i can upgrade update and
replace a lot of things so if you are a
patron pay attention for the month of
april you will get a great coupon code i
want to do a big shout out to everybody
who showed up for the groovy gravy
secret stash event um i'm sure it was a
great event of course i'm recording
ahead of time so uh in anticipation i'm
sure it was a great event thanks to
everybody that showed up look forward in
the future for a full review of the
groovy gravy secret stash event i am
recording ahead of time but that will
happen before this comes out so there
will be a time vortex and then we will
talk about it in what will be the future
all right let's get back on track in the
real world i may have mentioned this in
a previous episode i did ask our friend
pedro to record a video about cleaning
our rig and our banger so hopefully in
the near future here uh when pedro has
some time this weekend which already
happened when this video comes out see
how weird production time can be uh
pedro will make a video to teach us how
to clean our glass how to keep our rigs
our banger clean has given me some great
advice i just told him make a video for
me bro we'll show this to everybody he
will get that going i will get that out
to you as soon as possible so do look
forward to that
also look forward to feminized seeds
that's right i've got a lot of femme
seeds out there in testing uh there's
new stuff being tested i am also making
restocks of a lot of the things that are
in demand the lemon jeffrey will be
restocked golden goat will be restocked
orange gasm will be restocked red and
blue pills will be officially released
and there is more stuff in the room to
be pollinated that i will not mention at
this time but the reversal is working
the project is underway things look good
the reverse plant is showing me that it
is reversing it is showing that it's
working there are male parts or pollen
parts popping up on this female plant it
looks successful i have dragged the
female plants into the room the pollen
receivers are in there i am debating if
they will get their final spray one more
spray uh they've gotten sprayed up to
day 21 i'm not sure if they're going to
get sprayed on day 24 or not it looks
like it's working
that's a that's a game time decision to
be made right there maybe hit one of
them don't hit the other two that's
something we'll think about document
mark down uh take good notes of but the
fem project is working that means that
there will be feminized seeds in a
little bit of time uh the plants do need
to get uh mature enough to accept the
pollen the pollen donors need to make
the pollen there needs to be a little
bit of uh action happening there then of
course we've got six to eight weeks for
seeds to be made then we've got harvest
time dry time i said harvest time i
apologize if you heard that grossness uh
we do have dry and cure time packaging
time all that good stuff to keep in mind
also but it's happening they are coming
a lot of people ask me about the lemon
jeffree golden goat orgasm femmes uh
they're hot they're sought after i get a
lot of emails people on the show ask
people to listen ask so uh stay tuned
they are coming i am making them also
there is more stuff to be released um do
i want to say it here on the show why
not this is one of the best platforms to
release stuff i made afterglow feminized
seeds that's right i made the afterglow
that is the uh it is a uh it's a
clementine female pollinated by the
arise male it's clementine clementine to
arise clementine to king solomon made
afterglow shout out to mike for coining
the name afterglow he said that in a
conversation one day and i said you shut
up with that word i'm going to use that
as a strain name it became the afterglow
i made a bunch of afterglow seeds
somehow magically i got a bunch of those
seeds to our friend the painted lady uh
the painted lady grew the [ __ ] out of
the afterglow she found a keeper in
there that was amazing uh somehow
magically i acquired that keeper from
her i took that keeper of the afterglow
and i reversed it and i made afterglow
s1s and i also outcrossed it to a bunch
of magical stuff uh so stay tuned some
of those will be released some of those
uh some of them have already been tested
they're out there as testers getting ran
now some are just getting sent out uh
but stay tuned a lot of that stuff the
after afterglow will be released the
outcrosses are being tested now lots of
great femmes coming so you guys that are
asking guys and gals that are asking for
feminized seeds you will have a nice
menu very very soon where do we go from
here i've got a lot of stuff to talk
about let's jump into the email portion
of this podcast i do have a good message
right here in front of me this one may
be more of a compliment this one came
from our friend ass kickerson big up to
my buddy ass kickerson you keep kicking
ass kickers and arse out there however
you want to do it you keep doing it the
message goes a lot like this it says you
can use my name but i don't need this on
the podcast well it's going to be on the
podcast because i want to read one of
these compliments that's in here just
because a lot of people think i'm crazy
and this does kind of back up one of my
statements uh it says first and foremost
i have to say thank you i've been
growing for years now um then he
mentions where he is we're not going to
talk about that i'm going to skip some
of this then it says i'm working my way
back through the catalog in reverse
order so i'm around 520 now the point is
i've heard you mention switching to 18
six at the end of flower for a week or
more yes uh in one episode i do mention
turning your timer back to 18-6 during
the flush phase when you begin flushing
your plants turn your light timer to 18
hours on and six hours off
i do get a lot of feedback a lot of
people think i'm crazy a lot of people
talk a lot of trash to me for this
method but all of the people that talk
[ __ ] about this method about this advice
refuse to try it so you can't talk [ __ ]
until you try something at least put one
or two plants in there and prove me
wrong before you talk [ __ ] to me that is
my theory i've done it and it works for
me so if you're just talking and you
haven't done it that that is not really
don't don't even bother messaging me
with that anyway our friend here says uh
i have grown out the same cut four times
and i've never had the buds swell at the
end like this if this mic wasn't on a
stand i would [ __ ] drop it it would
just be never had the bud swell like
this mic drop it would be over right
there you'd hear the thud and then some
dope ass music would play and i would
walk off we have a supporter here our
friend backs up my statement that
changing the timer to 18 hours on and
six hours off for the last 10 to 14 days
of flower will bulk up and increase your
buds so this guy says i have never had
buds swell at the end like this i'm
getting rambly here bro welcome to the
party uh but these days while i do grow
for headstash and a couple of the homies
i also have two cancer patients in my
life that i grow for hey big up
congratulations and thank you uh for
putting in the effort the time the
energy the compassion the dedication to
grow for other people growing for
ourselves growing for money growing for
profit that's really easy growing a
product you're putting in time energy
effort electricity money possibly a risk
you're dedicating your space your plant
count uh your numbers to another person
to two other sick people that's
commendable uh that's respectable so big
up shout out for doing that you could
have gotten stingy and use that space
for profit that plant that space is
profitable you're doing it to give that
product to a sick person because they
have cancer that is great that's good
karma that's what it's all about that is
growing from your heart my friend so big
up for that i apologize if i seem
distracted i'm expecting a delivery and
they will not leave it if i don't sign
for it let's keep moving it does say i
also have two cancer patients being able
to help them just a little bit more
brings tears to my eyes honestly as soon
as i noticed it working i promptly
joined the patreon and ordered some irie
genetics bro i can support the statement
of um knowing what it's like to grow for
somebody i was lucky enough fortunate
enough blessed enough to be involved in
the very first dispensary here in this
city there were some folks that had the
right idea but they didn't have the
right uh they're the right idea they
just needed some pushes i'm kind of
younger hipper had more energy more
experience i'd been to more dispensaries
they had the funding and the idea they
didn't know how to really set up a
dispensary they kind of handed me the
keys and let me do it
i got the privilege to meet uh every
medical marijuana patient in my city it
felt like some of them were uh 70 year
old old ladies and i don't mean to call
you old ladies but that describes what
they were uh lovely gracious 70 year old
senior ladies is that the more polite
way to say it sorry ladies there were
also 70 year old veterans seven-year-old
firefighters ah seven-year-old
ex-gangsters
old city council members what city
council members came i'm not supposed to
say that but they may have popped in you
don't know who they are or which one
they was
um
there were a lot of people popped in
also i got 35 year old construction
workers i got
people that i think may have been a cop
sometimes came and bought cannabis
legally with a medical marijuana card
there were 21 year old dudes that would
jog up and buy weed and jog right on out
i got to meet everybody i got to see the
entire community every type of condition
you could imagine i got to see that come
into my dispensary i got to interact
with them and talk with them i got to
develop
actual relationships with a lot of these
people the the older people that slow
down and take their time and talk to you
and they're not in a rush to get out and
get back on twitter and instagram or
whatever the new [ __ ] thing we're
scrolling on uh get in the car and play
the new track and drive fast the older
people we really had time to connect and
they would tell me you know i smoked
this one and it didn't help much but i
smoked this one and i feel a lot better
and sometimes people would come with
their significant other older people
that are sick would come with their wife
or their husband or their caretaker and
they would say you know since you gave
us this strain since you've been smoking
this lemon jeffrey
my dad my husband my wife has been a lot
better of a person a lot easier to get
along with so we would see medicine that
we would grow and recommend improve the
quality of people's lives and that was
that is what it's all about i almost
said that's what it was all about that's
what it is all about when it comes to
recreational and medical cannabis is
improving the quality of people's lives
whether it's a healthy person like
myself who's got some bodily pain i
smoke to relieve pain there are some
people that are just smoking because
they've got some other issues whatever
we're smoking for people have cancer
aids cachexia a lot of other crazy [ __ ]
whatever you're smoking for as long as
it improves the quality of your life
that is the goal here so big up for
taking energy time uh effort out of your
day and having some some compassion to
take care of these other people bro that
means a lot to me and i get to see
exactly what you're talking about people
would come in and the first visit they
would be
intimidated scared confused they
wouldn't know what they were talking
about what they were buying they would
know they feel like [ __ ] and they're
down to try medical marijuana maybe that
will help by the fifth or sixth time
they came in to see me they would high
five me they would skip in be like
what's up ross to jeff good to see you
bro i need to get an eighth of the lemon
jeffrey and an eighth of this o.g kush
and i'll see in a couple days and they
do [ __ ] cartwheels and skip out and
i'd be like that's a completely
different person the person that came in
here before seemed uh almost defeated
almost like their their illness their
ailment was winning and now that we've
got them on cannabis their body is
better their spirit is better their
relationships are better so i got to see
that firsthand ah you said you were
rambling bro talk about a ramble fest
thank you i really uh i love thinking
and talking about those old days of when
the medical market started uh developing
because i really do enjoy did enjoy
developing those relationships with
people now i'm recommending seeds and
things like that but when people ask me
about cannabis and get me going about
this i really do like it uh i walked
into somewhere the other day
i'd been on the road for like three
hours and i walked in and i was like hey
i'm here and i didn't get my bag set
down and my shoes kicked off before
somebody was like hey you're the weed
guy i want to know about this and i it
didn't even phase me i just clicked into
like from traffic mode i was in [ __ ]
this traffic mode you ever been in
traffic where you just want to throw
bricks at the cars just because they're
cars you're like why do you have wheels
and doors you're so stupid that's how i
felt about the traffic that day but i
digress ah when i got into the place
somebody was like you're the weed guy i
have weed questions here's questions one
through seven i didn't flinch i didn't
hesitate i kindly kicked off my shoes i
set my bag down i sat down and looked
them in the face and i explained
everything i [ __ ] knew about their
questions i just loved talking about it
they were kind of new at cannabis they
needed guidance i definitely had the
answers and i just could not shut up
about it and it was perfect i really
enjoyed that so bro thank you for the
great reminder my friend ours kickerson
thank you for the reminder of how much i
enjoy uh the connection of recommending
strains and then seeing a person i would
give you two or three strains and give
them to you on a discount price and send
you home and let you smoke them
sometimes back in the day bro we could
smoke those strains in the dispensary
and see what you liked but then you'd
come back and have reports and then we'd
improve the quality of your life that's
what it's all about so uh thank you for
reminding me that uh sometimes it did
bring tears to my eyes to see the
improvements that we could give to
people's quality of life and then also
bro thank you for supporting the fact
that 18 6 at the end of flower is a
great idea you guys if you haven't seen
that episode i will link it to this show
at the end of the episode it does give
me the opportunity to put the subscribe
and then the next video up here i'll do
my best to put the correct video right
up here i'm not sure which side it will
go on i haven't figured that out yet
because it reverses and then what the
hell is going to happen but i'll put the
186 on the screen at the end of the
video so you just click that also make
sure you subscribe alright i do have
another email here in front of me let's
get to it because i am talky today
excuse me for the throat clearing also
i've been smoking a whole bunch of lemon
jeffrey live rosin out of a brand new
rig um the past couple of days have been
a little fuzzy i bought a new rig and
got a bunch of lemon jeffrey
concentrates on the same day
uh yeah i'm a spoiled brat but since
then i feel like i'm not sure if i'm
time traveling or if i'm frozen in time
or somewhere in between but time isn't
doing what it normally my clock isn't
spinning like this it's more kind of
like it's moving up and down in the spin
motion it is not consistent in any way
you guys don't care let me get to the
point this one says hi my name is fred
what up fred good to meet you bro thank
you for listening to my podcast thank
you for contributing with the great
message it does go on it says i am
planning on working with a variety of
cultivars soon including scarlet
begonias what a great choice i hope that
works well for you it says my question
which insects would you make sure were
present before beginning an outdoor plot
or soon thereafter i understand more
research will be necessary that is one
of the keys i'm going to get to is
research will be necessary is i've never
worked with organic methods however is
there a handful or a list of insect
species that you or other commercial
growers prefer to ensure a healthier
garden perhaps i could foster a
healthier yard in general as some of
these species are already present in
this environment he says i've got wasps
and ladybugs and the list goes on
the thing is
you've seen the wasps and you have seen
the ladybugs you're already watching for
waspis which is what you should be doing
you know the ladybugs are there they're
basically harmless but you can't see
most of the harmful insects uh the bugs
that are really going to cause you
problems are microscopic the spider
mites the uh i don't even want to say
the russet mites uh the fungus gnats the
thrips uh the what are the things you're
gonna run into mites thrips aphids
aphids are very common outside in
colorado we get caterpillars the
caterpillars leave these little orange
melon they're melon caterpillars they
leave a melon worm in there they turn
orange they eat the inside of your buds
i'm not exactly sure what those are
but we get a lot of those kind of bugs
here those are bugs that i would prepare
to battle i'm not sure where you are you
didn't tell me where you are but then it
says also as well which host plants are
your go to thank you for the podcast and
cheers all right big disclaimer before i
even delve too deeply into this i am not
an outdoor organic grower i grow indoors
with bottled nutrients and most of my
pesticide prevention is honestly
straight up sprayed pesticide
applications until i move into flour
that's when we do play with the uh the
pest uh the predator bugs but uh i don't
do this outdoors and i don't know where
you are so one of the first things i'm
gonna recommend
is find an insectiary near you
there is a an insectiary near you that
distributes bugs to greenhouses and
farms for this purpose i'm not sure if
they're going to offer you the small
order that you need but you can get the
information that you need from them and
then find a retail provider from there i
can make other recommendations
but call an insectiary near you or call
other farmers near you or perhaps get on
the internet and do some research what
pests are coming to you be prepared i
already mentioned we're getting mites
thrips aphids caterpillars i don't know
where you are i don't know if there's a
specific bug that comes where you are
every region is going to have an extra
attacker that the farmers there know
about i know about the caterpillars here
because i hear people [ __ ] about it
every year here i know that that's a
thing
so do some research and be prepared for
what bugs are gonna come your way also
keep in mind uh we also get what are
they uh uh grasshoppers i couldn't think
of what [ __ ] grasshoppers were we get
a lot of grasshoppers here in pueblo
mid-summer there'll just be a gang of
grasshoppers appear out of nowhere uh we
also get deer in this area we also get
bear in this area it sounds crazy i live
in the city but a few miles that way
you'll see bear and they'll get into
your grow this [ __ ] smells good they
want to see what it is if you're feeding
it organics it smells real good and the
bears really want to know what it is if
you used a fish product and you you live
by the river and you're in colorado
expect a bear to come up to that [ __ ]
that's very likely very possible uh we
get deer bear rabbits grasshoppers uh
then all kinds of small uh rodents and
ground dwelling animals just low [ __ ]
low small stuff skunks and [ __ ] like
that will eat your weed plants ah cats
cats will eat the [ __ ] weed plants
i've seen plenty of cats in weed grows
so my first piece of advice is to see
what bugs what pest what problems may be
present who may show up uh you can
google that probably through the
internet there may be a grover's group
in your area i don't know if it's legal
or illegal and i don't know where you
are so half of my recommendations are
going to be vague but find what bugs are
coming find what problems are coming
anticipate that then also
do some research with that insectiary
other grows forms websites to find out
what bugs uh predator bugs will do well
in your neighborhood we could release
all of the predator bugs on the planet
we could spend a million bucks
but
doorbell i'll be right back
all right i apologize for that the
doorbell did ring i was expecting a
delivery it is here now i can focus more
on the show i got the package i needed
i'm excited uh may show you that in a
future episode let's get back where i
was what was i saying i said you can
order a million dollars worth of
predator insects to try to guard your
garden your outdoor plot but if they are
not the appropriate insects for your
environment they may
die they may fly away they may just
crawl away they may not even stick
around they may get eaten by other bugs
they may battle each other if you get
the wrong combination of things
so i would do a little bit of research
on what predator bugs will work well in
your area now i know that sounds crazy
but an insectiary would give you good
advice they would say hey these bugs
work well in your heat your humidity in
your environment because if you buy i'm
just going to give you an example maybe
you spend a thousand dollars on
hypoasmus miles and you put those out
there and i don't know the range that
the hypos like i know that they do like
my indoor grow that's what i buy for the
indoor cultivation if you put the
hypoaspis miles out there and it's too
hot or too cold they'll either die or
they'll leave they'll just simply
[ __ ] crawl away and go find a more
desirable environment they're just like
us if they don't like what's going on
they're going to go somewhere else so
you've got to get the bugs that are
appropriate for your environment a
website that will help you do that of
course is arbico organics it's
a-r-b-i-c-o-organics.com
i cannot give them any
positive or negative endorsements on
their products nor their customer
service i have seen uh plenty of
positive reviews and i've also seen
plenty of negative reviews i'm right in
the middle with the reviews i've read
i would do my own research when you
order bugs there's got to be a closer
insectiary to you to order the bugs from
the advantage of arbico is they'll sell
you very small batches a lot of other
places don't sell small batches of bugs
arbico will deliver a small batch to you
again
i can't support or say they're good or
bad i know that they do offer the
products we need i know their catalog is
awesome i know their website is awesome
but i've seen people say that they get
dead bugs from them i've also seen
people say that they get amazing bugs
from them so be careful with that that
is going to be your decision to make
there although their website and their
magazines and catalogs are awesome for
research for information for educational
purposes even if you don't purchase from
them you can use their website to get
you a lot of information get you a lot
of education get yourself a nice
foundation and background you can read a
lot from their website again it's arbico
a-r-b-i-c-o-organics.com i believe to
the best of my recollection did not
write that down but um
one thing that i read is they don't they
don't breed any bugs they buy their bugs
from an insectiary and then mail them to
you they're kind of like a third party
uh they're like the amazon of bugs so i
may be easier if you can find a local
insectiary near you to get the
appropriate bugs that's the way to do it
and use arbico for your research again
if you can't find a supplier that
website is always there for you do your
own research i'm trying to be really
diplomatic about this i've read good and
bad reviews you guys i don't know which
way i sway uh if it's my only option i
may risk it uh risk a few bucks to save
the garden where was i do some research
then
once you've established which bugs will
live in your area and which bugs are
going to battle your area order the
appropriate bugs
i like to set up the subscription
service you can order them order them to
you can schedule them to come on
specific intervals when i run a
commercial grow i usually have them show
up either every week or every two weeks
depending on
the threat that is present if i see bugs
we double up if i don't see bugs we go
once a week with the sachets and with
the releasing of pests so let me give
you a quick list of the predators that i
did write down i don't think i wrote
down all of them because i just thought
of cucumarus and it's not on the list ah
the cucumaris the californicus some of
these they changed their names i may
repeat things because they've got double
names there's the californicus the
cucumaris the swarsky hypoaspis miles
lace wings that's a good start i think
those will work in a lot of environments
and they are very aggressive predators a
lot of people like ladybugs
ladybugs are lazy in my opinion
that is my honest opinion you can buy a
lot of ladybugs and they're not going to
do a lot the ladybug larvae will eat a
lot but
the green lacewing in my opinion will
eat three times i don't know the science
behind this i don't know but from what
i've seen when i use ladybugs they end
up in the lights and the ducting on the
floor uh just over there humping each
other you see them [ __ ] all the time
they make really cool pictures but they
don't eat the [ __ ] bugs when i
release green lacewing eggs i don't see
any more bugs i don't see any any lace
wings anywhere they're not over there
chilling out i'm not taking pictures of
them they're being [ __ ] warriors and
they're eating all of the bugs i want
them to eat and they're really really
fun to watch they're so ugly they turn
start off as little crocodiles and they
start getting little wings and they just
go through this weird metamorphosis
those are the lace wings so i am not a
bug expert i'm not an outdoor growing
expert but i do recommend that you
research the bugs that will be coming to
your area uh it's going to be spider
mites thrips aphids caterpillars fungus
um whatever bugs come in your area i
don't know where you are see it's hard
for me to anticipate so you got to find
what's coming to your area then think
about cucumarus californis is it
californicus uh you'll figure it out
when you search predator
arbico organics will have it all right
there for you i don't even need to
repeat this once you get to arbico
you're going to see more than what i'm
saying uh rove beetles are [ __ ] great
there's a lot of great things
what are the assassin beetles there are
a lot that you can release but if
they're not right for your area they're
not gonna have a good time they're gonna
leave like if you took me to a fish
concert i'm sticking around all day if
you take me to i'm trying i would stay
to most concerts because i like music if
you took me to see uh sorry if you took
me to a keith urban concert i'd probably
leave sorry i'm not into the country
music you guys i'm gonna just leave so
that somebody who is a keith urban fan
could have the ticket and enjoy the show
that's the way it should be um
i'm rambling there's no need to go on
with this message i have answered your
question as for host plants dude i don't
know that's my straight up answer for
host plants we would have to contact my
buddy jesse groves he is the outdoor
grower if anybody out there has any
recommendations for host plants we can
plant outdoors to help mitigate pests
send your info to grow from your heart
at hotmail.com i will read that on a
future episode also make sure you follow
the bug lady susan wayne wright evans is
it suzanne or susan suzanne wayne wright
evans that sounds right follow the bug
lady on instagram uh she is a pest
expert she's a pesticide expert i am
trained by the colorado department of
agriculture uh the colorado state
university also trained by the colorado
department of public health and
environment and pesticide application
pesticide handling i am trained the
trainer certified so i do know quite a
bit about pesticides and pesticide
application however what you're asking
is very regionally specific so i would
focus in on your region on the pests
attacking your area the pests uh the
prevention that would work in your area
and then go a little bit from there i
hope i put you off on the right foot got
you on to the right start uh uh leaned
you toward the right website hope i got
you going in the right direction ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers organic growers
salt spillers i want to thank each and
every one of you for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast my voice is burning out i
think i've covered enough ground on this
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns i'd love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you feel like the episode
was educational informative entertaining
maybe you just want to throw me a couple
of bucks because you like what i'm doing
all you have to do is visit patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information to support the show
will be right there on the screen make
sure you support the show in the month
of april if you're looking for
merchandise t-shirts stickers hats
things like that i will give you great
coupon codes in the month of april based
on the tiers of support on patreon so
make sure you support patreon in the
month of april
everything else check out the website
iregenetics.com that's all i've got for
you my throat is done i'll be back uh
one of the upcoming episodes probably
not the next one but maybe the one right
after that i do intend to do a groovy
gravy recap episode i'll let you guys
know how that event went so stay tuned
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
let's give a big shout out to my friend
tree star meadow and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you