[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode
729 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode clint is going to join
me and we're going to recap the secret
stash event that happened this weekend
before we get to that part let me do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend jay dutch let's
send a big thank you shout out to
shoetrader101 let's send a big fist bump
and a thank you shout out to polo paul
and kwazi let's send a thank you shout
out to indica chris and anvil gardens
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my friend colin at sacred tree organic
farms let's send a fist bump and a thank
you shout out to jimmy limmer and stoner
dave let's send a thank you shout out to
route 305 and elders garden then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to our
friend godfather kush big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit www dot
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make it nice
and easy for all of my friends all right
in a second here i will bring clint on
but i do have some very sad news i do
want to be very clear when i say this
unfortunately we have lost another
member of the ire army our friend giant
mike has passed away let me be very
clear that this is not white mike giant
mike and white mike are two different
dudes uh giant mike is a very tall
skinny guy he has passed away i want to
send him a fist bump send him a sacred
hug up to wherever mike goes whatever
you believe in whatever heaven you're
into that's where giant mike went to i
know that dude went to whatever
incarnation of heaven you do believe in
that's where he is he was a good dude he
was a giant tall gentle dude he was a
father he was a husband he was a friend
he was a grower he was recently in
trouble with the law for growing so he
got to give him a fist bump and some
love
um also i don't know if she'll listen to
this but big shout out to the dabbing
queen uh mrs giant mike if you need
anything you reach out the entire irie
army has got your back on make sure you
don't go without anything you've got
kids you got a family to take care of
let me know if i can help you in any way
please do not be shy big shout out much
love much respect to giant mike rest in
peace brother big hug to the dabbing
queen all right we do have clint here on
the show let's change the mood really
quickly i'm gonna step over here to
camera one uh ladies and gentlemen
welcome to the show clint is here i know
that's hard to follow bro uh saying
goodbye to a friend but dude thank you
for lightening the mood the comedian the
the lighthearted guy is here welcome to
the show bro hey man i'm super happy to
be here i
uh am such a big fan of the podcast a
big fan of you of course you know we've
been friends for
almost a decade now that's a long time
you're telling them how old we are bro
you know and thank you for supporting
the show it's uh i don't expect all of
my friends to listen to the show
especially you you're not a uh
a serious hardcore weed grower you're
not deep into weed culture you do i'm
not deep into weed culture we'll talk
more we'll talk more about it that
throughout the show but you're getting
your uh your green thumb your feet wet
and i love that you're listening i don't
expect that and sometimes my friends
apologize like bro i haven't heard the
recent episode i'm like dude there's a
lot in life you're not getting paid uh
there's no test uh enjoy the show when
you can it's free i want you to enjoy it
learn from it but i appreciate that
you're listening bro that's rad i mean
episodes
congratulations man thank you brother
it's really great to see you the last
time
i appreciate that i think the last time
you were here was number five or 600 i
know it was one of the double digits i
think i was on 500 was the last time
this was before video so this is the
first time that i've ever got to put a
voice and a face together on your
podcast i was going to say that uh the
beard is here you brought the beard the
face looking all shiny showing that
beard off i'll try to remember to zoom
in when i edit there you go check out
that shiny beard he brought dude welcome
to the show this is going to be a good
time oh yeah uh the reason i wanted to
bring clint not only is he uh beginning
to grow a little bit we'll talk more
about that and as the show progresses
that will come in naturally he's been
helping out been doing some growing he's
become really enthusiastic and i think
that's the word passionate about the
cannabis plant about the growing also
about helping with ivory genetics uh
just being a bro you've had my back i've
needed some help with some things uh
you've provided a lot of help and
service and bro ship so that's cool but
the reason i brought him on today is we
attended the secret stash the groovy
gravy secret stash seat exchange in
denver colorado there we go i got the
sales pitch going there you go
excuse me i got stuff on my teeth i'm
just going to keep talking here keep
recording right over it
uh we attended the event together we
also brought white mike uh i hosted the
the booth and i used clint we used you
as kind of uh security and bro ship and
backup ship and customer service
mike plays a very good customer service
role they are learning the strains
really well they both know how to talk
to people so it's great to have them at
the booth
so i thought i'd bring them to do a
recap of the event if you've been
following along i've been talking about
the event for a long time it was a
really cool event let's just jump right
into talking about it bro it was at a
super cool location i don't know what
that place was called i don't know what
that place is today all i know is that
on saturday they cleared everything out
of there and we put up probably 25 cool
booths a dj and a drum set and threw a
secret stash seed exchange in there
beautiful venue in the rhino district of
denver and
secret stash was uh definitely an
experience um
first not knowing exactly where it was
until the day of was kind of
unique for me
i didn't i didn't know either they
didn't tell yeah you would of course
known but they didn't tell anybody where
the event was located until the day of
the event they would give you hints uh
first it was it's in denver and then
it's going to be near downtown and then
it's at the rhino district and then the
day of the event they actually told us
the exact address the vendors got the
address i think around 8 30 or 9 is when
i got the text i was walking the dogs
and pulled up the phone and had it after
that
so there was a message saying hey
vendors here it is then it said do not
share this address yet we're not giving
it to the other people until later
most people didn't get it the attendees
didn't get it until 11 and it opened at
noon so
they made it really easy to set up
because a lot of times they'll be
walking into an event and everybody
outside is ross to jeff ross and jeff
because i'm 6'5 with dreadlocks to my
ass wearing an irie genetics t-shirt you
can't miss me so everyone's like what's
up bro i got the dunks on they all know
that's me and so everybody wants to talk
at this event bro i grabbed my stuff i
parked parking was super easy because i
got there early nobody none of the fans
were there yet the attendees got to park
carried my [ __ ] in set up my booth and
got ready before these guys even showed
up uh luckily i started my day in
broomfield they had to drive all the way
up from pueblo but i agree dude not
knowing where it is is a little
nerve-wracking how do you know where to
get a hotel how do you know how to plan
you just got to fly by the seat of your
pants that's how being a weed grower and
a seed seller has always been in my
opinion
it was but it was a beautiful venue and
so many
good people and such a great vibe
throughout the whole thing
smelled great outside they were cooking
a lot of food oh yeah
it was
really nice inside
very acclimate
conditions and i i i just enjoyed the
whole experience i got to meet so many
fun people and so many
passionate people about
weed it was uh it has reinvigorated my
love for the plants i appreciate that uh
this event was cool because
no offense to the bigger events i'm not
going to bash the endo expo that didn't
happen but that was one of the bigger
events to compare it to rest in peace
chris by the way i'm sorry the endo did
not happen you guys
but at that event you get people
who have no idea what they're talking
about about cannabis you get everybody
at that even it's a big commercialized
event at the secret stash
it was the people that were there
looking for specific genetics they would
come to the booth and they would be like
do you have this pack i want this pack
right now here's my money i've been
looking for this you're here i will take
it now today and then you can see them
have like a strategy they would go from
us and then right over to jj and get
that sour diesel and then run over to
masonic and get that wilson papaya like
they were getting everything they could
from every breeder they wanted uh and
one guy's like would you recommend i
shop with anybody else and i was like ah
definitely go see jj go hit masonic and
he held up his bag he had a masonic bag
with jj seeds in it that i could see and
i was like you're already winning bro
he's like i listen to the show dude so
he had a strategy already perfect
yeah he knew exactly where he wanted to
shop who he wanted to see i want to uh i
want to go backwards a little bit seed
vendors inside food trucks and art and
culture outside that was super cool
that's right we had artists right in
front of us like doing their oh yeah
artists inside their craft yeah that was
that was really fun i actually got to
like talk with a couple of the artists
and tell them hey man it's really fun to
watch you and your your art yeah so the
canvas would go from blank to artwork
and they would take down the art and put
up another one and then i was like what
are they drawing who is that and then
suddenly the guy that they had painted
walked by and they had him hold up the
painting i was like that's pretty cool
man that's that guy for sure so yeah
just a just a wonderful event uh groovy
gravy excellent job yeah yeah really
great good job we'll be there next year
so everybody absolutely plan ahead about
this time next year that'll be the third
one next year i'll be bigger better
better i will prepare better we had the
menu on a qr code because i didn't want
to waste paper
i never know how many menus to print out
and i don't like throwing them away
after the event so i made a qr code you
scan it with your phone i feel like that
may have costed us a few sales but
that's a learning experience you know in
denver it seems like everything is qr
code so it's tough for us to be
down on ourselves for something that
seems like a very
like trendy
should have been people should have been
ready for it and the people that weren't
it seemed like well i don't know
yeah we probably could add a couple of
menus they were definitely from
somewhere smaller is the polite way to
say it and welcome welcome to colorado
welcome to denver man such a good time
though such positive
energy everybody was in such a good mood
a lot of the times at these events you
get hungry or something like halfway
through the day you get the munchies
because you're there i was there kind of
early 11-ish that's not early but i mean
i had to get up and get there and get
set up and i got hungry i may have
allegedly been there was a no smoking
event but i may allegedly have had a
couple of dabs i got the munchies all i
had to do was walk out the back door and
there were there were tacos and there
were vegan tacos which is freaking
awesome there was cheesecake uh there
was all kinds of i smelled all kinds of
foods anything you could think of there
was a food truck a booth that had it
there was a massage booth big shout out
to priscilla and the massage booth a
bunch of great stuff outside we got to
watch art inside so let's kind of work
on the uh the list of the people that we
should give a shout out to because we
saw a bunch of cool people i tried to
make a list and a note as the day went
on but there were so many people and i
was working with customers and friends
and uh i was high there's a lot going on
also the the event was a very like timed
event for the customers yes because they
they had like an hour allotment to come
in and shop through every vendor so
is that good is that bad i don't know
because it kept people moving we had a
lot of different customers but you know
there was like five different
it was like five events almost right
like okay everybody get out next right
it was polite yeah so they bought ticket
they knew when they bought tickets they
would get a one-hour time slot to shop
and this was done to uh to uh follow
covid protocol this was before this was
booked before the coveted restrictions
were released so
this was just to be safe and comply with
all of denver's weird restrictions uh so
i think next year we may be able to open
it up and not do the the phases but what
they do to and also to limit capacity of
the building and to not overwhelm the
breeders and to follow covert
restrictions like said they give you
they open the door at noon
and you get to run through until 12 and
then they are at one and they kick you
out at one and then from one to 115 it
was really nice because we got to
regroup uh we got to reorganize when
you're selling seeds that fast your
organization gets messy we got to kind
of take a drink uh hit the vape pen a
couple times
reorganize the seeds restack the
t-shirts things like that
go go use the restroom at other events i
don't get to pee yeah it's super nice to
get to go pee once or twice during the
event because was drinking a lot of
water because i was yelling over the dj
all day which was kind of kind of hard
to do
we were we were having to speak up a
little bit so if you were at the event
you know uh the the music was a little
louder than we would have preferred i
mean mike was hoarse yeah mike doesn't
have a voice by about two o'clock mike
is his voice is still shot so if we
didn't seem like we wanted to talk we
did we just couldn't [ __ ] hear you
bro we apologize for that and if i
leaned in like i was trying to kiss you
i was just trying to hear you dude just
trying to hear a lot of people i was
leaning in uh my hearing sucks i played
the drums for 20 years and that that dj
was killing it but it was a little loud
for me um
uh we saw a lot of people there there
was a friend who uh i some people i
can't say their names i just wrote down
the guys from upstate new york because
that way we don't uh snitch on anybody
get any people in trouble never once bro
big shout out to those people remember
the group um that is doing all the great
work with the doctors they didn't give
us a card i don't have their business
card i don't know their names uh there
were three or four of them i think
they're from missouri they're from
missouri shout out to those folks i
don't know your name but i'm sure you're
gonna watch this because you've got a
podcast ad i had a good time with you
funny people
um then let's cover some of the breeders
dude it's always fun to reconnect with
top dog jj was there didn't spend a lot
of time with them got to stop and shake
his hand that's pretty much all that
matters got to say hi to jj from top dog
that's a good dude
um i got to talk to daz we're going to
talk more about that i'm sure you guys
saw the photos of daz daz's booth was
right next to us i got to hang out with
masonic smoker big up to big mace uno
what up mace um i wish i could have hung
out with mace and daz both for a little
bit longer it was such a quick event a
lot of people flew in and then after six
or seven hours of talking and selling
seeds or voices done you just want to go
smoke and eat food so everybody was like
hey good seeing you high five fist bump
we're out of here we all just dipped
right at six o'clock it was over uh big
shout out to masonic smoker if you're
not following masonic give him a follow
his instagram will get shut down just
follow the next one it's how he does it
um i finally got to meet our friend
colin from sacred tree organic farms him
and his lovely partner um they were both
very great people uh spent a few minutes
with them they bought a lot of gear they
got some free merchandise what a bright
uh
entity yes both of them were great both
of them were just so happy he took off
to go to the atm and so i just politely
made conversation with her and she was
super cool
they're both very petite folks that they
both got some t-shirts to wear because
the smaller sizes don't sell well so i
was like let's just bless our friends
with these genetics.com
ah that's the truth yes uh there's a
link to all the t-shirts if you're
watching this this was a note for the
end of the show but clint just gave me a
good segue this will come out uh it
won't be april 1st yet but when april
1st comes there will be a huge sale on
the merch store the t-shirts stickers
hats
other things that are on there there are
beanies there are rolling trays those
things will all be at a deep discount on
the website
make sure you are supporting the patreon
the higher level of patreon you support
the more discount you will get uh the
mail the mailchimp will get a lower
level discount the discord will get a
discount then of course the patrons will
get a deeper discount i'll go higher and
higher i'll tear it out make sure you
check that out um in the month of april
uh where were we um gingerbread big
shout out to our friend gingerbread
gingerbread made a promise been talking
to gingerbread for a while and they
delivered they brought me a gift we
shouldn't talk too much about it here
cool gift there will be some new flavors
coming in the future
um i want to give a big shout out to
somebody who's been supporting the
podcast for a long time i'm not sure if
you'll remember this person until i
described them this person was named
reggae in my head
very cool super energetic positive vibes
i made a friend that day bro
i've had a patreon supporter and a
podcast friend for a long time that day
i made a friend we uh shook hands we
hugged we looked at each other in the
highs we had a true bromance that guy
will be our friend for the rest of our
lives if we need anything in denver bro
all we have to do is type in the words
uh reggae in my head on instagram and
send a message that says bro i need this
it will happen dude that guy's got our
backs i'm sure of it uh one of the
coolest i already said these words most
positive energetic loving uh the dude's
got to be our age and he wouldn't stop
dancing around he had so much energy
bouncing around just jumping smiling
high-fiving and he was on his way to go
see a reggae concert at the end of the
show so big shout out to that guy bro it
was an honor to meet you as an honor to
actually share a moment you came at just
the right time sometimes the booth is
real busy and i don't get to really
connect with people i try but when
there's a line and i get busy i try to
connect with everybody briefly and move
you on um reggae in my head we got to
hang out it was a great time bro
thanks for repping the merch sir yeah
dude he showed up wearing a pink irie
genetics t-shirt that's great yeah
that's i saw the dude all the way from
across the show i was like he's gonna
make a loop and he'll come to us and he
sure did that was something i was gonna
bring up was how many people would be
walking past and see you their eyes lit
up and they just like we gotta get to
him that was i love that it was one of
my favorite parts of it because i was
talking with mike i was like oh somebody
watch this guy
watch this group watch watch these
people like they they would see you
and just light up and like that's where
i gotta be and so your community is
solid we love it i appreciate that thank
you for noticing and thank you to the
crew but we advertised heavily on here
so they knew to come and they knew uh
they knew what to look for and again if
we would have that menu printed on the
table they would have gotten more seeds
from us there was a lot of stuff you
guys missed i feel like we [ __ ] up i
apologize we're growing we learned we
learned a lot um
one of my favorite things about this
event this was our first time out since
the restrictions yeah like my first time
out at an event where we could actually
connect with people and feel like we're
having a good time i got to see some old
friends uh josh from la plata labs the
guy that gave us the tremendous gifts
man i am
i like that guy a lot that was the first
time i got to meet him what a what a
positive bright
just the vibes the whole everyone that
came up to the booth had
great intentions but
there's just those people that you
realize like
man i i need more of that energy in my
life yeah if we had time that night we
would have gone and hung out with josh
and gone to whatever party he was going
to that's where we would have ended up
that guy's a cool dude uh make sure you
check out la plato labs la plata seeds
that durango og is the fire uh good
friend of mine really good dude what up
josh hope you're well brother good to
see you good to reconnect the dude's got
some big plans i was like what's up he's
like i'm getting the [ __ ] out of this
country i just smiled he's always been
that way uh i hope you didn't hear that
kombucha in the voice ah there it is
again shout out to kombucha it'll stop
eventually we may not even edit that
part because clint's laughing at the
kombucha burgers i'm in man i don't you
know we're here we're here haven't i'm
i'm so happy to be on the podcast i'm so
happy to connect with your audience
because yeah it's i i'm on the discord
as tall clint so uh when you guys see
that just know like i'm i'm here with
you i i love this community and
um it's it's been such a great
thing in my life to to have people like
like jeff around the the positivity that
that i try to bring and that i receive
from jeff is
a is a
big thing in my life and it's a big
positive in my life i appreciate that
bro uh my friend cliff ravenscraft
taught me and he learned it from michael
hyatt see it's always important to
reveal your sources i'm no wizard uh
cliff ravenscraft taught me that you
become the sum of the five people which
you surround yourself with the most
uh you mike my girlfriend and probably
uh accidentally my mom is one of those
people because i like to hang out with
mama she's you know she ain't gonna be
there forever trying to lost as much
time as i can with her now your mom's a
great person she's my favorite person i
tell my girlfriend she's my favorite
person but mama you you win yeah and
babe when you hear this that's how it
goes um
you mike my mom my girl and there's one
other person i'm not sure probably
rotates you know what i mean i probably
rotate that fifth person out it's the
discord crew collectively is who that
fifth person would be uh but bro you're
one of the five people i don't surround
myself with [ __ ] because then you
become a [ __ ] uh if you surround
yourself with five ceos five
millionaires you'll figure out how to be
the ceo and the millionaire surround
yourself with five positive bad
[ __ ] you'll be you'll be a
positive bad [ __ ] hey man that's
all we try to be is just positive and
and i'm hoping that we're spreading that
especially to you guys and that you guys
will take that and try to be positive
even if it's just today i can testify
that the comments already on the
previous videos they feel the positivity
they feel the love that's what they
mention the most that's one of the
things they talk about is the positivity
and the love so we're getting it bro
we're sending it i'm going to continue
with these shout outs or this is going
to end up being a 45 minute show jaren
jeren you bad [ __ ] i got to run
into jaron from new millennium those
guys were passing out boxes of nutrients
with random prizes in all of the boxes
there was so much cool [ __ ] in there
some of it i can't mention so we'll move
forward uh big up to oni oni seeds was
there big shout out to kim blackburn
photography we've been trying to link up
for a long time brought me a great gift
uh special big hug to a good friend my
friend katie ann peterson she came out
of nowhere i don't know where she came
from i just saw her randomly she was
like right about there suddenly and i
just threw my arms up like you better
come give me a hug
before i could finish the words give me
a hug in my brain she threw her arms
like i have to go give ross to jeff a
hug hell yeah katie's a great person uh
just a good friend we've been hanging
out we ran into each other probably at
an adam dunn event years ago yeah she
was working at the uh the booth what's
the adam dunn's clothing line i can't
the hoodlam hoodlam she was working at
that booth and i met her there uh she's
been at all the events just a cool
person big energy uh big shout out to
her um yeah she hope you're well also
big shout out to priscilla the massage
lady made friends with her when i was
working with the indo expo i know her
from there uh she's always been a great
friend a good connection in the industry
so i hope she's well the massage lady
then here's where it gets fun dude the
cheesecake guy
dude did you see all those cheesecakes
at the event bro i only had one it was
delicious those cheesecakes everybody in
that place had a cheesecake everybody
said they were the most amazing [ __ ] so
big shout out to bubba's cheesecakes
super cool dude super cool i think it's
a couple a partner team whatever
business there were there was a male and
a female there so i would assume but you
should not assume uh i spoke well with
the dude that was making the cheesecakes
and serving them out super cool guy uh
we got some plans in the future
then um
how about this bad [ __ ] that's
on my list we're hanging out and i heard
the voice i heard the voice before i was
like doing something with another
customer and i heard the voice and i
looked up and i was like that is
scotty [ __ ] real what's up bro
that was fun it was fun to run into
scotty uh we took a couple of selfies
together i think for him to come over
and just be as as
gracious with his time as he is he's
he's such a i keep saying the positive
light but that's all i see out of this
community so like just his smile is is
contagious yeah he's such a cool dude
he's he brings a different energy he
definitely does and it's always positive
nothing it's it's recharging energy
that's so [ __ ] funny
also i want to give a big shout out to a
friend i haven't seen this person in a
long time i heard that possibly they
could show up i didn't know that they
would be there when they showed up i got
a big smile on my face
i am super huge friends with maddie from
the garden of wheaton i haven't seen
maddie in a long time the restrictions
got us all weird she works a lot she
lives kind of further away than she used
to we don't get to hang out that's a
really good friend of mine a good smoke
buddy a good dab buddy i love her dogs
she's a super cool friend and i heard
this voice and i looked up and i was
like i know that and there she was and
she's like rasta jeff i miss you and i
just gave her a big hug what's up maddie
i haven't seen you in so long uh we got
to talk about our dogs and growing weed
and all the [ __ ] we used to talk about
so big shout out to maddie uh mister for
a long time then uh clint kind of
covered this a moment ago but i owe a
big shout out to my friend groovy gravy
uh i call him wolf uh bro great event
everything was great i had one thing to
uh voice my concern to you honestly was
the music was too loud and my voice is
harsh uh maybe i'm too [ __ ] old but
other than the music being too loud that
event was perfect parking was great
entry was great for the vendors entry
was great for the attendees uh sales
were good the price of the booth was
fair for the amount of money that we
left with uh the ratio there worked out
paying the crew and paying for the booth
worked out well the location was
gorgeous uh
uh wolf and his staff were very
attentive when i tentative attentive
they paid a lot of attention to me when
i got there they made sure that i got to
my booth had what i need made sure i
knew where everything was they pointed
out the bathroom told me where the
cheesecake was like they covered all the
all the bases right when i got there
good communication all the way through
uh from the minute he told me the minute
i paid to the day of the event we talked
every day so uh big up to my buddy wolf
and the groovy gravy crew for throwing
in my opinion it was a perfect event
there could not have been uh there was
no hitch it couldn't have gone any
better yeah super cool crowd oh mm-hmm
just uh and and they were checking on us
throughout the event yeah yeah they come
behind the brakes hey you guys doing
okay just come by and give you the
thumbs up or thumbs down because you
didn't want to interrupt us and i just
give my thumbs up in a nod like [ __ ]
yeah we're good dude we're like meeting
people i got a bottle of water i'm
stoned everything is cool i do have to
make sure to give this disclaimer uh i
apologize to anybody i may have not put
on this list uh this is a minimal time
to show and we were blazed during the
event i wasn't spending the entire time
taking notes uh if you're a breeder a
consumer a friend a member of the iv
army and i didn't mention you here is
your fist bump love you bro thank you
for being there thanks for the vibes
thank you for the support and i'm sorry
i didn't write you down you know how it
goes dude
um
we've got a couple of cool things we
want to talk about now we just did the
bet awards here and shouted out
everybody in the community
special thanks to mike
mike isn't here
mike lost his voice uh being such a
customer a good customer service
representative telling people about the
strains uh the lines the stuff he lost
his voice by 2 p.m he still thugged it
out the rest of the day shout out to
mike also shout out to clint for being a
badass i call him security he carries
[ __ ] he stands there and looks stuff but
he's learning a lot on how to help
people that's not really clint forte
he's not the customer service-y uh sales
rep guy but we're getting him there i'm
working on these strains man you've got
there's so many intricacies in these
strains that i am
that's that's why i say i i'm happy to i
love growing weed and i just don't know
the nuances so when people are asking
questions it's like well
boy
golden goat's a daybreaker right right
yeah yeah that's that's the answer most
of the time but and half the time they
just want to talk to me anyway because i
know
like i've been growing these plants for
longer than i should admit so i've got
relationships with the golden goat plan
what the strawberry fields plan what the
tangie plan i know those the p91 i know
them i've grown them so many times but i
know what they're going to do like if
you cuss at it i know how it's going to
react if you feed it straight uria i
might know how it's going to react like
i know what they're going to do because
i messed with them so much and i've got
so much data from my my crowd that i
know what they're going to do so i can
tell you about them so much it's like
talking about my own kids you do you're
just the babysitter you i'm sorry to
interrupt no do it bro you do get a lot
of data from your crowd yes like that is
such an important part of your community
that maybe they don't understand how
how much that helps in in every way oh
yeah all the feedback they send if they
say this one smelled like blueberries or
this one smelled like feet i don't take
just one person's word for it but a lot
of people will message me and then i
start compiling a database like uh the
convergence will say a lot of people say
it smells like uh spicy fabric softener
sheets or spicy dryer sheets or
something like that and when i hear the
word spicy multiple times that's
definitely an accurate description if
one guy says rotten mangoes i won't
include that but if two or three people
say smell like rotten mangoes i will say
there's a phenotype that could smell
like rotten mangoes you just got to
include the data but data is also in the
weed community you got to like
exclude and be really filtery with data
that's why i love and hate the internet
forums because people can type whatever
they want
yeah data you guys thank you for the
data i do love it i want to give a big
shout out now i covered the crew i
covered the people we met there ah
here's where i want to go you guys on a
previous episode i did read a message
about making autoflower seeds and i said
that autoflowers are not for me
i have nothing against them they're just
not what i do i do photo period plants
i've been breeding developing my lines
for a long time i don't want to re-learn
how to breed autos i do know a guy that
does it he calls himself daz he's got a
little company called night owl seeds i
just happen to have a booth right next
to our buddy daz at the event and he may
have passed me a bag of some f1's i
can't tell you what they are right now i
don't know if i'm allowed to divulge
those details however i was given a bag
of seeds they are labeled
golden goat cross ii something else f1
these seeds will be photo periods um i'm
going to grow them i'm going to find a
keeper female then i may return that
female keeper to our friend daz my point
is you guys demanded there are
autoflowers of some irie genetic stuff i
sent a clip of that video to our friend
daz daz has replied there are
autoflowers in the making there will be
some irie owl some night irish some
night army some irie owls some night owl
irie iriegenetics collabs coming up in
the future stay tuned it's going to take
a long time you guys um
do not rush this project honestly this
could take at least a year and a half to
get we got to get to at least i think in
my understanding we got to get to the f5
or f6 before we've got reliable autos so
that could take a year and a half two
years to get there but you auto nerds it
is coming stay
tuned something i really wanted to talk
about at the event
um i saw a lot of breeders with
different approaches to customer service
that's the polite way to say it
don't let seed sellers intimidate you
and try to take your money without
giving you the product that you are
satisfied with and the information you
need to successfully grow that product
um i love talking about my seeds because
i made them i know the details i know
the the minutia is that the word i think
the nuances of each plant i know the
grandparents i know the parents of the
seeds i'm selling you yeah i know the
parents of those plants i'm selling you
i've probably researched their great
grandparents and their
great-grandparents on both sides i know
what i'm giving you i know what i'm
offering i'm really proud of what i've
made i'm not shy about it because it's
like talking about my kids i get to talk
about little jimmy's in soccer practice
and [ __ ] i don't have a jimmy i'm
just making [ __ ] up but i can talk about
i do have a jimmy but not a kid named
jimmy
i might not even edit that
i like it we're live to drive
but um i really love talking about so if
a seed seller isn't excited to talk to
you about his stuff to tell you details
about it
that makes me skeptical that makes me
and i'm not calling anybody out i'm not
saying any names i'm saying when you go
to the booth there should be info there
should be details there should be
conversation there should be a smile uh
if a dude's got a bad look on his face
that bad look maybe in his seeds uh if
he's got bad energy that may be in the
seeds also keep in mind we've been
standing there since 10 or 11 today and
talked to a lot of people so give us a
grain of salt and also a bottle of water
if you've got one maybe a dab if you can
but um the sellers should have info you
should get all the details you need they
shouldn't [ __ ] you you should feel
comfortable shouldn't feel rushed
shouldn't feel like you're bothering
anybody by asking questions
get the info that you need don't let the
sellers intimidate you don't let them
just take your money don't let them rush
you
something that i i talked about this a
couple times i'm proud of myself for
doing this and i've done this now at
multiple events people will approach my
booth i'm approachable i'm talkable very
they they like me they see the people
around me i'm giving hugs i'm taking
pictures they want to talk to me it's
cool i get it i love it um i invite that
come say hi come say what's up if you're
at an event you tell me later i saw you
and didn't say hi i wanted to message
you and let you know bro come high five
me and fist bump me i was there so a
couple of times this has happened at my
booth people have come up to me and
they're like hey do you have this cross
one time they were asking for roadkill
skunk or something super skunky and i
don't i didn't offer exactly what they
were looking for the guy had money
folded up in his hand like he's like
looking for the skunk you got it here's
my money it was going to be that quick i
did not have what he was looking for
that day and i knew that my friend who
had a booth right across the way was
offering a very similar product and i
said dude i don't have that but that
booth right there has got it go over
there and say hey rosta jeff told me to
come over here and ask you for this you
may not have it on the menu but i know
he's got it because he's my friend he
gave me a pack of it earlier he'd love
to make your money off of it just just
ask him for it he went over there and he
bought those seeds that he wanted i
could have taken his 300 for that pack
of seeds and given him
some seeds
but next year when he needs seeds he
would have been like man that guy said
this was skunk and it smells like
strawberries [ __ ] that guy now he's got
two new friends he's got me he can rely
on to say i don't offer that but that
guy does he made friends with me and the
other breeder and now the right guy's
got the money the right guy's got the
right seeds and maybe hopefully somebody
will walk up into another breeder and
say hey do you have something that
smells like watermelons and strawberries
and grows real tall and makes good hash
and they'll go oh you should go get
strawberry starburst from ross to jeff
that's the one that you need hopefully
the caramel works that way at this event
somebody asked me if i had sour diesel
bx3
i just laughed and shook my head i was
like go over there that guy that guy
right there he's got exactly that on the
menu it's 300 a pack but it's right over
there go get it and he walked over there
and he bought it he's got exactly what
he wants i didn't sell him oranges you
know what i mean he's gonna grow and
he's gonna get sour diesel he's not
gonna grow and get [ __ ] oranges and
berries like my product probably would
have given him i feel good about that so
uh trust the breeders pick up the vibe i
i kind of mentioned
that
um this is the way i describe it we're
like bands it's like having a reggae
band a bluegrass band a death metal band
a techno band a [ __ ] norwegian
[ __ ] folk metal band all lined up
next to each other one of them will
speak to you one of them will definitely
make you walk away that's a lot of how
the booths are you'll get vibes from all
of them if you're into reggae you'll
come to my booth if you're into
norwegian death metal you'll go to that
booth over there if you're into mariachi
music you might go see my boy mace what
up mace uh but you're gonna find the
vibe that you roll with and you're gonna
go there find the one that works for you
get what you want trust your breeder be
able to contact them maybe that's
contradictory because i get 3000 emails
a day and i don't answer them all but b
try to be able to contact them have
somebody who will answer questions that
supports the community doesn't just suck
up your money all right
this part here clint you're ready to
talk about this part on my notes this is
going to be the highlight the uh encore
of the show here yeah dude this is this
is my favorite part well let's uh you
want to tell me you want me to tell them
so i got to help jeff this last season i
do an outdoor grow in a greenhouse and
so
uh i was able to help
uh
with the moon tower
and oh man just it rolls off my tongue i
love it
he set help with the moon tower clint
was standing in the room when king
solomon was shaken to spread the pollen
onto the pre-98 bubba kush female in
clint's greenhouse
so clint was more than involved clint
was [ __ ] right there next to me as
pollination was happening clint was just
as involved in that greenhouse as i was
clint made the moon tower seeds right
alongside me so
i did the selection i chose the plants
to put in the room but clint uh was at
that greenhouse as much if not more than
me doing the hard laborous work
i was the the manager the guy in charge
i got dirty i [ __ ] got some sneakers
dirty out there got a little bit of a
sunburn in the greenhouse i got spiders
on my legs uh but dude you did a lot of
work clint was heavily involved in
making the moon tower so it was fun
watching and a couple other strains out
there also
it was really fun watching clint sell
seeds that he made you could just see
him like ah yeah he couldn't he didn't
feel comfortable telling people at the
time but i could see he's like i made
this moon tower back here by and i could
just see him like proud and excited
about it it was every time i heard moon
tower i knew
those came from me i i have a hand in
this and it made me feel spectacular and
it still does because now i know going
forward i'm going to see so many moon
tower pictures on our discord
and it's
it's just one of the the small pieces
of this industry that i get to be a part
of and i loved it it was and so as
as the moon tower goes out and as more
gets grown i mean
it's a rise to bubba kush yeah it's just
i'm
so proud to have something to contribute
to the community
you feel that guys uh dude thank you you
did a good job man it's a great it's a
great strain the seeds made it the
plants didn't die yeah i look forward to
doing it again next year oh man i hope
you guys are picking up your moon tower
this year uh you know outdoor grows are
coming very soon and this plant
i got to grow the bubba kush and i got
to grow the horizon and boy what a great
combination the bubba kush looked
amazing smells amazing
uh really all the plants that i got to
deal with this year were amazing but
that bubba kush i'm super proud of
you did a good job bro and that bubba
kush is awesome people have forgotten
about the bubba kush that old gassy
coffee stinky earthy smell people moved
on to the candy uh the the [ __ ] donut
smells the cake smells i predict the
kush and the skunks
will be back uh good job bro good job on
the breeding on the moon tower it's fun
watching you sell seeds that you made it
was fun man what a great event just
everything about it i'm having such a
good time being part of this community
yeah and it's fun watching you
um some people at the event knew who
everybody was when masonic walked by
their heads would blow up when oni
walked by their head would come back
together and re-explode jj would walk by
and they'd [ __ ] their pants like all the
top brit not all but a lot of the top
breeders were there some of them were
there just hanging out didn't even have
a booth i missed duke diamond what the
[ __ ] is wrong with me i did not give
duke diamond a shout out yet i should uh
i need a southern boy ass whippin for
not mentioning my buddy duke diamond
what up duke i love you bro i hope
you're well i got to hang out with duke
got to say hi to duke diamond uh freedom
is great brother it's good to see you
back rocking the events but there were a
lot of uh vendors there or breeders
there that weren't even vending just
hanging out for the party because it was
such a cool community event it's fun
watching clint have no idea who a lot of
these people are i'm like that's duke
diamond and he's like who and i'm like
that guy made [ __ ] dominion skunk bro
come on okay he's like why does that guy
have a long line over there and i'm like
oh you mean capulator that's right
[Laughter]
yeah you mean cap the guy that wears a
mask to every event when nobody knows
what the [ __ ] he looks like and he works
by himself yeah he was really kicking
ass i saw him over there in the corner
so big shout out to a calculator big
shout out to duke diamond big shout out
to all of the breeders that i missed i
know there are several that i missed i'm
trying to look down the rows i'm like oh
[ __ ] who am i missing that was mace and
oni and then [ __ ] uh clearwater and
then uh new millennium and then us and
then daz and then oh nbg nothing but gas
what up t big shout out all right guys i
have to stop trying to do shout outs
because i'm just gonna [ __ ] forget
somebody i'm gonna feel like a real
piece of [ __ ] if you were there thank
you for the love thank you for the
support if you came up to the booth if
you just wave from across the way big
shout out to kurt by the way all the way
across the way uh big shout out to
everybody shout out to the crew for
helping me out uh shout out to zara for
trying to make it for hyping me up she
couldn't make it that day i wanted you
guys to get to hang out but uh she
couldn't make it to the event next time
she will be there showing some love dude
we have been going for 40 minutes i said
i wanted to knock out a 45-minute show
um i'd like to give you the opportunity
if you've got any more left to say you
got a hot mic in front of you and you
look [ __ ] great uh you want to tell
the world anything that's on your mind
uh let's keep spreading positivity let's
keep spreading love uh
very pro ukraine and uh
just
i i loved seeing everybody today and i
know that uh
going forward like this i'm i'm so
excited for this grow season like i said
i do an outdoor growth so all my stuff
is just seasonal and i am so excited to
do it again this year this will be 10
years of me growing
and
uh
it's
you know i don't i don't know all the
players in the game but boy i appreciate
y'all that's part of why i love hanging
out with you you kind of humble me you
balance me because
i'm caught up in all the players in the
game and all this stuff and you just
walk in you're like what what the [ __ ]
work needs to be done dude i'm like oh
hang up some shirts and do some stuff
you're like sure and i get to go
schmooze and be the rock star couldn't
do the rock star life without the full
band you guys are the band thank you for
letting me be the lead singer i'll let
you be the lead singer i'll play the
bass how's that we'll let mike do the
guitar we're set sounds good bro sounds
good all right um
would you like any social media
following
you know i am at tall clint on discord
as well as
instagram and twitter there you go don't
use them a whole bunch you guys i love
you i just not a big internet guy if you
want to see a picture of a big sweaty
dude with the beard at the gym
clint's the guy to fight i do that he is
the guy bro thank you for being here
thank you for making this a fun ass
episode without you it would have just
been me rambling about an event that
wasn't
worth rambling about by myself so the
company was great i appreciate it thanks
for having me on man i had a great time
and uh i look forward to seeing your
comments in the youtube because you guys
need to help us with that like subscribe
comment do me a favor please because
that's going to grow our community and
the more we grow
everybody's growing together we're
trying to get to 10 000 subscribers
we're almost there big shout out to
everybody who has subscribed if you're
listening if you're on spotify or
stitcher apple podcast wherever you are
if you're not watching on youtube i do
invite you to check out the youtube
videos just click subscribe watch one
video you may enjoy what you are seeing
this episode clint join me he's not here
for every episode it's a good time
having the two mic set up i'm really
glad i did this i'm glad the
restrictions are over got to get you
back got to get white mike on the show
if you want to be on the show you got a
cool thing to talk about send me a
message maybe we can get you right there
on mic number two i'm really bored with
zoom meetings i'm kind of over it come
be on the show be here in person don't
forget about the merch sale going up on
the patreon in april uh there'll be
discount codes coupon codes get that
merch before it runs out i'm going to
blow it all out you guys it's going to
go on sale dirty cheap get it the [ __ ]
out of here so i can replenish get new
stuff if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns i'd
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me that feedback that
positive constructive criticism or if
you got some [ __ ] to talk let me know i
could take it i'm not shy
if you want to throw me a couple of
bucks if you feel like the show is
educational informative or entertaining
all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart anything else is on the
website there's a grow help tab on the
website there's a patreon link there's a
discord link there's a merch link
everything you could possibly imagine is
on the website at iregenetics.com
once again big thanks to clint for
coming and helping me out big thanks to
mike for helping at the event big fist
bump to my bro a big thanks to you guys
for watching i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my buddy
curbside gardens and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you