[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 73 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation if you're a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're
a cannabis activist or even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you I'm your host rosta Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always I
need to send a huge thank you shout out
to the Mystic Roots band for letting me
use their music on the show huge thanks
to cat CP and the entire Mystic Roots
crew what's up guys I'm going to turn
that music down well I'm going to turn
it down a lot it's kind of loud there we
go trying to get the party started uh
speaking of getting the party started
big shout out to my friends de's uh Roxy
let's see who else is on there I'm gonna
check on something real quick I'll talk
more about this later maybe shout out to
Kenny shout out to Cody and shout out to
uh Cody another Cody two Cody and Roxy
also I don't know if I said
that uh those are some friends of mine
that are watching me record this show
live right now on bong TV they can't
hear the show but they are watching me
record it on my webcam uh I was in the
chat room getting pumped up just getting
a little energy before the show taking a
couple dabs and I thought why turn off
the cam why not just let those guys
watch so when you guys hear this uh this
is the episode that you're watching that
you watched past tense all right anyway
uh shout out to the Bon TV crew there
are no ads for this episode you guys
we're not even going to do any
commercials we're going to get right
down to business I've been promising you
guys a uh lesson on how to set up a
Perpetual grow and I actually took a lot
of time and figured out how to do that I
think I've got it figured out for
you uh man my arms are a little bit
rubbery I'm working through my paperwork
here
I played my drums for about uh I don't
know a good solid hour I beat the [ __ ]
out of those drums and I needed that
that was kind of nice I haven't played
the drums in quite a while I needed to
make some space where the drums were for
uh some grow things of course but then I
had that space available set up a big uh
I'm just talking about the drum set on
the podcast you guys I'm sorry uh anyway
I'm going to tell you more about it I
started I've got an eight a 10 a 12 uh
14 16inch Toms 22in Kick Drum uh 14inch
snare drum I just to the [ __ ] out of
that kit all day today well it was like
an hour it felt like all day I'm going
to quit rambling I'm going to find the
notes here that are in my phone and we
will talk about this grow lesson that I
wrote for you let's see all right I
found it we'll get to the point here you
guys I'm super dabbed out I'm just
trying to talk through the dabest here
for a minute I find my way through these
clouds shout out to the Mystic root crew
here we go uh so episode 73 scheduling a
Perpetual flow uh when you're scheduling
a Perpetual grow a few things you need
to keep in mind are things like You're
plant count if you're in a uh a medical
State like Colorado where I am you have
a plant count and you have to stay
within that to be legal this will be a
good way to help you stay within your
plant count and produce the amount of
medicine or recreational Cannabis you
need to supply
yourself so that's something you need to
think about uh how much herb do you
require to keep yourself supplied
without trying to be stingy without
trying to keep a bunch of to make a
bunch of money how much do you
realistically want to grow and how often
do you need to grow it going to be
something we're going to talk about in a
minute also we will talk about how much
space it's going to take that's what
will really dictate your grow uh a lot
of the stuff is covered in previous
episodes you guys but we're going to go
back over a lot of it and we will uh by
the end you will have a Perpetual go
grow going if you follow this uh I guess
it's a recipe I wrote here
anyway holy [ __ ] excuse my throat
clearing there uh this Perpetual lesson
is going to be based on a uh on one
1,000 watt flowering light this covers
about a 4x4 or a 5x5 square foot area so
we're trying to create a Perpetual grow
that suits your needs if you're using
more lights simply multiply this method
by however many lights you're using or
however you uh seem necessary if you
have questions email me grow from
yourart hotmail.com and we'll help
adjust this recipe for your grow room uh
I'll tell you about my Perpetual grow I
run a four light setup and I fill uh the
whole light area with a set of plants
and harvest one light every two weeks so
here's where you need to make a decision
on your Perpetual setup you need to
decide if you want to start a crop under
a light and finish the entire crop and
then have another uh set of plants ready
as soon as that's done for you uh so
that as soon as you chop down that room
that light of plants you have plants
that were in veg in another room as soon
as they're done do you want to refill
the entire room or do you want to kind
of stagger it a little
bit um I think it's a little in my
opinion I like having a Perpetual
instead of having a whole bunch of herb
to harvest all at one time it can re be
a really daunting task in my opinion to
try to harvest uh four lights worth of
cannabis all at
once Gosh guys excuse my throat clearing
that'll go away here after a couple of
couple of minutes I hope all right so if
you're working with one strain where was
I let's see uh yeah you need to decide
if you want to start the whole crop and
run the whole thing where was I you want
to stagger your crops so you have a
harvest every 30 days or 2 weeks uh if
you're working with one strain uh that's
a lot easier if you've got multiple
strains try to get
strains that uh you're going to have to
time it so try to get strains that are
all about 8 to nine weeks that's your
ideal uh your deal ideal setup foret
Perpetual cycle under one light so uh
our main goal here is to have the rooms
moving constantly with as little
downtime as possible to keep your
production at its maximum without any
interruptions uh that way you don't have
any interruptions in your medicine so I
told you guys let's see I talk a little
bit about my for light my personal grow
uh is a Perpetual setup I harvest one
light every two weeks like I was saying
I'd rather trim one light worth of buds
which for me is a pound than four lights
which would be four pounds easily
sometimes it's pound and a half
sometimes it's more just depends on what
trins I'm running so I'm harvesting
every two weeks it means that every two
weeks I'm cutting clones I'm doing trans
transplants uh I'm putting taking clones
out of the cloner putting them into cups
and I'm harvesting every two weeks so uh
I have four flowering lights in my
flowering area I have two lights in my
vegging area and I have a separate light
for my moms and clones uh I have about
every 14 days I cut 12 clones after 14
days those clones go into cups and go
under a light in my mom and clone area
uh this could be like a T5 or a metal
highlight light or even an LED if you're
into that uh some uh those plants that I
cut will stay in the cups for about 2
weeks before they're transplanted into
seven gallon pots and you guys I'm going
to give you a lot of detail about this I
know I'm going kind of fast right now
I'm giving you a setup on mine and then
I'll get into a lot of detail in a
minute so I can fit 12 SG pots under my
two veg lights comfortably that gives
them enough space and keep in mind some
of these are uh we got [ __ ] all the way
from one week up to eight weeks old so
the ones on the far end there they're
real little so we can squish those
together and the other ones over there
on that end are a little larger so they
need more space I can fit 12 of
them uh once the plants are in the seven
gallon pots they'll hang out in the
bedroom for like 30 to 45 days depending
on the strain uh if you're going to set
up this Perpetual it'll probably work
out to exactly 8 weeks if you do this
right uh I use large pots so I can keep
big plants and keep my plant count down
like I was talking about earlier
Colorado is limited by plant counts so
getting as much from each plant is
important as much as you can from each
plant is important so I have four sets
of seven gallon pots under my veg lights
and I would have plants in veg for 2
four six and eight weeks and the plants
that have been in veg for 8 weeks will
go into the flower room on week nine and
more plants will be dropped into seven
gallon pots everything will be slid over
four spaces and the empty spaces I just
made will be replaced and it'll be
Tetris all right over the left so that
it's right by the door to the next room
so like I said every two weeks I'm
harvesting a light I'm cutting more
clones I'm putting clones into cups
putting cups into pots and I'm keeping
the cycle moving while maintaining a uh
Pest Management regimen uh I'm
lollipopping these plants I'm doing
pruning uh it's a lot of work to do in
there guys you can't just slack off but
it's a lot of work and it pays off every
two weeks I've got a pound of herb
harvested for myself every two weeks if
I do this properly so that's basically
my setup there uh you guys might not
have four lights so let's talk about
getting your Perpetual plan I got to
reach over and plug this phone in all
right so uh to have a per Perpetual grow
you'll need a solid mother plant or a
source of reliable clones I don't want
to rely on somebody else for clones I
would definitely recommend
keeping a mother plant if you have a
mother plant maybe if I haven't talked
thoroughly enough about mother plants
I'm going to write a note right now I
need a
pen I'll write a note to talk about
mother plants in the future and then we
can kind of talk about keeping a mom
that'll be a whole another episode
writing it down mother plant episode
boom I know it takes me a long time to
write but I rather be able to read it
later there we go mother plants I wrote
that so have a good mother
plant uh I'll talk about selecting a mom
I'll go WI depth on that for you if I
haven't so for this mother plant uh for
the mother plant you need a light cycle
that stays on in a vegetative cycle I
recommend of course the 18 on and six
off or you can try 195 if that works for
you um I do that because I see the
plants growing and it keeps any sativas
from autoflowering I've had some sativas
that like to Autoflower if the light
cycle changes just a little and that 195
that extra hour will keep them from
doing that so you can keep your mother
plants and your clones and these cups on
the same cycle if you can if you have
one light you can fit if you have one
good siiz fluorescent light you can fit
your cloner and a bunch of cups with
clones in there underneath that T5 and
you can probably fit a good siiz mother
plant underneath there also if you do it
right I know two of those T5 fixtures
would definitely do it all right so uh
this uh for this example Mike and I were
talking and uh of course I had to ask
Mike for some help because I was getting
stuck so shout out to mikee for helping
me um he came up with the idea to use a
uh two 5x5 grow ttin because that's when
he met me I was growing in grow tents he
learned a lot from those grow tents so
we're using two of those 5x5 grow tins
if you don't have grow ttin you can use
a bedroom or whatever and you can divide
it into two spaces as long as your
flowering space is totally dark during
the night cycle you'll be okay I can't
stress enough how important it is to
have a totally Dark Night cycle in your
flowering room okay so we're going to
use two 5x 510 right and you can use a
bedroom uh you can divide it out so one
is a flowering Hut I said that right
one's a veg space one's a flowering Hut
all right so we've got the one flowering
space it's a 5 by5 with 1,000 watt light
in there our other room is a 5x5 room or
tent uh that'll be our veg in mom space
all right so it's actually going to take
a couple of weeks to get your Perpetual
grow flowing and productive but once it
starts the flow should run perfectly if
you plan ahead and stay on top of your
chores don't get lazy don't get
complacent you have to stay in there and
be on top of things so in my example
we're going to set up a a Perpetual grow
to harvest one large Plant every two
weeks and your goal is 4 ounces per
plant with this method so we're going to
put one sgon pot under the light every
two weeks we need to start with a mother
plant or some clones so in this case
we'll start with a healthy mom uh you
should have your mom's uh your mom rooms
or Huts built and running before we even
take the first clone for the Perpetual
grow so you've got your rooms happy and
your mother plant is nice and healthy
now we cut clones to start our Cycles I
don't know if you're using like rapid
rooters or if you're using rock wool
cubes or if you're using an easy cloner
but either way two weeks is your your
due date for these clones they've got to
be rooted and ready to rock in two weeks
if you're not proficient in cloning I
would recommend cutting these clones
early so take some practice get some
practice and get some clones going so
we've got the 5x5 Hut that's one 1,000
watt flowering light and 5x5 area so
this is what would happen on week one we
would cut clones and let them root and
if for this one light situation we only
need one clone out of this whole setup
so cut some clones and hopefully in 14
days one of those clones is
rooted so now week two you don't have
much to do except make sure the Clones
are rooted and happy so week three of
the Perpetual cycle
uh you're going to take more
clones okay first you have to I guess
take the Clones out of the cloning area
put them into cups and then you're also
going to cut more clones for the next
run and you're only going to need one
keeper again so those clones that you
just put into cups You're going to let
them go for 14 more days and then you'll
just pick the best one and the Clones
that you just put in the cloner in 14
days you're going to pick the best one
of those all right so we only need one
at a time to survive but cut extras you
guys cuz it's always better to have some
to choose from
so week four week four is another chill
week but make sure the cups and the
Clones are happy and as healthy as you
can make them and the mother plant you
need so oh I didn't add that in here you
guys we're going to need to make love to
the mother plant every once in a while
you got to get in there and trim that
sexy [ __ ] up so I guess taking clones
every two weeks you'll be able to do
that something I should have made a note
of all right week five week five is
where we start to get busy you guys we
need to put the Clones into cups of dirt
we need to cut more
clones uh we need to
uh we only need one keeper like I said
every two weeks but I would take a few
extras and choose from the best I wrote
that down a lot of times uh the plants
that we cut that we put into cups two
weeks ago will now go into seven gallon
pots and go under the veg lights if
you're in that 5x5 Hut you should have
plenty of room for your mother plant a
little bit of clones a couple of Cups
and four seven gallon pots it it'll work
trust me so in week five uh we're going
to put One S gallon pot under the veg
lights and that's going to sit there for
eight weeks you guys but now you have
your first veg plant in veg you're
showing some progress you got that one
little itty bitty plant in a seven
gallon pot and it's only taking five
weeks so week six is kind of another
chill week but you have to make sure all
your plants are looking good cuz now
you're really setting the pace for your
productivity don't forget to watch for
bugs uh start doing any pruning and
training that you want to do make sure
you're getting good on your cloning game
you've had a lot of practice by now so
just start perfecting [ __ ] start really
paying attention to details now you have
a rhythm going start paying attention to
things let's move into week seven I'm
doing pretty good I'm at about 16 uh
yeah after a couple of edits here we
should be hit about 15 minutes so week
seven um for week seven we need to put
the Clones out of the cloning area into
cups and then we need to cut more clones
remember guys we just need one but cut
several uh then we need to put another
clone into a 7 gallon pot and then that
goes under that veg light and now we
have two of our first four plants under
the veg light and the first one has
seven more weeks or no it's got uh yeah
we're going on odd numbers right so it
would have six more weeks to cook before
it's going to go the first one's got a
few more weeks to cook before it's going
to go into the bedroom and this one's
now got eight so the other ones got six
yeah because we're going to be
harvesting every two weeks so week eight
is another week to focus on training and
pruning and plant health and keeping
your mother plant happy checking for
bugs going in there and cleaning up the
bottoms of all the plants that are in
the uh vegging area there's stuff to do
every week even though we're not doing
the big cycle on the even numbered weeks
so week nine I'm sure you're catching on
by now take the Clones out of the cloner
put them into cups cut new clones put a
clone from a cup into a seven gallon pot
and into the veg area so now you've got
three seven gallon pots under the veg
light uh one of them is getting big and
bushy by now and it's almost time to
flower that [ __ ] uh if you want to do
any topping or anything or any pruning
to it now is a good time
uh week 10 is another off week but it's
a good time to check for bugs uh we've
been going at it for 10 weeks now so
check all of your equipment out uh clean
up all your fans uh make sure the floor
is clean just get in there and clean
everything up on week 10 week 11 here we
go again we're going to put clones into
cups we're going to cut more clones
we're going to put our favorite clone
into a sgon pot and put that into the
veg area so now you have got four s
gallon pots in your room is full and we
will flower out our first plant in 2
weeks and I know that sounds like a long
time it's going to take us 13 weeks to
flower our first plant before we even
start flowering our first plant but
trust me once you get this rhythm going
it's totally going to be worth it so
week 12 this is the last week before you
start flowering plants make sure your
Bloom room is ready have that 5x5
flowering room cleaned up sparkly make
sure the floor is clean make sure the
ceiling is
clean clean it all clean it again even
if you did go in there and clean it
again and then after that clean it one
more time and then inspect it one more
time and find what you missed because
there's something that you missed do you
have a fire extinguisher near your grow
do you have a smoke detector near your
grow those are probably two things you
forgot about I don't want to see your
home I don't even want to say what could
happen you know what what I'm getting at
right so get a smoke detector put it
near your grow get a fire extinguisher
and put it outside of the room so that
in the worst case scenario you don't
have to run in there to get the fire
extinguisher to put the [ __ ] fire out
have it outside of the room yeah just do
that for me please so your room is ready
you're ready the plants are ready week
13 here we go you guys this is when it
gets fun this is the first day we start
the flowering cycle today you get to
move that largest plant into the
flowering room and begin the bloom phase
and now in 8 to 9 weeks hopefully 60
days we'll have buds to harvest and then
every two weeks after that you can
Harvest if you keep this rhythm going
properly um I'm serious about the
scheduling of this if you [ __ ] this up
you will be way behind and everything
will fall apart because you will miss a
beat and you won't know where to jump
back on it's like playing a really fast
song and once you jumped off that beat
it's going to take a minute to recover
and your lungs and your smoking habits
are definitely going to notice so check
it out week 13 move that big plant that
you've been working on that's been in
veg for8 weeks now that plant was in veg
for 8 weeks in a cup for two weeks and
in a cloner for two other weeks 12 weeks
of life and now you're just now moving
that sucker into the flowering room so
after you move that into the flowering
room feed it its flowering nutrients you
got to feed it flowering nutrients we've
talked about uh what to feeding stuff on
week one so feed that plant it's
flowering
NES uh then you have to you guessed it
take a clone out of the cloner put it
into a cup cut more clones put your
favorite cup into a sgon pot and replace
that seven gallon pot that you just
moved into the flowering room with a
fresh pot and a little baby plant in it
so now you've got one plant in flower
and you should have four plants in veg
now our goal is to keep this moving and
add a plant into the room every two
weeks you'll need to cut clones put
clones into cups put a cup into a seven
gallon pot drag a fresh plant into the
flowering room every 2 weeks and
eventually you will also be harvesting a
plant every 2 weeks if you're running a
56 to 60 day
strain yes if that went right that means
that every two weeks you'll be pulling
off about a quar pound of herb for
yourself if you do this properly it will
become a small parttime job for yourself
to maintain this but the more work and
love you put into it the better your
product will be I promise you some
people are like how is your herb so good
and I'm like I go in the grow room for
hours every day I touch every single
plant with my hands look on the bottoms
of the leaves I walk in there in the
morning and I'm like which plant haven't
I spent enough time with and I pick one
and I turn the leaves upside down and I
look at the bottoms of the leaves and
make sure there are no bugs and I look
around the room and I just stare into
the room like an old guy staring off the
porch into nothing but I'm looking
around the room to see if there's a
problem that maybe I didn't miss or
maybe if there's something I could tweak
to make the air flow a little bit better
to control the temperature and the
humidity just a little bit better when
I'm away I don't know so be in there do
some work keep on top of it I don't even
know what the [ __ ] started that R I'm
sorry so after 8 weeks it'll be time to
harvest that first plant that you put
into your flowering room uh it may need
a few extra days for the plant to finish
uh just squeeze that plant in there for
the last few days or if you have this
available put that plant in its own dark
room for two days before you harvest it
and it will kind of DSE up the buds and
I think it'll kind of make it a little
more resinous I think it does make it
kind of more dense is the word for it it
tightens up a little bit that 48 Hours
of dark kind of shocks the plant and
makes it kick out the last bit of resin
that it can put out it's getting freaked
out it knows it's going to
die so now you should have a full
Perpetual setup that should yield 3 to 5
ounces of herb every two weeks and if
you do this right you can keep your
plant count down to like 10 or 15 if you
only have one mother plant and you get
good at cloning because you're going to
have uh four in flower and then you're
going to have four in your veg area
that's eight plants then you've got your
mother plant and then you've got that
one that's in a cup that's uh 10 plants
right there if you take a couple of
extra clones and have a couple of extra
mother plants or whatever you know
that's going to put you up near 15 or 20
but dude you're pulling a quarter pound
of herb with 10 plants in your house and
you're using two maybe three lights
doing this see that's going to work it's
going to work for you guys uh if you
have any questions let me know so your
other option here would be to veg all
four of your plants for 30 to 45 days
and throw them all into the flowering
room and it's a good idea but like I was
saying when it comes to harvesting all
that pot you're hopefully going to pull
off a pound of weed here you guys maybe
a pound and a quarter oh my God I just
burped that root beer right into the mic
I'm sorry rude rude rude Rockstar uh
you're hoping to pull a pound and a quar
pound and a half a herb off that I would
rather trim you know 3 to five ounces
every two weeks and give my wrist a
break than be at it trimming for two
weeks straight because it gets crazy you
start cutting down plants and they're
all ripe at the same time and so you got
[ __ ] drying all at the same time you go
into panic mode you got to trim this
whole pound of herb uh I trim usually
myself and one maybe two other people at
the table cuz it just gets crowded and
it gets loud and I'd rather keep it
peaceful and have less people here just
kind of quiet for my head uh so that's
why I do the Perpetual grow it's a
little bit better and then it also makes
you feel like something's happening
instead of waiting 60 days for that damn
crop to finish you can oh it's cool I've
got one in two weeks so it doesn't feel
like it's so long of course the next
crop is 60 days but since I started one
40 days ago and then uh what's 40 - 14 I
[ __ ] myself picking a weird number
like that but since I picked one seven
weeks ago uh and started it then I'm
going to have one in two weeks and then
I'm going to have one in two weeks after
that you know I thought I had I'm
rambling because I took a lot of fat
dabs and this yeah anyway uh so if you
choose to run them all at one time you
should have plants in that vedro ready
to flower as soon as that room is empty
so you're going to have to to keep a
mother plant and then four pots uh four
seven gallon pots for about 8 weeks so
you'll need clones for two weeks cups
for two weeks you'll need four of them
four clones four cups uh two weeks each
and then you throw those into the seven
gallon pots and let those go for eight
weeks and then when you chop that other
room you throw those plants in there
that same
day that's the only way to keep it going
if you want to do it all at once or you
can do two plants every uh 30 days if
that's easier for you if you'd rather
have a half a pound of herb every 30
days you could do that as this is
completely adjustable this was just the
best I could come up with since I don't
know your garden I hope you find it
useful I hope you put it to use I hope
you start pulling off somewhere between
3 and 5 ounces for yourself or your
patients every two weeks that's a good
supply of medicine for you if you're
smoking more than that uh well I can't
judge smoke more than that [ __ ] it I'm
not even going to try to try to judge
you for it you might have some reason
you might be uh you might have hardcore
dab syndrome like I do all right you
guys I've been going for close to 30
minutes I really appreciate you guys
listening to the show I've been taunting
you and teasing you about this Perpetual
grow episode you can see why it took me
a minute it took me 13 weeks to get to
the flowering cycle I feel like I went
really quickly with all of the stuff
that I wrote If I skipped anything
please correct me let me
know um you pay so much more attention
when I do like a 30-minute episode so
I'm going to start w wrapping up the
show like a fat joint you guys thanks a
lot for listening I will be back uh next
Monday with a fresh episode for you we
are getting close to 100 and I'm getting
excited thanks for all your support
don't forget to check out our sponsors
the Rocky Mountain worm company hro
indoor growing supplies and also check
out Nature's green remedies.com for all
your seeds needs if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you've got a product that you'd like
me to review all you've got to do is
send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you all
of the information that you do need uh
now that the show is over you guys if
you're listening on iTunes go to the
iTunes Store search for grow from your
heart uh find the review section please
give me a festar rating and type in a
comment and let me know what you think
of the show and I will read your
comments on a future episode uh Stitcher
sucks for comments right now they keep
changing the platform so uh just leave a
comment somewhere on there and I will
find it
hopefully um yeah the reason you want to
leave a comment on iTunes and give me a
fivestar rating is because because that
moves me up in the ranks and people see
the show if we are noticed then it puts
us in the view of more folks which will
make more people grow better cannabis
which means you'll be able to smoke more
better cannabis I just said smoke more
better cannabis my grammar is getting
awesome oh we better just get to the end
of this before my brain explodes uh if
you guys have something to say find me
on all the social media I would
appreciate it um I'm on Twitter it's
gfyh podcast I'm on Instagram under I
gentics I'm on Facebook it's grow from
your heart
and also there's the email it's grow
fromy yourheart
hotmail.com you guys don't forget that
the show is available on iTunes Stitcher
and every single episode is archived on
iry gentics
color.com my buddy Tony added a donation
button to the page a little while back
if you feel like the show is worth a
couple of bucks and you want to make a
donation you can go to my website it's
iy genetics colorado.com click on the
grow fromy heart podcast tab at the top
right is a donation button that goes
directly to my Paypal account I will
never charge you guys for this podcast
this podcast is super free and it always
will be but if you feel like making a
contribution it would definitely be
appreciated I'm going to go over here
and make sure I'm telling you I'm in the
right chat room uh this was recorded on
uh trips pop party if you go to Tiny
chat it's tiny chat.com trips poot party
sometimes I'm on there sometimes I am on
Tiny chat.com I'm looking at it right
now so that I can not tell you the wrong
one come on browser I have so much [ __ ]
going on on the computer right now that
I wouldn't be surprised if it didn't
want to do this it's lagging a little
but we'll get there y'all we'll get
there together here we go the
appropriate web address will
be it will be there we go uh tiny
chat.com
BTV live main so sometimes I'm in that
chat room sometimes I am in the other
chat room um it's usually late at night
when I am bored and can't sleep and I've
got a lot of my mind and I'm trying to
write a podcast and I need a dab break I
jump in here and chat with these folks
de is shaking his head right now he
doesn't know I'm still watching him but
big shout out to de's Big shout out to
all my friends in the chat room you guys
keep me sane late at night us Growers
have weird hours we need friends online
like you thanks to all you guys that are
listening to the show I have been
rambling on for a long time today I'm
going to put better shows together you
guys can tell that my head wound is
definitely clearing up and I also want
to give a big shout out to uh Alpha
Brain if you need um a boost in your
brain and uh you don't want to do like
caffeine or yerba mate because it makes
you too uh jittery or something I
definitely recommend alphabrain from on
it.com o nnit t.com they don't pay me to
say that [ __ ] dude I just sounded like I
was doing a paid ad and they did not pay
me to say that is [ __ ] that I use uh it
made my head feel a lot better after my
head injury it made the clouds go away
and it obviously made me a little rambly
but that's confidence so uh yeah I'm
going to wrap up the show you guys
thanks for listening I hope I did you a
lot of good I hope you're setting up a
Perpetual grow right now as we speak
shout out to my ninja Spence until next
time you guys take a fat dab give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me
I'm
I'll it
[Music]
that