[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode 730
of the grow from your heart podcast i've
got a great show lined up for you before
we get to the main topic of today's
podcast let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
brian p let's send a big thank you shout
out to guido's grow room and roll this
nug i want to send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to stone trout bum
and roll me one kenobi let's send a big
rasta salute to my friend noah ann let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy adhd grower let's send a big fist
bump and a thank you shout out to
growing tennessee let's send a special
thank you shout out to og roach and the
devil's weed let's send a fist bump and
a thank you shout out to a long time
supporter my buddy know me by my
guacamole then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to grow man stan
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends who do want to support the show
truly you guys thank you for all of the
support it has been a great couple of
months on patreon i've added a great
coupon code this month for you so really
thank you i do appreciate that also i do
appreciate all of the response the love
the support and the encouragement for
the previous episode with my buddy clint
that episode's been out for a couple of
days at the time of this recording and
everybody seems to be leaving positive
comments positive feedback the emails
have all been great so thank you i'm
sure clint is reading the comments clint
you're probably watching this fist bump
fist bump bro you did a great job you're
welcome back on the show let's get some
cool [ __ ] for you to talk about bring
you back the crowd likes you you're a
good friend let's get you on the podcast
alright thank you guys for the great
feedback we do appreciate that clint
does appreciate it also if you've been
following along you may remember that
recently i bought myself a new rig it
was recently my birthday i did allocate
a budget for myself to buy a new dab rig
for my birthday i bought a whole new
setup i got a dab rig i got a banger i
got two carb caps i got some terp pearls
i even got a new torch and a new dabber
i went all the way in i got a nice case
for it uh once again shout out to my
friends at positively vibes for the
sweet hook up on the new rig
anyway i did talk about how it was
taking me a moment a few dabs to get
everything dialed in learning the new
temperature of the banger of a brand new
banger
learning the uh when to drop the dab in
when to cap it uh just learning the
function of a brand new rig and getting
the right equipment took me a moment it
took me a couple of days maybe uh three
or four days to get everything purchased
ordered arrived cleaned up and in use
and in action and test it and see what i
like the best i am happy to announce
that i have got my new dab rig dialed in
it hits like a champ it hits like a
[ __ ] mack truck running at 100 miles
an hour it has knocked me on my ass a
couple of times this week i am happy to
announce that rig works so big shout out
to my friends at positively vibes for
making sure i got the perfect rig also
big shout out to my shopping buddy the
person that went with me that day to
make sure i had a great birthday and a
great shopping experience thank you that
was a great day where do we go from
there let's segue into a little bit more
uh cannabis related content one of the
things i wanted to talk about on this
episode was simply be careful on social
media i have noticed that there are
several instagram accounts that are
mimicking my instagram account i am irie
underscore genetics that is me that's
the only account that i'm using there is
the grow from your heart podcast account
there is the rosta jeff account i rarely
log into those just once in a while when
i realize i've got so many messages i
should check don't check those very
often
i am irie underscore genetics i am not
the other accounts i'm not
irie.genetics i'm not irie
genetic.s i'm none of those accounts
those accounts have been attempting to
sell seeds to people on instagram i do
not do that don't fall for the scam
be very careful also one of the things i
wanted to talk about somebody was
telling me that they take great photos
uh they're a great grower but they are
afraid to post because of their location
and their legality and they don't really
want their face out there they just
wanted their plants to be seen my advice
to them was just don't post bro if you
really are that worried about it if
you're that sketched out about it
there's no need to post if you're not
gonna put your face on there if you're
not gonna link up with people and do
business through the instagram which i
don't recommend anyway that's a good way
to get robbed that's a good way to get
your money taken if you're the buyer the
seller it will go wrong for you if
you're doing drug deals on instagram but
if you're not trying to do something
where you need to be known remain
anonymous remain in the shadows my
friend is a uh a free market grower
allegedly and nothing he does uh gets
left behind it all goes somewhere so i
was like bro don't even post to social
media there's no need to open up that
pandora's box if you're not out there
don't be out there
so be careful on social media one of the
things i wanted to segue into is that
our phones do put a lot of data in our
photos when we take a picture of
something with our iphone with our any
phone we're using basically now also our
cameras will do it i've got a high
quality camera that tells me exactly
where i was my coordinates when i took
that photo your phone is marking down
exactly where you are when you take that
photo you can go and if you open up your
photos and you search on the map section
in your photos you can search via the
map and you can see locations where
photos were taken i live in pueblo i can
click on pueblo it shows all the
pictures i took here i go to denver a
lot i can see all the pictures i took in
denver all the pictures i took in
boulder all the pictures i took in
california all the pictures i took in
oklahoma i can see them all by category
all of my meow wolf pictures
are already organized into a folder and
i did not do it the phone did that it
knew i was at meow wolf so be careful
when you're taking pictures because that
data is stored in your phone i don't
know what you're going to do with that
photo once you have taken it i don't
know how much of that data travels with
that photo when you post it but that
data is in your phone that data is there
that picture the location the time the
coordinates it is all right there so if
that phone perhaps could land in the
wrong hands or that info could land in
the wrong hands it could get you in some
sort of trouble especially if you
shouldn't be growing where you're
growing when you're growing why you're
growing be very careful now i don't
again i'm not the computer expert i
don't know about this part i don't know
how much
comes along with that photo when you
post it i don't know if instagram gets
the metadata i don't know if uh facebook
gets that data i don't know if cannabis
gets that data i don't know if any of
those servers where we share our info
where we share the photos i don't know
if they get the data that is attached to
that photo
with the new photos app on the iphone
you can actually click on the photo and
you can see all of the data i can see
the location the time i can see what
settings my camera was on when i took
the photo if i dig deeper i can probably
see how far the subject was away what my
aperture setting was i can tell a lot of
stuff just digging into the phone just a
little bit that can be sketchy so be
very careful you guys if you're gonna
take pictures with your phone uh if
you're gonna post stuff be very careful
there's a lot of data hidden also not
all accounts are your friends i
mentioned there are fake accounts of my
brand iriegenetics there are fake
accounts of a lot of my friends brands
out there be very careful also a lot of
those people aren't real people uh what
would it take for law enforcement just
to make a account that said my name is
whoever they wanted to be with a cool
catchy name and just jump into the
community and they could they could
cause you problems if they wanted to so
be very careful on social media
all of the other accounts that are not
irie genetics are not me so be careful
be careful with email addresses be
careful with websites be very careful
also be very careful where you are
purchasing your seeds i highly recommend
you check my website
ireadgenetics.com that's official or go
to my discord look for a link that will
send you to my official vendors there
are uh somewhere between 8 and 12
vendors i don't remember what we've got
up there now we're going to do some
editing soon some shifting but my
website has a list of official vendors
those people do have actual irie
genetics beans they've been approved i
do know they're selling good [ __ ] those
companies have good customer service
they're reliable if you're buying from
anybody else i can't make you any
promises on what they are i can i can
back up dave uh dave's not here is a
good dude those are actually irie
genetics beans there are a few other
people that i may be able to vouch for
but not uh if they're not on the website
and i don't say their name out loud at
least a couple of times i might not know
who they are they might not be selling
my real seeds there are a couple of
brands a couple of companies out there
that just buy buckets of random seeds
put them in labels and tell you that
they're my brand and sell them to you
they do it to a lot of other famous
popular brands so be careful out there
be careful where you are purchasing your
seeds i have a correction to make in a
previous episode i was talking about
autoflower seeds i talked about dads
yeah that was a quick segue i'm sorry if
i lost you i was in a previous episode i
was talking about daz making autoflower
seeds with some irie genetics lines
in that episode i mentioned that to the
best of my knowledge it takes
approximately five or six filial
generations to create an autoflower line
well after conversation with daz i
realized i'm wrong as [ __ ] and i don't
know what i'm talking about when it
comes to autoflowers which is fine with
me i've admitted that that's not what
i'm into but daz says
he can make autoflowers by the third
generation they'll be solid auto it'll
start popping up in the second it'll be
locked in by the third by that fourth
generation they're definitely
autoflowers so uh i needed to correct
that because i misspoke in a previous
episode another thing i should mention
is in a previous episode i mentioned
that seeds here now was getting a
restock of seeds um the united states
postal service is taking their sweet
[ __ ] time with those boxes so those
uh packages have not arrived at seeds
herenow.com at the time of this
recording they are still in transit so i
do ask you my friends please be polite
please be gentle with seeds here now be
patient with them the order is on the
way it will get there it takes them a
few minutes to check that in there's
some work to be done it doesn't just get
checked in and sold there's inventory
things to be counted [ __ ] like that give
my friends a minute they do want to sell
you the seeds nobody makes money with
seeds sitting in boxes they do want to
sell them as soon as they've got the
seeds available they will take your
money but please maybe i spoke too soon
saying that they were going there
because a lot of people messaged saying
we want them now
sorry guys not there now wait patiently
they will get there there's a lot going
and we're going to do our best to not
run out as frequently we've got some
things in place making some upgrades and
some changes so be patient with my
friends at seeds here now if they don't
have what you want if they don't have
what you want in stock that was harder
to say than it looked just wait a little
bit they will get it it's on the way if
they still don't when they do get the
restock if the pack you're looking for
didn't get stocked message me i'll add
that to my list and replenish them get
that over there where do we go from here
i am making selections today i made
selections for the outdoor breeding run
which will happen this summer uh no i'm
not gonna tell you what i selected but i
am very excited to have made selections
to put in the outdoor breeding run this
summer fall season i am stoked i'll leak
some info i'll let you guys know what's
going on in the near future but i wanted
to say that i'm super excited to have
the outdoor plants prepared for the
summer and speaking of seeds the
feminized seed project is working that's
right uh if you've been following along
you know that recently i made a batch of
silver thio sulfate spray which i use to
reverse three female golden goat plants
those three golden goat plants will be
used to pollinate a lemon skunk and uh
platinum tangy and of course another
golden goat also several other female
plants in the room that don't need to be
mentioned right now
but my point is that the reversal is
working that
female plant is starting to make pollen
sacks i see the male parts on there
they're developing the balls are nice
and big they're turning purple doing
exactly what i want that golden goat
plant to do at this phase at this time
at this stage the pollen receiver plants
have been dragged into the room they are
now kicking into flower they're not too
far in there but they're starting to
show me pre-flower
the feminized project is well underway
so here and i don't want to say a time
frame because you guys will hold me too
closely to it i may need a few days
worth of leeway some time here some some
buffer zone what's it called the grace
period that's the word i'm trying to
think of i may need a brief grace period
however the lemon jeffery orange gasm
golden goat feminized and many more
femme seeds will be restocked here
in a short time uh once again short time
to a breeder is not as much time uh you
guys are gonna think it's been a long
time so be patient with me they're
coming that's my point femme seeds are
coming uh the reversal is looking good
the golden goat that i sprayed uh every
third day for up to day 21 at 70
dilution is the one that made uh it will
make the most paul and it looks like in
my opinion uh so far from what it looks
like with my observations but that is
the one that appears to uh be ready to
make the most pollen it worked the
silver was perfect in my opinion i did
the mix just right sprayed just right
i'm excited to get the femme seeds made
for you guys because you guys have been
asking for them for a long time uh there
are other films you guys there are other
films that will be dropping very soon i
may not have said it on the show but the
after glow s1
will be available at seeds here now dot
com all right where do we go from here
i've got one more long part that i want
to ramble about in this podcast then we
will wrap it up go take some dabs and
have a party i was talking with a friend
recently at an event and we were talking
about setting up a brand new grow and as
i was mentioning the parts the needs the
components uh the instructions and
details of a grow i could watch my
friends eyes kind of turn into the back
of their head and their face glazed over
and i saw them check out and i was like
you good bro and he's like
i can't afford half of the [ __ ] that you
just mentioned i don't have half that
much time and then i thought
you know
it shouldn't intimidate you what i'm
saying is how you grow top shelf uh cup
winning uh medical grade perfect weed
this is the best weed you can grow with
all of these details
you don't have to start off growing cup
winning championship weed you should not
start off growing cup winning
championship nobody starts off as a
black belt nobody starts off as a master
you've got to start off as a white belt
in any craft in which you start you got
to be a beginner
or you're going to fail later on if you
don't start off as a beginner learn the
basic steps the fundamentals you'll
never get truly good at anything so
sometimes when i'm talking about all of
the things that are needed to grow good
cannabis sometimes when i'm talking
about all the equipment the nutrients
the purchases the cost of entry uh the
time that it's gonna require the
modifications and or adjustments to your
home
that is for top shelf grade a
award-winning best cannabis you could
possibly consume you can grow some
cannabis that you can smoke and enjoy
with very minimal equipment cost setup
time effort the time effort energy and
equipment that you've got will produce
cannabis it may not be
the way that i describe it
you can put a lot of effort into it so
think about it this way i'm 6'5 and i
weigh about 190 pounds i am super skinny
i obviously don't put a lot of time into
beefing up i'm not getting bulky i got
cardio for days i'm strong enough for
what i need to do i don't want to get
big and bulky that's just not for me
maybe one day but that's never been a
thing on my brand i don't need to be
huge but then you look at brock lesnar
right there's brock lesnar brock lesnar
puts a lot of time into being a big
[ __ ] dude if let's just say that
we're going for elite muscular body
types uh if you are looking to win
awards you got to work out you got to
[ __ ] take the steroids do the
push-ups eat the protein get the diet
plan going you got to get it all [ __ ]
in line if you want to look like brock
lesnar uh if you want the plants that
look like brock lesnar plants you need
all of the nutrients all the equipment
the best lights the best seeds the best
soil you also have to be in that grow
space twice a day checking on everything
making sure that everything is fed
making sure that every leaf that needs
to be defoliated is defoliated making
sure that the stems and sticks are
popped and twisted and everything's
lollipop and if you're trellising it's
trellis correctly you're in there twice
a day you're in there right when the
lights come on and then once again right
before the lights go off here and
they're doing work every single day or
if you want to you could grow some
plants that look like me they're tall
they're skinny they're lanky but they'll
get the job done at the end of the day
you didn't have to spend a whole bunch
of time in the gym a whole bunch of time
on a diet plan and you'll accomplish the
goal but when you stand us next to each
other you'll go that dude right there
obviously spent more [ __ ] time in the
gym and that guy was playing video games
or recording podcasts or some [ __ ] over
there definitely not in the gym lifting
weights that's definitely not me you can
see that you'll see that in the grow now
with that being said
i don't want you to start off being the
best grower ever i want you to start off
with the equipment you can afford in the
space that you can afford with the best
light and the best genetics you can
afford and then piece it together after
that figure out how to control the light
cycle in the room once you've got a
space where you can control the light
cycle now you can focus on putting a
light in there putting some seeds in
there putting all of the better
equipment in there then you grow a
couple of crops read a few books before
you grow anything read a book then as
you grow you'll experience problems and
you'll see things you'll see things you
want to improve on keep reading more
books watch more podcasts learn things
but just like any hobby
most most people don't have the
advantage the blessing the uh they just
don't have the funding to go out and buy
the best equipment for a brand new hobby
if you're gonna start karate if you're
gonna buy the drums if you're gonna buy
baseball equipment if you're gonna get
into hockey if you're gonna be a new
podcaster most of us don't have the
blessings the advantage to go and just
buy the most expensive best [ __ ] which
is what we like to do for our grow room
that would be ideal you just go to the
grow store and you say i want the best
light the best tint the best [ __ ]
dehumidifier the best soil best
nutrients hit up rasta jeff get the best
genetics get all the best [ __ ] i
understand we can't all do that all of
the best [ __ ] costs a lot of money so
get the best light get a good tent get a
good environment something in which you
can control the light and dark cycles
that's going to be one of the main
elements which we need then after that
get a good light then get good genetics
i don't i'd recommend good seeds but you
can get clones clones are tried and true
maybe your friend grew them saved you a
step already you know they're good
clones but maybe also your friends
selected some [ __ ] maybe you need to
get some seeds and find the good [ __ ]
but spend the money on a good enclosure
a good tent to build something somewhere
you can control the light the dark and
the environment then spend money on a
good light then good genetics then from
there everything else will come into
place you're going to need fans
dehumidifier something to control the
climate and the room some sort of air
exchange a blower
stuff like that ph pen nutrients all
that stuff will come in line but by the
best
light and nutrients that you can get to
start off with then as you get better
you will buy more things if you are
growing for production if you're making
a profit off of this how about every
time you harvest you put a good portion
of that harvest back into your grow
space and into your skill if you're able
to pull a pound of ok weed this time how
about next time we pull a pound and a
quarter of even better weed and the next
time a pound and a half of even better
wheat and we work our way up until we're
pulling three pounds of light of [ __ ]
top shelf amazing impressive weed in
every grow this isn't your last grow
this first time when we build this this
is your first grow this is just the
starting run get a bike with some
training wheels get a helmet and just
start training you're going to crash a
couple of times find out if you're even
into it find out if you can dedicate the
time the energy the space
it's a commitment it's like getting a
puppy but at the end of it you get to
smoke it and take some dabs if you do it
right so you're gonna have to spend some
time some energy some love some money
some adjustments into there there are
some commitments uh some sacrifices some
dedication to be put into these plants
so just like any other hobby you start
you don't need to start off with the
best equipment uh when i got into
drumming i've been playing the drums i
like to use the drums for a good example
because i've been playing the drums uh
for over i don't even want to say how
many years i feel old i've been playing
the drums for over 20 years 25 years
holy [ __ ] i've had a drum set for over
25 years
when i bought my first drum set i
thought i knew exactly what i wanted i
thought i wanted this here this here
these things here this this i thought i
wanted these pedals now my drum set is
nothing like what it was when i designed
it when i was 15. i understand that my
body my physical
needs my skill
my setup for my body and my drums and my
budget and my ability it has all changed
and evolved in so many ways that the
idea of what i thought i was going to
play how i thought i was going to play
who where and when i thought i was going
to play with none of that is the same
now so my entire drum set is different
also my grow spaces have evolved
dramatically they also still continue to
evolve seasonally every season i change
stuff uh i've gotten to the point where
i can see what's happening to the plants
really quickly i can make changes on the
fly i'm not afraid to make some changes
and screw some [ __ ] up so now i try to
add or change or subtract or different
uh adjust modify uh change something
almost every run every other run so that
i can see where i can improve or see
what products work or see what doesn't
work sometimes if you've been following
along
you you learned that last winter i
learned that i should not switch to leds
right at the beginning of the [ __ ]
winter season i went from my hbs to
brand new leds that like a week later
was negative 17 degrees outside there
was no way to keep my grow space cold
because the hps lights that i had in
there were doing that so now i've
learned not to switch that [ __ ] in the
middle but my grow space is always
evolving ever changing new ideas new
equipment just like my drum set just
like your guitar setup just like your
hockey gear just like whatever you're
into all of our [ __ ] evolves so when
you're getting started
don't let all the stuff i talk about
intimidate you i say a lot of things you
need a light a tent
pots soil a dehumidifier possibly a
humidifier maybe an air conditioner
maybe a heater uh definitely some sort
of extraction fan to move humidity and
heat from the room then maybe a duct to
pull fresh air into the room then we
need some sort of ph monitor then we
need an ec monitor then we need all
kinds of mixing equipment then we need
nutrients also it'd be cool to have a
vpd monitor in the room there are so
many things to think about then i'd like
to add co2 and a co2 monitor then i want
to build an auto watering system and
then i want to do this and then all of
this and then i'm going to talk about
trichomes and terpenes and testing
numbers and
days and durations and [ __ ]
productivity of all kinds of things but
guess what that's just because i've been
doing it for a long time don't let all
that [ __ ] intimidate you nature grows
wheat outside every year all the time
without us nobody gets involved and that
[ __ ] happens beautifully just the way
that whatever you believe in the way
that nature the way that jaw the way
that buddha the way that the flying
spaghetti monster intended it to happen
it happens outside so it can definitely
happen indoors just let it happen screw
it up as little as you can stay out of
the way and you don't need all the fancy
[ __ ] you can start off with a little bit
of [ __ ] build up as you go and then i
didn't start off with the greatest stuff
i had a little tiny light that kind of
flickered sometimes when it came on it
hummed and made a weird noise and i was
afraid i was going to burn down the
freaking house i had a little tent that
had light leaks i put duct tape all over
the light leaks
i grew two good rounds in that the first
one we smoked all of it the second run i
sold it and made enough money out of
that second run allegedly possibly there
was medical marijuana then so this was
legit maybe possibly uh sold that second
crop and bought another tent that was
twice the size and bought another light
bought an air conditioner bought a
blower and had two grow spaces now and
turned one into a veg space one into a
flower space started production then
every time i would harvest another crop
i would just buy another piece of gear
another piece of gear a better piece of
gear uh that piece sucks let's buy a new
one when we harvest and get another one
and just make a wish list when you
harvest you're going to have some money
if you do it right you're either going
to save the money you've been spending
on product or you're going to flip some
of it and make a profit reinvest in your
business your grow is now your business
your hobby your passion put some money
into it it's going to put some love back
into you spend some energy some time
some effort on it and you will learn you
will grow you will become a great grower
i was a white belt i was brand new one
day now i'm here teaching the community
how to improve every day so don't be
intimidated don't be shy don't think
that you have to set up the first grow
the first growth should not be a ferrari
you wouldn't buy your kid a ferrari for
their first car you get them a pinto or
a pacer or some [ __ ] right get that
pinto get that pacer bro crash a few
times then get that f1 racer and [ __ ]
win the race
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters pollen chuckers
all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast i had a good time recording this
show i felt like i just started talking
and suddenly it's been 30 something
minutes later minus a few edits thank
you i do appreciate it also thank you
for all of the continued patreon support
if you'd like to support the show once
again it is patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart if you've got any
questions corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism or negative
feedback i would love to hear from you
the email address for the show is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy reach out let me know what you think
if you've got show ideas grow questions
feedback you want to cuss me out you
want to tell me i'm awesome send me a
message i will check that as soon as i
can anything else check out my website
iriegenetics.com there's a grow help tab
there there's a link to the discord and
of course there is a link to the merch
store make sure you hit that merge store
everything is on sale if you are a part
of the mailchimp newsletter you've got a
discount code if you're on discord
you've got a better discount code and if
you are a supporter on patreon you got
in even better discount code based on
your support level on patreon so check
for those discount codes and check out
the website get your shirts stickers
hats rolling trays grinders dab mats
there's all kinds of great [ __ ] on there
go check it out grab yours before it's
gone because we're gonna blow it the
[ __ ] out this month huge deals huge
discounts i've said more than enough
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
chicago dabber and until next time take
a fat dad
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you