[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 731
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy grow bandit let's
send a big fist bump and a thank you
shout out to stoner dave and
stashdrop269
let's send a big thank you shout out to
the hardest working man in cannabis my
buddy james brown let's send a big fist
bump and a thank you shout out to jimmy
limmer and kojaks let's send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy sam heads
let's send a big fist bump to kes burton
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to magic mike let's send a thank you
shout out to greene county grower i want
to send a big thank you to spherical
glassworks and g7 then let's wrap it all
up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to the new
old guy
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends before i get too far i
do want to send a big thank you to
everybody who supported and participated
in the merchandise sale that's right if
you're a member of the discord the
newsletter or of course the patreon you
did receive a coupon code big thanks to
everybody who used those coupon codes we
are cleaning out merch things are moving
we're making some space thank you there
are still some things left in the store
so if you want to grab your merch make
sure you sign up for that newsletter
make sure you check out the website make
sure you check out the discord or make
sure of course you sign up for the
patreon service you will get a sweet
coupon code save yourself some bucks and
the merchandise store truly you guys
thank you for all of that support
all right i don't have a lot to ramble
about here at the beginning i can make
this show super long at the start let's
jump right into it and get into a
message that came from our patreon page
this one came from my buddy tonto big up
to my buddy tanto out there in canada
hope you're well bro i hope the family
as well my message from my buddy tonto
goes a lot like this it says hey ross to
jeff i have a couple of questions that i
think might be good for the show let's
start with this one this is a great spot
to start it says i have a bunch of
medical conditions they make gardening a
struggle during certain parts of the
year
my ptsd depression and back issues make
a lovely cocktail of reasons not to get
my gardening work done i understand that
with a lot of uh ptsd depression back
issues that's three solid excuses to not
get out of bed not get off the couch not
get [ __ ] done all day we're gonna talk
more about that it says those conditions
are the main reasons i've pulled enough
or been pulled into organic growing i
found ways to make the workload easier
or less growing with this style i am
assuming that there are many others out
there like me who struggle to keep the
garden in tip-top shape what would you
advise someone with medical conditions
as the minimum things you would need to
do both in veg and flour to keep
everything going so that is the first
question that's a very good question um
man i'm not sure exactly where to start
for everybody but i can give you tips
and advice for your needs and for
possibly my needs but if you've got
different
limiting factors then i'm not sure what
i would recommend um so you ask what are
the minimum things you would need to do
both in veg and garden so what advice
would you give somebody the minimum
things the plants need to be watered
that's the most important thing
as a cannabis grower who likes to go
places likes to get away one of the
things i think about is are these plants
going to get water so set the plants up
in a way that you can water them is the
water itself accessible where does it
come from does it come from a faucet
does it come from a sink a shower some
sort of a tap a well do you have to
[ __ ] pull the water out of the lake
where does the water come from make the
water easily accessible easily portable
to your grow that's going to be the
first step we have to water these plants
at least twice maybe three or four times
a week depending on the size
so maybe set it up to where it's easy to
water it if it's easier to water it
you'll do it more make sure that you're
let's even back up a whole another step
is your entire grow space clean tidy and
organized and inviting i've noticed that
when my workspace if it's my office if
it's my garage workspace if it's my grow
workspace if it's the podcast area when
that space gets cluttered and it's not
inviting and presentable my mind is
cluttered when i'm there and i can't
perform to the best of my ability so i
make sure to keep my grow space as clean
as i can my uh nutrient mixing station
my nutrient storage area all of that
stuff is it looks like military-grade
cleaning happened in there and that
invites me to want to go in there i
don't go in there and go i got to move
this [ __ ] out of the way i got to look
for this i go i can go in this place
where it is organized and streamlined
and ready for me to go so from the very
beginning have everything clean
organized streamlined ready to go so
that you can set yourself up for success
and be invited in there by yourself
then maybe put some music in there i
love listening to podcasts and music if
there's a bluetooth speaker and a bottle
of kombucha i could be pretty happy just
about anywhere if you give me a dab
first things are really irie so i like
to put on a good podcast a lot of people
listen to me and the girl what's up hope
you're having a good day in the grow
hope i'm getting you through work hope
things aren't too hard uh you're kicking
ass today you're doing your job pretty
well keep killing it bro um also go take
that work poop work poop and get paid
for it while the boss is not looking but
a lot of people put on a podcast during
the workday but listen to some music put
a bluetooth speaker in there get some
air pods some earbuds something in there
that encourages you to go i put out two
shows a week you probably got to water
at least twice a week there's two
episodes of me to listen to two days of
growing covered right there there's some
entertainment uh you're from canada
maybe you want to listen to some rush go
put on some neil pier and jam out to
some russian there i'm just picking on
you because you're canadian bro i still
love you but encourage and inspire
yourself to go in there before we even
start thinking about the gear the room
is everything organized clean inviting
does it smell good does it look good uh
if it's not organized and inviting i
won't want to go in there and if it's a
mess and i do go in there i'm still not
going to work to the best of my uh
potential my ability and i'm not going
to enjoy it so let's make it inviting
get some music going make it in an
environment in which you want to be
now the things that are required of of
the grower is of course the watering
that's the first thing you're going to
need to get done can you get the water
to the grow without breaking your back
or your neck
can you get that water from a big vessel
into the mixing container without
breaking your neck or your back do you
have a good mixing container do you have
a good ph pen do you have a good ec pen
do you have good mixing containers and
devices make it fun um maybe if you have
a couple extra bucks spend a few bucks
on devices to make the growing more
simplistic more streamlined and more fun
more toys makes it better for a lot of
people if you get if you get that brand
new piece of gear it just may inspire
you to regrow again so maybe a new toy
every once in a while reward yourself
with a new piece of gear but mainly keep
it clean and get it set up now watering
we've got to get an amount of water from
one container into these plants can you
physically do it if not let's think
about setting up a watering system
you can build a watering system with any
sort of reservoir i like to use a trash
can a 35 or 55 gallon trash can on
wheels so you can move it to the water
fill it move it where it needs to be
drop a submersible pump in there run
some flex line that runs out of that
reservoir down to the ground down across
the floor and then i will put spaghetti
tubing that comes out of that with
emitters that go to each plant then i
just set that up with a timer and then i
know that um depending on the amount of
meters and the amount of emitters and
the amount of plants that i've got how
much water i want i can set up a timer
to where i know that if i turn on the
water for or if i turn on the timer for
two minutes that pump runs for two
minutes my plants will get enough water
it's really easy to figure that out the
first time you do it you guys if you
want to learn that
get your plants to where they need water
get your auto watering system set up set
a timer hit go plug in your pump let the
plants get wet when they're watered
enough hit stop on the timer unplug the
thing that's how long you need your
plants to come on your timer to come on
to water your plants every time a minute
and 40 seconds that will get the plant
saturated every time how long between
waterings maybe every three days so
every third day you need a minute and 40
seconds worth of watering it's really
not that hard to set up once you get
figured out so one of the things you'll
have to do is auto watering or some sort
of watering that is required you can't
get through without that then the plants
are likely going to need some sort of
supports as they grow
they're going to need up pots they're
going to need transplanting so that's
things you're going to need to think
about i go from a seedling into a cup
then my cup goes into a 3 gallon maybe a
one depending on my time space needs but
i'll go from a cup to a maybe a one
gallon maybe right to the three and then
from a three maybe to a five or a seven
uh but think about your pot sizing think
about the up pots that you're gonna have
to do that's going to have to happen
then supports the plants are going to
get taller and bigger they're going to
need more supports are you going to put
a trellis net are you going to put
sticks in there that's things that will
be required so some watering some up
potting some supporting and then a
little bit of defoliation maybe it's not
required but it will definitely help you
and make things easier so i'm trying to
think of things that we have to do
watering is the main thing you have to
do supports uh lollipopping twisting
things like that are all bonuses but
they should be done so i'm just thinking
of the minimum things as watering and
keeping the light cycle going and just
keeping the plants supported and happy
now with that being said
i want to inspire you to get in there
remember that keep in mind that every
day that you don't get up and get in
there and do your best in the garden the
harvest will show you today you can be
as depressed as down as you want you
could push it off or you can go in there
and kick ass it's not going to show you
until the back end until you go to cut
down at harvest time you're going to say
man if i would have gone in there that
one day when i was having that problem
and i just didn't feel like it if i
would have gone in there and spent one
hour in there and just handled this
issue this harvest weight would be
better this harvest quality would be
better this harvest this harvest
experience overall would be more
rewarding and would be more better more
better sure we're going to go with that
and it would be
more rewarding for you spiritually and
mentally and financially as well so
think about that think that's what i use
as inspiration and motivation when i
don't want to do any work if i just go
do it when it's done i'm going to feel
better that's a reward within itself and
then every little job that you do is a
small reward that leads up to the big
full accomplishment of the big picture
of the goal which feels very rewarding
you i know tattoo i know that tanto was
a former military person so i know you
know that feeling of accomplishment i
know that you know that feeling of pride
dig inside and feel that feeling compare
the feelings inside when you're laying
there go
man i could either lay here and let this
depression crush me today or or i could
get up and crush the depression and go
spend time with my plants which i love
which are like my little children which
put off good vibes which feed me good
energy which in a few months also is
going to give me quality medicine and a
big reward so i should just get up and
not not let this depression not to let
this win today i understand dude i had a
traumatic brain injury where for several
months i thought about doing terrible
[ __ ] to myself i'm cool now guys don't
worry i'm way past that but that was
years ago i do have a traumatic brain
injury when it first happened i
questioned if i would make it to
tomorrow and i understand the uh the
lack of desire the lack of passion the
lack of anything to get up and do
anything i didn't care if i got up in
eight i didn't care if i got up to pee i
thought i'd just piss in right there
because i was so depressed and so dark
that who cares i'll just piss on myself
anyway it wouldn't matter i've been
there um you just gotta dig deep man you
gotta dig deep inside of yourself and
and think that your mind is playing
tricks on you and that you are the
winner of that game you're gonna win
every time don't let that [ __ ] beat you
so um the bare minimum is watering
transplanting supporting and then after
that everything else is bonus you got to
feed them and you got to change the
light cycle but they will grow i have
friends that leave town for several
months at a time because they've got an
auto watering system and it just keeps
their grow going for them it will happen
but the more you do to it the better it
will become and that's what i'm going to
say would be the motivating factor the
thing that would get you in there is
just knowing like i can grow some
c-grade weed i could do that in my
[ __ ] sleep but if i want to grow a
grade weed i got to get in there i got
to touch the plants i got to do the work
that's the difference i mentioned that
in an episode before that's the
difference between a gray and c grade
wheat is just doing the work now another
thing i should really mention is that i
invite you to join my discord server
this sounds like advertising this sounds
cheesy but honestly bro um during these
weird times we were isolated through a
pandemic and we had to sit at home and
we weren't allowed to go places discord
is where i spent a lot of time hanging
out with some of my best and favorite
friends in my discord server we have
amazing deep conversations we are very
supportive we're all grown adults we're
all grown people they're men and women
ah there's uh transgender they're gay
straight color black white purple people
in there there's people of all ethnicity
ethnicities races genders orientations i
invite everybody and we have a really
good time hanging out in there if you're
feeling down if you're feeling depressed
if you're feeling alone if you need some
encouragement if you need a grow buddy
just to pep talk you or just someone to
be around to get the dark [ __ ] out of
your brain come hang out on the discord
server that's where i go when i'm lonely
bored need some friends if my
girlfriend's working or if she's asleep
because she goes to bed way earlier than
me or if i just need someone to talk me
through some [ __ ] cuz i'm a business
owner sometimes i have challenges i need
to talk to people discord is where i go
to talk to some of my best friends
mike's got kids he's busy glenn goes to
bed early sometimes the discord crews
who i turn to i invite you to do the
same thing a lot of my favorite people
are there so if you're feeling dark
feeling weird need that encouragement
need some grow bros ah come join us on
the discord that's where i am a lot of
the time
and i'll be there more i've made a
pledge to kind of be there more often
because it uh it got weird and we're
fixing it and making the vibe strong i
will be there no [ __ ] allowed on
discord i'm rambling tonto i know that
may not be the answer you're looking for
bro the minimum [ __ ] that has to happen
is they have to be watered other than
that they'll pretty much grow feed them
water them make sure they don't fall
over they're going to do it but you've
got to dig deep and get the motivation
and the inspiration to get in there and
make those plants champions i know you
don't want to smoke sea grate or b-grade
weed remember that when you're feeling
down all you got to do is get in there
and do the work and you can make that a
grade weed just use that as your
inspiration then reach out bro uh
message me message the army join the
discord get involved with some people
get some uh brain juices moving get
yourself out of that dark mode we'll get
you in the grow we'll get you going all
right there is more to this it does say
second question
i do have hopes and dreams of opening a
cannabis nursery within canada sometime
in the next five to ten years nurseries
can have up to 50 meters squared or 5
5000 or 538 square foot of canopy space
i hope to be selling clones and seeds in
the legal market here in canada
i do have two questions based on this
are nurseries viable businesses in the
states in your opinion and if you have
that allotted space how would you run it
and any advice to someone who may jump
into that market i know that's a very
general and broad
question and then there's more
let's talk about this clone nursery that
is not something that we see
uh completely dedicated to clones here
in colorado there's not enough of a
market in my opinion to just sell clones
there's one company that i know of that
focuses on just clones they seem to do
okay but there's only one company i know
of that really does that there are two
different ways that clones kind of work
here in colorado you can make clones and
provide clones for the commercial market
which means you've got a big this kind
of sounds like what you would try to do
you take your big warehouse and you
would cut hundreds of clones maybe
thousands of clones probably hundreds of
thousands of clones possibly then you
would offer those clones to other
commercial facilities and they would buy
those and then they would just run your
cuts in their grow many commercial
facilities do rely on somebody to
provide those clones they buy them every
time the problem is a lot of facilities
will buy clones from you one time they
run all your stuff they find their
favorites and they cut a clone of that
and then they never have to buy clones
from you again so that's one of the
downsides to making clones for the
commercial market once everybody has
their stuff they just start making their
own clones they don't have to call you
anymore that's kind of how the clone
game works the other option is making
clones for the consumer end of the
market which is a great idea but also
there are only so many consumers people
only grow so much weed
i think there are so many rules in
colorado i'm not even sure if you can
sell a clone to somebody from out of
state you may have to have a colorado id
to even be able to purchase a clone in a
store i don't know that because i've got
the id so i don't know
uh the steps and skips and caveats to
that but
um for a while my dream and i don't
think i'm gonna do this anymore so i
could talk about it but there was there
were goals and plans but i kind of
shifted my focus here just because of
life and paperwork and things but one of
my goals was to open a giant commercial
cultivation facility my one of my dreams
was to
make seeds for the recreational market
in colorado i wanted to be able to put
ivory genetics beans on the shelf here
in colorado that was one of the goals
that would be great to walk into a store
and see the seeds but there's so much
red tape that it's almost it's basically
not worth it so i wanted to put seeds on
the store shelf which would have
required me to produce those seeds in a
commercially licensed grow which then
would have given me the advantage and
the ability to sell those clones to
commercial grows so i wanted to sell
clones to commercial grows sell seeds to
recreational stores and at the same time
also possibly offer those clones to the
recreational stores that was kind of the
goal
mike and i did a lot of numbers we did a
lot of crunching it would have barely
made any profit the only way that we
think this would have been profitable is
if we did a crop where we produced seeds
and then sold all the seeds and then did
a crop of producing seedless flower and
sold the flower to supplement the income
and then in the meantime the flower
would be building hype for the seeds and
be building hype for the clones and then
the clones would be in demand the seeds
would be in demand and we'd sell more
flowering clones it was kind of a hoping
to make a cycle out of that but honestly
it got uh with all the licensing fees uh
the licensing fees basically um and the
rules and regulations and all that it
got a little bit ridiculous and we kind
of just i guess we sort of abandoned
ship on that idea i guess things were
working the way that they are mike got
two mike had two kids um irie took off
the way that it took off and we kind of
abandoned ship that way
but just clones in my opinion does not
uh look fell look smell feel or seem
like a viable option unless you could
develop contracts with commercial
cultivation facilities that will
be
relying on you to supply those cuts
every however frequently you need they
need them and you can supply them
probably every uh 90 75 maybe every 21
days depending on how they set up their
cycles i ran a big grow we had three
flower rooms every 21 days we were
cutting clones uh putting stuff into
flowers 21 day flip turnarounds there
because we had the rooms divided to our
21 days was the gap in between them
anyway if you've got somewhere for those
clones to go it may be a viable business
but without a predetermined customer for
that many clones i don't know you could
get that many cuts out however i could
be wrong because in the great nation of
canada you guys can mail [ __ ] to each
other we can't do that here we don't
have national legalization we've got
state by state legalization and things
cannot leave each state that's highly
illegal so with the advantage in canada
you can mail things from one end of
canada to the other or in the middle or
all over that may be advantageous to you
but i don't honestly know the clone
market in canada
again unless you've got that commercial
account or you've got some sort of uh
commercial availability where you can
advertise and say we'll ship clones
everywhere then i don't know if it would
work with that catch with that bonus it
may work for you but i don't want to
lead you the wrong direction all right i
think i rambled on enough about that
part of the question there is more it
says where was i i was here um any other
possible events you will be at this year
other than the groovy gravy event
unfortunately i could not make that one
yes i understand you my friend are
canadian i understand you could not make
the groovy gravy secret stash event in
denver however
i do not know of any upcoming events in
colorado at this time there are a few
events coming up in other states i know
there's something in oklahoma i know
there's stuff on the east coast coming
up but i don't know of anything coming
up in colorado right now unfortunately
with a lot of the rule changes we cannot
smoke at any of the events in colorado
it's basically illegal to consume inside
of a public building like that where
people are gathering so we can't really
smoke
we're either allowed to do business or
consume and you don't really get to do
both it's kind of weird people are
opening up consumption places and things
like that are changing but it's taking a
little bit of time however i do not know
of any events coming up in colorado if i
do
i will let you know especially of events
which i am attending and vending because
i like to let the people know where i
will be i love it when people come and
meet me shake my hand give me a fist
bump say hello uh tell me how long
they've been listening to the show show
me pictures of their grow let me smell
the weed they grew that [ __ ] is awesome
i love it so i will definitely let
everybody know when they're more when
there are more events coming up to
celebrate and congregate for um let's
see what else do i have on this message
this one says i hope all is well from
your friend tonto big shout out to my
buddy tanto up there in canada tonto
thank you for the great message i do
appreciate it if you have any more
questions about your clone nursery ideas
i would love to talk to you about that
send me more patreon messages send me an
email we will be in touch we will get
that dialed in for you if you've got
more questions again i don't know the
details about the rules up there in
canada i'm very limited in my clone
sales here in colorado i could only sell
to the uh colorado residents and also
colorado commercial production
facilities and then once they've got
them they clone them and they don't buy
them very much so only new growers will
be buying clones you're in canada where
you can ship nationwide that opens you
up to every single canadian is able to
buy clones i could be completely wrong
in my idea that it would not work you've
got a different business plan than i had
available all right i think that is all
i've got for this episode my voice is
burning out i seem to be quite stuttery
i'm not going to drag this episode out
too long we'll make it a short one we'll
make it a sweet one that way i can come
back and do a better episode in the next
show ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers growers
clone cutters paul and chuckers all of
you beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out
there i want to thank you again for
listening to another short episode of
the podcast i do apologize for this
being short i'm stuttery my voice sounds
like [ __ ] in my headphones it's not a
good show i'm gonna make it quick so the
next one will be better thank you for
all the encouragement that will flow in
from that you guys are great people
beautiful community i thank you i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content if you do feel like this episode
was educational informative uh
entertaining maybe you'd like to just
send a couple of bucks to encourage me
to do a better show next time all you
have to do is check out patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
please do send your constructive
criticism and your positive feedback to
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
everything else is on my website at
iregenetics.com
thanks for listening guys i want to give
a big shout out to my buddy trikeman and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you