all right that's recording that's
recording i think we're good here i'm
ready are you ready
let's get it on
[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me rasta jeff this
is episode 732
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on
listener emails before i get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those kind folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to uncle adam the uber driver let's send
a big fist bump in a thank you shout out
to terp burglar and levity loveday i
want to send a thank you shout out to
blackhawks fan and gramps memo let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to kenna organic illinois let's send
a big thank you shout out to my buddy
lefty's farm let's send a thank you
shout out to danny potts i want to send
a big fist bump to a longtime supporter
and a good friend my dude the candocrat
let's send a thank you shout out to
brohan78 then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to choke norris big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit www
dot
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and of course
i do include that link in the show notes
and in the video description to make it
super easy for all of my friends to
support the podcast i do want to send a
big thank you to everybody who took
advantage of the merchandise sale this
month the sale does continue through
this month of course things are running
out but big thanks to everybody who took
advantage of the coupon codes of course
everybody on patreon got a coupon code
everybody on discord got a coupon code
all of the members of the newsletter got
a coupon code so make sure you were
signed up and participating to get your
discounts on the merchandise all right i
don't want to ramble too much here at
the start of the show uh maybe too late
for that already i do have a bunch of
great emails here in front of me so with
no further ado let's jump right into the
email portion of today's podcast
this first message came to me from i'm
looking for their name i don't know if
they want their name said it says besh
best wishes from bob so shout out to my
buddy bob thank you for the great email
and made it on the show and it goes a
little bit like this
hey ross to jeff that's me it says
thanks for everything you do thank you
bro thank you for listening and for
supporting and for reaching out to make
the compliment it goes on it says i love
the show i love the vibes that means a
lot to me big up much respect putting
out a good vibe is important it's all
about the good vibes lately uh there's
too much not good vibes in the world so
i want to spread the best vibes i can
thank you for noticing thank you for
spreading that vibe i hope you continue
that vibe throughout the day after you
hear the show it does go on it says
you've helped me and so many people
become better growers with your podcast
ah thank you bro that is the goal here
and to know we are reaching the goal
that means everything so thank you for
reminding me that i'm hitting my goal
that means a lot to me
that inspires me that recharges me that
makes me want to do it even better so i
know that i'm reaching somebody helping
somebody and
so many people become better growers
thank you dude i appreciate that it goes
on it says i am eternally grateful for
the education and continued inspiration
uh keep listening keep watching bro
because i promise i will continue to
educate you and the inspiration goes
both ways these types of messages uh
there's some inspiration in the message
at the start and then there's more
inspiration and motivation because
you've got a question and that will help
keep me going so it is teamwork it's a
symbiosis so thank you bro thank you to
the whole community for all the support
let's keep going because i'm obviously
high and rambly i was smoking some lemon
jeffrey live rosin from a fort collins
grower who would probably rather remain
anonymous you may watch the show
awesome work bro i cannot stop talking
when i smoke that [ __ ] awesome podcast
concentrates this message does go on it
says just a quick follow-up on episode
when you were talking about integrated
pest management strategies i just wanted
to share a factoid regarding the hop
latent viroid on a previous episode i
did mention hoplate and viroid a virus
that many growers are being struck with
stricken with
however they're all getting this virus
right now everybody is encouraging or
encountering this virus in a commercial
grow in a home grow a lot of the grows
in california had to deal with this hop
late and viroid anyway he says just a
factoid i learned in the cannabis uh
regenerative conference big shout out to
our boys at the cannabis regen
conference uh they do a lot of great
work support them if you can it says
apparently alcohol does not kill the hop
latent viroid so what i said was to make
sure to dunk your scissors and maybe
your tools into some alcohol between
plants between rows apparently that's
ineffective that's not going to do it so
i may have told you to waste a step i
may have given you shitty advice i
thought to the best of my knowledge that
alcohol would sterilize your scissors
and kill that virus our friends at the
regenerative regenerative you say that
quickly our friends at the regen
conference have learned and taught us
that
that alcohol will not kill that virus uh
it says apparently alcohol doesn't kill
hlv as they clean up strategy it just
depends uh it just spreads it around
then it says um
hypochlorous acid which is hoci will
kill the hoplayton viroid just something
to consider when cleaning those scissors
from plants to plants best wishes to all
from our friend bob bob big up big thank
you lots of good compliments lots of
praise lots of encouragement and then a
factoid and a correction in that message
i like that i appreciate it thank you
keep the good messages coming you guys i
may have been wrong when i said that the
alcohol will fix your problem or help
prevent problems it's not going to do
anything you have to use what is it let
me read it again i thought i remembered
it when i folded the paper i got to
refer to my notes you have got to use
hypochlorous acid which is hoci that
will kill the hlv somebody else told me
that bleach would work i will not
testify to that i do not know if you've
got feedback input constructive
criticism or something to say about that
let me know will bleach work to help uh
clean up the uh the tools we used that
may have been contaminated with hoplate
and viroid all right i'm already high
and rambly i don't want to get too
sidetracked i've got another message
here this one comes from our friend jack
in australia what's up jack thank you
for uh listening down there in australia
should we turn upside down so you could
see me properly i'm just joking with you
bro i do love the uh the aussie support
big shout out to everybody in australia
who uh supports cannabis supports the
podcast especially all of you uh rebel
growers out there keep doing your thing
i'm high as [ __ ] and super rambly this
message it has a disclaimer it does say
you may have to edit this to make this
broadcastable bro i'm good at editing
this on the fly you speak stoner i speak
stoner i'll add that aussie accent to it
mate will be good it says hey ross to
jeff long time first time love the
podcast and have learnt so much from you
i'm just going to add the word mate in
here occasionally he did not type the
word mate but it says thank you mate
then it says i remember you talking
about how you would teach someone to
defoliate specifically during flower
when you were teaching that you
mentioned something along the lines of
anything with a purple petiole can come
off that is something i do remember
teaching practicing and saying on the
podcast that is still kind of a rule
that i follow i do believe that those
purple petioles are a good indicator
in the early flower room that those
leaves can come off i'll keep talking
about that as we go it says i wonder if
your stance has changed or if you have
more information or if you still
practice this i still do this
unfortunately with the um
excuse me for the throat clearing
unfortunately with the the pandemic we
had uh a lot of my career opportunities
and career moves did change i left a lot
of the commercial cultivation
consultation jobs because uh the
commercial crews the commercial grows
went down to uh what i was calling a
skeleton crew there was a lead grower
and then as minimal of a crew as they
could handle in there the lead grower
was doubling up his work all the main
growers were doubling up their work we
took people from working uh eight hour
shifts to working ten hour shifts that
way we didn't have to have as many
people coming and going from the groves
we just had uh the same people there all
the time to keep numbers down uh just
that was what we were doing for the uh
the pandemic the lockdown the quarantine
situation so when that was happening i
didn't want to be uh at all of these
grows my job is to travel from two or
three different grows a day uh do one
before lunch one after lunch and then
try to squeeze another one in whatever i
can during a day and go to these
different grows and see what's going on
that would put me in contact with a lot
of people and during the the quarantine
that wasn't necessary so i just chose to
uh i had contracts with a lot of places
and around september october they all
expired and i did not renew
many of them i have a couple of things
that i do on the side but i'm not
heavily contracted so i'm not in the
commercial grows as much as i was but i
still remember that the uh defoliation
strategy yes anything with a purple
petiole i do still employ the strategy
of let's pull that off that's what i
teach the uh the crew the grotex the
growers in the rooms is to remove those
there's more to this message let me read
it so that i could stay on track it says
i found this to be a pretty great rule
but i would love you to do
more uh would love you to go more into
removing large amounts of fan leaves
during flower perhaps day 21 roughly for
me on a flood and drain coco he tells us
about his grow it's still going to be
the same almost no matter how your grow
is i'm probably going to defoliate at
certain times just depends on how
intensely we will do it will be the
adjustments and the anomalies uh then he
says how about schwazing or stripping or
week 3 or day 21 a heavy doing a heavy
defoliation yes all of what you're
saying makes sense i will talk about
removing uh heavy amounts of leaves
since i'm thought thinking about this
and we're right here at this point if
you're going to heavily strip the room
and defoliate a lot of plants in a room
i'm used to working in large rooms your
spaces aren't probably as big as what
i'm thinking about but if you're going
to work in a space and you're going to
defoliate it
my advice and i do apologize for the
throat clearing i smoked rosin on a hot
nail i feel good but i got the throat
butter
the lung butter um so if you're going to
defoliate the room and you want to
defoliate i'm just going to make up a
scale let's say we're going to defoliate
on a on a one to five scale you want to
hit a hard four that's your goal right i
would not defoliate i would not start at
the plant in the corner and defoliate it
to a four i would do everything to a
level two and then i would come back and
do everything to a level three then come
back and do everything to a level four
that way uh we do it in a commercial
grow this way because it takes a lot
more time to defoliate i've got multiple
dudes and dudettes and non-binary folk
in a room defoliating their asses off
all day long i don't want this section
of the room to be naked and no leaves in
this room still to look like the 70s and
be all bushy i want to kind of keep it
even throughout the room so that we're
going to talk more about micro climates
and temperature pockets and humidity
pockets and things in the room i want to
prevent that so i'm going to defoliate
evenly just do a level 1 strip a level 2
and just do it in increments instead of
one section is naked one section is
really fuzzy
now you did mention the word schwazing
that is right here in the message i
don't necessarily do a schwas that is
when you almost take off every leaf
except those two at the top you strip
almost every
bigger leaf with a pedial off of the
plant i don't go that hard if that is a
level five i would say i do about a
three and a half to a four i like to
leave some leaves on there i believe
that the leaves do have a function
they're there for a reason but i do
defoliate for a reason let me talk about
several of the reasons why i do choose
to defoliate the plants um
the rooms and commercial environments in
colorado the rooms are hard to dial in
large rooms and keep the uh the
environment the conditions ideal
throughout a large environment
throughout a large space we do get the
rooms somewhere between like 80 and 84
degrees and the humidity is right for
the phase of growth in which we are in
but we've got a range and if you walk
through the room as you go you could
feel it's more humid here it's hotter
here it's not extreme but as a grower
who can
identify that [ __ ] you will notice it so
by defoliating a lot of the leaves i can
prevent a lot of the microclimates
there's not as much uh is it
transpiration respiration there's not as
much i should have researched this i'm
talking really quickly also because i'm
high as [ __ ] there's not as much water
coming out of those leaves when i water
that room not having so much water in
the room reduces my opportunity for
powdery mildew in colorado we are
notorious for getting cholera or for
getting powdery mildew every time the uh
the season changes right now we're going
from the cold and wintry season into the
warmer spring season it seems like it's
winter one day summer the next we're not
going to get a spring but that type of
[ __ ] creates powdery mildew if we can't
dial in the rooms so by taking off some
of the leaf and taking off some of the
water in the room that will help me
mitigate those issues also where do bugs
and problems hide where does the powdery
mildew go where do the spider mites go
on the leaves if we take away the hotel
rooms if we take away the empty beds
there's nowhere for the powdery mildew
for the spider mites whatever other
insect you may run into there are less
places for them to go so we remove the
leaves from the room destroy the leaves
less opportunity less campsites for the
homeless spider mites to chill out in
there
now i'm going to get back to the message
because part of what you say does kind
of lead into more of what i want to talk
about it goes on it says from my own
test and seeing others work it seems i
can increase yields and overall quality
by improving airflow yes improving
airflow definitely helps
the plants are happier do you want to be
in a room when you spread out your arms
you touch your bros everywhere you reach
you can't get any of your own space
that sucks you kind of want to open your
arm sometimes stretch out you want to go
to get some space the plants want to do
the same thing if we take off off some
leaves the leaves aren't dangling
touching each other all the time that
will help them out they will also
prevent heat pockets it also says it
increases
light penetration yes if we take off a
lot of the leaves the lower buds will
get more light the lower buds will get
more density they'll get bigger stronger
more potent you won't have to trim up
that little larfee crap at the bottom
there then it says and my plant seems to
focus more on buds themselves resulting
in more dense less leafy finished
product yes you're setting yourself up
for success because in the end we've got
to cut all the leaves off anyway so if
we strategically start cutting those
leaves off early in flower and as we go
week by week take off some here some
there some here some there when it's at
the end of the season you don't have a
bunch of dreadlocked furry leafy plants
you've got less leaf to deal with so all
of your theories are accurate are
correct so let's talk about timing
i like to defoliate about uh just like
you're kind of doing it here right when
we move them into flower i will do a pop
a twist and a light defoliation then
around day 21 another papa twist and a
light defoliation then around week six
another light pop twist and defoliation
then just slowly defoliate as we go and
let the plants work and then
as i begin to flush i see in a
commercial grow it's hard to time
everybody we got a crew that is trimming
sometimes doing other [ __ ] sometimes
when i can get four or five people to go
into the room that's about to be
harvested i'll send them in there to do
uh strategic defoliation take off all
the leaves with pedials now let's talk
about why i say this i'll remove the
leaves with the petioles the pedials why
is that my strategy because if those
petioles have turned purple they're
probably old enough to have been on that
plant for the leaf to be big enough to
be blocking substantial light that's my
main uh diagnosis my main theory behind
that once that the petiole has turned
purple the leaf is probably bigger than
my hand which means it's probably big
enough to block light to the bud below
it it's probably big enough to uh let
off enough water to create a powdery
mildew environment it's definitely big
enough for thousands of spider mites to
congregate underneath and throw a party
and reproduce under there that purple
color tells me that that leaf is just
probably old enough and big enough to be
removed it's really easy i like to have
simple uh training techniques for people
uh no offense to the people who work in
commercial grows a lot of you are
amazing a lot of you amazing people also
have one day a week where you're too
[ __ ] high to figure out your own life
which hey do your thing pimpin sometimes
i get too high to handle my own life i
just don't do it at a commercial grow
you get lit up and then you go in there
and i've got to give you instructions
and crayons a lot of times if i write
down those instructions and crayons and
give somebody an objective they'll do it
like a [ __ ] robot all day but you
have to be able to explain it to them
like a puppy like they're stoned like
it's their first day at work so if i say
take off all of the big leaves with the
purple stem they'll see the purple and
they'll just go start taking off leaves
it gives them confidence and then
they'll see what they did i could say
see like you remember how it looked
before do you remember how it looks now
now let's go and take off a few more
leaves and just clean it up a little bit
and do another level and i can teach
them it's just a training technique an
easy method of training the dudes uh the
dudettes the non-binary uh growers and
growtex this is getting weird in the
future here uh but that's my way of
training people that's why i say take
off the leaves with the purple starts
now your your girl scout cookies and
some of your stuff like that the soca
souffle is gonna make purple petioles uh
they're probably gonna be real long
those leaves are gonna be big and black
you can leave them on for the visual but
i would probably take them off uh i do
uh probably a level one defoliation on
the first day of flower like a level two
and a half to three defoliation if one
through five is our method here five is
naked and one is kind of just being lazy
i do a level one on day one
around day fourteen i'll hit him with a
two and a half to a three then around
week six i'll hit them with another
level three because they've bushed out
again i'm not gonna go past that level
three but i'm gonna get it back to the
three give it another buzz cut make sure
it's cleaned up in there
you can do
you can go kind of extreme on some
plants some plants however will not
recover from over stripping i've had
some strains that when you strip them
they stall they just freeze up they go
i'm naked i don't have any leaves i
don't know what to do some plants you
could do and they will really take off
and they'll really grow so this is going
to be strain specific environment
specific there are a lot of anomalies
that will factor in here let me get back
onto the email because there is more it
says are there commercial examples of
heavy defoliation
i've seen some commercial facilities
strip them totally naked to where i
would freak out like i if i was the uh
director of cultivation in that place
i'd be writing people up and we'd be
taking a class and it might be working
for them but dude it scares me to see
that sometimes then it says uh what do
you do in your garden when you're
growing for flower maybe you could talk
about the dangers of overdoing it and
going a bit easier and non-synthetic
garden systems i don't think that
synthetic and non-synthetic really makes
a difference in how much you defoliate i
think it's more about the genetics
environment your goal uh mainly the
environment and the natural leafiness of
the plant is that a thing the leafiness
the natural amount of leaves that that
plant makes also some nutrients make a
lot of leaves not as many leaves from
some newts more nudes from another so a
lot of things could factor into this and
a lot of things could factor into how
many leaves you take off some people
don't take off any leaves some people
insist that those leaves are there as
solar panels and they're feeding the
plants uh we're feeding the plants into
the root zone i'm spending a lot of
money on bottled nutrients mixing it up
pouring it into the root zone they're
eating from there i could tell because
the leaf tips are burnt uh we don't have
to worry about feeding the plant from
the leaves as much
they do work as solar panels you'll
learn if you start watching you'll see
when you remove a leaf you'll see where
the more leaves pop up and how it moves
the growth you'll start to learn that
but over doing it is one of the things
you asked about
maybe you could talk about the dangers
of overdoing it yeah you could overdo it
i mentioned it if you over strip them
those plants just might not recover they
might not spit out more leaves you may
have slowed them down burned them out so
my advice there is if you're going to
start schwasing stripping heavily
defoliating new plants if you're in
control and you've got multiple plants
of the same strain which hopefully
you're running multiple plants of the
same strain so we can do an experiment
strip one and a level one strip one at
level two strip one at level three and
continue all the way till one's naked so
you can do some experiments if you don't
have enough to do a lot of anomalies do
one a little bit one extreme and see
what you like better that's how we learn
these plants you guys i am not some sort
of magical wizard i am a jedi i am a
ninja but i'm not a wizard i don't have
any magical uh i don't have a magic wand
or anything like that i've grown a lot
of plants and i've tried a lot of [ __ ]
that's how i know what works and what
doesn't work i know that when i do this
and i do this to plants right next to
each other i can take notes and i can
see what works best and then i can say
shouldn't do that again or should do
that again then i've done a lot of those
experiments a lot of comparisons a lot
of uh tests a lot of trials a lot of
tribulations i've done full episodes
about mistakes you guys i have killed
plants i have killed i've cut down [ __ ]
in the middle because i wasn't happy
i've killed stuff don't don't think that
i'm a [ __ ] perfection a perfect
grower i'm no wizard um i may be a jedi
but i'm not a perfect grower but i've
done a lot of experimenting i've tried a
lot of things and that's how i've
learned what does and what does not work
sometimes you got to try different
things in different rooms in different
spaces sometimes you have to get
creative and inventive sometimes the
things that work for me won't work for
you and your grow sometimes it what
works for mike at mike's grow or bill at
bills grow will not work at jack and
jill's grow we've all got different
goals different ideas and different
strategies but don't be afraid to do
some experiments so get in there strip
the [ __ ] out of one plan kind of
defoliate one and then leave another one
alone take a lot of notes see what works
best for you repeat the process or
repeat the experiment for more reliable
data my dude jack let me wrap up your
message it says i thought it might make
a good episode and if not i hope to hear
back from you bro i think this made a
nice episode i rambled on for quite a
few minutes about this one i said quite
a few minutes i hope you didn't or did
hear that one uh it says cheers man give
your mom a hug for me from prohibition
land in australia jack thank you for the
great message thank you for listening
down there in australia please spread
the show spread the vibes spread the
love to more of the aussie crew shout
out to everybody down there in australia
listening to the grow from your heart
pod cast all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast if you feel like this episode
was educational informative or
entertaining maybe just like to support
the show all you have to do is check out
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen if you
have any questions corrections comments
or concerns you know i would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy let me know what you think of the
show if i said all of that too quickly i
do have a website it is
iregenetics.com on that website there
will be a link to the patreon campaign
there will be a grow help tab on that
grow help tab you can type in all of the
info i need to help you diagnose your
growth we ask a few questions then at
the bottom it says what's wrong with the
grow and we can help you solve all of
your problems send pictures uh type in
all the details let us know how we can
get your grow up to speed let me know
what your questions are we'll get you
going also there's a link to the discord
on there there's a link to the
merchandise store there's a link to uh
vendors on there many great links at
iregenetics.com make sure you guys check
that out that is all i've got for you
for this episode you know i'll be back
monday with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my friend
billy bong smokin and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you