[Music]
so
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
this is episode 734
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon
let's kick it off with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend rasta green thumb let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to my buddy curbside gardens let's
out to captain mojo and made while
medicated let's send a big fist bump and
a thank you shout out to mr mean green
listen to thank you shout out to jessica
k and lots of trichomes let's send a big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
my buddy doc grows let's send a thank
you shout out to b bala and glenn jeroni
let's send it thank you shout out to
frogman420
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to frugalrock then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to the
dad hayes big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show on patreon
before i get too far
i do want to apologize that sometimes
i've noticed the episodes are not
loading on spotify uh stitcher radio
apple podcasts in a timely appropriate
manner i do schedule those episodes to
pop up it is what is it midnight when it
shifts from sunday night to monday
morning i guess that's midnight monday
i'm not sure if that's midnight sun
anyway you know what i'm talking about
the shift in mountain time from sunday
to monday at 12 o'clock that's when the
show should post also wednesday to
thursday that transition it should post
however some of the servers are late
some of them are behind i don't
completely understand the technology
that makes it happen but i know that i
post my file my show to an rss feed
every so often those servers do what is
known as a crawl they make sure that
they've got all the rss feeds caught up
they go through and they do an update
it's like do i have any messages is
basically what they do they scroll
through and they say hey ross jeff
posted some new [ __ ] we'll put that out
to the feed they post it up to their
stuff then you guys were able to access
it sometimes it happens instantly
sometimes it takes hours for it to
happen there are servers that i can't
even get to update at this point in time
a lot of people tell me that my show is
not working on google podcasts i've
emailed them i've updated the server
i've done everything i know how to do
that [ __ ] isn't gonna work i don't know
what to do next the customer service is
basically tired of me they've quit
responding i might be stuck one day i
may get inspired to start over there but
so far google podcast has been [ __ ] out
of luck i noticed that recently stitcher
radio has stopped updating my show
completely i've messaged customer
service there they have not given me a
resolution my point here is i do know
now that the episodes that the shows are
messing up on some servers however i did
not know until a few polite listeners
messaged me if i'm missing shows
if the episodes are not popping up where
they should be when they should be maybe
i don't know i don't watch my show on
every platform as often as i should i
don't check as much as i should maybe i
rely on the audience to let me know when
things go wrong and a lot of times you
do sometimes you do not so i do
encourage you you may you might not even
hear this because you're waiting for an
episode to update someone you don't even
know that this is coming out with this
could be completely redundant however if
i do miss an episode you're wondering
where it went i put it out the server
just did not grab it on time uh if
you're listening to this which you feel
is way late i apologize i'm trying i put
the episodes out like i said i try to
have them ready for you uh sunday and
wednesday so they are prepared sometimes
those crawls don't happen sometimes they
don't grab again i apologize bottom line
here let me know because i'm putting the
[ __ ] out i want to make sure it gets to
your ears where do we go from there the
merchandise sale in the month of april
i'm doing a huge sale on all of the
merchandise on my website that is the
shirts hats stickers uh rolling trays
grinders a few things are selling out so
grab them quickly um thank you to
everybody who has supported the
merchandise sale the sellers sale has
been amazing i did do a coupon code for
everybody that joins the newsletter i
did a coupon code for everybody on
discord and i did a tiered level of
coupon codes for everybody on patreon
the lower levels got a smaller coupon
the higher levels up they got bigger
coupon codes the mod team on patreon got
really hooked up thank you guys for all
of the patreon and discord and what is
it merchandise support that's what i'm
trying to say thank you for the support
on the merge sale i've been trying to
clean out some boxes make some space so
that i can order more stuff having boxes
with like three and four t-shirts in it
taking up a space is annoying we're
going to replenish and refresh if you've
been looking for sizes if you've got new
ideas stay tuned new merch is coming
soon uh it is kind of a one-man show so
i'm a little bit overloaded with stuff
like that i've got a lot of great merch
ideas if you have more ideas send them
to me grow from your heart hotmail.com i
love merch ideas shout out to everybody
who sent me the great ideas i will get
them rolling
it is coming it's just me try to stay
more focused on making seeds doing
podcasts and stuff like that anyway
let's move forward thank you guys for
all of the merchandise sales and support
i do appreciate that the next thing i do
need to give a big shout out to is the
secret discord what there is a rasta
jeff secret stash discord that i'm not
supposed to talk about so i'm not gonna
we're gonna move forward in this episode
we're gonna cover a couple of emails and
i've got a few great messages right here
on the table let's jump right into it
the first one here came from my buddy
alabama man what's up you bad
[ __ ] hope you're doing well this
message goes a lot like this it says
rasta jeff here's one for the show
what is a private grower to do when all
of the testing labs on google require
strict adherence to state laws grower
ids and such are there any labs you're
aware of that accept private samples for
testing unfortunately in the state of
colorado right now we are not allowed to
have our personal private grows tested
to the best of my knowledge all of the
testing facilities have to be regulated
by the colorado marijuana enforcement
division
there is a reason for that a lot of
people don't like the rules and reasons
and regulations but let me explain why
this rule is in place
for a facility to possess the amount of
cannabis which may be delivered to a
testing facility at any one given time
they would go over their legal limits in
the state of colorado without some sort
of special licensing without some sort
of possession limit so if we all just
took it maybe take one gram maybe two
grams of your batch if we all took two
grams or a gram to this testing lab
they're going to have at least ounces
probably pounds maybe multiple pounds of
product on site at one time which does
make them over the limit for their
regular possession of cannabis in
colorado we're allowed to have two
ounces in our possession 28 grams times
two is 56 grams that's going to put them
over their limit really quickly if they
get good clientele good customers they
can't have anything in storage they
can't have a backlog so you can't bring
it in give it to them they can't test it
also there's no legal transfer
opportunity there they have to have a
way to receive the product from
the person giving it to them then they
have to receive it away it's got to be
documented so to avoid any sort of weird
legal complications illegal transfer
illegal possession they did decide to
regulate those facilities by the
marijuana enforcement division which
means only facilities which are
regulated by the marijuana enforcement
division are allowed to use those
facilities so the commercial groves are
the only ones that can use those here in
the state of colorado to the best of my
knowledge there may be little private
pop-up shops that are doing it uh there
are not advertising heavily i don't know
where they are wink wink but they may be
secretly available that is the state of
colorado in newer states i'm not exactly
sure
um
the way the testing is working there one
thing i do have two recommendations that
i can recommend for you
one is they are now offering at-home
testing devices i do not work for any of
those companies there's one company
that's named after a color
if you would like to send me a sample of
your
sample of your thc testing device i
would love to play with that i would do
a solid review on the show if you want
me to buy it for a half price or a
advertising price let's reach out and
talk to each other it's a little
expensive
for a toy that i wouldn't use very much
but if they sent it to me i would
definitely talk about it on the show
advertise the [ __ ] out of it it is named
after a color and it is a testing device
that will test your thc content at home
i have a couple of friends who say it is
a very reliable device now here's what
you can do with it i wouldn't rely on it
to be uh as reliable as a lab and i'm
going to talk more let's talk about that
right now the labs aren't 100 reliable
in my opinion anyway i know how to skew
a lab test i've sent uh one sample two
samples to a lab and have had two
totally different tests i've had the
same sample sent to two labs and had
totally different tests the lab testing
is not a hundred percent accurate at
this time yet anyway so the at-home lab
testing may be just as good you could
pay one price for this device i do
believe it's about fifteen hundred
dollars but once you've got it you can
test all your products the testing gets
expensive if you test a lot anyway uh so
you can get this one tester at home and
test with that it may not be a hundred
percent accurate is where i was headed
but it will give you a range if you were
a breeder and you were pheno hunting or
if you're a grower that is pheno hunting
you're trying to find that phenotype
that produces the most thc you'll still
know which one produced the most one
will say 17 one will say 18 one will say
19. if that machine isn't 100 accurate
we still know which one is low medium
and highest that will be a good place to
start and then test a bunch of products
with that then send those same products
to labs and see how close that testing
comes back compare them once again if
you run a thc testing company that makes
a
an at-home product let's talk because i
would love to have one of those on the
show i'd love to play with that i'm
talking to you if your company is the
name of a color all right so the at-home
testing in colorado the first thing i
would recommend is get yourself an
at-home testing device the one named
after a color is the one i recommend
nobody pays me to say that i've got
friends that have used it they say it's
a great product the next way that you
could do this in colorado
um allegedly i've heard of people doing
this i can't tell you to do this i can't
recommend that you do this i may get in
trouble for that so i'm going to say
what i know people to have done in the
past is to find a cbd testing laboratory
in the state of colorado if you want to
grow hemp or cbd plants those plants
cannot test within a threshold of
cannabis over 0.3 percent so they can't
sit 0.3 or 3 percent doesn't matter
there's a low number of thc those plants
can have in them and if they have higher
than that they're not allowed to be sold
as hemp plants they're no longer cbd
they're thc plants your crop is what we
call hot it's got to be destroyed or
it's got to be mitigated in some way
it's where that thc doesn't make it to
your clients so a lot of those brands a
lot of those farms are required to test
their product they have a testing lab
set up where a lot of people take their
hemp and get it tested
maybe possibly i've heard of people
taking their home-grown cannabis there
that they knew was gonna be super high
testing in thc and zero cbd and you just
turn it in and you say here's my hemp
sample can you give me a report and they
call you back and they go they don't
really say this but they kind of say
this they go you [ __ ] you knew
this was gonna be 32 percent thc and
zero cbd this is not qualifying as cbd
as hemp what are you gonna do and they
go oh thank you for the lab report thank
you a lot and they pay it and they have
a [ __ ] thc report that says 32
that is a shady shifty way to do it but
it's all too common here in colorado
because that is what we've got to do if
a home grower does want to get their
product tested in a reliable safe
effective way and not buy a home testing
device all right i think i wrapped that
one up um
with all the strict adherence to laws
yeah um you're gonna have to either find
a lab testing place that will test a
homegrower stuff buy yourself a home
testing device or be shady and send it
through a hemp testing facility another
way you could do it if you have some
friends that run a commercial grow maybe
you can sneak your sample in with their
sample batch and they'll let you get
away with that but that's illegal i
can't recommend that i couldn't tell you
that you do that but i've heard of
people allegedly possibly doing that
keep in mind rosta jeff is a fictional
character anything we say here is all
for entertainment purposes let's move
forward i do have another email here in
front of me this one says a little bit
like this it says yo ross to jeff i hope
all is well i have a grow question for
you buddy that is my department of
expertise it says if i reversed a female
uh it has hella pollen sacs but no
pollen could it be from too strong of an
sts solution yes it absolutely could it
could be from too strong it could be too
weak it could be not enough sprays it
could be too many sprays there are so
many variables that can contribute to
the sts not working that's why when i do
an sts spray i always recommend spraying
multiple clones of the same cultivar
that you want to produce pollen of that
way you've got
different uh applications will produce
different results i'll hit one plant
with 90 one with 80 one with 70. if i've
got more plants i'll spray one more
often i'll spray one less i'll just do
different [ __ ] that way i know that
something is going to work and i write
down what i did to plant a b and c and i
write down what worked and i remember
that for the next time i grow that
cultivar and i do intend to reverse it
let me read more of the message here
just to make sure i don't skip anything
it says i started with a 50 mil part a
and b to 400 distilled water spring five
days sprayed every three days oh i see
the problem you only put let's see 50
mils parts a and b that may work if you
used the right dilutions of the right
amounts of products a and b your half a
gram and two and a half grams you mix
them in the distilled water started
spraying five days before flipping spray
it every three days
the last spray was on day 20. what do
you recommend
um
i also want to try to reverse this exact
same strain so i don't want to just move
on until i'm sure she won't reverse oh
this is just the first try when it comes
to reversing plants do not ever expect
that first attempt to be completely
successful that is
sometimes that works but some plants are
very picky it doesn't say what plant you
are using some plants are very picky
some plants
will reverse very easily what i would
recommend uh is mix up a fresh batch of
the silver thiosulfate a brand new fresh
batch cut three clones of the same plant
spray one at 90 180 one at 70 dilution
and see what happens then spray
seven days before flip then flip then
spray day one then you understand the
pattern spray on the day one when you
flip and then spray up to about day 24
and then let's see what happens maybe
one of those will spit out the pollen
for you if not i do have other
recommendations we may have to spend a
little bit more money we may have to
step up our game but we do have other
options let's try different dilutions
and see if a little stronger dilution or
a little lighter dilution will work
possibly if you can do more plants let's
spray one of them ah more frequently and
one of them less frequently let's
experiment a little you've only got one
sample so this isn't scientific this is
all uh so many variables so many
anomalies because it is only one testing
sample let's do the test again let's
control it let's take a lot of notes and
see what we get from don't give up you
are absolutely correct you say you don't
want to just move on do not give up
let's try this same plant multiple ways
you know that that one way didn't work
let's see if we can get it to work a
couple of other different ways so if
you're out there trying to reverse a
plant and it didn't work the first time
don't get discouraged i hope you took a
lot of notes i hope you're ready to try
again i hope you didn't have those girl
plants all ready to go already and
you've got female plants in the room
that are not going to get pollinated i
hope we can try again don't get
discouraged put science into it put some
passion into it that is why femme seeds
are a little bit more expensive you guys
we got to do a lot of work to make that
stuff work all right my dude uh who did
this come from there is no name on this
message you know who you are thank you
for the great question i hope the sts
works uh maybe watch that episode one
more time make sure you're mixing
properly then spray three plants see how
that goes if you've got further
questions reach out because you know i
would love to help you out all right i
do have one more message in front of me
that i'd like to read it was not that
one that i picked up right there um
we're going to read this one
all right after some shuffling i found
the message that i do want to read this
one comes from the grow help tab on the
irie genetics website that's right if
you visit
iregenetics.com
iriegenetics.com iriegenetics.com there
is a grow help tab if you click on that
grow help tab it will ask you a few
preliminary questions we ask you what
strains you're growing if you're growing
indoors or outdoors what kind of lights
you're using just basic things like that
to give me an idea of how to help you
then at the bottom it says explain the
problem we let you explain your grow
problem just a few details on this one
we're growing multiple strains which
include hood candy 91 chem to bubba
there's a couple of cool crosses in here
we're growing under leds the plants are
in flower it says they're in week 19
that's got to be week 19 overall because
if you're flowering for 19 weeks you're
a [ __ ] savage it goes on it says it's
in cocoa it got fed jacks um
the temp is right the humidity is cool
then it says the problem
um hey there roster jeff i used to be a
patreon member uh we're not gonna read
all that we're gonna so basically the
issue i've been running into is powdery
mildew toward the end of flower that is
a common issue and i do know why based
on the photos that came with this
message it says i'm at my wit's end with
how to correct this my last run is about
six weeks in i had a pm flare-up so i
knew i needed to change things up as
well as do a super deep clean i need to
clean every fan blade and corner of my
room so this run and veg i stepped up my
ipm with a rotating schedule of defguard
and dr zymes with a final application of
myco stop the day that i flipped as well
as i added a 16 inch oscillating fan in
my little 4x4 all right so you got a lot
of stuff going on in that 4x4 a lot of
preventative sprays however a lot of
those preventative sprays don't stick
around long enough you're spraying at
the end of edge then you've got that
nine week flowering cycle about six
weeks the buds get chunky we get a lot
of activity from the leaves a lot of
water moving around in that small space
then guess what ding ding powdery mildew
pops up
it goes on it says i added a second fan
on the floor trying to create a cyclone
effect
below the canopy to push any stagnant
air up that is a good idea
and then it goes on it says so we're
about to start week three last night i
spotted two leaves with very small spots
of powdery mildew on them i'm at my wits
end and i'm not sure what else i can do
i'll admit i have some fluctuations in
my rh and temp uh never more than 10
points yeah more than 10 points that 10
points could be doing it especially with
some of the things that i see in this
room we're going to talk about it says
i'm about to do a super heavy
defoliation and i'm hoping that i'll be
able to finish this run out but i fear
the worst i'd love to hear your sop for
powdery mildew i think you've heard uh
you mentioned cease before but why i
would love your thoughts on this all
right
i've got pictures of this room and the
first thing that i noticed is that those
plants are way too close together
there are too many plants in there and
it is too leafy uh our dude mind's eye
open said they were going to do going to
go in the room
and do a heavy defoliation
that should have been happening much
sooner with as many plants as you've got
in there as much foliage as you've got
in there you are lucky that it took you
this long to get powdery mildew there's
a lot of activity happening in the room
there are a lot of leaves touching there
are a lot of spaces where there are
micro climates in there there's a lot of
moisture a lot of micro climates perfect
warmth in that room you're always going
to get powdery mildew unless you spread
those plants apart give them some room
to breathe and do a an extremely heavy
defoliation in that room it needs to be
defoliated very heavily i would go in
there on day one a flower and take a lot
of leaves off then when they grow back i
would go in in week three then i'd go
into week six and then right before
flower i would strip them just about now
right before harvest i would strip them
just about naked you've got a lot of
leaves in that room i wouldn't have half
as many leaves in that room as i
excuse me as i see on these plants so
one of the first things to do would be a
heavy heavy defoliation i'd go in there
and just take off all of the leaves that
you don't think are necessary i did a
defoliation episode recently give that a
listen anything with a hint of powdery
mildew get rid of it then take all of
those leaves get them far from the grow
the trash the dump the landfill whatever
get rid of them then clean up yourself
clean up your scissors clean up
everything real well now if you want to
talk about integrated pest management to
help get rid of that powdery mildew the
first thing we need to do is correct the
plants too much leaf the second thing we
need to do is correct the airflow you
may have a lot of moving air but are you
getting rid of the the stagnant air that
old uh sweaty air is that going out
somewhere are you evacuating that
exhausting that some more are you
pulling in fresh air somehow that may
help you out also let's get a lot of
random movement going on in those plants
a fan is going to move the air one way
all the time let's put another fan in
there to make that air mix you've got
one on the floor let's mix the air as
often as possible get a lot of air
exchange air mixing new air fresh air no
stagnant pockets in there i think
defoliating will really help your fans
be effective right now the fans aren't
working past that first layer of plants
every plant that is behind plant number
one is not getting wind there's so much
leaf and so much foliage you can't feel
the wind through the forest is what i
think i'm trying to actually say so
defoliate ah adjust the airflow in the
room adjust the air exchange in the room
that will also help you correct the vpd
the vapor pressure deficit the relative
humidity and the temperature will be
more easily controllable by having less
leaves because the leaves will be
putting out less water you'll have less
humidity in the room it will help you
out also save you on some watering time
you'll be able to water less frequently
because you don't have as many leaves in
there to keep wet
then uh if you really want to talk about
more of an integrated uh pest management
strategy to get rid of the uh the
powdery mildew there are a few products
that i do like you did say that you know
i mentioned cease cease is a great
product i do like to spray that one i
also like a couple of products called
b52 and double nickel those are also
great products for taking care of the
powdery mildew
also sometimes if it gets real bad i
wouldn't be uncommon for me to hit those
plants with h2o2 a very very low
dilution of h2o2 or hydrogen peroxide
people are going to say that the
hydrogen peroxide and h2o2 are the exact
same thing however they are not there
are other products added into that h2o2
if it was the same thing it would not be
labeled h2o2 i think would just say
hydrogen peroxide there's other stuff in
that bottle so i've been corrected on
that before uh it's a different thing
the 30 hydrogen peroxide and the h2o2
product are different things there's
also zero tall xero tall does have other
stuff in there uh those are all three
similar but different products they will
work very well for the powdery mildew
that will dissolve the powdery mildew
dilute it very low uh spray it directly
onto the plant wash it watch it wash and
eat that powdery mildew right off of
your plants all right so those are
products i would recommend i would do
the cease the double nickel i think the
other one was called b52 what's the one
that turns the water purple i can't
remember that one right now grandivo
grandivo may be good for powdery mildew
if i remember correctly um then also
there is xero tall there is hydrogen
peroxide and there is h2o2 please be
very careful using those products
they're very caustic they will burn your
skin they will burn your eyes they can
burn your plants if you do not dilute
them quite properly be careful read the
freaking label
follow the rules all right um my dude
mine's eye open i hope i gave you some
useful advice here uh defoliate that
room dude there are a lot of leaves a
lot of foliage a lot of water happening
in that room uh the less leaf in the
room the less opportunity for powdery
mildew i describe it as if there are no
hotels the hippies won't come to party
if there are no campsites the hippies
won't camp out if you get rid of all the
campsites there's nowhere for the bugs
nowhere for the mildew it will give you
some more success set yourself up for
success my dude defoliate correct the
room then if you still have problems
apply an integrated pest management
strategy that would include i may just
spray down that whole room with xero
tall or the hydrogen peroxide it may
just spray down the whole freaking room
just to make sure there's nothing in
there just to clean it all up all right
mine's eye open thanks again for the
great question i do look forward to
hearing back from you with the follow up
let me see if my my advice helped you
out at all let me know if we did any
good for your grow ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers all of you sexy cannabis
enthusiasts out there i want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast thank you for all the continued
support we are trying to get to 10 000
youtube subscribers we are super close
if you are listening on an audio
platform i do invite you to check out
the youtube channel go to youtube search
grow from your heart podcast just click
subscribe help me get up to 10 000
subscribers i would appreciate that if
you're watching on youtube and you have
not subscribed already now is the time
click subscribe click on that little
notification bell you will not miss any
of my messages i think that is all i've
got for you for this episode if you have
any questions corrections comments or
concerns you know i would love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com please don't
be shy send me that constructive
criticism that positive feedback let me
know what you think about the show maybe
i'll give you a shout out maybe we'll
make some adjustments of anything else
check out the website at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the merch store
there's a link to the grow help tab you
can sign up for the newsletter the
patreon link is there the discord link
is there and if you can find that rasta
jeff secret stash discord you will be in
luck there's some great [ __ ] happening
there some great [ __ ] coming up don't be
shy search for it give us a find join
the party that is all i've got for you
for this episode i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a giant shout out to my
friend james bean and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you