[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode 735
of the grow from your heart podcast i've
got a quick 4 20 wrap up episode for you
sit back relax before we get to the main
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those kind folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend brian p let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to david
w let's send a big thank you shout out
to double d let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to spa city gardener
and do9419
let's send a big thank you shout out to
guido's grow room and call in let's send
a fist bump and a thank you shout out to
all mixed up and randy's farm let's send
a big thank you shout out to operation
high vibes and roll this nug then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
buddy root305 big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show if you are
watching on youtube you may notice we do
have a little bit of a new setup this
may be a quick episode i'm going to
learn this new setup i've got a new
background some new equipment figuring
things out we've got to do a test
episode no need to waste time talking
into a mic i'm going to record it we're
going to make a podcast out of it you
may learn and adapt and adjust with me
follow along let's hang out and learn
the new room and the new gear all right
i said this was going to be the 4 20
episode this episode will come out
actually on 4 21 so i hope everybody had
a safe and joyous and successful 4 20.
it seems like
in the social uh the social area the
news the things we're going to talk
about they have lifted the mask bands
nobody's wearing a mask anymore
everywhere we go the masks are over it
seems like the the pandemic has ended
right on time for 4 20. it seems like
everybody's out smoking again taking
bong rips together taking dabs together
smoking joints together i don't know
when it happened but it seemed like one
day everybody just gave up that old
pandy thing was over it was back to 4
20. i feel like we all got comfortable
they've listed lifted a lot of the mask
mandates right on time for 4 20. that's
a time to celebrate i hope everybody had
a safe 420 i hope you're responsible are
you back to smoking with people are you
comfortable i've been dabbing with
friends i haven't been smoking with
strangers per se but i've definitely
been dabbing and smoking with friends uh
give me some feedback send me a tweet on
twitter it's at gfyh podcast or send me
an email grow from your heart at
hotmail.com let me know where you are
this 420 were you smoking with people
were you taking dabs are you passing
blunts how did you handle your health
this year for 420. it seems like a lot
of people are smoking i've been a lot of
places there are no mass it has been a
great time now let's segue into talking
about something that did change for 420
this year usually in denver we have a
420 freedom rally where people gather in
civic center park and they openly
consume cannabis is sort of a open
what is it a friendly peaceful protest
and a display of uh we want to smoke
cannabis openly and be peaceful and be
civil people so every year at 4 20 in
denver april 20th of course we would do
that in denver colorado at civic center
park uh we would get is at civic center
park is at the capitol i think it's
severe i could be wrong with the words
i'm saying with the location but we all
knew where it was uh that one big spot
where everybody was right at the
capitals at capitol park anyway somebody
correct me give me the right location i
knew where to drive and where to park
and how to walk there i didn't remember
the name of it
anyhow the point is we would all gather
there uh often and smoke freely for 4
20. a lot of people would hang out there
would be thousands of people there there
would be booths there there'd be people
giving out water
vending drinks a lot of people would
give away cannabis it was a good time it
was a good friendly open environment
there would always be a drum circle a
bunch of people smoking weed hanging out
there would be bands
over the years i've seen it get a little
bit more organized and a little more
corporate maybe the word they actually
built a fence around one part and built
a concert inside of the fenced area and
charged people money to get into the
concert which i thought was weird
because
that fence didn't stop the sound we
could still hear all of the musicians
playing but if you want to get down
there into the concert area you did have
to pay some money to get into there
however there have been some changes
this year the 420 rally has been turned
into the denver 420 festival that's
right the 420 freedom festival they
built a cage around the entire thing
they put up fences around the entire
venue around the entire event where we
would normally congregate freely and
they were charging a ticket price to get
into that area they also put out a
notice saying no cannabis consumption
would be tolerated now i know denver i
know colorado i know my friends i know
my crew i'm sure some cannabis was
consumed i'm sure the police were
outnumbered and outdone you can't stop
all of us but they were saying they were
not going to allow permit or endorse
any sort of cannabis consumption trading
giving away vending it was all going to
be shut down and people would be
arrested they also did mention that
there would be i read in one article
said five another article said seven
beer tents available sponsored by local
beer companies so they've really taken a
huge turn with this we used to go smoke
cannabis in the park for free now we've
got to pay money to get in we cannot
smoke cannabis bill we can buy beer at
the place what a big turn
that is partially because of
legalization that is mostly because of
legalization everything is different now
they have changed the rules it's gotten
so popular we've gotten so uh over
consumed overpopulated with people
coming to smoke on 420 inundated is the
word my brain was fishing for things are
different now so they've had to change
things up pay attention in your area in
your jurisdiction your locale when you
are making rules writing proposals for
legalization of cannabis in your area
these are the kinds of things that can
happen
it is great to have recreational and
legal cannabis here but i wish we would
have done several things differently i
wish we would have had places where we
can consume we've had legal cannabis
here
for
i'm going to say [ __ ] over 10 years
12 14 issues we've had legal cannabis
here either medical or recreational
cannabis approximately 14 years i'm
gonna try to remember off the top of my
head we've had legal cannabis here
there's not been a safe place until
recently there have not been safe places
for people to go and smoke the cannabis
which they can legally acquire here in
colorado when you're making the rules in
your area make sure to include places
that you can consume cannabis if it's a
social lounge if it's a medicating
lounge something where people can get
out of their car and go smoke inside
somewhere safely right now most of the
legal states you got to go smoke in your
car you got to go smoke some more shady
and that's illegal that's going to get
you in trouble make a place we used to
have the canna cabinet we used to have a
few places but legalization shut that
down a lot of the rules and laws were
made to put those places out of business
and prevent that from happening so when
you do make those rules try to include
somewhere to consume the cannabis in
your legalization your legislation your
regula your regulations and your
proposals for all of your goods because
we want you to be able to consume the
cannabis which we are legalizing we can
also you want to be able to grow it make
sure you can grow cannabis in your
legalization proposal we want home
growths to be legalized
the other thing i would make sure to
have in there is some sort of legal
events we want to be able to have events
um
it's i don't know what the feeling is it
feels it feels shitty to be honest that
i can pay money to get into this concert
to go see these bands that are playing
and hang out with my friends but i can't
smoke a joint but everybody around i
don't drink alcohol i don't i choose not
to drink alcohol because i cannot behave
responsibly once i do drink alcohol and
i know that about myself i haven't
consumed alcohol since i got my very
first medical cannabis card in 2008
haven't had alcohol since then there's
no need for it i can buy and consume all
the ganja that i need that fixes 90 of
my problems alcohol causes me problems i
don't drink it but everybody around me
is drinking beer getting hammered
getting [ __ ] faced some of them drink
responsibly some of them drink
excessively there's the full range but
i'm seeing lots of different types of
behavior stem from the alcohol i can't
reach in my pocket and smoke a bowl
without checking every direction and see
if there's a cop or security guard
around me because i'll go to jail for
getting stoned we all know i'm not going
to make the argument we try to leave try
to try to chill out an event the drunk
guy gets in a fight the stone guy wants
nachos right we're not going to go there
but legalization put us in this position
where i can only go in there and consume
alcohol all of the alcohol which i can
afford which is probably like 12 bucks a
cup or something but i can't smoke any
weed in the 420 festival kind of
[ __ ] is that so be careful is what
i'm saying when you do write these rules
propose these rules if you're one of the
people that is uh advocating fighting
for cannabis in your area make sure you
include somewhere to consume the
cannabis and also make some sort of
provisions regulations rules amendments
uh to where we can have some sort of
parties gatherings festivals where we
can legally consume cannabis what we've
done here in colorado is it makes it
really hard for the illegal
establishments to participate in any of
the events because they have to
illegally bring product they have to
legally display it it makes a big [ __ ]
show so all of the events now are kind
of smaller than they used to be they're
low-key they're a little bit more
private we can't advertise like we would
like to because that will set us up to
get in trouble we have to be very
secretive until the day of the event we
could be like it's here that way it
limits the opportunity for us to get in
trouble so um to recap on all that make
rules so that you can consume the
cannabis somewhere some sort of cannabis
lounge the dab lounge the smoke lounge
the church of ganja whatever you want to
make it make sure they're somewhere in
your community area jurisdiction which
you reside over for your legalization
amendments and movements to where we can
smoke some cannabis there also make sure
everybody can grow the cannabis they
need to supply for themselves then also
try to make some sort of rules to where
we can have freedom with our cannabis
festivals gatherings festivals events
parties tour the companies that we're
giving our money to every week every
month at the dispensary can throw
parties and have us back like they can
throw on a concert and get snoop and
whiz and they can actually put products
out for us and let us go if you i should
be able to buy if when i get in line to
get my nachos i should also be able to
get a couple of joints or get a dab or
something like that everybody and the
other line is getting a mixed drink a
[ __ ] margarita a hard lemonade or a
12 beer why can't i just buy a joint
from the guy at the counter right here
just get a pre-roll it's probably not
going to be a real good pre-roll but
it's better than not being able to do it
at all that's what i think we should be
able to or maybe some edibles maybe sell
me 25 milligram edibles at the concert
so we can get lit up speaking of edibles
i'm going to do a patreon only episode
where i'm going to eat some edibles stay
tuned and look forward to that one all
right i'm stoned obviously i've been
smoking some uh what was it it's the
garlic banger live rosin from green dot
labs that may be one of my favorite
concentrates i did say it was rosin i
know that's crazy it's really delicious
gets me high as [ __ ] so make sure that
you get consumption rules homegrown
rules event rules make sure the rules
are what you want them because we kind
of
pushed a lot of great [ __ ] out of the
industry when we made a lot of rules i
think it was sb 1280 that really messed
up a lot of things here in colorado we
should have seen it coming we should
have had more people on our side we
should have voted against that we should
have made
more awareness people didn't even see it
coming people didn't even know about it
so pay attention for things like that if
you are responsible for the legalization
movements in your area all right i feel
like i've rambled on for several minutes
about that part i did say this was going
to be a quick show to test the equipment
i do have a couple of more topics i'd
like to cover there are going to be some
discord server updates i apologize if
you have felt uncomfortable on the
discord server if you've had problems
logging in if you've been booted from
the server accidentally or on purpose
there have been some changes in the
discord there will be some updates you
may have to find the new discord servers
there are two servers the ire genetics
irie army community i'm not sure what we
titled the new server page and then
there's also rosted jeff's secret stash
do your best to find both of those
servers um we'll all be there hanging
out you'll know when you're on the right
one uh the old one will be phased out
very soon the new one will be updated
and totally correct
moderated um
managed and i'll be there more that was
i wasn't on the disc the older discord
enough some things got away from us so
we had to regroup rebuild i do apologize
we will be back better and stronger than
ever before stay tuned you guys the new
discord will be popping up probably
right around the same time as this
episode if we timed it correctly another
thing i should mention um where were we
i'm working on patreon content i think i
just mentioned that i was going to do a
patreon episode where i'm going to eat
some edibles
i'm going to try to record that if all
things go well i do have a guest invited
to come over here in a few hours we'll
record that try to get that up to you uh
this month on patreon if not it will be
up early early next month i do promise
that episode is coming uh depends on if
my partner in crime can make it over
here to eat edibles with me on this show
another thing i should talk about is i'm
slowly restocking all the vendors i get
a lot of messages of course i am also
the uh sole proprietor the head breeder
the hmfc of irie genetics premium seeds
a lot of people are messaging me and
asking me where are the seed restocks
you've got to be patient uh it is just
me mainly packing up beans i get them
packed allegedly they get to the vendors
then the vendors do have to take time to
check them in they've got to inventory
count them then they've got to add them
to the website then you are able to
purchase them but keep in mind that
there are a lot of people trying to buy
seeds and a lot of these companies are
smaller than they do appear iriegenetics
is me uh 90 of the company is me i do
have a few helping hands occasionally uh
some small packing stuff and you guys
know that clint's helping out and
there's some stuff like that happening
but most of it is me so i'm overwhelmed
i'm overloaded i'm doing my best to get
the seeds to the vendors then they've
got to get them
they've probably got one person that
works for them that is receiving seeds
from multiple breeders they've got to
count all the packs in inventory them
put them on the website make sure
everything is legit there's a lot to
running a business in the back end that
we may not see so please be patient with
the vendors i did say that i'm
restocking uh when i said that you guys
went crazy started uh harassing
messaging the vendors i appreciate that
keep doing that but your ravenous hounds
give them a couple of minutes to get the
products checked in they'll put them on
the website we don't withhold product on
purpose we're in business to do business
we don't do any business by withholding
product so that's not how commerce would
work so we do want to get them out to
you just give us time understand that
some of the companies are not as big as
they look we do have a large presence
but they're small numbers of manpower
and women power and non-binary power in
a lot of these companies the future is
weird you gotta say a lot of weird [ __ ]
i'm gonna clear my throat we'll keep
moving i'm gonna edit this part out all
right i do have one more very important
order of business to cover before we
start wrapping up this episode of the
grow from your heart podcast i want to
send a big hug a big fist bump uh just a
sincere uh love you bro to my buddy
grass tester we don't need to advertise
grass tester's business but he's having
a struggle uh and i want him to know
that he's not alone i'm with you bro the
entire army is with you the discord crew
is with you we got your back we [ __ ]
love you bro big shout out to my buddy
grasstester also known as jazz keep your
head up bro if i can do anything message
me directly nothing but love big fist
bump bro we're not gonna air your
business but just know you are loved
wanted to make sure to give you a shout
out on the show all right where do we go
from there let's wrap up the podcast
let's end this while it is still good
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters paul and chuckers all of you
beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
i do want to thank you once again for
listening to another quick episode of
the grow from your heart podcast i do
look forward to your feedback on this
episode be gentle with me this is the
first time running this setup um i've
got to figure it out so let me know what
you think send me your questions
corrections comments concerns uh
constructive criticism positive feedback
or let me know what i'm screwing up the
email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
don't hurt my feelings i can take it
also make sure you support the show on
patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
anything else you could possibly need
will be on the website at
iregenetics.com
check it out give it a visit tap in is
what i think all the cool kids say that
is all i've got for you for this episode
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content that is all
i've got for you for this episode you
know i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy trollin and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
foreign
you