[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff this is episode
737 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on an
email about stretchy plants before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend adhd grower i
want to send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to my buddy og roach and the
devilweed let's send a thank you shout
out to a longtime supporter know me by
my guacamole let's send a big fist bump
and a thank you shout out to grow man
stan i want to send a thank you shout
out to romy1 kenobi let's send a big old
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
stashdrop269
i want to send a special thank you shout
out to my buddy kip let's send a thank
you shout out to grow bandit let's send
a big fist bump to quasi then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to our
friend reaper big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends to support the show i
do want to send a big thank you to
everybody who sent me feedback on the
last couple of episodes i got a lot of
responses to the episode about
pollinating a male plant i did go get a
lot of responses to the episode about 4
20 so thank you for all of that feedback
all of those responses i did get a lot
of questions about reversing a male
plant a previous episode was about
pollinating a male plant with another
meal plant i did explain that that
simply isn't possible that is a sword
fight i also did get a lot of messages
saying maybe you could reverse a male
i'm going to talk about that in the
future i did add that to my notes that
is upcoming in the future so stay tuned
there will be an episode with a little
bit of talk about reversing a male plant
to see maybe what it might look like as
a female plant now before i get any
further i do want to also send a big
thank you to everybody who made
recommendations for new strain names
that's right i am a seed breeder if
you're just watching the podcast you
maybe don't know that i am also irie
genetics premium seeds
i am the
head breeder the only breeder the head
dude in charge at irea genetics premium
seeds that is all me
90 of the work that happens at ire
genetics premium seeds is done by me
by me personally i breed the seeds i do
the selections i do most of the
packaging
a lot of the stuff happens all by me but
anyway i am also irie genetics premium
seeds i'm always making new strains new
crosses new things that need new names
recently i posted to instagram and i
also posted to my discord that i've got
a new cross that needs a new name and i
got an overwhelming amount of responses
big thanks to everybody who sent a
creative name suggestion if you sent one
of those cliche names that has already
been taken a thousand times thanks i
guess but to the people that did do some
work and sent me a creative name extra
big thanks extra salute i do appreciate
that i have not decided on the name of
that cross i'm not going to talk about
what it is here on the show i'm not
going to talk too much about that new
strain here on this episode we'll just
keep moving forward because i don't want
to flood the youtube comments with name
suggestions if you were on the discord
uh in the general chat there i did ask
what the name should be so join the
discord check it out there there is a
link by the way to the new discord
server in the show notes and the video
description i did update and change the
discord i mentioned that a couple of
episodes back maybe some people don't
listen to every episode maybe you
haven't found the link i will include
the new discord link in the show notes
and in the video description please join
us on the new and improved upgraded
updated discord server big shout out to
my mod team for holding it down on in
there i just got done in an official
iriegenetics discord mod meeting so we
are trying to moderate the server there
trying to keep people happy keep people
satisfied keep the trolls away keep the
scam artists out of the server so join
us it is a very welcoming environment i
would love to help you grow love to hang
out with you in the voice chat in the
video chat come jump into the discord
where was i i was talking about strain
names i'm trying to name some new
strains and i've uh started doing a
thing when i make a new line of crosses
i'll take a male plant and pollinate
multiple females then that batch of
seeds will all get named kind of by the
same sort of a theme i've got some femme
seeds that will be coming out very soon
they are all kind of loosely named after
fish songs i'm sure you noticed a lot of
the grateful dead femme maybe you didn't
notice a lot of my grateful dead a
grateful dog feminized crosses were
named after reggae artists so i tried to
kind of bulk them into a group that
helps me remember what they are it helps
me identify what they are uh also it
helps other people associate with them
there was also the tmnt line we had
raphael donatello leonardo michelangelo
there was shredder bebop rocksteady it
made it really easy to just say is the
tmnt line sold out you knew that that
was all the reversed blueberries cross
now all of the fish stuff is actually a
reversed afterglow cross i took the
afterglow uh reversed that pollinated a
bunch of stuff all the things from there
got named or are being named loosely
named after fish
songs or fish associations we'll talk
about that in the future
some people will understand what the
rhombus is and some people simply will
not i am rambling my point is thank you
for the help in naming strain names i
feel like a lot of the good [ __ ] is
taken and when people try to give me
strain name suggestions they say things
that are already completely taken
because we're running out of all the
cool [ __ ] i do appreciate the help i
feel that naming a strain can almost
make or break that strain if a really
killer strain a really good cross has um
a bad name or an unappealing or a
non-desirable name people just don't buy
it as much as they would across with a
really cool name sometimes i think i've
got the greatest name ideas and it just
doesn't work ah soccer souffle in the
machine for example those are those were
made together in the same run um and
they are both kind of named after
tributes to two of my favorite comedians
saka souffle of course is a joke from
tom segura and larry king and then the
machine as burke crusher's puts one of
his most popular jokes ever that's where
those names came from the machine sells
very well people don't know what the
hell saka souffle means so they just
don't buy those seeds both crosses are
equally
equally powerful equally as potent
equally they're both bad ass crosses i'm
equally proud of both of them but since
i named one saka souffle i've got a lot
of seeds of that one since i named one
the machine i don't have as many seeds
of that left so that is a good example
of how a strain name can make or break a
cross
strawberry starburst sells real well sun
kiss doesn't sell as well i think
they're equally potent equally powerful
plants and seeds but because of the
names they simply don't sell as much
scarlet begonias that's a grateful dead
song i named that after a grateful dead
song it doesn't sell as well as some
other things and it is i think it was
really missed i think it was slept on
that one should have been more popular
people didn't buy it i think because of
the name of the strain so um naming a
strain can be difficult naming a strain
can make or break the strain in my
opinion some people i had a strain
called bounty killer a long time ago and
a friend of mine didn't want to grow it
because she said the name was too
aggressive and she didn't want to tell
people she was growing bounty killer i
named that after a reggae artist named
bounty killer
and i called it bounty killer because
they gave me gigantic buds the bounty
was beautiful it was a bounty killer
also reggae artist influence name and
there that's where that came from anyway
my main point was thanks for the strain
name recommendations i do appreciate
that i will post more of that stuff to
social media more to the discord also if
i do ask for strain name recommendations
and i can find the person who gave me
the name that i use i will probably send
you a pack of scenes also
i usually don't do this this is
something i should start doing
i've got a name that was given to me i
posted one cross i said hey i've got
this cross it needs a name somebody
shouted out a name i was like oh i'm
going to save that for another cross i'm
not going to use it on the one they were
talking about but it did get curbed and
shelved and actually i think i put it on
another one already if that is now
another cross i know what it's named
that goes on another pack um you'll get
points for that also when i do put that
cross out i'll try to remember who said
that if you remember i'll send you a
pack of those seeds that makes it super
easy that way people get treated they
get a prize they get rewarded for their
creative content all right i'm rambling
about strain names but that's what's
been on my brain all day i've been
trying to name a few things i got a lot
of great fun stuff coming out make sure
you join the discord that's where they
see it first all right i did say i was
going to read an email about stretchy
plants i don't want to ramble too long
maybe too late for that if you notice me
playing with the microphone i did wobble
here i apologize if i look distracted
might be time to replace this mic or mic
stand anyway let's get right to this
email here this one came from
our friend it does not have a name on it
so we're not going to say their name it
goes a lot like this it says what am i
doing that makes my plants stretch so
much that is a common problem a common
issue it could be a lot of things we'll
diagnose that here based on the evidence
we are given it see it it says they seem
to grow the most in week three for me
yeah that is very common um when you put
your plants into flower i call it the 21
day stretch the first three weeks
they're really going to take off then
about the start of week four they kind
of calm down and start building buds
they're just trying to develop space
they're getting going uh that is a very
common thing but there are things we can
do to prevent that to minimize that and
to keep you on track from growing those
plants up into the freaking lights it
says i start them uh day one at 10 to 12
inches tall and they always end up
around 36 inches or sometimes taller
this week this is week four my photos
were taken today he did include a couple
of photos or they did include a couple
of photos
it says i kept the 600 watt hps 18
inches from the canopy to try and keep
the plant short but it made the outside
edges stretch worse i think yes by
looking at the photo i would agree that
the plants on the outer edge of this
room did stretch worse they did not stay
compact like you would have hoped uh and
i know why we'll talk about that it says
it is a seed run that may account for
for some variation but it's wedding cake
not a tall plant by any means
um so you say right here that you did
raise the light from the canopy uh that
is why they're stretching that is not
enough light for that amount of space
they would prefer more light if you had
a thousand watt in there or maybe even a
an led light with the appropriate
spectrum they would not stretch as much
so a lot of the issue is light they want
more light i see that you have got the
kind of light that has got the wing that
you can bend and flex you've got it bent
down to create a very tight arc from
that shield that is a reflector is what
that piece is called
the umbrella piece that is making the
light stay inside of that reflector and
reflect around if you can bend that out
more and spread that out to get the
light you'll watch it happen as if as
you lift the sides of those wings up the
light will come out to the side more and
those plants on the side will receive
more light that will be the first thing
i would do then i would lower that light
i would start with lowering it about six
inches and if it didn't do anything good
i'd go about six more i'd watch until
those plants start to look like they're
almost mad then i'd go up a little bit
but i drop it down six inches right away
so spread that wing a little bit drop
the plants down six inches now you're
gonna spread that light more and you're
gonna penetrate a little more deeper
into that canopy the main problem is
those lights those plants are not
getting enough light that is the main
issue about those plants that i can see
um
now basically plants are going to
stretch that is what's going to happen
you can minimize that by giving them
more light you can minimize that by
using a trellis net to hold them down
pull them down you can use a tomato cage
you could pull them into the tomato cage
and spread them underneath there and
then when they grow up you pull them
under the next level of the tomato cage
kind of weave them in
you could drill holes in the top of your
buckets and you could put a
string on the branch and you can pull it
down and then tie it to the bottom of
the bucket i've seen that done
now people are making 3d printed plant
light stress or low stress technique
clips so you basically pop the plant a
little bit and put this clip on it and
it will hold the plant at a 90 degree or
a 45 degree they sell a couple different
styles it'll just bend that plant right
over for you the plant will start to
grow horizontal over a couple of days
it'll go straight back up then you grab
it a little further down and do it again
you can manipulate the plants to keep
them low that is something that you'll
have to learn to do as a gardener once
you find the phenotype which you want to
work with that's another thing that i do
want to talk about here in this room uh
we'll get to that another thing we could
do we can pop and twist these plants a
little bit something i really like to do
as soon as i put the plants in flower
day one i move them to the flower room
clean up the legs do a lollipop do a
little defoliation do a little uh
shaving the legs some popping and
twisting is the next thing i do i talk
about this a lot i simply grab the plant
with two hands and i twist different
directions to where you achieve like a
knuckle popping sound i'll do it
i don't have any knuckles to pop i'm
there we go you'll get that sort of a
sound when the plants make that sort of
sound you have now broken the cellulose
fiber of that plant
don't bend it sideways don't bend it
over just twist it and you'll pop it now
what's going to happen is that plant is
going to spend a lot of its energy
refocusing on that little popped and
twisted part it's going to heal that
it's going to make a knuckle
a knurled spot if you will that little
section will be stronger than it ever
was before also it's going to support
the buds better than it would have
without that but also what you're doing
you're slowing down the stretch because
now the plan is spending energy
repairing all of those pops and twists
because i'm going to do it i'm going to
start at the main stock i'm going to go
all the way up the main stock then i'm
going to go each branch all the way up
and pop and twist as much as i possibly
can and cause a lot of it's low stress
training to this plant just by popping
and twisting it now it's going to spend
a lot of energy repairing and recouping
all the damage that we just did instead
of growing tall it's going to just go i
can't grow tall i got to fix all my
broken arms and my broken knuckles we
didn't do a lot of serious damage to the
plant but we did enough to refocus the
energy on repairing instead of growing
tall now we're not going to damage any
buds any weed any flower development
because that's not even happening yet
the plants are still transitioning into
their flowering hormones that's why
they're starting to take off so rapidly
there are nutrients we can feed our
plants which will mitigate that stretch
maybe if you reduce the nitrogen that
will slow down that stretch i like to
give my plants shine right at the start
of flower and i notice that that does
reduce the stretch a little bit there
are a lot of products out there that
will claim to reduce stretch
do some reading do some research but
the main thing i would think about is
this is plant and phenotype specific
this is your first run with these plants
these came from seed
i would have flowered these much sooner
i've seen your grow space and it is a
little packed in there the plants are a
little stretched out they're a little
tall
and we don't even know if we've got
males or females or intersex plants or
mutants or keepers at this point
and you've been vegging for
at least 30 probably 45 days based on
the photos that i've seen
so you're already 45 days into these
plants and we don't know if they're
going to be keepers we don't know if
they're total trash or if they're gold
they could be either or you said you
have got some i think you said wedding
cake that could turn out to be a hundred
percent intersex plants or that could
turn out to be hot hot fire i'm not sure
what you've got either are you we don't
know until you flour them out finish
them dry them cure them smoke them and
approve them or reject them so what i
would have done is i would have grown
these much much smaller and then
flowered them much earlier my plants
would have been about the size of your
plants when they are finished my test
run of plants would be as big as yours
are now when they are done i would be
done already those would have been into
flower i would have sex them i would
have pulled out the males i would have
had them finished already we'd be drying
curing them and smoking them while
you're still vegging not really you're
only like 45 days in but i'd already be
a few days into flower with plants that
are brand new i wouldn't spend that much
time
lights energy electricity water soil
nutrient space i wouldn't have given
them all of that without knowing if they
were keeper plants so
one of the things i would have done
i would have put those plants into small
pots i would have grown them out until
they were six or eight inches tall then
i would have put them into flower until
i can identify the males and females i
would have pulled the males out of the
room immediately then you have a
decision to make do you want to re-veg
or do you want to cut clones i would get
a clone or i would dedicate to re-veging
at this time right now i'm limited on
numbers i would go with the re-veg
situation so we just move forward you
can either
keep flowering these plants or you can
veg them until they get a little bit
bigger and then flower them out but once
those boys are out of the room at this
point i would probably just keep
flowering keep flowering them out then
find the good females out of that batch
there's going to be a shitty one there's
going to be an amazing one there's going
to be one that tastes good there's going
to be one that harvest heavy you've got
to find the plant out of that batch that
works best for you do you want that tall
stretchy phenotype do you want that
short squat phenotype do you want the
one that makes the super dense buds and
tastes real good do you want the one
that makes a little fluffier buds but
gets you super high there's going to be
different phenotypes to select for in
there and i would have done the phenol
hunt before i did the big dedicated grow
which is kind of what it looks like you
did then we could have found out does
this one get tall does it get stretchy
what does it do then you can dial in
your environment for the specific plant
right now you got a big jungle uh some
plants are 18 inches tall some are 36
inches tall by the time you get midway
through flowers some are going to be
touching the light you're going to have
to get some and bend them down you're
going to have a lot of work to do so in
the future i would recommend flowering
smaller test plants don't waste a lot of
time space energy money and investment
on something you don't know is going to
pay off the return on investment is very
important especially nowadays the
cannabis is losing value electricity is
going up everything costs more we've got
to pay more attention to the return on
investment so i think the thing to take
away from this piece is to set yourself
up for success before you fill that room
or even your outdoor this does apply to
outdoors i've done a full episode on
this on outdoor growing before you fill
your room with giant plants and grow
them real big and give them a lot of
time and love let's find out are they
males are they females are they intersex
are they mutants or do you have the
plant that you want to work with let's
do a proper phenol hunt let's find the
plants we need then let's repeatedly
grow those let's be real careful this
year not to put
male plants outdoors and ruin other
people's gardens let's be real careful
not to put intersex plants outdoors this
year and ruin other people's gardens
let's be more selective let's be more
careful let's put plants outdoors that
we're going to enjoy smoking all season
because if you do it right you're going
to grow a bunch of it let's not put some
b-grade [ __ ] out there that somebody
else selected that they didn't really
want that they gave to you because it
was extras in their grow let's put some
good [ __ ] out there let's be more
selective let's pay attention set
yourself up for success if you have the
option to run that seat indoors and find
if it's a male or a female find the
keepers find the best plants that is the
ideal way to do it the first time you
run these plants is just the first day
don't expect uh the amazing outcome from
the first eight that's not going to be a
cash crop that's not going to be a
profitable crop you can definitely
you'll have medicine you'll have product
from that first run but this is your
inaugural test crop this is how a farmer
finds the plant that works for them the
first one is an audition the casting
couch this is tinder this is your
swiping right now you got to go on that
first date you got to find the one you
like then pamper that one once you find
the one that works best for you all
right i think i've made my point on that
part um don't put some random seed or
clone outdoors it could be a male it
could be trash don't waste your time
don't ruin yours or your neighbor's
garden my friend that sent me this
message i hope i did help answer some of
your questions i would spread that wing
up i would lower the light then i would
probably start popping and twisting and
bending those plants down now because in
the future they are definitely going to
get way out of control um if you're
looking for the keeper out of that pack
i don't know that this run was an
official solid test run because some of
those plants are super stretchy because
of their location in the room
next time maybe rotate the plants around
a little bit so that you get some on the
edge some in the middle and then just
move them just do like a rotation so
they all get a little bit of that prime
light and then they all spin a day in
the week light just move them around
that way you don't get super stretchy
super squat plants all in the same room
my dude thank you for the great question
i do appreciate it if you have any more
follow-up questions you do have the
email address everybody else out there
the email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
send me your grow questions your
constructive criticism your pot is
positive feedback
it's getting hard to talk i better keep
moving let's jump into this next email
here for this episode all right this
next question comes from our friend seth
big shout out to my buddy seth the
question goes a lot like this it says
hey ross to jeff how are you i am great
bro thank you for asking i'm doing
pretty well nice and stoned i smoked
some uh should i even talk about that i
had some machine
live batter from some friends in uh we
can't even talk about where they are
because
then you guys will bother them and they
would like to remain anonymous i smoked
some machine
live batter and i'm feeling great thanks
for asking it says i hope all is well
and i thank you for all that you do
everything is irebro and thank you for
checking on me it says at one point in
my life i was a high school biology
teacher and while while teaching things
like mandalay and genetics and plant
biology i was i would always try to tell
my students pay attention now because
it's free if you wait till later in life
someone will make you pay for this type
of information
most of the time that is true but it
goes on it says thank you for proving me
wrong i love how you are providing all
of this free knowledge so that we can
all learn from our hearts i appreciate
that thank you for noticing i do try to
keep the show free of course there is
the patreon it's where if people do want
to contribute they can so i do
appreciate you noticing but i do put all
of this content out here without
charging you a penny for it all right it
does go on it says i have a grow
question which is great because that's
what i am here for it says i currently
grow organically in soil with an hlg
600r spec and then it talks about the
grow a little bit it says i'm finishing
a run of strawberry glue from th seeds
which is a 7 to eight week flowering
strain that i had planned on taking out
the full eight weeks which would mean
harvest is in two days all right it goes
on it says i heard on your podcast that
for the last seven to ten days you
switch back to an 18 6 light cycle and
i've decided to give that a try yes many
people have said that i'm completely
crazy for doing so but the people have
that have tried this have given me great
praise when i am finishing my plants
when i'm flushing i turn my lights back
to 18 hours on and six hours off yes
that is uh not normally what people do
but i get great results i notice my
plants get beefier and chunkier and they
finish a little more quickly so that is
something i've implemented it into my
grow i do not do this on the very first
run i do this after i know the plants
after i know how long they flower how
long i need to flush them when they are
done that is when i start doing cool
fancy [ __ ] to them not on the first run
keep that in mind so let's keep going
there's more it says uh the problem is
that in two days i don't think the
trichomes will be ready i thought they
would have been ready but this morning
they're probably only two to five
percent amber and mostly cloudy but some
trichomes are even still clear that is
uh they will speed up quite quickly
they'll never be completely even
completely the same it says i feel i
definitely have to take the 18 6 light
cycle out to the full 10 days which
would be a tuesday harvest date my
concern all right this is where we get
to the concerns is that what if the
trichomes are not ready on tuesday which
would be the full 10 days of switching
back to the 18 6. i think you'll be just
fine going 14 full days with 6 light
cycle maybe even up to 17 days i've gone
and have not had problems
this is why i always say this is why i
say two things
ah always go always plan to go longer on
your inaugural run with the pack of
seeds when you said at the beginning
that this was supposed to be a 78 week
flowering cycle strain i was already
skeptical i would already plan to go
nine weeks with that i definitely
wouldn't go eight weeks i would go nine
just to see
then the other thing that i would
definitely not do is do the 18-6 on the
first run so that you don't run into
this type of issue
if you would have ran it and i'm not
trying to to criticize you or scold you
or anything i'm just saying if we would
have done a run with these plants first
we would have known they definitely
don't finish in eight weeks then we
would have known not to start the timer
too early so then we would have figured
that out but i don't think you're gonna
have too much of a problem they're going
to finish up on time you've still got a
couple of days to go plus you've got a
couple of added extra days always go
longer in my opinion than the original
breeder's recommended time um go 5 10 a
few extra days just to see what the
plants might do you don't even know what
they would do if you don't go that extra
time and they're not definitely not
going to be done if you would have done
the light cycle the regular cycle with
the breeder recommended so your concern
is that the trichomes are not ready on
tuesday which would be 10 full days of
switching back to the 18 6 light cycle
if i let the plants go even longer to
get 20 to 30 percent amber trichomes do
i run the risk of re-veging these plants
if i have to go longer than 10 days
18-6 should i switch back to 12-12 no do
not switch back to 12-12 that will freak
them out more than anything you've
already given them a hormone shift in
the i said hormone shift i apologize if
you caught that both times i said it
you've already confused them that will
just make them even more confused
they'll start doing wonky [ __ ] leave it
on the 18-6
let them finish out if you see any signs
of revenge you'll know what it looks
like at the tips of the buds they'll
start doing weird [ __ ] cut it down right
then begin flushing now be prepared to
cut right away but i think your plants
are going to finish up on time in the
next few days you'll notice that over
the next few days they'll just finish up
for you they're done and they're on that
light cycle that makes them go more
quickly they will finish up if you've
got to cut down before they are 20 to 30
amber that will not be a big deal you
will still have quality potent smoke i
don't think it's going to ruin the crop
for you so pay attention uh see if they
start looking like they're re-vegging as
soon as you see reveg cut them also pay
attention to the trichomes i would go
about 15 to 20 amber then i would cut at
that point but i do not think you should
switch back to the 12 12. now there is a
second half to this question it does go
on it says my next question is about
breeding these are my favorite questions
it says i'm about to become an amateur
pollen chucker and i just germinated
four of your firefly seeds with the
paper towel method for the record i
tried to germinate six and all six
showed a taproot coming out and i
planted them uh it talks about that and
then uh 100 germination rate it looks
like a couple of diet and i'm not sure
why we don't cover that i says my plan
is to get a cutting of another strain
from a friend and cross it with the
firefly with the dual goals of making
firefly a little bit shorter and to
really push the skunk nodes i know that
you always seem to give permission to
breed with your gear but i at least
wanted to ask permission and show you
respect you deserve not to mention i
wanted to make sure that you did not
have any plans to do the same cross
being that you are a professional and
this is your business and i'm doing it
for fun
dude
you have got my full blessing everybody
out there if you're listening or
watching or if somebody's reading this
to you or whatever you've got my full
permission to breed with my seeds and my
strains i did not invent cannabis i
don't own weed
i don't have a copyright on seed
breeding that is not me that's not my
way i make seeds just like all the other
breeders make seeds just like you're
gonna make seeds i didn't
sneeze some seeds out of my ass one day
and create a strain i had to get seeds
from other breeders you see me honor the
breeders that i work with that's all
that i ask you to do when you do breed
with my stuff if you post a picture say
this was whatever across the roster
jeff's firefly or firefly cross to
whatever give me some credit i would
love that that's all you've got to do
and maybe send me some of them i do
appreciate getting uh seeds from my
friends in my mailbox that is always
awesome but i do invite you to do some
breeding um find the plants that work
best for you grow them a couple of times
uh understand why i have a good goal it
seems like you do and then do your
breeding bro grow from your heart breed
with love and show me pictures of the
results it says if this email makes it
to the show please don't read this
sentence all right
um no i don't plan on working with the
cross that you're working with and i uh
i'm not even a fan of that plant no
offense to it that's just not my thing
so you're gonna do something totally
different than what i would do enjoy
then it says finally do you have an
application to become a seed tester i
could not find one on the website i'm
not an expert grower but i am not a noob
either obviously any seeds that you sent
me would automatically refrain from
doing any pollen chucking
or anything else for that matter other
than testing them i do appreciate that
thank you there is not an official
tester application i have put out an
episode about testing seeds i basically
ask you to watch that episode send me an
email then if you want to be a tester
you will be required to join the new
discord server and post all of your test
photos on the new discord server in the
tester section that is what i would like
if you're qualified and able to do that
send me a message maybe send me a few
pictures of your grow just say hey these
are the pictures i could take this is
what i can do uh let me know that you're
uh detail oriented let me know your
skill level and then i will consider you
as a tester so send me that email
i will do my best to get test seeds out
and i do appreciate that you know better
than to breed with my test seeds that is
always frowned upon in the tester
community i don't know that those seeds
are any good i don't know the future of
my new cross i hate it when people breed
with [ __ ] that i send them as testers
that's not cool let me do what i'm gonna
do with it before other people get out
there and do their thing with it uh
that's why i trusted you with testers
anyway um
yeah send me a message about testing
send me some pictures of your growth
send me some details watch the tester
video i do uh have a few rules and a few
a little bit of criteria that i would
like run them as soon as possible don't
share clones don't share seeds don't
share pollen don't do anything with them
until i give you a go ahead uh but yeah
please do send me an application send me
an email about it it goes on it says
sorry for the long email stay irie and
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me cheers from your friend seth ps
i'm in new york now so things are legal
big shout out to our friends up there in
new york extra thanks to my friend seth
for the great message seth i hope i
answered all of your questions in great
detail i look forward to seeing the
breeding project that you do create with
my firefly if you have any more
questions please do follow up
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
all of you sexy cannabis enthusiasts out
there i do want to thank you once again
for listening to episode 737 of the grow
from your heart podcast if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining maybe you just like to
throw me a couple of bucks for taking a
moment out of my day all you have to do
is visit patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen of course i do invite you to join
the new and upgraded and improved
discord server there's a link in the
show notes and in the video description
come hang out in the smokers lounge chat
cannot wait to meet you there don't
forget about the website
iriegenetics.com anything you may need
is at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the discord there's a
link to seed vendors there's a link to
the merch store anything you can imagine
will be on the website give it a click
give it a visit all the cool kids say
tap in all right that is all i've got
for you for this episode you know i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content i want to give a big shout
out to my buddy misfit and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
you