[Music]
so
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode
738 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to focus on a
grow question about flowering our plants
outdoors before i get to that part of
the show let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those kind folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
caribou heart tv let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to single t
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy danny potts let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to rut ro
and kanna reaper let's send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy pack northwest
dan let's send a big thank you shout out
to choke norris i want to send a grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to our buddy spartan420 let's send a
big thank you shout out to captainmojo i
want to send a thank you shout out to
our dude frankie let's send a big high
five and a thank you shout out to rosta
green thumb i want to send a special
thank you shout out to my buddy sam
heads then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to thor's trike factory
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the show
speaking of patreon i did have the honor
the privilege the pleasure uh whatever
other peace starting words you want to
throw in there to record a patreon
podcast with my buddy mike that's right
it was an honor a privilege a privileged
patreon podcast if you will i'm just
exaggerating now i did record a patreon
only podcast with my buddy mike mike
came over uh recently we sat here for
two or three hours we ate a bunch of
edibles and we did a podcast we uh we
did not cover any grow talk we made sure
not to cover grow talk i don't want to
waste grow talk on the patreon only
episodes uh if you are watching this
check out the patreon episode where mike
and i eat some edibles we get lit if
you're not already on the patreon now is
the time to join the patreon mike and i
do eat a hundred milligrams of edibles
we smoked a lot of dabs smoked a lot of
flour mike got a little quiet toward the
end of the show i was super lit it was a
good time that will be a patreon only
episode my point is we did not do any
grow content in that episode because
i've promised the listeners that i will
keep grow grow content free i want
everybody to be able to grow the best
product we possibly can grow medical
patients need the best product
recreational consumers need the best
product you need to be able to grow the
best i don't want to put that behind a
paywall i want the grow lessons the
education to be free so what we did was
we gave the patrons a bonus episode of
just hanging out getting lit kind of
connecting with us chilling out i think
it was a good time i hope you will enjoy
it if you watch that please send me some
feedback because we want to do more of
those episodes once again thank you to
mike for popping in and doing the
patreon episode and i do encourage you
invite you uh implore you is that the
word i'm looking for go check out the
patreon and check out the video that i
recorded with mikey will be up i will be
up at the beginning of the month of may
the patrons for the month of may will
get that video i'm going to try to
provide a patreon video once a month it
may contain mike it may just be me and
maybe other people who knows what could
happen send me your ideas all right
let's quit rambling about patreon i said
that i've got a grow question here in
front of me um outdoor season is quickly
coming upon us people are setting up
their plants indoors a lot of people at
least are vegging their plants indoors
they're going to veg indoors if you're
doing it correctly last year you ran
some seeds or got some clones or got a
plant from somebody then you grew that
and you made sure that it is quality if
you grew from seed hopefully you
eliminated the boys who eliminated
anything intersex you eliminated
anything problematic and you found a gem
of a keeper that you want to put outside
this year so you've done your research
done your work you've got a quality
plant to put outside now people are
vegging those they've some people have
been vegging since january they started
their clone their seed however they want
to do it since january it's getting big
they have now sexed it they've made sure
it's a female they've got a clone of it
they know what they've got it's getting
bigger and bigger they're going to put
it outside pretty soon i'm going to see
on social media a lot of people saying
that they put their plants outside and
immediately when they put them outside
they went into flower and they're going
to go into flower too early then those
plants are going to go back into a veg
they're going to continue a little bit
of a veg cycle then once they get
settled into that veg phase mother
nature out there is going to adjust to
the actual flowering cycle then they
will want the plants to go into flower
they'll go into flower they're going to
be weird they're going to be upset
they're not going to be the quality
which they could have been if we timed
this better if we understood what was
going on
what's going to happen
a lot of people are going to take their
plants from their grow room or they're
giving them 18 hours of light 18 and 6
maybe more maybe 24 hours of light and
they're getting a direct light from an
led or an hps or maybe it's just a t5
but they're getting a lot of direct
light out there and they're not getting
any stressors and you're giving them a
solid light schedule and you're going to
take them outside because you think by
looking at the sun and the sky
that we're getting more than 12 hours of
light outside so those plants should
continue
to veg outdoors is what a lot of people
think but sometimes that doesn't happen
and that is because of a couple of
factors i do have an email that i want
to read this will set me up to get
further into this topic i may skim
through this because there is a lot of
this email it's not all necessary um our
friend is as long-winded as myself here
so let me try to edit this and we'll
make something out of this message it
says bro
i really appreciate the way you do what
you do you are a positive light and you
are contagious
um that is awesome somebody taught me a
long time ago that smiles are contagious
uh somebody also taught me that uh don't
complain because nobody gives a [ __ ] and
it makes people just not want to be
around you so try to smile try to have
the good vibes especially when a
camera's on there's no reason to come on
a camera when i'm in a bad mood not
having a good vibe i do have uh bad days
[ __ ] does happen in my life i just don't
share that with the world there's no
need to put that [ __ ] out there uh just
shed love and light so thank you i'm
glad that you noticed that i'm glad you
like the way i do what i do uh because
i'm just doing it the way i know how to
do it i couldn't change it if i tried so
thank you it goes on it says you are an
extremely thorough you are extremely
thorough in the way you teach that's why
i'm pretty stoked and i think i might
have something for you to riff on here
and pretty much never gets covered by
anybody that is i've read this email
you're very correct this does not get
covered by a lot of people a lot of
people don't understand uh this concept
this phenomena here is it a phenomenon a
phenomena
um i should have did that research
should i learned the words right i speak
a lot of english i should know the words
uh but anyway uh you're right nobody
does talk about this a lot so i
appreciate that you think i am a
thorough teacher sometimes people say
that i will repeat myself and beat a
subject into the ground too many times
that's because there are different types
of learners some people learn visually
some people learn hands-on some people
learn by being told some people have to
have the combination of all three some
people need [ __ ] literally beating into
them so i try to approach a topic
multiple different directions give a few
different ways to learn the same thing
because there are a lot of people
watching the show and a lot of people
learning from uh they have different
learning styles i want to make sure to
get everybody i know that stoners have
add
we all we didn't like school because we
had somebody just lecturing us about
some [ __ ] we didn't care about but we
all like to learn we're passionately
curious about stuff we care about i just
didn't care about a lot of the [ __ ] in
school i am rambling this goes on it
says i want to say something about the
process by which cannabis plants
transition themselves from a vegetative
stage to a flowering stage outdoors that
is a very good uh conversation to be had
at this time of year it says
i think and he has think in capital
letters i think it is right to call this
thing that happens as a trait just like
the flowering time is a trait that can
vary between sisters the flower trigger
event varies greatly as well from plant
to plant this is my experience anyway
typically the equatorial satival sativa
dominant varietals can be put up to a
month earlier than your endica heavy
varietals with no chance of early flower
and a resulting revenge but not always
so this is a great topic if you haven't
followed along to what this person is
saying they are addressing the fact that
um
some plants so there are traits in our
plants let me back up and cover a couple
of things that he said uh aroma is a
trait of the plant potency is a trait of
the plant a characteristic an attribute
of that plant flowering time is a trait
of the plant
there's a thing that we haven't talked
about a lot in uh the podcast space
which is called the critical period
critical period is also a trait within
the plan i agree with you i believe i
think that you are correct that what is
known as the critical period is a trait
for each plant and what my friend is
talking about
is when we put some plants outside they
will flower sooner than other plants put
outside if you put a heavy indica plant
and a heavy sativa plant outside they
will begin to flower at different times
because those plants are from different
parts of the world so uh in one part of
the world they had more light in the
other part of the world it got dark
sooner and those plants just adapted to
that environment evolution did that that
was just years and years of evolution of
the plant maybe it was breeding maybe it
was evolution ah that's why we've got
autoflower plants autoflowers naturally
happened if you think about in alaska
there are time periods for months and
months and months where they don't get
dark but these plants are growing and
the plants finally said hey i'm just
going to [ __ ] flower you're not going
to give me any dark time i'm just going
to flower i'm i'm tired of growing uh a
cannabis plant's main goal is to
reproduce the main goal of our cannabis
plant its goal not our goal we prevent
this from happening the cannabis plant's
main goal is to produce a seed drop that
seed into the ground to continue its
generation next year it's life next year
the next filial generation we interrupt
that process by pulling all the males
out there we don't allow the pollination
we don't allow the seeds to happen but
cannabis plants main goal is to get
pollinated the females main goal is to
get pollinated the main the male's main
goal is to shoot that pollen just like
people one of our main goals is to
[ __ ] procreate that plant will do
everything it can to procreate like they
say in jurassic park life will find a
way life does find a way so we had these
plants in alaska now we they them
somebody there were plants in alaska
they were growing they never got dark
these plants went hey it's not going to
get dark you want a flower and they had
a meeting and they just [ __ ] decided
to flower and through years and years of
evolution those plants just learned that
it's not going to get dark we got to do
it on our own that's how we got
autoflower plants so that is a trait all
of our cannabis plants have a similar
trait which is known i'm circling back
as the critical period what am i talking
about the critical period the critical
period is the amount of continuous dark
hours that it would take to trigger our
plant into a flowering phase now most of
us are going to say that's 12 hours
right well kinda but
the plants weren't naturally doing 12
hours of darkness and they would flower
that's what we're doing indoors because
that's what worked with the equipment
that we had the lights we were working
with the plants that we happened to have
our forefathers my uncles uh maybe my
uncles uncles probably my uncles were
the guys responsible for selecting all
of those plants and they realized we've
got to force them to flower by putting
them in darkness so they probably just
reduce the light they're like well let's
give it four hours and never flower they
gave it six it didn't flower eventually
somebody realized when i give it 12 it
flowers every time
now did we select plants that flower
under that did we breed at that or is
that a natural thing that's uh so these
plants if we leave them outdoors this is
where this is going if we put these
plants outdoors the plants are going to
flower at different times that would
happen you'll see it happen naturally
indoors but it's not as drastic because
we've bred these plants to all be grown
indoors under these indoor conditions
and we've kind of bred the plants to
work with the rooms now we don't make
the rooms work for the plants we've got
so many varieties and so many different
things in the room that we're breeding
the plants to work for the rooms we need
the plants to work in 74 to 84 degrees
with like 30 to 70 humid i know it's a
huge range but that's what we're
breeding them for to work in those
environments so
something that naturally happens with
the plants is outdoors uh so and all of
the plants indoors and outdoors you'll
see it indoors not as drastically if you
put a strong indica and a strong sativa
next to each other and put them on 1212
lighting they will flower at different
rates you'll notice the indica plant
kicks into flower a little bit sooner
that sativa plant takes a little bit
longer to kick into flower but once it
does it really gets going then it takes
16 weeks to finish that indica plant
will be done eight or nine weeks that's
a trait and that is a critical it's
called the critical period the amount of
darkness which it takes to trigger that
plant into flower
some plants will go into flower with 13
hours of darkness dj short teaches us to
do 11 on 13 off some plants will go into
flower with 14 hours of darkness some of
them will go with 10. just we've done
all the breeding to where most of the
plants work with 12 12 also they'll work
with 11 13 either direction now let's
talk about outdoors outdoors we have
some anomalies
we've all noticed this we look outside
we got our clock we got our timer we got
our watch we see the sun come up it was
seven o'clock we see the sun go down
it's 8 30. we're obviously getting more
than 12 hours of daylight outside we're
getting 14 or 15 hours so it is safe to
put our plants out there a lot of people
move the plants out there they think
it's warm enough if you're in colorado
wait a little longer it's going to hail
on you you're going to get your plants
beat to [ __ ] a lot of people are gonna
go out early that's what's gonna happen
they're gonna say i've got 14 hours of
daylight after those plants are outside
for a few days they are going to begin
to flower and people are going to be
very confused there are a few things
that are happening here first of all you
just went from an 18-6 or a 24-hour
light cycle straight outside to less
lighting the plants are confused they're
gonna go into flower kind of stressed
them out kind of shocked them they're
flowering that's just how they they want
to survive they're going something's
wrong we better flower like they just
want to procreate before the end of the
world they think the world might end
they're just trying to get get pregnant
or make something pregnant at that very
last opportunity so that is why they
start flowering possibly you just went
from that indoor light cycle to the
outdoor light cycle it's so different
they freaked out here's another thing
that is happening
we are thinking we're getting 14 hours
of light however when the sun sets as
the sun begins to set you may see this
with your eye you may not see this with
your eye you may notice that the sky
gets a little bit orange a little bit
red as the sun sets so as the sun sets
it puts off a red spectrum which is
known as far red and that spectrum tells
the plants it is time to go to sleep
that triggers something within the plant
called phytochrome red and that
phytochrome red is basically the way
that the far red and phytochrome uh work
together when they touch that is
basically nyquil or ambient for your
plants it goes night [ __ ] and they go
oh look far red let's trigger
phytochrome and then they go to sleep it
just puts the plants to sleep so that
triggers them to go to sleep earlier
than when that darkness happens in the
indoor grow unless you've got one of
those new lights with the far red
lighting which they just started adding
a couple of years ago big up to that but
until then we did not have far red
lighting indoors so we had to turn off
the light and at that point the plants
were not asleep it takes them an hour or
two to actually fall asleep completely
and begin their dark cycle the night
cycle process takes a little bit to kick
in so they couldn't kick that in until
an hour or two after we actually put
them to sleep
okay i do apologize i was interrupted by
a delivery i am back on track now i do
not remember where i was i know i was
talking about phytochrome red i was
talking about the different plants going
into flower at different rates i'm not
exactly sure so we're going to jump in
right here a lot of people are growing
sativas a lot of people are growing and
because most people are growing straight
hybrids at this point most of your
sativas are going to take 16 weeks ish
to fill to finish out if they're a real
that's what i mean by a sativa most of
your indica stuff is your eight or nine
maybe maybe the 10 weaker stuff with
that big fat leaf that's the indica
stuff you're going to notice that some
of those plants will go into flower
earlier outdoors and some will go into
flower later outdoors that is called the
critical period you've got to get that
critical period of the right amount of
darkness for each plant and that's going
to be dependent on where that plant came
from where did the parent plants come
from which part of the world did that
plant start from now with all the
breeding
you've got plants that are they got
parents from all over the place so it
just kind of depends on which phenotype
it leans toward i do have some notes i
want to make sure i get onto all my
notes here because i haven't looked at
my notes at all i've just been talking
off the top of my head what we were
talking about here is the critical
period this could be very different
between different phenotypes if you've
got a pack of seeds and you put them
outside one may flower much earlier than
the other that is just different
phenotypes that is expression that's all
about uh the genetic location and origin
of that plant that's what i was just
talking about where did that plant come
from if you've got a plant that came
from alaska it may autoflower on you
some plants may flower as soon as you
give them a little bit of darkness some
may need a lot more darkness to trigger
into flower that's just going to be
genetics that's just like a lot of other
parts of our plants sometimes the plants
want more calmag sometimes they want
more nitrogen sometimes they need more
dark period that's how we've got
autoflower plants i touched on that at
the beginning uh they're autoflower
plants because up in alaska it just
wasn't getting dark up there in certain
parts of russia it wasn't getting dark
so the plants were just like hey we got
to do something dude or we're just not
going to be able to get to the party and
they wanted to party just like we all do
uh we chose 1212 because uh that seems
to be what works for most plants like i
touched on a minute ago you can do 11 13
either direction 11 on 11 off 13 on 13
off as long as you got a 24 hour light
cycle right there you could do 11 13.
i've seen 10 14 both directions it's all
about trying it with your plants and
what works best for your plants you guys
you've heard me talk about switching my
light cycle to 18 6 at the end don't be
afraid um a lot of people think that
when i talk about experiments
experimenting with my plants i'm talking
about doing this in like a 25 by 25 room
with [ __ ] 25 lights in there that's
not how i do it when i'm doing
experiments i do in a little teeny tiny
space where i can't ruin a whole bunch
of [ __ ] at one time so get one light and
a few plants and just experiment with
those we're not going to get better
we're not going to learn anything we're
not going to advance improve uh
if we don't practice try and fail you've
got to have some failures and some
successes to become better at anything
if it's growing weed if it's
skateboarding if it's playing music if
it's karate if it's ballet whatever
you're doing you've got to fail a couple
of times i got to learn everything the
hard way if you don't have some failures
you're not going to learn anything do a
lot of experiments try a lot take a lot
of notes but don't do it in your big
space do that all in a small space and a
small practice area if you don't
practice if you don't try new [ __ ]
you're not going to learn anything
you've got to fail occasionally i've
done full podcast episodes about
mistakes that i've made don't be afraid
to make some mistakes alright there's
more to this i do think that as lighting
and equipment evolves i think that light
cycles will evolve as well i've seen
other people playing with different
light cycles since we're getting the
proper light the proper spectrum
we've got far red lighting we've got all
we can cover just about any color of
lighting we can replicate it any color
spectrum we can make that with expensive
lighting or affordable lighting i think
as the lighting evolves so will some of
the schedules we're able to give the
plants all the photons all the energy
that it needs so that'll let it get more
sleeping time because it's getting the
dli which i need to do a podcast about
dli but that's uh there's some equations
to be done that i don't understand all
the math but i know what it means if
that makes any sense but with the
technology the plants will be getting
their dli which means we'll be able to
give them
maybe longer sleep periods
who knows how it'll work out but we're
going to learn a lot more with the
evolution of technology i did say that a
lot of the gear we have a lot of the
plants we have a lot of the selections
we have now are because of our
forefathers who did not have the best
technology they didn't have the internet
they didn't have par meters they didn't
have led lighting we've come so far and
also they didn't have legalization we've
got legalization on our side they
couldn't even talk about growing wheat
if they're going to grow weed they
didn't have the internet to do research
they didn't have a bro to talk about it
they just had to do it and hope not to
get busted and see how it goes and try
again they were learning it all from
scratch we're a little spoiled now i
like to say we're blessed we're cheating
back in the day you had to be secretive
you didn't have the internet and it was
not legal at all now we got the [ __ ]
internet and it's legal we are cheating
uh but i think there will be a lot of
evolution in the technology in the
growing and light cycles now that we've
got uh more technology and legalization
and the internet on our side i think
i've covered up all of my notes i talked
about far red i talked about phytochrome
red i said that's basically plant
sleeping pills let's talk about the
opposite end of that spectrum in the
morning the plant the sun puts off a
bluish colored light and guess what that
one does that works like an alarm clock
it says wake up [ __ ] it is time to
get moving and it wakes up all your
plants and they get the day started that
is the blue light that comes from the
sunrise so you get the blue and the
sunrise the red and the sunset that
dictates a lot of the plants movement
and actions through the rest of the day
all right i think that is all i've got
for you for my question about critical
period i know i skipped a lot of this
question i just used it kind of as a
springboard big shout out to my friend
uh where did he say his name oh his name
is taj big shout out to my buddy taj i
do appreciate the great message the
great content thank you if you've got
any follow-ups any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know i would
love to hear from you everybody out
there my email address is grow
fromyourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
send me your questions corrections
comments concerns positive feedback i'd
love to hear all of that stuff also make
sure you check out the website at
iregenetics.com
there's a link to the new and improved
and updated discord server on there i do
invite you to join the new discord
server if you were on the old discord uh
some things went haywire on there that
server has been it's no longer an irie
genetic server it might be running as a
different server i am not involved in
that that is not me join my new real
server there's a link in the show notes
and in the video description all right i
think that is all i've got for you for
this episode i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my friend
james bean and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
so