[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 73 73 74 I
don't know might be 74 of the grow from
your heart podcast your source for
Cannabis News education and conversation
if you're a new grower if you're a
professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran Dabber if you're a
cannabis activist or even someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host roster Jeff thanks
again for joining me sitting across the
table from me is my good buddy White
Mike how you doing bro I'm doing good
how you doing buddy I'm doing great dude
I want to give you a big personal thank
you before we start the show uh my car
has been broke down like you guys all
know and uh Mike was kind enough to run
my errands for me today and he actually
stopped at the dut shop on the way home
so we're all hopped up on donuts and
caffeine right now it's going to be a
great show thanks dude for uh hooking me
up with a ride lately happy too man uh
also while we're giving thanks I got to
give a thanks to the Mystic Roots band
that song that I cut off abruptly there
was the doggy dub from the Mystic Roots
off their album the constant struggle
shout out to cat coot and the entire
Mystic Roots crew I like that they let
me play their music on the show that is
really super kind of
them I also show ohow a shout out to my
buddy de he's working on a new intro
song for me so big thanks to De uh Mike
and I were talking we're kind of hanging
out we didn't have anything to do on a
Saturday night because we're a couple of
bums and we're like why don't we do
something productive and record a
podcast put some time to good use yeah
you know put our time to use right put
all sugar to good use at least I'm going
to be bouncing off the walls here thank
you Amy yeah thanks Amy's Donuts shout
out to Amy's donuts and peblo and
whoever was the the one sad lonely guy
working a
night glad to make you laugh bro thanks
for the sugar we weren't going to stop
and get donuts but as we drove by we
could see into the building that there
was just one dude standing there staring
out the window watching traffic and I
predicted that if we waited 4 hours
without going he may kill himself
standing there staring out the window he
looked so sad and lonely we just had to
go cheer him up I bought some donuts and
Mike gave the dude a fat tip yep that
was nice of you well fat for peblo yeah
it was a donut tip I mean when I handed
it to him it was kind of clear that he
did not expect to get tipped on this
shift well then now he's got money for
whatever he does after work right he's
at least got a story to tell at the end
of the these two super high guys came
through and bought a lot of donuts part
of the directions were to fill the box
with something quote colorful that's
what I said I was like I want one of
these specific Donuts cuz they're tasty
as [ __ ] and then after that just put
colorful [ __ ] in the box and he met that
goal we're looking forward to eating the
lime green possibly apple flavored one
later I don't know what that is a couple
of them got marshmallow on there I
really try to stay away from the
marshmallow products but uh you know he
didn't know that like I said I've had a
lot of sugar yeah we're we're we've been
talking about donuts for almost 3
minutes now so uh there are no ads on
this show we are going to read some news
the other day I told Mike he was talking
about news he's like I tweeted you some
good news and uh no not necessarily good
news good news articles it's not all
good news but he tweeted that [ __ ] to me
and he's like you can uh go ahead and
use that on the show and I was like dude
why don't you go ahead and be like my
news guy why don't you send me all the
news about cannabis that you can find
and that way I can work on the grow
lessons and we can get Mike doing a lot
of news for us I still have to read all
the news and review it but Mike's
searching out the news a little more for
me so shout out to Mike he's going to
keep doing that for us happy too man I
hope got to keep the people informed
yeah that's what we're here for I don't
have time to do uh this Show's news the
grow the spot uh my focus on what you do
best buddy everybody's got their
wheelhouse so having you do news is
fully part of mine is definitely going
to make it a little bit of an
improvement guys if you get bored on the
news shows I apologize but I think it's
just as important as as the uh lessons
and things tweet it both of us tell us
you want more or less and if you find a
news article you want me to read you can
tweet it to me it's gfyh podcast on
Twitter anyway let's find one of these
news articles we were talking about you
ready for this dude yep let's start with
uh let's start with Florida oh Florida
what have you done now well it's usually
some [ __ ] up [ __ ] we hear about from
Florida but this one doesn't involve a
goat it does not involve a chainsaw no
face eating no bath salts that's where I
was headed so this is actually
this this step in the right direction
for Florida yes Florida's going the
right way of course I've got a giant
slide on my screen right in the way here
where did that article go I I'm going to
have to refresh because this website I
am using is filled with ads that I
cannot find the article under all right
there's actually some good news coming
out of Florida this time I'm scrolling
to the article right now and the
headline is Florida low THC medical
marijuana law passes major hurdle I'm
sure you guys kind of know where this is
headed and it says uh this is actually
from the the firstcoastnews.com I got to
give them credit and it says we've
shared their emotional stories parents
from all over the state have been
waiting waiting to get their hands on
Charlotte's Web a low THC form of
medical marijuana to treat illnesses
their children have such as epilepsy
seizures and cancer and it says from
Tallahassee Florida we've shared their
emotional stories parents from all over
the state have been waiting waiting to
get their hands on Charlotte's Web AOW
THC form of medical marijuana to treat
illnesses in their children uh such as
epilepsy seizures and cancer now finally
on Wednesday they got an answer when a
judge threw out a lawsuit holding up the
implementation of the drug Jeff shy
started the medical marijuana Business
Association he's followed the entire
process of Charlotte's Webb from
lawmakers legalizing it last year to
several law suits from potential Growers
halting the sale of the drug to today
with a sale date in sight the rule that
was finally approved was fair and
balanced shy said it's been a long
discussion and dialogue it's been a long
discussion and dialogue and I know
there's been some frustration with it
but here are uh here we are with a rule
that's going into effect sorry guys I'm
trying to cough and read at the same
time uh we'll have people submitting
applications to become dispensaries and
I think Florida is ready for this
Florida's Department of Health has been
the agency in charge of implementing
Charlotte's Web they're expecting
they're expected to take applications
from eligible Growers within 3 weeks
under the law only five will be chosen
to sell it so pretty soon in Florida
there will be five dispensaries selling
Charlotte's Web medicine um I have mixed
emotions about this how about you Mike
you look like you got [ __ ] to say
already it's I mean I feel a little bad
because I didn't follow the story as
closely as I follow most Cannabis News
because it's another Charlotte's Web
state law and while any progress towards
medical marijuana access is huge and
awesome and it's another big win for
reality and science CBD only is silly
and just a it's a half step that no one
needs to take at this point California's
been medical since
1996 all of this CBD stuff in
Charlotte's Web came out of our medical
marijuana system here THC is fantastic
medicine and thanks to the vote last
year in Florida they've got CBD only now
thanks to this law but it's only
Charlotte's Web specific it's the only
strain they can sell and grow realm of
caring did an amazing job trademarking
and getting there name out and pitching
it as safe and not intoxicating um add
that and sanj Gupta together and we've
got 13 CBD only States no I know I said
I had mixed emotions uh one of my
opinions is like you said it's great
that we have medical marijuana in
Florida now so that these kids can get
their medicine and the parents don't
have to watch their children suffer and
the kids can live a happy normal life
but I don't think that CBD only medicine
is the way to go and also like you're
you're saying this one company that owns
the charlott's web is going to make
money off of this like crazy and that's
not a cool way to go about medical
cannabis well I mean if you really think
about it the article talks about the
kids but it's not just children in
Florida that would be accessing
Charlotte's Web medications through
these five
dispensaries there's all the adult
patients with all of those conditions as
well so you're talking about a huge
number of people five business or five
store locations one product brand it's I
mean are we going to run out oh for sure
there's going to be huge product
limitations and it's going to be like
two a ridiculous cost per gram like it
is out here I don't know the price off
the top of my head I almost threw out a
random number but I don't want to do
that because it's ridiculously high but
I don't want to be wrong about how
ridiculously high okay I'll let you live
with that answer yeah it's so there's
something that Mike said that the THC is
good medicine there's something I feel
about uh we used to call it the
Entourage effect in Colorado now the
industry term has moved to the
synergistic effect and that's the effect
of the canabo the paleet the terpenoids
the flavonoids and the Esters all
working together to provide you a
medicinal benefit and just by isolating
the CBD I don't think you're getting the
full benefit of the medicinal cannabis
and you're going to say it works with
the kids and the kids don't have
seizures yeah but for me CBD medicine
doesn't do anything for my medical
condition that I smoke for it works
great for me but it doesn't do
everything I need it to I need the THC
half of that puzzle as well yeah yeah we
see this with the there's been 100% thp
SE pill called Marinol on the market for
decades no one likes it because likes it
it doesn't have the rest of the canono
in it and they tried they tried sativ s
x I just called it sativa X you know
there's one company in Europe that's
doing a whole plant extract where um
they're taking the whole raw marijuana
plant and making some sort of uh I think
it's a sublingual spray is spraying
under your tongue like Baka nice um and
they were testing it for Ms the last I
read so there are companies looking at
whole marijuana plant extract rather
than isolating one or two components
does your friend Dave listen to the
podcast I have no idea he should well if
you do bro shout out I thought you when
he said that we've got a friend that
could benefit from this sublingual spray
for sure did I say that right sublingual
so y nice I just spat that one out yeah
so this is going to work for a lot of
people but I'm a medical smoker and I
definitely need my THC heavy sativas so
shout out for going the right direction
Florida for trying to do the medical
thing maybe this will open the door how
long do they have to just go with CBD
medicine is what I this is this is the
end of what they have going for now I'm
sure there's another uh group working
towards getting uh legalization on the
ballot in Florida either medical or
wreck again in the next Presidential but
I guess we can look at it this
way gosh excuse me guys I had sugary Dr
Pepper and donuts and my voice is
already all [ __ ] up from the
show but we can look at it this way the
sick kids who have seizures and epilepsy
and cancer and things like that that
need help can now get the CBD medicine
and the people like you and I that are
in our 30s that know people that know
some people uh that aren't we're
able-bodied we can go out and get some
herb you know what I mean so that's cool
the kids those kids needed it way more
than the folks that want the sativas so
I guess it does it helps a lot still I'm
a big fan but at the same time I
remember how many epilepsy patients used
to come into the shop I
remember I mean I remember them enough
to have research some of this stuff
after we left and THC is fairly
effective on treating seizures
yes and so having some THC in an
anti-seizure medication that's made from
Cannabis makes a whole lot of sense in
Charlotte's Web specific laws we didn't
end up with Charlotte's Web because it H
or we saw it working great for seizures
and dove into that they found it had no
THC and that certain medical patients
were looking for a non intoxicating
medication and they're afraid to give
the THC to the kids that's the big scary
part it makes a much better pitch when
there's absolutely no THC in there when
you can you just say straight up there's
no high to it you can take as much as
you want there's no intoxicating effect
but an intoxicating effect doesn't mean
non-medical effect it just means also
intoxicating all right let's get out of
Florida thanks Florida we've done a
couple minutes on that news topic I
don't want to bore the folks CBD was big
in the news this week yes uh CBD is
going to remain big in the news news I
think for the next little while what's
the next uh this is a random question
what's the next canabo to pop up that's
going to be popular I'm hoping it's CBG
that's what I was going to say um just
from what I've seen I I I had the Good
Fortune to get uh a small sample of CBG
capsules very neat and uh it was during
a period of time where I had some bad
back pain and oh Lordy they helped me
get through some long shifts did those
come from within our Circle they did I
had some of those they made me sleep
like a baby yeah that was awesome maybe
I need some of those I've been having
some sleep issues lately been smoking
too much sativa and taking the Alpha
Brain y one more reason to get
caregivers back into the testing lab
I've been talking about this Alpha Brain
and when I take it too late in the day
it gives me the most craziest
dreams uh so we just did an article from
Florida let's jump to our hometown here
in the lovely Steel City peblo
Colorado what's up
peblo 719 so the headline here is pelo
County wants to keep keep excess weed
money this article is by Jeff Tucker
from The Pueblo Chieftain and it says
Pueblo County will be asking voters
whether they want the equivalent of
about three spins of the city park
kitties ride or if they could rather let
or if they would rather let the
government use a little less than
$150,000 in excess marijuana revenues
for something else uh guys and AR from
peblo that's a local joke we've got a
park here with some kitty rides it cost
like 50 cents and they're saying that
they're going to write a check for about
three spins on those shitty rides or if
they'd rather let the city just keep the
money uh in the excess marijuana
revenues and use it for something else
so it says the peblo board of County
Commissioners instructed County attorney
Greg SAR on Wednesday to start work on a
ballot language that will give voters an
option on what to do with the marijuana
sales tax money they collected in
2014 as part of the of the exemption the
3.5% sales tax from the state taxpayers
Bill of Rights uh let's make sure I read
that right through 3.5% sales tax from
the state taxpayers Bill of Rights the
county made an estimated income of
$400,000 from the marijuana sales tax
collection in the first year of legal
recreational sales in Pablo County
$548,000
479 was collected from sales tax meaning
that
$148,400
uh let them keep it yeah let him keep it
maybe they can fill some of the damn
potholes that are all over this city
everywhere it's funny that you say that
the the county raked in a huge amount of
money it was like 1.7 million just in
pbl County last year from the marijuana
industry half of that was taxes half of
that was like fees and application fees
and things like that but uh pelo West
Metropolitan District wh that all the
shops were there but they weren't
getting a special cut so the County
Commissioners broke them off like two or
300 Grand and they're Throwing It All
into their streets it's a great plan and
they need their streets repaired as
badly as we do they made a good argument
the shops are all here we want to cut
and so the county said here's your cut
and they said thanks for the road money
was it an extra shitty winter or are the
roads just not getting paid attention to
because they've been terrible here yes
okay I thought it was a little bit of
both one of the sided issues I've caught
down at city council is uh our roads
right now to get them up to speed at the
pace we're doing just to get the peblo
stuff in in order is going to take 50
years that's how bad our infrastructure
stuff is right now and that's not just
peblo that's all over the nation that's
why bridges are collapsing and trains
are crashing wow yep holy crap time to
invest in infrastructure I would rather
have not heard that yep so one of the
big reasons to vote this year make sure
you're registered to vote for this
November election is if you're in
Colorado you're going to have half a
dozen marijuana questions almost all of
which are your state asking if they can
keep the extra tax revenue they
collected last year your county asking
the same question your city asking the
same question
so get registered to vote people
register to vote and guys in the future
Mike is going to come do an episode for
us all about how to get yourself into
politics if you're ready to lobby for
cannabis or anything else Mike is going
to come kind of teach us a little bit I
put him on the spot now he just looked
at me like [ __ ] now I really have to do
that yeah Happ it'll just be a quickie
bro just teach my friends that that are
listening how get into politics how to
get themselves started get them going to
Council meetings and shaking hands
micheel get you on the right track all
right so that was our article from peblo
let's see how long we've been recording
before we jump in anything else all
right we got some time left we're doing
good we are doing very well you need a
dab I could definitely go for a dab I'll
get you a dab you want CBD or
THC I've got what your options are here
this Toro Bora that was grown by myself
and extracted by our good friends at the
Garden of Weeden shout out family much
love and then from our good friends over
at turpex tpy boys what's up fellas uh
and I picked this up over at the green
and healthy wellness in lovely Colorado
Springs I really like that place I was
in a week or two ago very nice guys
right shout out to John John great
fellas John randles Jr what's up
buddy uh we got some deran poison on the
sativa end of things and we've got some
818 headband which in my opinion is more
on the Inda side of things I feel like
I'm on getting dug with high right now I
think it's poison time go for the poison
poison I think I'm going to get sued if
I do that too much longer yeah you get
what 15 seconds There Are Rules around
that and I read them and as long as I'm
not making money uh it's cool if nobody
gets mad if they get offended they can
make me take it down but really it's
like a fair use act law right and I'm
just talking out of my ass kind of right
now I don't remember exactly what I read
but you can and can't at the same time
and it's a up to whoever if I get
permission then I can use whatever I
want like the songs I use in the intros
and outros uh Mystic Roots band is given
me full permission DJ Nick has given me
permission to I totally just tried to
Sab the
microphone so Mike held up the rig and
you're not I don't know if that was your
second time doing it or if you're the
second person but he put his mouth full
on to the microphone and tried to dab
through the microphone yep I went to put
the dab on the nail and for some reason
put my face on the microphone as so that
was going to do anything for me I saw
the process happen in your brain and it
was [ __ ] funny all right I'm going to
start reading this article I don't even
remember what the hell I was saying
anymore uh feds tell their employees to
stay away from marijuana even in states
that have legalized so uh if you're a
federal agent shout out to turpy boys
that was delicious oh yeah big shout out
to the turpy crew we're going to get
them back on the podcast again um I'll
have my car back here within the next
few days so I'll be able to go do a
podcast with the turpy boy crew shout
out to the the Cannabis Grand crew that
happened that's happening as we record
right now I wish we were there but I was
not prepared uh so this article if
you're a mailman what a male person we
shouldn't say mailman cuz they're female
male carrier carrier if you're a male
carrier um if you is this a state park
people if you work for the Department
Park Rangers um anybody that works for
the federal government it's a huge
number of people
IRS FBI IRS can't smoke weed no more no
oh man if I had to crunch numbers like
that
going
up yep uh so let's read the article the
federal government wants to clear with
its federal employees that it that might
live in states that have reformed their
marijuana laws marijuana remains illegal
so don't use it in guidance issued this
week from Katherine archeleta director
of the US office of personal management
that's personnel management uh to the
heads of all federal departments and
agencies archeleta says in no uncertain
terms that marijuana use for the more
than 4.1 million federal employees
Across the Nation is
banned not a shocker no not at all but
what about man people need to smoke
their medical cannabis if that's what
makes you feel better you need to be
able to do that feds don't care schedule
one yeah the feds have high level of
abuse no medical use the feds have no
heart federal law on marijuana remains
unchanged she writes in a letter
announcing the guidance we've got four
Le States 30 some medical States 23
medical States and 13 CBD only and not
one of them came with worker
protection so you can take any other
intoxicating medication you feel like or
are prescribed or your doctor recommends
but not cannabis not cannabis it might
be intoxicating so who's uh who how do
we go about writing the worker
protection rules who does that that's
probably not going to happen in our
lifetime start it that's your new job
Mike there you go your new calling in
live okay someone's got to pay me for
that amount of lobbying um uh all right
guys there's guys click the Donate
button yep you know where I'm headed
with this there's a donate button and
you uh you write Mike on there and then
Mike will uh when that transmission's
done getting paid oh God don't remind me
we'll transfer that over to me don't
remind me so Mike just he's not even
reading the article and he just said
while four states have legal you just
read part of the article out of your bra
so uh federal employees are also part of
the drug-free workplace act guidelines
which ban any use of illegal drugs on
and off duty in general most of the
routine drug testing of federal
employees primarily occurs within
federal agencies that have personnel
with safety sensitive jobs like those
working in law enforcement or national
security this would be a good time to
mention to those of you living in not
Colorado thinking about moving to heaven
and uh for our wonderful weed laws that
uh have a job when you get here cuz
they're going to drug test just like the
one in Minneapolis or where wherever
you're flying from Texas yep I had a
friend that had to pass a drug test
yesterday in fact she's like how do I do
it I was like I don't I don't know if
they if I have to take a pest I don't
even want to work there I had to do that
back before dabs were a thing and Dab's
been a thing for a while so I've
probably forgotten exactly how to do
that now um my way of doing it is the
only way I can do it is use fake piss
it's the only way I've ever been able to
pass a p test you go by that fake pee
and keep it warm I just took breaks and
just I was just be sober it was never
that painful one time dude I went 63
days without smoking I don't want to try
fa a drug test and I really didn't smoke
everyone's like you had to have smoked
and I was like no I went to Reggae on
the rocks with my brother Bradley and
rolled down the windows when he puffed
and I did not puff at all he was
laughing at me and I still failed the P
test well I'm all right so if you're a
Fed in any way who else is a Fed we got
we said mailman's Park Rangers well it
applies to all sorts of stuff C
dot uh there's a number of
different professions I suppose is the
easiest way to say it that uh have rules
that the feds get to lay out regulations
that the feds get to lay out and a lot
of it comes with tax breaks if and one
of those ifs is almost always drug-free
work workplace act which is why [ __ ]
like McDonald's drug test like mad
they're not going to have to they're all
going to be kiosks pretty soon yep yep
all right that article actually came
from The Huffington Post by a dude named
Matt ferner thanks for letting me read
your article there Matt ferer let's see
probably get in one more article here do
you want to make it a good one yeah we
got about five minutes before I want to
start wrapping it up let's see that
one's going to be long that one's kind
of cool let's wrap this up with a funny
one you guys we talked a whole bunch of
stuff if you made it to the 30 minute
Mark in this show here is something
great for hanging in yeah this one is
good you guys it says and where is this
from um okay this is from Pendleton
Oregon and it says man asks City to ban
fart smells for a good reason and this
came from The Huffington Post it's
written by Hillary Henson I really liked
this story the article goes like this
you guys are going to like this also it
says a resident of Pendleton Oregon has
written a letter requesting the city
council ban the smell of farts in the
community but he has good reason to be
raising a stink last week the city of
Pendleton uploaded its nuisance
ordinance to cover the smell of
marijuana NBC reported at the time that
means that even though recreational
marijuana will be legal in Oregon
starting in July a person can be fined
up to $500 if someone complains they
smell marijuana coming from that
person's property in a letter published
in the East Oregonian on Thursday
someone who signed his name as Peter
Walters merely asked that council
members take the next logical step and
start regulating a far more noxious
scent it was with great relief Thursday
when I read the East Coast the East
Oregon
that Pendleton city council took the
time to pass an amendment to the city's
nuisance order Banning marijuana order
clearly there has been no issue of
Greater importance facing the city now
that this important work has been
completed I hope the council will move
on to restricting the other offensive
smell that plagues our community
farts Walters who is pretty clearly
mocking the marijuana ordinances notes
some habitual farters argue that they
need to fart for medical reasons but
that doesn't mean my kids should have to
smell their farts it's just beautiful
that's great if you're an elected
official and you behave absurdly people
have the right to mock the living [ __ ]
out of you by sending you public letters
asking you to ban the smell of farts uh
PUO last summer did we passed a smell
ordinance down here it's considered
automatically a yes that's definitely
offensive thing if your neighbor whines
about the smell of your pot garden um
you can be smoking marijuana on your
porch and that smell cannot be
considered automatically offensive but
growing marijuana is automatically
offensive by city
ordinance it's the only odor that you
can get in trouble for in PLO well if
this passes I pretty much can't go to
Pendleton
Oregon B I will be fined me oops 500
bucks every couple of minutes out of me
I'm a farting fool on some days I think
it's this vegetarian diet that's what do
it to me all right so uh pretty soon you
guys in Pendleton Oregon they're going
to and farts not really but I think
that's a great way to respond to some
[ __ ] ordinances made by some [ __ ]
people big shout out to the guy who
signed his name as Peter Walters I don't
know who you are way to go Peter but
you're one of my heroes today shout out
bro so we've gone 30 minutes uh we've
got some more news but we're going to
save that for another episode because
you guys really like these 30 minute
episodes dude Mike thanks for hanging
out with me today thanks for recording a
podcast thanks for kind of being My
Chauffeur the little Ford Focus is
killer we just need to get get you a
better stereo in there bro oh yeah that
whole car is from 2001 well it's not the
car it's what the radio plays around
here makes me want to stab my ears with
[ __ ] butter knives it's terrible
clear channels taking over the world and
I'm been back or pushed back to FM
recently and it's it's been a tough
transition um I'm pretty sure I heard
Taylor Swift poison Metallica and uh I
think it was some Bon Joy on the way
over here just as you Channel surfed
yeah we were in the car for a while it
got [ __ ] bad people yeah thank God
the digital age came along when it did
I'll be so glad to get my car back and
then we'll get everything back together
shout out to all the people that have
helped me out there are a couple people
that have really given me some rides and
[ __ ] for the past few days done me some
favors shout out to the people that have
showed up at my house with food because
I uh I hate eating food that I have at
home I cook the same [ __ ] all the time
there are a couple of people that have
showed up with some fatty it's hard to
be a homebound vegetarian yeah right
because all my shit's fresh you can't
stock the fridge for more than 3 days
yep yeah well I I can get a few that
yeah you you know more than a few days I
bought a [ __ ] ton of bananas and apples
and I've been eating all kinds of
goodies but yeah so thanks to the people
that have helped me out we're going to
wrap up a show Mike remind these people
how they can follow you on Twitter one
more time uh Nemo punk5 right on there
follow me guys because he does do a lot
of cannabis posting he's one of my
homies he's part of the team if you
follow me from the podcast just shoot me
a tweet saying that's why you're
following me because every time I do a
show I get random followers all week
long nice and I have to wonder if it's
me taunting Kevin subet that day or the
podcast and I just I'll never know oh
now all these people are going to go
troll Kevin sbet for you oh if they're
following me on Twitter it's something
you're going to get to enjoy anyway nice
man it was a pleasure recording with you
I'm going to wrap up the show so it goes
like this you guys thanks for listening
to another episode I'll be back uh this
probably will be a Wednesday episode so
I'll catch you again on Monday uh don't
forget to support all of our sponsors
it's the Rocky Mountain worm company
High gr indoor growing supplies also
make sure you visit Nature's green
remedies.com um if you guys are
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you have a product you'd like me to
review um send me an email it's grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you
all the information that you need if you
send me a product I will review it uh
here's what I'll do I'll get the product
in the mail uh we will open it up on the
show we will use it here on the show we
will check it out if we love it we will
totally give you a fatty review and uh
if we don't love it we will totally give
you an honest
review sound fair so if you've got a
product you want me to review send it to
me uh we'll do it on the show right here
live I'll have a couple homies come over
we check it out honest yeah um so now
that the show's over you guys please go
to iTunes go to the iTunes Store search
for grow from your heart find the review
section give me a Fest star rating after
that type in a little comment let me
know what you think of the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode I really appreciate the comments
uh that keeps the show moving up in the
ranks it keeps more people aware of the
show the more people that know about the
show the more people will listen to the
show they'll grow better cannabis tell
your dealer about the show yo your
dealer tell your caregiver about the
show tell your grower about the show
yeah tell everybody about it tell your
grandma about it too tell like five
people because if you tell five people
then two people will probably listen so
more people learn about the show they'll
get to watch it yeah I read that all
right so if you guys have something to
say find me on social media on Facebook
it's grow from your heart on Twitter
it's gfyh podcast on Instagram it's @
iry gentics don't forget that the show
is available on iTunes Stitcher and
every single episode is always and
forever archived on I gentics
color.com don't forget there is a
donation button on the podcast tab uh go
to the website iry gentics color.com on
the uh click on the grow from your heart
podcast tab at the top right that's the
donation button that goes right to my
Paypal account I'm never going to charge
you for this podcast the show is always
going to be free free free forever all
this info is for free all the love is
for free but if you feel like making a
contribution to say thank you that would
be appreciated if you want to pay for
Mike to start lobbying for uh workers
protection for medical cannabis use go
ahead and send him what do you need
couple million yeah yeah a couple Mill
should do it like 8 to 10 don't drop
that in my PayPal account because I
don't want to pay taxes on that 8 to 10
million just send me an email us an
email and I'll set up my own PayPal
account if you want to fund that
particular effort there you go if you
want to throw a few thousand or you know
what if you got a bunch of pennies you
want to throw at the podcast we would
appreciate it uh we could use a couple
new mic covers I've been spitting into
this one for a minute I just tried to
dab this one it's a little soggy now oh
yummy
all right you guys please follow us on
the social media sites I love the
interaction um yeah once again big shout
out to my ninja Spence until next time
you guys take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for
[Music]
me
stand roll ni roll up
[Music]
keep no
leftover like busy signal we the down
only one
[Music]
like
n