if you have ever used a brand new
product on the entire crop and destroyed
the entire run now's a good time to
click subscribe
[Music]
happy mother's day podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
this is episode 740 of the grow from
your heart podcast in this episode we're
going to focus on mother plants before i
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to the captain and
commander of the irie army let's send a
big salute to my buddy lemur priest
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my good friend billy podunk let's send a
big thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter my dude kurt z let's send a
big thank you shout out to andy d and
ez057
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my dude tree star meadow let's send a
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to one of my favorite photographers my
buddies oh soj let's send a thank you
shout out to my dude alabama man let's
send a big thank you shout out to danky
dave let's send a big fist bumping a
thank you shout out to my dude tonto's
garden let's send a big fist bumping a
thank you shout out to bong stain bear i
want to send a special thank you shout
out to a longtime supporter my good
friend miss mel let's send a thank you
shout out to crazy hand grows then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
groov 2112.
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
excuse me for the throat clearing right
here at the start of the show i have
been taking some monstrous dabs of some
machine live batter from a friend they
don't want to be mentioned fist bump you
know who you are great work it does mess
up the throat but it puts me in the
greatest mood the greatest zone for
podcasting that machine puts on these
blinders all i could really pay
attention to is that camera these lights
kind of went away the notes right here
really digging the vibe of the machine
live batter other than the clogged up
throat pretty phenomenal concentrates
excuse me for doing that rudely into the
microphone that was uncalled for
big shout out to all the friends who
support the show happy mother's day
let's quit rambling and focus in let's
do a podcast all right let's do a deep
dive into mother plants mother plants
are a very important aspect of cannabis
cultivation
let's talk about what a mother plant is
then we'll talk about how to establish a
mother plant then we'll talk a little
more deeply into mother plants let's get
started by talking about what a mother
plant is what am i talking about mother
plant what does that even mean
when we cultivate cannabis oftentimes we
will find a plant that we kind of fall
in love with something you want to keep
smoking over and over and over again you
want to keep growing it as a breeder as
a grower i like to grow something
multiple times i like to grow it uh the
first time i grow it i call it the first
date i'm just gonna give it the standard
operating procedure the basic nutrients
the basic grow room we'll see how that
plant reacts to the room the second time
i'll say well last time it didn't react
to the cool it didn't react well to the
hot it didn't like these nutrients it
could have done better with this i will
give it those things every time i grow
that plant i'll take notes i'll pay
attention i will observe i will sample
and i will make adjustments every grow
and by the third fifth sixth grow that
plant will be banging it'll be doing
much better than the first time that i
grew up because i've developed a
relationship with that plant now how do
i continue to grow that plant i need to
keep a mother plant of that plant let's
just get into so we know what a mother
plant is that mother plant in the future
is going to be
designated to give us clones to keep our
genetics alive in the future it's a
mother plant that stays in the room
unflowered and we can take cuttings from
that to turn them into clones or
clippings or reproductions of our
original plant and we can continually
grow this plant over and over again this
one never goes into flower we save it
it's like our little genetic preserve so
that is a mother plant how do we get to
a mother plant that's a very good
question
let's say we are either given a pack of
seeds or we are given a clone or we
acquire a clone or a pack of seeds so
let's start with a pack of seeds let's
say we are given a 10 pack of seeds you
just are gifted a pack of seeds i was
super nice i was like hey bro want some
seeds you're like i sure do or whoever
whatever i called you and i gave you a
10 pack of seeds and you grew them now
you're going to find an amazing plant
out of that 10 pack you'll find one that
really stands out to you we will do it
as a fino hunt we will grow all of these
seeds we will carefully observe them
watch how they grow there's going to be
a couple of plants in there that really
stand out one's going to not even be
desirable to you but maybe to somebody
else one's going to really stand out to
you one's going to be pretty good you're
probably going to get one that puts out
a lot of weight one that really tastes
good and then one of those will be super
potent there's always two that it's hard
to decide between which keepers you want
to keep let's talk about keeping one of
those as a mother plant what i would do
i would grow those seeds until they are
big enough to get a clone we talked
about cloning earlier i would take three
clones from each seedling now i've got
three opportunities to keep these plants
alive i would grow them out i would
either at this point what i would do as
soon as my clones show roots i would
flower these plants that have been
growing they're already established
they're already pretty big let's just
flower those out see what we've got
we'll pull the males immediately once
these plants i put in flowers show mail
i will also call that male clone if i'm
not looking for a male and this in this
final hunt we're just looking for a mom
to make a mother plant for a good keeper
to make a mother plant so we're going to
grow all of these seedlings we're going
to cut a clone we're going to put the
mom the original plant into flower when
those show us sex we will call all of
the boys the small boys and the big boys
now we are only down to the females one
thing i should mention carefully label
all of your plants the way i do it is
either alphabetically or numerically
i've just got plants a through z or
we're in colorado a through six whatever
number six is in the alphabet uh or 12
depending on where we are i number them
one through six one through twelve then
when i take clones the clones get the
corresponding number clone number one
came from plant number one clones number
two came from plant number two clones
labeled three came from plant three
makes it easy so if my plant number five
shows that it's a male clone five is a
male it goes bye-bye if number one shows
it's a girl number one is a girl that
gets to stay that's the way that works
so we eliminate the boys now we grow out
the females
pay attention some of them you're gonna
love some you're going to hate find the
one that you really really do love the
first time i run it i may keep two maybe
three of the females we've eliminated
the boys we've gotten rid of the
non-desirable females now let's really
run these girls one more time and see
what we really love i don't know what
you're going to do you could do it the
one time you could do it a couple times
find the girls you like
in this case we're just going to pick
one we're going to say we found the one
that we really liked we're going to say
it was number two in my case it often is
number two one number one's a boy number
two is quite often the keeper number
four is a champ is just weird luck of
the draw for me so number two we're
gonna say number two was a [ __ ]
amazing female keeper plant we're gonna
keep that right we grew it out we
flowered it we smoked it it is awesome
luckily back in the day we kept a clone
of number two it's just growing it's
over there in the grow room just grow
and we've still got it we know number
two is the champ guess what that clone
that is growing over there that is now
your mother plant that's how you
establish a mother plant you cut the
clone what i do is i cut the clone off
the top of a veg plant i put it in the
cloner i let it clone i let it root as
soon as it gets roots i put it in a pot
that's when i flower my other plant now
i've got nine weeks to find out what the
winners are that other plant's gonna
grow over there for nine weeks before
nine weeks is up you've probably decided
what your favorite plant is so you've
got your favorite selected now i would
cut clones from my favorite one again
and i've already got clones ready for
the next run so we cut a clone off of
our original seated plant just cut a
clone right out of the top put it in the
cloner it's going to take two weeks to
root ish as soon as i see roots i flower
the one that's already in the pot the
big one that the clone came from we're
gonna find the boys and girls pull out
the boys find your favorite girl you'll
know you'll know probably by week seven
or week eight what your favorite girls
are your other plants are over here that
you took clones of they'll have to come
out of the clone or they'll go into pots
they'll start growing they're gonna get
bigger it's gonna be nine weeks before
we need them for anything my
recommendation is around week seven a
flower on this run cut clones now those
clones become your next run guess what
you just cut those from your mother
plants that you've got sitting over here
your favorite one over here will be
designated your mother plant let's move
it over here and focus now on mother
plants we've done a basic phenohunt we
have found the mother plant we choose to
keep we've got a nice bushy plant of
that mother plant right here we cut a
clone it grew it's been growing for
several weeks you may have not taken
clones off of it by now you may have now
is a good time to go and clean up this
mother plant i kind of do a little bit
of lollipopping a little bottoming just
to clean it up it's going to have some
funky useless [ __ ] at the bottom just
small wispy shoots coming off i take all
that stuff off then i want to make a
nice bushy plant because this is going
to be the plant that donates a bunch of
cuts to me when i need to grow again so
if i need i'm going to i know how many
clones i'm going to need for my next run
if i know i need three i don't need
super bushy of a plant if i need 25 cuts
i need to start topping this plant
strategically to make more branches and
more arms so that i can produce more
clones to supply my growth for the next
run and then every time you top it at
the right spot it's going to produce
double the nodes so the next time you
run it you should have plenty of clones
available for the next round if you got
25 this time you should be able to get
50 next time no problem because you
doubled all of the spaces so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to keep this
big mother plant nice and healthy as
healthy as i can i'm going to keep it
under at least 18 hours of light and six
hours of darkness a lot of times i will
go 19 hours of light and five hours of
darkness just to prevent any sort of
autoflower any sort of ideas that that
plant could have darkness long enough to
flower i do give them sleep time i
believe
anything wants a little bit of sleepy
time you need a nap the dog needs a nap
the plants can use an app also your
equipment can use a nap
if we turn off the lights for just four
or five hours a night that will save us
a lot of electricity a lot of time on
your bulbs a lot of time on the air
conditioner a lot of things that don't
have to run unless it's the winter and
then you got to turn on a heater that's
a whole another conversation keep them
under at least 18 hours of light some
people will go 19 some people will go
20. some will do the 24 that is not my
recommendation once again we all need a
nap you'll notice that they'll start
getting uh spindly and growing too tall
and getting weird on you if you don't
give them any nighttime i do think that
weird growth is a symptom of them just
they're freaking out dude they're
they're going crazy they need a nap feed
them excuse me feed them another very
important thing is to feed them i feed
them a high nitrogen diet i focus on
just mainly the basic npk in a good
vegetative nutrient solution you will
get most of the things needed for your
mother plants they need a little bit of
calmag definitely feed them microbes one
thing is i really step up my pesticide
application or my integrated pest
management routine in the mother room
area because it all starts with healthy
mother plants if your moms start getting
healthy your stock is or if they start
getting unhealthy your stock is
unhealthy it all starts right there so
have very healthy mother plants if at
all possible keep insects away from them
keep powdery mildew away from them keep
any viruses away from them keep those
mother plants clean those are sacred as
a breeder that's my that's everything
sacred to me is those mother plants so
keep them clean safe and healthy up your
step up your integrated pest management
game in that room is where it all starts
if you can't get healthy cuts you can't
get healthy plants if you can't have
healthy veg plants you can't have
healthy flower plants you can't breed
healthy seeds it all starts with healthy
moms healthy clones healthy veg get
those mother plants super healthy so
give them a lot of light give them a lot
of strong vegetative nutrients then also
give them a lot of cleanliness give them
a lot of pest management make sure there
are no bugs on there that's where it all
starts now um something else to talk
about is the goal and shape of your
plants how many clones do you need
i top them early because when i top them
all those lower branches start growing
up now think about when you you've got
an intersection we call it a node so
you've got the branch coming up and
shooting off to the left is just one
more little space and then right above
that going off to the right is one more
little space little branches so if you
cut that one out of the middle you've
now got the one going up off the left
and the one going up off the right those
eventually will even out and start
growing as new apical dominant tops if
you top it right think about that
strategically when you are cutting it
think about the plant kind of it looks
like i'm giving you the finger here on
the camera i'm not it looks like a three
it looks like a piece sign turned upside
down you got the one going up the middle
then you got your left branch and your
right branch if you cut that one out the
middle that's a much better hand gesture
there if you cut that one up the middle
these two will compete and become new
tops later on those will both become
cloned so take out this clone now you
get these two in the future then those
two repeat the process you get four
repeat the process you get eight repeat
the process if he comes into like
[ __ ] 64. right if you do it just it's
mathematically bra so keep cutting keep
cutting them keep topping and you will
make more tops something that will
happen eventually this will happen
there's you could do this
process as long as you want but
eventually you're going to need to
replace your mother plant right now
people are going to say what about
genetic drift that is not a thing i've
done a full podcast on why genetic drift
does not apply to cannabis and why it
doesn't apply to cloning cannabis so
wash genetic drift right out of your
brain that's not a thing if your mother
plants are healthy you cut clones
properly genetic drift will not be a
thing i've done a full episode on that
do some research check out the episode
one thing that will need to be done is
you will need to re-clone your mother
plants they will get big they will get
tall they'll start getting old they'll
get out of control that plant is it's
old no matter how long every time you
clone the plant that plant is still as
old as that original clone so it's got
that much age on it we've got to keep
these plants fresh we've got to reclone
them what i do every three to six months
depending on the plant um the sun-kissed
plant doesn't grow super are the uh the
platinum tangy doesn't grow super fast
it stays kind of smaller doesn't take as
much time mach one doesn't take as much
time i can remom that one every six
months the mighty congo the chem de la
cam they need remomed about every three
months so what i do i simply cut
a nice batch of clones i probably cut
one row uh five clones off of each plant
right so we got five congo we got five
uh camdella chems and then i just let
those root and the best two i pop them
the best two of each one i pot them then
i let them grow the best one goes in the
flower room the second best one becomes
the new mother plant that becomes my new
genetic that's the one that i get to
grow from from now on and that's gonna
repeat the process forever then that big
plant that i cut the clones from i
either flower that which most of the
time i do not do or i simply cut it into
small pieces and throw it away because i
don't need it i don't feel the need to
just grow it because i've got it that's
not what that plant was meant for it was
meant to provide clones it served its
purpose i've got all the cuts i need i
can chop that big bad dog down and throw
it away sometimes they'll go outside
sometimes they get floured in a flower
room sometimes they get pollinated most
of the time it's better for me just to
eliminate that plant start fresh with
those new cuts they're already so big
they're already stretched out that's why
i'm re-momming it they just get they get
out of control they get unruly and
unshapely if you're not strategically
cloning it all the time and on top of it
it will get out of control and even if
so it will get root bound it'll just get
old reclone it remom it get it started
fresh i do that again about every three
to six months is how i redo my moms now
let's talk about another scenario i know
a lot of people
myself included i'm here in colorado uh
in my personal grow i'm very limited on
the amount of plants that i would like
to have so
instead of wasting space on mother
plants in some cases what we will do we
will use a dedicated veg plant as our
mother plant so let's just say you grew
your you've got a clone right you know
that this clone is the winner you've
done your final hunt you've got the
winner you've got your clone right here
you just right before you're gonna
flower take a couple of clones off of it
and save them and now you've got three
or five clones in the cloning area you
move that plant into the flowering room
it'll flower in nine weeks now your your
clones are in there for two weeks they
come out of the cloner they go into
their pots they got two weeks in the
cloner uh two or three weeks in the
small pots and then like six weeks no
what do we got that's five you've got
four weeks in the bigger pots then move
those right into flour and take a couple
of cuts off of them and use your veg
plants as your mother plant kind of keep
a perpetual cycle going people are going
to say what about genetic drift again
i'm going to say that is not a thing as
long as you are keeping your plants
healthy
excuse me as long as your veg plants
your donor plant is what i want to call
it is a healthy plant your clones will
come out healthily if you do it properly
take good care of them
i've done full episodes on clone care
all of that stuff that's another topic
but let me talk about how to do that
again because i feel like i breezed over
it you've got your plant you're going to
flower it that plant is your mom plant
and your flower plant it's a veg plant
that will be flowered at the same time
you got a plant put it into the flower
room right before you change the light
cycle take three to five clones off of
it those clones will be the next run so
while this bad dog is flowering your
clones are rooting they'll root they'll
take two weeks as soon as these plants
in the flower room start showing sex and
going into flower you've got plants to
move from a cloned dome into pots as
soon as they really start banging out
flour you gotta up pop these and get
them ready start prepping them for the
next run slide them into flour as soon
as these finish take a couple clones
repeat the process you've got a
perpetual cycle without keeping mother
plants because you're keeping veg mother
plants at the same time all right ladies
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers growers mothers fathers
paul and chuckers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there thank you
for hanging out with me on mother's day
thanks for listening to a quick lesson
on mother plants it is time to wrap up
this podcast it's time to go spend some
time with our moms uh if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
and or entertaining please support the
show on patreon all you have to do is
check out patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns of course i'd love to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy reach
out let me know what you think of the
show let me know if i missed anything
let me know if i need to do any updates
i do appreciate the listener interaction
everything else you may need is on my
website at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the discord server
there's a link to vendors there's a
merch link like i said anything you can
imagine is on the website once again
that is iriegenetics
dot
ladies and gentlemen that is all i've
got for you for this episode you know
i'll be back in a couple of days with
fresh new content i want to give a big
shout out to my buddy smoke what and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you