[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode
741 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the kind folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend william downs
let's send a big thank you shout out to
716 vibes and uncle gigi let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
my buddy chicago dabber and papa z let's
send a big thank you shout out to a long
time friend my buddy jesse gross i want
to send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to a great tester my friend
levity loveday let's send a big thank
you shout out to elder's garden i want
to send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to terry p and ez056
let's send a big thank you shout out to
my buddy b bala then let's wrap it all
up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to doc grows
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link to the
patreon in the show notes and in the
video description to make it super easy
for all of my friends to support the
show speaking of patreon the new patreon
episode will be available by the time
this podcast comes out that patreon
episode will be loaded up there's a
patreon only a patreon exclusive episode
that will be posted for the month of may
that episode does include myself and
white mike and we each ate a hundred
milligrams of edibles we rambled on
the show is two hours long there is not
any grow information in that show to be
completely open and honest i did not put
grow information on the patreon show
because i want to give you guys all of
the grow information education i want
that to be free i want people to be able
to get that the patreon episode is
honestly just a hangout with mike and i
we got lit we talk [ __ ] uh it's a good
time so please if you're on the patreon
look for that video with white mike and
myself by the time this episode comes
out that video should have loaded by now
it's a two-hour video it is 4k it has
taken all day to load you guys don't
care look for that episode on patreon
once again big thanks to the irie army
for supporting the show on patreon where
do we go from there also big thanks for
all of the uh shout outs and support and
positive feedback on the mother's day
episode usually i put out shows on
monday morning i thought it would be
nice to put out a show on mother's day
about mother plants a lot of people
caught my the irony there or my gag or
my trick or my joke whatever it was
there i was trying to be cute i put out
a mother's day episode about mother
plants a lot of people saw that a lot of
people commented they enjoyed the show
they also enjoyed that it was a mother's
day special big thank you for checking
out that episode big thanks for all the
comments i hope everybody out there had
a great mother's day hope you spent some
time with your mom your family if your
mom's not with us anymore big hug to
mama big love to all the moms without
the moms none of us would be here let's
move forward you guys i do have some
topics to talk about not just a bunch of
rambles on today's episode i've got a
few great emails here in front of me
this one we're going to jump right into
it this one i titled the selection
question this one comes from our friend
that calls themselves jh and it goes a
little bit like this it says in every 10
to 20 seeds there is one plant that just
looks happy the entire time
so that does make sense i've noticed
sometimes that when you run a pack of
seeds you'll run 10 or 20 seeds and
there's always going to be one that just
just shines that's that's like the
dating pool that's the way i describe
dating that's the way i find uh describe
finding the phenotype that you like that
one is gonna shine it says in your
opinion how important is that plant in
the selection process um that
the fact that it just shines says a lot
is it shining because uh is it now there
are a couple of things to think about is
it shining because it's the only one
getting the right [ __ ] or is it shining
because it is thriving we've got a
couple things to think about
when we run plants for the first time we
don't know what they expect so we just
give them in most cases we give them the
general uh 84 80ish degrees 70 humidity
we give them all the basics and we run
them the first time and see what they do
some plants are going to be happy in
that some are not going to be happy in
that
it looks like you're always finding and
that's that's a good uh the odds of that
one plant shining are always really good
because we've designed we've bred these
plants to work in the grow rooms which
we've designed the plants have been bred
to work in the rooms and the rooms have
been designed to work with the plants
the way that we bred them so if you've
got a 10 pack or a 20 pack in a decent
grow room you're always going to find at
least one that super shines now is that
one shining because the other nine are
not happy or 19 are not happy or is that
one shining because it is super happy
now also is it shining because that's
the one that doesn't isn't real picky
doesn't require a lot of stuff that is a
very common thing what you're running
into is just phenotypical expression one
of them is happier than the others and
it is shining um how important is that
in the selection process
that is half of what we're that's a
small portion of what we're looking for
less than half of what we're looking for
is the performance of the plants in that
one condition
it performed well that's a good
indication that it works well in your
environment that is one really good
thing but how does it smoke does it ah
does it give you good harvest weight
does it give you good potency does the
smoke give you a desirable effect
is the flavor there because flavor
matters a lot to me flavor and aroma um
does it give you the weight that you
need
those are also very
important factors to think about during
a selection process growing it is great
if it grows well that's really cool but
once you cut it down the consumer has no
idea how it grew and they don't care a
lot of times the best plants to smoke
are the plants that grew like [ __ ] in
the garden the one that the grower had
to struggle with is the one that the
smokers really enjoy quite often so um
only part of the it's like a chess board
it's like we call it mimetics you got 64
squares on a chessboard right and the uh
this one looking good in the grow room
during the grow is one square of the
chessboard we need potency we need bug
resistance we need uh terps we need all
kinds of other things to make this a
winner not just one square on the
chessboard you got to cover the whole
board if you want to win
there is more to this it goes on it says
i'm bad at describing things but i'm
sure you know this plant it always has
the perfect leaf angle perfect color no
visible signs of stress and it looks
like she just wants to give you a high
five yes i do know that plant very well
once you grow a lot more and you get
more experience you'll be able to get
every plant in the room to look that way
you'll know that this one i need to move
it away from the light because it
doesn't like the extra heat but if i put
it in the corner it kind of enjoys that
and the other one it needs to go right
under the legs it wants all the extra
light this one i shouldn't water it so
much this one i can practically over
water it and it loves it so you'll start
learning those individual plants but in
selection something i say a lot of times
is don't select the plant for the
internet we're not selecting for
internet purposes we are selecting for
uh potency vigor resistance to bugs
terps there are a lot of other things
that we're selecting for so if you're
selecting for instagram for photos that
is the great phenotype we've got to
smoke it we've got to grow it all the
way out dry it cure it finish it and
then see if it is desirable that's
really the only way to tell is to dry it
cure it smoke it and see what you've got
it goes on it says that being said i
haven't had the happiest plant and the
best smelling plant lineup ever in 18
years of sprouting 10 seeds at a time is
that just bad luck or am i doing
something wrong no that is the way that
the weed gods like to mess with us
we've learned how to grow you've been
growing says 18 years you've been
growing cannabis producing cannabis for
18 years which means
you're pretty good at it by now you i
hope you're pretty good at it by now
you've got a flow you've got a rhythm
you're comfortable you've got a lot of
skills
so the world goes oh you got some skills
you think how about instead of giving
you this perfect plant we're going to
give you two to choose from i often make
the joke that when you run a 10 pack one
is going to be best for the consumer and
one is going to be best for the grower
and it's kind of what you're saying here
the happiest plant and best smelling
plant don't seem to line up the one that
the consumers want they never saw how
much of a pain in the ass that plant was
to grow they go i want an ounce of this
and then that one that grew super simply
for you and put out all the weight i it
wasn't the desirable it's never the
desirable one for the consumer that is
kind of a joke that i say the weed gods
play on us that is very common you're
not doing anything wrong that is just
how phenotypes work
um
i
i always find at least one keeper and a
10 pack of my stuff so the hard part is
deciding which of the three i usually
want to keep there's one that usually
tastes real good one that's usually
super potent uh and then that one that
just super [ __ ] performs uh the goal
there is to breed that line further and
get the things that you want out of that
but i know you're not doing anything
wrong you're doing it just right in my
opinion that is just a funny joke that
the cannabis gods the ganja gods play on
us uh the best smelling one and the best
performing plant are not the same uh the
consumer and the grower are always gonna
have different opinions in that aspect
all right my friend jh i feel like i
rambled on quite a bit about that
question i hope i helped you out i hope
i answered your question if you've got
any follow-ups i would love to hear your
follow-up question if anybody else out
there has any questions corrections
comments or concerns on this question my
email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
reach on out i will answer your
questions i do have another message
right here in front of me this one came
from patreon big shout out to all the
patreon supporters
this one came from guido's grow room big
shout out to my buddy guido at guido's
grow room you say that three times fast
one time was hard enough it goes on and
it says hey mr rj got a quick question
for you i'm getting ready to flip some
plants via sts so he's going to reverse
some plants using a silver thiosulfate
solution i've talked a lot about that on
other episodes if you want to learn a
lot more about reversing plants with
silver thiosulfate i've done a full
podcast simply google grow from your
heart podcast sts mix or my sts it will
come up um it says so he said i'm
getting ready to reverse some plants via
silver thiosulfate and i am wondering if
you have ever done it under an 1113 dj
short style light cycle that's a very
good question let me explain what that
means most of the time we put our plants
on 12 hours on and 12 hours off to
trigger the flowering phase our friend
dj short a long time ago taught us that
11 hours on and 13 hours off will give
us different results in some cases they
are improved results in some cases they
are diminished results it depends on
your goal i think that the extended dark
period gives the plants an opportunity
to show their expression a little bit
more we see more phenotypical variation
more phenotypical expression is what it
is that i believe i'm seeing with this
extended dark period this is not common
practice for me i've stopped doing this
i do something way different which i've
talked about in other episodes but dj
short has been doing the 1113 for a long
time it's got a lot of advantages if you
think about it if you're flowering for
63 days that is 63 hours of electricity
that you don't have to run that's 63
hours of power that didn't go through
your light bulb your air conditioner
your blower all your fans everything got
to chill out and cool down for 63 extra
hours which economically that is great
but in my opinion photons are the number
one source of energy for that plant so i
want to give them all the light that
they can get that's a whole other debate
a whole other conversation right now
we're talking about putting these plants
under 1113 after they have been treated
with the silver thiosulfate solution in
an attempt to make feminized seeds it
goes on it says
i've got four ladies in the room
flowering now and we'll be adding the
two reversal candidates into the spot
tomorrow shouldn't be any issues right
um i do see an issue my dude um if the
four ladies are in the flower room
flowering room now and you're just
adding the two reversal candidates you
may have mistimed this
my general practice my standard
operating procedure is to begin the
reversal
uh get the plants being sprayed i spray
them seven to f ten to fourteen days the
first plant to get reversed get sprayed
10 to 14 days before it goes into flower
then that one will get sprayed again on
day one of flower then day 3 6 9 12 15
18 21 and possibly day 24.
i do not put the pollen receiving plants
into that room until i see those
reversed plants begin to show me
definite signs of male flowers when i
start seeing those pollen sacs pop up
that is when i move the female plants
into the room that is how i time it i
really think that timing works out
because it's going to be
a few days now several days 26 to 32
days before that male plant starts
producing pollen if your girls are
already in there
um how flung if they've been in there
flowering now i'll be adding to reversal
so you don't say how long they've been
in there but they're ahead they're too
far ahead of the male plants they're
going to be past their peak ovulation
point of receiving pollen to create
seeds
if you don't get those males dumping
pollen a little bit sooner it will work
don't don't panic don't freak out it
will work but if you would timed it a
little bit differently you would make a
lot more seed many probably double the
amount of seeds honestly it's all about
timing you want those plants to the
female plants the pollen receivers to
have the most i call it dandelions
people understand what i mean when i say
the dandelions when it starts making you
guys call it hairs those are pistols uh
when it starts making all the hairs
start popping up those hairs are what
are gonna catch the pollen that's that's
what catches the pollen it draws the
pollen down that into the ovule into the
bracton of the calyx starts forming a
seed within that area but all those
hairs are what are going to make the
seed those hairs have to be at the prime
peak point for pollination to get the
most seeds when they're real thick and
real strong looking
right after that is when they want the
most pollen then they start fading they
start wrinkling start crinkling up start
getting brown once they get withered up
and small that they can no longer
receive pollen they've passed their peak
point of pollination they've gone into
uh i guess they've gone into menopause
if you want to compare them to people so
so i think you are doing okay but the
timing could have been better but don't
panic don't tear it down don't start
over do what you're doing you're going
to get seeds out of this
um shouldn't be any issues right i think
the 11 13 cycle should work honestly i
have not done that so i don't have a
testimony but
with the info i've got the knowledge
experience uh i think it will work i
think it will do what needs done it may
help you out because your mail your
reversal plants may actually flip more
quickly because they're sleeping longer
i'm not sure how that will work it may
be beneficial
to correct your timing issue
it goes on it says and of course once
they start to show boy parts they'll go
into the breeding tent just need a week
to finish trim jail as i dry in the in
the other tent too i hope you have an
awesome day my man and thank you for
your time my buddy guido thank you for
the great question it sounds like you've
got the right idea but i think the
timing may have been off just a little
bit but i understand why we're limited
on space uh you're stuck in trim jail
which um should i ramble on that or
should i just let it go trim jail is a
weird thing to me because i actually
have friends in jail and if i said trim
jail to them they'd be like [ __ ]
do you see where i am and they'd find it
really disrespectful for me to say that
sitting here sitting at the table
listening to sublime eating doritos
talking to my friends and cutting up
weed under the air conditioner to put
the word jail in there my friends in
real jail would be [ __ ]
offended um they'd find it disrespectful
that's my quick rant on that nobody
cares about that i don't like trim jail
it's a silly [ __ ] word to say there's
real people in a real jail um
but i get it dude i get what you've got
to do you had to time it that way i
think it's going to work and i think
your light cycle will work i think
everything will turn out just the way
that you want it to um
my request is send me an update send me
feedback send me details how does this
work how many seeds do you pull from the
plants that you put in there
are you satisfied with the outcome and
uh did you get pollen on time that is
going to be my main question so guido
send me a follow-up send me some info
bro i can't wait uh for the follow-up uh
this came on may 9th so it should be a
couple of weeks here before i get more
info i'll give you until about june 1st
and i'll expect an update from you my
dude all right guido thank you for the
great message let's see how long we've
been rambling we've got plenty of time
for one more message i got a great
question here in front of me
this one came on the grow from your
heart at hotmail.com email address and
it goes a lot like this it says hey ross
did jeff my actual name is jack what's
up jack good to meet you my dude it says
when you use the thousand watt hps which
is a high pressure sodium lamp what
reflector type and what distance to the
canon canopy do you find to be optimal
that is a very good question
um when i was running a thousand watt
high pressure sodium light um
i
let's talk about my personal small home
grow because i'm pretty sure this person
isn't running a commercial grow with
gavitas which is what i do in a
commercial environment let's talk about
a small home grow or a small personal
private setup if i had 1000 watt hps
what reflector type and what distance do
i find to be optimal we've got a few
options i really like the vented and
ducted hoods that sounds weird to a lot
of people let me try to explain what i'm
talking about because some people may
not know
we basically
so all lights not all but the basic
design of a grow light is that you've
got your bulb and the bulb hangs
horizontally so it's going this way it
screws into the socket and it goes this
way then when it shines the light goes
all out of that bulb every direction so
we put it inside of what we call a
reflector or a hood and that it does
just like what it sounds like it's
supposed to do it reflects the light
down so all that light that goes up from
the top of the bulb hits that reflector
and gets spread down onto our plants
down onto our canopy we're paying for
all that light we want to move that
light down where we want it get those
photons to the plants so the light is
the light bulb is inside of this
basically an umbrella think of it as an
umbrella that is directing the light
back down onto your plants
now think about there's going to be a
lot of heat
generated by that bulb and that heat is
going to come down heat does rise but
that heat will come down into the plant
area into the canopy it will also raise
rise up out of that uh environment that
hood there that duct that uh the shield
the reflector will rise up out of there
and start heating up the grow room very
rapidly a thousand watt light puts off a
lot of btus of heat so one thing that i
like to do is buy what is known as a
ducted hood it's got glass underneath
there so the light goes inside the hood
or in the reflector and the glass goes
underneath that so now the heat cannot
escape from that enclosure and it stays
inside of there but
they've added six or eight inch flanges
on either end of it to where you can run
ducting in and ducting out and put a
blower at one end and extract that heat
from that light and get it away from the
grow environment i run a carbon filter
then ducting then the light then more
ducting and that goes right out of the
enclosure if it's a house if it's a
warehouse if it's a into another room if
it's a garage i run that right out to
another place just to exhaust that heat
get rid of it immediately and never even
makes it into the grow environment in
the winter i'll actually dump that into
either a veg room or a bedroom just to
use that heat utilize the heat i'm
spending the money on the electricity
let's utilize that heat that i heated up
get something out of it so
my favorite light setup in a thousand
watt environment for a home grow or a
personal project grow
is um a reflector with glass at the
bottom and the flanges at the end that
is ducted we call that a vented hood so
that i can just move that heat right
away from that grow light and get it
right out of the grow environment that
is kind of old school that is kind of
archaic but honestly um when i'm trying
something new in my grow space if i'm
trying a new nutrient a new grow style
a new product or anything new i run
those hps lights because i've had the
best results with those i've got the
most experience with those i know how to
operate those very well that's old
school it's kind of archaic but it works
really well for me
i've got a lot of led lights i've been
gifted led lights
people offer me led lighting and
sometimes i just go right back to those
hps lights just because they're reliable
and i love the way that they work in a
commercial grow i always prefer double
ended gavita hps lighting for my
flowering rooms that's always what i
prefer now the next part of the question
was um distance from
the canopy to be optimal
i talked about a vented light a vented
hood if your light is not vented this
answer is going to vary greatly if the
hood is vented and i'm moving a lot of
air through there and getting that heat
from that bulb away from that reflector
i can get those bulbs that reflector
down super close to the plants
depending on the age and size of the
plant i can get somewhere between six
and 24 inches from the canopy that may
sound crazy but you've got a thousand
watt light on a bunch of clones that are
eight inches tall drop that [ __ ] down
to about 24 18 inches above those and
then as they grow up raise the light
raise the light and the light can't go
anymore i just let those plants grow
right up to it by the time they're done
they may be six or eight inches from
that light but it is ducted it is vented
so they're not getting any heat stress
they're not getting any problems they're
not getting bleached from the light
because they grew into it i didn't just
drop that light right on there i let
them grow up into it they knew what they
were getting into they adjusted they
adapted slowly so it all depends on the
plant size and the plant health and how
hot you're getting that environment if
you can keep it cool if you can move
that light get it low get it on there if
you drop that light right on there
you'll notice real stacked tight dense
buds real tight inner nodal spacing that
close to the light uh learn about the
law of the inverse square the further we
get that light away we definitely start
diminishing the value of that light we
get a bigger footprint but we don't get
the intense uh it's the law of the inver
law of inverse square read about that
with lighting you'll learn a lot there i
cannot even delve into that honestly
when it comes to lighting uh lighting
definitely is not my specialty i know
about it i can talk about this really
easily but when it comes to spectrums
and numbers and kelvins my brain does
not absorb that info and i don't that's
i'm lighting ignorant to be mostly
honest with you but uh for this thousand
watt reflector i would drop it real low
if you're not using a vented reflector
stay at least 18 inches above those
plants so they're going to get roasted
stay at least 18 inches above or they
will get too hot have a fan going move
that heat around
but i get as close as i can and i start
paying attention do i see the leaves
curling up do they start giving me signs
that they're pissed off if so then i
just raise that light up just a little
bit i really like to push things that
comes with experience um
you've really got to just do it to learn
it i say get in there and experience
some [ __ ] if you cook some plants you'll
learn what the cook limit is it's how
you burn a pizza that pizza oven the
[ __ ] box says leave it in for 12
minutes you try for nine you check on it
it looks good you check it at 10. it's
cool if you leave it in there for 13 the
things [ __ ] toast you just got to
learn it you got to figure it out
um
as long as ah the thing is cool you can
get it really really low now let me talk
about uh more of what you've got printed
here it says my room is a four and a
half by four and a half room and my
ceiling is six and a half feet high
um i would definitely get a ducted
invented hood if you could that would
definitely be ideal for that room then
it goes on it says i have a 600 and a
400 watt hps system i can use but i'm
thinking about buying a thousand watt
hps system to fix my stretching problem
do you think the two lights are equal or
lesser than a single 1000
that is a really good question i want to
touch on something before i go too far
your stretch problem let's talk about
other ways that could help with a
stretch
because
the light is a good idea the light is
one great step to mitigate the stretch
but is your temperature and humidity
dial then if it's too hot the plants are
going to start stretching if it's too
dry or too wet the plants are going to
start stretching
what is your nighttime temperature and
humidity like how drastic are your
diurnal swings is your daytime and
nighttime temperature and humidity
within 5 or 10 degrees if you can keep
those super close within 5 degrees that
will drastically reduce the amount of
stretch you get from those plants other
things i've talked about is popping the
knuckles on the plants doing a little
bit of lst a little bit of super
cropping where you grab the plant and
just twist it and give it a little a
little my knuckle popped didn't do it
too loud but give it a little pop sound
there that will slow down the stretch so
those are things that could help if
we're going to do it with lighting one
thing i would think about you've got two
fixtures here i wonder if that 400 watt
system will run a metal halide hear me
out this is what i would do tell me if
you think i'm [ __ ] crazy send me an
email grow from your heart hotmail.com
if you were going to do this
i would run the 600 watt high pressure
sodium and the 400 watt metal halide
together as close as you can not as
close you get them but fairly close
together in the dead center of that room
you got a 4x5 room um that's not very
big a 4x5 square that's not very big
that 400 will get enough light down into
there especially with such a low ceiling
and the 600 will get enough light down
in there i'd put those right at the
center of the room
and run both of them the metal halide
and the high pressure sodium you'll get
a lot of great effects from that the
metal halide the blue spectrum from the
metal halide will help you keep that
light or that plant shortened squat
here's a quick detail that i have forgot
to talk about this is something i used
to say a long time ago this detail just
came to my mind as i was rambling if you
guys are experiencing too much stretch
during the beginning of flower another
thing we can do to mitigate that stretch
is don't change your bulb until 14 to 21
days into flower after the stretch phase
is over then switch to that red bulb if
you're running metal halides and hbs's
the blue from the metal halide will keep
those plants shorter and squattier and
more stacked once you see that stretch
stop then switch over to your flower
bulb
let me get back on track to what i was
saying i would use the 600 and 400 i
would do the 600 watt high pressure
sodium i do a 400 watt metal halide and
i would run them together i would do
them on the 11 on a 12 12 cycle and that
honestly i have i had run a crop in a
5x5 tent with they used to make a
reflector called the grozilla and it
would hold two bulbs and i put just like
this i put a 600 and a 400 in there and
i ran those just like a thousand watt
light and that was some of the uh
tastiest most photogenic densest best
most dense anyway some of the best wheat
i ever grew came from that 5x5 with
those two bulbs running side by side in
your situation and in your environment i
do believe that the 400 and the 600
would be better because it's such a
small environment that you don't need
the super penetration from the thousand
watt you want the spread from the two
bulbs imagine if you've got one light
source
you get more shadows if you've got two
bulbs you have two light sources and
less shadows and more light spread yeah
one section is getting a bunch of hps
one section's getting a bunch of metal
halide but you'll get more light spread
we're not going super deep because your
ceiling is only six and a half feet tall
you've only got you've got very little
penetration to try to get there i would
do the 600 and the 400 honestly that is
what i would do in that situation if you
can make the 400a metal how wide that
would be totally ideal for you and that
halide will definitely reduce the amount
of stretch that may help you with your
stretch situation if you can switch both
of those bulbs to metal halides until 21
days into flower then switch the big one
out to the red bulb uh the high pressure
sodium that should make it bang for you
bro that should definitely give you some
progress
all right it goes on it says i know you
have an insane amount of inside
information on this specific topic but i
do understand that you get thousands of
questions per day and may not have time
for this question you guys i do get a
lot of emails and a lot of questions and
i really do
try to get anything that i feel like is
useful for the show that people could a
lot of people can gain knowledge from i
try to get those on the show as soon as
possible don't ever feel discouraged if
i don't answer your questions right away
uh this person said i get thousands of
messages i've got 4 000 unread emails
i'll try to read a lot of them over the
next couple of days and guess what when
i reply
i'll get 4 000 replies so i'm trying i'm
doing my best
it's just me
the show is written produced hosted
edited oh burped into the microphone all
just by me excuse me for the kombucha
burp there i do apologize for that but
it's all just me so i'm doing my best to
get all the questions answered all the
material covered uh don't feel
discouraged don't get upset if you've
sent me a question and i have not
answered it maybe i'm compiling your
question for the appropriate episode
maybe two other three two or three other
people had a similar question i'm going
to dock them out all at once uh maybe
it's just not time for that question or
maybe it just didn't fit the format of
the show and i do apologize i do my best
you guys i'm gonna quit rambling about
that that's enough excuse time with
roster jeff
um thank you for sending me the great
question my dude j.h i had a good time
rambling about this one i hope people
learn some stuff out there i hope we
help people
mitigate the stretch um also
pay attention when you're buying seeds
that's a very important part a lot of
the breeders at least myself i try to
warn you that you're going to get double
or triple the stretch in a pack of seeds
try to read that when you're shopping
and buying stuff that may give you a big
advantage um then it says why not led
for me which is a great question it says
money and and then it goes on to say in
my research there aren't many options
for led that truly outperform hbs and
anything larger than a 4x4 configuration
there are a couple but they are super
expensive and they run 650 to 800 watts
anyway
um i kind of agree with you it seems
like all the leds are designed for
little tiny spaces
and you got to buy a lot of them and
they are super expensive to buy those
lights at the beginning the upfront cost
is expensive of course you save money on
air conditioning electricity bill but
that initial investment
does set you back a little bit
uh my opinion
is that if hps lights are working for
you metal halides are working for you
and you're not you don't find the led
that works for you do your thing the
beauty of running your own grow the
beauty of growing cannabis in your own
environment is that it is yours you can
do what makes you happy as long as you
are satisfied with the outcome of your
product nobody should tell you otherwise
as long as you're not hurting anybody
contaminating anything poisoning anybody
or putting anybody in clear and present
danger ah do your thing bro grow the way
that you want to grow from your heart
breathe with love and don't let the
haters sway you if somebody's telling
you something that you're doing is wrong
and you're happy with the way you're
doing it keep doing it let let yourself
be open to suggestions and have room for
improvement but don't let the internet
haters mess up your game your strategy
everybody on the internet wants to say
you're doing this wrong you got to do
this but they don't even know what
you're doing they don't know the rest of
your project so don't let them [ __ ] you
up do your thing grow with the lights
that work best for you i found that in
the winter my led lights do not keep my
grow room warm i found that in the
summer those led lights are awesome
because i can take down those hbs lights
and not have to run half the amount of
air conditioning so it's all about the
environment the space the time most
importantly what works for you people
always ask what is the best
the best is what works the best for you
i think that uh
i don't even have the best because i
have to change things i think that leds
are the best in the summer and i think
that hbs are the best in the winter you
may think something totally different
because your grow room is totally
different do your thing find what works
best for you adjust and adapt and i like
that my friend here said he's done a lot
of research um
why not in my research there aren't many
options i love it because not enough
people do enough research out there my
friend jh i want to thank you once again
for a great question
if anybody else out there has any
questions corrections comments or
concerns once again you know i would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
send me a message i love creating
listener generated content that lets me
know that i'm at least helping our
friend jh and i'm sure this topic will
help a lot of other people out there so
once again please send me your cannabis
cultivation questions all right ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers growers clone
cutters pollen chuckers led growers high
pressure sodium growers surfers
snowboarders all you great cannabis
smokers out there thank you once again
for hanging out for episode 741 of the
grow from your heart podcast if you feel
like this episode was educational
informative entertaining maybe you just
like to throw me a couple of bucks for
spending time making a show all you have
to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information that
you need to support the show will be
right there on the screen don't forget
to check out that patreon exclusive
video featuring white mike anything else
you need will be on my website there are
a link there is a link there are links
check out the website tune in tap in for
a link to seed vendors merchandise ah
there's all kinds of great stuff a
discord link if you're not on the
discord server you are missing out check
us out on discord
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
billy podunk and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me