[Music]
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 742
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk about
reversing a male plant before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friends at caribou heart
tv let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to my buddy glenn
gironi i want to send a thank you shout
out to frogman420 let's send a big thank
you shout out to my friend colin at
sacred tree organic farms i want to send
a thank you shout out to guido let's
send a big fist bump to operation high
vibes i want to send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy double d let's
send a thank you shout out to kip i want
to send a special thank you to my buddy
all mixed up let's send a big thank you
shout out to noah and let's send a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter my
friend godfather kush then let's wrap it
all up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
brian p big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
slash www.patreon.com from your heart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make it nice
and easy for all of my friends welcome
to the show everybody i feel like we got
all the business out of the way let's
settle in and hang out and chat a little
bit i'm coming to you on a super warm
day here in colorado it gives me the
idea that it is time to get the outdoor
stuff going i've been excited about the
outdoor season many of you may know that
i do a little bit of a breeding project
in a greenhouse i spent part of today
making selections for that outdoor run i
have chosen my mail plant for my outdoor
run i have chosen most of the ladies
that i want to put out there and in the
next few days those ladies will be put
those ladies and gentlemen will be put
in the greenhouse and i am very excited
big shout out to the greenhouse crew
hope you are ladies and gentlemen i hope
you are ready i was going to say i hope
you guys are ready but it's guys and
gals at the greenhouse i hope you are
ready for another kick-ass summer i am
really excited if you can't tell uh
making selections for outdoor got me
hyped up it got me excited for the
outdoor season for summer to get out
there in the greenhouse and play i get a
sunburn get some sun on my face again
it's going to be a great summer i'm
excited i'm not going to tell you the
plants that i've chosen and the plants
i'm going to put outside just yet stay
tuned in future episodes that will come
to light that that information will be
revealed but be patient i'm not ready to
tell anybody yet you'll be excited once
you start hearing the details of what
i'm putting outside all right that's
enough chatter here at the start of the
show talking about the greenhouse i've
got a great email here in front of me
from a person with a very creative name
we will get to that let's do a bit of a
recap on a previous episode probably
three maybe four episodes ago i did a
talk about reversing female plants to
make them give us pollen so we can make
feminized seeds a lot of people had a
great response to that a lot of people
had a great a lot of great questions and
feedback
one of the questions and comments and
pieces of feedback i received the most
was can we or could we or may we or what
happens if we attempt to reverse a male
plant can we take a male plant treat it
with a solution and turn it into a
female to possibly see what that female
plant that male plant would look like as
a female plant a lot of people asked
about that a lot of people had a lot of
great questions so i do have an email
here we're going to read this one we
will use that as a pivot point as a
segue to discuss reversing a male plant
to have it show female sex the message
goes a lot like this it says what's up
bro what's up bro i'm doing good hope
you're well also it says the last
podcast got me thinking i know obviously
two dude plants rubbing weiners together
won't make anything however is it
possible to s1 or r1 cross a male using
sts i'm just thinking it would be an
excellent way to somewhat preserve
genetics of a breed or male and make
some meninized or masculinized seeds or
even see what type of female traits the
male offers i don't know if this is even
possible does this only work for me
females i'm just an overthinking stoner
i hope to hear from you or catch this on
a podcast one day much love from our
friend joe jizz big shout out to my
buddy joe jizz i've never really thought
i'd say that on the show but big up for
the great question
i hope to hear uh from you or catch this
on the podcast well here you are mr jizz
i'm gonna answer your question in detail
here on the podcast
we can
reverse a male plant to show us its
potential as a female the reason we
would do that is exactly what i said we
want to see its potential as a female
which would show me what it will deliver
to my breeding project if i take this
male plant turn it into a girl i've got
a good idea of what the girl offspring
are going to look like as usable
smokable buds it's a completely
different structure a completely
different idea a completely different
purpose so i want to take that male
plant and turn it into a girl and see
what it's going to look like there are
ways to do that that is viable that is
possible
i wouldn't do it i personally wouldn't
do it
to show me what that plant possibly may
look like as a female because in my
theory in my opinion and the time it
would take a grower to reverse a male
plant and turn it to female
i could have grown the male plant and
put pollen on a true female and just
made a bunch of seeds and then grow
those and actually have
real viable seeds that will show me what
the progeny looks like instead of
reversing the male it takes nearly the
same amount of time except i have seeds
i have to grow but it's more fun to me i
get seeds at the end of it i don't just
get one reversed plant that i can't
really do anything with because i'm not
going to smoke it or consume it because
it's been treated and it's been reversed
it's going to show me potentially what
it would look like as a female kind of
it's going to
it
it's going to be a little bit wonky
you'll be able to tell that something
happened to it it'll still have an
adam's apple or wide shoulders or
something you'll know but it will give
you an idea of what it's going to look
like as a female so it will work but in
the time it's going to take you to
reverse that plant i've already grown
out my male pollinated females and i'm
growing out the seeds to see what my
breeding project is i'm already a step
ahead of the person who didn't uh waste
time doing that so it's very possible uh
the reason that we would do it is now
making
male seeds or masculine or mennonized
seeds that doesn't
really interest me i wouldn't want to
preserve a breed or male i can make
seeds i know that in a batch of seeds
there'll be males or females i know if
i've got all females i can make a male
out of that or a pollen donor out of
that so that's not something that gets
my attention but it is possible it is a
viable option for somebody it's not an
avenue that i want to explore but it is
something that could be done um you
could make an s1 or r1 cross yes you can
do that now let's talk about i've got
some notes here on the computer that i
want to jump into
um
so when you reverse the mail it shows it
as a female i said kinda it gives an
idea of its potential but it only shows
what it will look like as a female it
doesn't show what it's going to do in a
breeding project we will see what it
looks like as a female but that doesn't
show what's going to pass if we do
breeding
we can see that there's this trait and
this trait as a female and we know that
it'll express that but when we breed it
to other plants how much of that stuff
moves over how much of that carries how
much of that is shared into the
offspring so once again i feel like if i
just pollinated and grew out the seeds
i'm getting much more uh progress much
more details much more info a lot more
data because now i know
i always talk about when i pollinate i
never use a male i rarely use a male to
pollinate one plant most of the time if
i'm using a boy he's gonna pollinate at
least four six maybe nine or ten
different girls because when i grow the
seeds from those nine or ten different
girls i can see what that male is doing
amongst a different population of
different female plants if i cross let's
say i take a lemon we're just going to
pick lemon because lemons are very easy
to work with flavor take a lemon male
and cross it to a strawberry female a
blueberry female a chocolate female i
don't want to see lemon come out of all
these crosses i want to see a blend of
lemon strawberry lemonade i want lemon
blueberry i want lemon chocolate or
chocolate lemon i don't want that lemon
to wash over everything
so i want to see what the lemon is
contributing so i'm going to mix it to a
lot of different other things pour that
lemon juice on a lot of other things
taste it see what works best if i only
cross it to one thing i don't really i
can see that it got this and this but is
that a one-time thing is that an anomaly
is that what it actually passes is that
how it does it play well with others
does it get along with just that one
plant it's kind of the thing so i can
see that by actually doing the
pollination the reversal is cool it
shows you a lot of cool [ __ ] but we
don't see what it does as breeding so
it's fun it gives you a lot of details
but it's not as effective as i would
want it to be for the amount of time
effort energy and expense which it takes
me to do that project um
making a plant show reverse and show its
potential probably takes longer than
breeding it and growing out those seeds
from multiple females is what i wrote in
my notes i'm just covering the notes
make sure i get all the stuff here so
one thing i should definitely cover and
talk about is we're doing something
different when we were reversing when we
are attempting to reverse the male plant
uh compared to when we were reversing
the female so that means we need a
different solution we want to do
basically the opposite um when we are
making fems we want to stop the ethylene
production when we are reversing a
female to make it a male
or reversing a male to make it a female
see i'm even getting confused on all
this new stuff the future is weird you
guys when we're making fem seeds we want
to stop the ethylene production when
we're doing the opposite we want to
encourage and promote that ethylene
production and do things a little bit
differently so we use a different
chemical or a different solution for
this project we use a chemical or a
product called ethaphon and it's spelled
e-t-h-a-p-h-o-n
ethephon is what i believe the product
is called the chemical is called i use
that product to reverse the male plant
to show its female sex
the product that you would buy is called
ethaphon 2 sl if you're shopping if
you're going to do it that's the product
you need here i go with my rant
if you're going to play with any
chemicals if you're going to apply any
products
read the labels read the manuals read
the safety data sheets also after that
where all of the recommended and
required personal protective equipment
if you get hurt if you get sick if you
go blind if you [ __ ] up and do something
wrong i am not responsible for your
dipshittery i'm telling you right now
read the [ __ ] label wear the
protective equipment if you hurt
yourself make yourself sick [ __ ] up some
plants have a bad time not my fault bro
i'm telling you read the label do [ __ ]
correctly do [ __ ] carefully um when
you're mixing when you're applying have
gloves have goggles if it recommends
anything else wear that stuff when you
were spraying the plant remove that one
plant from the grow environment put it
in a safe place spray the one plant wait
till it dries then put that plant back
in the rest of the environment or you
will run the risk of getting the other
plants a reversal spray on accident
those other plants didn't sign up for a
sex change let's not do that to them so
the product you want is ethephone2sl
be very careful when you were using it
apply it to the plant is to where it's
uh
dripping off but not [ __ ] soaking off
the plant you want it kind of saturated
but you don't want it raining off
because then too much of it falls off
you want it to stay on the leaf
possibly consider using a a wetting
agent a sticker a spreader sticker to
keep that on to the plant a little bit
better also don't just spray the leaves
spray the stems and the stalks as well
get the plant fully wet with the
ethaphon 2sl spray now let's talk about
dilutions i use very little too much of
this stuff and the plants go
and they just start twisting up and they
start getting weird crazy arms and they
start showing you that they are pissed
off
i recommend you start with approximately
a one to one hundred ratio that's right
one milliliter of ethaphon 2sl to
199 milliliters of distilled water so
it's a one to i do one and a hundred
milliliters it's a one to a 100 ratio
maybe even a half or 0.7 of a milliliter
if you can measure that small i don't
have a device to measure that small
maybe you quantify it go bigger do a lot
of water and then more of the ethe fonts
you could do the math but about half to
one milliliter per 100 milliliters of
water is enough more than that and the
plants will get pissed off i don't have
enough experience with this to give you
a lot of details i've done this
i can't say i did this i was involved
with this project i did this with
somebody else i was kind of the uh i was
the one watching and taking notes we
were doing it together but they were
much more excited about it so i just
kind of observed and i was there but we
did it with the ethephon 2sl
we sprayed multiple plants a lot of them
crinkled up curled went to [ __ ] some of
them can take it very well we noticed it
is ratio dependent also very strain
dependent and the plants look ugly as
hell once they're transitioning to
females they're not attractive in any
way shape or form once they finish up
they get kind of weird kind of strange
and if you uh don't
uh spray one time with that the font
i've learned that one spray of that the
font will do it if you spray too many
times they definitely freak out later in
flower all right that is all i've got
for you with reversing males that is all
the experience all the info all the data
that i've got it does work it is
possible however i don't find it to be
useful because i can get more data in my
opinion um from just breeding that plant
to females i get more feedback more data
and i get seeds if i'm just reversing it
i don't have [ __ ] to show for my work
except for some half-assed data that is
my opinion it does work
it will show you potential uh we use a
different solution we use the ethaphon
2sl i apply it at a 1 to 100 ratio i
apply it one time the day we put the
plants into flower that's all it needs
and it should work
that's all i've got for you if you have
any questions corrections comments or
concerns you know that i would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy let's keep this conversation going
if you have reversed a male to show its
potential as a female send me pictures
send me uh stories of your experience
we'll talk about it more on the show if
you have more questions like this i
would love to hear from you of course
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy also
don't forget about the patreon campaign
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart
once again everything is on my website
iriegenetics.com sometimes i talk a
little bit fast sometimes people miss
stuff everything you could possibly
imagine is on the website
iriegenetics.com alright this is going
to be a quick episode short and sweet
nice and to the point sometimes that's
all we need i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a giant shout out to my friends at
lollipop farms and until next time take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for me