[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode
743 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to talk about
seed packaging we'll read a couple of
emails before i get to that part of the
show let's do a few shout outs to a few
of those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
elder's garden let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to route 305.
i want to send a big thank you shout out
to my buddy adhd grower let's send a
special thank you shout out to jay dutch
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to my dude dreadlock farmer
let's send a big thank you shout out to
grow man stan special thank you to jimmy
limmer a big fist bump to my dude kojaks
let's send a big thank you shout out to
quasi then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend danny potts
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast let me
start off by sending a big thank you to
everybody who gave me feedback on the
current patreon episode that's right if
you're supporting the show on patreon
you were sent a link where you can watch
a special edition patreon only version
of the podcast it does feature myself
and white mike we both ate 100
milligrams of edibles
we did get a lot of feedback on that
episode all 100 positive feedback so
thank you for that i do appreciate that
i do want to attempt to give you more
episodes like that but i need more ideas
for more content people have sent me
some ideas some things to think about i
will work those into into the show i
don't feel like i want to do grow
material on the patreon because i want
to include everybody and grow material
so if there's other stuff you'd like me
to talk about if you've got questions
that are not grow related or something
you just want some info some details on
other stuff i've talked about whatever
you want to know that's not grow related
we could put it on the patreon send me
that question join the patreon check for
those special edition episodes also let
me give a giant shout out to my buddy
riven that's right riven waters made
that if you're watching the video
episode and i hope you are if you're
listening on spotify apple podcast
wherever you may be listening i do
encourage you encourage you to join us
on the youtube channel because my buddy
riven did make a great uh really cool
intro video for the podcast that's what
you've seen for this episode in the past
couple and probably for the next few
episodes because i do like that intro so
big special thanks a fist bump a high
five a thumbs up a shout out to my buddy
riven for the beautiful intro screen i
love that spinning cross he took my logo
made it spin around
that is super cool it made me smile real
big thank you bro i appreciate that the
next order of business if you hear some
jingle and some clang-a-langing sounds
in the background ah that's my new air
conditioner it's making a lot of noise
it's a hot day here in colorado the
first real hot day i'm not going to be
an old man to talk about the weather but
it's hot outside so i got the air
conditioner going i don't know if the
software and equipment will cut that out
if not there you go disclaimer there's
some background noise i apologize it's
hot you got to deal with it
where do we go from there
a lot of people have been asking where
is the discord what happened to the ire
army discord server uh there is a new
discord server i've been talking about
this on a lot of episodes but i'm trying
to get the word out i would appreciate
it if you share the word with your
friends if you had friends on discord
and they're not on the ire army discord
server please invite them remind them
that there was a change in the server we
are no longer on the old server if you
click on that that's a different link
some things went weird there we have
abandoned that server we have created
our own new server uh we've got a great
new mod team things are i just actually
finished up an hour and 20 minute mod
meeting with the discord mods so uh big
thanks to all those guys the point of
this is there is a new link to the new
updated discord server in the video
notes and the show description if you
want to find the new discord server join
us on there you are invited on that
server uh there's a lot of great content
a lot of great information one of my
favorite things is the smoker's lounge
chat where anybody can just come in and
hang out and chat it is a video chat
i'm there at least one night a week
sometimes twice a week depending on how
busy things get i like to pop in just
depends on if i get done with my chores
or maybe i'm packing up seeds something
i'm doing sitting at the desk that kind
of work where i can hang out in [ __ ]
i'll just pop into the live chat hang
out with people answer a few questions
uh sometimes i'm just hanging out
listening to you guys chat we just have
normal everyday conversations sometimes
we talk very intensely about growing
cannabis and cannabis ideas a lot of
interesting conversation also one of my
other favorite parts is the tester tab i
send out a lot of tester seeds to people
and they post their reports there on the
tester tab and i love seeing what people
are growing the progress of the testers
i love that
on the discord you will also find tabs
for most of the strains i have created
the users and the mods have created a
tab for most of the strains i say most
because there's stuff that's not even
put out yet things they don't know about
that are coming out uh that will be out
very soon hint and tease teas but uh
they've got a list on the side of every
single strain that's available you can
click on there and you can see other
growers experiences with that strain you
can see their flowering photos their
grow reports if they had problems if
they have questions the answers to those
questions so i find it to be a very
great resource and a useful resource for
anybody growing ire genetics so
my point here if you are a part of the
irie army the grow from your heart
podcast community which you are if you
are watching or listening i invite you
to the discord server come hang out with
us you never know you may pop in on the
smoker's lunch and i may be hanging out
right there in the chat you might see me
taking dabs might get to hang out you
might get to ask me your question face
to face what else are we going to talk
about uh one more thing to ramble about
then we're going to talk about some of
the main topics of this podcast
i got to see if you know me at all you
know i'm a huge uh reggae fan uh not
only am i huge i'm also a reggae fan i
am also a huge reggae fan that just
works out for me um yeah i'm 65 with
dreadlocks down to about my calf region
you guys just in case you wondered how
far down these crazy things go they hit
the calf area and i'm 6'5 so i am a huge
reggae fan i will move forward um a few
nights ago i got to go see with my
lovely queen miss dread vibes also known
as miss zara we got to go see the lovely
natalie rise if you know anything about
me you know that i smile weirdly when we
talk about natalie rise i think she's
amazing she's a great musician she's a
great singer she's a great writer and i
may have a little bit of a crush on her
and my girlfriend is okay with that so
don't go snitching on me uh but we got
to see natalie sing we got to see her
perform it was a great show
good energy uh something about just the
uh the recharging of the energy there
that comes from a natalie rise concert
felt really good so big up to natalie
rise big up to the few people saw a
couple people there that knew who we
were and what we were doing so big up to
the crew that saw us there shout out to
all the great dreadlocks at the event
there were so many people at dreadlocks
at that concert i had a great time you
guys go see some live music we're
allowed and able to go get out and see
music again it doesn't have to be reggae
if you're not a reggae fan if you're not
into that go see whatever you're into if
you're into norwegian death metal go get
your mosh pit on if you're into some
celtic folk dance go spin your legs
around do your thing and have a good
time is what i'm talking about get out
there fill your vibes with some good
music fill your soul up we're able to do
it again go get out there it felt really
nice now i'm [ __ ] rambling let's talk
about some cannabis cultivation things
that's what this podcast is all about
we've been going for a long time i
haven't talked about cannabis yet
um i recently got a message from
somebody who was saying that they want
to start a new seed company they said
that they look up to my company that
they see that what i've been doing is
obviously working and they wanted ques
they had questions about how important
is seed packaging and how to package
seeds
i'm going to focus mainly on like seed
company with branding and all that sort
of stuff like an official company that's
going out for a seed vendor for retail
sales let's think about uh that type of
packaging and we'll also talk about just
brodabro peer-to-peer seed exchanges and
that sort of stuff uh when it comes to
commercial packaging something that's
very important is branding some people
are not going to know who you are what
you're about what your vibe is what your
motto is they don't know anything about
you except this package of seeds that
they've got in their hand that's the
only thing that is representing your
company your seeds your expectations of
those beans
so i think ah branding is very important
have the company name on my packaging
you can prominently see irie genetics
displayed at the top then it says
premium seeds it lets you know these are
premium seeds it tells you what the
brand is and what is in the package when
you flip it over on the back it tells
you the strain now in the middle of the
pack it says the straw on the top once
again it says irie genetics because i
want it to be redundant when you flip it
over you see it's irie genetics in the
middle i use a sticker that says the
strain it indicates what strain it is
sometimes i will put how many weeks it
takes to flower on that package
depending on how old my labels are
sometimes i do that sometimes i don't i
should be more
more fluid with doing that more
regularly but i'll put the brand the
brand on top the strain in the middle
then on the bottom something i find to
be very important i put my website
address why not have the web address on
there that way if there are any
questions any problems anything you want
to know more details you can go to the
website on my website there's a full
report on that string possibly with a
link to a podcast of that strain
possibly with discord info all kinds of
great [ __ ] linked up to it that you can
read about the whole strain get the info
you need so
the main things i think about are the
company name what's your company name
what are you called i'm obviously
iriegenetics that's printed on the very
front then it says premium seeds i
created a logo i did not create i had an
artist create me a logo big up to my
artist friends name's adam i believe
they made me a very cool logo that i
feel represents my brand very well um
obviously uh the name is irie which is a
jamaican word it's a patchwhile word
that means uh it's got a lot of meanings
to it but basically means to feel really
good it's most powerful the most
pleasing feeling you could ever imagine
i describe it as kind of like if you're
sitting on the beach or if you're
sitting on a hill a grassy hill and the
sun is setting and you see the waves
going maybe and you got your girl on one
side and the dog on the other maybe
you're smoking a fat joint and
everything is just cool man there's
nothing bothering you nothing's wrong
nothing could go wrong everything feels
right that is irie feeling irie got the
irie genetics so i my vibe and my brand
is obviously got that rasta reggae irie
sort of vibe to it so there's a lot of
red yellow and green colors in there
then i use a cross logo that comes
heavily from rasta culture then on the
back when we flip it over it's got a
cool little design there's another
little design hidden under the main
design also that you may not notice but
then on the back
i feel like it's got my face on it and a
website address i feel like putting my
face on there really puts a lot of
transparency to my brand that is me i'm
the guy to that brand uh you know who to
talk to when you email it you know when
you email my company you know who you're
talking to you know who the customer
service guy is you know who made the
seeds you know whose ideas these are you
know who you're representing uh and
whose product you're buying so on the
top it says irie genetics in the middle
it's got the strain on the bottom it's
got the website with my little face logo
on the bottom of the packaging so i feel
like we cover most of the important
aspects that are on the outside we've
got branding and we've got contact info
and we've got product information a lot
of people will put disclaimers of some
sort this is a novelty item souvenir
purposes only it depends on where you're
shipping your product that is legal
stuff that i would consult your legal
team with i don't add that to my
packages because many of my vendors will
staple a card to the package or a big
order will get one card that says
whatever it needs to say depending on
where it is going if it's a novelty a
souvenir a cbd a hemp item that will be
attached later on as necessary depending
on where it's being distributed so the
first thing i think about is branding
put your brand name on there this is the
one op this is like your business card
this is the one opportunity people get
to identify your brand associate it with
something in their head if you draw a
dagger on it some people may not be into
that but the people that are into
daggers are definitely going to remember
it if you put a lollipop on there some
of my packages have really cool logos
the lollipop logo gets a lot of
attention the blue raspberry truffle
logo gets a lot of attention orange gasm
has a fancy logo it gets a lot of
attention those packages get noticed
after many strains get success i will
create a specific package for that
stream but most of my stuff comes in a
generic package with irie genetics
premium seeds the cross logo you flip it
over it's got the brand the strain name
and the website on the bottom keep it
simple but give all of the pertinent
information that is needed then people
can contact me from there kind of got
rambly forgot where i was going the next
thing we should think about is
protecting those seeds what is inside
that package is the most important part
the branding is great contact info is
good
having a an identity on a table filled
with seed packs in your seed packets
standing out that is really cool but are
the seeds in there crushed because
they've got to get mailed handled and
delivered so always put them inside of
some sort of protective
packaging of some sort i buy
bubble containers from a company called
lacontainers.com they're quite expensive
i buy them by 3000 at a time to be quite
honest with you and it is quite
expensive shipping on those things is
super expensive they ship from la via
ups uh really expensive that that eats
up a big cost of seed sales right there
it's just the packaging uh so i use the
bubbles with the foam insert i open up
the clam shell bubble put the seeds in
there put the foam insert over it and
then i close it then that goes inside of
a 3x3 baggie with the folded card inside
with all the info those all slide
together then just for security purposes
for safety for peace of mind i like to
heat seal most of my packages if you get
them directly from me they might not be
heat sealed but if i send them to a
vendor i try to make sure they're heat
sealed before they go out so they cannot
be tampered with
if they come from me and they're not
heat sealed they came straight from me
bro the only person that [ __ ] with
them was me and then if you plan on
reselling them or something just tell
them you got them straight from me it
should be legit but um yeah i seal most
of the packs that go out so they are in
a protective bubble in a foam so they
don't rattle around too much in the
packaging and also so they don't go
flying out when you open that
that gets put inside of a baggie which
has got a card folded inside of it for
all the info also that card um keeps the
light out now the seeds are protected
from the light then that gets heat
sealed then i bundle them in packs of
five they go into a container that is
labeled properly
that's how those go but mainly think
about branding put your brand name on
there the strain name as much strain
info as you can and then some contact
info i think my website info is great
sometimes i do include a sticker on the
inside with a link to my discord so if
people want to join the discord they can
check that out as well but i try not to
put too many confusing things inside
there now keep this in mind i do come
from the music industry so when you look
at my packaging my packages are designed
as record labels if you look at an album
like an album yeah guys we're going that
old people vinyl is coming back back in
the day we had these big now this is
older than me even but back in the day
we had vinyls i grew up with cds it's a
square case with a square design all the
cd covers were a square i always wanted
to be in a [ __ ] successful rock and
roll band or some [ __ ] i had fun i did
my thing but this is where i'm supposed
to be is in the cannabis industry but i
did tour with a lot of bands i did a lot
of work with a lot of bands a lot of my
uh art and design and branding ideas
come from the music industry so it's all
about catching somebody's eye and
standing out and kind of identifying
your so in the music industry if you're
metal or some sort of hard rock stuff
use skulls and like that blood drip sort
of [ __ ] logo right we already know
what that is uh if you use um a certain
kind of font we know that you're a rap
group if you use a certain kind of font
we know that you're a pop group we've
just identified certain things with
certain if you see the k you know that's
kmart if you see that lady with their
legs behind her head you know that's
starbucks they're just certain things
inside of our brain they give us a
certain idea i've learned how to do that
through branding through bands with my
seed company so i've learned how to
identify myself create a vibe and stand
out with my packaging so i think a lot
of that came from the end the music
industry is where i get a lot of that
vibe a lot of those ideas if you notice
a lot of my [ __ ] looks like a record
label it's like the band name the album
name you flip it over the songs are
listed on the back here's our website
that's a lot of how albums do it that's
kind of how i was doing it and then i
found a really cool artist shout out to
my buddy kevin who does great art for me
also shout out to dp710
but these guys do great art and then i
put those on the packages that makes it
a lot of fun all right i've been
rambling for a little bit here i did say
i was going to read a cannabis
cultivation question i do have one great
question here in front of me i said one
great question i hope you guys enjoy it
as much as i do this one came from our
friend who calls himself used to be cool
every time i read that i say you're
listening to the podcast bro so you are
still cool in my book don't ever think
you're not cool bro you're cool until
you decide you're not cool anymore it's
just like getting old you're not old
until you decide you are i'm rambling
let me stay focused a little bit this
one says i had five plants in my 4x4
which included two orange gasm plants
all of them but one orange gasm finished
between 55 and 60 days the remaining
orange gasm appears to be within
appeared to be within 10 days of
finishing so to help it along i followed
your pro tip about switching the lights
back to 18 6. let me talk about that
because maybe people don't listen to
every episode i've talked about this in
several episodes this is a technique and
a method that i do use quite often when
i'm flowering my plants at the end of
flower approximately 10 to 14 days
before harvest around the same time that
i begin to flush i put my grow lights
back on an 18 hour on and six hour off
cycle my theory and what i've proven by
doing this several times is that my buds
get chunkier they get more dense and
they finish up more quickly so that is
why i'm doing this i'm turning my lights
to 18.6 for a faster finish and a
chunkier product now let's talk about
what our friend is doing and what has
happened here
i followed your advice and switched the
lights to 18 6. i'm now on day 67 and
the remaining orange gasm still looks
like it's about 10 days from finishing
i'm not sure what to do if it doesn't
finish within the 14 days of the light
switch can i go back to 12 12 if it's
not done and then okay i know i know
where we are it says thanks for any
advice you can offer now this is a great
question i'm going to start off by um
i'm not going to scold you but i'm going
to give you some constructive criticism
that i keep saying when we talk about
the 186 because i need to get this piece
of advice out and make it more clear
many people have taken to the 18 6 idea
at the end of flower it seems to be
successful for a lot of people
one thing i want to make clear and
reiterate and remind you that i think is
a better practice
is to not do this the first time you run
a plant run the plant the first time
find out how long that plant takes to
finish then do this the second time we
don't know how long that plant is going
to go our dude used to be cool here
started too early now the plant is not
done because he didn't know the plant
doesn't have any experience with this
cultivar and now he's got himself in a
weird position and he's not sure what to
do so my very first piece of advice is
don't do this on the first run with a
new plant run that plant once run that
plant maybe twice find out how long is
ideal for that that plant to finish that
particular plant to finish up then do
this technique the second time and see
if you can reduce the flowering time
have some data to compare it to the
first time would be my suggestion now
unfortunately we're past that we can't
go back in time we can't grow this one
more time and then figure it out we've
got to work with what we've got so let's
find a solution
what i would do is keep going the way
that you are going keep going do not put
it back to 12 12. you've already gone
from 18 6 to 12 12 back to 18 6. we
don't want to confuse this plant anymore
that's when you may get seeds that's
when you may get manners that's when you
may get problems that's when it just may
completely [ __ ] freak out and ruin
everything so i would not go back i
would keep going until the moment i see
signs of absolute re-veg once you know
it's for sure re-vegging on you that's
when i would cut down you should be
flushing already so it's going to be
ready to cut whenever you're ready to
cut it so as soon as you see that
revenge cut but
um it'll take a little bit it's not
going to happen to re-veg right away
you've got a pretty strong plant if it's
still taken away if it's still taking
time to finish that means it will take
longer to re-veg as well
that's just a commonality in the
genetics if it takes longer to finish it
will take longer to revenge so that's a
good thing keep it going wait until you
see signs of revenge you've got more
than the 14 days i say 10 to 14 because
that is ideal you won't see signs of
revenge until at least 17 21 maybe 24 26
days pay attention to the plant keep
going and as soon as you see that
revenge then cut it down that's what i
would do
um i would not do the 12 12 it's had
enough i said this before it's already
stressed out it's already had enough uh
it will get confused it'll get pissed
off i don't know what it will do uh if
you put it back under 1212 that that
really could freak that plant out so i
think uh
the number one thing to take away from
this and my dude i know it's already too
late we can't go back in time but the
number one thing that i would take away
from this is do not do this with new
cuts that we don't know how long they
take to finish because that is how you
run into this exact situation to wrap it
up i would keep going until you see
signs of reef edge uh reef edge will be
little leaves poking out of the top of
the buds uh the bottom leaves will start
curling up kind of weird i would keep
going until you see that you're already
flushing so it'll be clean by the time
you cut it down as soon as you see that
revenge starting cut it down unless it
gets ready before that which it might
that's another thing i wanted to touch
on
since you're going at this light pace it
is finishing more rapidly than you think
uh you're saying it appeared to be
within 10 days looks like it's still 10
days if it doesn't finish in within the
14 within the next few days this plan is
going to show a lot of progress it is
getting a lot of light it is going to
progress much more quickly than you're
anticipating because it is at the end if
it's not already turning yellow the
leaves are getting droopy that will
happen very soon uh it will begin to go
into senescence and it will be done uh
before too long just naturally because
the plant knows that it's just about
time for that plant to be done so i
think you'll be all right and if not
you're gonna have to cut down a plant
that is a little bit too early it's not
quite done but ah that's a learning
lesson and
if you cut down orange gasm i think
you'll still have if you cut down orgasm
too early i think you'll still be happy
you'll still have a satisfying outcome
because it's still going to be a head
ringer of a buzz that sativa buzz is
really strong when you cut it down early
so even if it's a little bit early you
still may get a real head ripping
psychedelic sativa buzz out of that even
though it didn't finish as long as we
could have let it go my dude used to be
cool it's been great hearing from you i
haven't gotten a message from you in a
while hope everything is irie let me
know how things go let me know when you
finally cut this plant down let me know
how it looked how it smoked how it
tasted let me know if you got any reveg
let me know i want a feedback report ah
thank you bro i do appreciate that all
right we've got one more breeding
question here this one came from our
friend uh no need to give me a shout out
we know who i am so my dude thank you uh
he wants to remain anonymous so we're
gonna quickly read this message and it
says ross to jeff you bad [ __ ] i
hope all is well in your corner of the
world i'd like to start off by saying
thank you for providing high quality
content practical and reliable advice
and at the best price the internet has
to offer dude thank you that is a great
way to start a message i appreciate that
um
you're welcome high quality content i
appreciate that that's a lot of work
practical and reliable that's what it's
all about too many people on the
internet are giving crazy [ __ ] advice
keep it simple stoner and then the best
price yes the show is free i do
appreciate it that you notice that the
show is free uh some people are bothered
that i do ask for patreon contributions
but there nobody's forcing anybody and
the people that do contribute seem
grateful so thank you for that let's
keep moving it says leading to the
question i found two plants that i have
selected to breed for very different yet
specific reasons and then he talks about
the plants i don't think i'm going to
talk too much about that
he says one has lateral branches okay we
can skip a lot of this it says the
second plant they talk about the second
plant now i know the answer to this
question is which is why i'm able to
skip over some of this i did pre-read
this it goes on it says i know part of
this was covered in a previous episode
but i cannot seem to find it but which
of these plants should i reverse my goal
is basically to get buds and terps as
well as the shorter flowering time from
the tall skinny one and get the
structure and vigor from the short one
it seems logical to reverse the taller
one as it will seem it will have an
easier time pollinating the shorter
plant more thoroughly that's a good
logical approach to that but i'm not
sure the best way to go just because it
seems to make sense to me i attached
pics he goes on to say i did attach pics
i did look at the pictures i'll have
some feedback on that it says
respectively and i hope they give you a
better uh mean to my goals thank you for
the time bro any advice would mean a lot
to me i'll be sure to give my mom a hug
for both of us as well p.s okay and then
he said there's no need to give him a
shout out so i skipped a lot of the
plant description here because in this
message your plant descriptions are not
uh super important to the audience i
know what your goal is i know what
you're going for i don't need to read
the long descriptions here you've got
the right idea i think
you answered your own question with your
own intuition you said it seems logical
to reverse the taller one
something inside of you was saying to do
that and if you don't do that you're
always going to wonder what you would
have done if you what you would have
done if you did that and didn't do the
other thing so my first advice is always
follow your intuition if something
inside of you says to reverse that one
as a breeder as a plant grower as the
person in charge of this product as the
artist involved here do what your heart
is telling you to do what your intuition
says when it comes to breeding i often
say learn about mendel charts learn
about alieal charts learn about dominant
recessive genes learn about codominant
genes
learn about filial generations learn how
to label things then once you've got all
that stuff figured out
forget about it and grow from your heart
and breed with love and use your
intuition when you look at two plants in
a grow room something's gonna go man if
that plant and that plant got together
and made seeds and made plants they
would be amazing do that it seems like
you're on that path which is the passion
the desire the grow from your heart the
breed with love that's the most
important part of it um then seeing what
comes out of it is the most fun if you
are making a project that is assigned by
me that's an assignment that's work uh
that's a project that you're just doing
do what you love to do do what your
heart is calling for you to do and
also my next piece of advice is do the
other way also because ah this isn't
going to be your last time breeding
seeds your only time breeding do them
both and see what they both do then in
the future breed them together that's i
know it sounds crazy it sounds like a
lot but as a breeder who's way ahead of
you in this breeding game who knows how
this uh i don't want to say addiction
but that's how this addiction goes but
that's how this passion goes you're
going to make some seeds out of plant a
to plant b and you're going to grow them
and you're going to go hmm and you're
going to do plant b to plant a and
you're going to grow up and then you're
going to see two plants and they're
going to go oh [ __ ] and then you're
going to cross those and that one is
going to be your [ __ ] the mastermind
right there that's going to be the ninja
samurai warrior yoda buddha right there
that you're looking for so my first
advice is use your intuition follow your
heart
do what your heart told you to do if not
that's almost
a lot of things in life follow your
heart use your intuition because if you
don't if there's something that you want
to do and you don't do it when you're
too old to do it you're gonna be like
[ __ ] i should have done that i'm gonna i
wish i would have done that like you're
gonna you're gonna really that's when
you have regrets is when you don't do
the [ __ ] that you thought you should do
so get that [ __ ] done do the one you
have the idea for use that taller one as
your first pollinator then again the
second time reverse that [ __ ] do the
other one and let that tall one receive
pollen um
also it really depends on who and we
don't know this until we breed we don't
know which plant has dominant and uh
recessive and co-dominant traits we
don't know which traits are gonna take
over the mix you've never bred with
either one of these plants we don't know
what either one of them adds so we don't
know what to expect you could uh
possibly and this is just hypothetical
you could reverse plant a and pollinate
plant b and the outcome could either be
all plant a or all plant b you could do
the opposite and both of those effects
could be the out the outcome or you
could reverse plant a and pollinate
plant b and it could be a 50 50 mix you
could reverse plant b and pollinate a
and it could be 70 30 on the outcome on
the phenotypes we don't know what
they're offering it could be all
intersex plants it could be all
intersects if you do it one way and all
solid fems if you do it the other way so
really we just have to breed with these
plants is really the only true way to
find out you have to breed them make the
crosses grow them take a lot of notes
and pay a lot of attention but that is
where the passion comes from that is
what the passion is all about that's why
we're growing from our heart and
breeding with love my dude who wants to
remain anonymous i really hope i gave
you some useful advice my main piece of
advice with this one is follow your
intuition do the thing that first
inspired you to do this then you got the
rest of your life to do the rest of the
projects i recommended
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters and paul and
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i'm sure you can
hear my throat burning out so it is time
to wrap up this episode if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know that i would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
fromyourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
send me a message let me know what you
think of the show also if you'd like to
support the show all you have to do is
visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart of course there is a link in
the show notes and in the video
description everything else is on my
website and i read iregenetics.com
check out the website there is a vendor
list there is a discord link anything
you can imagine will be on the website
iriegenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy doc and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you