hey everybody this is doug benson and
you're listening to the grow from your
heart podcast hosted by my buddy rosta
jeff
[Music]
so
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me rasta
jeff this is episode 744 of the grow
from your heart podcast in this episode
i'm going to answer a couple of listener
emails before i get to that part of the
show let's do a few shout outs to a few
of the kind folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my
friends at randy farms let's send a big
thank you shout out to mr mean green and
the larf knight rises let's send a big
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
stone to trout bum and roll this nug
let's send a big fist bump to og roach
and the devil's weed let's send a big
thank you shout out to my friend growing
tennessee let's send a special thank you
to just a smokin i want to send a big
shout out to stash drop i want to send a
thank you shout out to my buddy anvil
gardens then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to levity love day big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and you know i
do include a link in the show notes and
in the video description to make it
super easy for all of my friends to
support the show
at this time i would like to announce
that ivory genetics will be attending
the dude groves cup that's right this
summer there will be a dude grows cup
the location is in fort collins that is
all the information i have got for you
irie genetics will be there it is in
fort collins we will be dabbing we will
be smoking flowers and i am excited to
see you i'm excited to get back out into
the community and see some of my old
friends and make some new friends shake
some hands bump some fists take some
dabs share some flowers and most
importantly get some seeds out to the
community so i do look forward to
meeting you seeing you and hanging out
at the dude grows cup i'm sure all of
the information you need will become
available as time goes on i'm sure all
of the information is available at
dudegroves.com so check out
dudegrows.com for links deets tickets
info all of that stuff i am not hosting
the event i am simply attending and
vending at the event trying to be a part
of the community going to hang out with
the community meet a lot of friends see
a lot of people join us the dude grows
cup i've said more than enough all right
i did say that i've got a bunch of great
emails printed here in front of me uh
where do i start how about this one
because it is on the top of the list
this email came from my friend john this
one came to us on the grow help tab at
iriegenetics.com that's right if you go
to the website
iriegenetics.com there is a grow help
tab on there when you click on that grow
help tab it does give you the
opportunity to answer a few preliminary
questions i ask what are you growing are
you growing indoors or outdoors what's
your temperature what's your humidity
what are you feeding this plant i ask
several questions that gives me an idea
of how to answer your questions people
will send me a question they'll say hey
my plants yellow what do i do and i've
got 20 questions we've kind of cut to
the chase and asked some of those so
that i've got some info a little bit of
a triage a little bit of a checkup if
you will so before we get to the main
question i ask a few questions our
friend john here asked a very simple
question so we don't need to know about
his plants as grow room this one came
from my friend john
this is on the grow help tab of course
and it goes a lot like this it says hey
quick question for you what strains were
bred with the e phenotype of arise that
is a very good question there's a lot to
talk about here uh first of all what
does john mean when he says the e
phenotype of a rise let's talk about
that i am known well maybe i'm not i
like to think that my strain my brand is
known for a strain known as a rise i
made a rise f once i took a
golden goat female and a daybreaker male
and i made some seeds and i named those
arise now out of that batch of arise
seeds i ran a lot of them i ran
thousands of those myself and i found
several keepers
i found the king solomon male king
solomon my stud male the male that makes
my line really potent and popular is
known as king solomon he is a selected
phenotype from the arise line so there's
a male that got called king solomon
there's another male that is known as
the golden goat dominant male it doesn't
have a real name i just call it the
golden goat male because it's not for
sale nobody else touches it nobody's
ever seen it but me
that's the golden goat male it's over
there that is the one that is used to
make the golden goat back cross
so those are the two males that i kept
out of that also there were several
stellar females that stood out in the
arise line when i would grow them we see
what is known as phenotypical expression
not all two seeds will grow the same
especially in an f1 or a polyhybrid so
when you cross a plant uh when you cross
two plants you got a male and a female
right the offspring are going to show
some mommy traits some daddy traits some
of them may show grandparent traits and
then some may be right in the middle you
never know what ratios you're going to
get until you do the breeding so that is
where phenotypical expression comes in
some of these plants were taller some of
them were skinnier some more more squats
some were real branchy um some of them
were super potent some of them were not
as potent
these are the different phenotypes i was
finding as i was growing these plants
different expressions of the genes maybe
that's different genotypes and phenotype
is the expression of the room so it's
finding the different phenoes and
genotypes now i was labeling these
plants really basically
i knew they were called a rise because i
named it it was mine so as i grew seeds
hypothetically maybe i had a five maybe
i had a hundred pack of seeds as i would
grow them as i would plant them i would
just number them a rise number one a
rise number two a rise number three up
to the number that i was using so i did
letters the next time it was probably a
through like g or somewhere that's like
13 right get 13 14 maybe 20 down the
alphabet is as far as i'd usually go uh
so that is where the arise e comes from
we have found a specific phenotype that
i kept it was just a plant that i went i
like that one and the cup or the pot or
the label happened to be labeled a rise
number and i know it's a letter but it's
a rise number e so i kept that one
because i liked it for a specific reason
that is where the letter schemes come
from now let's talk about these arise
letter indications uh there was arise
number four there was number seven there
was number eight there is number e and
there was number a were my five
favorites of all time growing thousands
of seeds of arise
ah then there were the two males of
course the king solomon and the golden
goat looking male so i've got seven that
stuck around at this time i have
eliminated all of the females except
number four number four is a stud not a
stud number four is a champion if it was
a stud it'd be a dude uh number four is
[ __ ] awesome number four is an
amazing plan number four is a keeper
it's got the potency that i look for
it's got the vigor that i look for it's
got the bud uh density and shape and
type that i look for it's got leaf shape
that i look for it's got plant structure
it is the champion it does all of the
things that i wanted my arize plant to
do so number four has stuck around uh
number four was the uh the perfect one i
can't even it's the one that was the one
i'm gonna try to remember off the top of
my head here number eight uh was good it
was more golden goatee and a little bit
more sativa number e i think was the
super real tall real long finisher real
psychedelic finishing phenotype so i
don't have a list of which phenotype was
which here it's a lot to remember when
you get into breeding a lot of strains
and trying to remember specific phenos
but that is where the letters come from
so you'll see this in other breeders
you'll see it in my work a lot of time
uh you'll see a rise so there's right
now available and this is what my friend
inspired our friend john's question
right now available is a rise f2 number
four and a rise f2 number e and a rise
f2 uh number seven those have been
distributed and shared with friends i
shouldn't say available because uh those
are probably gone by the time you hear
this but those have been made and our
friends are getting those so why did i
call them f2 number e
because
i probably used the same male in a batch
right i got the one male i was king
solomon and then i had five different
females of a rise in there and they were
all labeled the different phenotypes
from which they came from from their
original phenohat so there was a rise f1
number four a rise f1 number two all the
way up there were five of them that were
selected we had number four number seven
number eight numbers a and number e and
then those all got pollinated by the
king solomon to make the f2 and now that
became a rise f2 number a
or a rise number af2 i'm not sure how i
labeled it either way as long as the f2
and the number a is indicated in there
that is to let you know let the consumer
know which phenotype of the female i use
which female phenotype of the arise i
use because it will make a difference uh
the number four will stay shorter and
squattier the e is going to get real
tall like a fishing pole so that does
make a difference you've also seen me do
this in the jack the ripper f2s there
are jack the ripper f2 number two number
three number four and number five i
believe is how i numbered those so those
are also available with different
numbers you'll see another seed company
um we're not going to bring anybody
else's names into this but you'll see
they do version a and version b which is
just simply probably i'm assuming they
had a they grew from seed they found two
really stellar keepers that were
different but they were both keepers for
different reasons so they bred them to
the same male so let's just say that
i've got i grow a batch of seeds and i
find two stellar females one is super
potent and really uh super potent we'll
just focus on the potency of this one
and then i've got another one that
[ __ ] tastes super good so i've got a
version a and a version b as long as i
make a note of which is which then it's
cool to have two different versions not
a big deal you could sell them both
advertise them both mark and them both
grow them both as long as people know
what they're getting the flavor or the
potency then what's to stop me from
taking a male one male and pollinating
both of them and offering the
uh version a and version b of the same
cross we could name it the same thing
you could call it uh fist bump that's a
cool strain name don't [ __ ] steal
that fist bump i'm claiming that strain
name that could be fist bump version one
and fist bump version two that wouldn't
be a problem just list what the parents
were and that's two different two
different crosses of the same thing
basically so that is why we see letters
in there thank you for inspiring me to
ramble and rant about letters and weird
seed package labels i hope i covered
some ground there and i hope any of that
was useful to some of you folks out
there who may have seed packs with
version two or version b or phenotype a
written on the package that's why we're
doing it the breeder is trying to give
you as much detailed information as we
can share with you on the package to
where you know what you're working with
i'd like you to know what you're working
with i like to know what i'm working
with it makes it easy set yourself up
for success all right i am rambling
let's keep me back on track and move to
the next message this one is great this
one came from our friend mark
and it goes a lot like this it says yo
rasta jeff i just watched your show
about reversing male plants and i was
curious if female plants can detect a
male plant nearby and if so how is it a
pheromone the male plant emits or is it
something else thanks for all you do and
i will give my mom a hug kind regards
from mark this is a great question i
don't have any scientifical data any
real evidence other than uh observation
personal observation i've been growing
for years i've been cultivating in
small scales and large scales for a long
time i've had the privilege of having
male plants in the same room same houses
female plants and attempting and
successfully
finishing a seedless sensamia crop in
one room while pollinating another crop
in another room of the same house
so the evidence that i do have uh may
may be uh useful the scientific report i
have may be useful but this is what i
have observed when i do have females in
one room and they are waiting for pollen
and they know there's a male plant in
the other room who's starting to ski i
do believe and i do see those female
plants
flowering more quickly and producing
more pistols it looks like they're
putting off more spaces to receive the
pollen i've seen this a couple of times
i feel like they get stickier they get
more pistols and they do grow more
rapidly i don't know what causes it i
will give you credit for the idea or the
assumption that it's a pheromone or
something similar because that would
make sense uh when i smell my girl come
into the room i do get excited so maybe
that boy plant maybe those girl plants
know the other one is there and they're
just smelling each other and just
getting horny and starting to make more
flowers so that the magic can happen
also i do notice that uh if i'm just
collecting pollen and there's no females
around the dudes don't produce as much
pollen as they would if there were
actually females in the room that's
something else that i've noticed so i do
think the plants know that they are
there i think the plants can detect the
presence of the opposite sex i think
they can detect the presence of other
plants i also think they can detect the
presence of pests and the presence of us
i've said it before
those plants think that i'm just the
delivery mechanism the delivery guy that
shows up with calmag that's all the
plants think that i'm there for they're
like is he here he's got the cow mag yay
that's that's all the plants think about
me and they're grateful that i gave it
to them so i do think that the plants
know i do think they get stickier i
think they start flowering more quickly
and they do get more pistols so i think
that's a great answer to your question i
don't have a lot of scientifical
evidence behind that other than i've
bred in the same house uh and i've seen
the plants get stickier because i think
they knew that their date was on the
other side of the room just getting
prepped for them she's over there
putting on her perfume and shaving her
legs and that dude was up there doing
push-ups until we introduce them all
right that is enough of that one i've
been rambling on um there's one more
great question that i did receive i did
not print it because my printer ran out
of paper so i just took a quick note of
it this one said hey ross to jeff why is
some stuff only available in femme seed
and other lines are only available in
regular seeds that is a very good
question as a seed breeder i've got a
very good answer for that
why is some stuff only available let's
start off with femci that is the easiest
answer why is some stuff only available
in fams i have to start off by teaching
you about what is known as a clone only
golden goat is what we call a clone only
when the maker the original breeder of
golden goat who was not me i've got to
give mr dank and topeka kansas credit
for breeding the golden goat i did not
breathe that a lot of people give me the
credit did not do it don't want the
credit i made enough of my own stuff
don't need to steal credit for that one
however golden goat is a clone only
which means when the original breeder
made the golden goat they did not give
out any clones or seeds of other
phenotypes of that cultivar they've got
so the breeder made a handful of seeds
right he grew them he found the winner
he shared that one did not give anything
else out there are no seeds to be had of
the golden goat so it is a clone only
there's that one female clone which
means there is no real true male golden
goat plant which brings us to why there
are only femme seeds because
imagine if you only had one rhinoceros
and it was a female make more rhinos you
need some sperm or a male rhino to do
that and with golden goat there's only a
female so we cannot make regular golden
goat seeds unless we adulterate it which
i have taken the liberty of doing so i
have pollinated that with another plant
we've done some work to it we have done
what is known as a back cross i've done
full episodes on back crossing back
crossing is the solution when you want
seeds of a plant that is only a clone
only no male exists there are ways to
kind of replicate recreate uh what's it
called reverse engineer may be the
better word to create a line that is uh
non which is a clone only which has a no
male pollen donor available there are
ways to work around that but
that's an adulteration that is not a
pure version of that plant so if we make
feminized seeds we only need that female
plant because in a female pro in a
feminized process
i would take uh we're gonna stick with
golden goat i would take a clone of the
golden goat i would take another clone
of the golden goat these are both golden
goat clones i would treat one clone with
a solution i've done a full episode on
this
that solution would cause this golden go
plant to make pollen which is only
female pollen which also only contains
golden goat chromosomes there's only the
genetics of golden goat so we are not
adulterating the golden goat line i'm
going to take that golden goat pollen
and put it on a golden go female now we
have made golden goat s1 we have selfed
our golden goat which all those seeds
will be very very close to the original
golden goat so that is why some things
are available only in feminized seed
because it was a clone only plant
meaning there were no seeds which means
there was no male which means if we
wanted to create a seed from that it
either needs to be self or adulterated
and many people don't want the
adulterated version of golden goat they
want the original pure version of golden
goat now let's talk about the other side
of that coin
many people are not fans of feminized
seeds back in the day many of the dutch
makers were not making femme seeds
properly
quality control was not what it should
be we figured it out now femmes are a
lot better but because of miseducation
or trial and error that didn't go well
many growers are
disgruntled or they have a bad taste in
their mouth or they are simply opposed
to using femme seeds
in that same vein many breeders are
opposed to making feminized seeds many
people that many people that make seeds
feel like making femmes is kind of a
dead end what do you do if you don't use
a male you've got to keep reversing
something in my opinion that is fine i
know a few other breeders that really
agree with the idea of using a an alpha
female plant something a really a badass
female plant could really make a lot of
good breeding projects but a lot of
breeders don't agree with that they only
want the natural selection of a male and
female plant so that is why a lot of
things are only available in regular
seed because
when you make a cross you take a male
plant and a female plant you put the
pollen on the female it makes a lot of
seeds now you've got your cross that
happens naturally that is easy to do
creating feminized seeds from that line
is a different line of work it involves
treating a select it involves selecting
a plant to be a pollen donor it involves
selecting female plants to receive that
pollen then it also involves treating
the selected pollen donor with a
chemical solution uh a certain amount of
times there's work to be done you've got
to treat a plant you've got to reverse
it you've got to do some manipulation
then you've got to make the pollen
happen you've got to chuck the pollen
and then honestly um when i make red
seeds i get 50
more seed than i do when i make feminize
seed that's why femme seeds are twice as
expensive
they cost twice as much to make they
take twice as long to make so a lot of
seeds are only available in reg seed
because a feminized grower a feminized
breeder has not taken the time to create
a feminized line from that project or
that product it's a whole other step
it's a lot more work it could be
it could be six nine maybe 12 more
months worth of work to get that
feminized line out to you so the reason
why some things are available in fem is
because uh the breeder a breeder like
myself that is interested in making fems
has done the work to make the femme
seeds available the reason why some
stuff is only available in rags is
because some breeders they either
haven't done it yet or they are just not
interested in making stuff in regular
seed a lot of the times that fem is
because it was only available as a clone
only and the only way you're going to
get seeds of it is through making fems
so i hope i answered that question
i do have a lot of other episodes about
back crosses about femme seeds i do
invite you to explore those episodes if
you have any more questions corrections
comments or concerns i would love to
hear from you of course the email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
questions corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism i would love to
hear all of that from you also don't
forget about the patreon campaign at
patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart that
was harder to say than it looked uh if
you have anything else uh any questions
you want to contact me anything else you
could possibly need that is all on my
website at
iregenetics.com don't be shy check out
the website give it some clicks give it
a visit everything you need might be
there the web store is there links to
vendors the grow help tab is there the
discord the new updated discord link is
there i don't know if i mentioned that
at the top of this episode but please do
join us on the new updated discord
there's a much uh much more important
much improved i don't even know what i'm
freaking saying anymore the new discord
is badass come hang out that's what i'm
trying to say all right that's all i've
got for you my throat is done i've got
80d it's time to take some dabs and eat
some food hope you guys enjoyed the
episode as much as i did you know i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content i want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy sam heads and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
so
you