[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode
747 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode i'm going to read a
couple of listener emails before we get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the kind folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it all off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my friend thor's trike
factory let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to my dude mobius
grows let's send a big thank you shout
out to deal let's send a big fist
bumping a thank you shout out to a
fellow breeder my friend rasta green
thumb genetics let's send a big thank
you shout out to sc dung slinger let's
send a thank you shout out to captain
mojo i want to send a big fist bump to
my friend luke let's send a special
thank you shout out to rasufa want to
send a big thank you to trojan i want to
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy sam heads then let's wrap it all
up with the grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to orville turner
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit www.patreon.com
slash grow from your heart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen and you know i do include
a link in the show notes and in the
video description to make it super easy
for all of my friends to support the
show speaking of support i want to thank
everybody for the words of support
encouragement ah the thank you the
constructive criticism the positive
feedback on the episode that i did
about never giving up i recently did a
podcast episode where somebody sent me a
message they said they were frustrated
with their grow they were thinking about
giving up i gave some advice that my
main advice was focused on the grow room
but most of that advice was also
applicable to life you could apply most
of what i said to most situations in
life to expand your knowledge get better
move forward and conquer obstacles i got
a lot of great feedback on that on that
podcast episode i got a lot of great
emails a lot of youtube comments a lot
of good constructive criticism and
positive feedback there are a lot of
great people listening to this podcast
so i wanted to take a moment and say
thank you for all of the encouragement
the words of uh support that really
meant a lot to me to read so many uh
positive words and so much great
feedback on just a great episode that
honestly i didn't know is going to have
such a big impact sometimes i put out
these shows i think the episode about
cutting clones and like selecting males
and female plants and identifying sex
and things i think those are super
important the thing sometimes when i'm
just rambling and saying things that i
was just touching on a subject here
that's when really people really seem to
respond the most so thank you that was
super cool to get such a great feedback
i am rambling now let's talk about
growing cannabis this is a grow podcast
thank you once again you guys i do
appreciate it
again i do apologize for the throat
clearing dabs we won't ramble on about
that i did mention previously that i did
load up a greenhouse with some plants
i'm happy to say the plants are alive it
hasn't been very long since i put the
plants in the greenhouse since i'm
recording this episode there is not much
to report they look happy they're
rooting the roots are spreading into the
dirt they're bigger not a lot to report
they're alive i'm not sure if you caught
it but i did say that the male plant i
put out in the greenhouse was a jack the
ripper male there are two jack the
ripper male plants it's a clone of the
same plant i put two of them uh in
different places in the growth
strategically to work with the airflow
to get maximum pollination so if you're
wondering the plants that are in the
greenhouse the male is the jack the
ripper over time i will of course reveal
some of the females out there let you
guys know what i'm working with but
that's a jack the ripper male out there
in the greenhouse
where do we go from there i've got the
note that says everybody looks happy all
the plants look super happy that's
really all i've got to report on those
plants i did recently in a podcast i may
have appeared on another show i may have
been on caribou heart tv where i
mentioned that i am now breeding with a
new male plant and a lot of people were
a little bit confused a little bit
excited um there's a lot of confusion
because i haven't talked too much about
it i do keep some things kind of secret
some things under wraps we talk about a
lot of stuff you have to have some
secrets that's how you win
but i didn't talk about this plant a lot
and then i did start talking about it
people were confused let me talk about
the plant i was mentioning
i've got a male plant i'm working with a
male plant that is a bc lemon skunk male
it is a bc lemon skunk bc is the seed
company bc seed company it's from
vancouver british columbia it's a
british columbia uh lemon skunk so the
bc is not a back cross a lot of people
were asking i saw on a message board i
saw on some forms is that a back cross
is bc for bat cross that could be what
bat cross is but in this instance it is
uh a bc that's why it's first if it was
bat cross it would have been at the end
and i would have used a bx which drives
p crazy shout out to my buddy f1p and i
hope you're well i hope somebody tags
you in this i would have used bx you're
right bc does work good for back cross
however it would have been at the end
this is bc lemon skunk that stands for
british columbia it's a lemon skunk that
came from vancouver british columbia so
that is a uh it's a monster male plant
it makes amazing plants we'll talk more
about that in the future i wanted to
clear that up that it is not a bat cross
it is a bc seed company a bc lemon skunk
a male uh what we're working with now
one more detail i do want to throw out
there involving the same topic
this is not
the same lemon skunk that is used in the
lemon jeffrey or the lemon sunrise or
the jack the jack tripper this is a
different lemon skunk plant the
lemon skunk that is used for the lemon
jeffrey the lemon sunrise or the uh the
firefly the jack tripper that is
actually from greenhouse seeds um that
is a female it's only a female that's
actually a feminized seed that i've been
breeding to so there's another ramble we
could talk about when people talk about
you can't breed the femme seeds well you
sure as [ __ ] can because i'm reversing
femme plants and breeding them to other
fem plants i'm getting way off topic
here but we're just rambling at this
point anyway the bc lemon skunk that
i've been talking about is a bc lemon
skunk from bc seed company that's a boy
that's a dude the other lemon skunk i've
had for years and i've talked about a
lot that is a female from greenhouse
those are different plants completely
different plants don't get confused
wanted to clear that up i hope that
makes any sense to everybody out there
all right let's segue into my next batch
of notes here i am recording right at
the start of the month today is june 1st
so it is a good idea to take this
opportunity to remind you to calibrate
your equipment if you've got a ph meter
an ec meter whatever kind of meter
you're working with maybe you're using a
dosatron go calibrate all of those
devices now is a very good time to do it
the start of the month is a beautiful
time to clean up and calibrate things
if you've got filters
go clean them if you've got something
that needs to be cleaned up go clean it
take the first of the month just to go
polish it up it's the start of the
summer season get in there and clean
some [ __ ] up get a head start on summer
cleaning make the grow room shine get
ahead of any problems go in there and
find the issues go clean everything up
go calibrate all of your meters clean
the air conditioner vents if you've got
one of those portable air conditioners
that thing has a filter in it if you've
got another kind of air conditioner
could have a filter in it if you're
using a heater that sounds crazy but
last night in colorado the heater came
on because it got super [ __ ] cold if
you're using a heater maybe clean the
filter on the heater everything's got a
filter that needs to be cleaned maybe
you're running some kind of hydro gear
maybe you're running something maybe go
clean all the fans today is a good day
to clean all of your grow equipment for
now i'm going to focus on our ph meter
recently i was at somebody's grow and
they were excited because they just
bought i recommended a blue lab ph pen
blue lab doesn't pay me uh maybe i
shouldn't even have said the brand but i
recommended a brand new blue lab ph
meter to my friend they went and got it
we showed up at their grow together
we're gonna hang out and work on our
plants my buddy busted out a blue lab ph
pin took it right out of the box mixed
up some nutrients and plopped it right
into the solution and read it and said
ph is great and i was like bro
you didn't do that correctly at all and
he's like what do you mean i was like
you got to calibrate that and he was
like what do you mean and i was like
you've got to calibrate your ph meter
and he didn't even think about this
did you know do you know i'm going to
tell you now just because a lot of
people apparently do not know that when
you buy your ph pen in the instruction
book it is recommended that you soak
that ph probe in a ph calibration
solution for 24 hours before calibrating
it did you know that you just paid 100
for that device why not follow the
instructions and set it up correctly to
work correctly we're going to rely on
this device to measure the nutrient
solution which we are feeding our entire
crop these nutrients you paid a lot of
money for the nutrients you want those
nutrients to give you maximum benefit on
the crop which you were growing why
wouldn't you make sure the tools that
you just paid money for are not dialed
in and calibrated [ __ ] perfectly
that's what i would do if it were up to
me so
when you get that new ph pen when it
comes out of the box the first thing you
should do is set it in that calibration
solution for 24 hours it'll say 12 to 24
hours it may say 24 hours plus on your
package on your instructions read those
do that some of them may not recommend
it but in the blue lab it was definitely
recommended in the instructions and my
buddy didn't even bother to calibrate it
he took it sorry i'm calling you out bro
we're not going to say your name but
he's listening what's up bro fist bump
hope you're well salute anyway took it
right out of the box and plopped it in
there and stirred it around it was like
the ph looks good and i was like what
the [ __ ] are you doing bro but uh adjust
it calibrate that thing calibrate it
needs to be who knows how long it's been
sitting in the box who knows if it got
calibrated who know what the who knows
what the guy at the factory calibrated
at so let it soak in the solution then
take it out then there are very simple
steps for calibrating a ph pin most of
them it's going to be a couple of
buttons until one thing flickers you put
it in the four solution until it says
four then you're gonna put in the other
solution clean it off between solutions
pull it out of the four rinse it off in
clean water then put it in the seven
then make sure it comes on at the seven
then here's what i recommend buy another
batch of four and or seven solution
because
just like i don't trust that calibration
that original pen calibration i don't
trust these solutions either sometimes
they go dry sometimes they expire
i'm a suspicious [ __ ] person i got
trust issues i do not trust these
calibration solutions at all so i buy
another fresh bottle of four and seven i
pour a little bit of them into little
containers and then i re-dip my testing
so my testing probe into that and make
sure it shows me four clean it off dip
it into the other one make sure it shows
me seven on my backup solutions now i've
got four tests that are positive that
show me that it's actually calibrated
the way that i think it is so i would
soak it in the solution for 24 hours
then when you're going to go in the grow
the next day pull it out clean it off
put it in the for solution calibrate it
properly put it in the seven calibrate
it properly clean it off between each of
those
then pour your other brand your other
bottle of calibration solution your
backup standard is what that is your
backups testing sample then test those
again and make sure that they all come
out properly four and seven as you
calibrate it that way you're double
checking your equipment like i said
before we're paying a lot of money for
our nutrients we pay a lot of money for
the ph pen we're putting a lot of money
time space energy possibly felonies into
our grow there's a lot of things going
into this why wouldn't we calibrate our
ph bin and get the ph the best that we
can and if you're just buying the thing
and using it it might not be perfect so
i'm gonna keep saying it calibrate the
damn ph pen do it today do it while
you're thinking about it do it while i'm
rambling it's only going to take you a
few minutes if you've got the proper
solutions um
like i said before we're spending all
this money on nutrients we want the
plants to be able to uptake those
nutrients and without the proper ph they
won't some stuff will just get left out
you may be adding cal mag let's just say
the bot those are two separate nutrients
you need to we're gonna stick with the
bottle of cow maggots sold in one bottle
most of the time you're buying this
bottle of calmag if your ph isn't right
you're putting the calmag into your feed
solution you're pouring that into the
plants and guess what it's falling out
of the bottom they're not even eating it
because your ph isn't correct so adjust
correct that ph most of the plants i'm
not going to delve too far into ph i
wanted to ramble more about calibrating
your equipment but most plants are going
to like a ph of somewhere between 5 8
and 6.4
if you can get within that range most of
your plants will be happy do pay
attention uh maybe six three six two
will be a little bit better this will
depend on the age of your plants uh the
size of your plants of course the health
of your plants the growth stage of your
plants also the amount of food you're
giving them a lot of stuff will depend
on what makes also the medium i was
going to say if you are you're in cocoa
are you in soil soilless mix what are
you doing that's going to make a big
difference also so get that ph dialed in
most importantly get your equipment
dialed in go clean some [ __ ] up clean
the fans clean the air conditioners go
clean your scissors maybe buy some new
scissors if you've been cutting a bunch
of clones maybe today is the day to buy
some new scissors if you're using a
sprayer to spray the garden clean the
[ __ ] out of that thing
another thing we can think about is
inventory do you have enough nutrients
to get yourself through the crop that
you're working on now do you have enough
gloves to get yourself through the crop
which you're working on are you prepared
for harvest are you about to cut down
some plants are you ready are you
prepared right at the first of the month
is always a good time to go take an
inventory order all the [ __ ] that you
need for the rest of the month that way
you don't have to stress about it that
way like on watering day when it comes
time to feed you're mixing up you got
your ph probe in there you're like i
need some cal mag you go ah [ __ ] i'm all
out of calmag you don't want to find out
while you're in the grow mixing [ __ ] up
go check right now go shake the bottles
go make a google doc go make a
spreadsheet uh go start making a list of
things that you use and then mark how
much is in each bottle keep track of it
figure out how often you got to buy it
how often you got to order it also this
will help you keep track of how much you
were spending in the garden then you can
determine how much you are spending per
pound or per ounce every harvest in your
grow all right i've rambled on enough
about the first of the month adjustments
uh let's move on a little bit another
thing that i did notice in my friends
grow yeah your grow bro we're gonna talk
about this real quick uh my buddy's
running three and five gallon pots in
his grow room he's got cocoa amended
with perlite in there he's got plastic
pots the plants look pretty good for the
most part there could be he knows what
he needs to do to make them look amazing
we don't need to air his business we are
going to call him out for one thing
though my dude is way over filling his
pots when you guys are putting this is
my recommendation you guys and gals can
do whatever you want in your grow but my
recommendation this may help you out
this maybe uh just my buddy's brain
[ __ ] really dinged when i gave him
this advice um
he fills the pots completely with coco
so let's just say that a five gallon pot
is this tall it's not but we're going to
say that the five gallon pot is this
tall my dude had cocoa to here like it
was to here it was almost falling out of
the pot and i was like bro why'd you put
so much cocoa in there and he's like
it's a five gallon pot why wouldn't i
put five gallons of cocoa in there it's
like that's a really good thought
process but how am i gonna water this
[ __ ] and he's like what and i was like
i'm pouring in water and it i have to
stand here and just [ __ ] wait for it
dude so i've got my watering container
and i'm pouring in the water it's gonna
need somewhere between probably like a
half to maybe uh two-thirds of that
gallon of water that i've got but
instead of just being able to pour it in
there it's like running off the top of
the pot because he's got it so full in
that cocoa it's not hydrophobic but it's
packed in there pretty well to where i
can't absorb it as quickly as i want to
pour it if if my dude would have left i
don't know maybe an inch maybe two
inches maybe an inch and a half of space
at the top of that pot maybe just a half
an inch i'd be able to just pour that
water in and it would spread across the
top and then puddle down in there evenly
but instead i'm over there just [ __ ]
trickling water in so my advice to you
just leave a little bit of space so that
that way we can get some water in the
pot you just pour that water right on
there keep moving keep going keep
growing all right i've rambled on enough
i did say i was going to answer some
emails let's jump into the email portion
of this podcast this one comes from my
friend wickednuggs what's up wickednuggs
thank you for the great question
it does go on and it does say i was just
listening to episode
651 you're way behind brother ah maybe
you're caught up and going back but
thanks for listening it says and i had a
couple of questions how does a breeder
find a gem bag seed and create a new
strain from it not knowing the lineage
of that genetic strain and start
breeding from it that's a really good
question it says i love the show and i
listen to it during the grow during the
busy work life in the airpods and it
feels like i just gained so much
knowledge and helps pass time and i
learn and take notes
and that's what i'm thinking about when
i'm doing the show i'm usually thinking
that people are either watching on
youtube or they're working with me in
their air pods so big up for uh letting
me know that i'm getting you through a
work day that's what i used to do when i
was at the commercial grows i just put
on the airpods and there was something
good in the ears and just jam all day
and it would keep uh when people see two
airpods in they know that you're not
supposed to talk to you so that always
made life easy uh it goes on uh learning
a lot of knowledge thank you bro i'm
glad to hear that you're learning and
taking notes uh that's what the goal is
here is to teach people get everybody
grown the best herb they can grow so
thank you for that um
then it says thanks for all you do ross
to jeff keep up the growing p.s i gave
my mom a hug for you sincerely wicked
nugs big up bro thank you now let's talk
about the question the question is how
does a breeder find a gem bag so you
didn't breed from it not knowing the
lineage of that strain
um that's a good question
and i've got a couple of different
thought processes on that first of all
if it's a good strain if it's a good
plan you can tell
it doesn't matter
at all what the history genetics lineage
story behind it is
when a grower grows a plant
ah we just go oh [ __ ] that's the one
sometimes you just know sometimes you
know that's not the one sometimes you
hope it's the one sometimes you really
really know that that's the one and if
it's a random plant that nobody knows
really the story of it maybe it's just
if it came from a bag you know at least
one half of it it came from this bag
that's called this you know half of it
probably
but
um
now it's too easy to know all the stuff
back in the day so let's talk about a
very famous cross let's talk about our
very famous very very famous strain that
happened a lot like this i recommend um
after you listen to this podcast i
recommend checking out the legend of
chemdawg and the 13 beans if you're a
cannabis enthusiast a strain hunter a
pheno hunter that is something i
recommend you check out because that
will correlate very well with what i'm
about to say
so
um chem dog all of the chem dog line was
bag seed to be if you want to talk about
bag seed so this dude chem bought some
weed and in that weed were seeds and he
grew them and he found 13 seeds and out
of those 13 seeds some were boys some
were females some he still has
some of those famous plants that came
from that were the original chem dog the
chem 91 the chem d the kim's sister all
of those came from that bag of seeds and
we are all breeding all of the breeders
i know everybody that's bred some stuff
is breeding to one of those plants we're
breeding with one of those because
that [ __ ] is fire the only thing we know
about it
well since since it got so popular and
since cannabis culture has blossomed and
developed we know a lot more about it we
don't know the exact genetics we know
that a guy named i know his real name i
almost said it sorry bro i almost said
your real name a guy named kim got some
weed from some guys in colorado and
those guys called the weed the dog bud
um they called it the chem weed because
it smelled like chemicals and when you
smoked it it would make you roll over
like a dog so one guy called it dogweed
the other guy called it chemweed um
these guys met up at a grateful dead
concert they traded some of it later on
uh chemdaw got home and he called them
and he's like can you send me more they
mailed more of it from colorado kim
found seeds in it that's basically
that's the story the other guys don't
know
the origin genetics lineage or history
of these plants allegedly possibly maybe
so that's bag seed at that point when
chem dog got it and started breeding
with it it was just bag seed but he knew
the wheat it came from was [ __ ] fire
so that's all he had to go on then he
grew the plants
once the plants were grown some of them
were amazing that's why we all know chem
dog chem d chem 91 kim's sister
we've all smoked most of us have smoked
all of those if you're in a an area
where cannabis has any sort of
legalization you've probably smoked
those or something that somebody grew
and tried to tell you was that but
they're really prolific and dominant
strains in the cannabis industry so
we've all and a lot of the breeders have
gotten their hands on them too once you
see a plant like that and you grow it
and you smoke it you know that is
something you want to breed to just like
uh pick my king solomon when i saw that
i was like that's the dude right there
that's the guy to breed to and then when
i saw strawberry starburst i was like
that needs some pollen on it you just
it's a breeder intuition so the question
is how do you breed to it without
knowing the genetics or anything um you
don't need to know it's real it's really
cool to know the history it feels really
nice it's uh it feels good it's a lot of
cool details but you don't need to know
that we were breeding plants and
crossing cannabis plants long before we
knew all this fancy stuff a lot of us
are spoiled now the new generation
i'm a little bit older than a lot of the
youngsters out there but i am also part
of the internet generation where i'm
freaking spoiled where i could go on the
internet and type in i want to find
these cannabis seeds at 45 websites will
come up and i can order them luckily
i've got some i got a couple of friends
in the seed industry so i can get but
basically whatever seeds i'm searching
for but we're spoiled now back in the
day you had to get whatever seeds you
got if you got some bag seeds you had to
accept those and grow them if you got
some clones you just had to hope they
were good whoever selected those clones
did a good job for you now we're
freaking spoiled so um the answer is
just do it bro if the plants look
amazing if they have the traits you want
it's all about observation it's all
about knowing what traits you're looking
for knowing the goal having a goal
understanding the plant
understanding pairing what plants are
you going to put that to what does this
plant offer in a mix how are you going
to complement the other plants what are
you going to do and then of course
growing them out and testing the
offspring is another big part of it but
by not knowing the lineage and genetics
how do you start breeding from it um
throw some pollen on it bro and see what
it does that's the best way to do it
that's one of the funnest things about
breeding and growing weed just seeing
what the outcome is after you do some
crazy [ __ ]
all right my dude um thank you for the
great message uh big shout out to my
friend wicked nugs for the good question
if you have any questions corrections
concerns or follow-ups i'd love to hear
from you of course you've got the email
address let's jump into one more email
this one comes from my friend buzzards
bay shout out to buzzards bay it says
it's been a long time it's been a long
time bro you know i'm coming up in may
it says it's buzzards bay i'm glad to
see your success on the podcast thank
you brother we're almost to 750 episodes
you guys it says come a long way since a
couple of years ago yes thank you for
noticing uh we're doing 4k video
sometimes it's multi-cam when both cams
want to cooperate uh when i feel like
[ __ ] with both of them sometimes i
just want to smash camera two right onto
the floor but we're gonna keep the vibe
the vibes positive here it says anyway
um i had a quick question about male
selection i can answer this question
really thoroughly when you make regular
seeds and you find a male you really
like do you have clones of that mail as
a backup or is that mail used once and
then you find a new mail to work with
for example when you discuss king
solomon
do you have a backup clone of him thanks
in advance stay irie my bro peace excuse
me for burping in the middle of your
message peace from buzzards bay buzzards
bay thank you for the great question um
so a lot of you may not know a lot of
you may know so i'm the head breeder the
sole proprietor of ivory genetics
premium seeds and i do make a lot of
seeds you may know you may have heard
about my male plant known as king
solomon it is in a rise f1 male i've
named him king solomon
if you research king solomon you'll get
the joke behind that uh but king solomon
makes a lot of plants our friend
buzzards bay is asking do i keep a
mother plant or a father plant if you
will of king solomon or do i find a new
one every time or do i have clones of
backups now that's a really good
question here is honestly how i do it i
do keep a plant of king solomon all the
time i've got one uh maine mother plant
that i keep it's a father plant i guess
it stays in a five gallon pot right
under the middle of all the lights in
the bedroom or in the mother room that
is where he chills that is king
solomon's spot
uh he'll get big he'll get bushy as soon
as he's big enough to start giving me a
few clones because i re i reclone him
every so often i talk about that
occasionally so i'll start growing him
i'll get a fresh clone of him let's just
say i just cut brand new clothes i got a
brand new clone of king solomon
put him into a pot grow him up as soon
as he's big enough to give me a cut i
take another cut um then i put that one
in a smaller pot and they just keep
going so i've always got one or two of
king solomon around just to keep that
one alive just because that's my gem
i've always got him around at least the
big one probably one or two other copies
of him as well
now
if i need clones for breeding from him i
generally take them from the biggest
plant i'll just go grab a few off the
biggest one because that one's getting
big it's gonna have to get cut down or
do something with it eventually i'll go
get as many clones as i need and then
i'll grow those out throw those into the
flower room so i can make my pollen
happen there um then when that one gets
too big cut him down let the next plant
keep going and just so basically i keep
one big father plant for approximately
three to six months depending on how big
he gets and how many cuts i need uh it's
a male so i generally generally only
need two clones of him at any time plus
a backup plus the mom so um yeah that's
how i do it probably keep one big plant
and i cut clones off that as needed and
then about every once or twice a year i
cut them down and start them over and
give them a fresh cut a bunch of clones
and keep the best two as the brand new
starters i wouldn't want to try to start
again from seed every time because i
know that king solomon's reliable
finding a male is a struggle uh maybe
not a struggle it's uh it takes a lot of
time it takes a lot of effort it's a
project it's a real uh it's work so
finding that male i have to grow out
seeds i have to eliminate the females i
gotta find the dudes that have the
traits i want then i gotta kind of
audition those and narrow them down once
i've chosen what i like then i have to
pollinate stuff then i have to grow that
out so it's a big process choosing a
male so i definitely try to keep the
same dude around
there is a jack the ripper male there's
an arise male of course there's the bc
lemon skunk male those are all kept
around
in big pots in different areas different
locations so that the pollen never gets
crossed ever anywhere uh the males are
in different places that way we know
that there's never i call it the maury
povich situation we always know who the
baby daddy is in ire genetics all right
my buddy buzzard thank you for the great
question
that is all i've got for you guys for
this episode i want to thank you again
for listening to episode 747 of the grow
from your heart podcast hope you enjoyed
the show as much as i did you know i'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns make
sure you send me an email the email
address is of course grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
anything else you may need is on my
website at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the discord there are
vendor links there's a merch link
there's a way to sign up for a mailing
list on there also there's a link to the
discord server make sure you check out
the discord server don't miss the party
happening on the discord i hope to see
you there
that's all i've got for you i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a big shout out
to my friend ron zell and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
you