[Music]
all right all right all right welcome to
the show podcast world i'm your host my
friends call me ross to jeff this is
episode 749
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on my
new strain the moon tower before we get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to william e downs let's send
a big fist bump and a thank you shout
out to uncle adam the uber driver let's
send a big thank you shout out to
another local my buddy fiscals organics
let's send a thank you shout out to zoso
j and ez057
i want to send a big fist bump to my
buddy chicago dabber let's send a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter my
friend tree star meadow let's send a big
thank you shout out to kurt z let's send
a special thank you shout out to a
friend with weed i want to send a big
high five and a thank you shout out to
miss mel then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to oh cannabis
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast where do
we go from there let's talk about what i
got to do this weekend i went to the
museum and it was awesome ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls if you are
cannabis consumers if you'd like to go
see cool [ __ ] get blazed and go to the
museum i went to the museum of natural
art and science i think that's where we
went museum of art and science some [ __ ]
like that it was [ __ ] rad dude go
there go check it out go get educated go
get blazed and go see some really great
[ __ ] that is my recommendation for the
week all right i want to focus on
talking about uh the main topic of the
podcast which is one of my new strains
called the moon tower a lot of people
know that i am a podcaster but many
people may not know that i am also a
seed breeder i am the the head breeder
the sole proprietor for irie genetics
premium seeds we make great regular and
feminized seeds we do not make
autoflowers but we are doing a collab
with a friend at a night owl big up to
my buddy daz but we do make seeds i make
seeds i make a lot of great seeds one of
the things i have recently been
releasing that went through testing that
is now being released to the public is
something called the moon tower let's
focus on the moon tower what is the moon
tower the parents of the moon tower are
a pre-98 bubba kush female pollinated by
my arise male who is also known as king
solomon let's talk briefly about the
bubba kush then we'll focus a little bit
on solomon then we will move deeply into
talking about the moon tower so the
pre-98 bubba kush the female plant that
makes up this cross
i like that plant i've loved that plant
for a long time since uh medical
cannabis got popular i've been buying uh
bubba kush pre-98 bubba kush from
dispensaries from friends
from any type of grower i can find it
from forever i've had the clone a few
times i've uh when i get cloned
sometimes i work with them i breed to
them and i let them go or i grow them
for my own personal consumption and then
i'm limited to so many plants so
sometimes i'll just let things go over
the years i've gotten my hands on bubba
several times and i've let it go
i've always loved the coffee flavors the
earthy uh the dirty kind of notes and
tones and flavors and aromas that it
creates i love that i also love the buzz
it gives me a really nice uh heavy eyed
buzz a lot of strains now that i smoke
give me like an open bug-eyed kind of a
thing the bubba kush makes my eyes a
little bit heavy it makes me a little
bit lazy it makes my shoulders kind of
relax a little bit it makes me sit back
in the chair instead of the edge of the
chair which is where i usually am
so i love the bubba kush because it's
got that kind of couch lock feeling it
almost sits me down i'm a hyperactive
dude you could tell me the way i'm
talking [ __ ] a million miles an hour
right here under the microphone
but i go super quickly when i smoke the
bubba kush it will chill me out it's
good for nighttime smoke for me it's
good for if i'm hanging out with the
lady and i'm too talkative and she wants
to watch a movie smoke that bubba kush
it'll calm me right down get into the
mood for a movie if i got to do some
emails or some work and i'm too hyper
that will chill me out so i love the
bubba kush that couch lock
relaxation plus the coffee the dirt the
earthy tones beautiful beautiful
cannabis it grows very well there's not
a problem with the way it grows it grows
like a kush it grows a little bit
stretchy it could be better but there's
not a huge problem with the way that it
grows now let's talk about king solomon
king solomon again as an f1 male f1
let's say that again king solomon is an
arise f1 male so i crossed the golden
goat and daybreaker was a golden goat
female a daybreaker male put that
daybreaker male pollen on the golden
goat that made my arise from that first
batch of seeds i found a dude that is
he's a stud he's a winner he's a
champion he's proven himself to be a
winner because i've crossed him to
hundreds of females probably we'll say
at least 100 females and i've grown
probably 70 of them or somebody's grown
70 of them and they all
probably say 60 to 65 of them were quite
stellar they do perform quite well so
king solomon is a stud there are a few
that don't work super great some of
those won't be released some of them
aren't amazing but that's not the point
here let's focus on king solomon
when i breed with king solomon i know
that he is going to improve anything
that i put his pollen on he will make
things more more potent he will make
things grow with more vigor he seems to
be the improver or the fixer plant is
what i know him as
once again he is a golden goat female
pollinated by a daybreaker male let's
talk briefly about daybreaker because
that will come into play here uh
daybreaker is a chem d to joseph og
cross you got that chem dog the chemd
that like cushy chemical sort of a smell
over here and joseph og which is like
swampy uh just cushy if you know what
kush smells like it's straight up kush
that is what kush smells like so you got
joseph you got kim and then they cross
that and then i put that to the golden
goat so that gave us kind of a sweet
cushy chem dirty feet sweet feet sort of
a flavor so somebody took the chem d and
crossed it to the joseph og that made
the daybreaker i took the daybreaker
mail pollinated the golden go female
that made sort of a tropical fruit sweet
cushy dirty feet aroma sort of a plant
those plants were labeled arise from
that batch of seeds was a male who's
been labeled solomon that is king
solomon he grows with those sweet kimmy
flavors aromas hyper vigor super potency
and he's also resistant to problems he
can handle a lot of stress
so why did i want to cross these two
plants that's always important i say
when you're breeding have a goal have
something in mind honestly
uh the thing that really got me excited
about this was these are two of my
favorite strains i've always loved the
bubba kush it's been a favorite of mine
for quite a while i've always loved king
solomon obviously he's done a lot of
great work for me i had an opportunity
put that to put them both in the same
area and breed to them and i thought why
would i miss this opportunity then as i
was doing it i thought what am i going
to create here and i thought i wanted to
create that i wanted to keep the coffee
and earth flavor add some sweetener to
it just a little bit of sweetness to it
but then try to hype up the growth time
because the rise grows super quickly to
where it cuts down the veg time with
some plants when i breed it to things it
veges more quickly so i was hoping to
make the
bubba kush veg more quickly and keep
that sweet kush flavor add a little
sweetness to it at the same time add a
little bit of potency was honestly my
main goal the main idea when making this
cross so
the results actually were i wrote this
down coffee earth fuel and funk flavors
and then we get
medium height plants with tight internal
spacing and long lateral branching that
means that the plants in my opinion in
my experience what i've seen from
testers is the plants they'll grow kind
of tall but the internodal spacing will
be tight together and those branches
that come from those nodes get really
really long as something that i'm
noticing so we've got medium height
plants with tight internal spacing and
long lateral branching now we're kind of
talking about how it grows in its growth
structures and features moved on from
that uh flavor and aroma profile talking
more about the grow features if you
don't top these plants or uh yeah if you
don't top them they will make one giant
cola they'll make one big butts you'll
get a lot of branching coming up it'll
make a lot of nice side buds but then
you'll get one big donkey dick bud right
up the middle if you don't top it if you
do top it it'll make it spread out i
recommend topping low a lot of people
top when there's that one v section
that's only a few inches apart go down
one or two more nodes lower top it there
veg a little bit longer let it recover
let it kind of even out a little bit
then you'll get a lot more from it in my
experience with this plant so um
they take off they stretch early in
flowers some phenotypes will double in
height before they are done a lot of
phenotypes have the potential to become
double in height before they are done
flowering so if you've got a two foot
flowering space flower at a foot allow
for pot space allow for light space but
you understand what i'm saying if you
flower at 12 inches they will finish at
24 inches so be prepared for that sort
of a thing they do take off and stretch
a little bit in early flower that is
something i recommend you be prepared
for if you were growing up the moon
tower it will get stretchy for you early
in flower so be prepared some of those
phenotypes are going to get tall we'll
talk about how to take care of that here
in just a little bit i do have some
notes i should try to stay on track of
let's talk about phenotypes let's see
some of the phenotypes that i'm
experiencing and that test growers have
seen through the populations of moon
tower i see a structure the same
structure across most of these plants it
is the same shape the same structure
that is happening in most environments
and from most phenotypes
they get tall and they've got that long
branchy structure the main differences
i'm seeing the main difference in
structure that i'm seeing is depending
on your light depending on your
environment people are getting a
different stretch space in that
internode spacing if you don't have a
lot of light if you pack the plants in
too closely also if you put them in too
small of a pot and they get root bound
they do get a little more stretchy but
when all things are good when the lights
the air water soil the spacing is all
correct they do stay pretty squat not
squat they stay tight not squat tight is
the word the node spacing is tight so
that's something i've noticed ah that
one tall structure is very common they
get long branches the long branches
however do fill in with giant colas they
will also need support i recommend a
support for the top if you leave it
there a lot of people are going to cut
it out but i do recommend supports for
the taller branches i like a trellis net
trellis makes it super easy for me to do
what i like to do in the grow some of
you like to move the plants around that
may not work for you i may recommend
sticks but be careful the sticks will
get in your eye
those are dangerous maybe a tomato cage
is better for you there are a lot of
ways to do that but a trellis net is my
ideal situation sometimes i use three
nets of trellis in a commercial
environment uh so the plants start
growing up as soon as they start growing
toward that trellis i'll top them and
then spread them out let them grow into
it they'll get a little bit taller up
i'll spread them out a little bit more
that third one is just to guide those
buds straight up to the sky to where
they know where to go then i defoliate
everything below that first net of
trellis three layers in a commercial
grow now the main things you guys will
see in my experience of differences in
phenotypes is going to be leaf shape and
bud structure now that's going to be the
most obvious visual determination of
different phenotypes now that skinnier
leafino in my opinion is like kush and
coffee that's kind of what i was
breeding for it's got that kush earthy
coffee flavor but then it's also got
that kush buzz that like sets you down
chills you out but then there's also
something in it that's got some caffeine
or some energy to it it's like i'd like
to sit here and [ __ ] around but i gotta
go do something but i'm so high i'm not
sure what i'm supposed to do kind of
gives me that feeling i like it a lot of
people it may drive you crazy it's got
some motivation to it it's got some kick
and some arise intensity to it the kush
buzz comes through most of the
phenotypes you're going to get that
cushy feeling that like chilled out
relaxed sort of a feeling that's going
to come through most of the phenotypes
those skinnier leaf phenotypes however
are going to have a little bit of a head
ring to them possibly a little bit of a
caffeinated feeling to it that does come
from the golden goat side of things now
the bud structure on some will be
tighter than others in my opinion
the less dense phenotypes are excellent
for concentrate makers if you don't have
that super tight bud i think you can
make a better concentrate i believe the
dense buds are great for bag appeal and
smoking but extracting in my opinion my
experience from what my friends tell me
extracting a less dense product is
easier uh there's more room for
trichomes on that so if you got like a
bud that's kind of airy kind of fingery
imagine if we took a kush nugget that's
super tight and like a haze nugget
that's got fingers and we rolled them
both around in powdered sugar i'm sure
showing my hands to the camera for
everybody that's listening on spotify or
anywhere else if you look at my two
hands i got a fist how much i can cover
my fist the outer of my fist with
powdered sugar if i i'm sweaty if i open
up my hand i got the inside of my hand
between my fingers all of this i can
coat in powdered sugar or trichomes if
that were a nugget so i believe
sometimes if you're growing for
concentrates sometimes those more airy
fingery buds are good for the
concentrate making so the tighter buds
obviously are more cush leaning those
come from more of the cush chem side of
the genetics the more fingery buds are
more from the golden goat the romulan
the hawaiian sativa side of the genetics
in there those are going to be more of
the the head ringer the head buzz the
psychedelic feeling the where where the
hell are my keys while i'm driving my
car where are my sunglasses while
they're on my face i lost my phone while
i'm playing on instagram that kind of a
buzz uh those come from the skinnier
leaf shape buds that feeling is going to
come from those long skinny leaves and
kind of even the more airy bud so the
longer and skinnier the leaf the more
airy the bud of course the more head
ringer of a buzz i believe you're going
to get from those plants so use that
leaf shape use that leave of that bud
density to help you determine kind of
which phenotype that you have got but
most importantly the most important part
when it comes to phenotype selection i
talk a lot about which phenotypes you
will see i'm telling you you're gonna
see one with long skinny leaves one with
a little bit wider leaf one with tight
tight buds one that's a little bit
fluffier then you're gonna get different
combos of those buds and leaves together
but it doesn't matter to me which
phenotype you find that may sound rude
as long as you find the one that works
the best for you i've described a lot of
phenos and then people email me they're
like how do i find the phenotype that
you call the mean girl how do i find the
phenotype that you called the fat girl
how do i find that and i say just grow
it and honestly look for the best
phenotype in your garden you don't have
to have the one that i like the most
i like weed that makes me [ __ ] panic
attack while i'm sitting at a table by
myself i like to just freak myself out
by taking a dab like oh [ __ ] what's
going on that's my favorite feeling that
might not be for you you might want to
smoke and lay down and take a nap that's
not what i'm trying to do so find the
phenotype that does the thing that you
need done from it the one that grows the
best in your garden you've got to grow
it you got to manage it you're going to
have it for nine weeks in flower
four-ish six-ish weeks and veg two weeks
is a clone you're dealing with this
plant for [ __ ] 15 16 20 weeks 120
days ish make sure it's something you
want to grow again um also find the
phenotype that is something you want to
smoke or if you're selling it or
profiting from it or using it as
medicine make sure it's the thing that
works for that so
choose the one that works for you in
your environment for your wallet for
your budget for your clientele whatever
you need it to that may be a totally
different phenotype than me i'm not
worried about making money off of the
flowers i grow i'm going to smoke all of
them or i'm going to pollinate them and
make seeds so my grow and your grow are
focused on two totally different things
find the phenotype that works the best
for you now i'm going to go back talking
about phenotypes because there is one
one anomaly out of i talk about most of
them are going to get tall most of them
have that long branching most of them
have tight internal spacing there is one
however that just loves to [ __ ] with you
because that's how genetics work that is
a short squat runt looking plant it
doesn't look desirable it doesn't look
like it's going to be any good it looks
like it's going to suck but if you
finish that plant out and flower it and
let it go its full 67 72-ish day term
that it needs to go
that plant will punch you in the face
like mike tyson it is like cinder blocks
to the head it is like cement shoes it's
like i don't know it's like some sort of
medicine it will put you down that [ __ ]
will just lay you out it is such good
medicine but you don't get a lot of it
it doesn't look pretty it smells like
dirty ass skunks and it takes you two
hits to go full [ __ ] from smoking it
but
you don't get a lot of it and it doesn't
look super good so if you're growing it
just for yourself if you just want to
smoke it for you there's a little shitty
rump plant that may pop up in a pack of
i don't know i found it like two or
three times out of a lot of seeds not a
lot of the testers have reported it but
if you get that one finish it out get a
clone of it it's hard to get a clone
because it stays so little it doesn't
grow very big you gotta veg it for a
real long time and treat it like a baby
but the medicine that comes from that
the buds from that it is worth the extra
effort and the work if you're gonna sell
it if you're doing a commercial grow
that's not the one for you if it's for
your bag for your head for your jar grow
that one if you've got it just over
there in the corner of the room finish
that bad [ __ ] out because it is worth
it one time maybe don't take a clone
maybe just run it the one time see what
it does all right so we've talked about
the phenotypes we talked about terps
flavors i've talked a lot about the
feelings and buzz that this plant gives
me let's talk about a few of the grow
features and tips that i can give you
for this plant i really think that the
moon tower works very good in a screen
of green environment when you trellis
them down with the net they enjoy that
they also work well in a sea of green
environment because they grow that one
big tall apical dominant cola if you veg
them until they're what is this what is
it eight ten inches tall if you veg them
to about ten inches tall cut off all the
bottom branching and flip them you'll
just end up with a bunch of nice main
colas you gotta run a lot of them real
close together of course if you're gonna
do that method don't expect a huge
harvest from each one that's when we do
a sea of green that's when you do like
64 of them on a three by three table an
eight by eight square on a three by
three table lots of plants if you're in
a state where your numbers are regulated
that is not the way to go but the plants
will enjoy doing that i always recommend
with the moon tower
cleaning up the branches but not
completely
removing the entire branch we do a lot a
lot of lollipopping we do a lot of leg
shaving a lot of cleaning up of the
bottom of the plant in my school of
thought and my training camp in my
facilities in my grow however i wouldn't
cut off all of the branching at the
bottom of the moon tower i may leave
more branching than usual and instead of
cutting that off i would kind of strip
the bottom half or two thirds of that
branch just clean that right up to where
the bottom is naked you can see their
legs for a far way up but when you get
up to the top of the skirt you're just
going to grow big long buds leave a
leave a nice section up at the top and
have a naked tip or a naked naked leg
nice tip and that'll grow nice big
donkey buds at the end of that so clean
it up and then leave the end of it
enough at the end to make you a nice fat
cola all that space should fill in
generally a cush plant is going to make
a bunch of golf balls but what the arize
has done the rise makes that bud stack
up a little bit better and fill in all
of that space another thing i should
mention don't over water the moon tower
plants they don't like being over
watered they may survive better if you
underwater them than they would if you
over water them that has been my
experience that's what i have noticed
they do eat moderately heavy so if you
are used to feeding a plant a certain
diet maybe step it up just a little bit
higher now let's talk about some of the
things you may want to feed them
they do
love the cow mag and when you feed a cow
mag it makes the leaves kind of get the
serrations they they pop up a little bit
they love that and they look super good
for photos the plants do like a low ph
toward the end of flower that will
increase your colors once again help you
for photos low temps at night will help
your photos make it change a little bit
of color they will tolerate that cold
quite well they do like kelp products
kelp products will help your flavors
aromas and bud density one thing i
noticed they responded very well to a
product called bud swell i fed them bud
swell they did exactly that they swole
up they got fat they got beefy so that
seemed to work one thing i want to
mention
these plants do have a tendency to just
go yellow around week eight right around
the end of week eight week day 56 day 59
day 60 they're just going to go wonk and
turn yellow on you don't be afraid that
is not a problem that is just a sign of
hey
we're done it's almost time to harvest
if you haven't started flushing if you
do that now it may be time to flush if
you do the 18 6 light switch now it may
be time to do that these plants are very
cool they let you know they're like hey
bro
we're almost done it's time to go ahead
and start wrapping it up get ready for
harvest time so if they turn yellow that
is fine i don't think you did anything
wrong that is a common issue that
happens with these plants i don't even
guess it's an issue that's just a trait
that happens within these plants it goes
hey bro time to cut us down and they let
you know the leaves will just turn
yellow some of the big leaves will fall
right off for you they start
pre-trimming themselves i've gotten that
report from a lot of test growers i've
seen it along a lot amongst a lot of
phenotypes that i grew don't freak out
they're almost done and they're just
letting you know that it is almost time
for their haircut i'm scrolling through
my notes to see where i am
um
they did like the buds well i mentioned
that they liked bud swell a lot they
really seemed to take well that bud
swell that organic bat guano liquid
nutrient made them swell up made them
get super beefy i watched them swell
i've grown a couple of batches of this
i've seen other people grow it people
that did not use bud swell did not get
the swell that i saw my plants get where
are we some of these plants can be
challenging to clone i'm not sure why
they don't like to clone well the pre-98
bubba kush clones well king solomon
clones well i don't know where the
problematic cloning came from what i've
discovered what i've learned to realize
is if you don't feed these plants for
three to four days they will clone
better so when you're going to take
clones of the of the moon tower make
sure the mother plant has been starved
for a couple of days this is common
amongst most cannabis plants if you over
feed them nitrogen if they're high in
nitrogen when you cut clones it does
slow down the rooting time so make them
a little bit hungry that will speed up
your rooting process everything else is
fairly easy they root well
they'll get kind of tall it's going to
be your main thing to think about you're
going to have to be prepared for tall
plants but they should be fairly easy
for most growers you shouldn't
experience too much problems you
shouldn't get too much trouble don't
over water uh keep an eye on the feeding
everything should be cool feeder a
moderately high nitrogen diet so if you
feed your plants um however many ppms of
nitrogen now maybe increase that by 10
20 percent and pay attention to these
plants these plants are hungry [ __ ]
and they will eat i don't want to tell
you to super feed it because then you're
going to go pounding it with too much
nutrients here's something i would
recommend that you do consider this is
not instruction none of this is
instruction this is all recommendation
from a friend here i would consider when
you flip to flour
so you go from your veg phase you turn
your lights to 12 12 you are now in
flower day one starts when you flip the
lights
most people will now switch to their
from their vegetative to their flowering
nutrients at this time i would recommend
you go two more weeks with your
vegetative nutrients with this strain
because these plants do eat a lot of
nitrogen and they will need that extra
nitrogen built up this will help you out
in my opinion this works for a lot of
plants
maybe taper off that veg feed into your
bloom feed over the next two week period
but adjust that slowly don't just drop
off that nitrogen completely that's when
you will see problems
the moon tower does enjoy moderate
defoliation but don't overdo it i like
to defoliate plants i've learned that if
you over defoliate the moon tower she
will get a little bit pissy with you so
don't overdo it go lightly instead of
doing one fat defoliation uh over a
couple of weeks do a couple of light
defaults it will work better for you
i usually suggest popping and twisting
these plants to build structure and
mitigate stretch that is something i
recommend on most of my plants i got a
few cultivars that don't react well to
it but the moon tower responds well if
you don't know what i'm talking about
i've done a full episode on popping and
twisting i basically grab the plant with
two hands and give it a twist in
different directions and it goes
like pop in a knuckle and it makes the
plant break the cellulose fiber right
there and it will rebuild a little
knuckle it looks a little bit knurled
might be the word it makes it stronger
it also slows down so it's going to make
it stronger right there it can support
itself a little bit better more
nutrients can flow through a thicker
stem also that will slow down the
vertical stretch so they're not growing
as quickly through that phase it'll slow
that down and make them stronger one
thing i think really helps with these
plants is keep the ph consistent they
seem to like that consistent ph
ph swings ph jumps they get a little bit
out of control of course medium does
matter uh they really will like
consistent ph i mentioned before they
like cow mag they really enjoy kelp and
these plants responded a week six we hit
them with bud swell they went [ __ ]
kaboom so hit em with that bud swell
they should be happy i'd want to remind
you don't panic if they turn yellow
close to the end that is called
senescence they are starting to they're
just dying but they're still living keep
the buds going the leaves are going to
die we're going to cut off the leaves
anyway that is okay harvest of these
plants will generally be ready around
day 63 to day 67. i always recommend
going long for your first couple of runs
see what they do i told you when i hit
them with budswell they really swelled
up maybe if you let them go 74 75 days
they really might beef up at the end
there pay attention to the trichomes
that's really what matters let the
plants finish
let the plants finish i do recommend
though at least 70 days 63 70 days is
ideal you will get outliers of course
there will be 60 day finishers i believe
that if you've got the right setup for
the moon tower you can get pretty fat
harvest from her if you clean up the
bottom of her give her that attention
she deserves make sure there's no junk
on the bottom no larf none of that
fluffy stuff none of that wasted buds
none of those mini shoots clean all that
[ __ ] up send all that energy up to the
top spread it out get plenty of light
down into the canopy with a good light
with the proper care with the right
airflow i predict that you could get
pretty fat harvest from the moon tower i
don't want to give you numbers i don't
want to set expectations i'm going to
say if you do it right and you put in
the work a new grower can get fatty
harvest from these plants i do want to
take a moment to give a shout out to my
friend lefty i was throwing around a
strain name ideas it's really hard to
name strains all the cool [ __ ] is taking
all the things in my head as soon as i
come up with it i feel like i uh
telegraph it out to other people and
they take the strain name also i've had
a bunch of cool names in my head i'm a
big fan if you've been listening this
far now is the time that i'm going to
reveal how the strain got named
i'm a big fan of the movie dazed and
confused and i try to name stuff after
dazed and confused my buddy my buddy
lefty's got a strain known as waterson
that is banana kush to arise
i've had moon tower written on us on a
strain name list for a long time i got a
document in my phone it is just strain
names that's all it is anytime i watch a
movie or whatever i get a strain name
idea type it down in the list then when
new strains come up we scroll through
and see if anything matches and if it
works out in my head moon tower was on
the list for a long time i was in a chat
i said what do we name the bubba kush to
arise my buddy lefty said the moon tower
and i was like i just saw that movie i
just watched it with my girlfriend she'd
never seen it before she's from sweden i
introduced her to that movie she laughed
she liked it
lefty said moon tower i just talked
about banana kush to arise a moment ago
i was like that's gonna work so it
became the moon tower it came from the
movie dazed and confused the party at
the moon tower that was a good movie
that came out right around the time that
i was partying at the moon tower bro not
really at the moon tower but you get it
we were at different places anyway that
doesn't matter that's where the name
came from shout out to my buddy lefty
lefty bro i hope you and the wife are
well hope you're killing it down there
thanks for all the good work that you do
for me and great job with those testers
dude you did so good
all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
growers clone cutters paul and chuckers
all of you wonderful amazing cannabis
enthusiasts and growers out there thank
you once again for listening to my
report on the moon tower if you have any
questions corrections comments concerns
positive feedback constructive criticism
maybe i left some [ __ ] out maybe you got
more questions i would love to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy send
me those messages i do check that email
quite often looking for your
constructive criticism anything else
maybe on the website check out my
website
iregenetics.com that's really easy to
find i r i e g e n e t i c s
i read genetics dot com check that out
on the interwebs there all the
information you need will be right there
on the website if you're looking for the
discord link if you're looking for seed
vendors if you're looking for
merchandise i recommend while you're
there you sign up for the newsletter
there's a little spot about halfway down
that you can join the newsletter sign up
right there very shortly i will be
sending out a great newsletter those of
you have signed up for the mailchimp i
haven't been sending out a bunch of
stuff because i haven't had to watch a
report i say most of it here on the show
um i don't want to spam you and bombard
you but i do have something coming up
very soon so if you're not already
signed up to the newsletter i do
recommend you sign up to that because
there's a cool announcement coming very
soon the newsletter the discord and the
patreon will be the first places to hear
about that cool new thing that is being
built big shout out to my buddy ben for
the help
um the newsletter the website i think
that's all i've got for you guys thanks
again for watching and listening if you
are only watching the show on spotify or
apple podcast or stitcher radio i do
invite you to come join us on the
youtube channel there's a 4k youtube
video going on i'm pointing at you right
now inviting you you come hang out with
us at least subscribe to the show on
youtube i would appreciate that i'm
trying to get up to 10 000 subscribers
please subscribe on the youtube server
that's enough begging all right ladies
and gentlemen that's all i've got for
this episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
pedro's grow room and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
you