[Music]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
i'm your host my friends call me ross to
jeff this is episode 751
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to focus on a
couple of grow questions before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy stoner dave let's
send a big thank you shout out to sam
heads i want to send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to b bala and doc
groves let's send a big canadian thank
you shout out to my buddy caribou heart
tv let's send it thank you shout out to
a longtime supporter glenn geroni let's
send a thank you shout out to frogman
and kip let's send a thank you shout out
to brian p and double d let's send a big
thank you to my good friend trollin
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to elder's garden big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the show speaking of
supporting the show i want to start by
saying thank you to everybody who sent
me feedback and constructive criticism
on the last episode i previously asked
about uh what do you like and dislike
about the show would you like to see
more solo shows would you like to see
more guests i got a lot of great
feedback a lot of great responses thank
you i do appreciate that
it really helps me to make a quality
show that you enjoy if i know what you
enjoy
the number one response and request that
i did get from that feedback was longer
podcasts
i would love to give you longer podcasts
but just being me sitting here rambling
at a camera with a few notes in front of
me it feels really weird going for
longer than 25 35 minutes it's hard to
talk to yourself for that long without
somebody at least nodding at you and
replying i've got this camera looking at
me but it gets weird after about 30
minutes or so i feel like i'm just
talking at the wall because i'm just
talking to a camera lens it doesn't give
me any feedback which is hard to do so
i've gotten good at it the instagram
lives definitely help on the instagram i
do get the comments and some feedback in
there but that does help me get going
here there's i'm just talking at the
wall so it's hard to uh carry on a 30
minute conversation by myself then also
my voice will burn up there's nobody i
don't get a time to like let my throat
cool down my voice uh cool my voice and
i guess are the things that it doesn't
get any rest while the other person
talks because it's just me talking so
it's hard to do more than 30 minutes or
so the voice burns out then also the add
burns out i start thinking about like
well now i have to edit this long ass
show i got to get the show up to the
internet also another thing that you
guys probably don't care about is when i
do the
multi-cam shows and they get real long
they take a long time to edit so that
stuff does come to mind when i'm making
longer shows but mainly it's because uh
i just can't talk for 30 minutes by
myself the other request was that i do
bring mike on more frequently people do
seem to enjoy having mike on the podcast
which does of course result in longer
shows because mike can talk quite a bit
as well so in the future you will see
some shows with mike the uh the general
uh survey says that they do want mike on
about a third of the shows maybe a
quarter maybe a fifth of the show
somewhere in that area but not every
show but they do want to hear from mike
so we'll get mike on uh mike this is an
official invitation get a babysitter
come be on the show let's talk about
some cool [ __ ] all right i feel like i'm
rambling
my main point of that start of the show
there was thank you you guys for the
great uh constructive criticism the
positive feedback steering me in the
right direction i do appreciate that uh
sometimes we all do need a little bit of
encouragement and if i don't ask you
what i'm doing right and wrong you might
not tell me so i'll never figure it out
all right the next order of business on
the list of things to cover is something
i'm very excited about i may have teased
or hinted about this previously
but ire direct is live that's right if
you check out my website iregenetics.com
on the top in the middle row of things
you can select the options is what those
are there is one that says i redirect
guess what that gets you to that takes
you right to i redirect where you can
get some i read i read genetics direct
from the breeder that's right that menu
will change often
things will be updated frequently some
things will sell out and not get updated
some things will be restocked frequently
you've just got to pay attention also if
you were on the discord the discord
occasionally will notify you when i do
some updates and things like that there
will of course be a link to the discord
in the show notes and the video
description so make sure you check out
the discord you will get a link to the
ire direct page if you need that of
course you can find it iriegenetics.com
but the discord will give you the
updates when there are new drops also a
good way to stay updated on the new
drops is to join the newsletter when you
go to the website iriegenetics.com there
is an opportunity to join the newsletter
simply type in your email address i will
send out a newsletter approximately once
a month maybe every other month i try
not to spam you too much if i don't have
a lot to talk about i'm going to give
out coupons very soon for the irie
direct website patreon will get coupons
the discord will get coupons the
newsletter will get coupon codes those
are coming out so do of course join the
newsletter also of course join the
patreon and of course do join us on
discord where do we go from there i've
got one more very important order of
business to cover i will be at the dude
grows cup saturday july 30th join me the
event starts at 2 p.m the party ends at
8 p.m it is just outside of fort collins
i will be there i so far i think white
mike will be there i should have
somebody else there with me don't want
to make any plans or announcements or
promises yet until we get a little bit
closer but i think we will have a great
team there come hang out with us a lot
of cool members of the ire army will be
showing up
a lot of people are traveling from all
over the country possibly all over the
world to come hang out with us at the
dude grows cup so do please join us that
is once again july 30th that is a
saturday the event does start at 2 p.m
it will end around 8 p.m we do invite
you it is just outside of fort collins
for all of the deets links details
anything you may need do check out dude
grows dudegrows.com they'll get you
tickets they'll get you laced up check
it out this is a cannabis uh tasting
event a cannabis competition everybody
that shows up will be given a fresh one
hitter they will be given a lighter and
then they will be allowed to sample all
the entries that have entered the
competition it will be a good time also
many of your favorite seed breeders will
be there vending so come say hi i will
have a lot of great things prepared for
the dude grows cup all right i have one
more very very important message that we
do have to read this might be the most
important message in today's episode
this one came from patreon
and it goes a lot like this it says
rasta jeff thanks for addressing my
question on the show much appreciated i
think i'm going to change my methods for
the foreseeable future but then it says
i appreciate you bro in a completely
unrelated note was it you that i heard
about frying a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich like a grilled cheese i had one
last night and it was unreal i'm pretty
sure i heard about it from you a while
back but i wasn't sure if that tip was
you then big ups once again bro that
definitely was from me i did talk about
in the 7-11 episode episode number 711
was all about the munchies i hope you
guys got the joke that i did there
7-eleven and the munchies um i did an
episode talking about snacks and
munchies and i did mention a fried or
maybe a grilled peanut butter and jelly
sandwich you make yourself a normal
peanut butter and jelly sandwich slap
butter on the outsides of both pieces of
the bread and throw that [ __ ] in a hot
pan grill it like you would a grilled
cheese sandwich and that peanut butter
and that jelly make this melty smelty
gooey warm texture flavor in the middle
that is just amazing so big up to our
friends here for following the guidance
following the advice
experiencing life and enjoying the
grilled or the fried peanut butter and
jelly sandwich i'm glad you found out
about that thanks for reporting back
enjoy okay let's focus in a little bit i
did say that i had some grow questions
here i've got a grow question that came
from the website from the grow help tab
this one came from our friend oh it says
keep me and not a mouse this one came
from our friend anonymous and it goes a
lot like this it says rasta jeff when
you switch to 18 6 at the end of the
flowering cycle do you reduce the
intensity of the lights or just let them
rip i'm thinking about their dli needs
if you if you do reduce the power okay i
don't so we don't even need to talk
about that um
so let's kind of recap what our friend
is talking about i have been preaching a
method a technique of i switch my lights
back to 18 hours on and six hours off at
the end of a flowering cycle many people
think that that is absolutely crazy they
think i'm [ __ ] everything up by doing
this but it has proven to be very
successful for me i learned this by
doing it to my seated crop i learned
that my seeds become more healthy
they harden up faster they're bigger
stronger faster more vigorous i get a
better germination rate i get more
successful seeds from a crop by
switching my flowering lights to 18
hours on and six hours off toward the
end of flower when i'm doing this with
the flowering crop that is not seeded i
generally do this when i begin to flush
the final 10 to 14 days or so is when i
will do the 18 hours on and six hours
off one note that i have been stressing
that people
make sure to follow this word of advice
please listen to this one if you're
going to do the 18 6
do not do it on the first run with a
plant learn the plant see how long that
plant takes to finish
then you know when to change the timer
to 18 6 next time so let the plants
finish the first run don't do this on a
brand new plant this is not a first date
trick this is a trick for a plant that
you've got some experience with
so at the end of flower during the flush
phase i will turn my lights back on from
12 12 to 18 hours on and six hours off
now i'm giving them half a day more
worth of light worth of more more worth
of photons more energy for growth
more uh more robust fat dense buds is
basically what you're going to get or in
my case bigger fatter healthier seeds so
i do just straight turn the light timer
on to 18 6 and i do not change the
intensity of the lighting at all i don't
want to reduce the intensity i want to
give them more light longer days let
them grow now people are going to say
your plants are going to re-veg it takes
much longer for the plants to re-veg
than it does for them to beef up and
swell in time for the harvest that's why
i talk about don't do this on your first
run if you do this on the second and
third run we know when the harvest will
be you kick it right in time you cut
down before anybody revenges you don't
cause any problems so the short answer
is no i do not reduce the amount of
light when i switch to 18-6 i keep them
banging i keep them going and i do it
business as usual until the plants are
done very good question thank you for
that one uh thanks for letting me know
to keep you anonymous i do appreciate
that
all right i do have another message
right here in front of me this one came
from our friend do they want their name
said
they know who they are they go by jh
what up jh good to see you bro you send
me a lot of questions i don't read them
all on the show but i do read them all
on the screen i don't reply to every
single one of them please do keep
sending me your great questions you're a
smart person you got some great ideas
but you should go outside and get away
from the computer for just a couple of
minutes
nothing but love bro this question goes
on it says what's up ross to jeff what
is your personal order of importance in
your grow operation would this change at
home versus commercially then he kind of
touches it up it says is there an order
in which you enter and exit your grow
areas to prevent bringing issues from
one area to another like in order of
work flow then it follows up with does
your mother room have a special entrance
or exit or plan are there any special
procedures then there's some more stuff
that we don't really need to cover a lot
right now we can jump right into this
this is a good question the first part
of the question um is there an order of
importance in your grow then it says
would it change at home versus
commercially i can answer that very
easily yes and a personal grow versus a
commercial grow the order of operations
the importance of operations change
drastically in a commercial environment
uh we've got a lot of people going in
and out there's at least three to five
maybe 10 maybe 20 people going in and
out of any commercial environment at any
time
that are regular employees you've got
your
lead cultivator then you've got your
growtex and then you've got your
your helpers and then you got your trim
crew your lead trimmer your harvest
manager um your compliance manager
there's a bunch of people running
through there then also sometimes
ownership shows up like the owners
aren't employees they're not there every
day they don't give a [ __ ] about
standard operating procedures sometimes
you could tell the owner we do it this
way and they go that's fine i'm gonna go
in there and you're like but we all put
on tyvek suits and [ __ ] tie up our
hair and the owner goes i'm gonna wear
my dress and my high heels in there and
i don't give a [ __ ] what you think and
you go you own it you get to do what you
got to do so we get a lot of people
coming and going through the grow
sometimes you have contractors in there
i assume just because that's why my
brain works i assume that those
contractors came from another grow
before they worked in my grow that's
just what my brain thinks i think
everybody that shows up in a commercial
facility just came from another
commercial facility that's all that they
do that's all we think about that's just
that's not real but that's what my brain
thinks so we got a lot of people coming
and going is my point here some people i
can
kind of and i don't want to say control
but i can control the coming and going
of some people i can control the
procedures of some people the
cleanliness uh the approach to some
people other people i cannot ownership i
can't i am a paid consultant i can
recommend things to the owner but i
cannot tell the owner what to do i can
fire employees i can hire employees the
owner can fire me so i can recommend
that you don't wear the high heels and
the skirt into the grow room that you
put on the tyvek suit like the rest of
us but if she wants to look hot that's
what she is gonna [ __ ] do today so
the order of importance definitely does
change in a personal grow compared to a
commercial grow environment like i said
we've got so many people coming in a
commercial grow
also there's so much more at stake in a
commercial grow if my personal growth
fails
i will survive i won't make a crop of
seeds or i won't make a batch of flowers
and mike won't get to smoke and we won't
have as good of a time
but life will go on [ __ ] will continue
if we ruin a crop at a commercial grow
because we let somebody bring in some
bugs or i brought in some bugs if there
was a mistake there are millions of
dollars at risk there um one crop
one major crop failure in the commercial
market right now could destroy a
commercial grow
if that commercial grower to fail it
could also destroy
their medically infused product uh
facility which would be
so the grow is where the flowers are
grown obviously right they don't the
flowers aren't sold from there they are
then taken either directly to the
dispensary for sale which is my next
avenue or they are taken to a medically
infused products laboratory where they
are turned into a concentrate turned
into edibles turned into a lotion turned
into a lube a lubricant they do all
kinds of [ __ ] with it but that medically
infused products facility
would also go under if the growth sinks
so do all of these subsequent facilities
which is the medically infused processor
and the dispensary attached to it so the
one crop could ruin three businesses
that all fall under one business entity
which would mean you got probably 15 20
people at the dispensary or at the grow
working uh probably maybe five or ten
people depending on your medically
infused uh whatever you got going on you
got 520 people there then at the
dispensary you got probably 20 people
working there there's going to be
somewhere between 20 and 100 people that
are fired and are out of work because of
one crop failure so things are much more
critical things are much tighter in a
commercial environment also something
that um
it matters it does make a difference we
cannot use the same methods of
eradication in a commercial environment
i do my best to stick to colorado
department of agriculture and colorado
marijuana enforcement division
regulations when it comes to pesticides
and fungicides and cleanliness and
things like that within my personal grow
but honestly when people um if i were to
get a clone from a friend i'm trying to
think i had to say that safely if i get
a clone from somebody no matter where it
came from i will treat it with a
pesticide that is not allowed in a
commercial grow because
uh that is my my way of protecting
myself i can treat those incoming plants
with a really
a strong pesticide that i wouldn't
recommend unless it's an incoming plant
that's the only reason i have this
pesticide is
people say i don't have bugs and people
like to say that they don't have
diseases but guess what not everybody
knows that they got a disease or a bug
so when i get a plant i treat it with
some crazy [ __ ] i've learned my lesson i
got spider mites from somebody uh no
names to be said here but somebody sent
me a clone that had the most ferocious
[ __ ] spider mites i've ever seen it
slowed me down honestly for a full year
these spider mites
they would not go away i needed a solid
colorado winter i was sucking in cold
air from the negative 17 outside blowing
it into the veg room the plants look
like [ __ ] but eventually the spider
mites died i kept treating for them
anyway
i don't want to get that problem again
so i treat very heavily when plants come
in to prevent problems you couldn't do
what i do in a commercial grow because
the products that i'm applying are
actually banned i know that that's i say
that i try to grow from my heart breed
with love and treat these plants with a
lot of love but that is my preventative
measure to keep my livelihood my
business afloat if i let spider mites
get in here again and ruin a bunch of
plants then that's that's a bunch of
seeds you guys don't get to grow that's
a bunch of herb that mike and i don't
get to smoke so i've got to prevent that
sort of stuff now let's get back to um
the commercial girls can't use that
stuff i can use that stuff so that's one
of the main differences is the amount of
people that come and go and the products
which we are allowed to use also i was
talking about the funding in the budget
if my crop goes away that's a couple of
lights at six plants not a big deal bye
bye in a commercial grow we've got
hundreds maybe thousands of plants in
one area and if you get a problem over
here in this tray
there are fans there are people walking
around the [ __ ] is gonna move around
very quickly if one room gets
contaminated if one table gets an
infestation of bugs it's gonna move
around with the fans the spider mites
climb up to the tops of the plants and
they feel the wind and they go oh
there's a breeze and they put out a
little web and they jump and they have a
leap of faith and they draw that that
web with them and wherever they land
that's where they build the new web too
and they just make that leap of faith
and they use the fan to blow themselves
around and travel also they use the
growtex and the growers to travel around
they're jumping on your if you're
wearing scrubs they jump on your scrubs
if you're wearing a t-shirt they jump on
your t-shirt they move around the grow
with that stuff so we're spreading them
around the grow if we get one small area
infected infested with bugs it moves
very very quickly so my order of
operations is
not just different but it's more very
more strict and very more astringent in
a commercial environment one thing i
should loop back around in my personal
grow it's personal nobody goes there
you're not invited get the [ __ ] out you
cannot come there i don't bring
contractors there i don't bring
inspectors there there are no investors
there i don't even nobody gets to see
that [ __ ] mike hasn't even seen the grow
in weeks and months and clint hasn't
seen it my girlfriend actually had to
ask can i see a couple of your plants i
had she had to like ask for permission
to actually get to see the [ __ ] i don't
take anybody in there that's not that is
my space i share a lot of stuff on the
internet i share a lot of my life on the
internet my podcast is all over the
place i'm on instagram all the time
doing instagram live [ __ ] i'm on discord
hanging out with my friends my grow
space is my little zen area that is my
space i don't take people in there you
can't judge me you can't disrupt me you
can't learn my tricks you can't steal my
secrets that is my little 10 by 10 area
of leave me alone you can't change the
music in there you can't turn down the
fan
don't touch it you're not invited i know
it sounds rude right
it's cool you're allowed to do that with
your space it's mine it's yours you do
what you want i'm gonna do what i want i
love it so that is my grow space nobody
gets to go in there but me i definitely
don't have any pets down there no dogs
get to go up there
that is just my grow space so what i've
got to do for preventative is much less
when i get uh when i get home if i'm
going to the grow space i simply drop
the clothes that i'm wearing and from
the shoes the socks the pants i leave
the same undies if you want to visualize
that ah the shirt's got to go the dreads
are usually tied up or untied somehow if
i'm going into the grill i've got a
specific hat tie the locks up put them
into the specific hat i wear a couple of
outfits that i rotate into the grow i
wash them quite frequently but i've got
specific grow room clothes that i wear
in there so i come from wherever i was
basically strip down put on the grow
room clothes go into the grow as i come
out before those go any of those i go
into any other room those grow clothes
come off and they get stacked into a
little bit of a pile sometimes they get
thrown in the washer if i saw any
problems a lot of times i'll take a
shower before i even go into that grow
space of course i got [ __ ] six foot
long dreadlocks so it's kind of hard to
completely shower before i go into every
grow space but i do my best another
thing that helps me out is i'm allowed
to use different products so my main
standard operating procedures are very
different in my personal grow and in
commercial grows because the amount of
people that are coming and going
the amount of risk that is involved the
options that we've got for mitigating
problems if i see a problem in migraine
i can blast it with whatever i want that
i feel ethical doing so and also keep in
mind people aren't going to smoke 90 of
what i grow most of what i grow is
seeded so technically i could i don't
don't give you don't think i'm doing
this but i could spray it with
everything because you're not going to
smoke it that's the reason we worry
about spraying our plants mostly is
because we don't want people smoking
contaminated [ __ ] you're not going to
smoke it bro it's all going to be seeds
which
i'm just hypothetically saying i could
treat it with all kinds of [ __ ] we can't
do that in a commercial grow so order of
importance um
it's similar order of importance keep
the plants healthy keep them bug free
have an integrated pest management
strategy and then grow from your heart
breed with love the order of importance
is the same
but the uh the way the operation the
procedures change a little bit because
like i said we've got so many people
coming and going at the commercial grows
that we've got to do a little bit of
stuff differently then it says is there
an order in which you enter and exit
your grow areas that's a very good
question
uh one thing that i do in a commercial
environment
um
if i am the boss which most of the time
not to sound egotistical i'm the boss
i'm the guy directing the grow team i
like to learn what each grower is good
at and what each grower is not good at
let's just hypothetically talk about my
friends elijah and brian elijah is five
foot something
brian is six foot something why would i
have brian do the [ __ ] on the bottom and
elijah do the [ __ ] on the top i've
learned that brian can do the tall stuff
elijah can do the lower stuff so it's my
job as the kind of the boss the director
of cultivation the guy in charge of the
crew i find who is good at what that's
one of the things i really like to do i
know that cletus likes to be outside a
lot so if there's a job that goes
outside galitus gets that job
immediately i know that some of the
growers they want to be inside all the
time so if there's a job that goes
outside don't make him do it it'll get
done half ass that's something that i
try to learn now something that i keep
in mind when i'm assigning tasks for the
start of the day is i put a person in a
room and i try to leave i we we're doing
elijah and brian and cletus if i've got
rooms a b and c i will try to put brian
in room a all day so that he doesn't
have to come out of room a and [ __ ] up
room b he doesn't bring the problems
from room a to room b that is something
that i would do elijah would get room c
cletus would get room however i did it
we'd give the guys an individual room or
the ladies too we've got plenty of
ladies in the grow i just say guys all
the time because it's just what i
[ __ ] say dude um so let the guys and
gals uh have individual rooms or i'll
put three or four guys or gals in one
room and just make them stick in that
room so they're not moving the problems
around that's one way that i really
focus on it then you asked about an
order of workflow in my personal grow i
tend to check on the clones
first and most often because they're
kind of they're critical they are in
triage they're in icu the clones are not
alive they need a lot of attention if
that dome gets bumped a little bit and
the humidity comes out we're [ __ ] all
your clones are going to die so i check
those as often as possible kind of ocd
as frequently as i can
then the smaller plants are probably
going to dry up the soonest so i check
those next then
i'm in the veg areas and i will check
the bigger veg plants i'll check those
next then of course the mother plants
are in there i would check the mother
plants next i got the clones the veg the
moms all in one area so i make sure that
those are cool
then we would check the flowering space
after that but i basically start from
the the starters all the way up to the
enders because my thought process is i
need healthy starts if they're already
uh infested infected contaminated at the
end they're almost done i can't save
them i just gotta get them i gotta ride
them out but i need healthy [ __ ] for my
next run always i need healthy moms
healthy clones healthy veg or i cannot
have a strong flower so i focus mostly
my order of operations honestly
in the commercial grow and the home grow
i focus on the littles and i work my way
up
all the way to the end of the day is
we're checking on burping the jars and
harvesting and that's a whole other
[ __ ] conversation then it says does
your mother room have a specialty
entrance or exit plan um without
revealing too much info
the home grove is a home grow it's got a
bedroom door on it bro
it's got a lock and a key and a bedroom
[ __ ] door no special grow the windows
are covered so nothing can get in and
out i put uh
the it's two great words together one of
my favorite products i use gorilla [ __ ]
to seal all the cracks and then put tape
over that as well so nothing's getting
in and out of there unless it goes under
the door or through the air ducts which
i have created i use the air underneath
the door for passive air intake let me
read more of this question because i got
rambling really well i'm not even sure
that i've answered the question but i've
talked a lot so you guys asked for
longer shows you [ __ ] get it today uh
personal order of importance in your
grow i go personal order of importance
um
i don't know if i did my flow chart but
order of importance is like clean
healthy plants
does all the gear work one of the first
things i do when i walk into a
commercial growth i make sure that
everything is working um
we haven't been there for 12 hours did
anything break i teach the new people i
always say all right now we got to go
find out what went wrong last night and
they're like what i'm like oh something
broke last night a timer died a pump
failed something [ __ ] shorted out
something somewhere broke last night we
got to go find that so order of
importance check the gear check the
plants uh smallest to largest then do i
scout a lot um when i come back from
lunch probably because i'm blazed i just
[ __ ] took fat dabs at lunch i like to
just cruise and look for bugs just go
cruise a room send the guys in the rooms
just go guys and girls just go scout for
bugs right after lunch go see if you see
anything and if you do report back if
not get back to work business as usual
so order of importance i talked about
doing the small plants up to the biggest
plants doesn't really change at home in
order which i enter or exit the groves
um
since i my homegrow is basically two
small rooms so not there's no
if there's something in that space it
got in both spaces probably but i do the
veg stuff then i do the flower stuff
then you ask about how i prevent from
moving problems around basically in a
commercial grow the way that i do that
is i try to keep people in specific
rooms when we go to lunch when we go to
break i try to remind the guys to take
off their they're wearing a jacket or a
hoodie or something i try to have a
special shirt special shoes and stuff
for each grow sometimes it's hard to
implement certain sops that some grows
when i'm not fully
100 in charge they will take my advice
and my guidance but they won't always
take everything as instruction does my
mother room have a special entrance and
exit
and the commercial grows we like to get
those things you can step on the floor
mats it's got pesticides inside of it
you stomp around on it it will kill all
the [ __ ] on your shoes in some places we
use booties uh just little shoe covers a
lot of places we do use a hair net and a
beard net a lot of places we do scrubs a
lot of places honestly bro we walk in
and out of everything in our regular
[ __ ] clothes it just depends on which
facility and what the owner agrees with
i make suggestions
the owner kind of makes the final move
it does go on it says i have a shared
mom and veg room what can i do to help
keep my mom plants safe that is very
good question uh we've been talking
about viruses lately
between
if you go from your veg plants to your
mother plants uh consider dunking your
scissors in bleach and cleaning those
scissors before you go cutting on your
mother plants that way if you do and if
you've got the viroid it's probably in
the mother plant but if you don't want
to move it around perhaps maybe it would
help you cleanliness is the key um
that's what i would recommend and i have
a shared mom clone veg space as well i
think you'll be just fine with that
setup then it says i like starting in
the veg mom room closing everything up
and moving on to the flower room have
you ever worked backwards i've done it
backwards i've done it forward as long
as you're clean and paying attention and
not moving problems around that's what
matters as long as you've got a strategy
a standard operating procedure that
works for you that's the most important
part one of my favorite things of
growing cannabis
is that my way works and it could be
totally different than your way and your
way is not wrong as long as at the end
of it we're both sitting here at the
table smoking a bowl and we go
i'm satisfied that's what [ __ ]
matters as long as you're satisfied with
the weed you grew i'm satisfied with the
weed that i grew we didn't do it wrong
the only way you really do it wrong is
if the plant died then you obviously did
it wrong if you burned some [ __ ] down
you did it wrong if you get somebody
sick by using a pesticide improperly you
did it wrong um
i'd like to say if you go to jail you
did it wrong but that might not even
been part of the case that might have
just been some [ __ ] there for you but
if you're smoking weed and you're happy
with the way that it came out you're not
doing it wrong there may be things i do
differently there may be things i
wouldn't do or maybe things that i would
do in your garden but as long as you've
got an outcome that you're smoking
you're not doing it wrong there are a
thousand ways to skin a cat there are
probably a thousand ways to grow a plant
that's the beauty of it that's why i
love it that's part of what i love about
cannabis i can do it my way i've been
doing it my way i've been establishing
developing and i don't want to say
perfecting but honing my way for several
years now to the ability to the effect
of the level where i feel like i can
teach you guys to follow my my standard
operating procedure and have great
success but i also encourage you to do
it your way your grow is not the same as
mine your lights are not the same as
mine your plants aren't the same as mine
you may have an astronomical [ __ ]
budget you could buy all those new
lights that came out last week that i've
been looking at going when do they come
out with this one and you may not have
any budget at all you may be duct taping
[ __ ] old street lamps to the ceiling
to make that work we've all got a
different set up we've all got the same
goal our goal is to grow the best herb
that we can so that whenever we hang out
whenever we don't feel right whenever we
want to feel better we can smoke the
best herb that is available and we can
produce it ourselves and not have to
rely on anybody else all right i think i
got rambling pretty good there i am not
sure how long i've been recording we're
going to call this a podcast everybody i
want to thank you for listening i had a
good time recording this show i hope you
had as good of a time as i do i look
forward to your feedback your
constructive criticism uh your positive
words of affirmation or if you want to
tell me there's something to correct i
look forward to it the email address of
course is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me that
feedback let me know what you think of
the show of course do not forget about
the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else is on the website do not
forget about i redirect go to
iregenetics.com click on i redirect see
what's available today some things come
and go very quickly you never know what
i might post up there we do some crazy
deals on that site stay tuned i think
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to ben the
web guy and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
so
you