[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode
752 of the grow from your heart podcast
i've got a great show lined up for you
before we get to the main topic let's do
a few shout outs to a few of the kind
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to stone to trout bomb let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy all mixed up i want to send a big
thank you shout out to the larf knight
rises let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to route 305. let's
send a big thank you shout out to my
buddy operation high vibes i want to
send a big thank you shout out to randy
farms let's send a thank you shout out
to a longtime supporter my buddy
godfather kush big thank you shout out
to noah and i'll send a big thank you
shout out to adhd grower i want to send
a thank you shout out to og roach and
the devil's weed let's send a big thank
you shout out to jay dutch then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
growing tennessee
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
everyone to support the show
i want to start off by sending a big
shout out to my friend who um allegedly
possibly sent me or made some lemon
jeffrey concentrates that has got me um
i don't even know the word i'm a little
bit goofy i'm like dodging [ __ ] that's
not coming at me over here uh i'm high
as [ __ ] from that lemon jeffrey bro if
you made the lemon jeffrey concentrates
that somehow landed in my rig a few
minutes ago
that [ __ ] is effective bro good good job
where do we go from there the greenhouse
if you've been following along you know
that i'm doing a breeding project in a
greenhouse i was at the greenhouse today
and guess what everything looks good not
a lot to report things are growing
things are in veg they're getting big
they're growing quickly
i'm always amazed at the outdoor growth
i'm not there every single day so when i
do go there it looks like they've grown
astronomically since the last time i was
there they grow so fast outdoors
compared to the indoors double or triple
as fast outdoors is what i think but
they're looking good they're going
strong not a lot to report but
everything looks good in the greenhouse
breeding project stay tuned in future
episodes i will talk more about what
plants i've got going on out there of
course we did put the jack the ripper
mail outside so that's what we'll be
dumping pollen this year i love doing
the teases about the greenhouse and
keeping you updated not a lot to report
stay tuned there will be more in the
future
all right the next order of business i
look forward to seeing you at the dgc
growers cup that's right saturday july
30th at a location just outside of
colorado springs team irie genetics will
be at the dgc growers cup i hope to see
you there the cup is going to be a great
event it is a consumption friendly event
we will be there consuming cannabis
making friends shaking hands having a
good time there is a small competition
happening a bunch of people have entered
some flowers into a competition
everybody who attends is a judge if you
attend the dude grows cup the dgc
growers cup you get to be a judge in the
flower competition you get a one you get
a lighter you get to taste all the
entries and you get to vote on what the
best flower at the event is so show up
come taste some good herb come hang out
there will also be a plethora of great
seed breeders vending their seeds at the
event so we do look forward to seeing
you at the dude grows cup for tickets
deets and links make sure you do check
out dudegrows.com for all of the
information on the dgc growers cup
there's a big tab right on the front
page you cannot miss it come join us it
is going to be a great time all right
i've been rambling long enough let's
jump into the email portion of this
podcast i've got a bunch of emails
stacked up here on the table this one
comes from our friend mark this question
is a recap uh in a previous episode
somebody did ask me if i think that the
male plants or the female plants know
about each other in the other rooms they
asked if i notice a difference in the
female plants if i have a male in the
other room or if i notice a difference
in the male plants if i have a female in
the other room i said i've noticed
visible differences but i didn't have
any real scientific background our
friend mark updated me he said i have an
update thank you for the update bro it
says i watched a documentary called the
magic plant and it said the terpenes
come from the sun and they are the sex
hormones for the plant so it sounds
plausible i guess anyway take care and
thank you for everything you do
those terpenes do have a lot of purposes
the chirps put off a lot of aromas think
about when you smell food or when you
smell uh candy or when you smell flowers
or when you smell a pretty lady or maybe
you smell a pretty dude you go that
smells nice i want some of that maybe
the cannabis plants are doing the same
thing to each other maybe that lady
plant is over there going laminene
limonene and that male plant's going i
need some limonene
we don't know exactly what they're
saying because we can't speak their
plant language but it sounds like you're
onto something uh maybe those terps act
like pheromones maybe the plants have
pheromones that we haven't that i
haven't learned about yet but it does
make good sense to me those terps are
doing a lot to me they make me want to
smoke it so maybe they're making the
plants want to meet with each other and
i can smell the terps in the other room
that is for sure so it does make good
sense my dude mark thank you for the
great update i do appreciate it if
anybody else out there has any updates
of course the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy reach out i love generating
i love creating listener generated
content that's what i'm trying to say i
am pre-reading this next message while
i'm talking
all right this next message comes from a
good friend and a patreon supporter big
shout out to my friend girls grow too
this message goes a little bit like this
it says when is it too late to save a
plant that is a very very good question
when is it too late to save a plan when
do you give up when do you try to fix it
what is that boundary where is that
borderline where you say [ __ ] it and
throw in the towel how hard do you
actually try on a plant and also is it
one plant is it several plants that kind
of makes a big difference here but
there's more to the message it says if
the plant is very sick is there a way a
product etc that would save it let's
just say newt lockout or over hot or
stunted growth okay um
it kind of depends on how bad the plant
is first of all
it kind of depends on how bad i need the
plant honestly
um it depends on how far along the plant
is honestly depends on is it the
personal growth or the commercial grow
is it life or death or is it a breeding
project that's kind of just for fun
i've got the honor the privilege the
blessing to be able to if i'm growing a
crop and i'm not happy with the way it
looks i can scrap it and it's not going
to ruin me financially i talked in a
previous episode about a commercial grow
if they were to scrap one grow
too far in then that could ruin them
that could ruin the commercial grow
which would fire everybody in that
facility i'm just recapping that fire a
lot of people so
in a personal grow i've got maybe maybe
hypothetically somebody's got one light
and that's just gonna be maybe a pound
of herb maybe two pounds maybe it's just
a few ounces that's when i start making
decisions like do i really need this
crop or do i really need this crop or
would it be less of a headache just to
cut this [ __ ] down and start over again
so there are a lot of determining
factors in my
strategies here in a commercial grow
we don't i don't cut enough clones and
have enough plants to have enough of a
backup strategy i'm on a tight schedule
i'm on a tight plant count so i'm going
to do a lot to try to save every single
plant that i can in a commercial
environment also in a commercial grow
my panic button is much shorter my panic
fuse is much shorter than it would be in
a private grow in my home grow like i
said i can lose a personal crop you guys
might not get some seeds mike might not
get some weed for a couple of weeks but
we could lose a personal crop nobody's
gonna go bankrupt nobody's gonna have to
file any paperwork no one needs to look
for a new job
if i do kill a crop at this rate i may
need to look for a new job by then but
nobody's gonna get fired nothing too
crazy is gonna go wrong in a commercial
grow
i can't let it get that bad before i
start taking drastic measures to correct
things luckily in a commercial grow i've
got all the technology i've got all the
meters i got anything i can imagine to
help me figure out what is going on also
i've got a really good network of
friends people think i'm like the wizard
of oz of growing i often times when you
guys ask me grow questions i've just got
a team of friends that i know that i can
say hey bro why this or why this i'm
willing to admit that i am not the light
guy i don't know anything about grow
lights when it comes to
lumens and frequencies and all that
stuff i my brain simply does not care i
would love to learn about lights my
brain and my add does not want to learn
about lights when it comes to outdoor
growing i simply don't do a lot of
outdoor growing i rock a greenhouse this
will be my second year growing in a
greenhouse that's not outdoor growing
it's close it's greenhouse growing but
when you ask me greenhouse growing
questions i call jessie or when you ask
me outdoor growing questions i call
jesse i go hey bro somebody asked me
this he tells me something i parrot that
[ __ ] back to you on the show i'm not the
wizard of oz but luckily i've got a big
team i've got people that i can call
there are other consultants that i work
with that they call me too they're like
hey bro i've got this weird [ __ ]
thing going on in my grow can you help
me and i'll take a look and i'll go oh
it's because of that and so we just do
each other favors just call each other
back and forth so my panic button what
i'm getting at is i've got a lot more
resources in the commercial growth so i
will do a lot more in the commercial
growth to keep those plants alive to
rescue them to save them and i don't let
them get too far [ __ ] up before i
really start taking drastic measures and
the personal grow i might go ah there's
some yellowing i might want to up the
nitrogen the next time i feed it if i
see yellowing in the commercial grow i'm
going and telling everybody bro the next
time we feed up the nitrogen pay a lot
of attention like there's a meeting
about it there's a lot of [ __ ] to be
done we're making sure that that
nitrogen gets added the next time we
might foliar feed like i don't let it
get too far it it's time to take action
uh and the commercial grows we're
running uh coco with perlite which is
basically hydro so the minute you feed
you're gonna start seeing reactions not
necessarily the minute but i mean you're
gonna see some [ __ ] change so in hydro
it can go really quickly so in a
commercial grow
i really uh it's
i try really hard not to let them get to
that panic mode but i will try to pull
them out we've had a pretty bad mite
infestation one of the things that i
talk about one of my goals uh one of the
things i pitch myself as is i'm able to
help get rid of bugs and problems and
turn a problematic grow around so i've
been hired to take over grows that were
infested with spider mites grows that
were infested with powdery mildew and i
almost have more fun turning a grow
around than walking into a girl that's
doing well and just keeping it going or
making it better i like a good [ __ ]
it sounds maybe it's because i've been
grown for so long and it's more of a
it's more fun to me i like a nice
challenging grow a grow that's got
spider mites and powdery mildew and got
nine bad employees that's a great grow
for me to walk into because i can cure
spider mites i can cure powdery mildew
and i can get rid of nine bad employees
and get five bad ass people to rock that
facility so it's kind of a fun thing i
like fixing things so i don't i like
being in the weeds so i don't throw [ __ ]
away i don't give up my
there's
uh it sounds crazy maybe i've grown so
much weed that it's like i can do that
sure we can do that we can turn rooms
and cut down a crop and have that room
running tomorrow in flower again we
never missed 12 hours of a day in that
room with plants it was [ __ ] i can do
that so now it's more fun for me to try
to go into those rooms that are
problematic and kind of start in the
weeds like i said it's more fun to dig
myself out of a hole and then try to fix
that and then give myself so many crops
to have this goal
buy five crops out of this facility
we'll be kicking up this much product
and we'll get this much thc percentage
and we'll get this much concentrate
percentage and we'll get this much
customer retention and i try to work on
those sorts of things so i almost have
fun pulling myself out of the weeds
a lot of it is just having
knowing if you've got the resources can
you repair the problem knowing that
you've got the time can you invest the
time
or is it going to be how far back is
that problem going to set you is it
going to set you two weeks back would it
be easier just to cut new clones get
them going maybe that is easier let me
focus you said newt lock
nutrient lockout depending on when if
it's like it's usually going to happen
right as you switch that usually happens
when you go from veg into the flowering
stage
your transition phase is going to suck
but your stretch phase is going to suck
your plants are going to look like [ __ ]
but you haven't started getting bud set
yet
so you've got a new lockout and you've
still got like six weeks to go you've
you figured it out like day 10 of flour
it started showing signs by 14 you're
ready to make corrections i would mix up
a solid batch of nutrients that you know
is correct a good base nutrient some
good microbes in there but your calcium
your magnesium your phosphorus potassium
molybdenum get all the good [ __ ] that
you need and they're all the basics of
perfectly balanced meal perfectly ph to
the perfect dc and then feed that to
those plants on that day and that's i
would start correcting it from that day
now you've got six or seven more weeks
to go before that plant's even done
you're gonna transition out of that [ __ ]
phase where it's looking like it's been
beat up it's gonna take about a week
then you're going to get a bunch of new
growth then you're going to get bud set
and you're going to get buds you haven't
even started developing buds yet to do
any damage to them so why not just keep
pushing on through if that loot newt
lock happens later on when you start
adding the bloom boosters at that point
you're [ __ ] six weeks in just push on
through and finish the buds
once you're like four or five weeks past
a lot of people might just cut it down
once you're four or five weeks into
flower a lot of people may consider
cutting it down if they've got spider
mites or a nutrient lockout but you're
so close to the finish line why not just
push through it you may not get the
outcome that you wanted you may not get
the product that you wanted the weight
the yield the potency the flavor the
dank photos but you're gonna get a
learning experience push on through and
have something to show for your work i
wouldn't give up um if you're in flower
keep going that's i never i would never
want to just give up and cut my losses
if i've made it all the way to the
flowering phase you've done veg work
it takes a lot of work to get up to that
phase so i always try to fix them i i
keep saying i really enjoy trying to fix
the plants it's really easy to grow herb
for me i why not try to fix these
problems and pull my way out of it so if
you got newt lock i would try to fix
that that's only going to set you back
two weeks
if you were going to pull a pound maybe
you're only going to pull 14 13 12
ounces now you're still going to have
product don't give up some is better
than none
the next example was over hot and
stunted growth
over hot let's talk about too much heat
as soon as you change the temperature
they'll start growing back they're going
to be tall and skinny and lanky and kind
of pissed off but as soon as you correct
the temperature they'll start growing
back unless you meant overhot by too
much food which um depending on how bad
you roasted them you may be able to
recover them feed them a normal diet
dial back the nutrients they may recover
from that as well
the other one is stunted growth
if they look super pissed off if you're
embarrassed about it and you just want
to start over sometimes you just have
that feeling inside you're like [ __ ]
these plants if you feel
[ __ ] these plants then just cut them
down and start over because you're never
going to
give them the love and care that they
deserve because you've already got that
that [ __ ] these plants feeling in your
heart and you're not going to change
that you might try to convince yourself
that you're going to take care of them
and pull them through but once your
heart and your brain decide man [ __ ]
these plants it that they know it too
the plants heard you say that the plants
felt you say that and so that is the
point when i would just kind of cut them
down give up at that point i have never
lost a commercial crop i've never cut
down an entire commercial crop and given
up i've had commercial crops that were
not up to the standards that i would
like them to be they definitely did not
get posted to instagram there were no
pictures but i've never cut down an
entire crop in a commercial grow and
given up i have cut down crops in my
private grow
because we discovered that the whole
back corner excuse me
i did cut down an entire crop in my
private grill one time because mike and
i discovered that the back corner uh it
was wintertime and this one back corner
at the exterior part of the house uh
that whole corner i said whole corner
excuse me for that that entire corner
got powdery mildew there were some big
beefy plants back there but we noticed
the powdery mildew along the back wall
the buds were late into flower i wasn't
experienced and knowledgeable as
knowledgeable as i am now to know what
to have done about it so we just went
and cut down all those plants i knew
that um they weren't healthy they
weren't safe they weren't any good so i
just cut all those down because there
was so much powdery mildew that treating
them spraying them cleaning them up
still would not have made me happy i
would have felt gross about that
i was
working as a caregiver i was growing for
uh medical cannabis patients and i was i
really thought about a couple of those
people i thought about my friend doug i
thought about what if i give doug or
mike some herb that's covered in powdery
mildew and we smoke it one of us or all
three of us get sick i'm gonna feel like
a [ __ ] my
job my goal as a cannabis grower as a
caregiver is to make people feel better
and heal them not to give them a lung
infection or a sinus problem or whatever
the [ __ ] else that powdery mildew could
have caused so i did cut down um i think
i cut down ninety percent of that crop
maybe we saved a few of the plants that
were up in the front but i do remember
cutting down all the [ __ ] in the back
there were uh white rhino plants with
buds the size of footballs and we were
really sad to cut that [ __ ] down but
sometimes you gotta cut your losses so
ninety percent of the time i would push
on through i would just because it's
rewarding um i do know that our friend
girls grow too has military experience
and you know that feeling of like uh i
said the example being in the weeds and
[ __ ] pulling through i know you've
got that that rewarding feeling inside
you of that accomplishment because
you're a soldier we've talked about
things like that i know that you've got
that feeling
that [ __ ] feels good when you're like
i'm going to fail i'm going to fail i'm
going to fail and then at week 10 you
cut some [ __ ] down and you've got usable
smokable tangible
enjoyable product it may not be cannabis
cup winning herb it may not be trophy
weed but you got something and without a
struggle
maybe it wasn't as enjoyable and you had
to learn something maybe it's better to
learn how to fight spider mites now than
it is way later on when you think you've
got when your grow is flowing when it's
humming you got more expensive genetics
you got more expensive lights and then
you get mites maybe it's good now to
find that sort of [ __ ] out when you're
beginning or maybe when you're newer and
then you can learn how to fight that
[ __ ] so when is it too late to save a
plant
that's really up to you that is really
up to you um
if it's cover if it's got webs on it it
might be time just to go if you've got
spider mite webs it might be time just
to cut that [ __ ] down um if it's got
powdery mildew it might be time to cut
that [ __ ] down um most of the other
things we can usually usually get rid of
now now i know how to get rid of powdery
mildew now i know how to get rid of
spider mites uh prevention is key uh use
use that feeling inside of oh [ __ ] i
want to give up to remind you of like
how did i get here maybe that's a good
thing to touch on how did i get to this
point if your plant is sick enough or
new locked out or over hot or stunted or
has bugs or mildew badly enough to where
you're thinking i might want to cut this
down think of that as like how did i get
here what kind of was it neglect was it
laziness was it uh ignorance was it
miseducation was it lack of uh
communication with the team maybe you
got somebody else helping you was it
lack of communication communication with
a partner
what happened why did we get powdery
mildew and spider mites to the level
where i've got to cut down all of these
plants think about that
then uh see how you can prevent that
from happening in future grows because
we definitely don't want to deal with
the problem twice but if you get that
[ __ ] these plants feeling that is
basically the only time that i would
really cut them down and sometimes i've
had that like
not [ __ ] these plants but yeah with
these plants you know it's borderline
and i've pulled those crops through
those did survive um not every crop has
been beautiful but i've had some that
have made me want to grab my dreads and
just start yanking so when is it too
late to save a plant that is really up
to your level of patience how badly do
you want to learn how bad do you need
the medicine if you're in veg and you
can tell like two or three weeks in that
that [ __ ] just isn't gonna work go ahead
and cut it down i always talk about last
winter or two winters ago the pandemic
really [ __ ] up my scheduling i have no
idea what year it is and how long it's
been anymore i felt like it was tuesday
for two years so i'm kind of [ __ ] up
on timing but at some point in life i
decided to switch from uh hps high
pressure sodium lights to led lighting
and when i did
the plants looked like total [ __ ] and
honestly a few weeks into flower i just
went in and cut them all the [ __ ] down
and started over because
they were not gonna do anything good
from what i was seeing from those plants
nothing good was gonna come out of that
room i was gonna have a headache i was
gonna have a struggle i was gonna have
tall shitty plants that were getting
burnt by the light that were never gonna
meet my goals so like week three i just
said bucket and i cut every single one
of those plants down about 25 days into
flour
chopped them all up yeah mike was really
heartbroken over that but it for me it
was like i can do better than this and
what i did was i learned how to grow
under leds i made some adjustments and i
pulled through and i did it better the
next time so that's that is two crops i
guess that i've
cut down uh the powdery mildew crop and
the failed led crop are crops that i cut
down just because i wasn't happy i was
frustrated but that is up to you how bad
do you need the herb how frustrated are
you how much do you want to learn
do you have an opportunity to get more
plants do you have a backup plan that is
something i may keep in mind all right
girls grow too i feel like i rambled on
and on about that question i hope i
helped you out i hope i gave you some
useful advice it's all about your level
of frustration what will you accept how
far will you take it all right girls
grow too thank you once again for the
great message i have got time for one
more quick email before we wrap this up
this one came from our friend
oh this one came from my buddy jh what's
up jh you do send me a lot of messages
uh i apologize that i don't answer all
of them bro you send ah j.h i get more
messages from you than i do all day long
from everybody else combined that's why
when you wonder why i don't answer every
one of them nothing personal but just
send a lot of them buddy keep them
coming because you do send a lot of
great content i do pull some great
messages out of there ah there's some
gold and all that mud this one i'm just
picking on you bro i got nothing but
love for you this one goes like this it
says hey ross to jeff long time listener
first time caller here it says when
you're growing a small crop in a four by
four tent or maybe a five by five tent
what size pots do you go with that is a
really good really universal really
common question it does go on it says
would reducing my pot size from a three
gallon to a two gallon pot help reduce
stretch to use fabric or plastic pots is
one superior to the other this is a
great line of questioning i do like this
shout out to you jh um when i'm growing
a small crop in a four by four or a five
by five what size pots do i go with that
depends on my goal
um
if i am running new plants and just
running new [ __ ] and trying to take some
pictures and see what we just made i may
do one or two gallon pots sometimes i
may do uh beer cups i may do a now
honestly we are limited to uh plant
counts here in colorado so in a personal
grow
that's going to be way different we'll
touch on that as the as the uh the
theories and the ideas of this progress
keep in mind in a commercial grow i can
run as many plants as i want in a
commercial grow if you're in a home grow
follow the legal limits follow the rules
there that is quite often what
determines how many plants i put where
is legal limits and things so if i were
to do a 4x4 and i was to put a bunch of
beer cups in there i may consider
putting like 100 beer cups in there
maybe put like 10 rows of 10 and just
space them out just a little bit but i'm
limited to plant count so i wouldn't do
that here in colorado we'll segue into
what i would do here
maybe you would do a bunch of one gallon
pots and you could probably fit
i'm gonna guess you could probably fit
10 or 12 of those in a five by five so i
would just say 10 by 10 there you go 100
again you're just taking up some of that
cup space maybe it's only eight of those
but i would do uh maybe that's 64 one
gallon pots in there and that crams them
in real tight then we're only vegging to
about 10 or 12 inches tall and then
flowering and getting just getting in
and getting out really quick so maybe
you would do like 16 one gallon pots and
just have them in there real tight maybe
you could do 25 one gallon pots i'm not
sure how tight that would fit in there i
can't visualize it i think i could see
five one gallon pots across that five by
five or four by four uh so you got 25 of
them in there but a more practical
application that we would run in a tent
and a five by five maybe you could do ah
9 12 maybe 15 maybe 16 3 gallon pots
depends on how tightly you want to pack
them in there if you're gonna veg for a
short time put more pots in there if
you're gonna veg for a long time put
less pots in there something that i
frequently do is nine three gallon pots
and a five by five that works
beautifully for me that gives the plants
enough space i let me grow them up to
about my knee-high then i flower them
they finish at just the right height so
nine three gallon pots is quite often a
very good very successful grow or if
you're more limited on plant count four
seven gallon pots is beautiful in a five
by five i like to do four seven gallon
pots and a trellis net and pull them all
down or if you want to run a perpetual
grow in a five by five environment i
recommend four seven gallon pots and you
put one in every two weeks and take one
out every two weeks so you've got one
that's in there at two weeks one that's
in there at four weeks one that's in
there at six one that's in there at
eight and then hopefully you got a
cultivar that finishes right at eight
weeks and you can just rotate every two
weeks you take a plan out harvest it put
a new plant in there and put it into
flour four seven gallon pots work
beautifully in that five by five that is
probably what i would do uh running a
small crop in a four by four you're
probably looking at like a whole bunch
of one gallon pots i'm guessing you
could probably do
like ten of them across this one gallon
pots are little uh the ones i'm thinking
about you probably fit ten across that's
like 100 of those if you really wanted
to cram them in there if you want some
space maybe do 64. uh and then start
working up to 3 gallon pots where you're
doing like maybe maybe 12 maybe 16 maybe
9 it just depends on how big the plants
and how much space you want to have if
the plants are bigger you need more
space of course if the plants are
smaller you don't need as much space for
them to grow that does segue me into the
next part would reducing my pot size
from three gallon to two gallon help
reduce stretch no i believe it would do
uh kind of the opposite i believe that
the plants um they know how wide their
pot is and you'll notice that the plants
generally unless you do some
manipulating they don't branch out much
wider than the
size of your pot if you get keep your
plant in a two gallon pot that's only
what's this eight ten inches around i'm
a drummer that's i'm gonna say that's
ten inches around if you keep your plant
in a ten inch around pot the root base
only gets ten inches if you look up that
plant it only spread out about 10 inches
maybe those bottom branches where it got
real far maybe they went 14 18 inches
but not much further than that 10 inch
base then if you put that plant in a
wider pot you'll notice it will widen
out that is because it knows it's like
um i don't know it's sort of a gravity
thing maybe just knows that if i get i
can't get too wide because my feet
aren't big enough to hold me up i'm 6'5
maybe that's why i wear size 13 shoes
need that bigger pot for that bigger
plant that is my theory that is just my
theory and my experience they get whiter
when you put them in a wider pot so um
they'll stretch up more if you put them
in a skinnier pot also you're probably
going to put them closer together when
they get all close together like that
they don't like to grow uh out they like
to grow up somebody recently asked me uh
why plants would get angry if i put them
too close together why they would get
stretchy they're just angry uh they're
they can't grow out the way that they
want to they gotta grow up they get
stretchy trying to get to the light
because the light's not penetrating
because they're so close together
they're just mad they want to grow out
but they can't so they just grow up to
fight for the light there is more uh do
you use fabric pots or plastic pots in a
commercial environment i use three
gallon fabric pots with uh 70 cocoa and
30 perlite with two drip emitters per
pot each drip emitter comes from a
different reservoir so i can feed two
different feeds during the day if i want
to um
lots of different controls so i can mix
up a reservoir reservoir a will have one
feed and res a will have a resby will
have another feed so that i can feed one
part throughout the day and then right
before they go to bed i can feed them
with another thing if i so choose to or
i can just run clean water through one
if we decide to clean them out so in the
commercial environment
uh fabric three gallon fabric pots 70
cocoa 30 perlite two drip emitters
running from two different reservoirs so
we could feed two different nutrient
solutions uh and the home grow
i switch it up all the [ __ ] time
honestly i'm currently using the tall
five gallon plastic pots um
during the the pandy [ __ ] was hard to
get and those were what was available so
that's what i grabbed from my local
groce store i am very versatile very
flexible i can work with what i've got
um i'd like to have some [ __ ] but those
were the parts that were there so that's
what i grabbed is one superior to the
other uh no it's all about your goal all
about your intent all about your purpose
they both have pros and cons um
the one thing i don't like about the
fabric pots is if you don't get them
full and don't pack them up right the
water will kind of run out of the sides
but also i like that you can't over
water them because the water will run
out of the side so pros and cons there
my friend j.h i think i answered your
question at least this one i've got a
lot more from you please don't get
offended that i am not answering your uh
is that a deluge of questions that might
be what that is dude i got nothing but
love and respect for you thank you if
anybody else out there has any questions
corrections comments or concerns you
know that i would love to hear from you
the email address once again is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy reach out let me know what you think
of the show ask me those cultivation
questions you know i do love creating
listener generated content also don't
forget about the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart support the show if you feel like
the show is entertaining if i made you
laugh if i saved your garden patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else is on my website at
iregenetics.com check out
iriegenetics.com for links to uh the ire
direct seeds the merch you can grab
yourself a t-shirt a grinder a rolling
tray i will be restocking new merch very
soon the things do take quite a while to
ship but check out the website uh
there's a link to the discord server a
link to the beans a link to the merch
anything you could possibly need is on
the website once again iriegenetics.com
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
growers clone cutters and paul and
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i do want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
752 of the grow from your heart podcast
i really had a good time rambling out
this episode thanks again for hanging
out you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my buddy billy
podunk and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me