if you have ever been so blazed that you
made sure you hung up the gas pump
before driving away from the atm
now's a good time to click subscribe
[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rosta jeff this is episode 754
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend justa smokin
let's send a big thank you shout out to
dreadlockedfarmer i want to send a thank
you shout out to ars kickerson let's
send a thank you shout out to a longtime
supporter my buddy know me by my
guacamole let's send a thank you shout
out to stash stashdrop269 let's send a
big thank you to shoetrader101
i want to send a fist bump to my buddy
kojaks let's send a big thank you shout
out to my friend jimmy limmer let's send
a thank you shout out to crafted flower
i want to send a big thank you to grow
man stan let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to jeff o then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
anvil gardens big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show i do
apologize if you hear me struggling to
catch my breath i've been taking a
couple of fat dabs before the show here
i just smoked a nice buffet a
smorgasbord you if you will of great
concentrates amongst those dabs was a
mix a combo of the lemon jeffrey and the
machine that dab made my vision go weird
it made my head feel funny in all the
right ways so i'm over here struggling
trying to catch my breath i feel like
i'm underwater i feel like i got someone
sitting on my chest it's a little bit
heavy to breathe over here i will get my
[ __ ] together eventually we will make a
podcast out of this thank you for
dealing with my wheezy voice trying to
catch my breath here all right i've got
one more thing to cover before we get to
the main topic of this podcast i do
invite you to join team ivory genetics
and the dude grows crew and the irie
army and many other great cannabis
breeders for the dgc growers cup in fort
collins on july 30th that's right team
irie genetics and many other breeders
many members of the cannabis community
many members of the dude grows cup the
dude grows crew and the irie army will
be hanging out at the dgc growers cup in
fort collins i do invite you to come
hang out with us i look forward to
smoking a joint with you taking a dab
with you giving you a hug giving you a
fist bump taking a selfie with you
getting to know you meeting you face to
face if we've never met before and
seeing your smiling face again if we've
hung out before i do look forward to
seeing you at the dude groves cup so do
please come hang out you can find all
the info you need at dudegrows.com
i cannot wait to see you there all right
i have been teasing these emails saying
i've got an email portion of this
podcast we have not done any of that
let's jump into it
this question is not 100 cannabis
related but i feel like i am qualified
to answer this question i feel like my
friend orville was uh felt that i was
qualified because orville asked me this
question big shout out to my buddy
orville the question says really simply
how do you start a podcast i would like
to know that's a great question since
i'm 754 podcasts in i've got quite a
nice follow ship here a listenership a
viewership if you will we've got a good
audience we've built a good community
out of this get a lot of good
interaction here so i do feel like i may
be qualified to talk about starting a
podcast starting a podcast can be
very difficult or it could be very easy
it depends on how you want to make it
the one thing that i hear people say
about their podcast is they're going to
start it when or once i get this ready
i'm going to start it my advice is just
start it it is never going to be the
perfect time the podcast is never going
to be perfect you're never going to have
the perfect time to start a podcast the
perfect time to start a podcast is right
now because if you put in my opinion
if you put too much production into it
too much thought into it make it too big
of a production it puts too much
pressure on you and it won't it'll never
meet your standards this podcast i've
done
750-something episodes none of them have
been perfect but they've all come out
they've all served their purpose they're
all viewable listenable enjoyable they
all get a lot of good reaction it's
never going to be the perfect time the
perfect time is now since it's not
perfect you'll capture the moment
whatever the podcast is about there
needs to be a moment that is captured
you guys know kind of what's going on in
my life you know what's going on in my
greenhouse you know what's happening in
my grow you know small details about my
life because i share them here on the
podcast and you can capture the moment
here with me that is what's important so
don't make it too perfect i've done
754 episodes i don't feel any of them
were perfect but all of them were
perfect so don't wait for the perfect
episode don't wait for the perfect time
capture the moment i talked about making
making it hard or making it easy
one of the first things about a podcast
i guess is you need an idea what is the
show about you've got to talk about
something it's got to be something
you're at least passionate about
something you're educated about or
curious about or something that people
will want to hear you talk about what or
what is your topic if you're asking this
question you've probably already got an
idea
go with it if you are thinking about it
that means that there needs to be that
podcast if you want to start it there
are probably people out there that want
to listen to it so have an idea then
you'll need equipment um it doesn't take
a lot to get your idea from your brain
to your mouth into a microphone and onto
the internet it just takes a microphone
some sort of a usb recording device and
possibly some editing software and a
computer but some of that isn't even
necessary you could you could record
directly into your iphone you could open
up a voice app into your iphone and talk
into that and say what you have to say
and then send that file directly to a
website and have it posted to the
internet as a podcast you could take a
moment and edit that file if you wanted
or you could just send it up raw that's
called live the drive if you just talk
and then don't even edit don't do
anything to shine it up send it right
out to the world that is live to drive
that is possible if you want to be more
critical this show is well edited i use
a camera i use a microphone i record
simultaneously i match the files
together
using final cut pro then i edit them i
put stuff in it i make it look fancy it
can be as difficult or as simple as you
want it to be you need a microphone the
better the microphone obviously the
better the quality of the sound i am
using a shure sm7b this is one of the
top microphones available for
broadcasting for podcasting this is a
really great mic also it is not the
cheapest mic on the planet there are
many more
uh much more affordable microphones
available that will work for you as a
podcaster like i said you can use your
iphone you can use a little handheld
voice recorder you can get a good
microphone then if you get a sm7b you
need another piece just to power the mic
i've got a cloud lifter over here that
provides power for the microphone
because it needs some sort of juice you
can get as technical as you want to get
this microphone does not plug into my
computer directly my computer is not
here i don't need the macbook or any
sort of mac devices at this time i'm
running into a zoom pod track p4 so i'm
doing the sm7b into a cloud lifter into
the zoom p4 i'm capturing the audio file
on the p4
that is all you need if you want to do
an audio podcast that would be more than
enough to do an audio podcast when i'm
done i would if i were just to do that
when i were done i would take the file
from the zoom dump it into a computer
and edit it from there and then post it
to the website the rss feed however that
works that's a whole nother topic but
what i'm doing i'm doing another step
don't let me confuse you don't let me
overrun you i'm just letting you know
kind of what i do and giving you options
i go sm7b to the cloud lifter to the
zoom device i get the sound dialed in in
the zoom device then i use a headphone
out so i've got headphone one comes to
me headphone two is the uh small jack
going directly out into the input of the
camera so i've got a camera in front of
me i'm using the sony a7 iii is what i
think that one's called i can't see the
label i'm looking at the front face of
the camera can't see it great camera
camera one is awesome camera two can eat
my ass that thing only works half the
time can't figure it out uh but i'm
running it the headphone directly into
the input the mic input of the camera so
i'm getting straight from the zoom
device onto the same file my file is
synced up my audio and video are synced
i don't unless i make a mistake i don't
have to go into final cut pro and sync
them manually although i am recording
here on the zoom p4 audio format just as
a backup plan if this audio file on the
camera does go wrong i've at least got
the audio recording uh if the video
fails i don't do a second camera right
now because camera two was really
pissing me off to tell you the truth and
it made the file much larger to load to
youtube and it took too long
but i do have a backup of the audio if
the audio fails i've got that i'm
recording it twice on two different
formats so um
i go microphone cloud lifter usb device
then to the camera you could do a
microphone that links
excuse me you could do a microphone that
directly links via usb to your computer
and save a couple of steps but then you
need the computer to record all the time
i catch myself being distracted by the
graph on the computer and all the data
that the computer gives me i want to
play with the computer i end up staring
into it so i've kind of eliminated the
computer from my recording mix if i were
only producing if i were the producer
paying attention to the show and sound
levels and there were multiple people
with headphones and mics i would have a
computer in front of me so where i could
monitor the mix and if somebody got too
far from the mic i could say hey bro can
you lean into that mic so we can hear
you but i'm producing recording i'm
doing it all i'm talking i'm hosting
doing it all so i can't have so many
distractions but um so you need an idea
let's recap you need an idea what is the
show about is it about boats and hoes it
is about is it about cars and coffee is
it about weed and whiskey is it about
growing dope is it about playing guitar
is it about sneakers is there a sneaker
podcast out there ah there are a lot of
great podcasts what's your show about so
you need an idea then you need a
creative name all the podcasts need a
real cool name then you need equipment
obviously you need a microphone your
iphone would work something to get your
voice into a digital format that's
either a usb device a computer um that's
the the basics of it i like again i go
from the mic to the cloud lifter to a
usb interface and that goes to the
camera most of the time that would go to
a computer and you'd record it onto the
computer or a drive on the usb device
then you can edit it in software from
there then it's got to go to an rss feed
which you can create that using uh there
are a lot of ways to do it i've built my
own website and put my rss feed in my
own website it's much easier that way
for me
because i've got the website for some
people you don't have a website you may
want to use an rss hosting service
libsyn is great libsyn is short for
liberated syndicate so it's just lib syn
there are a couple other out other
services out there that would work for
you nobody pays me i don't get any
advertising fees or any sponsorships i
know that libsyn is a good product all
right so you're going to need gear an
idea then you're going to need a an rss
feed something about the gear i keep
talking about equipment and kind of
getting i don't want to be too specific
about the gear that you should buy it's
kind of about your budget and what works
for you there are a couple things to
think about
i come from the music industry i used to
work at guitar center i saw plenty of
people buy guitars for their kids they
were never going to make their kids
excited about playing music because no
matter what you do to that guitar it's
going to sound like a [ __ ] box with
strings on it it's a piece of wood with
strings to make kids think they got a
guitar to do parents into giving guitar
center 100 bucks never going to work out
well for you the kid's going to hate it
if they would have spent 250 on a guitar
they could have got a guitar that sounds
[ __ ] good every time they play it
that kid would be playing guitar every
day and be excited about it so get
equipment that is not the cheapest get
something that inspires you to use it
something that makes you sound good also
get equipment that you can use there are
a lot of buttons a lot of knobs a lot of
toys when you get into podcasting i
don't know
your technical abilities or limitations
or experience i don't know anything
about you right now so i'm just politely
saying get the gear that works for your
ability because uh you can definitely
out gear yourself i did it when i moved
up from
the video format or the audio format to
the video format that was a learning
curve i out geared myself
my computer said oh you're going to put
videos into me you got to get a new
computer so i got a new computer and
then i realized oh this is really easy
to edit this i want to get a 4k camera i
got a 4k camera and the computer is like
nope got to upgrade one more time so i
had to upgrade again ah there was a huge
learning curve learning to sync two
videos together and get the audio and
everything right that was a learning
curve so get the gear
that is within your technical abilities
don't out gear yourself that is
something that i see musicians
podcasters men we like to just [ __ ]
out gear ourselves if we've made a
couple of bucks this month and we got
into a new hobby you can guarantee i'm
gonna buy something [ __ ] ridiculous
to go with my new hobby i don't just
want cupcakes i want cupcakes with
[ __ ] sprinkles if i'm doing cupcakes
all right so get an idea get good
equipment get an rss feed get equipment
that you can afford but is good
equipment that is not cheap equipment
that inspires you to work but is also
not too confusing for you
then the hardest part for some people is
just sit down and [ __ ] press record
if it's a solo podcast you've only got
to wait for you to get in the room i can
record uh to date full disclosure it is
6 40 p.m as i record right now the last
episode i recorded i think i completed
around three in the morning so i can
record whenever i want it's just me
chilling i've got a really weird
schedule with my life i fit in podcasts
when i feel i've got to be in the mood i
got to be in the zone uh if i'm tired if
i'm lazy the podcast won't be any good
so i wait till i'm
uppity i've had some food i've had some
smoke i've had some kombucha in my
bloodstream i'm going to feel good can
do a good podcast so um just do it if
you're solo sit down and do it if you've
got a way for other people that is one
of the hardest things about podcasting
is getting one two or three other people
to join you for the show unless there's
advertising money or some sort of
commitment on the line it's really hard
to get people there so the hardest part
is just go make an outline for episode
one make an outline for episode two make
an outline for episode three hit record
and bang out episode one maybe
if you really want to i wouldn't even do
it record episode zero
put on the cameras put on the
microphones and just talk for 30 minutes
with your friends see what it's like and
then take notes as you're doing it um
the guy on mic one talks too much the
guy on mic three is too quiet the girl
on mic 4 we can barely hear her because
we got to turn up her microphone the
camera wasn't picking up the guest in
chair number three just
write down the things you're noticing
for episode zero and then everybody
watch episode zero together and then you
have an idea what you do and do not want
to do i like episode one just do episode
one and put it out then you've got
documentation of where the show was in
the beginning this show is nothing like
what it was in episode one we have come
i have come so far that's a totally
different podcast uh my approach my
delivery my editing everything is way
different and i am slightly embarrassed
of episode one but also that's where we
were at that time it's a time capsule i
could easily take it off the internet
but why that's what i said that's what
we did that's how it was it is there so
just press record just go the hardest
part of starting a podcast is starting i
know so many people that have the idea
they've drawn the logo they've built the
rss feed they got the [ __ ] 600
microphone sitting on the table they've
got everything they've played around
they've done sound check but they've
never sat down and said hi i'm ross to
jeff this is my podcast this is what
it's going to be about join me there's
going to be a lot of growth and a lot of
progression through this time of
developing this podcast and i hope that
you're here from the beginning all the
way until the end whenever that may be
tell your friends if you're interested
in this show we'd love to hear from you
then start saying what you've got to say
the first couple episodes are going to
feel [ __ ] weird they're going to come
out terribly but guess what you've got
infinite episodes to improve and your
audience will come along with you if
you've listened to the show you are a
patreon contributor a patreon a patron
you see the community that we have
developed along with this podcast
if i post a youtube video and somebody
doesn't like something i said in there
and they attack me i sit back and laugh
because all of my social media followers
all of my youtube supporters all of the
irie army all of the podcast listeners
they roast the person who tried to bash
me and i don't even have to say anything
that is the type of community that we
have built and all it took was
consecutive reliable episodes that are
real they're from my heart like i said a
moment ago i don't record a show that
i'm not feeling if i'm not feeling it i
just won't do it i'll wait uh i make my
own schedule i know there's a timeline
for the show i know there are deadlines
and sometimes i don't work until there's
pressure the show comes out monday and
thursday sometimes it's [ __ ]
wednesday night and i'm like oh i gotta
record right now and i get the show out
and it's beautiful
but love it love what you do do what you
love make it a podcast about what you
enjoy um start talking get it out there
share that community build the community
then the next note on my paper here is
build an audience and interact with them
build a social media following that goes
along with your podcast do as much as
you can to interact with the people that
make your show successful
you can do what you can do to make the
show great you can produce it write it
edit it put it out there spam it
everywhere but it's up to the audience
to make it successful they've got to
enjoy it they've got to share it they've
got to listen to it they've got to tell
their friends they've got to find some
sort of value in that show so advertise
the show share it to your community
interact with your community
i interact i try to interact there are
so many of you and one of me i know that
sounds egotistical or whatever but
there's just one of me and i get a
thousand messages a day i try you guys i
try but do your best to interact with
your community i try to address you guys
via patreon here social media i try but
i'm really spread thin lately and uh
it's it's not gonna ease up which is a
good thing when things are busy that
means business is successful when it
slows down i start freaking out so
um advertise your stuff um find ways to
advertise your podcast social media is
free it's the best uh find certain
niches what is your podcast about is it
underwater basket weaving is that
medieval
shield making is it [ __ ] tattoos and
tattoos are cool by themselves
an audio podcast about tattoos would be
awkward though anyway what is your
podcast about let's say your podcast is
about tattoos advertise in a tattoo
magazine if that's what you want to do
go where the tattoo people are then find
the fringe of where the tattoo people
are where also are they they're in pop
culture they're in the motorcycle world
they're in the fashion world they're in
the hair world that the barber shop you
could advertise your tattoo podcast
think about other ways to advertise and
get out of your bubble but also include
your bubble because you want your crowd
to be your crowd so get an idea get some
gear create an rss feed then press
[ __ ] record and start going
it's gonna feel weird i know i've said
that before i still hate editing my own
podcast i it bugs me to just sit there
and listen to me for 30 minutes i've
already said all this [ __ ] once i don't
want to listen to it again and make sure
i got it right but i have to so you'll
get used to hearing your own voice it'll
drive you crazy but just accept it other
people are gonna like it it's okay
they've been listening to you to talk
your whole life it will be okay press
record then put the show up on the
internet and wait just let people
respond let them react then consistently
and reliably put out your episodes on a
schedule that is really important in my
opinion my people know that monday and
thursday there's a show if the show
isn't there i get messages they're
waiting they're hungry they're relying
on me you'll begin to manifest
relationships with your audience and
you'll start remembering people when
they start emailing you and messaging
you you'll know who they are so get some
gear get an rss feed press record say
what you've got to say edit it to make
it feel good if you want to post it up
to the internet and wait to see what the
world says then when the world bashes
you don't be surprised because the
internet is a big old hater think about
this when you go to a restaurant how
often do you tell the staff
this food was perfect everything was
what i ordered it was great you don't
really say that but if something one
little thing was wrong you'll [ __ ]
make sure to tell them i ordered this i
got this i'm not happy the internet is
that times 20.
if somebody's happy they'll go i'm happy
they might click like on your video
maybe if you're really lucky come on
guys click like for me please maybe if
they loved the [ __ ] out of your video
maybe they'll click like if you really
touch their lives maybe they'll
subscribe if you said one second of one
word wrong watch your comment section
because you're [ __ ] that's just the
way the internet works so develop a
thick skin you've got to have thick skin
when it comes to the internet another
thing i want to touch on is something
called imposter syndrome
somewhere in the along the line of your
podcasting career you will think to
yourself why am i podcasting about my
chosen topic who do i think i am am i am
i weed wizard of oz am i weed jesus am i
cannabis christ i'm just ross to jeff
i'm just some dude growing weed why
would anybody want to listen to me why
am i doing this i'm embarrassed i feel
weird but then i remember
oh i do this because i'm [ __ ]
passionate about it i care about this i
want other people to be able to grow as
good of herb as i can so they can
medicate or recreate as comfortably and
often as i'm able to i want to cut
people's cost of medication down i want
to improve the quality of their medicine
my overall goal is to have people
growing better weeds so we can all smoke
better we to
improve the overall quality of all of
our lives so i remember that and i go
that's why you're doing the [ __ ]
podcast no matter what the internet says
but no matter what the trolls say i'm
doing what i'm setting out to do and i
know that i'm successful because you
guys are sending me messages you're
sending me patreon support you're just
sending me love and praise so impostor
syndrome will kick in don't let it get
to you don't let impostor syndrome win
it'll come in it just kicks in one day
it's usually around episode 5 or episode
30. you'll start going oh what am i
doing why am i doing this push through
the imposter syndrome you're doing this
because you are the one to do this you
chose to do this whatever you believe in
chose you to be the spokesperson for
this you guys know what i believe and i
call myself rasta jeff they call me ross
to jeff i believe the most i jaw has
called me and asks me politely to teach
you guys how to grow cannabis if i
didn't
use this gift that i've got i've got the
gift to
read a paper and get some instructions
and then go apply that in my grow room
and make the paper into useful data
because what it says on paper is often
good theory but in practice in the grow
room it doesn't [ __ ] work
the books are written by people who've
never grown the weed they've only talked
about it and read about it and been to
college they've never been in the grow
room i've been in there so i read the
book i went in the grow room and i'm
able to take my reading and my hands on
and i can spit it back out in a way that
most people can enjoy and absorb and
learn from it if i didn't do that if i
didn't put that gift back out to the
world i feel it would be disrespectful
to whatever you believe in you know what
i believe in i'm not judgmental on what
you believe in i agree with you we just
call it by a different name bro whatever
you believe in gave us both this desire
to do a podcast so do it put it out
there for the people do it from your
heart i always say grow from your heart
breed with love bro podcast from your
heart speak with love get that message
out there and it will work all right i
wanted to do another message in this
show but the message i've got is going
to be very long and i feel like i
rambled for long enough about how to
start a podcast that is going to be it
for this episode my buddy orville thank
you for the great question i hope i
inspired somebody out there to start a
podcast if you've got any follow-up
questions if you've got any corrections
concerns or if you need more info i
would love to hear from you check me out
on patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart of course the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
everything else is on the website at
iriegenetics.com there's a link to i
redirect where you could get your
discounted packs there's a link to the
web store where you can get your irie
genetics t-shirts there will be new
merch coming very soon also check out
the website that's what i'm saying join
us on the website all the cool kids are
doing it why wouldn't you that is all
i've got for this episode i'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content i want to give a big shout out
to my buddy billy bong smoking and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Applause]