[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode
755 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode we're going to talk
about integrated pest management before
i get to that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend quasi let's send
a big thank you shout out to spherical
glassworks let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to g7 i want to send
a big thank you shout out to one of my
favorite testers my buddy levity love
day let's send a big thank you shout out
to kes burton let's send a thank you
shout out to the hardest working man in
cannabis my buddy james brown let's send
a big thank you shout out to turt
burglar i want to send a thank you shout
out to frugal rock let's send a big
thank you shout out to indica chris
let's send a big fist bump to brohan 78
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to stoner dave big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include that link in
the show notes and in the video
description to make it super easy for
all of my friends to support the show on
patreon before we get too far let me
remind you that we are approaching the
4th of july here in my neighborhood we
play a game which i like to call gun
shots or fireworks
quite often we hear some bang some boom
some pops and at this time of year you
just wonder was that gunshots or
fireworks and you place your bets
oftentimes you never find out who's the
winner or not my point is if you hear
some bang some pops and booms play along
try to decide with me were those
gunshots or fireworks you never know
around here now is the time when i do
want to invite you to the dude grows
growers cup that's right the dgc growers
cup is coming to fort collins july 30th
from 2 p.m to 8 p.m and somewhere right
outside of fort collins i do look
forward to seeing you your crew your
smoke buddies at the dgc growers cup
join team irie genetics join a bunch of
other great breeders join the ire army
the dgc crew at the dgc growers cup july
30th just outside of fort collins for
all the info all of the links all the
details all the tickets you may need
will be at
dudegrows.com go check them out let them
know that rosta jeff sent you i do look
forward to seeing you at the dude grows
growers cup event i will be there with a
bunch of great beans available come say
hi come take a selfie come give me a
fist bump come chat come hang out it
will be a long day i may be busy
sometimes but if there's a break come
shake my hand come give me a fist bump
come introduce yourself come share some
of your fine flowers i would love to see
what you're doing all right let's move
on i do have a lot to talk about in this
podcast i've got an email here in front
of me
which i get very often i don't answer
this question enough because this is a
big podcast so i did put this one
together for you the question is very
simple it says i have a spidermite
problem i could read you a lot more of
the email but i think that gets us right
to the point let's jump into something
that is very important for any cannabis
grower of any level if you're brand new
at growing if you're experienced it
growing if you're somewhere in between
there integrated pest management is
something that should be on your radar
on your mind in your standard operating
procedures that should be part of your
method part of the method to your
madness we are going to get invaded by
bugs at some point you may have not
gotten bugs at this point i'm going to
knock on wood for you and hope that you
don't get them but the chances are
someday you're going to get bugs and i
would like you to be prepared understand
how to eradicate them also understand
how to prevent them so let's get into an
integrated pest management podcast the
main question is about spider mites but
with any pest any bug
um almost most problems in life i like
to say set yourself up for success when
it comes to bugs spider mites thrips
fungus gnats almost any pest we can
think of prevention is key if we can
prevent them from getting in there have
some sort of security system in place a
standard operating procedure that will
make things a lot easier so if you're
not already doing some sort of
preventative program to make sure the
bugs don't come now may be a good time
to start thinking about it think about
it this way when [ __ ] goes down would
you rather have security guards there
waiting to break up the rumble the might
battle the might orgy because that's
what's going to happen it's going to be
a mite picnic and then a mite orgy do
you want security guards there already
those security guards could be either a
spray application or those security
guards could be other beneficial insects
but would you rather have security on
standby or would you have to rather have
to call the cops and wait for them to
show up which could be for you to spot
the problem and then start applying a
pesticide or maybe even to have to order
the predator bugs from an insectiary
wait for them to come distribute them
wait for them to develop population and
start eradicating your bugs prevention
is key i would rather have security on
hand i don't want to have to wait for
those bugs or sprays to arrive so
prevention is key what are you doing in
your room to make sure that no bugs get
into your room there are a lot of things
you can do if you've got cracks in the
walls seal those cracks up with some
caulk if you've got a window or
something where things can get in get
some tape over that get some sort of
sealer think of all the ins and outs in
your grow space and seal all of that
stuff up keep in mind it gets cold
outside it gets hot outside in your grow
room that's the most perfect environment
for most of the bugs that we're gonna
face that's why they thrive so well in
our grow room we're providing the
perfect temperature the perfect vpd we
give water at a very specific interval
and the bugs love that rhythm if the
plants are happy the bugs are probably
happy as well so it's outside the bugs
can feel and sense that there's warmth
in that other room they can smell those
great terps in that other room and
they're like hey guys it's cold and
shitty we're out here living in a
[ __ ] rose bush let's go party in
there where the weed plants are and all
the spider mites just find one little
crack in the wall one little gap in the
window they congregate into your weed
plants where it's [ __ ] beautiful it's
jamaica and they're all day long you got
it at just the right temp just the right
vpd they go make a little hammock up on
one of your plants they start eating
then they start breeding then they take
over so they know that it's there let's
prevent them from coming in let's think
about ways that these bugs get into our
grows a lot of times like i just
mentioned they come in through the
cracks in the walls sometimes they're
already there many of these bugs are
very common if there are plants around
they're already there but how do they
get into the grow if they're not already
in the space a lot of times they will
come
in your soil many people blame a
specific brand of soil or soilless mix
for having bugs in it
every brand can have bugs in it i don't
care if it's ocean forest i don't care
if it's pro mix i don't care if it's
roots organics
all of those bags of dirt have the
potential to have bugs in them i've
gotten bugs in every bag of dirt every
brand there's been no brand that has
been bug free let's talk about this
people claim i bought ocean forest and
got bugs in it i bought roots 707 it got
bugs in it i bought the other brand
whatever it is it doesn't matter yes of
course there's bugs in there it's
[ __ ] soil it's soilless mix it's dirt
it's very desirable for bugs also it is
made stored and kept in a place where
those bugs are very readily available
you can't blame any specific brand for
giving you bugs
all of the bags of soil are kept and
most of them are made very near each
other then they're sent to a warehouse
they're all kept in a warehouse together
do you think the bugs go hey let's just
go into this one bag let's just the bugs
are not brand loyal is what i'm trying
to say they don't care about they can't
see the cool coloring on the roots or on
the fox farms bag they don't know those
fish are even printed there those bugs
go wherever they can go to find a party
to get some warmth to get some food they
want to eat and they want to breed just
like you they're going to go into every
bag that's available you just bought a
bag that had bugs in it and it happened
to be whichever brand you chose so if
you've gotten a bag of soil that had
bugs in it it wasn't the maker of that
soil's fault that soil went to a
warehouse it stayed in a warehouse
possibly outdoors there's a very popular
grow supply center in colorado springs
they keep all of their soil outdoors if
there's there are bugs in one bag
they're going in every bag they're gonna
overload that one bag all the food all
the hiding places the hotel will be
booked they're gonna go somewhere else
which is the next bag over it may be a
different brand it may be the same brand
all the brands are gonna get bugs they
get transferred and the same trucks
the roots organics the fox farms the
tuper the [ __ ] everything it came on
the same truck why wouldn't the bugs
travel from bag to bag so don't blame
any specific brand for getting bugs into
your grow that is your responsibility as
the farmer as the lead grower as the
head cultivator as the head [ __ ]
in charge it is your responsibility to
make sure that bugs don't make it into
your grow inspect the soil treat it with
the pesticide treat it with the
uh
treat it with a predator bug if that's
what you've got to do but be
preventative inspect your soil it is
your job to make sure that doesn't get
in there treat everything like there is
bugs there are bugs on everything that
comes in there's bugs in the soil let's
talk about the next way they come in
they come in on plants are you bringing
in clones are you getting cuttings from
a friend that is a great way to bring in
bugs
all of your friends are going to say
dude my grow is clean i don't have
anything the person that claims to have
the cleanest grow is usually the person
with the worst bugs they just haven't
found them yet so when you get a clone
or a plant or a cutting from a friend to
make sure it is treated that's the best
way to bring unwanted bugs into your
grow room all right here's a side note
that i'm going to totally derail my
train of thought and try to throw this
in it's not on my notes but i just
thought about this we build very nice
grow rooms indoors we put really good
lights in there we put ducting in there
we clean everything up hopefully
hopefully you're cleaning your grow
space clean that [ __ ] up dude i'm
talking to myself too we build these
really nice controlled environments i do
not find it wise i would not recommend
to move our ganja plants that we have in
our indoor area outdoors for sunshine
during the day and then back inside i
would not recommend that if that is
something you choose to do if that's
your main strategy that's cool but if
that is your main grow space where you
mainly intend to have the plants indoors
i wouldn't contaminate it with the
outdoor plants the minute you put those
plants outdoors they're gonna get
trespassers they're gonna get stowaways
you're going to bring them into your
grow space they're going to find places
to hide in there it's jamaica like we
talked about earlier it's perfect
environment in there some of the bugs
might hop off that plant and stay in the
room the next time you carry that plant
outside so now you've kind of
contaminated that indoor grill with
outdoor bugs you just brought the bugs
in the reason we really built that room
was to isolate everything and keep that
plant safe from all of those outdoor
bugs we've got a perfect room in there
so i don't recommend moving your plants
from indoors to outdoors that is not and
then back in that's not something i
would recommend have indoor plants or
have outdoor plants i understand you're
going to do light depth and some [ __ ]
like that is going to happen but my
general recommendation is if you've
built a nice indoor grow room have a
nice indoor grow room that you've never
contaminated with those outdoor plants
what i was getting to before that i want
to get back on track is when you get new
plants new clones from a friend make
sure you isolate those plants don't take
those right into general population you
can put if you get a clone a small plant
you can put it in the windowsill for a
couple of days take it out of the window
treat it with whatever pesticide you
choose to use something i use something
strong when [ __ ] comes in if i get a cut
from anybody if it was from one of my
best friends if it was from my mama if
it's from my girlfriend or a complete
stranger i'm going to treat that clone
the same it's contaminated in my mind it
is contaminated it's got mites thrips
spider fungus gnats powdery mildew it's
got herpes it's got all this [ __ ] you
could imagine i'm gonna treat it and
keep it away from my plants for seven to
ten days until i'm sure that that plant
is clear then it gets to go into general
population i cannot risk bringing [ __ ]
in and destroying a grow i got spider
mites from a very reputable grower and
they were the most ferocious [ __ ]
spider mites i've ever seen they did
some damage slowed me down we recovered
however they did [ __ ] me up i learned my
lesson there i talk about mistakes i've
made
trusting a very reputable popular grower
[ __ ] me over i got a clone that was
riddled with mites i brought it right in
and before i noticed we're [ __ ] all
right we're talking about how bugs come
in bugs come in on
you the soil they make it in in the soil
bugs come in and other plants bugs also
come in on you your clothing your shoes
your dreadlocks yes i'm holding up my
own dreadlocks i'm guilty i'm talking
about it myself my dreads go to my
calves you guys i don't know if you've
seen recent pictures i posted on the
gram
my dreadlocks i'm six foot five i'm six
foot five tall and my dreadlocks touch
my calves i got quite a bit of hair i do
have a dedicated grow area hat i keep
the dreads tied up
try to keep the just trying to mitigate
problems there but you do bring you
travel the bugs around through your
shoes your pants your shirt your
dreadlocks your long hair whatever you
may be wearing that's a great way to
move bugs around also we've talked about
it before the dog will bring bugs into
your grow room i don't prefer to have
the dog in there that's man's best
friend but be my best friend upstairs
we'll hang out in the backyard stay out
of my grow space
so the bugs make it in in a variety of
ways it is our responsibility to
minimize those ways for those bugs to
get in it's your responsibility like i
said it's we're farmers we're growing an
agricultural product we've got to keep a
farmer's mindset in mind and that means
we're battling pests and insects at all
times
unfortunately some of the pests that we
are battling are nearly or are actually
microscopic so we can't even see them so
we've got to pay attention to the plants
we've got to keep a good eye on the
garden and see what that garden is
telling us and be ready to react as soon
as we see a problem based on an insect
now the reaction part is where people
really mess up they see a small problem
and they want to do something freaking
crazy to solve that problem and they
overkill the small problem and cause a
bigger bigger problem by panic mode i
talk about panic mode grower panic mode
you see that little issue and you've got
your plants are at risk and now you just
[ __ ] everything up because you went into
panic mode and didn't think things
through
think about what you're going to do when
you get those pests start thinking now
how nuclear do i want to go how gentle
do i want to go how abrasive or toxic do
i want to be with the pesticides which i
choose to use that is up to you i will
make recommendations i'll give you
product names but
i do not judge you
based on the pesticides you choose to
use in your garden i do judge you if you
use a product too late in the fl on the
flowering stage or in flowering stage
and there are residual chemicals left
behind that can cause harm to a consumer
i will judge you for that
if you use a pesticide correctly and
properly at the right interval duration
dilution application rate you're safe
about it i will not judge you for any
product you choose to use if you're
doing it safely and correctly that's
what the products are for that's what
we're we've got a goal we've got a
product to protect i understand but it
is your uh your prerogative how toxic
how gentle how what what products you
want to use some things are pretty
[ __ ] rough some things are really
fluffy and gentle people want to stick
to the word organic i always say
remember that cyanide is organic and
just a couple of drops of that will kill
you so don't let the word organic be too
much of a buzzword when it comes to pest
eradication just because a product is
organic
doesn't mean that it is safer less
harmful to a human body less harmful to
the environment than a product that
doesn't have an organic stamp on it also
with that same thing being said
an organic product
does not have to be considered less
effective than a non-organic product for
the right situation that organic product
may wipe out your [ __ ] problem on the
same
in the same battlefield in a different
situation that non-organic product may
be exactly what you need it's all about
situation it's all about understanding
it's all about the pest you're trying to
attack a lot of it is based on the phase
of growth which these plants are in i
want to get back to where i was it is up
to you to decide the level of
abrasiveness toxicity how powerful how
potent you want to go with your
pesticides do your research on the
products you are thinking about using
read the msds sheets see what's in there
read the active ingredient read
is it toxic is it poisonous what does it
do to the environment read about that
product do you want to spray that on
flowers that you're going to consume
if you're the only one consuming it
spray whatever the [ __ ] you feel you're
safe with doing if you're going to give
it to other people keep them in mind
spray something that is safer maybe
stick with something with a shorter
half-life something um let's talk about
half-life somebody asked me about this
in an instagram live feed lately
recently
half-life when i spray a product over a
certain duration it is going to break
down 50 and that product will not be
available on the plants anymore it ah i
don't know the exact science it
biodegrades it breaks down it disappears
uh the sun breaks it down the wind
breaks it down the rain breaks it down
the the availability of that product on
the plants
dilutes dissipates again i'm not
completely qualified to teach this but
i'll teach you the way that i know it
when you spray that product on there
it's a hundred percent over a certain
amount of time it breaks down to 50
percent then over at that time again it
breaks down to 25 percent then over time
you get 12 and a half percent then over
time again you get 6.25 then eventually
down to 3.12 percent keeps breaking
half-life understand the half-life of
the product you are using also
understand the re-entry interval of the
product you are using that is when you
apply a product in a grow space how long
do you have to wait to safely enter that
grow space again now i want to group
these two things together
take your half-life and your re-entry
interval and if you're growing indoors
increase those drastically because in an
outdoor environment we've got the sun
the sun will break down those chemicals
those products those agents the
ingredients in the pesticide spray and
they won't last as long on the plant
they will disappear they'll be gone
basically in a shorter amount of time
because like i said earlier the wind the
sun the rain those things get rid of
those products indoors we've got caustic
grow lights that are nowhere near as
powerful as the sun they're not breaking
the chemicals down as quickly so they
will be there longer we don't have the
same ventilation indoors so your
half-life and your re-entry interval
basically need to be doubled indoors
some people aren't going to follow that
some people think i'm crazy
as somebody who is trained by the
colorado department of agriculture it's
my responsibility to make sure i say it
what you do with that info is up to you
you're a grown-ass [ __ ] adult have
fun do your thing pimpin all right the
next thing i want to talk about i'm
going out of order on my notes here but
i feel like this is very important um
protective personal equipment ppe
personal protective equipment i don't
know what order i set it in the first
time but protect your protect yourself
with the proper personal protective
equipment you guys when you buy a
pesticide there's a little booklet on
the side of the bottle that's not a
story about the guy that made the
pesticide that's not a comic book that
is actually the instructions and a bunch
of tips about that product it will tell
you if that product is if you can drink
it it'll tell you if it's dangerous
it'll tell you if it's toxic it'll tell
you if it'll [ __ ] kill you it will
tell you the personal protective
equipment that is recommended for that
product most of the time they're going
to want you to wear six millimeter or
thick is it millimeter or milliliter
millimeters these are solids milliliters
or liquids you want six millimeter or
thicker nitrile gloves most pesticides
are going to ask you to wear long
sleeves we don't want you to get any
pesticide on your skin most of the time
pants cover your feet with shoes a lot
of the time they're going to want to
mask some sort of a respirator every
time we want some sort of eye protection
what you do from there will be probably
pesticide specific but
i recommend putting on the personal
protective equipment before you get the
pesticides
what if and i don't know where you work
i don't know where you grow but what if
the person that managed that pesticide
before you didn't put the lid on it all
the way and you just naturally grab it
the next move to do with the pesticide
is to give it a shake then measure some
out what if you're just moving doing
your thing you got joe rogan in your ear
maybe i'm in your ear jam in the podcast
you grab that bottle you give it a shake
if you or the person before you didn't
put that lid on all the way pesticide is
now flying out of that bottle if that
pesticide gets in your eye you could be
[ __ ] you could be really [ __ ] you
could have some big problems it's gonna
burn it's gonna suck but you could have
long term damage let's have our personal
protective equipment on before we even
touch the pesticides it sounds like
overkill which is what i want i want
overkill i want you to be safe i don't
want you to get sick i don't need you
contaminated i want you to live through
this we're growing cannabis let's not
get [ __ ] hurt growing cannabis we
want to smoke some urban chill out not
end up in the [ __ ] hospital so
personal protective equipment is very
important let me get back on track here
and keep my notes here
the products you decide are up to you
the applications you decide to use are
up to you many people will choose to use
predator insects if that's what you
choose to do that is up to you it's all
up to what you want to do in your grow
that's one of the best parts about
growing weed you get to s to decide what
you want to do one important thing
though is monitoring that grow and
keeping an eye out for bugs how are you
going to know if bugs there are there
are you scouting personally do you have
a crew scouting occasionally do you walk
in and just blindly grab it a leaf
occasionally i don't even know what
plant i just touched i know i just go
right there and i took a leaf and i'm
going to inspect this leaf very
carefully i'm going to look at the top
of it i can tell a lot by the top uh no
powdery mildew it doesn't look like any
chew marks no thrip [ __ ] looks good flip
it over do i see any spider mites do i
see any fungus gnats do we see any white
flies if that leaf is cool probably
pretty good i won't pull another one i
don't need to i've seen all the info i
need but i will go in there sometimes
twice a day in my personal grow and just
give it a good scouting how does [ __ ]
look are there any bugs
one thing i want to talk about is
yellow sticky traps and the blue sticky
traps those little cards you guys like
to use i love them i highly recommend
them those are great products
however those are not any way to
eradicate or remove a bug what those are
there for is to show you that there is a
presence of a pest they do not do
anything to get rid of a bug a bug has
to land on that [ __ ] yellow card for
it to do anything how many of the bugs
do you think oh look a yellow car let's
jump right into it most of them don't do
that those are there to show you some of
the bugs that are in here were stupid
enough to fly onto the yellow car there
are probably a lot more and you should
think about it a lot of them come with
like a grid they've got squares printed
on there that's so that during the
morning you can count basically get a
good visual count how many bugs per
square there are two bugs per square
they're five bugs per square they're 20
per square we're really stepping our
[ __ ] up check again at lunch see how
many there are see over the day how many
bugs progress do you need to do
something about it or is it an
acceptable amount of bugs what's cool
with you a few fungus gnats and a big
grow that's fine a bunch of fungus gnats
and a small grow [ __ ] that we got to do
something it's up to you but those
yellow sticky traps are not any source
of eradication they are alerting their
notification it's not doing anything but
telling you there are bugs here
now let's talk a little bit about things
we can do
to get rid of and prevent pests and our
grow of course the fir some of the first
things we can do come with standard
standard operating procedures i guess
the first thing is building a proper
room seal that room up are all the gaps
from outside sealed or all the gaps from
the other room sealed are you clean when
you're going in do you have a standard
operating procedure do you have grow
room clothes do you have grow room shoes
do you have grow room a grow room hat
for your dreadlocks are you stepping on
one of those mats that's got the cleaner
in it to clean up your shoes do you put
on booties do you wear a scrub jacket to
go in there or a lab coat or scrubs to
go in there what are you doing to
prevent the bugs the next thing we can
do is i think defoliation is a great way
to minimize all of the problems in the
grow if we defoliate
i basically describe the leaves as like
hotels and hammocks for the plants it's
where the plants are chilling that's
houses and hotels they're on the leaves
they're not chilling out on the stocks
mostly maybe if you got a lot but
they're on the leaves if there aren't
too many leaves there aren't too many
places for bugs also that's less
opportunity for powdery mildew get that
[ __ ] out of there you don't need all
those leaves that's going to lead to
problems people say that the leaves are
the source of food and the solar panels
for the plants dude there are so many
leaves in there you could take some out
don't worry you don't have to worry
about the food we're feeding the [ __ ]
plants through the roots we're giving
them very expensive nutrients they're
eating and they're getting the best
light that they can take off some of
those leaves so the light can get to the
buds that you want to get big and fat
defoliate that will help you prevent bug
problems also turn up the fan i think if
you turn up some fans and have some
airflow in there the bugs don't want to
be around as much also one thing i will
notice though if the bugs do if the
spider mites start getting out of
control they use those fans as like um
it's kind of like a hang glider they
climb up to the top of the plant and
they catch the wind off the fan and they
drop a web
and they blow from this plant right over
to the next one they use the fan to do
it
so have the fan in there so that they
can't colonize they can't establish a
presence but once they do get present
you might want to slow down that fan to
keep them from traveling around
so
much now another thing we can do to
prevent some bugs is to just make an
undesirable environment for any bug that
may show up any pests that may come
around let me give a quick disclaimer 99
of what i'm going to tell you is going
to be for an indoor grow outdoor growing
is a whole new beast we'll touch on that
not very much now i said create an
undesirable environment for the bugs
i've said before that we're creating
jamaica in our grow space we've got the
perfect vpd the temp is great the
humidity is great just enough wind to
make it comfortable we don't disrupt it
there's no predators in there unless
you've introduced some so let's make an
environment that is undesirable for
these bugs maybe occasionally you can
just mist the plants with water they
don't like water a lot of the bugs don't
want to hang out if it's too humid
90 of our bugs are going to be on the
underside of the leaf the top of the
leaf you don't have to spray it they're
going to be on the bottom so come from
the underside of the plant with your
little mister with your spray bottle and
just start at the bottom and work your
way up under the plant lift up the
leaves as you go and spray the underside
make it undesirable if you want to add a
product you can put in some sort of
insecticidal soap or you can step up
your game and start actually using a
pesticide as a preventative there is no
problem and i highly recommend using a
spray application of pesticides on a
weekly basis to keep bugs at bay
so some of the first steps are to prep
the room the next step is to have a
standard operating procedure so that you
don't bring bugs in through the soil
through your plants or through your
clothes then we start creating an
undesirable environment for the bugs a
little bit of defoliation a little bit
of wind maybe some moisture on the
leaves maybe i recommend start applying
a foliar fed pest application some sort
of pesticide targeted for the bugs you
know you are going to get in your area
i would recommend doing preventative
sprays on a weekly basis rotate your
products then if you do see a pest
problem start to arise then increase the
interval the amount of sprays increase
the amount of spray that you put in the
mix then maybe start doing rotations of
a stronger pesticide more frequently
now i do recommend a rotation of
pesticides because these bugs will
develop a resistance to pesticides think
about if i walked in your grow space
every day and tapped you on the shoulder
and threw just a shitty left jab at you
by day three you're going to block that
left jab here go here comes the jab tap
you on the shoulder you're going to turn
on your block will already be up you'll
be ready to block my left jab no problem
if i came in there on day four tapped
you on the shoulder through a vicious
right cross you're not going to be ready
for that [ __ ] it's going to get you
we've got to do that to the spider mites
also they do learn they do start to
build up resistance they are
evolutionary creatures they will say oh
you sprayed evergreen on me three days
in a row watch this day four the bugs
that live from the first three days of
evergreen they're gonna lick their arm
and they'll go ah
evergreen and they're just gonna look at
you like they're [ __ ] crazy they're
gonna eat up the evergreen and get
stronger from it so i recommend a
rotation of products i will go through a
list of products that i do recommend
once again nobody pays me they're just
[ __ ] that [ __ ] that i know that works
let's talk about
some of the pests that you will
encounter in your indoor grow let me do
that disclaimer once again this is going
to be mostly indoors i'm an indoor
grower i do have a greenhouse a couple
of greenhouses what did i say that got
some greenhouses going but most of this
is indoor stuff what bugs are we going
to get indoors and our garden most
commonly we are going to see spider
mites the dreaded spider mites spider
mites are scary a lot of people think
they're a huge deal uh it's a [ __ ] up
situation depending on the stage of
growth which you are in but spider mites
are very easy to get rid of if you are
patient have a strategy and understand
what you are doing and you're not lazy
about it you cannot be lazy in the grow
the bugs will take over if you get lazy
they'll start [ __ ] challenging you
basically you're going to see the
two-spotted mite
the real problem is the russet might if
you've got russet mites that changes
everything
i do uh consulting my consultation
includes pest eradication in your grow
if you've got russet mites i do charge
you another level to get rid of those in
a commercial grow it's more expensive it
takes a lot more work it's a lot more
strategy a lot more cooperation from the
team so we've got spider mites uh
another thing you may see are thrips
people get scared of thrips people have
a lot it takes them a long time to
identify that it's actually a thrip
issue thrips are easy we can definitely
get rid of thrips aphids you may see
aphids in your grow aphids of all colors
aphids have become like [ __ ] skittles
they're every color now through
evolution and through
regional evolution i guess it is there
are aphids of every [ __ ] color you'll
see them they're not a big deal we can
get rid of those as well uh fungus gnats
are very common in a grow environment
those are very very easy to get rid of
not very problematic but they can lead
to other problems they can be
if you've got a small problem plus
fungus gnats those two together compound
a problem very well another common issue
is white flies a lot of people get white
flies indoors and outdoors those are
very easy to eradicate another big issue
that's not a bug per se but does happen
quite often is powdery mildew especially
here in colorado we get huge temperature
swings temperature spikes
last year in the winter we had negative
17 degree temperatures try keeping your
grow room warm inside with the wall
right here and then on the other side of
that wall it's [ __ ] negative 17
degrees there's snow packed up against
the walls and you're just trying to
balance the [ __ ] out in the rooms
there's condensation raining from the
[ __ ] ceiling it's very interesting at
that time of year we do get powdery
mildew from that show so be prepared
um let's talk about outdoor outdoors is
totally different you guys i am not
super experienced with the outdoor but
outdoor uh you may experience birds
birds could be problematic i've seen
birds steal buds just fly down and pinch
little pieces of the weed off the weed
plant all season long and just destroy
plants uh deer deer will come and eat
your whole [ __ ] plant i've seen bears
come i haven't seen them personally i've
seen instances where bears have come and
stolen plants from the grow
bunnies are notorious if you got too
many rabbits they'll eat the [ __ ] out of
your plants um in colorado we get these
caterpillars we get moths they land in
the plants they lay eggs and those turn
into these orange caterpillars those
things have [ __ ] ruined so many crops
of people that i know so you're gonna
get a lot of outdoor bugs
one though another thing we should think
about outdoors is thieves we get a lot
of thieves especially here in colorado
especially here in pueblo people love to
steal your outdoor weeds so if you're
gonna plant outdoor weed plant one for
the crook one for the bugs one for the
bunnies and then maybe you'll get one
for yourself also
i'm hoping you get the best i'm being
optimistic uh i've done a full episode
on bud washing if you do grow outdoors
your outdoor weed may be very dirty
there may be some bugs in there i've
done an episode on bud washing maybe
check out the bud washing episode that
may be a good episode for rinsing off
your outdoor weed a lot of people are
that's really controversial i think it's
a good show check that out i digress
let's get more into
integrated pest management we've talked
about the bugs that we're going to face
we're going to face spider mites thrips
aphids fungus gnats white flies possibly
powdery mildew there are other things
that a lot of the grow books talk about
that do pop up honestly mealy bugs and
scales and [ __ ] like that is a very very
uncommon i've been growing for a
thousand years it feels like i've never
seen a mealybug or a scale so
we're not going to worry too much about
that let's talk about now about options
on how to
get rid of these bugs we've talked about
ways to kind of prevent them let's talk
about ways to get rid of them i am a
commercial ganja grower i like to grow
in large warehouses with large plants
with a lot of toys the way that i prefer
in my method
to get rid of and prevent bugs is a
rotation of pesticide applications and a
spray method sprayed pesticide
applications are my favorite a lot of
people out there don't agree with that
they don't want to smoke pesticides they
don't want to smoke chemicals but
everything is chemicals if you
understand that and i understand that
you may not want to consume some
pesticides but we've got to do what
we've got to do to keep the bugs away to
protect our investment to make sure that
you were delivered a product and my job
as the lead cultivator the consultant
also somebody trained by the colorado
department of agriculture it's my job my
responsibility also somebody
who is highly passionate about cannabis
i'm not just a grower i'm not just a
breeder i love to smoke the root of all
of this it all started because i love to
smoke ganja i'm a cannabis consumer i'm
going to smoke everything that we grow
at my commercial facility so i keep that
in mind i'm also very passionate about
cannabis consumers and cannabis patients
i come from the medical marijuana side
of cannabis is where i got started i
want to make sure not to get anybody
sicker than they already are i don't
want to make anybody sick at all the
goal for my cannabis that i grow is for
people to feel better to have a better
quality of life after they consume the
product that i produced
so not only am i professionally and
ethically uh
responsible but i'm also personally and
passionately invested in making sure
that these products are safe so one of
my big jobs in the facility is to make
sure that we are safely ethically and
effectively using the correct products
at the correct time to get rid of bugs
but also not contaminate any of the
product to where it could be problematic
for anybody who may consume the buds the
edibles the concentrates anything that
comes out of my grow i am responsible
for that my name is on that product if
you look at the jar where the herb came
from it will tell you the number where
that product was produced here in
colorado and if you know the numbers and
you know the right facilities you know
who grew that [ __ ] you could say this
was a rosta jeff grill you can find it
and you can [ __ ] call me out and
blame me for whatever you need to blame
me for
so i know i do talk a lot about the
business side of commercially producing
cannabis it's a big investment it's a
lot of responsibility but please never
feel like i've forgotten about the
patience about the consumers about the
people that sparked this passion for
large-scale cannabis production in me i
grow cannabis to make people feel better
i breed cannabis to make people feel
better that is the overall goal of this
here i have not lost sight of that goal
i am involved in a lot of things i have
gone very far from the original route of
this project but i know that the
original
the whole mission the intent is to make
people feel better and i know that
giving you a pesticide on your product
is not going to make you feel better i
want you to live longer healthier
happier and i can't do that if i poison
you with the [ __ ] pesticide so one of
my big things is to make sure that we
are doing this ethically and responsibly
that is something i take good pride in
so i do talk about sprayed applications
a lot of people are not into the sprays
that is cool do your thing how are you
keeping the bugs away if you're not
using a sprayed application a lot of
people will choose to use predator
insects they get other bugs that do not
harm the plants but they do eat the bugs
that are there and the grow so you can
get things like lace wings
swarovskis persimilis hypoaspis miles
rove beetles assassin beetles things
like that and you buy them and they come
in the mail and you release them in the
grow and those will go and act just like
predators on the wild they'll eat all of
your [ __ ] spider mites all your
fungus gnats a lot of people do choose
to use ladybugs
let me talk about ladybugs briefly
i think they're lazy they're cool if
there's like bugs are right here a
ladybug may go over here and eat it but
if there's a bug over here and a ladybug
over here ladybug's not going anywhere
to [ __ ] eat it in my experience
you'll spend money on ladybugs you'll
release them into grow into the grow
you'll take a bunch of pictures because
they're gorgeous you'll find a couple
that are humping there's always ladybugs
humping uh you'll find them up on the
tops of the plants you'll take a great
bunch of great photos and you'll turn
off the lights and you'll go to your
business and you come in the next day
half the ladybugs will be dead they flew
into the [ __ ] light they flew into
the fan they flew into the blower
ladybugs are pretty but they are not the
smartest [ __ ] creature on the planet
they're suicidal they're kamikaze they
don't last very long they stink ah they
die they land on the floor and they
stink in my opinion that smell from the
dead ladybugs is terrible then you gotta
sweep them all up uh and it's kind of a
waste of money i would recommend a more
aggressive more effective predator ah
californicus swarsky that may be the
same thing they changed the names on
these bugs and i can't keep the latin
names all straight in my mind i order
them honestly and i can remember the
names that i order the swarovskis the
kookamarus the californicus the
hypoaspis miles green lacewings rove
beetles um what's the other one that i
said assassin beetles
those are all great predator beetles or
predator bugs but
just like a pesticide what i'm about to
say applies to predator insects and
pesticides you've got to have the
correct
eradication device for the correct
problem
if you go releasing the wrong bug for
the wrong bug they may never meet up but
if you know what you're what bugs you're
facing and you do the right research
you can find the correct bug to go in
there and get that bug right away the
problem is in my opinion with the
predator bugs is that you've got to
build up populations on the same hand it
does take time effort and energy to
spray a pesticide and that does do some
stress to the plants if you're letting
out bugs the plants barely know that
those bugs are there but it does take a
little while for that army to get out
there and start doing work so you've got
your toss up there you're 50 50. let's
talk about another way to get rid of
bugs in our grow
many people forget that a lot of the
bugs we face are not on the leaves of
the plant they actually live down in the
soil the cocoa the medium that's where
they go you may see them pop up
occasionally and show you that they're
there but they're living down in the
soil so a soil dredge is another very
effective way to get rid of many of the
bugs we face
oftentimes
if we've got a bug if it's thrips spider
mites fungus gnats white flies a lot of
the time my first reaction is to
defoliate let's just get rid of some of
these leaves clean up the bottoms take
off a bunch of leaves that's going to
help us out that's the first step then
the next step let's do a soil dredge of
the appropriate product if i've got
let's just say if i've got fungus gnats
i would use
15 to 30 milliliters of evergreen per
gallon of water as a soil dredge i would
run that right through the pot right
through the soil until i get a little
bit of runoff that way i know that all
that soil in there has now been poisoned
any fungus gnats in there are going to
get poisoned they're going to die
they're not going to want to live in
there now the next move i would spray
the plants with 15 to 30 milliliters per
gallon of evergreen it's down there in
the soil let's get it up top also that
way we killed everything if there are
bugs on the leaves they're going to run
to the soil looking for refuge guess
what poison down there if there are bugs
in the soil they're going to run up to
the leaves looking for refuge guess what
poison up there let's get them let's get
them on all levels let's not give them
anywhere to hide
and one thing i want to talk about is
fungus gnats those are there because
you're over watering if you stop over
watering the fungus gnats will stop
coming around so those should be easy to
get rid of fungus gnats quickly how do
you get rid of fungus gnats defoliate um
do a soil dredge of either i would just
say evergreen let's just start off right
with evergreen you could use azetrol as
a max but i think evergreen or pyganic
which is a very similar product reduce
the dosage of the pyganic though
give it a soil dredge defoliate soil
dredge foliar feed repeat in three days
fungus gnats are gone bro if you do it
right the fungus gnats will be gone
maybe repeat a third time the plants are
gonna look a little bit stressed if you
hit them with that much oil three times
but your [ __ ] bugs will be
gone all right where are we
um let's talk about what we can do
things are really
all right another thing we need to talk
about is what phase of growth are our
plants in if we're in veg we can do a
lot of things to the plants if you're
just starting to flower your options are
slimming out if you're in flower your
options for spray applications become
very thin keep in mind that people are
going to consume this we don't want to
put a product on here that is not going
to the half-life is not going to come up
by the time we consume this product so
keep that in mind you don't want to
taste it you don't want to smoke it you
definitely don't want it in your
concentrates
imagine if i sprayed something on your
buds and you taste it in the buds
imagine if i put those buds in a
extraction device of any kind we're
concentrating the pesticide that shitty
flavor as well your dabs are going to
taste 20 times worse than the flowers
taste so
think about the stage of growth you are
in and adjust your pesticide application
accordingly something i like to do in a
commercial grow i just said we focus on
spray applications yes as soon as i see
bud set guess what i do i release a [ __ ]
ton of predator bugs so i've got sprays
all the way up to about day 14 maybe day
20 then by day 21 i've got an army a
bunch of boxes of predator bugs to
release into the entire grow so i switch
it over to predators later in the season
so i start off my grow season with spray
applications once i get buds i do switch
over to the predator bugs then i have an
arrangement with the insecury we
basically set up a subscription service
to where those bugs come every week
every two weeks as needed until i tell
them that we have harvested then they
stop sending them they just show up in a
box that says live bugs i just start
putting them out as soon as they get
there build that population keep those
problem bugs away
those predators do need to be planned
for they need to be planned ahead you do
need to get them there it's going to
take you if you're new with ordering
from the insectiary it may take you two
weeks to get your first batch but after
that you'll be in the rotation they may
have to breed more bugs for you
sometimes they're making the amount of
bugs they sell these people know what
they're going to sell they're making
that amount they got to step up the
program to get you your order in two
weeks so be prepared also keep in mind
delivery time also keep in mind
somebody's got to disperse all of these
bugs which is cool because you can just
do the whole room or you can really
focus on problem hot spots
i've come to a part in my notes where it
says ppe we've already talked about
personal protective equipment but guess
what once again
be safe in the grow protect yourself
personal protective equipment long
sleeves pants shoes goggles respirator
if you need it gloves for sure
maybe even a tyvek suit come on protect
yourself all right i just want to make
sure that you're safe and that you go
home to your kids or your dog or your
turtle or all sexy or cats or whatever
you're doing take care of yourself
now i did say that i was going to talk a
little bit about some of the products
that i use and do recommend i've got a
few disclaimers here a bunch of rambling
to do about this
first one nobody pays me
i'm not paid by any [ __ ] companies
for any products the only sponsors the
only people that are in my pocket the
only people whose pocket i am in
whichever way that goes i do have an
advertising agreement with seeds
herenow.com i'll be transparent with
that if you're watching on youtube you
don't even get that ad i can't put that
ad on youtube because youtube doesn't
agree with advertising for seeds
herenow.com if you're listening to the
audio there's a seeds here now.com
commercial at the beginning that's the
only advertising agreement i've got
arranged nobody pays me uh nothing like
that so let's talk about the products
that i do recommend i talk a lot about
evergreen evergreen is a good product
it's a pyrethrin-based product it works
on a lot of pests a lot of problems a
lot of pests it doesn't do a lot of
stress to the plants that's a good
product another product i recommend is
azimax another product i recommend is as
a troll
something else i like a lot is botanic
garden max another product i'll
recommend is venerate
something else i really like is monterey
garden spray monterey garden spray has
an ingredient in there called spinosad
which is very effective against white
flies if you've got white flies hit it
with that monterey garden spray
every three days for like three or four
applications your white flies will be
gone you can also do the soil dredge
with the monterey garden spray get that
spinosad in there your white flies will
disappear
the spinosad is a
fungus
a fungus is a bacteria or fungus it's a
fungus that grows on the bottom of
whiskey barrels and they've found that
that kills white flies and many other
insects other products that i really
enjoy are cease i use cease for powdery
mildew i also like regalia i like double
nickel i like a product called b52 i
really like a product called zero tall
it's good for a lot of things you can
clean with it it'll help you get rid of
powdery mildew it creates that
undesirable environment for your plants
and you can use it really late in the
game i'm not going to give you any time
frames another product i really like is
the mammoth p
pest what's it called if i know the name
of it my brain won't say it
anyway the people that make mammoth p
mammoth makes a pest applica pesticide
application i know the name of it my
brain will not say it guys at mammoth i
apologize your pesticide application is
[ __ ] great and it smells wonderful
which i don't know is that a good thing
cause i'm in there going this smells so
good i'm just sucking up the pesticide
that could be dangerous but there's a
mammoth insect control product my brain
will not i apologize because it's a good
product whatever whatever the name of
that [ __ ] is google mammoth and mammoth
pesticide it'll come up
something i want to rec uh one thing i
want to recommend is do not use i do not
recommend using botanical oils um
you see them at all the grow stores all
the hydro stores they're in pretty
colored bottles there's a purple one a
pink one one's got lavender one's got
rosemary and [ __ ] in it i do not like
those
that flavor ends up in your buds and it
doesn't taste good have you ever like
tasted perfume like when a somebody
sprays perfume or cologne in the room
and you can taste it that's what
botanical oils taste like when you smoke
the bud that's what they taste like when
you make concentrates don't put that
[ __ ] in there please also i do not like
neem oil at all get rid of that [ __ ] now
something i do need to touch on being
that i am certified by the colorado
department of agriculture to be uh let
me explain my credentials here since
we're in the middle of a [ __ ]
pesticide application podcast
my certification comes from the colorado
state university also the colorado
department of agriculture i took a class
at the university and i was given the
license by the colorado department of
agriculture i've got license number 17
i'm 017 in the train the trainer
certification program i was trained by a
great person named theo walker she gave
a great class good teacher very
personable person
so i am certified i am train the trainer
certified which means i can go to a
commercial grow whether it's a farm
whether it's a weed grow if it's
tomatoes if it's soy and i can train the
crew and the lead grower in safe
pesticide management application
handling and education i am certified by
the university and the department of ag
to do this i've got paperwork so i am
qualified to give this pesticide
information something i want to touch on
right now is all of the products i
recommend all of the method methodology
i've recommended is legal here in
colorado in a commercial grow i think
actually azimax may have been banned
recently
but most of the products i recommended
are legal and safe here in the state of
colorado i don't know where you are i
don't know the laws we have to work with
the colorado marijuana enforcement
division the colorado department of
public health and environment the
colorado department of agriculture and
probably other entities that i'm not
even aware of they've got to approve
every pesticide that we use on our
products so make sure that the products
you are using are approved by your state
regulators i don't know what state
you're in i don't know what products
you're using don't blame it on me you've
got to do that work i'm telling you what
i use what i recommend don't let me ruin
your license don't let me [ __ ] up your
plans
don't get in trouble because of me
also i try in my personal grow to stick
to those sta same standards that are
held by the commercial grow
sometimes i'm a little bit more strict
but also
full disclosure when i get new clones in
i spray it with [ __ ] that i will not
even tell you because it's not going to
be consumed it's going to become a
mother plant it's going to get cloned
out a bunch of times and then 90 of what
i grow is not consumed it's turned into
seeds so people aren't smoking most of
it so that's a different argument right
there
know those laws and rules and i've got
the word quarantine written down because
that was something i already touched on
but i wanted to segue into it now when
you do get new clones new plants make
sure you treat them so that they can be
quarantined don't put them in the
general population keep them safe all
right let me review my notes make sure
we've covered everything i talked about
ways to make sure you don't get bugs
into the room i talked about
preventative sprays i've talked about
preventative predatory bugs i've talked
about ways to eradicate those bugs if
you do see them if you do see bugs in
your grow
it's time to step up your pest
application keep in mind rotation and
keep in mind bugs do build resistance
also multiple modes of attack understand
how each pesticide works
some pesticides make the bugs forget to
eat some make them forget to breathe
some pesticides grow a mushroom inside
of the bug and the mushroom takes over
the bug and they explode understand the
method of attack if you can get two
modes of attack in a mixture
there's nothing wrong with spraying two
pesticides at the same time on your
plants if
if you understand what's in both of
those bottles some things you can't
spray together some things will have
negative reactions but most of the time
you can mix one two maybe even three
pesticides together and blast the [ __ ]
out of that crop maybe do a tester spray
don't hit the whole crop at first but
you can mix things
all right i think that does wrap up my
integrated pest management episode you
guys have been asking for longer
episodes there you go i'm actually tired
from recording a podcast i wore myself
out doing this thank you so much for
listening i hope you learned a lot if
you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know that i
would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me those
questions corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism positive feedback
let me know what you think of the show i
would love to hear from you also if you
feel like the show is educational
informative or entertaining maybe you
just like to throw me a buck for helping
you out all you have to do is visit
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need to
support the show will be right there on
the screen once again big thank you to
everybody for supporting the show any
other info you may need will be on my
website at
iregenetics.com don't forget about i
redirect there will be a fourth of july
sale on i redirect if you have not found
it yet
go to my website
iriegenetics.com there's a tab for i
redirect click on there don't be
discouraged if stock is low i randomly
update that whenever i've got some seeds
available to put on there it could be
three in the morning it could be two in
the afternoon you never know seeds may
pop up on i redirect stay tuned refresh
often here's a hint if you are a part of
the discord the ire army discord if you
go to any tab on the ire army discord uh
the general chat any of the chat boxes
and you type in dollar sign i redirect
it will respond with a real-time update
of what is in stock on the website it
will give you a list it'll say um the
machine is in stock strawberry starburst
in stock the red pill the blue pill in
stock it'll tell you what is there in
real time
they do sell out quite quickly so once
you've got that notification you got to
get over there and buy the bad
[ __ ] but that is one way to
cheat and get an update on stocks you
don't have to click on every one of them
and see if it's sold out or not i
apologize that the website does that
also
there are a lot of kinks to building a
new website thank you for being patient
with me while we get i redirect ironed
out i appreciate it also
big up to the web guy you guys i'm
rambling let's get the hell out of here
uh website iriegenetics.com check out
iredirect there's a fourth of july
coming new [ __ ] will be on there more of
the older [ __ ] will be on there most
importantly coupon codes and fat sales
stay tuned that shit's coming up real
real quick here you guys that is all
i've got for this episode i'm tired my
eyes are heavy my throat's burning out
give you a lot of great content that is
all i've got for you for this episode
you know i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my friend lauren
at lb seed company and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
so
you