if you put your plants outdoors way too
early and they're already in flower
now's a good time to click subscribe
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rosta jeff
this is episode 757
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode we're going to celebrate 7
10 we'll talk about some 7 10 glossary
terms before we get to that part of the
show let's do a few shout outs to a few
of those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my
canadian buddy jh let's send a big thank
you shout out to kenner reaper let's
send a thank you shout out to
dungslinger i want to send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy ivan m let's
send a thank you shout out to luke i
want to send a thank you shout out to
rasufa and captain mojo let's send a big
thank you to spartan420 and rosta green
thumb i want to send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy sam heads let's
send a big thank you shout out to
curbside gardens i want to send a huge
fist bump to one of my favorite testers
my buddy mobius grows then let's wrap it
all up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to mid
michigan micro grow
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast this of
course is the part of the show where i
do invite you to the dgc growers cup
that's right july 30th in fort collins
just outside of fort collins the dude
groves crew is hosting the dgc growers
cup there will be many great breeders
growers and consumers at the party i do
invite you to join us for all of the
information all of the details do check
out dude
dudegrows.com i look forward to seeing
you at the party all right that is
enough chatter here at the start of the
show happy 7 10 everybody this will be
the 7 10 celebration episode many people
may be confused they're going what is
710 but have no fear because this
episode will be focused on teaching you
and explaining what 710 is all about
what is 710 let's just jump right into
it many of you probably already know
about 420 if you're watching this show
if you're a cannabis consumer if you're
part of the community you're probably
very familiar with 420 420 is when we
celebrate cannabis consumption we like
to get together at 420 smoke a bowl it
used to be the the code in high school
hey bro you want to bust out a little
420 between classes or meet me at this
place at lunch for a little bit of 420
or meet me at 420 for some 420. it was
just kind of cool to smoke down at 4 20.
so 420 got super popular we all know
about that if you haven't listened to my
podcast about 420 it was started by a
group of young men who called themselves
the waldos they would meet every day
after school at 4 20 and smoke together
it kind of stuck that's why my friends
and i a bunch of the grateful dead
community is where it got popular then
it traveled around a bunch of my friends
and myself we all started saying 420
everybody around us was saying 420. it
got super popular then we started seeing
420 festivals and 420 events it got
really commercialized with the
legalization of cannabis so that is
where 420 came from and 420 got popular
now let's segue into 710 what is 710
with the evolution of cannabis
legalization has also come the evolution
of cannabis products one of the greatest
things to come out of this evolution in
my opinion is high quality cannabis
concentrates if it's shatter if it's
batter if it's rosin whatever it is i
love a high quality cannabis concentrate
when it first started getting popular
bho concentrates were known as oil they
would come out looking like honey oil
bho butane honey oil
i'm not going to tell you how it's done
but you would use butane and some
products and the resulting product would
look like oil and it would look like
honey they call it butane honey oil we
learned how to refine it do a bunch of
different things to it but that bho that
butane honey oil i looked like oil so
they were calling it oil then we
realized that if you turn the number 710
upside down on the clock it does spell
the word oil seven one zero flip it
upside down it says oil that's why at 7
10 we smoke some oil that's why 710 has
become the new 420 so that's why 710 has
become the new 420 we have upgraded a
little bit
i do find that 710 is a little bit more
convenient a lot of the time uh compared
to 420 it takes me
uh much less time to prepare and consume
a dab than it does to uh prepare and
consume as much cannabis as it would to
get me where i want to be and also
there's not as much aroma if you take a
dab some of the dabs i've got on the
table smell like straight up candy so if
i hit this blue fruit right here it's
not going to smell like i just smoked a
blunt in the room it's not going to
smell like i smoked a fat joint it's
going to smell like this fruity blue
candy incense potpourri delightful air
freshener stuff so it may be a little
bit easier to conceal and it makes it a
little bit more convenient for a lot of
reasons now we've talked about what 710
means 710 is simply oil upside down it
is when we smoke a dab so a lot of you
have that 420 alarm set on your phone
when 420 comes you all got to get
together and smoke a ball bro at 7 10 we
take dabs in colorado so that's 7 10 a
lot of places are taking dabs at 7 10.
definitely here in colorado so 710 is
oil upside down and that is dab time i
do want to give a big shout out to my
friend task rock task rock from highly
educated titanium uh now also highly
educated quartz
uh also from task and linus tnl the
movement big up to taskrock uh also big
shout out to our friends from
healthstone glass there may have been
other people in the room but to the best
of my knowledge there was a meeting and
people were talking about the new term
and i think taskrock is the one who
coined the phrase 710. so i'm going to
go ahead right here on the show and give
credit to task for coining the phrase
710 i want to make sure that he got that
now when we talk about 710 i keep saying
the word dab
many people might not even know what a
dab is what is a dab a dab when i talk
about a dab a dab is a hit of a
concentrate uh a hit of a cannabis
concentrate just a hit just one
consumption the reason why we call it a
dab let me just go ahead and get out a
dab here i'm going to open a brand new
package of blue fruit live batter from
green dot labs nobody pays me to talk
about this product but i'm just going to
talk about it for the fun of it since
we're here
this is blue fruit live batter
this is a blend of sex on the beach and
black and blue two different strains
extracted together in the same machine
and the same device on the same run that
makes one great tasting concentrate they
do describe the flavor of this
concentrate as blueberry cheesecake and
exotic fruit on the back it says it
contains
74.99 thc and non-detectable amounts of
cbd there's a little pull here tab we
can pull this and probably get more
information if we open this up i don't
usually do that but let's see what's in
here all right through the magic of
editing i got that really quickly when i
open the little book on the back of the
package here i've never done this with
this brand i don't think i pop it open
and it says oh we should talk about this
it does say the um the grow where it was
grown and it says the infused product
place where it was uh processed it's got
those two numbers on there you can't see
the numbers but i see them there's a 403
r and a 404 r number if you have any
problem with this product they could
trace this product back to that
cultivation facility and that extraction
lab so it's cool that they've got that
on there just wanted to mention that it
goes on inside this little book it says
extracted using 99.9 percent distilled
and butane this product was produced
without regulatory oversight for health
safety or efficacy this product complies
with testing requirements there may be
long-term physical or
mental health risks from use of
marijuana including additional risks for
women who are or may become pregnant or
are breastfeeding use of marijuana may
impair your ability to drive a car or
operate machinery intended use inhaled
product and i think that is the end of
the book here that's the end of the
story so it does come with a nice little
uh warning label a bunch of stuff on the
inside here then we're going to crack
this open we are getting to the point
oh it smells so good it smells
disgustingly good the concentrate's
definitely this batter definitely has a
really concentrated aroma in there as
well i'm going gonna try to show you
this i don't know what you can see i
don't want to lose my concentrates i
just bought this i don't want to fall
out of the jar there but i want to put
it up on the camera for you
um i'll pick it up i shouldn't do that
but i'll kind of grab it show you that's
a gram of green dot batter i don't know
if it'll focus on that or not but we'll
try i'll try to zoom in and editing
there it is we'll put it in there
i'm going to show you why we call it a
dab when we take a dab we go like this
we scoop out just a little piece and
most people would take
i don't know if you can even see it on
there because it's just a dab you just
get a little dab just a little dab will
do you that's kind of a big dab that
would make mike cough i'm not going to
show off i'm not trying to brag but this
is the size of dab that i would normally
do here
um scoop this up a little bit i know i'm
not talking into the mic but this is the
kind of dab that i would normally do
something about this size ah that's
that's a decent sized dab i'm gonna do
that while we're here on the podcast in
a minute so um
that's the size dab i would normally do
so we scoop up a dab a dab is a hit of a
concentrate now let me talk about what
is a concentrate maybe concentrate
doesn't even make any sense
when we have cannabis we have dried
cannabis flower tops that's usually what
we consume we cut off the tops we cut
off the leaves we dry and cure the tops
and then we smoke those
we don't need all of the green leafy
matter the vegetable part doesn't really
do anything for us that is the carrier
for the potent part the trichomes the
little the crystals you guys call them
the little mushrooms that are growing
off the weed plants uh those are where
the potency is hidden most of the
potency is in the cap of that trichome
through science and technology people
have learned how to basically rinse or
remove all of that potent part from the
green part so that way we don't have to
smoke uh a bunch of green [ __ ] to get
stoned we can just smoke the important
part we've taken the good part and
washed it off basically using solvents
or water we've learned how to just strip
that potent part from the green leafy
matter and then the green leafy matter
is discarded the potent part is turned
into a delicious batter which i do love
to consume so that is what a dab is a
dab is a hit of that concentrate when
the phrase dab first started i think it
did refer to a bho concentrate because a
lot of this movement
did evolve because of the bho
concentrate movement when cannabis
became legal i don't want to teach you
too much about bho about butane
extracted products but that is how it is
done people say it's not there people
are going to say that's not safe that
can't be healthy
butane is very clean we know how to
clean it out of the product there's none
left in here it's lab tested we've been
doing it for a while we know what we're
doing it's [ __ ] great products rasta
jeff approved uh so back in the day a
dab was a bho hit now we call it dab
basically anything if it's rosin if it's
batter if it's shatter uh if you put it
on the dabber and put it in the banger
and take a dab of it that's a dab that's
what they'll call it um i just said a
bunch of words right there that you may
not even know so i said dabber what's
the dabber the dabber is the little
stick that i scoop up the dabber with
that's all it is that's the dabber the
stick that i went and put the dab on
this is the dabber also i am a dabber
i'm a person who consumes dabs i am a
dabber so i've got my dabber um
just keep talking here there's more to
cover concentrates uh there are a lot
when i'd say concentrates that means a
lot of different kinds of hash a lot of
you older smokers uh you'll think of
just old school hash
water hash bubble hash that's just basic
hash that is a concentrate you can dab
that but it does make a mess on your
banger sometimes uh you can make
concentrates with dry ice i've seen
people take a sieve bag and dry ice and
product and just shake the [ __ ] out of
it the dry ice works as a solvent and it
kind of freezes up the it works like how
you get gum out of your hair it freezes
up the uh the vegetables and then the
crystals fall off basically that's not
exactly but that's the short version of
what happens
um i've seen people press stuff people
can press plenty of stuff into
concentrates they're shatter they're
solventless
there's so many different styles and
preparations of dabs but all of that is
concentrates all of that falls into the
label of hash or concentrates there's a
very good uh distinction between two
types of concentrates that people really
do love there is solventless and
solvent-based concentrates people like
to make concentrates with heat i'm sure
you've heard of people making rosin
right now people are using uh any kind
of heat and pressure you can use a hair
straightener or a hydraulic press but
with heat and pressure people are making
raws and they're squeezing the potency
of the potent part out of the plant
squeezing it right out and getting that
part that is a solvent-less product you
didn't use any chemicals no solvents
were used in the making of that product
also people will consider water hatch to
be solvent-less because yes i do
understand that water is a solvent but
let me try to quote my friend nicoti
here dj nicotine from essential extracts
has taught us that
when we're making water hash water is
not being used as a solvent because
trichomes are not water soluble it is
being used as an agitator we are using
ice and water to simply wash the
trichomes off of the plant we're not
using it as a solvent so when we use
water and ice to make hash that is
technically solventless concentrates a
lot of people really like the
solventless people that have had seizure
problems some older people they're
afraid of the butane so a lot of those
folks a lot of the younger the rosin
heads they really love the solvent-less
products then there are people like
myself i really love a butane extracted
product the product i'm going to dab was
made i said a moment ago with 99.9
pure butane so that's a butane extracted
product um in my opinion the butane
extracted products burn cleaner they
don't leave any residue on the nail they
don't need they don't leave any mess in
my my rig i think they work a lot better
for me i do smoke some rosin green dot
makes an amazing garlic banger rosin it
tastes disgustingly delicious it smells
so grossly good it's like a garlicky
trash can with hints of vomit i love it
it sounds gross right give me all of it
i'll take four grams right now i love
that [ __ ] that's a rosin when i smoke
that my lungs feel a little bit heavy it
makes me a little bit
uh it makes all of me heavy it makes me
like want to sit down and like almost
take a nap it makes my face and my eyes
heavy it almost makes me want to cough
and it leaves a little bit of a [ __ ] on
my banger the rosin doesn't do that the
or the re
the live batter doesn't do that the live
batter gets me a nice head buzz my eyes
perk up i start getting wild i want to
do some [ __ ] i get active and lively so
that's the big difference between those
two products but i do enjoy both of them
uh just in different ways so the rosin
from green dot is made without any uh
solvents it is heat and water then the
uh the bho the batter is made with the
butane of course and i do like both of
those so we've talked about solventless
and solvent concentrates
let's talk about rigs i've said rig just
a moment ago the thing that you smoke
your oil through is a rig right an oil
rig that's why we call it that i prefer
a little rig this is my dab rig this is
the one i have chosen i've got a lot of
rigs i've got several rigs this is my
favorite rig this is my go-to hitter try
to hold it up here to where you can see
it it's not very big uh it's just big
enough to where when i put the dab in
the this is a banger when i put the dab
into the banger i'll put the carb cap on
it we'll show you that in a moment the
smoke will travel down through here
through these bubbles i always prefer a
something with water if i'm smoking
concentrates i want it to go through
water i'm gonna heat it up pretty hot
i take a pretty uh pretty vicious size
dab so i need some water to cool that
down then it comes up through the water
then i like this really flared out
mouthpiece when i take a dab um if the
mouthpiece is too small i feel like the
concentrates stick to my lips my
mustache my teeth and i don't like that
again i take bigger dabs than the
average bear so i like the flared out
mouthpiece this is my favorite rig in my
collection not the most expensive not
the shiniest the brightest but this one
punches the hardest so i like a rig that
is small uh just enough to get water and
enough to get the [ __ ] the smoke
cooled off then a nice flared out
mouthpiece something i do pay attention
to when i'm buying the rig is how far
from my eyes and face is the nail or the
banger or the bucket going to be when
i'm trying to take a dab am i going to
be able to carve it am i going to be
able to work the banger because i don't
want it right here in my face when i'm
all cross-eyed i don't need it down here
by my fingers where i can't see it i
don't need it up here where i got to
look up and it's all awkward i like the
way this one sits
so when i'm buying a rig i look for
something kind of small
i look for something with a flared
mouthpiece something that holds water
and something that's not awkward when
i'm going to hit it something that's
comfortable in my hand something that i
can function with i'll show you what i
mean i'm going to put it to my face and
kind of give you an example i like to go
right here
so i can look right into where my banger
is where i'm going to be lining up
putting my dab into there
i could definitely manage that all the
time not going to miss not going to go
cross side when they're too close i feel
like i go cross-eyed and it just feels
[ __ ] weird so i like a little rig
this is my rig i could have cleaned it a
little better for you it's got some some
dab residue in there but hey we've been
dabbing that's what the rig is for
so this is the rig
um i talk about this part this is the
banger this part comes off right here
this is a separate purchase
this is a banger this is the part where
you're gonna heat this and then you're
gonna put your dab in here and then
you'll put the carb cap on i'll show you
the cap the cap fits on right here kind
of swirl it around a little bit what
that does um when the cap goes on
it creates a vacuum now the air cannot
flow inside of this area because i've
just sealed it off i'm also smoking
through here at this time so i'm pulling
air through here there's a small hole in
the cap so i'm not restricting the
airflow the heat in here now does not
need to be as intense because i've
created a vacuum it's like putting a lid
on the pot i've trapped the heat in here
now my dab will cook at a lower
temperature it'll burn more cleanly more
smoothly without so much heat less heat
is a little bit better we're going to
talk about heat and temperature in just
a moment but the less heat on there is
better for your lungs better for your
throat it doesn't burn as bad but the
less heat will work better for you it'll
taste better it won't mess up your
throat your lungs it'll be a more
enjoyable experience however i do enjoy
a little bit of an excessively hot dab
so this is my banger one thing i should
mention
is the sizes of bangers that are
available this is a 14 millimeter i do
believe that 14 millimeter is my
favorite size uh for the joint now that
all depends on the size of the joint on
your rig your rig may have a male or a
female joint this is a male joint on the
rig a female joint on the banger
obviously they meet just like that
they're both 14 millimeters so you got a
14 millimeter 14 mil male female they
connect like that this is a 90 degree
banger goes at a 90 so it's nice and
flat let me show you another option
this my friends is a 10 millimeter let
me get it out of here real carefully i
don't want to break it it's only 10
millimeters it's kind of delicate that
one's 10 mil it's a little bit skinnier
it's obviously four millimeters skinnier
that one's also a 90 degree this one is
a male if you can see the shape on the
end let me hold it over here this one's
got that this one goes in right the
piece that goes in is a male just like
us the piece that goes in that's a male
my rig is a female you see it's got a
hole right there watching me do it a
little bit a little bit of rig porn oh
yeah that just sits in there just like
that in this one i've got let me get
them out of here so i could show you i
have got these little guys little glass
balls we call them terp pearls i'm
holding two of them up to the camera
right now tiny little glass balls i put
these in here then when i take a dab i
use a carb cap a spinner cap that makes
those balls spin around the nail around
inside the banger and what that does is
it stirs my oil it stirs my dab and it
makes it move around so it moves it
around the hot surface of the bottom of
the banger and my i get the whole dab i
don't waste any of it i don't get a
little puddle that didn't get roasted up
for me so that is a 10 millimeter uh
banger with a male joint on the banger
and the one we've got over here is a 14
millimeter male oh i may have done that
wrong this is a female 14 millimeter
female 14 mil and then we've got a male
10 mil over there this is my i like this
rig a lot this one is my favorite though
all right so we've talked about the rig
the nail or the banger there are other
options there are a lot of other options
for nails you could get a terp slurper
which then you're going to need a gasket
and a marble and some other stuff for
that
there are other options that look
different but they do the same thing you
guys this is my preference this just
happens to be my preference i like these
uh round bottom bangers uh with the carb
cap on it that's just what i prefer it
just hits real nice like i said i like
the flared mouthpiece that's just it's
all about preference find what you like
now talking about finding what you like
let's talk a little bit about dab
temperature i said that i like to take
my dabs a little bit too hot some people
prefer them a little bit cooler if you
don't have a dab right thermometer or an
email dialing in your dab temperature
can take a couple of dabs you may have
to waste a couple of dabs to figure it
out so my advice would be to just scoop
up a dab then get your torch we didn't
go over the torch i'm using it's
basically a creme brulee torch from
amazon i like this one because it spits
out two flames i don't know if the
camera will catch this but uh there are
two flames coming out of there they kind
of blend into one in the camera it does
have two little flames which really
heats up the stuff really quickly so my
banger gets real hot real quick but
i would scoop up my dab i would heat up
my banger when i heat up the banger i
heat it from the bottom corner this is a
round bottom banger if it were a square
bottom i would heat it where the floor
and the wall meet that is kind of the
the rule of thumb that i follow where
the floor and the wall meet and i'll
kind of work my way around it just a
little bit but i heat right about here
because i know uh just from dabbing a
lot i know that when i put my dab in
there that's where i'm gonna hit
right there on that corner and then
since i hold it kind of tipped it all
tips to that direction anyway when i put
the cap on it's going to start spinning
it around so i heat it i heat it until
um it almost starts glowing if it's
dirty i'll clean it with the torch
that's ridiculous i'll heat it until i
see that it's hot then i let it cool
down
now i let it cool until i use my hand
it's not hot right now i keep touching
it's like a loaded gun i have to keep
checking it or a maybe loaded gun i
check it with my finger my hand the palm
of my hand and i can tell by the palm of
my hand when the dab is ready i wanted
to feel like
if i pushed the banger into my skin
it wouldn't burn
the [ __ ] out of me but it wouldn't be
pleasant at all it'd be like oh i burned
the [ __ ] out of myself but then it'd be
red for a minute you might get a little
blister but it's not going to make a
[ __ ] big problem if it goes and [ __ ]
your skin up that's way too hot don't
try it don't that's not a good way to
test it but if it's sizzling up your
skin that's too hot i want it to feel
kind of like a painful pinch but not a
scary burn when i get close when i'm
just right about here it's like feeling
the baby bottle like you just got to get
it close and see what it feels like so
once i feel like it's close then i just
go sometimes i'll give it a pull
and i can tell the temperature of this
nail by pulling through this water if
it's still super hot don't do it it's
still super hot so heat it up let it
cool give it a feel then put the dab in
there and be i i'm already inhaling as
the dab goes in it's kind of like it
just happens kind of simultaneously i've
got to dab on the dabber i'll use the
other end but i go
just happens like that so i'm inhaling i
put the dab on there it starts smoking
up a little bit if your dab goes
and sizzles right away she was way too
hot way too hot your lungs are gonna
sizzle abort mission quit inhaling
if it bubbles up real nice
oh yeah next step sorry i forgot a step
put your dab in there set the dabber
down then grab your trusty carb cap and
put that carb cap on top and watch that
[ __ ] in there if it bubbles up and just
boils really smooth you might have a
pretty close temperature give it a good
pull
see what happens are you getting smoke
is the smoke real thick is the smoke
real thin
if you're not getting any smoke if the
dab didn't melt guess what not hot
enough if that [ __ ] sizzled up right
away way too hot just take a few more
dabs and kind of feel remember where you
were like this is way too hot this is
way too cool and then find your middle
ground
if you do take a dab and you've got some
concentrates puddled down here in the in
the bottom of your banger put the carb
cap on it hit it with the torch for two
and a half to three seconds i know
that's not much time but
that's enough to get a reheat we call
that a reheat
so you got your carb cap on here and
then you're just going to hit it with
set the torch down grab the cap and then
hit it again i bet you'll get smoked
that time that's a reheat so if that
worked that means that the first time it
was not hot enough i don't have
super
like super accurate dial it in advice to
get the temperature that you want i
prefer a hotter dab than most people for
a while there was a trend of you gotta
waste it to taste it where people were
uh burning it so low temperature that it
would taste super good but you'd have to
get two q-tips and clean up the [ __ ]
banger because they would leave so much
junk behind i don't leave [ __ ] behind
when i take a dab i take mine a little
bit hotter than that but also sometimes
i roast myself and i gotta catch my
breath and sit down for a minute but i
kind of enjoy that so maybe i'm a sicko
my advice like i said heat it up feel it
with your hand feel it feel it is it too
hot is it not hot enough
take a dab maybe waste a few dabs what
are you gonna do hang out with your girl
get a gram or two of concentrates and
just take a couple of dabs and dial it
in you'll get one dab that will make you
so high that you'll be satisfied uh take
a few mental notes like it was way too
hot it's not hot enough learn what you
like you may like it a lot hotter than
your bro your bro may like it a lot
hotter than you you never know what
people may like so dial in that
temperature the way that is perfect for
you another thing that you may want to
do is get yourself an email what's an
email now we've got devices that plug
into the wall it's got a little wire
that comes off of a box that hooks up to
your banger or your nail or whatever
device it may come with depending on
what company you shop with on that box
it's got a number which you set it to
and that number will control the heat at
the end of the nail then you can get a
consistently heated nail every time you
want to dab and it's always on if this
were had an email cable on it and i
wanted to hit it i could just grab it
right now take a dab there would be no
need to heat it up no need to torch it
it would already be ready already so
that's an email that's a great device
you could definitely dial that in get
that completely perfect one thing i'm
going to say about the email
most of those devices the number on that
device does not correlate with the
number on the surface of the nail
in temperature it is just a number on
the box it is probably it's like a
volume setting on your car it's got one
through whatever i'm gonna go with one
through ten maybe your spinal tap and
you've got eleven but we got one through
ten right i know that if i turn my car
stereo up to ten it sounds like total
[ __ ] i'm over doing it the speakers
can't handle it the gear is not meant to
do that i know if i hover around seven
it [ __ ] rocks it's as loud as i want
to go i know if i get down to six that's
cool for traffic when the cops come i go
down to like number three if i'm trying
to find an address i turn it down to
number two why do i need it down so low
to find an address it's just weird [ __ ]
that we do but what i'm getting at is
that number on the 1 through 10 on my
car stereo doesn't mean that it's coming
out at level 10 on the speakers it
doesn't know it's just 1 through 10.
those are just arbitrary settings it's
not one decibel or 10 decibels it's just
1 through 10. basically one through a
hundred percent so what i'm getting at
is on that box that's not a a
temperature on the nail that doesn't
correlate as a temperature that's just a
setting it's high medium low
but find the number that works for you
and set it at that number but don't
think that that number is the exact
temperature that your nail is at because
i don't think that that works that way
if you want to find out get yourself a
dab right and then put the dab right
under there turn on the email and see
what the dabrite measures that may be a
good thing if you're new to dabbing and
you want to spend some money at dabrite
is a great device i do not have one i've
thought about getting one if dabrite
would like to advertise on the podcast
what's up guys i'll trade you a dab
right for a couple of ads here we'll use
it on the show it may work out i'll do
it on instagram live anyway enough
pitching myself also your ad could be
here if you'd like to do some
advertising on the show reach out i'm
[ __ ] high and rambling get an email
you guys check that out dial that in but
don't think that the number on the email
is actually a temperature i think it's
actually a frequency like megahertz or
something that's probably more likely
what that is um for on the road dabs i
like the puffco a lot of times allegedly
possibly you may see me hitting this rig
in the car if not i may be hitting a
puffco a puffco pro puffco peak
whichever the newest one is
it's growing on me at first i didn't
like them they take a lot of maintenance
and care but they are growing on me
another thing i should talk about is a
nectar collector nectar collectors are
great if they've got some water uh my
buddy tanasi is a big fan of the honey
badger big shout out to our friends at
the honey badger if you're looking for
an email
i recommend a colorado company called
the bee nail check out the b nail tell
them roster jeff sent you i'm going kind
of fast because i feel like i've been
going for a long time my throat's
getting dry i want to talk about some
more things and most importantly i want
to take a big fat dab for you and show
you how i do it um something else you're
going to need if you're going to start
taking dabs or q-tips i mentioned q-tips
earlier after i take a dab there's going
to be a little bit of stuff left in here
possibly maybe i do grab a q-tip and i
just give it a couple of good swirls
clean all that [ __ ] out there so my
banger is clean and fresh for the next
lovely contestant who's going to step up
and take a dab there are other great
accessories you could think about i
talked about the tert pearls that i've
got in here they do sell a little
grabber so you could pull the pearls out
and clean those i like to use a product
called dark crystal glass cleaner dark
crystal is from canada it's a great
product i use it quite often on a lot of
my products i probably cleaned all the
[ __ ] on the table with it recently it's
a good product my shit's dirty now so
don't judge my stuff by don't judge the
product by that i've been using it but a
dark crystal is a great glass cleaner i
recommend that
you've got 10 14 and 18 millimeter
bangers i really like a rig with water
in it um i think i've covered all of the
notes so one of my favorite things about
dabs is most of the flower that you buy
that you can buy that is available in a
colorado dispensary is going to come in
somewhere between 19 and 30 thc a
if we look at the back of this container
of concentrates this product contains
74.9
thca
one big fat dab of this is like
basically smoking two or three regular
sized joints to the face by yourself and
i get to get all that potency into my
bloodstream into my lungs into my face
into my brain just that quick one quick
fat dab maybe a fat cough and then after
that i can move on with my business i
don't have to sit here and roll up three
or four joints and smoke three or four
joints and cough a bunch of times and
smell like herb and i could just smoke a
big fat dab don't get me wrong i do love
smoking flowers but sometimes that dab
is what i need speaking of dabs i'm
going to take a little sip of a frosty
cool beverage i've already got part of a
dab up here on the dabber we're going to
heat up the nail we're going to kind of
do a little tutorial i'll show you guys
how i take a dab then we're going to
wrap this up
all right podcast world i do apologize i
was interrupted by the ups guy bringing
me a cool package that we will talk
about on a future episode let's get back
into the show here i was about to do a
dab and wrap up the show it does occur
to me that maybe i should start doing
the wrap up before i hit a dab so that
the show does make some sense here at
the end so let's start wrapping up the
show i'm going to heat up my dab nail my
banger while i do ramble then we will do
a dab and we will say good night let me
start like this ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes smokers growers clone cutters
paul and chuckers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there i do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another episode of the grow from your
heart podcast if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns i would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy also make sure you check
out the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else you might need will be
on my website at
iregenetics.com all right this nail is
super hot i'm going to let this cool for
a little bit while that cools down i do
want to thank you once again i really do
appreciate uh you dabbing with me you
hanging out you trusting me with all
this guidance all of this grow advice uh
thank you for all the comments all of
the feedback all the constructive
criticism it does mean a lot to me it
does keep me going so keep sending me
those emails those messages keep the
youtube comments going i love it thank
you so much i do appreciate all of the
support from the community i am of
course just kind of rambling while this
does cool down it's a bit too hot i'm
using my hand to measure the temperature
here it's a little bit too warm still i
can tell because it feels like i would
burn the [ __ ] out of myself if i touched
it right now
but it is getting super close so i'm
gonna move the microphone out of my way
i want to give a big shout out to my
buddy purple skunk and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
happy 710 everybody
you