[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 76 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host roster Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always I need to
send a huge thank you shout out to the
Mystic Roots band for letting me use
their music on the show big thanks to
cat cot and the entire Mystic Roots crew
of course the song you're listening to
is the doggy dub and it's off their
album the constant struggle make sure
you check that out and support the
Mystic Roots band and stay positive
sound all right guys I'll let you know
that while I'm recording the podcast I
am live on a new application called
Periscope uh people on Periscope are
watching me live I've got five live
viewers uh I'm recording they can hear
everything I'm saying they could not
hear the podcast or the theme song but
they could hear everything else uh
they're able to send comments that I can
see on the bottom of the screen uh I'm
not going to pay attention to the
comments on Periscope while I record the
podcast today but if this goes well in a
future
episode this may open up the doors for a
questions and answer segment uh you'll
be able to answer questions I will
answer them live on Periscope as I
record the podcast and then in the
future uh it won't be any more than I'll
do it I'll try to get it up as quickly
as possible right after the live Q&amp;A
I'll go ahead and throw the podcast up
into iTunes and Stitcher and then you
guys can listen to it uh again if you
didn't already uh if you listen to it on
the [ __ ] uh Periscope app and if you
didn't already listen to it then you'll
be able to hear the actual episode with
questions from the listeners so we're
going to figure out how to do that you
guys check out this Periscope app it's
pretty neat um you can log in and you
can watch people broadcast their lives
or you can broadcast your life if you'd
feel like it it's kind of neat I've been
going in the grow room and walking
around in the garden and showing people
what I've got going on in the garden uh
I've been driving around and throwing
the phone up on the dashboard just while
I drive around it's been pretty neat so
let's move on a little bit in this show
you guys I do plan on talking about uh
pheno hunting and selecting mother
plants I know I've been teasing about
feno hunting a little bit we're going to
do that in this episode uh before we get
that far though I do want to send a big
happy birthday shout out to Maya Luna
Happy Birthday monkey bear that's my
daughter she is now 12 years old uh this
episode will come out on the 14th late
late at night on the 14th you guys will
hopefully listen to it on the morning of
the 15th going to drop it late on the
14th just to say happy birthday to my
daughter happy birthday my Aluna your
Daddy loves you I'm not sure if you uh
listen to the podcast I'm pretty sure
you're tired of hearing my voice so uh
maybe one day when you're old and you
listen back to all the episodes you'll
catch this one and it'll put a smile on
your face dads think about that kind of
[ __ ] all right so happy birthday Maya
bear I love you so much more than
anything uh let's keep the show moving
dude a couple of nights ago my good
buddy Clint got me a ticket uh I drove
we took along uh Clint's little brother
Chris and then we met up with our good
buddy Joe who will be on a future
episode of the podcast we've talked
about that uh but we went up to Denver
to Comedy Works and we saw Joey Coco
Diaz and that [ __ ] blew the roof
off of Comedy Works that dude ripped it
up that's one of the best comedy shows
I've seen in quite a while I know I say
that about every comedy show when I come
on this show but it was one of the best
shows I've seen in quite a long time it
totally kicked ass uh for the first six
or seven minutes of the show uh he came
out and he told a joke right and he kept
telling jokes but he told it it was like
he hit me and then I would start
laughing and as soon as I felt like I
was going to catch my breath he'd Hit Me
Harder so I'd laugh even harder and lose
my breath and every time I feel like I
was coming around he'd hit me and I was
starting get a pleasant pain in my
cheeks and stomach from laughing so hard
and then I got this weird headache
toward the back of my head from laughing
so [ __ ] hard I was like Joey stop for
a minute bro I need a little bit of
oxygen because I cannot breathe and I
cannot keep up with this I'm moving the
Periscope camera right now so that they
can see me a little bit better I think
I've got everything I need on the
screen so uh Joey Coco Diaz is
definitely one of my favorite comedians
Joe Rogan says he's the best comedian on
the planet right now I could almost
agree with that if you're into that
style I can listen to Joey talk all day
I listen to his podcast the Church of
What's Happening Now it's [ __ ]
awesome so big shout out to Joey Coco
Diaz for putting on an amazing [ __ ]
comedy show at Comedy Works in downtown
Denver also big shout out to Baker and
the entire Comedy Works crew Baker I owe
you one bro if you ever need anything if
you're ever in peblo make sure you get
in touch with me I will hook you up with
any help you need Comedy Works I love
that club I've said it once or seven
times the best [ __ ] Comedy Club in
Colorado possibly the world also I want
to send a huge shout out to Clint for
the ticket and for being a hell of a
good friend dude uh you're my homie
forever and I appreciate it and I see
what you do and you're a good friend
dude I just want to throw that out there
we hung out today had a great time I
know you're always going to be my friend
I appreciate that [ __ ] uh also shout out
to Joe and Chris uh man we and we killed
it as a group at that show nobody was a
[ __ ] nobody whined about anything uh
Joe met us up in Denver Chris and Clint
and I all rode up together nobody was a
little whiny girl we had so much fun we
had a successful dinner we flirted with
the beautiful waitress at the Mellow
Mushroom uh we kicked ass at the show we
all met Joey Diaz we all had a nice
little smoke out in the car before and
after such a great time so shout out to
the crew for kicking it you guys are not
pain in the asses you are professionals
you are grown men and I [ __ ] love
hanging out with you guys let's do it
more
often all right you guys were all
invited on the podcast whenever you'd
like to be so I wrote a note and I lost
it [ __ ] I gotta reach for a note it's
right over here hold on you guys
okay I've got my note ah I wrote down to
give a shout out to a guy who calls
himself Beast of Omaha big shout out to
the Beast of Omaha he follows me on
Periscope and we were talking earlier
told him that I'd do a podcast he said
he was going to check it out this is the
episode I did right after we spoke bro
so I hope you were listening I hope you
check this out all right we're going to
keep the show moving we are going to get
on to the main topic of the show the
main topic of the show you guys is going
to be feno hunting and selecting mother
plants I didn't take a lot of notes
because I feel like I can pull that
episode off without a lot of preparation
I mean I've got all the preparation in
my head I've done this a thousand times
so I think I can pull it off but let's
see I got one or two more things I want
to talk about where are my notes Here we
are uh I want to announce something this
one is going to be really really cool so
a very long time ago I was scrolling
through Instagram I'm sorry about the
clearent of the throat you guys know how
that goes I smoke Dabs and drink Caff
and then the throat goes to [ __ ] uh a
long time ago I was scrolling through
Instagram and I came across an Instagram
page of a lovely lady called dude it's
damsel and I've been following damsel
she's a Suicide Girl she's tattooed up
she's got dreadlocks and she's [ __ ]
beautiful she's an amazing woman uh I've
been following damsel on Instagram for
quite a while and then a good friend of
mine our friend hunt the grimy Gatsby
introduced me to damsel uh and also my
friend Julia I got to give shouts to
Julie what's up Jules miss you Boo uh
she is partly responsible for
introducing me to damsel so I introd I
got introduced to damsel we've talked
we've spoken a few times and I am proud
to announce that I am working on a
strain for dude it's damsel The Suicide
Girl it will be a strain specifically
selected for her and this strain will
represent damsel it will be colorful it
will be sexy it will stand out from the
crowd it will be something you want to
look at it will smell Beautiful it will
taste amazing and her idea is that when
she smokes it she wants a nice giggly
sativa head high so I'm working on that
strain I've got several the seeds are
ready here's here's where I am the seeds
are ready and I have several crosses
that I think would make damsel happy but
instead of just running one cross I'm
going to run three or four crosses that
I've made and we're going to see if one
of those gives us a phenotype that
damsel completely
loves so that is a great segue to get
into the main meat of this podcast the
main topic of this podcast is feno
hunting and selecting a mother plant for
the future we're definitely going to
focus on feno Hunting because I've
already gone about 10 minutes so uh let
me head over to Google here sorry about
the microphone bumps let me head over to
Google here uh shout out to damel also
before I get too far I want to give a
huge shout out to damsel uh make sure
you guys follow dudit damsel on
Instagram and let her know that you
support her new strain
uh use the hashtag # damsel dank d m LS
D- n k damsels dank I think I said that
right I'm high uh hashtag damsel dank
let her know that you follow I genetics
you listen to the podcast follow her on
Instagram she's beautiful support her
watch the progress of the strain that
we're working on I'll start posting
pictures soon um so shout out to damsel
for
um giving me the honor to grow a strain
that will represent her forever and also
I want to send a big huge shout out to
my buddy hunt hey hunt thanks for uh
linking damsel and I up together to get
this project started I'm sure this is
going to work out great for everybody
once this project is completed and damel
has picked her favorite phenotypes or
phenotype uh The Strain should be
available for purchase in flower form at
Green and healthy cannabis in Colorado
Springs and also the spot dispensary in
PUO West Colorado so that'll be a long
time coming but once it's available uh
we will let you guys know so to get that
far I am going to have to do a pheno
hunt which is actually the main topic of
this
show now it feels like a good place to
start would be to define the word
phenotype so I'm headed over to Google
and Wikipedia says a phenotype is the
set of observable characteristics of an
individual resulting from the
interaction of its genotype with the
environment so kind of what that says is
if we have a bunch of seeds and we grow
them out and they are all the same
genotype which means they came from the
same parents they're the same batch of
seeds uh if we grow those out we will
see what is called phenotypical
Expressions which means some of those
plants are going to show characteristics
of its mother some are going to show
characteristics of its father some are
going to show characteristics of
grandparents that we didn't even see in
the parent plants and then some of them
are going to show perfect traits of
50/50 combinations of each and then
you're going to see variations in
between depending on which final
generation you're working with so one
way to kind of put that is uh if you
have a brother or a sister you probably
don't look exactly alike because you're
from the same parents but you are
different phenotypes basically uh maybe
maybe your brother is a little taller
than you or a little fatter than you or
something that's just phen phenotypical
expression of the same genotype
basically so when we're working with
plants when we're looking for phenotypes
the purpose of a pheno hunt is to find
the plant that you want from that 10
pack of seeds now you have a couple of
uh decisions to make do you want um do
you want the plant that represents the
one that's on the picture of the package
of seeds the one that you read about do
you want the one that grows a little bit
shorter for your grow room do you want
the one that's a little more indicia
dominant the one that's a little more
sativa dominant that's something to
think about when you were starting a
pheno hunt the purpose of the pheno Hunt
is to run through see I would recommend
at least 10 seeds as a breeder I do
anywhere from 25 to 100 seeds of the
same same strain so the ideal thing is
to run as many of these seed seedlings
as you can underneath the same
conditions to find the one that you want
that is the Stellar keeper out of all of
the plants that you're working with a
lot of times I see people purchase a
package of seeds and they will run two
of those seeds and then they'll say hey
look I've got sour diesel or hey look
I've got Super Lemon Haze and you might
have a decent Super Lemon Haze but you
don't have that super phenotype because
you haven't gone through and done the
work you haven't pheno hunted out the
one that is Stellar that is worth
keeping that's going to blow everybody
else's mind so a pheno hunt is where
you're going to find a lot of good [ __ ]
and you could have gotten that Stellar
keeper out of just a couple but I mean
if you do a large feno hunt the chances
of finding what you want and that
Stellar keeper just even better all
right so let's talk about a couple of
really popular phenotypes while we're on
this subject before we get into me
explaining how I do my pheno typical
pheno hunt
um I'm sure you guys have heard me talk
about jell Bean there is a really
popular phenotype of jell Bean known as
the candy store phenotype and there's
also another phenotype known as the
orange
phenotype um the the candy store
phenotype smells like uh when you walk
into the candy store in the mall it's
got that sweet uh it's like those candy
hearts you buy at Hall or at Valentine's
Day it all smells real sugary and sweet
and it makes you like want to eat candy
that's what the candy store phenotype
smells like that's of course why it's
called candy store the orange phenotype
smells like a basket of [ __ ] oranges
it's so delicious and those are known
phenotypes so when you hear people
talking about yeah I got the orange
phenotype I got the Jil pheno that's
what they're talking about uh I breed a
strain called Heart of Gold and there is
the chunky girl phenotype which just
grows big fat phenos and then there's
the mean girl which looks a little uh
she's real Jagged and the way that her
buds grow are real spiky and pointy so I
call her the mean girl just cuz she
looks angry when she grows it's a really
great plant but it looks like ferocious
it's like an intimidating plant for some
reason and then there's also the uh the
other feno which is the non-desirable
feno it's the one that's more Golden
Goat leaning I don't keep that feno when
I grow Heart of Gold I'll toss that one
out right away when I identify it but
that's more of an advanced thing uh so
when you hear us talking about like I've
got the whatever feno that's what we're
saying that we grew out a pack of seeds
and we found the feno that was known uh
that's been talked about a lot or that
the breeder told you to look for like I
know that there are fenos of black
cherry Chim that I tell guys my friends
I'm like if you see that I wouldn't even
keep that one I would just get rid of
that right away I'm like if you see this
that's kind of the one you want to keep
so if you're growing black cherry Kim
the one that shows dark dark purple
right away like a plum purple right away
I don't think that's a keeper uh it
grows little tiny popcorn balls of
bright dark dark purple buds and I don't
find that to be a keeper so as a fenal
Hunter I know to throw that away and I
only know that because I've grown it out
so many times I feel like I'm drifting a
little bit away from the topic but it's
all useful information here all right I
should probably get into explaining a
little bit how I do a pheno hunt or how
I would recommend you doing a feno hunt
as a kind of a new grower without a lot
of space and a lot of money to spend on
seeds um so the way to do it I would get
a 10 pack of seeds or a 12pack if you
can get it some some folks are selling
TW get about 10 seeds if you can 10's
enough you know if you want to run a
feno hunt for yourself 10 is enough
seeds I would get seeds from a reputable
company from a reputable vendor um I
would recommend stuff like gagee green
genetics llat Labs iy genetics of course
uh Sin City Seeds has shown me some
great [ __ ] lately the sour seed company
has a great uh lineup and a lot of great
things to offer there are a lot of great
uh DNA genetics is somebody who I would
recommend rare dankness uh somebody who
I would recommend uh Crockett Family
Farms there are a lot of seed breeders
out there you guys try to do some
research get a reputable brand uh give
yourself a chance get some good seeds
and give yourself a chance so get a good
10 pack of seeds feminized or regulars
that's up to you so what we're going to
do we are going to germinate all 10
seeds and we are going to treat them all
the same we are going to do everything
exactly the same to all 10 of these
seeds for almost all of their lives
until kind of midflower if we see that
they need more uh water or more nitrogen
or more something in late flour we'll
make a note of that and then we will
keep that in mind when we select our
Keepers in the future so we're going to
germinate 10 seeds we're going to get
we're going to pay attention to them
from day one because you just want to
keep notes if you've got a seed that's a
straggler uh make a note of one that's a
straggler if you can label your seeds
somehow like seed one seed 2 seed three
make a note of that so germinate these
seeds get them into cups grow them take
some pictures if you can about once a
week if you can then what we want to do
is pay attention to them really closely
veg them out a little bit then you want
to take a clone of them as soon as
they're big enough to take clones so now
you've got these little plants that are
probably in like one to three gallon
pots and you've probably taken a couple
of clones off of them hopefully right so
now you've got a decision to make do you
want to flower out the original seed
that you started or do you want to keep
that seedling as a mother plant or do
you want to keep one of the Clones as a
mother and flower out that plant that's
already large uh it's kind of a toss-up
it depends on how much space you have
and what you want to do what I have
learned is I like that seated uh the
seedling mother to stay as my mom for
some reason it has more Vigor it seems
to be a good idea to keep that one as
your mother that's just my opinion um a
lot of people say that that one's
already grown and already big why not
flower it out lately uh from watching
clones grow and watching seed plants
grow I prefer to have my mother plant
come from seed that's something I have
learned um I may be hypocritical because
sometimes time doesn't always allow that
sometimes I need the space in the room
to bloom so I Bloom out the large Plant
that's already going but from now on I
will try to keep that seed plant as my
original mother so um you got these
plants they're big enough to take a
clone off of you take a couple clones
and then you decide which one you want
to flower so if you're going to flower
that original mom you put all 10 of
those Original Seed moms into a
flowering room and you treat them all
the exact same and you flower all of
them if you choose to do clones all you
have to do is get the Clones into pots
get them rooted and everything get them
healthy and then put those into the
flowering room that'll catch everything
right up we're on the same lesson now so
now you're in flour now is when you
really have to start paying attention
taking good notes uh if you've got males
you'll find out about day 10 uh get
those out of there unless you plan on
breeding because those males are going
to start dropping pollen uh it'll start
causing you problems get the males out
of there about day 10 we talk about that
a lot if you're pheno hunting for males
that'll be a whole another episode you
guys you're I'm not even ready to do
that I'll write it down but I'm not sure
that that's going to happen for a long
time uh pheno hunting
males that's going to be neat that's a
really Advanced lesson that'll be way up
there in like the way past episode
episod 100 but we'll talk about it maybe
so pull out the males now you want to
take a lot of notes because around week
three week four is when you're going to
start seeing a lot of different
[ __ ] um if something Herms you're
probably going to see that around
between five and eight get rid of all of
those you don't want to keep the
hermaphrodites so um if you got a 10
pack you're probably going to get
somewhere between four and six boys out
of there right if you've got regular
seeds so you pull those out now you got
like five more to deal with if you've
got fem seeds and probably you lost one
during germ you only got nine so now you
probably got four or five plants to work
with maybe six uh if you're working with
fems you may still have 10 of them a
couple of them are going to be runty a
couple of them be squatty or whatever
it's okay to pull those squatty plants
if they're shitty uh if it's healthy and
not looking like a run and a problem
keep it because when you run LA
Confidential the shitty looking plant is
the one you want to keep honestly it's
the it's not the runt it's not crappy
looking it's the small slow growing one
if your plant looks like a run you can
go ahead and get rid of it so you want
to watch them grow some are going to do
stupid [ __ ] uh pay attention to what you
like the ones that fall over a lot if
the one if one attracts bugs or one
attracts mold that's not the keeper uh
watch for naners like I said around week
five or eight if you get a hermaphrodite
get rid of that one so take a lot of
pictures uh smell them pay a lot of
attention to how they grow then you're
going to have to harvest all 10 of these
plants or however many made it to the
end I said four to six right so Harvest
all four to six of these trim them down
uh cure them properly listen to episode
number 35 about drying and curing uh dry
and cure your medicine properly once all
of your finished plants are dried and
cured it's time to do a few smoke
samples on every phenotype that you've
grown now if you're growing it for just
you you can smoke it and you can decide
which one you like for yourself but if
you're going to be selling it or giving
it to medical patients or sharing it
with your friends it's a good idea to
pass out a few buds of each one and I
don't tell anybody which is which I just
label it A or B and I'm like tell me
which one you like better and tell tell
me why and then I send it off to a
couple of my patients my buddy Doug
what's up Doug I hope you're listening
uh every time I grow new plants I don't
label them and I I remember what they
are I'll give them initials or a code
word or something and I'll take it to
Doug and I'll be like smoke these tell
me which ones we need to keep and which
ones we should get rid of and since I'm
his medical provider his opinion is a
big influence on what I keep and then
also White Mike that's on the podcast
milky tricomes uh Nemo Punk 15 he does a
lot of helping with my selection also if
you're the grower
uh it's a lot up to you 50% of it is up
to the grow if it grows like [ __ ] if it
grows 12et tall in 8 weeks and you're in
doors and you're under an 8ft ceiling
that's not the phenotype for you you
know if it grows 32 feet wide in 6 weeks
and you're in a small room that's not
the phenotype for you if it grows super
completely lanky and falls over and
needs a thousand staks and you're trying
to get one bud kind of scrog system that
might not be the one for you so look for
the one that grows the way that you want
it to grow hopefully that out to be the
one that smokes well also and typically
this is what I found as a a grower
growing a 10 pack you're going to end up
with one that is [ __ ] beautiful
you're going to end up with one that is
covered in resin and has a lot of
tricomes and then you'll probably have
one that tastes really really good and
you'll have one that harvests really
really heavy but if you can find one
that does all of those then you're
golden that's the one that you want but
if you can get two or three of those if
you can get the good high and the good
flavor that's awesome I would sacrifice
that for weight if you're a cash Cropper
maybe you want to sacrifice the good
flavor for the weight you know just
think about what you want if you can
find a strain that does it all for you
find that get clones of it and grow it
forever but a good fenal hunt you have
to take clones because if you don't take
clones of everything you grow you're
going to end up having the best weed on
the planet one time and not have a clone
of it and be so pissed off at
yourself all right guys that's the
basics of a pheno hunt basically keep in
mind that uh not all seeds are going to
yield the exact same plants you might
not get the plants that you saw in the
package you might not get the plants
that were
advertised uh but your goal is actually
to find the one that you love and keep
that one around and turn it into a
mother plant we're going to talk about
that in a second but once you've got
that one keeper you know what you can do
next you got to do another feno hunt of
10 more seeds and find another keeper
and if it's better than the other one
that you've got then toss out that other
one or do it until your mother room is
full just keep hunting for keeper plants
and more keeper plants until you've got
the most Stellar [ __ ] lineup of
plants all right so let's talk about
keeping a mother plant now you've grown
this pheno hunt you have found the plant
that you like you've got the one that
has the flavor you like it gives you the
high you like it grows well for your
room now you've got you either took a
clone of it or you've got that remaining
seed plant that you're going to use as a
mother so the trick to keeping that
plant as your mother plant is to keep it
under a vegetative light I like to use a
195 cycle for my mother plants uh 19 on
19 hours on 5 hours off because I feel
like this gives my plants uh plenty of
light to keep them from uh trying to
autoflow some more tropical strains will
try to autoflow if you let them go a
little less light so the 195 5 hours to
give them a little bit of sleep cycle
and let my equipment rest uh every
living thing likes to sleep so I like to
give my mother plants a little bit of
sleep time so you keep your mother plant
on a vegetative cycle a vegetative light
cycle to keep it alive indefinitely and
you like I would like to feed it some
sort of like uh just a basic uh veg
nutrient whatever you're feeding your
veg plants you can feed your mother
plants that just basic nitrogen keep the
roots happy uh if you want to keep them
for a long time you're going to have to
repot your mothers they will get root
bound so what I do uh my mother plants
only last me about eight months to a
year I'll cut new mother plants I'll cut
a clone I'll cut six or eight clones for
my mother plant right and I will run
four or five of those but I'll keep one
of them behind uh it'll go into a cup
it'll go into a pot and then I'll just
put it into that mother room and replace
the old mother plant because they start
to get ran out they start to get kind of
lazy and [ __ ] you you take a bunch of
cuts from it take clones from it it's
been sprayed for bugs it's been
manipulated under these lights for 8
months it starts to get kind of kind of
lazy so I feel like it's a good idea to
take a fresh cut from my mother plant
keep it under that 18 [ __ ] or that
195 light indefinitely and then just
keep it alive and then if you prune it
if you keep it free of bugs if you keep
it healthy that mother plant will stick
around and give you lots and lots of
clones and keep that strain alive
forever so I think that wraps up uh
pheno hunting selecting a keeper and
using that keeper as a mother all within
we got that down here in 25 minutes and
30 seconds so I think that's going to
work for you guys I really appreciate
you listening to the podcast I recorded
this in two sessions on a on a new app
called Periscope I do plan on possibly
doing a podcast through Periscope I will
record as normal I will also record on
Periscope if you're participating on
Periscope you will be able to ask me
questions live on the show and I will
answer them for you you'll only be able
to type in the text box but I'll be able
to read them answer the questions I'll
be able to help out the listeners live
on the show it'll be a little bit more
interactive uh we're going to try it out
once and see how it goes I will try to
announce when it's going to happen so
that people can participate and then we
can get people on and then we'll try to
do regularly scheduled shows like that
every four or five episodes will be a
question episode a live Q&amp;A is what I'm
aiming for so guys I really appreciate
you listening to the show everybody on
Periscope watching now thanks for
participating I'm sorry I've been
ignoring the chat on Periscope I'm more
focused on the podcast in the future I
will participate with you guys uh
Periscope is a new app you guys check it
out I in there uh you turn on the camera
and you talk and it turns you into
basically your own reality show you guys
can watch from wherever you are on your
phones I watch other people's periscopes
also it's pretty
entertaining um yeah happy birthday Maya
bear I love you so much guys thanks for
listening to the podcast I'll be back in
another week with another episode don't
forget to check out our sponsors the
Rocky Mountain worm company hro indoor
growing supplies if you are interested
in sponsoring the podcast or if you've
got a product you'd like me to review
send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you all
the information that you need you guys
now that the show is over please go to
iTunes go to the iTunes Store search for
grow from your heart find the review
section give me a festar rating check it
out I need a festar rating because that
moves us up in the ranks more people see
us the more people that see the show the
more people will listen to the show the
more people will grow better cannabis
the more better cannabis I keep saying
the more better cannabis it's such a
great [ __ ] set of words the more
quality cannabis will be available for
you to smoke we'll overgrow the
government there'll be good weed
everywhere more people will listen to
the show so give me five stars leave a
little comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comments on a future episode I would
appreciate it if you leave a comment on
Stitcher but Stitcher kind of sucks for
leaving comments it's really hard to
leave a comment that I will find if
you've got something to say and you want
to make sure it gets to me you can find
me on Twitter it's gfyh podcast you can
find me on Facebook it's growmart
podcast you can definitely email me it's
growmart hotmail.com make sure you get
in touch with me I really love the
interaction uh follow me on Periscope if
you do that thing it's brand new we're
just starting that one off don't forget
you guys that every show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is forever archived on iry genetics.com
don't forget there's a donation button
on the podcast page uh go to the iry
genetics.com website click on the grow
from your heart podcast tab at the top
right there a little PayPal button that
goes directly to my Paypal account I'm
never going to charge you for this
podcast this will always be free uh but
if you do feel like contributing and
saying thanks I would definitely
appreciate it all you got to do click on
there type in whatever amount you want
and that will go directly to my Paypal
account I will buy a new microphone
cover I've been spitting into this one
for quite a while I would like to get a
new mobile recording device so that
maybe we can go to the Cannabis Cup The
Secret Cup other places and go do
podcast from there be a little bit
easier than hauling around the big rig
that I've got anyway I'm not begging but
it would be appreciated uh do it if
you'd like uh make sure you follow iy
genetics on Instagram we're at almost
16,000 followers I post a whole bunch of
high quality cannabis pictures up there
make sure you follow that you guys big
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks
again for listening you guys until next
time take a fat dad and give your mom a
hug for
[Music]
me