[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me rasta jeff this is episode 760
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to guido's grow room let's
send a big thank you shout out to roll
this nug and godfather kush i want to
send a thank you shout out to effa plant
count and brian p let's send a thank you
shout out to larf knight rises and stone
trout bomb let's send a big fist bumping
a thank you shout out to one of my
favorite growers route 305
let's send a thank you shout out to jay
dutch i'll send a thank you shout out to
one of my favorite photographers adhd
grower then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to know me by my guacamole
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the show on patreon
this is of course the part of the show
where i invite you to the dgc growers
cup that's right july 30th in fort
collins colorado the dude grows crew is
hosting the growers cup i do invite you
to join us i will be there with team
irie genetics many other great breeders
will be there many members of the dude
grows crew and the ire army will be
there hanging out it won't be the same
if you don't join us so come to the
party i look forward to seeing you there
i do want to send a big thank you shout
out to everybody who has been supporting
i redirect that's right i recently added
i redirect to the irie genetics website
there's been a great success thank you
for all the positive feedback i've been
getting a lot of updates and feedback
from a great customer service feedback
thank you i do appreciate that i do feel
like that is most of the rambling that i
had written down here for the start of
the show
i want to talk about something that i've
got called evolution of a strain and
then we will work our way into uh some
grow questions here i was recently in a
chat and somebody asked uh kind of how
long it takes from the time i make a
strain until it is released they're like
man didn't you make those like a long
time ago and why are you just now
putting them out and then i thought that
would be a great thing to talk about
here on the podcast so we're going to
talk about the evolution of a strain
when i make a new cross when i get a
male plant and a female plant i do some
pollen chucking and those plants make
magic happen how long from the time that
cross is made until those seeds are
actually released to the market let's
talk about the process that uh takes the
steps that takes uh just the way we do
that here we go we're gonna jump into it
let's just say that i'm gonna grow or
maybe somebody sends me a plant or i'm
working in my garden and i realize that
female plant right there would work
beautifully with that male plant over
there just something intuitively tells
me that or maybe i'm smoking a plant and
i go
this is really good but it's missing
this and then i go oh well this male
plant got that let's put those together
so there's an idea there's an inception
there's so a spawned idea in my brain
i've got to get the idea so i've got the
idea now i've got to cut some clones
i've got to clean out a room i've got to
get space there could be at this time
who knows i may have just put a room
into flower it could be 70 days before i
could [ __ ] do this project or i could
get it going right away so i've got the
idea in my head now i've got to get the
idea on paper i'm going to write this
down i want to breed plant a to plant b
and my goal is going to be to improve
the part of this plant that sucks kind
of get this straight from this plant
this is what i'm hoping for so i'm going
to write that down then i will cut a
bunch of clones the appropriate clones
to breed this project about female a and
male a and we're going to cut those
plants then i'm going to veg them then
we're going to put them in the flower
room then of course there will be some
pollen chuck and then six to eight weeks
later we'll have seeds and it takes
about a week for them to dry pull the
seeds out separate them get them all
packaged up from the time i start
cutting those clones to the time i
actually have usable packageable seeds
in my hands is probably somewhere around
16 to 20-ish weeks depending on how
large i want those plants to get
depending on how much space i've got
depending on which strains i'm working
with some veg much more quickly some
don't veg as rapidly so they've got to
go another week but it could be up to 20
weeks from the time i cut the clones
till i have the first seeds in my hand
ready to put into packages then from
there there's a lot of work to do so
let's just say i got the idea i wrote
down the goal i put the male plant the
female plant the room at the right time
they did their magic uh we let the seeds
harden up uh the seeds have been
harvested they get the plants get are
the plants get harvested they get cut
down the plants dry pull the seeds out
separate them it's been 20 weeks now
let's talk about the other steps that it
takes this is where the work really
begins before i can start releasing this
product we put 20 weeks into the grow
now i've got to harvest it package it up
and do some testing this is when i start
growing the seeds
it's been 20 weeks already and i don't
even know what i've made yet i'm going
to grow these seeds i'm going to veg
them out for just a couple of weeks
they're going to be really little on my
first run my tester plants are tiny they
go in a one gallon pot they veg till
they're about eight or nine inches tall
and then i flip them and then i take a
lot of pictures and a lot of notes so
the first step the first step is to make
the seeds we already established that's
about a 20 week process then i'm going
to grow them i'm going to veg for two
weeks then i'm going to flower for 10
weeks we're already up to approximately
a 30 week process and all i've done is
test the seeds myself nobody else has
even grown these yet so once i grow them
if i approve then i package up testers
and i go recruiting the test team to get
some seeds going for me now they're
going to take a week or two to get the
seeds then they're going to take two to
four weeks to veg though some guys go
even longer so we're looking at 40 weeks
already then they've got nine to ten
more weeks of flowering that's 50 weeks
you guys we're at nearly a year two more
weeks is a full year
so that is several weeks of work before
we even really get to put a seed out to
market i've got to make it then i've got
to test it i've got to send it out to
the testers now it's oftentimes when i
see that the testers are having success
with these seeds i will add them as
freebies to orders if you're getting
seeds off of ire direct then you will
get some brand new [ __ ] as freebies
those are testers instead of just
putting them out as test seeds i also
give them that give them away they're
labeled on the package that they're
testers that i don't know what they're
going to do yet i make it clear this is
a freebie tester but here you go have
fun with it what then happens after i
give those testers away a lot of those
people will grow those before they even
grow the seeds they paid for because
they got some brand new exciting [ __ ]
they weren't expecting they're gonna
grow that then i get even more feedback
because now i've got the feedback i got
from the crop i grew i get feedback from
my testers now i get feedback from the
people that are growing it as freebies
so i test it the group tests it then it
goes out as freebies now i'm getting a
bunch of photos i'm getting a bunch of
data and a bunch of feedback and we know
what we've really got at this point if
it's gotten this far i know it's going
to make it it won't get this far if it's
not going to make it if if i didn't like
it if the testers didn't approve of it
if there were problems it just got
scrapped it got put on the back burner
it got forgotten about those seeds are
probably flushed down the toilet or in a
compost bin or fed to the birds so
once we once i see enough people growing
and i've got pictures and photos and
data then i can start hyping it up i
know it's going to come out for an
official release what i may do at this
point is do kind of a pre-release on my
website or another website a lot of
times i will pick one vendor and i will
do an exclusive drop with that one
vendor a lot of times it is seeds here
now because that's my preferred
exclusive vendor but sometimes i will
rotate it around to where vendor a is
going to get these packs on this day and
then vendor b is going to get these
packs on this day that way i don't
overload one vendor everybody gets to
play somebody gets to everybody gets to
eat the money gets spread around the
business gets moved around i like to
support all of the vendors because they
do support me and they support you the
consumer
so at this point we have gone from me
making seeds me testing seeds the test
crew testing out seeds the freebies
going out now they are going to a
pre-drop at one vendor or on my website
we'll just put out a few of them we'll
let them go we'll see what the
excitement is like what the hype is like
get a count of how many sell and how
quickly then that lets me prepare for
the official drop where i will call up
all the vendors and say hey i got this
many packs how many do you want they'll
claim their packs i'll send it out to
them and we will all agree that at five
o'clock on this day they are going on
sale we'll all drop them on our websites
all at the same time sometimes that
process is over one full year many of
the seeds that you guys see me putting
out on the websites right now the seeds
that are dropping on i redirect were
made a solid year maybe 18 months ago
you'll notice the inspector royale
it is on the website on the iredirect
website right now it will make a huge
debut at the dgc growers cup i will have
plenty there that one was made in a
greenhouse approximately a year ago
those seeds were made uh we put plants
outdoors already in that greenhouse
again and i am just now dropping those
seeds so that that is what goes into
testing and ensuring that a seed is a
quality product i don't just make some
seeds and throw them out there i've got
these seeds sitting around being tested
they're in storage they're in a jar
they're in a vault they're being saved
and preserved for up to a year before
you guys get to get them because i want
to make sure it is a quality product
oftentimes
i'll make a small batch of these seeds
and we'll test those and once i realize
if it's a real big hit then i'll go back
and make a lot more sometimes that's
really time consuming i try to bang it
out on the first run so we could keep
moving forward remake stuff that really
sells well and move past the [ __ ] that
doesn't but that is the inception of a
seed sometimes from the time i think
about it to the time you get your first
batch of seeds is up to a solid year so
be patient with me be understanding
there's a lot of work to be done also as
a consumer as a buyer as a customer as a
grower you should be excited that i'm
spending a solid year doing research and
development on one package of seed so
that you don't get intersex plants dud
plants i really put a lot of care into
this is what i'm trying to say all right
that's what i wanted to talk about the
inception and evolution of a strain oh
there's one more part
before i will release a strain and this
was really frustrating shout out to my
buddy fiskell uh fiscal wanted to buy
some seeds off of me he's like you've
got that cross and i was like yeah but i
got a lot of them and he's like sell it
to me and i said i can't sell it until
i've got a name for it
he was throwing out names every day i
would get a list of names eventually
that one did become fist bump that's
available check out the fist bump on
irie direct all right that is all i've
got for the evolution of a strain let's
work our way into these emails that i
was talking about i've got a great email
right here in front of me this one comes
from my friend petepan007
and it goes a little bit like this it
says question maybe for the podcast this
is a good one bro it says a lot of
people are going on vacation right now
and harvest time always seems to fall on
one week you leave for vacay and then he
says the thing that i was going to say
right after that i need to plan better
yes uh you plan to the grow and the
vacation i bet your wife planned the
vacation i know how that [ __ ] goes but
you do need to plan better everyone's
got a calendar and a schedule and we got
alexa and siri to tell us when we [ __ ]
up
but planning is key right there but it
says my question is would you harvest
when things are looking super close at
about a week nine or would you wait and
cut them down when you get home thank
you bro i love your straightforward info
you give to us
i am petepan007 on the gram and your
awesome discord and you can say my name
you guys go follow petepan007 on the
gram and also join the discord server
check out the discord server there will
be a link in the show notes and in the
video description to get to the discord
let's talk about this it's summertime
people are going on vacation people are
traveling around i'm guilty i've been
all over the place i haven't left
colorado but i've been to every freaking
border of colorado in the past couple of
weeks here it's been no complaints it's
been great but it's time consuming it's
exhausting and the garden does almost
suffer at times because i'll catch
myself driving home going [ __ ] i hope
the plants are okay i hope the plants
are okay and they are but it's a little
nerve-wracking so
if you're gonna go on vacation
it will be less nerve-wracking if you
cut before you go but the plants will do
you better if you wait until you get
back
don't cut them until you get back
when in doubt always just give them that
extra week 10 days let them grow longer
you're gonna have better buds if you go
longer you'll have more bud better bud
more dense bud more flavor more potent
more potency so just wait i would cut
them down after the vacation go have a
good time go enjoy your trip go enjoy
the time with the family or whatever
you're doing and then when you get back
you've got something really cool to look
forward to you don't want to cut it down
right before you leave anyway because
then it's just going to hang there your
whole trip it may get too dry it may get
too crispy
you may need to do some adjustments you
can't burp it you can't put it in jars i
would wait till i get back
as for watering while you're gone i
would just soak them real hard right
before you go unless you've got a buddy
or a grow helper which i really i don't
like that most of the time they always
end
i hear more stories about the grow
helper [ __ ] up than helping all the
time but uh just water them real hard
before you go and then just let them
ride it out until you come back and
maybe you'll have some some buds that
are already drying on the stick for you
getting a little pre-harvest going but
my advice is always let them go a little
bit longer don't do them too early ever
unless that is absolutely what you got
to do and i hope you learned your lesson
bro plan ahead next time so you're not
on vacation during the harvest all right
thank you for the great message all
right the next question here comes from
my buddy alabama man big shout out to my
buddy alabama man thank you for all of
the support this is a good question it
says i hope all is well sir bro things
are great it's summertime i'm healthy
business is booming relationships are
good we've been having a good time uh
the world hasn't exploded yet so i guess
things are going quite well the question
says have you ever initiated a back
cross using pollen from the original
male
donor the original male donor using
pollen initiated a background so if i
had the original male
i probably wouldn't need to make a back
cross the reason i make a back cross
generally is because the male plant is
not present and i want to make seeds of
a female plant something we would call a
clone only
so generally
i wouldn't do that because i don't have
the original male pollen donor my main
goal when i'm making a back cross is to
replicate a female clone
so let's talk about how i make a back
cross since we're here uh what i would
do let's just say we want to make golden
goat back cross seeds people want golden
goat regular seeds they don't want the
femmes they want golden goat that's not
available because there's no male of the
golden goat available so what i did was
i took daybreaker daybreaker is a great
strain but it is completely different
than golden goat it is the opposite in
every way it's got big fat leaves it
grows kind of with a stretchier pattern
uh it's a little shorter and squatty but
stretchy at the same time if you grow
kush you know what i mean but it is
totally different than the golden goat
golden goat's got the big skinny sativa
leaves
really tight internode spacing so my
goal here i took a male daybreaker plant
and i pollinated a female golden goat
now when i found the plants that came
from there my goal was to replicate
golden goat so anything that looked like
daybreaker and that progeny got
immediately eliminated that was harder
to say than it looked the plants that
looked like daybreaker got cold from the
population right away i only needed
plants that look like golden goat and i
only needed a boy that looked like
golden goat so females got pulled right
away and plants that look like
daybreaker got pulled right away
eventually i narrowed it down to a male
plant they looked just like the golden
goat he grew the same way he had the
same leaf serrations he reacted the same
way to stress it looked just like the
original female golden goat it looked so
close to the original golden goat though
when i took leaves off and held it up to
the other leaves they matched perfectly
they had the same serration same ripple
it was a perfect match so i took the
pollen from my golden goat to daybreaker
cross
and it's a male that looks just like
golden goat i took that pollen and put
it on to the golden goat now my goal
here is to wash out the traits from that
daybreaker now we've got golden goat in
here twice daybreaker in here once
mathematically genetically this should
be mostly golden go the way that i saw
it in my prediction i thought that i
picked such a close golden goat dip
probably 80 to 90 percent of the
phenotypes should look just like golden
goat after we ran a bunch of the seeds
you guys have ran a bunch of them i'm
going to say 75 percent of them look
just like the original golden go so my
next step would be to back cross it
again in that process what i would do is
i would take the original golden goat
clone which is a female and i would find
some of those back cross the first
failure filial generation of the back
cross that's a back cross one i would
find a male out of there that looked
just like golden goat again and put that
pollen back on the original golden goat
clone again making a back cross number
two now the seeds that come out of there
should in theory if my selection was
done correctly
those should be approximately eighty
percent golden goat dominant phenotypes
maybe eighty two eighty four percent the
method here is to keep finding golden
goat looking males and putting that
pollen back onto the original golden
goat to solidify that golden goat trait
and in essence wash out all of the
traits of the daybreaker i don't want
the daybreaker in there i only used it
for that pollen for that one inception
for that one round to create some seeds
now my whole goal is to wash that out so
i don't think i would use the original
male pollen um
unless my goal is to lock in that male
trait but that doesn't seem necessary
because
i'm working with a female clone only now
let's hypothetically say
that a friend of mine got a seed of a
plant that i've been wanting forever but
it turned out to be a male i could
in theory take that male plant pollinate
a female create seeds find a female that
looks like the male that i want use that
original male to put on another female
and keep going but
i don't know what i'm looking for
because i don't have the original female
so it's kind of a wild goose chase there
i don't know exactly what my goal is
unless i can identify the female that
i'm looking for i need to know what it
grows like what it looks like
what it smells like so in most cases no
i would not initiate a back cross using
pollen from the original male pollen
donor if i had the original male then i
wouldn't need the back cross
um that is going backwards my whole goal
is to wash out the pollen from that
original male so i think that answers
the question i hope i answered the
question there if that did spark any
more questions please do follow up i
would love to hear from you the email
address of course is grow from your
heart at
hotmail.com let's keep moving i do have
a big stack of emails here right in
front of me this one comes from our
friend do they want their name said it
does not say if they want their name
said this one goes a little bit like
this it says yo rasta jeff i'm asking
about that 10 days in flowering on the
light change to 18 6. so let me recap a
little bit right there for about the
past year i've been talking about a
method where i turn my lights to 18
hours on and six hours off for the last
10 to 14 days of flowering many people
think that flushing is a myth if you do
or don't flush when you start flushing
just turn those lights back on to 18 6.
in my experience your buds will get
beefier they'll get more dense they'll
get fatter they may even finish up a few
days early that extra light really makes
the plants go faster i really think it
does a lot of great things so our friend
here is trying the 18 6 method and they
do ask how much ppfd should i run i'm
currently at about a thousand with 13
11. so that's a great switch from 13 11
to 18.6 that'll be a great cycle
but i would not recommend changing the
ppfd all i do is change the amount of
hours
changing the pepfd will be too many
variables in my opinion i wouldn't go up
i wouldn't go down i would just change
the amount of hours then you're going to
get more white without stressing them if
you change it to more light you may burn
them if you change it to less light it's
kind of pointless to increase the amount
of hours so i don't change anything i go
with the exact same amount of light the
same number of lights all i do is
increase the amount of hours which the
plants are given somebody else also
asked me if i do a ramp up if i do like
going from 12 12 do i do 13 hours one
day and then 14 the next no i go
straight from 12 12 to 18 on and six off
sometimes i'll even do 19 and five
that's a new thing i'm [ __ ] with
seems to be working the plants do seem
to enjoy that i've got one more question
for this episode this one comes from
another person who would like to remain
anonymous it says what is the reason
some plants lose their aroma at the end
of flower
there are a lot of things that could be
causing this this could be a nutrient
issue this could be a vpd issue this
could be a light intensity issue are
your lights too close and too hot to the
plant
the number one thing that breaks down
terpenes is heat so if you've got too
much heat in the room the terps are
getting destroyed so the first thing i
would do is check on the heat check the
vpd how hot is it in that room maybe get
it a little bit cooler toward the end of
harvest uh cold temperatures later in
the grow will give you better flavors
aromas and also will bring out some
really cool colors and may really help
with the density of your buds so this
could be a feed issue
this could be a vpd issue this could be
a lighting issue this also could be a
genetics issue are you not cutting down
on time are you letting them go too long
are they simply going into senescence
and just giving up are you not feeding
them long enough are you feeding them
too long are you feeding anything to
enhance the terpenes are you giving it
anything to make it smell good what are
you doing um there are several things
that i would check on i would check on
like i've already said temperature
that's my number one uh culprit for
killing terps then i would check on
light intensity how far from the canopy
is your light is it just roasting your
terps you should be able to tell by
looking at the plants
do you have plenty of airflow in there
do you have bugs then i would make sure
that you're feeding something to
encourage healthy plants i can't see the
room i don't have a lot of details but
those are things that i do think could
make plants lose their smell at the end
of flower all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pams hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters and paul
and chuckers all of you beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there i do want
to thank you for listening to another
episode of the grow from your heart
podcast this one may get short after a
little bit of editing i do apologize if
i have to cut a bunch of nonsense out of
the middle of this i got quite rambly
lost my track anyway if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining maybe you just like to
throw me a couple of bucks because i
helped you out in the garden all you
have to do is check out patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again
there is a link in the show notes and in
the video description to make it super
easy for all of my friends to support
the show everything else is on the
website at iregenetics.com
there is a link to the discord there's a
link to i redirect there's a link to the
grow help tab anything you can imagine
at iregenetics.com
that is all i've got for you for this
episode you know i'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
jh and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you