[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode 761
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a
couple of listener emails before i get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to og roach and the devil's
weed let's send a big thank you shout
out to randy farms in growing tennessee
i want to send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to noah ann and just
to smoking let's send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy ars kickerson i
want to send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to shoe trader 101 and stash
drop 269. let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to dreadlocked
farmer i want to send a big thank you to
kojaks let's send a special thank you to
my buddy grow man stan then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
do9419
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show this is the
part of the episode where i invite you
to the dgc growers cup that's right july
30th in fort collins colorado the dude
grows crew is throwing the growers cup
team ivory genetics and several other
breeders will be there a lot of members
of the irie army and the dude grows crew
will be there the dude will be there
scotty will be there guru will be there
i will be there white mike will be there
it will be a good time it will not be
the same if you are not there so i do
invite you to the dgc growers cup july
30th make sure you check out
dudegrows.com
for tickets details and all of the
information you may need
i also want to take a quick minute to
thank everybody who was supported i
redirect if you check out my website
iriegenetics.com
there is a tab that says i redirect big
thank you to everybody who is supported
i redirect if you have not gotten your
tracking number yet please do send me an
email i will get that tracking number
out to you as soon as possible
all right i did start off the show by
talking about listener emails that i was
going to read let's jump right into that
portion of the show this one comes from
our friend chase and it goes a little
bit like
this it says yo what if you have a pack
of femme seeds but you really want to
breed or make seeds can you just use sts
on a female plant and get normal seeds
or will they always be feminized that is
a very good question
if you only have fem seeds there is not
a way to make a male plant unless you do
something to one of those female plants
to make it create pollen so
without introducing a male plant to that
mix without having some male pollen
there is no way to make regular seeds
your seeds will always be female unless
you do introduce a male if you do put a
male plant into the mix and you
pollinate a female a feminized female
plant with a regular male plant the
seeds that come from that will be male
and female it's all about that pollen
donor so your original question is if
you've only got fems and you want to
make seeds can you make a female plant
get normal seeds or will they always be
femmed
these will always be femmes if you only
have femmes to work with you're only
going to make more fems there is nothing
wrong with breeding from feminized seeds
but i would recommend doing some sort of
outcrossing not just taking it further
filial generations i would add some more
plants to the mix but this is your
project you do what you want breed with
love grow from your heart most
importantly have a good time i hope i
answered your question the real quick
answer they're always going to be
females uh and then i do encourage you
to do your breeding project all right
big shout out to my buddy chase for the
great question
let's keep it moving i've got another
question here this one says hey man can
i use rain water instead of distilled
water the quick answer is going to be
you could you can
i would at least do a basic water test
maybe uh find out what's in that water
maybe at least check the ec in the uh
the tds of that water definitely check
the ph but maybe do a quick test and
find out what's in there it kind of
depends on what's in your area i live
near a steel mill that puts off a lot of
disgusting chemicals the rain in my area
will probably have steel mill chemicals
in it which will end up in my plants
which is probably going to be some form
of heavy metals or some sort of junk i
don't want in my plants honestly i don't
know enough about water science and what
can travel through the water and through
the air that way to have a solid
testimony but i wouldn't recommend it if
you live
in the city or near chemical plants or a
lot of factories and [ __ ] if you're on
the trees and out in the woods where the
water tastes good then i would
definitely recommend it then i would use
that water but before i use any water
that doesn't come from a regulated sort
of a municipal system and municipal
source i would check on it see what's in
that water if you don't have a way to
test it if you can't scoop up some water
and take it to a water testing place or
at least do a little bit of testing on
your own maybe at least just feed it to
a couple of plants before you give it to
the entire garden and see what a few
plants do that is my version of testing
if you were isolated don't have a lot of
resources so the short answer is yes you
can use rainwater but think about what
are you collecting the water in how are
you collecting it what is that water
running over as you collect it is it
running off of your roof of your house
onto your car then into a bucket are you
actually collecting it in some sort of a
semi-clean manner where you're not
gathering a bunch of [ __ ] whatever it
washes over it's going to end up into
your collection vessel i'm not trying to
discourage you but i want it to be clean
now something that caught my attention
you said you're using distilled water
why what are you using distilled water
for why are you doing that that's um
nobody else does that we use filtered
water
maybe ro water maybe water that went
through a big boy most of the time my
water here in colorado is pretty cool i
just run for the home grow i don't even
use a filter for the commercial grow i
choose a big boy so i'm not sure why
you're using distilled water that may
not be the best idea but if it ain't
broke don't fix it all right thank you
for the great question that one came
from our friend joseph i told you i had
a few messages here in front of me we're
just going to keep cooking right through
them this one came from you know we're
not going to say their name because they
have a question that says should i worry
if my buds have started throwing nanners
at week six of flour then it says in
light depth um
yes i would be concerned if my plants
started showing nanners at week six of
flour that is a sign of intersex
or hermaphroditism which is not
desirable when it comes to a cannabis
plant we don't want that trait
those nanners if they are uh if they're
viable they can have pollen in them
they'll open up and they will pollinate
at least the buds right next to them
possibly the entire crop and having
nanners at week six is not a good thing
i would definitely kind of freak out a
little bit since you say it's a light
depth garden i'm going to assume that
there is a little bit of a light leak
somewhere probably right where you're
seeing those nanners light is probably
getting in there when you think it is
dark that would be my main assumption so
i would uh assess the situation see if
you've got total darkness if not correct
that then i would work on what to do
with these uh intersex plants you've got
a couple of options are they throwing
just a few nanners if it's just a few
maybe you could cut them out if it's a
lot i would really start freaking out if
it's just a couple
spray them with water and pluck them out
with tweezers and then keep an eye on
that plant
if they reappear you got [ __ ] to think
about if they don't come back you're
okay if you've got a lot i would
probably just cut them down you are past
the point now
where i don't think those plants are at
risk of getting seeded but it still
isn't going to make the crop any better
to have a hermaphroditic plant inside of
the
the greenhouse the what is it a hoop
house probably in the light depth
situation
so it is probably detrimental to that
crop i would pay very close attention if
you've got all clones of the same strain
it's a very good likelihood it could
happen across the room if you got
different strains different plants will
have different resistances also again i
would check um wherever that plant is i
bet you it's on an outer edge at a
corner or something where the tarp isn't
covering perfectly at night maybe the
wind is blowing it's still daytime
outside but it's nighttime in your grow
environment the wind is blowing there's
a crack in the tarp something like that
the light's coming in right there that
is probably right where the culprit with
the intersex plant will be found so uh
yes you should worry if your buds have
started throwing manners at week six of
flower that is called an intersex plant
that is a breeder's nightmare that's
also a grower's nightmare i hope you've
ran this plant in a smaller environment
to figure out if it's a good plant
before you put it out in the light depth
either way sounds like you've got some
problems time to start thinking about
what to do
all right this next question is sort of
a change of pace this one is a little
bit different and it goes a little bit
like this it says i have sent someone
who is very popular in the cannabis
field 500 pheno hunted seeds he was
supposed to work with and his girls too
oh and add his girls too so our friends
sent 500 i'm not sure what you mean by
feno hunted seeds you can't really
phenoh hunt they haven't been pheno
hunted yet he's got tofino hunt them
maybe they were especially bred or
specially selected seeds anyhow our our
listeners sent 500 seeds to a very
popular grower who was supposed to work
with them and add his girls to the mix
this popular breeder claims he lost all
of the seeds that's kind of sketchy
sounds sketchy to me it says my question
is what's the best way to do a collab
with someone without them [ __ ] you
over my other question well let's talk
about that part first best way to do a
collab without getting [ __ ] over uh
build a solid relationship work with
people that you know
um
meet people face to face it's great that
we're making friends on the internet and
we're so spread out and that like-minded
people in one part of the country are
meeting like-minded people in the other
part of the country and we're doing [ __ ]
together
but if you're gonna send somebody 500
seeds and it bothers you enough that
you're gonna send me an email about it
maybe you need to meet these people face
to face shake hands make an agreement do
some things like that before you go into
business like this my other line of
thought is um this is partly why
sometimes i don't do business with some
of my friends
i started doing when i started my
business my company i relied on friends
for a lot of their services i like
having my stuff made by my friends
because then they get to make some money
their business moves my business moves i
see them get to buy groceries with the
money that i gave them and then my
business moves there's moves it feels
good
but sometimes it's hard to do business
with your friends because when your
friends mess up
like let's just say that random company
messed up let's just say that cloud who
makes this this is called the cloud
lifter let's say cloud [ __ ] up i could
call them and cuss them out because i
don't know them
just not a problem hey my thing [ __ ]
up i need a new one if they give me
problems on the phone i go no listen it
broke it has a warranty send me a
[ __ ] new one if i do business with my
friends and [ __ ] goes wrong it's like no
it's okay buddy i'll just eat the loss
went deep down inside you're like [ __ ] i
needed to make that money and now both
of our businesses are not gonna work and
i got weird [ __ ] animosity toward you
and you you think you're getting one
over on me and i don't like that you're
getting one over on me and this is gonna
last forever ah
that [ __ ] sort of sucks so a lot of the
times i choose to not even do business
with my friends at this point if there's
somebody else out there that can do the
job i may hit them up for it um if
you've recently done artwork for me or
done some [ __ ] don't feel like i'm
saying you're not my friend i'm saying
in most cases uh but
uh i do love feeding my friends and
giving my friends work but oftentimes
i'll just skip them and go somewhere
else because it it causes less headaches
honestly but don't let that sway you
don't let that stop you from doing
business with your friends with your
crew how i started saying this was build
solid relationships with solid people
spend time with people get to know them
vet them see how they act go to dinner
with somebody how do they treat the wait
staff are they cool to the waiter are
they cool to the waitress are they
respectful do they treat the waiter do
they treat the waiter just like they
treat you or do they treat the waiter
like their waiter is a piece of [ __ ]
that stuff matters you'll learn a lot
about those people so just go spend a
few minutes spend some time with them
before you jump into big 500 seed
relationships and business proposals
with this people so
the best way to do a collab is to do it
with somebody that you trust and you
know and that there's a reason for you
to be doing the collab
i'm not just doing collabs with random
people on the internet because there are
plenty of other people that i know and
trust and have a reputation that i am
doing collabs with and it works better
that way so the best way to do it is
just build a reputation the other option
is contracts you can write a contract
contracts are very easily uh established
written drawn up however you want to do
it legalzoom.com will throw you out a
very simple contract for a very good
price they do not even pay me to
advertise them legalzoom.com will get
you out of so much hot water they'll
save you so much headache check them out
they'll help you out you can get a
contract or maybe you've got a basic
lawyer or maybe you could just find a
basic contract online that will cover
what you need done but have an agreement
have it in writing have a paper trail my
expectation is this you agreed to do
this together we expect to do this the
outcome will be this the proceeds and
profits will be divided this way in the
case that this goes wrong this is how we
will deal with it have all that [ __ ] in
paper in writing before you get to that
point that's why when you go to the car
dealership you got to sign your
signature 7 thousand times they're
covering their ass every way that they
can so that you two are entering a
contract you're saying i'm gonna get
this car they're gonna give you the car
the bank is gonna help you out you don't
get any extra [ __ ] other than what's on
the car but you do have a warranty
you've all got to sign all of that [ __ ]
so that if anything comes up every nut
and bull on that car is covered you've
got to do the same thing when it comes
to making a contract with your friends
with your partners when it comes to a
500c deal i would definitely have some
sort of arrangement some sort of
protection in place but first of all man
meet these people
uh go shake their hands be friends see
if they're cool see how they interact
with the community see how are they cool
with their girlfriend are they cool with
wait staff are they cool with their
grandma see who they're cool with see
see how they act in traffic just see how
they are you can learn a lot about
people it says my other question is
because he says he lost my seeds
shouldn't he pay me for my time and
effort he's now going to send me 100
seeds of his and his pollen but i feel
i'm owed more for all of my time and
effort a year of projects lost what do
you think
i think that if you would have had that
contract with a stipulation of if you
lose my seeds then i get to take your
firstborn child and i get to smash your
car with a hammer you probably wouldn't
have lost the seeds you might not have
signed the contract
also get your contract notarized but
that's a whole other can of worms he
probably would not have gone into
business with you if you would have been
uh more strict more of a stickler people
that have contracts and cover their
asses don't get taken advantage of so
the other part of this was uh he should
pay you for your time and effort but
who determines what your time and effort
is worth is that you or is that him you
probably both totally disagree on what
your time and effort is worth you
probably totally disagree on what your
seeds and pollen are worth uh you feel
you're owed more uh it was a year of
projects lost what do you feel a year
worth of breeding projects was worth uh
not only the year worth of the seeds but
the year it sets you back the year you
could be in progress that's a lot of
stuff to think about right there
so
um man this is there's a lot to think
about here i would have had a contract
in place i would have had agreements in
place i would have had goals in place
and
500 seeds is a lot to send somebody that
you don't really know at all and really
have a bonafide relationship with so
my advice um your first question is how
do i do a collab without someone [ __ ]
me over get to know people understand
how they do business understand how they
operate
are they hiding behind the internet or
are they right here transparent with
their face out on the internet pay
attention to stuff like that the second
question is um he lost my seeds
shouldn't he pay me
of course we shall be paid for our
product our time and our energy but
how do we determine how much that was
worth without some sort of that's why
you decide how much the car is worth
before you test drive it so that way if
you crash it they know how much you got
to [ __ ] pay them
so my advice is next time have some
contracts in place have some
preparations in line have an agreement
and stop messing with people who you
can't trust all right thank you for the
great message i would say your name but
you did not say if you wanted on here
you know who you are thank you my friend
for the great support
all right i've got one more email
question here in front of me that i want
to read on this show this one came from
my buddy newbie nuggs shout out to my
buddy noob nuggs what's up bro hope
you're well the question goes a little
bit like this it says hey ross to jeff i
have a question about when a seed
description says indica and sativa
percentages is this just breeder's
opinion from the phenos they have grown
or tested and seen or an estimation
based on what's in the lineage or some
lab tested data to come up with this
number thank you for everything you do
bro this is a really good question i
think i could ramble on this one for a
couple of good minutes here
um currently we are shifting away from
the terms indica and sativa those are
going to be expired terms in the next
few years we're going to have updated
new modern terms for that broadleaf drug
cultivar and weird [ __ ] like that are
all gonna take over but we're gonna have
to reassess what we're calling indica
and sativa one author says we got it
backwards a long time ago we've been
doing it wrong a lot of authors say that
those are expired terms i know what you
mean when you say indica and sativa so
they are valid terms for the purpose
we're using them right here most of the
time an indica plant is going to be your
shorter squatty plant with the big white
leaves when you smoke it you get a
little bit more of a mellow buzz you
want to chill out the things we call
sativa are usually a taller thinner
plant with the skinnier leaves when you
smoke that you get that psychedelic buzz
you want to get up and do [ __ ] we're
going to stick with that description for
sativa and indica for the purpose of
this podcast question so is it just
breeder's opinion based on phenos
they've grown
honestly there's no really like uh tried
and true hard and fast system or way to
identify this it is honestly um the
breeders we kind of take the plant that
we started with the two plants we say
well that one's like 50 sativa 50 indica
this one's like 70 30 and we breed them
and then we have a kind of a prediction
i've always got a prediction when i put
them together then we just see how they
grow a lot of times most of the stuff
that i breed is straight up sativa heavy
because i am breeding for that sativa
head buzz so we kind of watch the
phenotypes that come out watch the
majority of the phenotypes and then when
i say that is 70 30 that's because out
of all of the plants that i have seen
the majority of them would be on that
average it's based on the average of
what i see there are always going to be
outliers there are going to be
phenotypical differences
outliers anomalies and everything in
every population when it comes to
working with plants or anything with
nature with genes and chromosomes any
kind of breeding there will be outliers
but
the way that i compile most of my
information is by watching a lot of
grows i grow the seeds i've talked in a
previous episode about testers growing
it i give it out as freebies we start
selling it i'm constantly updating
descriptions and details about my
strengths as i see things evolve so
basically the way that i do it is i
watch the plants if i see traits i know
that that's an indica trait if i watch
traits i know that that's a sativa trait
so i just decide overall by what i've
seen from every version of that plant if
you've grown a million seeds of dark
hollow and i see how it grows then i say
70 of those is an indica we're going to
call it mostly indica just i use it by
observation and details and then just
base it off of averages of what i see is
how i do it i cannot speak for other
breeders i can't tell you how other guys
are doing things sometimes i have no
idea how they're doing some of those
things honestly those ah those phrases
indica and sativa are going to disappear
i've stopped putting that on my website
uh most of what i make is really heavy
sativa if it's indica then i do try to
indicate that this is more of an indica
dominant thing if you're looking for
indica stuff in my lineup i would
recommend the moon tower the dark hollow
maybe the double dose
and in the future there will be some
more stuff that is a little bit indica
heavy for you maybe some indica dominant
crosses coming in the future i did hint
that there may be an indica male in the
vault all right newbie nugs i do thank
you for the great question i hope i gave
you a useful answer it feels like i kind
of danced around it and avoided it but
honestly there's no real tried and true
way you asked if there's a lab test
there's not really a lab test it would
tell you if it's indica or sativa a lot
of it is based on growth structure leaf
size and then i think a lot of it is
determined by terpenes how does it feel
when we smoke it what kind of buzz does
it give us so i wish i had a better
answer for you i make my decision by
looking at plants and just deciding is
this indica or is this sativa
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters and pollen
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i do want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
761 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you have any questions corrections
comments or concerns you know that i
would love to hear from you my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com
if you feel like this episode was
educational informative or entertaining
maybe you just want to throw me a couple
of bucks because i made you giggle or i
helped your garden all you have to do is
check out
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart all of the information you need
will be right there on the screen once
again big thanks to everybody who
continues to support the show everything
else you could possibly need will be on
my website at
iregenetics.com you guys my voice is
burning out i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i want to
give a big shout out to my friend james
bean and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you