[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me ross to
jeff this is episode 762
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to answer a few
listener emails before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend girls grow too let's send a
big thank you shout out to crafted
flower and anvil gardens let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
levity loveday and james brown i want to
send a big thank you shout out to
froggle rock and quasi let's send a
thank you shout out to jimmy limmer and
danny potts let's send a big fist bump
to g7 and terp burglar then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
buddy kes burton big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show on patreon
this is the part of the show where i
invite you once again to the dude grows
growers cup that's right july 30th in
fort collins colorado the dude groves
crew is hosting the growers cup i do
invite you to join us team irie genetics
the dude grows crew and a bunch of
members of the community will be there i
look forward to joining you for all of
the info do check out
dudegrows.com
all right i said i was going to answer a
few listener emails on this episode
let's not waste a lot of time this first
message came from our friend on patreon
big shout out to my buddy kip this one
says yo ross to jeff i hope you're
having a great monday it is a beautiful
day it is super hot but i'm adjusting i
apologize if you do hear the air
conditioner in the background i'm not
turning it off it's hot we're going to
keep that thing flowing anyway it says i
just received my ire direct order and i
noticed an extra 10 pack of seeds so our
friend has discovered the irie direct
page if you go to iregenetics.com you
will see the tab that says i redirect
make sure you check that out our friend
has seen that link and it says i
received my order and received an extra
10 pack of seeds i know you said on a
recent podcast that you do occasionally
send out testers
but i just wanted to make sure i didn't
get a whole extra pack by mistake
you are correct i do send out testers
but i make sure that people know they
are getting testers i make sure they can
run them right away that they are
prepared we have a conversation what you
got my friend was a gift i know that
people work hard for their money i know
that uh money is expensive the only way
to get money is by putting in your time
your effort and your energy we don't
have a lot of time uh we're bombarded by
life as humans so i understand that you
work really hard for your money and when
you buy seeds from me i appreciate it
and to show everybody their thank you
for and their appreciation for buying
seeds i make sure to include some
freebies with every single order so
those were a gift to you from me to say
hey thank you you didn't have to buy
seeds from me you could have bought from
hundreds of other seed makers i'm sure
there are thousands of seed makers out
there that you could have chosen to give
your money and i appreciate that you
chose to send your money my direction so
to say thank you my friend you got 10
extra seeds i do appreciate you noticing
thank you for asking enjoy them if you
don't have room to grow them now send
them to a friend grow them next time
they're extras they're yours they're a
gift thank you bro i do appreciate your
support all right anybody else out there
if you do get extra beans in your order
uh have no fear those are yours you can
grow them you can share them with a
friend like i said if you don't have
space or time to grow them right now
share them with the grower in need if
you know somebody that needs some beans
pass them out spread the love the next
time you order seeds from me the caramel
will probably double up it will work out
in your favor
all right this next question does come
from the youtube channel it is a comment
left on a video i don't usually take
questions from the youtube but this one
looks like a good thing i should mention
i could ramble about for a couple of
seconds it comes from our buddy local
grow guy what's up local grow guy i hope
you see this episode of the show it says
great show brother much respect you need
to do a live q a show youtube followers
would love it just thought
just they thought much love and stay
safe that is a really good message um my
answer is i do a live show every monday
on instagram every monday around 7 10
p.m mountain time i'm in colorado i go
live mountain time i don't know what
time zone you are in i'm in mountain
time so every monday approximately 7 10
it could be 705 it could be 7 15.
sometimes the internet gives me some
trouble i usually get there as quickly
as i can about 7 10 ish i go live i take
dabs i hang out i answer questions and
everybody in the instagram is able to
type in and ask me questions i do my
best to answer every single question
that comes in through the instagram live
and honestly some of my favorite
questions get written down and recycled
and i do make a full podcast out of them
because i don't feel i don't i'm not
prepared on the live show it's like
stump the grower people can ask me
whatever they want so people ask a lot
of random crazy questions ask grow
questions music questions questions
about random [ __ ] questions about
sneakers i'm a sneaker head if you're
not aware of that so join us monday on
instagram the instagram is irie
underscore genetics i r i e
underscore genetics that is me on
instagram follow me on instagram look
for the notification on monday around 7
10 p.m i will go live we will hang out
you'll be able to type in all of your
grow questions your random questions and
i will do my best to answer all of them
on the fly live maybe in the future i do
need to learn how to do a live uh q a on
youtube but for now we're sticking with
the instagram i do it every monday i've
been doing it for several years it has
become kind of a tradition a lot of
people jump in and check it out so join
us once again irie underscore genetics
on instagram every monday 7 10 p.m it's
not as well produced as this podcast i
edit this i write notes i have a plan
for this on monday i bring the dab rig
and a bunch of good dabs and a couple of
cold beverages and we just hang out and
get lit and i try to answer the
questions as quickly as possible as
accurately and thoroughly as possible
without any preparation any study so
that keeps it fun that keeps me on my
toes keeps my brain active also a good
time to just kind of hang out with the
crew and take some dabs and talk some
[ __ ] all right i do have another
question right here in front of me this
one came from patreon this comes from
our buddy who calls himself f a plant
count bro i know what you mean f your
plant count that's how i feel
let me do what i need to do although i
do have to follow the rules because
everybody knows who i am by now anyway
this message came from patreon shout out
to the patreon crew it goes a lot like
this yo rasta jeff what's up my brother
i hope everything is irie bro things are
pretty good uh it's a hundred and
something degrees outside and it is nice
and cool in here i got a frosty cold
beverage in front of me i took a few fat
dabs uh shout out to my friend who uh
teleported me manifested somehow the
lemon jeffrey dabs that [ __ ] is great uh
you know who you are bro i just don't
want to uh you know anyway we're live
here on the show it says thank you for
answering my last question about
reversing a male i really appreciate it
i've grown a few dozen strains but i'm
coming across an anomaly which i've
never seen before those are my favorites
i love anomalies all right it goes on it
says i am growing end game rbx punchline
by ethos that is a very
creative long name it says i've come
across a phenotype that virtually does
not pistol out so it's not making any of
the things that you guys call hairs
which are the breeding parts of the
female plant it is not making any of
those which is kind of rare it says both
phenos i have through very little
pistols in the stretch phase now at day
50 one house beautiful dense hairless
nugs top to bottom and stinks like
swedish fish and hubba bubble hubba
bubba gum had an orgies so if we took
some swedish fish hubba bubba gum and we
had an orgy with them that's what this
plant would smell like that doesn't
sound too bad in my mind smells kind of
sweet and juicy i enjoy that smell
he does go on it says the other plant
has hairless maine colas all the lower
golf balls got pistols late and flower i
spoke with other people growing this and
it seems to be common i remember you
mentioning some wonky things happen
after a few reversals down the line and
i can count at least three or four that
went into these is this a mutation that
comes from reversals i don't know that
it's a mutation
i could just be a trait maybe just a uh
i don't know necessarily it's a mutation
because i i i don't have the
qualification to identify that that is
uh
a a definition of a mutation it is
definitely a trait that we're noticing
and it's a commonality if a lot of
people are getting it um it goes on it
says uh do you think these plants would
be sterile i would assume so
but i have no way of being certain i'm
gonna keep going as i took three clones
of the hairless girl and put them
outdoors i already assume putting them
outside may give them a different
phenotypical expression you may see a
lot different stuff you may not it says
but i figured no pistols no pollination
and i would have to worry less about my
outdoor crop being pollinated by a
careless neighbor or something that is a
really great
idea a really great assumption a really
great hope
but i would take one of those plants and
put it indoors and attempt to pollinate
it just once just to see what happens
being the
highly inquisitive curious person uh
there wants to know i just want to know
what if i would take that pistol-less
plant and i would put it in a room with
a male plant and i would just put some
pollen on it or i've always got some
pollen in a fridge or in a freezer i'd
grab some of that pollen and just dust a
couple of plants with that or a couple
of clones of this plant with that and
see what happened and see if you can
make any seeds out of it then you would
know that those are sterile or not but
your assumption is great that plant will
probably not take pollen as well
probably make fewer seeds that could be
a really good plant for you the problem
is how do you get more seeds off of that
you've got to keep cloning it or make a
bunch of clones is the only way that one
carries
that is the end game
there's something that we used to hear
about wow this is old cannabis laura i
didn't mean to talk about this how long
have i been going all right we're going
to get off on a side right here there's
a thing that they talk about back in the
day that is known as the terminator gene
which was bred into plants so i don't i
don't do this i don't know how to do
this honestly if i read up on it i could
figure out it's not something i want to
do
um some breeders a breeder somewhere
along the line discovered how to breed
plants and breed what is called the
terminator gene into it if you breed
certain filial generations into each
other you can create sterile plants
basically and i don't know exactly how
to do it but it's uh i think it's an
octopoid or from what i i've spent so
long since i read it i'm not going to
ramble and get it wrong but there is the
terminator gene where you can breed it
to where the plants actually do not make
any more seeds they just stop they are
not fertile plants you'll get males
that'll kick out pollen but the females
do not take any pollen they don't make
pistols they cannot get pollinated
they're sterile they're non-fertile is
the word my brain is searching for as i
ramble so it is possible i'm not making
any assumptions or accusations i am
saying it as an option then maybe our
friend has bred in the terminator gene
by accident here or it just popped up or
maybe these plants will breed completely
we have no evidence of either direction
but these are all possibilities let me
make sure i got to the bottom of this
message it says i can't wait to pop your
wombat femmes in a couple of weeks
thanks for your time much love from our
friend who calls themselves joe
jizz you're doing so great till that
part bro no i'm just kidding i love the
creative name uh i think you do have the
great assumption that since these plants
have fewer pistols than most plants that
they won't receive pollen but i would
hate to find out the wrong way ah that
would definitely be the way to make an
ass of you and me so maybe put it
indoors hit it with some pollen see what
it does then put it outside sounds like
you've already done it so we're gonna
put it to the true test if any of your
neighbors are out there with some stray
pollen that plant will get it if it
makes seeds then it makes seeds that's
the only way to find out though is to
pollinate that [ __ ] and to find out
dude thank you for the great message
thank you for letting me talk about the
terminator gene on accident i had
forgotten all about that i will do more
research maybe you guys remind me i'll
try to do a show that involves more of
the terminator gene all right this next
message does come from patreon big shout
out to the patreon crew once again
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart this one comes from our friend
aron and it goes just like this it says
how about an in-depth conversation about
getting into the cannabis industry that
is a very good topic that we can talk
about what i'm going to cover is what i
know i know how to get into the uh
basically the legal what i'm going to
cover today is getting into the legal
colorado cannabis industry the marijuana
enforcement division regulated legal
cannabis industry the big grows that
produce legal cannabis for the legal
dispensaries that's what i'm going to
focus on today because any other
cannabis business or getting into the
industry
you have to kind of find your niche it
doesn't i didn't mean to even do this
when i started this brand this seed
company i think i invented this on my
own on accident i made seeds people
wanted them
i sold some of them people wanted more
it just kind of snowballed eventually i
had a seed company i was breeding out of
passion so if you're doing something
you're passionate about that you can
turn into a business
do that if you're doing something that
is ancillary of cannabis that you can
cater to this industry do that but one
thing i'm going to say before i jump
into talking about creating your own
cannabis or what i'm going to focus on
here is the legal side of the industry
is
don't turn your passion your favorite
thing into a career that could possibly
burn out your passion for whatever that
subject is um i used to be in the music
industry i'm not i'm not hyping it up
i'm not bragging this is just a story
here for you i used to play music
professionally i've been around the
country playing the drums with several
bands i've been on a lot of big stages
been on even more small stages been in a
lot of tiny [ __ ] clubs playing little
tiny shows but i've been all over the
place playing music i've been all over
making money that was my career playing
drums was my job that's what i did five
nights a week that's how i paid the
bills how i paid the rent how things
worked out for me
i also worked at guitar center for a
little while i was a department manager
obviously a drum department manager at
guitar center those two things combined
kind of
burnt me out on the desire to be around
and involved in music there was a time
when i would leave my job at guitar
center and most people when you get out
of work you probably walk out to the car
you get to the car you sit down and do
that oh i'm [ __ ] off work thing you
check your phone and you crank up some
music and get on the road right
that wasn't me i would get in the car
and hit the pipe as hard as i [ __ ]
could because i wanted to get super
stoned and get all the terrible guitar
sounds out of my head i don't want to
hear the intro to enter sandman i don't
want to hear [ __ ] back and black
anymore i don't want to hear stairway to
heaven i've been hearing it all day long
and it was just driving me crazy so i'd
get in the car and turn the music off
and try to get as stoned as i could
where i didn't hear music anymore
so it was kind of and then going on tour
it wasn't fun to be like well we've got
to play this gig but then we can't have
any fun because as soon as we're done we
got to get the gear off the stage and
get in the van and get to the next city
because we don't have we got to play in
12 hours in another city and we don't
even have that much time to drive there
it would just get hectic maybe not 12
hours but you see what i'm saying it
would burn you out to where playing the
drums was more it became work it wasn't
fun now that i don't have to show up for
a gig and play at a certain time when i
do get to beat on the drums it is so
joyous it is so much fun my point here
what i'm rambling forever about is don't
turn your cannabis career into what i
did with music
some there was a while when i didn't
want to go to a concert i didn't want to
go see live music because it just felt
like work i was like i'd rather just
miss this show and let myself start to
miss music again now i'm passionate
about music again but
don't let this happen to you
with cannabis don't uproot your whole
life to move to another state to get a
job as a tremor because you think it's
going to change your whole life being a
trimmer or being a grow tech or being a
dispensary bud tender
it could ruin your passion for cannabis
you're going to have hours you're going
to have goals you're going to have
expectations you're going to have bosses
around cannabis and do you want to
associate one of your favorite things
with work with stress with a paycheck
with a headache with bad customers with
a terrible boss with deadlines
expectations do you want to put that on
your favorite thing that is my advice to
you luckily fortunately beautifully i've
established a beautiful uh career a
place in this industry to where i love
it i cannot get burnt out on the city i
am passionate about i wake up thinking
about growing and smoking and consuming
cannabis and teaching you guys how to
grow a better herb so make sure that you
don't
put yourself in a position where you're
going to hate your life your career your
location and the plant because you
wanted to combine all of those things
into one thing keep some space
separation of plant and state i guess if
you will all right now let's talk more
about the email the [ __ ] that i did
write down if you want to get into the
legal marijuana enforcement division
regulated legal cannabis industry here
in colorado the first thing you have to
do is
do you qualify there's a checklist of
things on the marijuana enforcement
division uh can i get my badge checklist
there's a website you will go to i
should have written that down i didn't
you're gonna have to do some of the work
on your own there's a website marijuana
enforcement division you will see if you
qualify to even get a marijuana
enforcement division workers badge there
will be a few questions have you had any
felonies within the past few years um i
don't remember the exact questions i'm
not going to ask all of them right now
there's a questionnaire you have to find
out if you qualify if you've done some
things that they find unacceptable or
that you may need to correct you do not
qualify for the badge at this time which
means you shouldn't pack up and move to
colorado and try to get a weed industry
job because you can't even get the badge
before you even think about coming here
before you think about applying for a
job see if you qualify for that badge if
you can't come here check other states
there are so many other states
developing cannabis industries this
isn't the only place to go but this is
where i know the rules the process and
the steps it's what i can talk about
so do you qualify for the badge do you
maybe i don't know if you do get all the
required paperwork the money uh it costs
money to get it get the money together
then apply for the badge you may have to
come all the way to colorado just to
apply for the badge so when you come
here to apply for that badge i recommend
you
visit where you're going i've got a
friend who is on our patreon who listens
to the podcast what's up bro i hope
you're well i hope you're safe uh that
person decided that after listening to
the show and hearing about the industry
they were going to pack up their life
and move to the east side of pueblo
colorado and get a job in the cannabis
industry
that only took them about four days to
realize they do not want to be on the
east side of pueblo and they got out of
there as quickly as possible they've
been complaining to me in a friendly way
they've been venting about how not so
great their new location is and if they
would have moved here or visited here
i'm sorry if they would have visited
here for just a couple of days before
they moved here and set up shop they
probably would have realized they did
not want to move to where they were
moving so my advice to you is come visit
or go visit wherever you think you're
going to move if it's broomfield pueblo
denver longmont um what's down south
trinidad any of those places they're all
they all have good and bad things about
them go visit go see if it's for you
some places are for me some places are
simply not for me go see before you
uproot your whole life and move there to
grow weed first of all do you qualify
can you even get the badge the
requirements to work in the industry
then go see the place you're thinking
about going everybody tells big tales
and fantasies about what they do for
work when they grow places they want you
to think they're living the dream
they're not gonna tell you that it
[ __ ] snows for four months out of the
year and it's terribly [ __ ] cold
they're not gonna tell you about that
crazy [ __ ] but uh come visit that's what
i'm saying let me get back on my list
here um do you qualify get your badge
think about visiting when you get your
badge look at the places you think
you're gonna live shit's expensive get a
heads up before you move
then
search for jobs before you move when you
come out here to visit look at the
dispensaries around you look at the
grows around you
when if you want to be a grower when you
go to the dispensary ask is there a grow
attached to this facility and are they
hiring and they'll probably have no idea
they'll tell you how to apply they may
give you an application they may be able
to help you out if you want to work in
the dispensary just ask can i work here
i don't recommend shopping in the
dispensary in the same trip as you get
your application and or drop off your
application i don't want a customer
employee interaction at the same time
it looks to me as a hiring manager it
looks like you just happened to be here
buying weed and thought maybe i'll apply
do them in two separate transactions
just for professionalism that is my
advice when you do go to the interview
don't show up uh in your torn lead
zeppelin t-shirt and your sweatpants and
your dirty shoes
show up looking like you want a job
treat this just like any other job show
up for the job you want if you show up
looking like you don't really work hard
we're gonna think that you don't really
work hard clean up a little bit i do
have dreadlocks but i tie them up and
make them presentable shave a little bit
if you've got a good beard trim it up
manicure it you can have a beard and
look good i got dreadlocks when i take
care of myself you can be presentable
don't show up looking lazy don't show up
late don't show up high
that okay show up high i show up to
everything high but don't show up
noticeably high if they can tell you're
high you're not going to get the job bro
don't do that be sharp be present that's
what i'm trying to say took my brain a
minute to get there we're learning life
be present at the job interview if you
could be lit and be present do that if
you're too stoned to be [ __ ]
functional at the interview don't do
that that is a bad thing so look for
jobs before you get there then take the
interview very very seriously then
something you're gonna have to
accept here is that in colorado most of
the jobs are going to start you off as
either like a trimmer or a bud tender i
am usually so i used to be a consultant
and a hiring manager i used to do a lot
of things in the commercial industry and
the commercial grows since covet it got
kind of weird i've taken a step back
from that i made sort of a career change
it's for the better honestly it was
really stressful running commercial
grows
but one of my responsibilities in those
commercial grows was to hire the crew
hire the staff i was the hiring manager
one of my jobs was to make sure that
everybody was going to work well
together make sure that everybody was
going to be able to do their job make
sure that everybody understood their job
one way that i did that was that
everybody that started that grow
if i was hiring you to be the lead
grower or the next consultant my
starting position was that you are going
to be the trimmer everybody starts off
as a trimmer you have to show me that
you can show up on time you can follow
instructions you come back from lunch on
time you don't get so high you can't do
your job you can work with the group you
can participate just basic [ __ ] that i
need employees to do before i give them
too much access to the plants they are a
tremor we make them trim a little bit
then we find out who you are once we see
that you can work after a week or two
i'll take you back to the grill and
introduce you to small grow tasks my
point is be prepared to start at the
bottom you may be and i'm sorry if the
trimmers are offended that i say you're
starting at the bottom that is the entry
level into the growth i'm not saying
you're the bottom let me give the
trimmer some love because i feel bad
that i said that tremors i [ __ ] love
you guys without the trim crew there
would be no product all the [ __ ] that we
grow would sit in a room and get moldy
and funky if the trim crew didn't trim
it up and take it to the store they are
the go-between between the grow and the
store is the trim crew they are your
quality assurance team so you're
learning quality control they're
learning how to trim they're learning
what to expect what goes to the
dispensary the trim crew is a very
important aspect of the operation i feel
bad that i kind of made it feel like you
were not as important as you are because
you are very important but you are the
entry area for my training so big up to
the trim crew i'm kissing your ass now
feel bad the way i said that trim crew
you got to start on the trim crew we
know you show up once we know you're
going to show up then we'll move you
around the grow to the place that you
wanted to be but you're going to have to
move up i'm not going to let you show up
and water plants on the first day i
don't know who you are i don't know if
you're crazy i don't know if you can
follow instructions i don't know if
you're on drugs man we gotta learn you
and figure you out so be prepared to
start at the bottom and work your way up
your performance will tell me how far
and where you go in my facility i want
everybody to be lead growers because one
day and it does happen i might get sick
or who knows what could happen to me and
i want there to be people in line to
take over my position
i don't want everybody to be a grow tech
forever i want everybody to be the lead
grower the consultant the head grower
the head [ __ ] in charge that is
the goal so that everybody just keeps to
get moving up as i leave a facility that
lead grower should become the new
whatever director of cultivation and
then everybody should just take steps up
i think we should all be passing down
that knowledge
so don't be afraid to start at an entry
level position as a trimmer as a
training bud tender as in as just
somebody in the back packaging [ __ ] up
all day we've got to find out basically
we're testing you can you show up five
days in a row on time can you come back
from lunch five days in a row on time
can you work with the group can you
follow instructions did you steal
anything basic [ __ ] that's all we're
trying to do so be ready to start at the
bottom also expect [ __ ] pay [ __ ]
treatment [ __ ] work and [ __ ] hours the
new people always get the [ __ ] but
that's how it is in almost any industry
we exaggerate that in the cannabis
industry
if you do get hired in the commercial
facility it will not be glamorous work
you're going to get sticky you're going
to get dirty you're going to get
nutrients on you you're going to get
muddy you may have to do some outside
work you're going to have to take out
the trash you also may have to clean the
bathrooms also i'm going to make a note
i clean the bathrooms also there's just
a chart on the wall every employee gets
a list and then we just go down the list
uh start at the top today i clean it
tomorrow you clean it the next day that
guy cleans it we just go down the
[ __ ] rotation hopefully there's
enough people on the list you don't have
to do it very long just cleaning the
bathroom once every couple of weeks it's
not that bad you guys clean the [ __ ] up
you took a [ __ ] in there too clean it up
it's not that bad but we all have to
clean the bathrooms you got to do all
that kind of stuff but
you're going to start off at kind of low
pay because unless you get a job like a
lead grower or a consultant or a lead
bud tender or a manager or something
higher up it is going to be low pay and
crappy hours and the terrible part about
it is a lot of the employers don't have
to pay higher because there are plenty
of people that keep coming from other
states to work here to do the jobs
unfortunately so they're not going to
raise the wages there's not enough
profit to raise the wages unfortunately
that's just how it is in the cannabis
industry ladies and gentlemen i noticed
that camera doing something weird i want
to wrap up this show before i lose it i
want to make sure we get all of this
recording saved i really do hope i
answered this question thoroughly
because i just bailed uh pulled a
ripcord and panic mode
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers growers clone cutters paul and
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there i do want to thank
you once again for listening to this
episode that i do hope makes it to the
internet if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns please
do send them to me at grow fromyourheart
hotmail.com i look forward to hearing
from you check out the patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart everything else is on the website
at
iregenetics.com i apologize for wrapping
it up so abruptly don't want to lose
anything i'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content i'll fix the
camera we'll see what's going on let's
give a big shout out to my buddy stoner
dave and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you