[Music]
welcome back podcast world i'm your host
my friends call me rasta jeff this is
episode 764
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to read a couple
of patreon messages before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my buddy lefty let's send a
big thank you shout out to gramps memo
and brohan78 i want to send a big fist
bump and a thank you shout out to indica
chris let's send a thank you shout out
to luke and trollin let's send a big
fist whomp and a thank you shout out to
my buddy rosufa let's send a thank you
shout out to spherical glassworks i want
to send a big thank you to my buddy jeff
o listen to thank you shout out to
greene county grower i want to send a
big thank you to commander cochran then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to curbside gardens big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know there is a link in the show
notes and in the video description to
make it super easy for all of my friends
to support the podcast ladies and
gentlemen i'm not sure if you could
still hear it in my voice i could still
feel it in my body still kind of
recovering from the the virus the plague
that i had for a little bit uh so if
this show feels a little bit low energy
a little bit slow i do apologize i'm up
here doing my best uh the virus kicked
my ass dude i feel like i've still got
uh low energy and high temperature as
how i felt i'm still doing what i got to
do trying to get my day going get the
world going get the podcast going the
business going taking care of the garden
back in action but i do take a little
bit more breaks and it takes me longer
to do things anyway that is my covet
update also one thing i've noticed my
attention span is really ah it's it is
messed up something's [ __ ] up the vid
messed up my attention span so i
apologize if i feel a little bit out of
focus i [ __ ] am dude i am also
something i'm going to notice and
mention after covid dabs are wrecking me
oh my goodness when i take a little dab
or a medium dab or a big dab
it feels so so incredibly dabblicious
i'm getting lit from the dabs right i'm
just rambling now let's get into uh the
main part of this podcast here i did say
that i had some patreon messages here in
front of me this one comes from our
friend s c dung slinger and it goes a
little bit like this it says hey buddy
could you send the patreons an advanced
text when you add drops to i redirect i
listen to all of the podcasts and ig but
i don't do discord when i found out
about i redirect and all that stuff i
would have enter uh let's see it it's uh
your your autocorrect blasted you out
here uh it was already gone by the time
you saw it was available i'm not sure
what autocorrect turned your sentence
into it doesn't make sense to me but
we'll not deal with that here on the
show it says i know you have stuff i
know you don't have a staff like the
dude grow show but they send the
patreons a text every time they post
anything to the dgc patreons um so what
our friend here is talking about is i
have added iriedirect.com
to my lineup iriegenetics.com in the
middle of the webpage there is a tab
that says direct or you can simply click
or simply type in i redirect it will get
you right there that is where you can
get irie genetics you can get the
regular seeds the feminized seeds a lot
of new stuff a lot of older stuff is
available there
so what my friend is asking for is for
when i post new items on i redirect is
that i let the patreon members know that
there is new stuff up there so that they
can get a jump on it that is a great
request that's a great question yes i
will do my best to start doing that like
you said i don't have a staff it's just
me doing
99 of this work i get some help here and
there are some things i feel comfortable
with but honestly i like to do most of
it by myself it lets me know it's
getting done correctly if there's a
mistake i blame it on me i fix it
quickly
things will happen but i do most of it
by myself also i don't
i don't advertise on the patreon and the
discord and as much as i could i don't
advertise online as much as i could
because that's not really what i'm there
for people know that i exist people know
the company is established the seeds are
available i'm on discord and patreon to
kind of hang out with the crew to hang
out with the people part of the to be a
part of the community not there just to
advertise i do throw my advertising out
what kind of business would i be if i
didn't that's a big part of social media
a big part of why i'm there but i try
not to bombard you with like hey buy
seeds hey buy seeds you know they're
there but i do appreciate the request
that i let you know the seeds are there
yes i will let you know when i put new
beans on the iredirect.com
website also uh the patrons are going to
get exclusives and discounts i know that
for a long time you guys were
asking for deals on seeds through
patreon i can't do it directly through
patreon because patreon doesn't agree
with that what i can do is i can give
you coupon codes where you can go to my
website where the beans are available i
can
do the coupon codes i can help you out
there so in the future there will be
exclu exclusives and there will also be
discount codes for the patreon members
also sign up for the mailchimp because
if you go to my website there's a part
on the bottom of the website that says
sign up for the newsletter if you sign
up for that you will also get
notifications about fresh drops you
don't have to join the patreon the
newsletter on mailchimp will help you
out but patreon
patreon patrons are going to get
exclusives early drops discounts things
like that um i do plan on putting more
stuff up on i redirect there's plenty of
stuff up there right now there's some
great deals up there i'm not going to
talk about too much here on the podcast
um there's some great stuff i will be
adding a lot of stuff right after the
fish concerts in september the start of
september fish is playing four days at
dick's uh soccer field in denver and i
am going to all four nights then i will
need a day or two to recover from that
then we will load up i redirect with
brand new stuff for the month of
september the patrons will get a coupon
code there will be a mailchimp
newsletter to let you know that it
happened uh discord will get notified
but once again the patrons will get a
fat coupon code it'll be tier-based
based on your level of contribution all
right there is more to this uh do i need
to read this part on the show no this
part is for me
that was personal thank you bro i did
read this part where you gave me a huge
compliment i do appreciate that thank
you
no matter how long i do this podcast no
matter how many people show me love give
me respect send me letters the type of
things that you said those compliments
that encouragement that always matters
that does go a long way that fuels the
fire so thank you i do appreciate that
all right i'm going to keep moving i've
got a couple of more messages here in
front of me and i am already running out
of air i operate at a high pace when i
do this podcast i go kind of quickly
somebody told me that it felt urgent i
just tried not to lose my train of
thought is really what's going on but i
can't keep up my own pace i don't have
enough air uh
the vid got me bro i apologize i'm not
making excuses i'm just letting you know
that's why i sound like i'm out of
breath and i'm trying to get through the
show all right
excuse me for the throat clearing not
gonna edit a lot of this this message
comes from they don't even say their
name but i'm not gonna say her name
because you didn't put your name on here
uh the message says hey rosta jeff
what's up bro good to meet you says i
live right near the beach that sounds
like a good time until we read the
message it says i see that my early
flowering plants were pollinated that's
a bummer um
maybe they were pollinated i would go
check and squeeze it a little bit and
see if there's seeds in there those
could just be swollen brax a lot of
people assume sometimes that a swollen
bract is a pollinated plant ah go give
it a squeeze that could be just a
swollen calyx a swollen bract up there
go check it out i could be completely
wrong i haven't seen your girl i don't
have any pictures i'm hoping for the
best it goes on it says do you think it
is a bad idea growing outside living
right near the beach or a tourist
destination so you live uh
near the beach or a tourist destination
and you're saying uh anybody could pass
a hemp farm on the way
to
said beach and then you think that
they're gonna pass the hemp farm and
then they're gonna bring the pollen to
your girl on accident as they travel
that is
um
less likely than my suspicion my
suspicion is that it is probably wind
there's probably somebody else growing
in your area you're not the only person
who got the idea to grow some ganja this
year and there is probably somebody else
growing hemp or cannabis within a few
miles of your cultivation site hemp uh
hemp and cannabis it's the same pollen
pollen can travel for quite a distance
in the wind and it can pollinate your
plants uh so it was probably when
somebody in your four or five mile
radius probably has a male plant
whichever the way into travels wherever
you are you could be in another country
you could be a different part of the
world but the wind is probably going
this way there's probably somebody with
a male that way and you're down this way
and the pollen is just going that way i
don't suspect it's people
going to a hemp farm and getting pollen
on them and then passing through your
neighborhood that doesn't seem it's
possible it could be more likely it
would be pollinators birds bees things
like that
and the wind is probably the number one
culprit there um or it could just be
weird genetics or something went crazy
in the grow also but my assumption i
think i've talked enough about that one
i think there's a male plant within the
four or five mile radius of your plant
and it's simply skeet skeetily deeded on
your plant i don't think that it was
tourist let me answer the question
because there was a specific part do i
think uh that it's risky let me dial
that in and not just ramble past it do
you think it's a bad idea growing
outside living near the beach uh no but
you're gonna have to these are the kind
of things that we're going to
have to deal with as the nation the
entire country is starting to legalize
cannabis there are way more states that
have legal cannabis than illegal
cannabis
this is a an agricultural issue that um
we're gonna have to deal with when
people are growing and their own
personal grows and some a lot of people
out there don't know how to identify a
male a lot of people don't even think
about identifying a male
some people
don't do the way that i think it should
be done in test to plant indoors and
then grow it outdoors they don't all
have that opportunity so they're going
to be males outdoors wherever people are
cultivating males will happen and this
is going to happen in occulta in a in an
agriculture and
let me try that again i'm not even going
to edit that in an agricultural
environment like in farmland uh back in
the day before cannabis came about i
feel like they forgot about this when we
started zoning for cannabis here in
colorado they would make sure that
certain crops are certain distances
apart so that this guy can't pollinate
this guy's crop and this guy can't
pollinate this guy's crop they'd keep
them so many miles apart i think it was
like 2.4 miles or one point i obviously
don't remember the exact number but
there was a distance they would put
farms apart where they couldn't cause
problems for each other seems like we
totally forgot that when it came to
cannabis a lot of new people out there a
lot of just home growers growing in the
backyard this is something we are going
to have to deal with so be ready for
that be prepared also don't be that
grower i've done a full episode on
making sure you don't put male plants
outdoors all right i've got another
message here in front of me this one is
kinda long
let's go for it this one says ross to
jeff what are some of your favorite
integrated pest management management
that's harder to say than it looks let
me try to read it again what are some of
your favorite integrated pest management
products and rotations you did mention
evergreen but you didn't list any of
your other favorites all right that's a
really good question what pesticide
products do i like to use i often work
in commercial cultivation facilities
i've also got a personal grow i'd also
do a lot of consulting for friends and
family
most of what i'm going to talk about
are products that are approved and
regulated by the colorado marijuana
enforcement division and also the
colorado department of agriculture and
also the colorado department of public
health and environment i do not know the
rules the regulations the laws the fine
print where you are i can only speak on
my area and honestly i didn't re these
rules change so rapidly and frequently
here that some of the products on my
list could have been banned since i
blinked after i wrote this i could have
came from the computer sat here they
could have sent out an email saying hey
you can no longer use some of the stuff
on your list that's just how the
industry goes right now it's how it's
going to be we're evolving we're
adjusting and adapting when they find
out there's a problem with the product
i'm happy to adjust find a new product
to use for that so what i'm going to
tell you
is what i recommend for
my personal facilities my commercial
facilities in the state of colorado
you're going to have to make your own
personal decisions when it comes to
pesticides what level of toxicity do you
want in your facility
a lot of people want to stay organic a
lot of people don't care if they're
using nuclear war in their grow
it's all chemicals no matter how organic
you go no matter how abrasive of a
product you use it is all chemicals uh
people like to stick with the buzzword
organic but then i remind them that
cyanide is organic does that make it
okay to you and then they get flustered
with me but keep in mind that you're the
one making the ethical decisions in this
grow so if you want to use something
that may stick around in that plant that
could cause harm to somebody don't share
it don't sell it smoke it yourself but
if you're going to share stuff use
things that are more uh health conscious
to your consumers also the big hippie in
me is going to remind you to be
conscious of the environment don't
destroy the earth don't destroy the
planet that small patch of land right
there is yours right now but everything
around it is other people's the part
above it below it other people and in a
few years it will be somebody else's so
don't [ __ ] that up now my other rant
when it comes to pesticides
i am trained by the colorado department
of agriculture um i was trained by a
lovely lady named theo walker took a
nice long class passed a really great
test
and if i did not remind you guys to
always wear your personal protective
equipment when mixing and using a
pesticide i would be doing my friend
theo walker a disservice and not
honoring my education so you guys out
there i'm i have to say this as part of
just who i am my responsibility my my
morals my ethics and i want you to be
safe wear the appropriate personal
protective equipment when you're
applying a pesticide when you're getting
it off the shelf have your eye
protection and gloves on when you start
mixing it up have your long sleeves so
on your pesticide container
if you grab the container there's a
little book that folds out inside that
book it will tell you the recommended
clothing or personal protective
equipment the minimum personal
protective equipment required for that
pesticide please wear that
also inside of that booklet you will
find what is known as the re-entry
interval what that means is from the
time you spray it this is how long you
have got to wait before you can go back
in that environment they don't want you
to get contaminated if you're spraying
you're creating air bubbles there's a
mist in the room you don't want the
misty part in your lungs and you don't
want the wet fresh pesticide off the
plants on your skin in your eyes and
your body now you're contaminated let's
not do that to ourselves honor that
re-entry interval something i'm going to
add if you are in an indoor environment
which means your house inside your house
inside of a cultivation facility a
greenhouse may not be uh fall under this
category if you're in an indoor enclosed
environment or the sun is not getting
into there i recommend that you increase
your re-entry interval by a minimum of
two hours i would recommend four hours
my reason for this is i mentioned the
sun a moment ago most of the time the
sun the wind the environment will break
down a lot of the pesticides which you
have applied to the plants nature can
happen better outside we are in an
indoor environment there's no wind we do
have fans but it's just moving it around
the room it's not traveling anywhere
necessarily then we've got no sun in
there to break down that pesticide the
light's not going to do the same thing
the same the sun is magic so give
yourself two to four more hours of
re-entry interval time before you enter
that room after applying a pesticide
application i recommend uh applying a
pesticide right as the lights go out or
right after the lights go you can open
it up and spray spray them they're not
going to mess anything up if you're just
in there for one or two minutes hit them
with the pesticide spray zip it back up
close it back up whatever do it right as
the lights go out then you've got at
least eight 12 hours before you're going
to be in there again so they've got
plenty of time to dry up then when you
go in there again look at them they
should look super happy
sometimes if i've applied an oily
pesticide or something that is really
abrasive i will go in and just hose the
plants down with just fresh water i'll
get my pump sprayer or my paint spray or
whatever i'm doing and just spray the
plants down with clean ph balanced water
just to wash off that extra pesticide i
just give it a little bit of a rinse
i'll turn off the lights give it a spray
let them dry turn the lights back on
business as usual keep rocking so we
talked about re-entry interval we talked
about pesticide we talked about your
ethics we talked about not sharing uh
contaminated products with other people
smoke whatever you want bro if you're
gonna [ __ ] smoke it by yourself if
it's not going anywhere you can spray
whatever you i don't recommend it it's
not what i would do but you can do
whatever you want if you've got to get
rid of the bugs just don't share that
[ __ ]
ah we make medical marijuana was our
goal here not make others sick make
other people sick marijuana keep that in
mind the people are already sick they
already have a compromised immune system
possibly they could have cancer they
could have other conditions and you want
to give them something to make them
better not sicker that's your goal don't
be that guy now let's actually talk
about some of the pesticides that i will
recommend my strategy all depends on um
the space the environment the room the
type the time of the year what am i
going to be facing as a problem as a a
bug what's my problem in this room what
am i trying to get rid of
uh we all know that most of the time
we're trying to get rid of spider mites
thrips fungus gnats white flies um those
are most and powdery mildew also is a
very common thing that we're mostly
trying to get rid of or keep away from
our grow i work in a lot of commercial
environments a lot of big spaces in
colorado where they get a lot of spider
mites it's like they're just passing
around the mites it's the trim crews
that are bringing them around i suspect
i can't prove it but they're the only
new people coming and going it's the
trim crew bringing the spider mites
shout out to the trim crew i still love
you but um we got a lot of mites here
and we get a lot of powdery mildew so i
know how to beat that very well a lot of
people are getting rusted mites i can
destroy that the fungus gnats thrips
white flies that's amateur hour we can
get rid of that [ __ ] so i really treat
to prevent spider mites powdery mildew
things like that the way that i do it is
i like to have a
yellow sticky trap every uh three to six
feet ish in the garden so if i got those
six foot by five foot trays i usually
put two to three sticky traps per tray
down kind of low
we do a lot of lollipopping between the
pot and the
start of the plant is about 12 to 18
inches depending on the strain and how
long we [ __ ] veg
uh in that area i will hang yellow
sticky traps the bugs love to go in that
area then i may put some up higher also
but i definitely get down there by the
legs
those are not in any way designed to
eradicate or remove or eliminate a bug
those are there to indicate the presence
of a pest those say hey dude there's
these black sticky things all over here
count them see how many there were you
saw them on the first break before you
went to break check on them before you
go to lunch and check on them at third
break then if we need to up our game we
know we've got bugs in there so the
yellow sticky traps are my first line of
defense my second line of defense is
just myself and the grotechs looking
just use your eyes when you're in there
watering defoliating popping twisting
taking up the trash whatever you're
doing just look at the plants
occasionally do you see signs of spider
mites do you see thrip damage do you see
anything that indicates hey there are
bugs so the first way to get rid of and
prevent them is just to scout for them
and have some sort of alarm system those
yellow sticky traps let me know that
they are there now let's talk about um
what i like to apply what i like to do
is i generally apply pesticides on a
monday it's just something that's easy
to keep in mind every monday we do apply
a pesticide
if i know that the season is coming
where the mites are going to get strong
or the fungus gnats get real strong or
if another facility has bugs or
something like that then i will increase
to monday and thursday
depending on which bugs i'm facing uh if
i'm doing a preventative or if i'm doing
an eradication spray or if i'm doing a
holy [ __ ] spray that tells me which
products i'm going to use i do rotate
i do like to rotate the products i will
use two or three products together at
one time also i'll mix them in this pump
sprayer and i'll spray two or three
products at a time
make sure you rotate that's a very
important thing is to rotate if you hit
them with one product today and the same
product tomorrow by day three they're
ready for it it's not gonna even matter
they're just gonna get stronger you're
gonna make super mites so i recommend to
rotate a product if you can afford one
two maybe three good products spray two
products on day one and hit them with
the third product on the next spray and
then two different products two
different combos on the next time just
keep switching it up somehow so they got
a new way to try to figure it out
understand the mode of attack how does
this product work on the bug i am
treating also the first thing is
identify the pest which you're trying to
get rid of what are you trying to fight
if you don't even know that you'll never
win identify the bug then think about
multiple methods of how to destroy that
bug first of all make an undesirable
environment if they don't like being
there if the leaves are sticky if the
leaves are wet if the leaves are oily
they don't want to be around then attack
them a couple of ways some of these
products make them forget to eat the
bugs just walk around and they're like i
should be doing something
they don't eat they die some of these
products make a mushroom grow out this
little they eat this little bacteria and
it goes inside of the mushroom or inside
of the bug and it grows out of them and
makes a giant mushroom and they die and
then the mushrooms decompose it's kind
of cool to see the little pictures and
videos of that happening but understand
the uh the methods and mode of attack
some just stop them from being able to
reproduce so that's cool you got them
they can't eat they can't reproduce and
now we're blowing them up with mushrooms
and we made it sticky think about
multiple modes of attack and then also
think about not letting them build
resistance now we're gonna kind of just
focus in on a list of products that i
wrote down uh identify your bug
i didn't understand the pesticide you're
using and apply with purpose and rotate
your pesticide
now um let's just talk about some of the
products that i wrote down i like a
product called pyganic i also like
evergreen those are both pyrethrin-based
very similar products but very different
application rates
i like as a max and as a troll i think
as a max is banned in the commercial
facility
excuse me for the burps i also do like a
product called
venerate venerate is a very strong
product be careful with that one i like
botana garden max let me tell you what i
use these for let me back up
pyganic evergreen azatrol venerate those
are good for almost everything but
especially spider mites
botanic garden max i will use the
botanic guard max as a spray for fighter
spider mites uh fungus gnats and then i
will use it as a soil dredge for fungus
gnats or white flies also the gigantic
and evergreen those make a great soil
dredge as well for fungus gnats and
white flies when you're treating for
white flies
i recommend you do a soil dredge and a
spray application at the same time
because if you spray one and don't do
the other they just move they go hang
out in the other spot they go you [ __ ]
up the soil we'll go to the leaves you
spray the leaves they go to the soil
you've got to do both when you're
messing with the white flies for white
flies i recommend monterey garden spray
with spinosad spinosad is a bacteria
made in the bottom of a whiskey barrel
and it will work very well on your white
flies i also like a product called cease
cease is a good product i like smite and
banish however if you use smite and or
banish rinse your plants off before the
lights come back on those products will
cause photo toxicity um i also like a
product called regalia that's good to
keep away the powdery mildew and a lot
of pests in an outdoor grow i would use
a lot of regalia i also like double
nickel
anything with spin assad
grandivo's a great product triac 70 is
like one of my last lines of defense if
everything else didn't do it we'll mix
in some tri-act there are other products
that are more abrasive more aggressive
i'm not going to talk about them here
today i don't want you to use them if
you want to
do your thing it's your grow it's your
ethics but i would not recommend it
another great product if you've got soil
bound problems like white flies fungus
gnats and you want to drench that soil
something that works really good is
mosquito bits
like your local hardware shop maybe
target definitely home depot lowe's they
sell things called mosquito dunks they
look like little it's a red package with
yellow writing they look like little
shitty donuts in a package there are six
of them small six shitty donuts i will
take one of those and crush it up into
like a very fine dust and then put that
in my reservoir with my water and water
the plants with that you may see some of
the chunks floating around that's just
fine
inside of those mosquito bits is a
beneficial bacteria beneficial to the
plants not so beneficial to the fungus
gnats and white flies it'll wipe them
out so give them a soil dredge with fung
with the
fungus now what is it called the
mosquito dunks in there and that will
help wipe out soil borne pests and
they're super cheap and affordable those
products are really cheap and readily
available you can get that at your local
hardware shop hopefully if not lowe's
and home depot will have it over there
in the garden center
all right so i was losing my breath i
tried to go fast i got my [ __ ] back
together really quickly i'll go through
the list pygamic evergreen azatrol
venerate botanic guard max cease smite
banish regalia double nickel monterey
garden spray let me add tangle foot to
that mix you can get monterey garden
spray and tangle foot both at like your
big box hardware store so if you're
limited on resources and places to shop
tangle foot
monterey garden spray those will both be
available at your local garden center
you can also use grand devo and tri-act
70 and sometimes don't tell anybody that
i said this but granulated sulfur is a
great product for getting rid of a lot
of pests
now that i've told you products that i
do use let me tell you something that i
do not use i do not recommend neem oil i
don't like neem oil in the garden it
tastes like [ __ ] it doesn't go away it
makes the plants taste terrible and i
also don't like to use botanical oils
like hippie oil sprays rosemary oregano
oil all that stuff i don't do that in
the garden why not because a lot of the
stuff that we grow turns into
concentrates we make hash out of it and
you can see when you're making a
concentrate you can see those oily
pesticides float to the top i did just
tell you a bunch of stuff to spray on
the plant that's going to make them
sticky but you're going to apply it way
early they're going to last long enough
to where you don't have to apply it
again and they will be gone they'll be
broken down evaporated dissipated and
gone away from the plant before it is
harvest time dry cure smoke that [ __ ]
will all be gone by then but those
hippie botanical oils they just leave
that flavor i can taste the mint i can
taste weird [ __ ] and the concentrates in
the flowers i can taste it when i get
certain products so i don't recommend
that sort of stuff no botanical oils ah
none of that neem oil stick with ria and
my this is my opinion my recommendation
stick with the real
agriculturally recommended pesticide
application if you want to really
strategically get rid of your pests if
you guys want to use the hippie oils do
that also something i do really like
another uh completely flipped option a
whole b-side too using all these
pesticides is why not use some sort of
predator mites you can release
swarovskis hypoasmus miles persimilis
cucumaris green lace wings i know i went
really fast on that
but rove beetles all those guys will
really really help you out
in your garden
and they are harmless that way you don't
have to smoke oils that way you don't
have to spray things you do have to
disperse the bugs if you're growing in
your home a lot of people don't like
that but for a commercial grow i greatly
highly recommend
aggressive predator bugs once again
swarskis persimilis hypoaspis miles rove
beetles cucumeris um what else did i say
green lace wings get
get the green lace wings that are on the
cards and they are just about to hatch
they turn into little [ __ ] alligators
and those things will eat all of the
bugs in your grow
all right ladies and gentlemen that is
my rant on which pesticides i would use
i think i stretched that one out quite a
while
thank you guys for putting up with my uh
my terrible voice my wheezing my lack of
oxygen i do appreciate it i'm trying to
get it back together trying to get
everything going give me time that's all
it takes uh they just say
get a lot of rest and hydrate i'm trying
bro i'm trying but i got a lot of [ __ ]
to do also i'll do my best to keep the
shows coming uh thank you for all of the
support make sure you guys check out
iredirect.com that's right i redirect
dot com for fresh drops all the cool
kids are doing it tap in is what i think
masonic said uh ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers growers clone cutters pollen
chuckers all of you beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there truly thank you
for listening to another episode of the
grow from your heart podcast i'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns please
do send me an email the email address of
course is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't forget about the
patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart everything else is at
iregenetics.com
check out the website that's all i've
got for you i'm out of breath i had a
good time check you next time i want to
give a big shout out to my buddy billy
bong smokin and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you