if you have ever rescued or improved
your garden with advice you got from
this podcast now is a good time to click
subscribe
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world i'm
your host my friends call me rasta jeff
this is episode
765 of the grow from your heart podcast
i've got a fun episode lined up for you
before we get to the main topic let's do
a few thank you shout outs to a few of
those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to a good
friend and one of my favorite testers my
buddy mobius groves let's send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy
blackhawksfan i want to send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy stoner dave
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to single t and ivan m let's
send a big thank you shout out to mid
michigan micro grow i want to send a big
thank you shout out to captain mojo at
northeast 420. let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to a great
breeder my buddy rosta green thumb
listen to thank you shout out to easy
going grows then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to soil to bowl big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show i'm not sure
if you guys want to hear about it or not
but it is time for an update on my
health if you've been following along
with the show you know that i did
experience the plague i'm recovering
i've still got this junk in my throat
the energy still kind of fluctuates but
i feel much better i'm much better in
spirits i feel way uh like i'm almost
back but i can't just get rid of this
you can hear it in my voice i can hear
it it's much much more exaggerated when
i get the microphone and headphones
going but i think i'm mostly back thank
you to everybody who has been sending me
messages
well wishes ideas for things that will
help me get over this i do appreciate
most of that some of you guys are crazy
but most of you are sending great ideas
thank you for all of the love
encouragement support of the kindness a
lot of people said hey bro we understand
you're sick take your time i am doing
just that you may notice that the
podcast went from two episodes a week to
one episode uh my lungs get really tired
just talking through a whole podcast
that sounds ridiculous to me that sounds
crazy i'm a mostly healthy dude i'm
active i run around i talk a lot and now
for my lungs to get tired doing a
podcast feels uh ridiculous to me
honestly so i've got to take my time
gotta pace myself
can't bang out two shows like i used to
excuse me for hearing the junk if you do
hear the junk in my throat i apologize
i'm doing my best i'm back on the mic
we're gonna have a good time let's quit
talking about my health nobody cares
about the plague some of you do thank
you for the folks that send me messages
most of you guys out there don't want to
hear me talk about my health i said we
have a fun podcast lined up i was sent a
very good question um just from a friend
actually from my friends at lollipop
farm shout out to lolly shout out to
john at lollipop farms beautiful people
up there i don't need to mention their
location or anything else about them
they know who they are they know that i
got nothing but love and respect for
everybody up there
they asked me and maybe a pot they sent
me a text message and said it may be a
good idea if you talk about how and why
you got into breeding i realize i've
probably done that on this podcast but
there are 765 episodes up and maybe you
didn't see the episode where i talked
about it it's probably been 300 episodes
or so
so here we are i don't want to try to
put out a lot of grow information right
now because uh since uh the plague hit
me my attention span is not where it
should be so i don't want to try to give
you grow information
lots of detailed information with weeks
and numbers and times and things like
that that i could definitely flub and
mess up right now so i want to just kind
of ramble for another episode or two and
just talk about things that i can flow
about and i can talk about so i'm going
to just talk about how i got into
breeding on this episode this is a
personal story we can't make mistakes
here if i do make errors or mistakes
somebody do correct me and remind me of
how the story really went but this won't
mess up your garden in any way and it
will be a fun episode for everybody to
be involved in so with no further ado
let's jump into a little bit about how
and why
i got into growing and breeding and how
we got where we are
many many years ago
i was around growing before i should
should have been before i should
probably admit it probably statue of
limitations are over but i remember
being a little kid and one of my uncles
was growing cannabis in a backyard and
another uncle said hey bro tonight when
the sun goes down do this and he gave
specific instructions it was 40 years
ago i don't remember it 35 years ago i
don't remember it um so we get uncle
uncle a gave uncle b instructions names
will be changed to protect the innocent
here um and rest in peace to the uncles
that are gone damn it i miss you guys um
uncle gave uncle instructions the sun
went down uncle went outside to do the
thing and he was about to do it wrong
and me being just the little kid that i
was the pride was this person when i was
a little kid but i was like hey uncle
that's not what he said he said to do it
this way and my mom was standing there
my uncle was standing there our other
family friend who i was named after was
standing there um and they're all like
oh [ __ ] he's right that's what he said
and this was the time before like text
messages and google and [ __ ] we didn't
have none of that this was the 80s bro
so we had to just trust and rely on that
when i said that was wrong and i said
the correct way like he is right
that was the first time i remember being
around somebody growing cannabis i
didn't realize at the time what was
happening but they were growing cannabis
in the backyard at that time
um
fast forward to i moved to another
location i don't want to give too many
details because um i moved to a place
where cultivating cannabis was illegal
and i
accidentally spotted a friend's
cultivation in their
um their place they had a place i don't
want to give too many details but i was
somewhere
and from above light hit me in the eye
that shouldn't have been coming from
somewhere and i was like what the [ __ ]
was that and so i just kind of i was
playing the drums to tell you the truth
i was playing the drums so i was
obviously in a place where we played the
drums and light hit me where i shouldn't
have and then i realized i was like oh
that's a [ __ ] grow light so after we
were [ __ ] after we got done i can't
give too many details i don't want to
bust anybody after we got done playing
music i guess is what i could say um i
told my friend i was like hey bro i can
kind of tell that you got lights coming
from up there you might want to
seal that up a little bit and he goes
bro do you know what you're doing i go i
kind of know about growing and he goes
come here i got to show you some [ __ ]
and he showed me his grow and i was like
oh this is what i think is wrong and so
i helped him so we go up there we take a
look at the girl i kind of helped him
figure out what was wrong and then he
needed a helper he just was in over his
head he needed a buddy they could do it
since i'd already discovered it and i
was cool about it he just decided that
we were also friends also so he decided
that i was going to be his his bucket
helper his bucket monkey uh basically i
carried buckets up a ladder to upstairs
and did weird [ __ ] like that and then he
had to go out of town surprisingly and
when he went out of town i just took
over and ran that grow he came back for
harvest and then paid me pretty well but
that was one of my first experiences of
running a grow by myself is when he went
out of town shout out bro if you hear
this hope things are well i hope you're
killing it um but that dude went out of
town i kind of took over that grow so
eventually i had to leave that
prohibition state and i had to come back
to colorado when i came back to colorado
everybody was talking about medical
marijuana one of the first things i did
was get my medical marijuana
recommendation from a doctor and get all
set up to be able to shop at
dispensaries having this medical
marijuana card also gave me the ability
to grow my own cannabis i'd already been
growing with my friends in another state
i'd grown a little bit when i was
younger so i had some experience i
thought i could definitely do this and
it was a huge market here in colorado
everybody needed medical marijuana but
there weren't enough people growing it
and if you could grow a good product
reliably people would be knocking down
your door
in a good way that sounds bad but it was
a good way this time so i was i decided
i'm going to grow some medical marijuana
unfortunately it takes a little while to
grow some medical marijuana you can't
just start growing you got to get some
clones from somewhere so this is where
the story kind of branches off and a
couple of different things happen
um i ordered seeds from a seed bank
shout out to the seed banks out there
the key people supplied with seeds
wanted to grow ordered seeds
had
somewhat okay somewhat not okay
experiences with seeds also at the same
time since it's taking a while to grow
i'm shopping at dispensaries and i'm
looking for quality products and i'm
just shopping around while i'm shopping
around i realize there's not a quality
dispensary in my area so this branches
out how
buying seeds and being dissatisfied
leads me to making my own seeds and then
at the same time shopping dispensaries
looking for quality products leads me to
finding a group of friends where i was
part of opening the first dispensary in
the city of pueblo so that's two
different branches of this story that
kind of put us where we are on the map
of being a breeder and a commercial
grower so let's go the way of i've got
some notes here let's talk about it this
way i was growing for myself then i
found this group of friends that wanted
to start a dispensary they had a great
idea they had a good strategy but they
just didn't have the the umph they
didn't know they were older than me as
the bottom line no disrespect to the
elders this was prob this was in 2008 so
it's been several years i am their age
now so i've grown into that but they
were older and didn't have the energy
the hipness the enthusiasm that they
needed but they had most of the other
things they had the product and the
building
they needed a guy like myself i've been
going to dispensaries all over the state
of colorado i've seen things that i
liked i've seen things that i did not
like i've seen what i thought worked and
did not work i come from a retail
background so i understood this going to
the dispensaries i understood what i was
looking at what i was seeing how i
interacted with people what i liked in
the interactions and didn't like how the
stores were set up the products i
enjoyed i learned all this so when i
discovered this group of people in my
neighborhood that wanted to start a
dispensary and they were a little slow
about i was like i'm the guy you need
and then i put my young
energy my young creativity into that and
we started a very flourishing dispensary
we had a great facility here in colorado
uh here in pueblo unfortunately we were
shut down for
uh illegal zoning but they built that
rule around us they zoned us out because
they did not want us there in that part
of town
that's a whole other story i may talk
about that at another part of the show
but i was growing c i was growing for
this dispensary and i was growing for
myself
um
if you so i did acquire some clones i
got some clones from some neighborhood
friends and i grew those
i ordered some seeds they came so what
inspired me to get seeds was the
dispensary and everybody in my
neighborhood had the same clones my
dispensary was selling clones to people
so the dispensary had all the same weed
and the neighborhood all had the same
weed because we were just selling clones
like crazy so all the growers in the
neighborhood came to my dispensary and
got clones of the same [ __ ] that i was
growing at work so it was just all the
same [ __ ] and i was trying to sell on
the black market as well i had my own
side hustle going and we wanted to stay
fresh at the dispensary so we had to
separate ourselves the way to do that
was to get a bunch of seeds so i bought
a lot of seeds i used my own money and
did my own final hunts at home in my own
personal grow then i would take the
winners from that to the commercial grow
that we had at the store
which route do we talk about that right
now um i would just buy seeds and grow
them i started growing at home and the
seeds would come and i would grow them
at home and i would pheno hunt them i'd
get a pack of seeds and find the best
one then i would take that to the
commercial grow that commercial grow is
where i learned how to grow on a big
level it wasn't necessarily a commercial
building it wasn't set up right it was
before commercial grows were really
happening it was kind of right before
that but it was as big as i had been in
and we made a lot of flour come out of
that room so i had to run a lot of
lights a lot of plants by myself that
started me in a big grow i had that one
i had the one at home
allegedly maybe possibly had a couple
others in other places we shouldn't talk
about but that's what got me going on
commercial growing and in a dispensary
environment
then ordering those seeds is another
part of this big story some of those
seeds i bought were awesome um some were
terrible the ratio of [ __ ] awesome to
[ __ ] terrible seeds was not worth
buying more seeds so i did what any good
grower would do i took some of the best
seeds i actually made friends with some
growers
some other breeders online i would start
posting pictures of my grow of my stuff
that i was growing from seed and from
clone and people took notice and other
people started sending me seeds i took
some seeds from some other really
reputable popular breeders and i would
cross them and make other things and
then i realized i can make better seeds
than what i am buying i just have to do
research i have to do a little bit of
work and i can make enough seeds for
myself to grow and have better seeds
than what i'm spending hundreds of
dollars for coming from websites back
then you had to buy all the seed banks
were in canada or in europe and you'd
have to hope your [ __ ] got over the over
the border through customs they'd go
through your package a lot of times
you'd get a package that had been cut
open and there's a letter inside of it
that said nice try we took your seeds
you can't have those sometimes you'd get
your [ __ ] sometimes you would sometimes
you pay for the money back guarantee and
you'd get your money back and you
wouldn't get the shipping fees and you
wouldn't get a half your [ __ ] back but
that's just how it went back in the day
so i made my own seeds i didn't want to
keep spending money on seeds when i knew
i could do it myself just as good as the
guys on the internet why couldn't i'm a
smart dude i had the experience the
space uh the encouragement the [ __ ]
the drive to do it so i made my own
seeds
um so i did it i made a few crosses i
made a feminized cross i made a batch of
feminized seeds that i grew and when i
started posting pictures people were
like dude that's fire that looks really
good when my friends would smoke it and
grow it so i bred some grateful dog and
i took it to a party here and it was the
first batch that i thought was dried and
cured properly enough to take some more
and smoking i cracked open the jar and
everybody at the outside of the party on
the back porch where i was everybody for
about a 10 or 12 maybe 15 foot radius
just came right to me like a bunch of
cockroaches like what kind of wheat is
that bro and i cracked it open i rolled
a fat bowl i rolled a fat joint packed a
couple of bowls and we all smoked and i
knew that that weed was super special
and i'd made seeds of that so i had some
seeds of it i packaged up a bunch of
those and there was a cannabis cup
coming to denver i don't remember i
think it may have been the first one at
that place with the outdoor maybe it was
denver mart it could have been the x
though i don't remember what year it was
i've got a brain injury in this [ __ ] i
didn't know to document this i didn't
know it was going to be some sort of
historical event for me i was just doing
what i was doing so
i made a bunch of seeds and i took them
to the cannabis cup
and on those seed packages i just put
i was calling myself irie genetics
already i just decided it was that was a
cool name so i put irie genetics and
then i put the name of the strain on the
cross and i put my email address on
there because i didn't have a website
yet and at the cannabis cup anybody that
had if you're walking around with like a
bottle of nutrients or a grow light or
like a pot or maybe some soil anything
that indicated to me that you were going
to go home and attempt to grow cannabis
i gave you seeds i thought that was a
great just a freebie for me to give to
you i didn't ask for money it was a good
way to get seeds in people's hands my
idea was just i made a lot of these
seeds i need to grow maybe 100 of them
you guys can have the other 2400 that i
made and i put them out there for the
world
so i gave a bunch of those away with my
info on the packages
it took a while
i think a lot of those people sat on
those seeds for a minute but then
eventually it takes four five maybe six
months to get the growth finished
eventually six eight months later people
started messaging me and they're like
hey bro i grew these seeds here's
pictures and the pictures would look
stellar and those people would say can i
get more seeds from you and i would
politely say yes you can but this time
they may cost a little bit of money so i
started posting around social media
i started going to more cannabis cups
and more events and started breeding
more learning more about breeding people
started giving me plants they thought
would breed well breeders started
sending me seeds and cuts i made a name
for myself in that industry then when i
went to more cannabis cups people would
hunt me down and try to give me money
for seeds i actually got
politely asked to stop selling or leave
a cannabis cup i had a backpack filled
with seeds people would run up and i
just take their money give them seeds
and then some of the high time staff
thought that that was bad that i was
selling without a booth i agree should
get my own booth and sell so that's what
i'm doing now i get the boots at the
events sell seeds there
um eventually i built a website and it
wasn't the best website but that was my
way of starting to build a brand i built
a website and a social media presence uh
started doing a lot of online and live
stuff and that's a lot of why i think
that's why people trust me is because
i'm right here you can see my face i'm
wearing a bright yellow shirt with a
purple background i'm 6'5 with
dreadlocks to my knees to my ankles
they're almost touching the floor right
now i'm in like a bar stool high chair
and they they're touching my shoes i can
feel it but i'm right here that's why i
think a lot of people support the brand
and support me because i support you
back and i don't hide a lot of breeders
you don't even know who they are you
have no idea what they're about you know
me i'm friendly i'm peaceful i think
building an audience with the social
media folks doing a podcast that really
helps out just showing you that i'm a
normal person i'm passionate for
cannabis and uh kind of opening up the
the window the curtain i guess so that
you can see what i'm doing i talk about
my breeding i share a lot with you i
think that really helps with my brand
so um that's a lot of what got me here i
started doing events i got my own booth
set up started selling at shows
and then um still sell the events when
they do happen uh the indo-expo got
cancelled and then the next event that
was lined up was the dude gross cup
unfortunately i had to skip that because
i had the vid i did send mike in place
uh to do work for me great job mike i am
rambling like crazy but i'm telling a
story bro this is story time with ross
to jeff so now i make a lot of feminized
and regular seeds my femme seeds seem to
be quite reliable my regular seeds seem
to be quite potent um i don't follow a
lot of the trends and the hype of what i
see in the market you don't usually see
me work with i hate to be naming things
but like the skittles and the cake and
the gelato you never saw me do stuff
with a lot of that i try to stay away
from the trends and i just do um my
motto has always been grow from your
heart and breed with love when i see two
plants i just know that this plant needs
to donate pollen to this plant they need
to make little babies i could just see
it
maybe i'm a matchmaker maybe i'm a plant
porn director either way it just feels
natural it's what i think i was
part of what i was born to do one of the
things i was put here to do so that's
how we got started that's how i became
rosta jeff the breeder i was basically
tired of buying seeds
that were not quality that did not reach
my expectations and for paying
ridiculous prices for things that had to
get shipped from another country that
are being made in america us the
companies would be that have california
and the name and they'd say like new
york and the name and those people would
ship their seeds overseas and then i
would pay money to have them [ __ ]
shipped back to me and then half of them
wouldn't be good i'm not dissing either
of those companies i'm just saying they
would we know they're coming from
america and they're shipping it to
another country then shipping it right
back and i've gotta it gets taken in
customs and that was just a pain in the
ass so um that's a lot of what led me to
making my own seeds i could do it we can
all do it i encourage you i'm a seed
maker i'm a seed seller but still if you
find something stellar
make some crosses and i do encourage you
uh promote you um you're allowed to
breed with the seeds that you get from
me i didn't invent cannabis i didn't
fart one day and have fresh seeds i
didn't sneeze and make a clone i started
with other people's genetics just like
all other breeders do so you've got my
permission breed with my stuff if you do
breed with my genetics all i ask is that
you put the name of the cross that you
used on the package and give me a little
bit of credit maybe send me a 10 or 20
pack of seeds i might grow them some of
my friends might grow them you may see
pictures of your seeds on my instagram
page that's always fun
so if you got like strawberry starburst
cross to your whatever you got mail or
whatever you got i may be interested in
those seeds it could be fun do that
you've got my permission so i talked
about how i got into it basically i was
buying seeds not happy with them
got into the dispensary life let's talk
a little bit about that the commercial
growing started at a dispensary we had a
multi-level building the bottom was a
dispensary the next two levels or
straight up a production grow we do
smaller stuff in one area carry it up to
another area flower it up there uh that
was an amazing um experience it was an
amazing uh cultivation facility made out
of a retail store is basically what that
was
so eventually that place did get closed
down unfortunately um the city attorney
and some law enforcement came handed us
some documents and said we had to close
a lot of people when those people when
the law enforcement came in they did not
have their firearms out they were not
doing a raid they were simply escorting
the law enforcement was escorting the
city attorney city attorney handed paper
paper was signed and they said you guys
are now not allowed to sell any cannabis
related products the next question was
well can we sell non well what about no
they said they have you have to lock the
door and stop selling cannabis related
products and i said what about the
people in line and they said we don't
know about them we don't know what to
tell you and they left after we signed
the papers those last few people that
didn't get up and run when the cops came
in when the city attorney came in guess
how much cannabis they got for the money
that they brought that day they came to
buy a 20 bag they probably left with an
ounce each for very cheap because they
stuck around when the cops walked in
they didn't get up and bail we thought
that was respectable respectful and
commendable so they got hooked up but
they did close us they closed this like
i said earlier for zoning violations
um
so at that point we had to figure out
stuff on our own and that's kind of when
i started doing uh commercial growing at
other places drifting around i worked at
a another commercial growth that never
really got off the ground we helped him
build it uh but they always had
technical difficulties then i got called
to go work at green and healthy kind of
helped get that grow going then from
there i think i ended up over at uh
three rivers then i built a commercial
um what's it called a commercial
consulting reputation and just started
doing consulting at several facilities
uh those few places i mentioned were
public i was they're i'm allowed to talk
about them a lot of them we signed
non-disclosure agreements to where they
i can't even tell you that i worked
there but i worked a lot of cool places
in colorado so that's where i got to the
commercial cultivation learning how to
do things on a totally different scale
different level uh fighting pests in a
different way so i think i rambled about
the question the question was um how and
why did i get into breeding i went quite
a ways into that honestly the bottom
line was i was not satisfied with what i
was buying and i knew that i could
create a quality product for myself one
day the people at the dispensary
i brought them some of the flowers i
grew and they're like bro you grow a
better herb than us and i was like thank
you that's all i wanted to hear so that
is the wrap up i think that is all my
voice and throat have got time for for
this episode thank you for hanging out
with story time with rasta jeff this
podcast has almost reached 10 000
subscribers if you haven't already
subscribed please click the subscribe
button right now also click that
notification button every time i put out
an episode you will get a notification
you will not miss a show for the time
being until i get oxygen into these
lungs i will only be putting one episode
out once a week that's every monday once
i feel like i'm back at it excuse me for
the throat clearing that's once again
that's what we're dealing with once i
get back at it get the energy get the
throat the lungs all back in shape we
will do two episodes again please be
patient with me still love you not going
anywhere i appreciate you keep listening
um what else do we have for you make
sure you uh if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns you can
send me an email the email is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't forget
about patreon
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart we are updating i redirect make
sure you check that out for everything
else check out the website
iregenetics.com that's all i've got for
you for this episode thank you for
hanging out i'll be back next monday
with fresh new content i want to give a
big shout out to my friend modern roots
va and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you