[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world i'm your host my friends
call me ross to jeff this is episode 766
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode we're going to feature my
new strain john lemon before i get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of the kind of folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to jessica k let's send a fist
wump and a thank you shout out to my
buddy sam heads i want to send a thank
you shout out to a longtime supporter my
buddy glenn gironi let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to sc
dung slinger i need to send a big thank
you shout out to canner reaper let's
send a thank you shout out to dude grows
let's send a big fist bump to spartan
420. i want to send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy growing old man
style let's send a thank you shout out
to aaron i want to send a big fist bump
to b bala i want to send a thank you
shout out to my buddy frogman420
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to mr mick bluntz big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
continues to support the show on patreon
if you are not already supporting the
show and you would like to learn how to
do so all you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast if you've
been following along i'm sure you know
that i've been struggling from
recovering from the coven 19 virus you
could probably hear it in my throat and
my voice i'm doing a lot better now this
episode's going to sound a lot better
i've got more air i don't have to clear
my throat as often so that is your quick
covet update for this episode thank you
for all the well wishes uh the ideas the
advice the comments the emails all that
stuff thank you guys i do appreciate it
it's great to have such a good community
behind me supporting me thank you i feel
much better i'm sure you can hear it
still a little bit of funk in the throw
in the lungs but way better the ears
don't sound so gooey so i feel much
better thank you i'll stop giving
updates in an episode or two um i'm glad
i'm feeling better because fish is
coming to denver that's right my
favorite band on the planet is fish and
they are doing four nights at dick's
sporting goods uh the giant soccer field
and commerce are in uh yeah commerce
city there in denver colorado commerce
city just outside of denver you know
what i mean but fish is coming and i
will be at all four nights of the fish
concerts if you are there please come
say hi give me a high five give me a hug
shake my hand give me a fist bump i
really don't like it when after an event
people email me and they say hey bro i
saw you at the fish concerts but i did
not come say hi why not dude come say hi
it's a fish concert we're all friends
we're all bros we're all hanging out
come say hi however don't talk while
fish is playing that's a general rule
don't talk to me while fish is playing
save it for set break save it for right
after the show give me a high five keep
going just say hi don't ignore me you
don't have to say hey bro i saw you
there and ignored you that's not cool
i'm a community kind of dude i'm
friendly say what's up i may just may
have some seeds in my back pocket
especially if i can sneak them through
security on the first night if first
night goes easy we'll take more every
night all right that is the fish ramble
please join me say hi at the fish show
i'm also excited proud and happy to
announce that i redirect can now accept
credit cards that's right if you were
shopping at iredirect.com
we can accept credit cards we can take
credit card payment we could take venmo
cash app uh what's the other one paypal
we could take most forms of payment at
this time in most cases we can even
accept cryptocurrency but you will have
to send me an email for that one let me
know what you've got i'll figure out how
to take that one but we can now accept
credit cards on
iredirect.com make sure you check that
out there are new strains and new prices
on i redirect today this episode comes
out on monday the sale will start on the
first it will go through this month
there will be some things left you did
not miss it if you're just hearing this
on the first of the month however the
patrons and the discord members and the
members of the newsletter did hear about
it first this episode will come out
monday that sale does start on the first
there will still be a lot of things left
for the sale and the fresh drop that
sale will continue through the month
make sure you check that out the people
on patreon the people on discord and the
members of the newsletter did hear about
the sale first so make sure you sign up
for one of those avenues the patrons of
course did get a coupon code shout out
to everybody for supporting the show on
patreon once again that sale will last
through the month of september on
iredirect.com
while i'm talking about the website i do
want to give a big shout out to my web
dude shout out to the web guy i don't
know which name you want me to use here
bro you know who you are you're the
badass [ __ ] web guy i've been
keeping this dude busy for the past week
i think i'm the only project he's had
time to work on getting i redirect going
and compliant with the credit card
compliance setup was kind of a challenge
so we got that going web dude shout out
bro i owe you one i know i already sent
you a gift pack but that took longer
than anticipated so i owe you another
one bro let me know what i could do for
you all right let's move forward i've
been rambling for quite some time the
show's getting long already we haven't
even talked about the main topic of this
podcast the main topic of this show is
my new strain or one of my newest
strains it is called john lemon i'm sure
you've seen me post maybe you haven't i
hope you have seen me post pictures of
it to social media uh follow me on
instagram irie underscore genetics check
me out on cannabaz once again irie
underscore genetics join the discord i'm
all over social media search ire
genetics you cannot miss me i've been
posting pictures lately of a plant that
i am calling john
lemon let's talk about john lemon for
just a little bit
a quick description is that john lemon
ah smells like sour skunks and diesel
feel the main thing you're going to hear
me say a lot here is sawwa this one is
stupid sawwa i'd almost got a lot of
names with the word sour or sawa in
there shout out to my east coast friends
but i don't say sawa and there's enough
sour out there so i wanted to go with
the creative name we will talk about why
i got that name um the aroma makes my
eyes feel itchy i've always talked about
sour diesel
it has this weird effect on my eyes the
john lemon has that same like i don't
know it's almost like an allergy effect
but in a good way like my eyes get i
could tell when someone's got some sour
diesel or john lemon in the car in the
room it makes my eyes get this itch
the real deal east coast sour diesel
stinks so bad that i said in the car it
stinks so bad you can't hide it uh you
could double bag it you could put it in
a jar you could put it in a bag inside
of a jar you gotta vacuum seal it or
something or we are going to smell it
that east coast sour diesel the real
deal diesel is a super [ __ ] stinker
you cannot hide that one and then when
you do open the bag at a party or in the
car especially everybody knows what
you've got right away like bro he's got
the fire and they all come congregating
so you got to be careful if you got that
one keep it double bagged be careful or
you open it and you can't even open it
in the car you cannot open the real deal
sour diesel or the john lemon for that
matter in the car because it will stink
up the car so bad that it smells like
you smoked in there for the next week
even if you don't light it just open the
jar give it a smell let your friend
smell it close it up that car is now
stank it's broken it'll never smell the
same you got to burn some hippie incense
drop some ozium in there vacuum that
[ __ ] out smoke a cigarette in there it's
still going to stank it is not gonna
work so east coast sour diesel is a
super stinky plant a lot of those stink
traits definitely come through in this
cross um let's see where are we i do
have some notes but i try to stay on
track because i get quite rambly east
coast sour diesel grows tall with thick
dense buds
i'm talking about the parents of the
plants here kind of giving you an idea
of why i made this uh let's see the buzz
from sour d is super aggressive uh when
i smoke that one my eyes get super heavy
and i get this weird like tunnel vision
isolated sort of a feeling sometimes i
get of a sort of a heart racing sort of
a feeling but it's definitely in my own
head introspective introvert kind of
weed i don't want to talk to people i
just want to be left the [ __ ] alone
cause i'm trying to figure out the
meaning of life and a rubik's cube all
at the same time so that's what that one
does now let's talk about the lemon
skunk mail that i used in this cross um
first of all i should mention this is
not the lemon skunk that i used in lemon
jeffrey and firefly and all the other
lemon stuff that you've heard about in
the past
this is not the same lemon skunk that is
a lemon skunk female in this situation i
am using a male lemon skunk plant this
is a bc lemon skunk so this has been
around for a while from the bc seed
company
i've got my hands on a great lemon skunk
male that does great things
it adds great vigor it adds great shape
it adds great potency and most of all it
adds a really amazing lemon flavor to
things you guys know how i like that
lemon terp this one is packed up with
lemon it's got a beautiful structure the
node spacing is really nice on this one
my lemon skunk female the node spacing
is kind of far this one's more of a
compact structure compared to that lemon
skunk it's got a giant top flower it
makes really sturdy plants they can hold
themselves up that other lemon skunk is
kind of floppy and needs supports the
male is more sturdy more robust i can
hold itself up and it makes offspring
this lemon skunk makes offspring that
reek of lemons and they are stupid
potent so i got the idea why not take
the lemon skunk and the sour diesel the
east coast sour diesel and put those
together and see what we could come up
with and the results let's talk a little
bit about the results now first before
we get there let's talk about why did i
name it john lemon that's next year on
the notes why did i make it john lemon
honestly john lemon was recommended to
some by me uh to me by somebody on
social media i don't remember who did
that exactly there were so many names
given and so many things to keep track
of if you recommended it and you think
you were first let me know i'll give you
a prize shout out for the great name but
uh the name is awesome i am honestly not
a huge beatles or john lennon and
definitely not a yoko ono fan my buddy
chris in high school shout out to chris
i hope you're well brother he's a huge
beatles fan i had to listen we got to
listen to the beatles all the time in
the car with chris uh he chose the
beatles robbie chose pink floyd greg
chose the grateful dead and i chose fish
that's kind of like how we picked our
favorite bands uh everybody got their
own band but i wasn't the beatles guy
that was chris
uh but
the beatles are cool dude don't think
i'm saying that i hate the beatles
that's just not the one i would have
chose i would have chose the grateful
dead or fish over the beatles any day
and pink floyd's kind of boring to me to
be honest with you i know i'm going to
get hate mail send it have fun in the
comment section get it on down there uh
but when somebody said john lemon i
thought it was a great name because
we've all seen john lennon in front of
the statue of liberty in new york that
brought me to the new york vibes he's
not from new york but you know he made
it there and then uh we've got the uh
the lemon flavor brings in the lemon so
it's john lemon john lennon it's just a
beautiful play on words when i heard it
could not resist i tried to resist for a
long time but i kept coming back i have
a list of names and i kept going this
john lemon right here that's going to be
the one bro and it's my my decision
overall so i chose john lemon now let's
segue into talking about flavor and
aroma or terps if you will
this one's got a lot of great flavor to
it you're going to hear me say the word
sour a lot because this one is dominated
by sour flavors there's a backup of a
backup of lemon flavors there's a backup
of some skunk there's hints of maybe
some cat piss some ammonia in there but
let's talk about some of the aromas and
flavors that will come from this it's
going to be mostly sour the bc lemon
skunk i use makes everything taste like
strong sour lemons that the lemon skunk
on the other plants i use is kind of a
softer lemonade kind of a lemons this
one is more just straight up non-diluted
sour ripe lemons in your face lemons
like if you get that plastic lemon with
the juice and squeeze it on your tongue
you make that pucker that's this kind of
lemon
then the sour diesel adds a
definitely a diesel aroma to it there's
that diesel funk to it then it also adds
sort of a uh an astringent sort of a cat
piss sort of a really sharp aroma maybe
ammonia to it to the mix
most of the phenotypes are very sour
some of the other phenotypes are going
to have a little bit of lemon some are
going to have some diesel some plants
will even have a little bit of fuel and
skunk terps to them you'll get a little
bit of cat piss and ammonia in some but
you're mainly going to get sour straight
sour and lemons but you're mostly gonna
get sour sour fuel sour ammonia maybe
some sour cat piss it sounds disgusting
but if you're a cannabis smoker you know
that that sour diesel cat piss aroma
with lemons mixed into it is going to be
amazing and you know the buzz will be
high every time you smoke something like
that the buzz is just straight to the
brain my eyes go crazy i get kind of
anxious my heart starts racing the
armpits get sweaty that's what i love
when i smoke so now let's talk about the
buzz a lot of times i feel like this one
goes right to the face right to the head
it's like oh gosh when i smoke it my
eyes go oh there it was they get all
droopy my face gets warm ah i feel like
i'm hot i feel like i got my temperature
raises the pits get sweaty the heart
starts racing i can't remember where i
put my sunglasses but i'm probably
wearing them i can't figure out where i
put my phone but i'm probably playing
with my phone and can't find it that's
the kind of buzz that the john lemon
gives to me all right we've talked a lot
about the smoking effects most of you
here are here to grow this plant so
let's talk about the growing
characteristics of john lennon most of
the things i breed take a little bit to
flower i would recommend letting these
go for about 70 days maybe a little bit
longer i say 10 weeks is average and
standard for this plant there may be
some shorter there definitely may be
some longer most of the best phenotypes
finish around 10 weeks the plants to
take a little bit longer are definitely
the lemon skunk leaners and they
definitely get super potent and super
lemony but i don't want all that lemon i
want more of the sour in there i prefer
the 10 weakers if you want to play with
those longer finishers i encourage you
to do that
expect tall plants these plants will
triple in size before they are finished
that's right triple if your grow space
is only six feet tall start flowering
around two feet save some space for the
light also that may mess you up um
the lemon skunk phenotype will get tall
quickly and it gets taller and it's a
little bit thinner the sour diesel
phenotype will spread out a little bit
more and not get as tall as quickly
you'll notice it does more branching
more spreading out more lateral growth
instead of just straight going straight
up
all those long arms do fill in with fat
colas on both phenotypes if you don't
clean them up too much a lot of us
do too much lollipopping and pruning
this is one that i recommend pruning and
lollipopping a little bit less if you
let all those little balls grow they
will fill in and that will make one
giant nugget all the way up the branches
will be big fat colas if you don't take
too much off so leave a lot of that
that's my advice even the bottom buds on
these plants will get frosty and dense
if they're getting just a little bit of
light they'll fill in don't worry about
that i usually most of the time when i'm
talking about growing i recommend and
suggest a heavy defoliation
not with these plants if you were going
to defoliate your john lemon go medium
maybe just a little above medium but do
not go hard they don't reply well they
don't react well respond well to that
you'll get hate mail they'll tell you
they're pissed off for the next week or
so they won't recover so go light with
the defoliation go light to medium maybe
medium hard medium at the most popping
and twisting is okay with these plants
they will take it very well and it does
slow down that vertical growth so as
soon as you throw them into flower maybe
even a week before flower pop and twist
all those stems as soon as they recover
about 14 21 days guess what pop and
twist again or do it in more spaces
they're growing there's more space to
pop and twist keep popping they will
keep growing it'll slow them down from
going up they'll keep growing out
they'll get whiter they'll get stalkier
and they will recover from that before
they start flowering where are we i've
got more notes
they do react well to topping but i
wouldn't recommend topping them too many
times i think one top kind of low to
make all those lower branches meat
because these plants will make one giant
top cola if you don't take it out take
that out all the bottoms will meet
they'll meet right up to it i wouldn't
go more than one top
these plants do not like the screen of
green method very well they don't like
to be trellised and manipulated and
pulled around too much
i usually do a screen when they're low
to spread them out so these plants like
to go up i put a screen on them and pull
them down to make them go out and then i
can shape them the way i want after that
i don't do a lot of manipulation most of
the time i'll do some weaving and do the
weave the arms in where i want them now
with these plants i realize they
probably grow better if i don't weave
them into the net so i do minimal
trellising i do a spreader and i do a
supporter a lot of your plants are going
to get really tall really quickly so i
recommend at least that support net or
maybe some sticks or tomato cages or
something like that because they are
going to get tall a lot of the
phenotypes will be very robust and
turgid and be able to hold themselves up
some of them will need supports
especially when they start developing
big fat chunky frosty i'm just
exaggerating big beautiful buds you guys
are going to need some supports for
that one thing i have noticed is that
these plants do eat a lot of nitrogen
and they do benefit from continued
nitrogen into the flowering phase a lot
of times they'll run out of nitrogen
kind of early so a good way to prevent
that is to continue your veg feed a
couple of weeks into flower a lot of
times we just cut out that veg nutrient
right away we quit giving it nitrogen we
switch right to the bloom newts on day
one of flour these plants will run out
of nitrogen or have the opportunity or
are likely to run out of nitrogen if you
do things that way
i don't recommend giving them just a big
hit of nitrogen right before you flip
them they won't like that they will
benefit and they will appreciate it and
respond better if you give them lower
doses of nitrogen later into the
flowering phase maybe all the way up to
day 14 maybe even a little later
they will start burning out of nitrogen
and they do grow for 10 maybe more weeks
be prepared if you do run out of
nitrogen you can foliar feed them feed
them your base nutrient that will help
but once you start seeing it it will be
a chase and a race because they will eat
a lot of nitrogen that's going to start
throwing everything else out of whack
also so give them some nitrogen early in
flower don't cut that out now let's talk
a little bit about phenotypes that's
always everybody's favorite i'm going to
give my disclaimer everybody always asks
not everybody a lot of people ask what's
your favorite phenotype or what
phenotype would you pick
um that phenotype popped up in my garden
and it was perfect for me it may not
even pop up in your garden since you've
got different lights air water soil
microbes nutrients
different love different music
everything is different in there
you may not even see the same phenotypes
that i have because a phenotype is an
expression based on an environment if
you don't have the same environment you
may not even get the same expression so
that's step one of talking about
phenotypes the other part is
when i select a phenotype i am selecting
it for me that's who i want to smoke
grow
breed take pictures of smell it look at
it for the next year or two that's the
plan i'm working with
it's kind of like picking your date do
you want me to select your date
i like to describe phenotype selection
kind of like this i made a bunch of
seeds there are several lines to pick
from we have agreed you want lemons you
want sour you want diesel feel so you
pick john lemon that's what you've got
now in my mind we've got it narrowed
down pretty damn close to what we got
i'm going to compare this to we've all
decided that we want italian food we've
all now driven to the italian restaurant
that's what we're going to call john
lemon this just got weird and it became
italian food but follow along this will
all make sense in the end when we get to
the italian restaurant they're going to
pass us a menu on that menu is going to
be nine different kinds of pasta
there'll probably be an eggplant dish
there'll be a bunch of other great [ __ ]
in there um you might want the white
sauce you might want the garlic sauce
i'm going for the red sauce today that i
usually do the white sauce but i already
assigned it to somebody else we all want
different sauces right so that is kind
of what i think it's like when we're
selecting phenotypes we've all decided
we want italian food no it's up to you
to pick if you want the marinara or if
you want the garlic sauce or if you want
the white sauce i've driven you to the
italian restaurant i got you that far so
phenotype selection i don't want to
choose off the menu for you you've got
to open up the menu and see which one
gets your opinion
the phenotype i'm going to select is
great for me the meal i'm going to
select is perfect for me i'm a
vegetarian i like this i like this i'm
going to order the right [ __ ] for me you
may want to order totally different [ __ ]
and that's how your phenotype may be i
want the one that takes a long time to
finish not in this case i want that 10
weaker but generally i want a long
sativa dominant longer finishing longer
flowering plant with a lot of flavor
that gets me wrecked when i smoke it
that's got a certain shape
i don't really care too much about the
colors and the
certain things i'm not growing it for
instagram i want it to be potent i need
to be resistant to pathogen i wanted to
not be intersex i really needed to
handle problems and bugs well because
i'm going to breed to it make market
seeds out of it so i've got a different
criteria than you you may want one that
grows short and squat and tastes like
chocolate has an indica dominant buzz
and puts you on the couch so me telling
you which phenotype to select
doesn't do either one of us any good in
my opinion we've driven to the italian
restaurant you've got the menu grow them
out find the italian dish in there that
is the best for you now with that being
said let's talk about some of the
phenotypical expressions i have
experienced in my test growers and my
friends growing these strains have
experienced
there is the sour phenotype then there
is the more sour phenotype all of the
phenotypes are sour
the main difference
some is going to have more diesel than
others some is going to have um so the
main difference is the growth structure
we'll talk about the flavors and i've
already talked about that we'll touch on
that again in a second the main
difference is the growth structure the
sour d phenotype uh kind of creeps
outward it branches out it gets a little
bit whiter the lemon skunk phenotype
gets a little bit taller it doesn't grow
out as wide so you don't need as much
space between plants
but it's going to get taller so you need
more vertical space for that one other
differences like i mentioned before are
flavors and aromas those are things that
you'll notice as soon as you start
flowering you may notice some of these
differences
one thing i notice is some of my
favorite phenotypes if you give it a
little stem rub and smell your fingers
it is cat piss and ammonia and i love it
but let's stay on track here i've got
notes in front of me uh the background
aromas the so it's sour and lemons that
is obvious that is the main ingredient
the main aromas you're gonna smell here
sour is just overwhelmingly kind of
gross sour and then you've got lemons uh
just fresh ripe lemon so it's like oh
that's grossly good and lemons oh gross
you make a pucker face and you smell it
again then there are background and
backup aromas that come with that some
of those are like diesel feel or
gasoline uh then there's skunk in there
some of them smell like sour skunk ass
but then we've got things uh like i've
been talking about ammonia cat piss and
real astringent flavors like that
there's one of them that randomly throws
out a little bit of lavender terps and i
don't know where that comes from one
thing i've noticed though that i think
that medium and feed really play a huge
difference in the flavors and aromas of
this cross
when i grow it in soilless mix it tastes
pretty pretty similar pretty much the
same way when i put it in cocoa it
tastes different when my friends grow it
in living soil it really brings out that
lavender sort of thing it brought out
sort of a floral terp that i could not
quite describe still had that main sour
thing to it but there was something at
the end i've got a really sensitive
palette i can really identify things i
like to think i like to believe i seem
to have proven that theory but there was
a lavender sweetness at the end of it
and he runs organic living soil so
that seemed to bring that out all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls that
is my report on john lemon i feel like i
rushed through that one kind of quickly
so if you need more details more
information if you have any questions
corrections comments or concerns of
course you can send me an email at
growfromyourheart hotmail.com
also make sure you check out the website
iredirect.com there's a sale going right
now where you can get john lemon packs
for a great price tune in tap in is what
i think my buddy may says big shout out
to masonic smoker uh make sure you
support the patreon page at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else is at my main website
iregenetics.com
check it out i hope you had as much fun
watching this episode as i did recording
it it's good to be back from the uh the
sickness the virus the plague i feel
like i flowed pretty good on this one
this was the first episode that i
actually really felt comfortable on and
natural again so thanks for watching
thanks for hanging out i'm gonna wrap it
up while it's still a good show i'll be
back in a week with fresh new content i
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
rozin ryan and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you