[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world i'm your
host my friends call me ross to jeff
this is episode 767
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode i'm going to talk a little
bit about having a backup plan before i
get to that part of the show let's do a
few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to a longtime supporter my
friend girls grow too let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to one of
my favorite photographers my buddy all
mixed up let's send a big thank you
shout out to double d and godfather kush
i want to send a fist bump and a thank
you shout out to my friend stoner dave
and billy bong smokin let's send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy in
canada caribou heart tv let's send a
thank you shout out to guido's grow room
and the dad hayes let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to doc gross
and brian p then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to stoned trout bomb
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show but you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know i do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast
i also want to send a big thank you to
everybody who participated in the new
drop and the big sale on iredirect.com
that's right there's a bunch of new
merchandise on iredirect.com if you're
looking for some new beans now is the
chance to grab them i redirect.com of
course all the patrons got a great
coupon code all the members of the
newsletter got a warning that the drop
was coming so make sure you either sign
up for the newsletter or support the
show on patreon and you will get a heads
up and some coupon codes for the new
drops on i redirect don't be shy don't
feel left out there are still plenty of
things left on sale at
iredirect.com go check it out all right
i want to send a big thank you to a
bunch of friends that i saw this weekend
i got to run into my buddy nick dude i
got to see my good friend erica i got to
hang out with my buddy baker i got to
boogie down with my buddy justin and
most importantly i got to boogie down
and have a great weekend with the lovely
dread vibes also known as zara also
known as the queen of my world i got to
take her to see fish where we bumped
into a bunch of great friends we had a
good time my favorite band is fish they
did four nights at dick's sporting goods
what is the sporting goods event center
sport the gigantic soccer field in
denver colorado fish did four nights
there
i was planning to go to all four i don't
miss a fish show in colorado if they
come within a couple hundred miles i
will be there so i got tickets for all
four nights i asked miss dread vibes
also known as zara if she would like to
go with me for a night or two and being
not a fish fan at the time she said she
wanted to go to the first night i
thought that was great but i am a fish
fan and i know that you never miss a
sunday show so i got her a ticket for
the first night and the last night which
was sunday and after the first night she
looked at me and she said hey babe can i
come with you tomorrow and of course i
said yes because there's nothing better
than fish other than fish with your
favorite person so i took her to the
second night on the second night she
said hey babe this was amazing and i
said yes i already got you a ticket for
tomorrow she ended up going to all four
nights because she loved the band fish
so much i've tried to describe the
the vibe the uh the feeling of official
the entire event from pulling into the
parking lot to getting into the show to
seeing the band to getting out of the
parking lot the parking lot party
everything involved in fish is a big fun
productive event uh it's it's a it's an
event that's all i can describe it as
i've tried to explain it to several
people and i've never gotten it right
when i took her there she was blown away
uh she had such a great time she smiled
for uh the entire four days she had a
big smile on her face on day five we
were all sore and felt like we were
dying but it was a great fish adventure
uh once again big shout out to all the
friends that i saw there
if i ran into you at the fish shows and
i was uh
goofy or short with you and just said hi
and walked away or didn't seem like i
was all there you're correct i wasn't
[ __ ] all there i was having a good
time it was the weekend i was a little
bit checked out still got nothing but
love nothing but respect for you if you
got some seeds please do post pictures
of those when you grow them all right
let me make sure i covered all the notes
and then we are going to jump into the
main topic of this podcast yes i got to
take the beautiful dread vibes to see
fish we ran into our friends ah nick was
there shout out to nick dude shout out
to a longtime friend erica big shout out
to my buddy baker baker's the [ __ ]
mayor of denver uh an awesome dude and
also got to see a longtime friend an old
friend my buddy justin who's a fellow
drummer fellow fish nerd from back in
the lawrence kansas day so it's good to
run into all those folks plus several
other people that i saw ran into i
wanted to make a note to say hi to those
folks shout out looks like we covered
all of the main
business at the top of the show let's
just jump right into the main topic of
this podcast i've been talking about it
a lot
i recently had the kovid 19 virus it
[ __ ] me up pretty bad i was down for
10 or 11 days feeling really sick then
probably another solid week of not
feeling well and then another couple of
days of feeling like damn i just can't
shake this my body felt ran down my
attention span was funky my lungs were
lacking oxygen my voice sounded like
[ __ ] i was in rough shape for a little
while uh while i had kovit i was
basically face down either in bed or on
a couch for about 11 days i would get up
to go pee uh then i would get back on
the couch i'd eat as much food as my
body would allow me to have which wasn't
much then i would try to find the couch
and the air conditioner i was so hot
that i thought i was gonna die couldn't
function i got dizzy every time i stood
up that is gone now but um what i wanted
to talk about today is do you have some
sort of a backup plan i don't want you
to get coveted i don't want you to get
sick i don't want anything bad to happen
to you but it is possible i don't want
those things to happen to me but it did
i was
very minimally uh able to work in my
garden for the time that i was sick
there was a two-week period where it was
just kind of like [ __ ] it if the plants
live they live if they die they die that
was my attitude i know a lot of you guys
are probably cringing hearing that
that's how sick i was i did not care if
the plants that operate my business
lived or died i do care deeply about
that but i was so sick that it was like
go stand up and water those plants and i
would stand up and i feel like i was
spinning in circles and wanted to throw
up and do back flips i didn't want to do
the back flips my brain was doing
backflips so i couldn't really take care
of the garden now my question is do you
have a backup plan is there somebody in
your circle your life hopefully within
your home possibly maybe they can water
or wherever your grow is they can water
your growth for you should you get sick
injured have to go away for a couple of
days maybe you get a job opportunity you
got to take off maybe fish comes you got
to go for four or five days and be away
do you have some sort of a back-up plan
is there somebody that can water those
plants for you does that person know how
to adjust and check ph do they know how
to mix nutrients maybe now is a good
time to think about who would i call if
i do have to go out of town who would i
call if i do get sick because i always
preach especially in illegal red state
areas i always preach shut up don't tell
anybody about your grow but do you have
one person that you can trust with your
growth luckily i've got a i've been in
this town for a long time i have a lot
of great friends a lot of family i've
got one or two people i can uh heavily
rely on to take care of a garden if
things do go completely wrong for me
i've got people i can give instructions
to and i can help them out plus there's
cameras in there so i can guide them by
using the cameras and we have facetime
now but do you have somebody in your
immediate area that can come help you if
you are going to have a problem it's got
to be somebody that you trust but also
somebody that you know is going to
follow the instructions but also
somebody that when they mess it up
you know how you're going to be able to
handle being mad at them because you
might be super pissed if this person
accidentally ruins your garden so do you
have a backup for sick days do you have
an auto watering system do you have
somebody that can come in and water for
you if you do have that auto water
system it's going to need to be refilled
eventually those shouldn't go for more
than a week maybe 14 days at the most
to the best of my knowledge if you're if
you've got water sitting in a reservoir
you don't want that there for too long
especially if it's got nutrients in it
even if it's moving still in my opinion
you're going to want that changed out
eventually does that person know how to
change that water for you how to
replenish refresh replenish and or and
or i'm going to not even edit that look
i'm human you guys does that person know
how to replenish and or refill your
reservoir that was harder to say than it
looked geez
all right let me get myself back on
track uh also
do you have somebody i don't want you to
get hurt i don't want you to get sick
but [ __ ] does happen this is the reality
do you have somebody that you can call
if you are to get hurt in your grow
especially in an illegal place or maybe
you don't want anybody maybe you just
don't need paramedics and cops there
maybe you're working in the garden you
poke yourself in the eye maybe you get
something in the eye maybe you cut your
finger and you just need some help do
you have somebody that you can call do
you have a way that you can do that
maybe if you get some [ __ ] in your eyes
this has really happened to somebody
that i know he told me the story he got
ph down in his eyes while mixing a
reservoir he was blind he could not see
a [ __ ] thing he was in an illegal
area allegedly growing illegally
allegedly it's all a fictional character
you can't do anything about a guy you
don't know who he is anyway this dude
had ph down in his eyes and could not
figure out how to work his phone because
he was blind luckily he was able to hold
the phone up and say hey siri and then
he was able to call one of his family
members who lived nearby who was able to
come and help him i just activated siri
on my phone i was afraid that would
happen but he used the hey siri feature
and then he called a family member they
came and helped him out do you have
something like that set up is there
somebody that knows about your grow that
if you call and you say hey i need some
help you can say it discreetly over the
phone and they know what you're talking
about they can come help you out that
may be beneficial to you if you are in
some sort of a
prohibition area have somebody that can
back you up all the time even if you are
not in a prohibition area because [ __ ]
does go wrong now speaking of having
backups i recently experienced a power
outage the uh the transformer uh near
where my grow is located exploded it
seriously [ __ ] exploded there was no
power for about 18 hours uh do you have
a backup plan for no power do you have a
generator do you have some sort of idea
of how to get out of the grow if the
lights go dark because i've been in the
grow and the power goes out and it's
completely dark in there if i didn't
have my cell phone or most of the time i
carry a little pocket flashlight these
days if i didn't have one of those
devices i would have been [ __ ] out of
luck and stuck in that grow would not
have been able to find my way out i
thought i would have tripped over things
broke a bunch of [ __ ] that could have
gone terribly wrong for me so do you
have some sort of power backup in there
do you have a battery-powered light they
sell these little lights at all the
plastic stores the stores that sell the
plastic [ __ ] um it looks one of them
looks like a light switch and you
actually can uh just glue it or tape it
to the wall it's got its own self
adhesive on the back and it sticks to
the wall it's a light switch when you
flip it up the light comes on when you
switch it down the light goes off it is
battery powered that way if the
electricity goes out it's still got a
battery in there you can use that flip
that on maybe find your way out of the
grower or something like that they also
sell some that are just little domes you
tap them and they come on you tap them
and they go off i'm sure you've seen
them on tv they're as seen on tv sort of
items like i said they sell those at all
the plastic stores or maybe just get
yourself a little carry flashlight or a
lot of us have our cell phone already
but have some sort of light in case the
power does go out in there then
do you know an electrician or have an
electrician friend or somebody that at
least knows a little bit about
electrical and wiring because if you do
experience a problem in your home and
you're in an illegal state are you able
to actually call whoever is in the phone
book or on the internet for electrical
services you may need somebody on your
team that can handle electrical be very
careful messing with electricity don't
do it yourself if you're not qualified
don't burn the house down because you
decided to do electrical upgrades on
your own and you have no idea what
you're doing that puts a very bad look
on the cannabis industry that's going to
get you in trouble that's just a step
back for the legalization and the
freedom of cannabis so don't be that
person uh make friends with an
electrician do you know an electrician
find somebody that maybe works at an
electric company or works for an
electrical uh company that does installs
or something and buddy up with them and
see if they'll come do work for you on
the side so you don't have to involve
too many uh receipts and books and
things like that just find a friend is
what i'm trying to say be careful is
what i'm telling you also same thing
applies for an hvac technician if the
air conditioner or the heater does go
out in your house and you happen to be
growing in that house do you want to
call whatever it is local abc heating
and plumbing do you want them in your
house or do you want one of the bros
that you could probably pay with some
product if things go right find an hvac
guy find a plumber and find a friend
that you can call if you're to hurt
yourself and find a friend that can back
you up if you do need water it'd be
really cool if this is all one person
but that would be a bad [ __ ] you
got a plumber you got an electrician you
got a hvac guy i'm i'm like a an
apprentice and all of those after
working and grows for so long i feel
like i can fake my way through most of
those but um do you know all those guys
find those guys they'll be very very
helpful and beneficial to you some other
things i want to talk about is do you
have backup pumps if you're running
hydroponics or any sort of moving water
sort of system deep water culture
trays ebb and flow do you have a backup
pump do you have a backup air pump and a
backup water pump because those things
love to [ __ ] out at the worst time
usually like friday seven o'clock right
after the growth store closed and you
got plans for the weekend you're going
to hear
and that's going to be your pump not
pumping water the way that it should be
you're going to take it apart you're
going to try to clean it you can put it
back together throw it in there and
smoke's going to come out of it still
[ __ ] you got to go get a new monday
pump everything's closed just ruin your
weekend have a backup i know they're a
little bit expensive but everything is
expensive if you can have a backup pump
that is one of the things i definitely
recommend having a backup of i also like
to have a backup ph tester because
sometimes my ph tester i don't believe
it i'll calibrate it i'll check it i'll
throw it in there and if just maybe
something will make me concerned i'll
check it with the other one i like to
have two just because [ __ ] does go
haywire keep them both calibrated and
cleaned properly calibrate them
frequently pay a lot of attention also
maybe have backup testing standards
because if you test it in your seven
solution you test it in your four and
one of those is expired now you're way
off have a backup testing standard
solution as well now we're just getting
crazy here but these are things i do
like to have backups of um something i
don't need a backup of something i want
a couple of around in the grow
especially since i've learned the
commercial growing environment you need
them every so many feet apart it's
either 50 or 150 feet i like to have a
fire extinguisher do you guys have a
fire extinguisher in your grow space i
don't want you to need it but i'd rather
you have it and not need it than need it
and be like [ __ ] i don't have anything
and you're just throwing reservoir water
on a fire that would be terrible also
do you have an eye wash station or some
sort of eye washing plan a lot of people
do have their grow at home but a lot of
people don't have access to water right
away in a commercial environment we need
water very close we need a eye wash
station very close
for the department of health and the
osha standards i recommend that you
carry a bottle of clean water on you or
within reach in your grow if you get
something in your eyes tear off your
gloves you should be wearing gloves tear
off your gloves get that clean water
bottle start pouring that water in your
eyes get that contaminant or whatever it
is out of your eyes then if you need to
pull out the phone bust out the hey siri
then call that one good friend that can
come help you out and make sure you're
safe to help you clean up talk you down
from the panic attack that you just
[ __ ] had from getting ph down or
whatever it was in your eyes all right
where are we i feel like i'm getting
rambling i've got a lot of notes here
that i do want to keep up on
all right the next part i'm going to
talk about is a little bit weird but
it's something that i do feel like we
should be prepared for especially if you
are in a red state or a non-friendly
state how quickly can you make your
entire operation disappear let's just
say hypothetically you piss somebody off
it happens people are [ __ ] sensitive
nowadays let's just say somebody gets
mad at you and they know what you're
doing and they go to the wrong people
and now the people are coming within 12
to 36 hours they're gonna be not even
knocking on your front door they're
gonna be pulling the [ __ ] front door
off can you make your [ __ ] disappear
within 12 to 24 to 36 hours with no sign
that it was even there can you get rid
of it if you do so make sure you get rid
of
everything all the way down to the
mixing shot glasses all the way down to
the instructional books clean up very
well do not leave a trace that anything
has happened will happen could have
happened no trace leave no trace how
quickly can you do that if you were in a
place where growing is not approved
tolerated or accepted that may be
something that you want to think about
you may want to be able to get rid of
that quite quickly if things do go wrong
for you do you have a plan do you have a
strategy also very importantly
it helps to have a good friend to help
you stay level headed when things like
that do happen so you have a bro that
can back you up
all right there is one more person that
we do want to make sure to have on our
team if we are going to be growing
cannabis in any legal or illegal sort of
fashion which by the way i should make a
disclaimer rosta jeff and the grow from
your heart podcast does not condone
promote or encourage you to do anything
illegal always follow local laws and
regulations don't break the rules but
you're a [ __ ] adult do what you want
to do rasta jeff is also a fictional
character and this is a an entertainment
show so that's how that's going to go
with that being said the other person
that you should always have on your team
if you are going to cultivate consume
possess carry transport uh be anything
involved in cannabis or almost anything
fun or illegal i almost insist that you
have got a good working relationship
with a lawyer lawyers are readily
available a lot of them are terrible
many of them are [ __ ] awesome and can
be your best friend
just like your doctor i recommend you
are totally open with your lawyer once
you've paid them money everything you
say has a client lawyer confidentiality
clause they can't snitch on you right on
you if you kill somebody they may be
required to to tell on you for that i
don't think so though but if you're
doing crime and you do something or if
you did something or if you've got
something weird that is in a gray area
they cannot get you in trouble it is
best you let them know what you're doing
so they can prepare you can't properly
prepare if they don't know what you're
doing so let them know exactly what
you're up to if you've got an idea if
you're going to do something weird if
you're just curious about something
contact them that's what they're there
for you pay them
try to pay them a monthly fee if you can
for a certain amount of contacts or have
a retainer just have a relationship with
a lawyer make friendship with them if
you can go to lunch with them if you can
buy them lunch occasionally call them
just check in just see how things are
going maybe they'll call in and check in
with you that way when [ __ ] goes wrong
if it's three in the morning if it's one
in the afternoon when you call them they
answer on the first ring that is what
you want from your lawyer a lawyer
that's going to answer on the first ring
and do the work to get the case
dismissed because we all know you were
not doing anything illegal or wrong or
problematic or whatever i'm getting off
track here but i do recommend that
you've got the lawyer so we need
somebody that can help us out on a
backup date we need somebody that can
help us out if we are injured or have an
emergency we need someone that can help
us make the grow disappear it's always
good to have an electrician and an hvac
guy most importantly i always recommend
that you've got yourself a lawyer and
then get a bunch of grow books and keep
reading those that's what i recommend
all right that part took me right as
long as i was hoping it would take i do
have one more part of this podcast that
i do want to cover recently i did a
podcast called why i started making
seeds i did a really long uh
storytelling with rasta jeff if you will
as i was editing and listening to that
so many more
thoughts and memories and nostalgic
feelings came through my mind
and i forgot one
um
minor major details something that i
felt like i should have included in that
i talk a lot about uh making seeds and
getting seeds out to people so that
people can grow quality plants one thing
that was happening is i was posting
pictures of things uh like golden goat
golden goat is a very good example i
would post pictures of golden goat and
people in other locations would say uh
you kids in colorado are spoiled you get
the golden goat we can't get the golden
goat where i am i would kill for that i
would do anything for that and me being
the type of person that i am i want
everybody to have good medicine that was
part of my mission here uh that still is
part of my mission i'm out here teaching
you how to grow the best derby you can
i've taught you guys how to breed by now
i'm a seed breeder by career and i'm
teaching you how to breed your own seeds
that's how much i love this plant love
teaching you guys so um i wanted
everybody to have access to
good quality genetics good seeds at a
good fair price and many many people
wanted the golden go so i took it upon
myself to make golden goat feminized
seeds that was one of the things i
really wanted to do was put some of
these elite cuts into people's hands in
a feminized form
so the golden goat is a very good
example of me putting a feminized line
of a very uh elite clone only out to the
market for people all over the world to
be able to grow and enjoy so making fem
seeds and making s-ones of clone onlys
was something i really enjoyed doing
because that was giving uh making it
more fair for everybody i i like the
idea of everybody having um the same uh
the equal playing field why should some
people in colorado be able to produce
better medicine than people in wyoming
or new mexico or arizona or even
california why should the people in
california be able to produce better
medicine than the people in colorado or
new york or the same states we should
all have access to the same thing if
you're sick you need medicine that was
my theory that is still my theory if
you're sick why would i not get you the
golden goat that would make you feel
better just because you're not in the
correct state that's [ __ ] stupid
that's silly that's what the government
has been doing they've been limiting you
us on medicine because you're not in the
appropriate square that allows you to
consume cannabis this square no weed no
relief no feeling good this square you
could feel good you could smoke weed so
i don't want to do that i think that
every state uh everywhere every country
every sick person every well person
should feel good and or better was my
theory behind that so i wanted to add
that short rant that minor detail that
point of passion if you will to this
part of the podcast make that another
part b of why i started breeding seeds
because i wanted it to be fair i don't
want i don't want to have just me with
elite genetics that's not fair
i love having elite genetics it's
[ __ ] cool that way everybody around
here gets to grow and breed with elite
[ __ ] genetics everybody's well
medicated super high and having a good
time but then my part of my passion is
making people feel better not a limited
amount of people everybody let's be fair
let's get that [ __ ] out there so that
was a big part of why i wanted to make
femmes especially s-ones uh that's a big
part of why i'm getting the seeds out
there so that everybody can grow the
good [ __ ] and feel better that's the
bottom line everybody grow the best herb
we can so the sick people can feel well
and the well people can feel even better
all right i think that is a good way and
a good time to start wrapping up this
podcast thank you once again for
listening to another episode of the grow
from your heart podcast if you have any
questions corrections comments or
concerns you know i would love to answer
those on the show the email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me those questions
corrections comments concerns
constructive criticism
or fatal feedback whatever you want to
call it i'm up for all of that
make sure you check out iredirect.com
that's right iredirect.com
also support the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart you will get a coupon code for i
redirect everything else is on the
website of course that is
iriegenetics.com
i know that's a lot of stuff to write
down and take in here at the end of the
show pick your favorite one join us tap
in is what i think all the cool kids say
that is all i've got for you for this
episode i'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content i want to give a
giant shout out to my friend black thumb
grower and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you