[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world I'm
your host my friends call me Rasta Jeff
this is episode
768 of the girl from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to answer a
couple of grow questions before we get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to one of my favorite Growers
my buddy root 305 let's send a big thank
you shout out to my Canadian buddy JH I
want to send a thank you shout out to
Kip listen to fist bump and a thank you
shout out to larf Night Rises listen to
Big thank you shout out to Elders Garden
I want to send a fist bump and a thank
you shout out to my buddy Mr mean green
let's send a thank you shout out to
Growing Tennessee
let's send a big fist bump to f a plant
count let's send a big thank you shout
out to roll this nug and Randy's Farms
let's send a big fist bump to Jay Dutch
and Noah and then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to Anvil Gardens big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the show speaking of
patreon I'm working on a patreon special
episode I do not try to leave any grow
material out on patreon so I do special
content on patreon I am planning an
episode where I'm going to eat a heavy
dose of Edibles and ask questions about
myself that's right I asked the patrons
to contribute questions that they've
always wanted to know or ask I've got an
a lot of great feedback already that
episode is in the works it is being
planned being written I'm compiling
questions I encourage you to join the
patreon campaign and send me your
questions and stay tuned for the episode
that will be coming out on the beginning
of next month so stay tuned for that but
join us on patreon look forward to the
episode where I ate too many Edibles and
try to tell and try to answer questions
about myself that the patrons have sent
in so check that one out that will be
coming out next month before I get too
far I do want to give everybody a big
thanks for 10
000 YouTube subscribers I do appreciate
it that was a big push we got a lot of
great folks supporting us there are 10
000 people subscribed thank you I do
appreciate each and every one of you if
you're not already subscribed to the
show please do click that subscribe
button also click that notification bell
every time I put out a new episode you
will get a notification you will not
miss any episodes also there are 768
episodes of this podcast they hear a lot
of times hey bro I wish you'd put out
more content uh we miss you doing two
shows away week there are
767 more episodes that you could go back
and listen to that if you haven't heard
all of them I do encourage you to go
back and listen to the old content
there's a lot of great stuff in there
still a lot of great grow knowledge grow
information grow Tech to learn even if
the episodes aren't completely current
that info is still completely useful
also a lot of people do laugh and enjoy
watching the older shows going back and
seeing how the show has evolved how my
approach to podcasting how the gear how
everything has evolved my point is go
watch a lot of the old episodes I've
been noticing that some of them have
been getting more views and more clicks
so thank you for that once again thank
you for 10 000 subscribers on the
YouTube alright I feel like that is
enough rambling here at the top of the
show I did say that I was going to
answer grow questions I've got a couple
of great emails right here in front of
me this one comes from my friend Kip big
shout out to my buddy Kip it goes a lot
like this it says what's up Rasta Jeff
what's up Kip good to see you thank you
for the patreon support thank you for
the great question it says I've got a
quick question for you I was wondering
in your experience what is the best
practice for flipping into flower after
taking clones that is a very good
question Kip goes on to say I typically
wait a couple of weeks so I can make
sure my roots are my Cuts root but I've
been getting nearly 100 percent rooting
success lately uh the funny part about
that is as soon as you get too confident
and you do flip your plants early that's
when you're going to have rooting
problems I'm not trying to curse you I'm
not trying to jinx you that is the way
that the grow gods do treat us so be
very careful with that it goes on it
does say is there a timeline you should
wait to flip after taking Cuts or can
you take a cut from a healthy plant and
then go straight into flour I'm doing a
fairly large Fino hunt right now of 36
plants congratulations bro that sounds
like a lot of fun uh in my 2x4 with Solo
cups and I want to keep them small also
thanks for all of the great content
every week and for the bomb genetics
enjoy your week brother from Kip I had
some notes on here but as I was reading
this I realized you're doing this in
Solo cups and I'm going to give one more
detail before I read the notes that I
actually have written to avoid taking
clones from 36 Solo cups have you
thought about re-veging I know that is
totally derailing your plan and you're
asking me about cloning which I will get
to but in my mind if you're running solo
cups those plants are going to get
they're only going to get so big you
don't want them too large in a Solo Cup
especially in your limited space large
Plant count there I always just grow
them very small then I would flour them
then I would Mark uh I would keep my
favorites then when I come to harvest I
would not Harvest all of it I'd leave
the bottom buds from every one of them
then smoke it and then re-veg your
favorites that's what I would do I would
re-vege them instead of doing clones for
plants this small but I don't want to
ruin your whole strategy I don't want to
rethink your whole program that's just a
suggestion that is what would Rasta Jeff
do I would just re-vadge now let's focus
on the question because that's what you
want to know let me be useful here there
are a couple of different ways to do
this in most situations we would not be
running such small plants in most
situations we're going to have larger
plants most people are not growing in
Solo cups a very small percentage of us
out there are growing in cups I do it
that's how I run a lot of testers some
of the things that I just bred I don't
know what they're going to do I want to
see if it's intersexy if it smells good
looks good so I'll run a bunch of those
in cups just to get a feel for what I've
got but not everybody does that in most
scenarios we're going to be growing
larger plants in larger containers so
the first scenario I want to talk about
is if we were to take clones from the
bottom of the plan A lot of times the
plants will grow up we leave the tops
alone we clean up the bottom right
before we go into flour that's called
lollipopping or shaving the legs you
clean up the bottom branches and they
take the suckers off the lower branches
that you do leave when you're doing that
I find that to be a great opportunity to
take a couple of clones the bottoms will
have two four maybe six clones available
right there on the bottom you can cut
off if you are taking clones from the
bottom you can cut those off and you
could in theory put your plant into
flour right away because you don't need
any hormones to move around you don't
need any recovery time because you're
taking stuff from the bottom you're just
completely removing it the hormones are
already at the top where you want them
so if you're going to take stuff from
the bottom when you're lollipopping you
can do that basically anytime they don't
need recovery time time for that again
that one detail you should focus on is
do you have roots on your clothes or are
you confident that your clones will root
before you put your other plants into
flour I still kind of use that same
practice I don't flour the room until I
see roots on the other clones that I've
taken so I know I've got backups that's
kind of a practice that I do employ
let's talk about another option now if
you do choose to take clones from the
top of the plants then yes I would wait
for some recovery time when I'm growing
larger plants I do generally top the
plant once or twice that main apical top
makes a beautiful clone a lot of times I
will take the two bottoms and the main
top right out of the plant and use those
as my three clones in my cloner or in my
clone machine so that's where my first
three clones will come from if I take
that top clone I do allow the plants at
least 10 to 14 days to recover you want
the hormones in that plant to move
around so that plant can establish who's
got the new apical dominant top that's
part of why we top it is to confuse that
plant's hormones and it goes wait we had
one dominant top that's the plant's goal
is to have one dominant top to get up
there and get pollinated and the rest of
the branches are just kind of extra
branches to get pollen to keep life
going but when you take out that main
top all the others go hey I've got the
chance to be the top so we got to let
that action happen and they'll all even
out and all try to grow up and be tops
and you get a bunch more main Tops on
the plant we do need to allow some time
for those hormones to move around and
for things to recover after we do take
the main top out you could
hypothetically go directly into flower
but you will get a much smaller yield
your top buds won't be as large as they
could be and that's always where most of
the weight and the yield and the bulk
comes from is that top part of the plant
there so you would be handicapping
yourself kneecapping crippling yourself
if you were to do that too quickly
another thing to think about there is if
you were trellising if you're topping or
if you're scrogging excuse me if you're
working them into a net you may want to
allow some time to work them in the net
let them recover a little bit before you
do put them into flour that will help
them grow like I said bigger fatter Buds
and that is the main goal is those big
fat juicy nuggets so if you are take
taking the quick answer if you're taking
clones from the bottom go ahead and flip
it if you're cutting the tops do allow
some time for Recovery my friend Kip
thank you for the great great question
bro I do appreciate it I look forward to
hearing back from you and I do look
forward to seeing how your 36 plant
funeral hunt goes in your small space if
you need any help have any questions
need some guidance please do reach out
for that because I've done basically
this exact thing that you were going to
do and I do wish you the best of luck
all right I'm Gonna Keep the show moving
I do have one more great question right
here in front of me this one comes from
our friend Sean it doesn't have a lot of
info about the name they want me use so
we're going to call you Sean today this
one was quick and to the point it said
do a video collecting pollen another
pollinating a female then it says you've
done the STS and clone cutting just the
thought but I know you're busy man I
love these quick to the point emails
these are awesome
um let's talk about this so Sean said do
a video collecting pollen that is a
great idea however
um YouTube does not like it when I post
videos that do contain live plants
YouTube has removed a couple of my
videos because they've got live plants
in them uh YouTube has also been taking
down uh videos and channels uh that are
part of our community so I'm trying to
be extra careful you may have noticed
sometimes I'm more careful with some of
the words that I do use I'm definitely
going to be more careful with some of
the content I would like to keep the
channel alive we do a lot of Education
we've got a great Community here the
comment section is always beautiful you
guys keep going in the comments I love
that but I have to be very careful with
what I'm putting out on YouTube so I
cannot do a pollen collection video but
I can describe it with words that should
be safe so let me talk a little bit
about collecting pollen I've got too
many notes on the table here let me
cover up this other page so I'm not so
distracted yes I do have the add big
shout out to the friend who made the
lemon Jeffrey concentrate it is working
bro anyway let's get back on track let's
talk about collecting pollen I can't
can't show you the plants because of
YouTube rules that's my first note here
the first thing I want to talk about
when it comes to collecting pollen is uh
know your male what are you working with
do you know that that's a good male
where'd you get that make a good
decision there then the next thing I'm
going to talk about is ah no wind and no
disruptions and no sprays we don't want
a lot of wind in the room so you're
going to put your plant into flour and
around day 14 or day 17 maybe 21-ish
you're going to start getting a lot of
pollen we don't need any wind in the
room that's going to blow that pollen
right off of your plant you're not going
to be able to collect it we don't want
to spray anything in the room because
that of course is going to destroy the
pollen we don't want that basically no
disruptions to this plant try not to
nudge it bump it don't move it around
keep that male plant in the same place
so that it can basically build up a
whole bunch of pollen for you to collect
all right so there are several ways to
collect the pollen let's jump into that
part the first method that I'm going to
talk about is while the plant is still
alive and standing and then eventually
we will cut this plant down and talk
about other ways to gather the pollen
there the first way this plant is
standing you've got your growing plant
it is growing just like a normal plant
except this one's a boy it's got balls
all over it uh one thing you can do to
collect the pollen is to put a
collection vessel underneath the plant
I've seen people use a big mirror I've
seen people use dinner plates I've seen
people use just a sheet of glass
something like that underneath the plant
that will collect the pollen that you
can scrape it up and scoop it up very
easily is a really good idea make sure
that whatever you use is non-static I've
seen people use like a little plate that
was plastic or a styrofoam plate and the
pollen actually fell out of the plant
and static electricity pushed that
pollen right away and we did not collect
any pollen at all because there was
static on the plastic or styrofoam plate
don't do that I recommend glass maybe a
Pyrex dish maybe a glass dinner plate if
you've got a big mirror that is perfect
so imagine that you just put the mirror
down and this is just an idea you put
the mirror Down Under the plant and then
you set the plant the whole pot right on
top of that mirror then all of the
pollen that falls down will land right
on that mirror or that sheet of glass or
whatever you have chosen now that does
sound kind of sketchy because you're
putting a plant right onto the mirror if
you've got a small plant it's not a big
deal if you've got a thick mirror it's
not a big deal you got to run some risks
if you want to win the game sometimes
now another thing we could talk about is
uh you just let that pollen fall right
onto that mirror so it'll start
pollinating it'll fall right down on
there another thing we can do is
sometimes I'll take a plan instead of
letting it grow straight up I'll just
grab it right in the middle and I'll put
a tie on it and I'll bend that plant
down maybe like uh 45 maybe a 90 degree
angle I'm not sure where my arm is right
now I'm not good with angles I guess
that's a 45. I'll put it at a 45 degree
angle and then we'll put the collection
vessel underneath that now the plant's
kind of tipped it's going to fall more
directly onto the vessel you don't have
the 360 following a pollen you got one
more long distance of pollen falling
maybe like a glass baking sheet a Pyrex
sheet or something like that would be
perfect to collect the pollen underneath
there so you can just let it grow and
that pile will start falling out that's
a really easy way to do it another way
that you could do it is to start tapping
the plant if you've got it growing
straight up or if you've got it tipped
over I go in there I honestly I'm a
drummer I've got drumsticks laying
around I go in with the drumstick and a
collection vessel usually a Pyrex dish
sometimes a jar and I'll just hold that
dish or that Pyrex dish or the jar right
up to the plant and I'll just start
tapping the plant the pollen Falls right
out into my dish I just use the
drumstick tap tap tap when you do this
pollen is going to go everywhere I
recommend maybe wearing a mask maybe
covering up if you've got other plants
around that you don't want to pollinate
definitely take precautions for that you
may want to wet those plants while
you're messing with the pollen then
clean yourself up make sure that so
water deactivates pollen you guys if
you've got pollen on you in your
dreadlocks and your clothes and your
beard on your clothes wherever else I
haven't said on your shoes is where I
think I'm headed water will deactivate
that so you can get a pump spray or a
water bottle spray yourself down real
good or hop in the shower that will get
rid of all that active pollen also if
you spray down the plants the pistols
are wet they are less likely to receive
the pollen at that time that should help
you out a little bit but be be very
careful because that pollen is very tiny
and one plate of pollen equals one seed
and you can get a bunch of pollen just
stuck in your dreadlocks and your arm
hair and your clothes on your shoes it
does not take much so be very careful
with the pollen so as soon as you start
tapping that plant pollen is going to
start coming out and going flying a lot
of it will fall straight down tap gently
just enough maybe tap lower on the
branch tap down here and the pollen up
here will start falling out don't be too
aggressive also don't have any fans on
don't breathe too heavily and definitely
do not sneeze because you will blow your
pollen all over the place all of your
work will be a waste of time that pollen
will go everywhere as long as this plant
is alive it will continue to produce
pollen up till probably week 10 week 11
whenever it starts burning out it'll
start good it'll go into senescence and
give up but you'll get plenty of fallen
out of it you can keep that plant
pollinating and just keep tapping it
every few days and more pollen will come
out or leave your collection vessel
underneath it and more pollen will land
onto that glass plate or that Pyrex dish
if you've got it bent over more pollen
will fall out I've seen guys just run a
ganja plant a male ganja plant in the
extra bathroom or in the window just in
the sunlight in the flowering season
right now outdoor season the plant would
go into flower within 21 days excuse me
within 21-ish days it would start
banging out pollen we could collect
pollen really easily just by putting a
plant in this window right here and give
it some time if we gave it a dark period
if we turned off all the all the lights
in the house and just use the the
sunlight the natural sunlight so if you
put a plant in the bathroom close the
door open the window let the sun
function on that it would make pollen
for you if it were a male it would begin
to make pollen for you you could collect
pollen that easily now we can continue
to collect pollen until we've got as
much as we need we do not need a lot
once you feel like this plant is done
now it is time to cut the plant down I
would gently carefully if you can try to
remove move the largest leaves from the
plant not a big deal if you can't do it
without disturbing the plant I'm kind of
a defoliation ninja I could just grab
with the thumb and the forefinger and
just take off the Leaf real easily it
just pops right off for me if you don't
have those ninja skills maybe you don't
do it but now is a good time to take off
some of the bigger leaves then I usually
get a Pyrex dish I've got a Pyrex dish
that my I don't even know where it came
from it probably used to be made to make
used to make brownies or some sort of
casserole I have commandeered it that is
now my pollen collection vessel it's
about probably 16 inches long and eight
or nine inches wide a beautiful pan to
go in the oven no longer that now it is
my pollen dish I usually take the top
off the plant or if it's a small plant
maybe I'll take the whole plant chop it
and gently lay that male plant into that
Pyrex dish and I will let it dry right
there as it dries more pollen will fall
out of it so it'll just fall all the
pollen comes out into that Pyrex dish
once I feel like it's super dry I'll
kind of crunch the tops of my fingers
all the last bits of pollen will fall
out I'll lift that male plant and I just
give it one one of these I kind of grab
it at the base and use my fingers just
to kind of pull all the the pollen right
off of there into the dish to make sure
to get the last of it then I'll discard
that male plant he's done his job I've
got a dish with pollen in it now I let
that dry I want the pollen dry I'm gonna
say it again bone bone dry I said
earlier water will destroy your pollen
so at this point we want to get that
bone dry I would get tweezers I'd get
some sort of sifting device and pull out
all of the debris all of the male
flowers anything that is not pollen
needs to come out of here let it dry
really dry then put it in a container an
airtight dry container I prefer a glass
container maybe a glass vial with a
silicate pack I'm going to say it again
a silicate pack not a Boveda pack we
want the package that sucks up the
moisture not maintains the humidity
level we want zero humidity in this
package so put a put a silicate pack in
there some people use rice to absorb the
moisture that may work for you I don't
know how much rice per pollen honestly I
don't do that at I use the silly kit
pack so put that in there to absorb the
moisture and get your package super dry
before you seal it up then when you seal
it up I do recommend you put that in a
cool dry dark place I keep my pollen and
the crisper drawer in the refrigerator
and it seems to work for about two maybe
three or four sometimes up to six months
it depends on the pollen uh kind of
depends on I don't know I've had a lot
of variables so I don't know what it
really depends on some of it stores real
well some of it just doesn't now the way
that I usually do this is I don't
generally collect a lot of pollen the
way that I usually do it is I will run
the male plant I'll run the female
plants I'll time them perfectly when it
is time for pollination I drag that boy
plant right to the middle of the room
and I give them a good shake and all
that pollen will come out and I'll watch
that pollen go everywhere there are no
fans on I usually do it in the dark I
try not to breathe I try not to sneeze
let the pollination happen then I'll
wait four or five days let that pollen
build up again I'll go back in there
give them another Shake then when I'm
done Shake taking him I'll cut him down
and actually go and smack that male
plant either against the fan or against
the light I've got lights with the
shield right out of the glass up the
glass reflector right above it I'll hit
that light and the pollen just comes
raining down yeah it makes a little
extra cleanup there's pollen everywhere
I got to clean up anyway so I smack that
dead plant that I just cut it down I
smacked that plant right up against the
light all the pollen comes raining down
then I will discard that male plant
because I don't need it anymore but I
don't even keep the mail around I don't
collect the pollen I just cut them down
smack them around get the pollen
everywhere he's done his job and now
he's free to go now you've got pollen in
your collection vessel uh you've
probably stored it you've had in the
fridge for a little while now your
female plants are ready for pollination
let's talk about how to do that there
are several ways you could do it if
you've got a lot of pollen you could
just go in there and maybe turn off all
the fans and just go right above the uh
right above the canopy and just open up
your pollen whatever it's in and just
give it a few Taps and just let some
pollen just gently fall out you'll see
it just gently sprinkle the plants or if
you want to care fully pollinate one or
two branches you can get a Q-tip or a
paintbrush and you can pull the branch
down that you want maybe even pull that
plant out of the room and do this in a
more isolated space take that female
plant take that pollen and just paint
the branches that you want with the
pollen put a Q-tip or the paint brush
right into the pollen and then carefully
apply that pollen to the pistols of the
plant you want to pollinate then Mark
that Branch if you only do a couple of
branches mark it keep an eye on that
Branch then when those seeds are ready
you know that they're right there in
that one those two branches that you
pollinated be very careful because I've
talked about how easy it is to
accidentally pollinate things if you
sneeze if you breathe too heavily if you
bump that jar if you bump the baggie
pollen will go flying around you may
accidentally pollinate things but if you
are careful you should be able to use a
Q-tip a paintbrush something of that
nature and get in there and scoop a
little bit of pollen out of that
container and just apply it perfectly to
the plants or you could take it and you
could just sprinkle it right above the
plants I've seen guys pour it onto a
piece of paper and just blow on it
but when you blow on it that [__] goes
everywhere it's gonna move more than you
expect it takes one or two test runs
maybe to figure out how hard to blow to
get the pollen to move but dump it onto
a little piece of paper and just give it
a
and just let it blow the reason you
don't go straight onto your hand you
guys is because your sweat will destroy
the pawl and that moisture will has the
opportunity the potential to destroy
your pollen so let me make sure that
I've answered most of the question here
uh collect the pollen tap it just bend
the plant over and tap it and collect
that [__] or let the plant get finished
up cut it down when you've got enough
pollen and then start [__] smacking
that plant on flowers or put in a
container collect the pollen that way
get the pollen super dry that is one of
the most important parts here
um use a silicate pack do not use a
Boveda pack dry the pollen then use a
paintbrush or a Q-tip to apply the
pollen to the branches that you want to
pollinate when you have successful
pollination you will see the pistols
kind of curl in the pistols look like
the dandelions the hairs you guys call
them that part is sticking out when you
put pollen on there that part will curl
up and turn brown and get withered that
is a sign of successful pollination pay
attention to the parts you've pollinated
over the next few weeks watch the
development around 4 5 6 six weeks in
some plants go faster than others you
guys I can't tell you exactly how long
it will take four five six weeks in
you'll start seeing the seeds getting
harder around five or six weeks start
pulling one or two out randomly and just
squeezing them and see how hard they are
around week seven or week eight they'll
definitely be ready by then you'll have
a nice batch of seeds the way I harvest
seeds we'll just quickly do this since
we're here I've done a full show on it
but we'll go quickly when I harvest for
seed right before Harvest time I do a
heavy defoliation we don't need all
those leaves in there
also I turn my lights back to 18-6
shortly after pollination to speed up
the time to get the seeds ripe but I'm
getting ahead of myself I chop I heavily
defoliate I chop down the plants I hang
them upside down I let them get
completely dry before I even mess with
these plants they are bone dry if you're
trying to grow weed and smoke this weed
it's going to be dust this is useless so
I let it get bone bone dry then I take
that plant and I put it into a big
sterilite container and I use a glove
and I just pull all of the buds off the
sticks I just yank the sticks right out
of it so the buds land in this container
it sounds like seeds and rocks hitting
the container then I put on rubber
gloves again and I grind all that butt
up with my hands until I've got just a
pile it looks like we're going to roll a
bunch of joints and there's a bunch of
seeds in it and a bunch of joint
material then I will run that through a
seed sorting machine and I do have a
seed sorting machine that makes it very
easy if you've got a lot of seeds I
would recommend investing in that it
will save you a lot of time if not there
are a lot of ways to go about sorting
the seeds but that is how I harvest I
defoliate cut them down let them hang
get them dry as [__] and then once
they're dry as [__] I just do this and
crumble them up until I've got joint
rolling material pull out all the sticks
pull out all the junk then pull out all
the seeds honestly the rest of that
material has been so beat up that it
goes into the compost bin or the bokashi
bucket I do not even use it that may
offend a lot of people but it is garbage
at this point there's so much
chlorophyll and just junk and dust in it
that you don't even want it all right I
think I've covered the best part of my
pollination and collecting pollen uh
recipe my secret here my guide if you've
got any more questions please do send me
an email if anybody out there has any
questions Corrections comments concerns
uh maybe any follow-ups let me know the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy please reach
out I do appreciate the listener
interaction also make sure you support
the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart I
will put a link in the video description
somebody told me recently that the link
I used was not working I do apologize
I'll put an update Link in the
description or just go patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart that
will get you there everything else is on
my website at iregenetics.com make sure
you check out iridirect get those fresh
beans Straight From the Source there is
a link to the Discord there is a link to
the patreon there everything you could
possibly imagine is an
iriegenetics.com ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast you know I'll be back in one
week with fresh new content I want to
give a giant shout out to my good friend
Sonic and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you