[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
769 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to talk about
selecting nutrients for your grow before
we get to that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to OG roach and the devil's
weed let's send a big fist bump and a
thank you shout out to Justice smoking I
want to send a big thank you to know me
by my guacamole let's send a fist month
and a thank you shout out to kojax and
Kess Burton let's send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy ADHD grower let's
send a special thank you to grow man
Stan I want to send a thank you to stash
drop to say X9 let's send a fist bump to
dreadlock farmer then let's wrap it all
up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to ours
kickerson big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast speaking
of supporting the podcast I am seeking
questions for an upcoming episode that's
right I'm going to do an episode where I
eat too many Edibles and I answer
questions that are non-grow related
that's right I don't try to abandon the
grow questions on patreon but I'm going
to do a patreon only episode I'm going
to eat too many Edibles and I want to
answer questions uh mainly kind of about
me about my company anything you want to
ask me that is not grow related this is
a good time to ask that so if you've got
a question now is a good time to join
the patreon send those questions to the
patreon campaign and I will work those
in to the upcoming edible episodes where
I do eat too many Edibles and answer
personal questions is kind of the idea
that I'm going for it could be personal
questions it could be questions about
dreadlocks it could be questions about
shoes you know that I'm into sneakers
there could be questions about music
anything you want to know that is not
cannabis related this is the format for
those questions so please do join the
patreon and send me those questions on
patreon because I'm going through the
patreon to do the episode that is where
I'll get the questions from I look
forward to that I am also looking
forward to my Greenhouse filled with
seeds being harvested here within the
next couple of weeks I was in the
greenhouse today looking around and the
seeds are coming along quite nicely the
seeds are getting hard if you have not
been paying attention I do have a
greenhouse somewhere that I will not
tell you where it is in that Greenhouse
I've done a little bit of breeding we
took a Jack the Ripper mail and put that
Jack the Ripper mail to 10 solid female
plants so there will be 10 Jack the
Ripper crosses some of which you are
familiar some of which will be brand new
uh just to tease you a little bit there
will be a platinum Tangy pollinated by
the Jack the Ripper there might be an LA
Kush and we may be making more blue
berry butcher out there in the outdoor
run can't say too much more I've already
said enough but I am getting excited the
plants are looking good the buds are
swollen the seeds are getting fat
they're getting hard we keep pulling
seeds out every couple of days and
giving them a squeeze they are getting
close within the next two weeks maybe
three weeks if the most of those will
come down it will take me a while to get
those processed packaged and out to you
but I will be sending out test seeds I
will be sending out a lot of new stuff
very soon a lot of new great stuff
coming up 4 20 22 I wanted to brag tell
you how excited I am about that
Greenhouse coming along I cannot wait
you may hear that I got some Greenhouse
dust in the nose I feel like I got some
allergies I'm not sick it's not the vid
again but I do have some if you do hear
it that's just some some outdoor dirt
and dust from being outside too much
today that's all that's from excuse me
for that I'm talking about outdoor grows
I want to give a big shout out to a
friend I'm not going to say his name a
friend of mine got his plants stolen
from his outdoor grow if you've ever
heard me talk about outdoor growing I do
always say plant a few extra you've got
to plant one for the thieves one for the
bugs one for the animals one for the
weather then maybe plant a couple for
yourself and hopefully you will get one
or two of those at the end if you got
your plants your outdoor plants were
stolen this year I do send you love I do
have what is it condolences for you I do
have love and empathy for that so maybe
some sympathy uh be careful where you're
planting your plants you guys don't tell
anybody chances are it's an inside job
and your plants do get stolen or you did
not do enough security work it's usually
the plants right there at the corners
near the edge of the fence those go
first maybe don't plant right there
maybe be more discreet but be prepared
if you're growing Outdoors that [ __ ] is
going to potentially get stolen do you
have a strategy that you're going to
follow if somebody does come to take
your plants it's not up to me to tell
you what to do but keep in mind that you
can grow more plants next year if you
are not in jail so whatever you're going
to do be very careful protecting your
garden but now is the time people are
out stealing plants the buds are getting
big plants look ready the people that
don't know they're not ready are going
to start stealing [ __ ] over the next
couple of few weeks plants will be
getting stolen be ready for that I don't
want you to get your plants taken bro if
your plants got stolen you know who you
are shout out fist Brent broad I wish I
could give you a fat plant to replace
that or something nothing I could do for
you except send you some love and a fist
bump better not better luck next year
all right and the last order of business
that I wanted to ramble about is
something kind of silly just kind of
personal I think I've discovered over
the past couple of weekends that uh
cleaning cloners is probably my least
favorite task when it comes to growing
cannabis I love growing I love
transplanting I love doing all of the
work that comes the defoliation popping
twisting putting up the Nets cleaning
the rooms is even fun doing all the
reset all that work is fun even
packaging seeds is fun I do not like
cleaning cloners I use the easy cloner
clone machines and for some reason just
cleaning those is one of my least
favorite tasks let me know what your
least favorite Garden tasks are send me
an email send me a tweet let me know we
will talk about that on the show here in
the future if you want to tweet me it's
at gfyhpodcast if you want to send an
email it is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com let me know what are your
least favorite Garden tasks maybe we can
find some way to make those more fun
make them better of course it's always
better when you got to grow from your
heart podcast rambling in your ear
enough rambling I did say that I was
going to read a message about selecting
nutrients here in this episode this
message came from our friend shotgun
Yoda on patreon big shout out to shotgun
Yoda the message goes a little bit like
this
how about an episode on how to pick the
correct nutrient line what are the
advantages and disadvantages of each
that is a really good question uh this
could be a really in-depth episode I'm
going to try to cover this kind of kind
of tight but you know how I get we will
get rambly let's get right into it there
are a few things to think about when it
comes to selecting nutrients the most
important ah maybe is availability is it
available can you get it where can you
get it can you get it sustainably is it
a one-time thing or is it readily
available do you have to order it online
is it an Amazon purchase is it a
purchase directly from the company or is
it available at your local grow store
which of those mean the most to you is
it available that's what's going to
matter the most can you get it because
if you pick a line if you research a
line and it's not even available what's
good you can't use it what's it going to
do for you so the most important part is
is that product is that line available
then one of the next things to think
about this may be important for more
people than others but the cost is this
product is this line line cost effective
you're going to have to feed the plants
for nine weeks of flour a few weeks of
veg is it going to be cost effective is
your return on your investment going to
be worth it sometimes some bottles are
super expensive Sometimes some bottles
are really affordable you've got to do
the math think about I'm buying a gallon
I need to use one ounce every time I
water how many waterings do you get per
bottle how many times per week do you
water how much product do you expect out
of that product at the end out of the
end of the Harvest do the math on that
with each bottle then you've also got to
factor in electricity the water that you
use you got to put in your time your
labor all of that stuff you got to pay
for trimmers you got to pay for scissors
factor in all of that stuff but think
about the cost of the nutrients are they
cost effective some Brands out there are
really expensive some Brands out there
are really affordable sometimes you get
what you pay for sometimes you are
paying for advertising colorful bottles
fancy labels expensive advertising
sometimes you're not really paying for
what you're getting so think about that
one when it comes to buying your
Products Research the brand research the
products you were thinking about buying
research the brand that makes those
products then research the other
products that they make and see where
they get their products from see where
they're sourcing their ingredients to
make your products some companies have
great ethics some do not think about if
you want to support companies like
Monsanto or Scots that is up to you you
can vote with your dollars you can spend
your money wherever you would like it's
none of my business but it is something
that you may want to think about you may
want to be aware of so cost is very
important here's something you may not
have thought about how about
sustainability are the products you are
purchasing or thinking about purchasing
causing problems to the world or is that
company doing something to prevent
damage to our Earth and our world we
only get one world we only get one Earth
it's up to us to not destroyed I know
that's my big hippie talk for the day
but are the nutrients and the products
you're buying for your grow are they
sustainable is that going to destroy the
Earth is this a product that we can
continue to buy and use for several
years is this a product is this a brand
that just appeared yesterday and made
disappear tomorrow I prefer to buy a
brand that's been around for a minute
that I know is going to be around so
that if I do fall in love with their
products I can get it forever so that's
another part of sustainability first
we've got environmental sustainability
then we've got company sustainability
are these products going to be around in
a few years if you grow the best herb
you've ever grown and that product's not
available next year you're going to be
frustrated so is it going to be
available the next thing I'm going to
talk about is compatibility are the
nutrients you were thinking about
purchasing compatible with your grow
style maybe you're growing hydroponic
maybe you're growing cocoa maybe you're
growing ebb and flow maybe you're doing
a living soil mix Maybe not maybe you're
doing a soilless mix maybe you're just
growing in old dirt you found in the
backyard are these nutrients compatible
with your grow style also another thing
to think about are these nutrients
compatible with each other that's
something we're going to talk about
later in the episode I prefer if a new
grower is selecting nutrients you pick
one brand and get what you need from
that line I don't don't recommend that
you go get a base from one company a
bloom booster from another a root tonic
from another a phosphorus thing from
another because those companies didn't
talk to each other and you may run the
risk of overlapping nutrients we're
going to talk more about that in the
future I think I've got that written
down the next thing that really matters
is results when you grew with these
nutrients were you satisfied with the
outcome of your product did your bud
look smell taste Burn smoke give you the
buzz that you were hoping for that you
spent all these weeks and all these
nutrients pouring into it did it work
for you a lot of things you're going to
notice from the nutrients are flavor
Aroma and color that's gonna be the
first three things I notice flavor Aroma
and color you can see during the grow if
you're getting good colors you can see
if you're getting big fat buds or little
puny buds you can see that then what
about flavor and Aroma smell those
plants smell those butts do they smell
good one thing I used another company
I'm going to try to avoid bashing
companies here but I used to use a
company when I was brand new uh they
sell you about 30 bottles they mix it up
like a science lab all their bottles
have real fancy packaging the labels are
really cool every label is well thought
out really good advertising you see them
in every magazine I got big fat buds
trust me everything was big and fat and
huge and dense and smoked well but it
all tasted exactly the same I was
growing 12 different strains they all
tasted like strawberry bubble gum
because of the nutrients that I was
using and I'm pretty sure that it was
that one bottle a couple of the bottles
made it all taste like bubble gum but
there's one they're Bloom booster really
made everything taste like this
strawberry bubble gum flavor and why am
I going to grow 12 different strains if
it's all going to taste like strawberry
bubble gum I should have just grown a
whole bunch of one thing and mono
cropped it I didn't get any variation so
does it taste the way that you want
that's something that I noticed so
you're gonna see colors you're going to
see flavor you're gonna get flavors
you're going to get Aromas you're gonna
see Bud size and some nutrients will
grow more Leaf some nutrients will grow
more Bud Mass some nutrients I've
noticed make the plants a little more
robust I'm not going to name any Brands
but some Brands will just give you a lot
of fat at buds but a lot of fat leaves
some Brands will give you big robust
stocks and hardly any buds I just I've
learned this from just growing and
experience with nutrients over time it's
all about what works best for you with
your results also these results will be
very grower specific room specific
strain specific environment specific
everything else will fall into effect
into play here in this uh this that's a
chess board it's a whole chess board
yeah it's 64 squares you got to get all
64 squares right but every one of those
will make a difference in your results
not just the nutrients let me stay
focused here because I am quite dead and
I'm trying to read these notes so we've
got availability can you get these
nutrients you have to have them shipped
to you maybe think about are you getting
powdered or liquid nutrients if you're
getting them shipped do you want to ship
water because liquid nutrients are
probably 70 to 99 water if you choose to
buy powdered nutrients all you're paying
for at that rate is the powdered
nutrients they're not shipping water
across the country they're more cost
effective you do need to use a scale to
weigh those which I don't mind doing
anyway I'm using a scale half the day
anyway use a scale weigh those powder
nutrients and mix them into the water
stir them up super easy so are they
assist are they available are they cost
effective are they sustainable are they
compatible with your grow style your
plants and each other and then most
importantly do you get results that make
you happy that is the very most
important part is the results now let's
go a little bit deeper into this uh do
you want to work with Organics do you
want to work with salts how organic do
you want to go how scientific do you
want to go that is up to you there are
plenty of brands that do offer organic
products and plenty of brands that offer
completely non-organic products it's up
to you how hippie dippy you want to go
how organic you want to go one thing I
always remind people when they say I
have to grow organically this has to be
completely organic I remind them that
cyanide is organic and a little bit of
cyanide will [ __ ] kill you so are you
that hung up on the word organic a lot
of times it is a buzzword uh it makes
things more expensive and it's
unnecessary a lot of the times in my
opinion if you want to be organic if you
think that organic is the way to go I am
not here to argue that I am here to help
you select what is best for you I'm
trying to stay unbiased I'm trying to
give you information and educate without
pitching any brands or any products
because that's that bugs me when shows
do that like I recommend you buy this
and then they do a commercial for it
right at the end of the show and you're
like well that's why you recommended it
because they paid you money like that
sucks all right anyway uh do you want to
go Organics do you want to go salt do
you want to be hippie dippy if you're
running Organics and you add synthetic
[ __ ] into your mix you are no longer
organic you can't say organic at all you
have not yet non-organic is what that is
any of the words that you made up to be
a combo of those is not accurate organic
means organic once you put [ __ ] that's
not organic in it you are now
non-organic that's all that is so quit
making up new words for that I disagree
you can call it whatever you want but
it's not organic anymore all right how
about cost effective can you afford it
we've already talked a little bit about
that liquid or dry we don't want to ship
water across the country maybe some of
you do maybe you want a lot of bottles
maybe you want a few bottles there are
some companies out there that will sell
you 30 bottles there's one company that
sells you three bottles I've seen great
results from both Brands it's kind of
all about what you are into how much do
you want to mix how much uh how much OCD
do you have want to have over this how
much control do you really want over the
feet of your plants the three bottles
generally work as like you got a base
and you got something a microbe and then
you got a bloom booster and they just
tell you feed this much of each one
start with your base and then you start
you add microbes and then cut out the
microbes add Bloom booster that will
work your plants will be great there are
other companies that want you to feed
these two bottles on week one this
bottle and this bottle on week two these
four bottles on week three these seven
bottles on week four these five bottles
on week five these nine bottles plus
these two powders on week six there's
companies that want you all kinds of
[ __ ] it is up to you what you want to
choose find a company like said that you
trust you enjoy their ethics a lot of
the time before I ever grew weed I was
reading magazines I was looking at the
internet I don't even think there was
the internet when I was dreaming about
growing about growing dreaming about
growing weed I was looking at magazines
and I would see Brands and they would be
advertising and some of those Brands
would speak to me and some of them would
not you're probably already drawn to a
brand there's already probably a logo a
company somebody said something you
heard something that has got your
attention now just think about that
brand think about the ethics of that
company where do they spend their money
how many bottles do you want you've
already got an idea so do you want to go
a bunch of bottles do you want to go
just a few bottles this may really help
with your decision how much OCD and
control do you really need all right
let's move forward from that because I
rambled on with that one
um sources and science where are these
companies learning to make the nutrients
who are the formulators and where are
they getting their ingredients are they
using high quality ingredients or are
they using bottom shelf leftover
ingredients find out where these
companies are sourcing the ingredients
that they are selling you now here is
something I started rambling about
earlier and I cut myself off because I
wanted to get to it sort of here at the
end closer to the end of this rant
it is okay to mix and match nutrients by
that I mean you can use and I'm just
going to say names randomly here don't I
said I was going to avoid names but you
can use a Botanicare base and then you
can use New Millennium additives or you
could use a Advanced Nutrients base and
Botanical additives or you could do that
if you are careful to not overlap any of
the elements within those bottles
carefully read what you were feeding we
need nitrogen phosphorus potassium
aluminum sulfur there are a lot of
things I can just go on listing we need
a lot of these things in our plants but
company a Advanced Nutrients did not
talk to Botanica and say hey we're going
to put this in the base so you don't
have to put it in the bloom booster you
don't have to put that in the other one
we don't know that this company didn't
add [ __ ] to that that's already in this
bottle I'm sure that uh company a if you
buy all of their lineup you're not going
to overlap things because they know that
this product has nitrogen this bottle
has phosphorus this bottle has potassium
this bottle has all the other [ __ ] we
need if you go adding a bottle from
another a company they didn't talk to
each other you might be doubling up on
nitrogen you might double up on
phosphorus or potassium or anything else
and then you do risk the chance the
opportunity of burning your plants I'm
going to get off on a side tangent here
a lot of people often ask me about ppms
and how much to feed the plants at what
PPM level I can't give you a PPM number
because I don't know how many ppms of
each nutrient you are using in that mix
and it is very plant specific when you
get to the high PPM high performance
plant levels you could feed the plants a
thousand ppms and they'll Thrive you
could also feed them 2500 ppms and they
will Thrive if you give them the correct
nutrients if I gave them 2500 ppms of
phosphorus they will cook if I give them
2500 ppms of nitrogen they will cook
it's got to be a balanced diet of the
proper [ __ ] then you can go real high if
you know what you were doing and you
have not overlapped anything too
critically all right I did get off on a
side 10 ship there what I was headed for
is I would recommend instead of mixing
and matching things while you were new
while you were learning your nutrients
while you were determining what works
for you is I would pick a line I would
just pick whatever line you've been
studying just choose one that is going
to work for you it's available it's cost
effective it's sustainable uh you've
it's been getting your attention and uh
we don't know the results yet your
friends have had good results that's
probably a good way to measure that so
pick that line then I would get the base
the microbe the bloom booster the Cal
Mag if you need it and then see what
else they offer because they all offer a
couple of other different bottles I
would get as much of that line as you
feel necessary or as fits your budget
then I would water I would feed that
entire crop that entire run with that
line of nutrients the only way to do a
solid test is to go from beginning to
end with that product if you go adding
in other [ __ ] we don't know what worked
because that is adding anomalies and
then [ __ ] can it's hard to determine
what did what so feed it with that one
line see what you like did it taste good
did it give you enough weight did it
smoke well was it potent if not either
research the next line you need or find
something to add to what is missing from
the line that you have chosen I do use a
specific line but then to that I also
add another Brand's Cal Mag and I had a
couple of Bloom boosters from another
company and then I had another trichome
and resin producer from a totally
different company so I'm mixing probably
four or five maybe five or six different
companies feeds in over the course of
flowering but that is because I have
started with one base and I learned them
and I grew with that one base a lot and
I said well if I give it too much of
this product early I get too much Leaf
if I cut this out it reduces my leaf I
get bigger fatter Buds and then I
realized these buds could probably be a
little fatter so I added a bloom booster
and then I realized oh I missed that one
product that I was using before that
would go well in here so I added that
and it worked really well I've just done
it by starting by running the original
base several times documenting my
results seeing what I desired and then
adding one more product every run and
documenting that and comparing it to
previous runs is it better than I get
get more weight more potency more flavor
is it better or did it was it cost
effective did I buy another bottle feed
it and not get [ __ ] out of it or did I
see results a lot of the times I'll see
results a lot of the times I'll just
stop using a product all together don't
be afraid to switch up your nutrient a
little bit per plant these nutrients
will be plant specific like I said
earlier this will be plant specific room
grower phenotype specific this will be
very specific feeding to get dialed in
perfectly for each plant don't be afraid
to adjust if you've got two totally
different plants in the room don't be
afraid to adjust the feed a little bit
for each plant because the plants do
want different things you've got to
develop that relationship with the plant
so you've got to learn the plant and the
nutrients and if you keep switching
things up it is hard to dial that in so
feed that one plant that same nutrients
for at least two or three runs and see
how they react together then start
making Minor Adjustments each run after
that maybe run six plants of the same
strain and feed three one thing feed
three the other and feed three the other
just Minor Adjustments maybe a little
more base nutrients maybe a little more
Bloom booster you know what you're
looking for that is a great way to
experiment but I do recommend locking in
with one brand to start getting as many
of their products as you can either
afford or find necessary I like to buy
the whole damn lineup if I'm going to do
it why leave anything out just get them
all get it going feed them see what
happens do it again and then make
adjustments on that third run if I want
to add something take something out
that's when I will make the adjustments
all right the last two notes that I have
on my sheet are run side by sides if you
think that one nutrient is doing really
good and you think another one is doing
really good what's to stop you from
growing if you got a six plant count do
three plant to one and three plants of
another side by side in the same room
and keep it scientific that way you can
figure out which lineup really does work
best for you the last note that I've got
is some things that work for me may not
work for you some things that work for
you may not work for me our Grow rooms
are different our plants are different
our goals our Styles our approaches are
all very different even if they're very
similar they are still very very
different so what works for me may not
work for you what works for your best
friend may not work for your worst
friend will work for your girlfriend may
not work for you so be open be flexible
and pay attention to the plants because
overall the plants are the boss all
right ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers Growers
clone Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to episode
769 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy send me that constructive criticism
that positive feedback don't tell me
about how crappy my voice sounds in this
episode because I can already hear it
through the headphones and I do
apologize make sure you check out the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart everything
else you need is on my website at
iregenetics.com make sure you check it
out tap in is what I think all the cool
kids say you'll find a link to the
Discord you'll find a link to iridirect
so you can get the seeds you'll find a
link to merchandise everything you need
at
irydirect.com that is all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
I'm gonna give a giant shout out to my
friend black thumb grower and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
foreign