[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
770 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to focus on a
couple of patreon questions before I get
to that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to one of my favorite
photographers my friend levity loveday
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shot it's a crafted flower and quasi
let's send a big fist bump to the
hardest working man in cannabis my
friend James Brown listen to Big thank
you shout out to froggle Rockin G7 let's
send a fist bump and a high five to tert
burglar and do9419 honest send a special
thank you shout out to my friend Danny
Potts let's send a big thank you shout
out to Green Goblin grows and trolling
let's send a big thank you to Green
County grower then I want to wrap it all
up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to operation
High Vibes big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast if you
are watching on the YouTube video which
I do highly encourage you may have
noticed I'm rocking one of the brand new
irie genetics logo t-shirts that's right
I put the cross logo the red Golden
Green Cross logo on a black T-shirt in
my opinion it looks super sharp I think
these colors pop quite well on the black
T-shirt you can get your on my website
there is a link in the show notes and in
the video description or simply search
ire genetics go to the ire genetics
website click on the merge tab that will
get you to the merch store you can get
your fresh new ire genetics t-shirts
also I will be taking pre-orders for
hoodies with the same logo very soon
probably by the time this episode comes
out there will be pre-orders available
on the same website to get your hoodies
for the winter all right let's not waste
too much time let's jump into the main
topic of today's podcast at the top of
the show I did say that I was going to
focus on patreon questions recently I
posted to patreon that I was going to
eat too many Edibles and do a patreon
only episode where I answered a non-grow
questions maybe grow questions about
myself about my personal life maybe the
music I'm into maybe some of my past or
my history I opened it up so that the
patrons can ask any questions they felt
comfortable asking something I don't
want to do is do a patreon episode where
I answer a bunch of great grow questions
questions and leave people out I want
that knowledge free and available to
everybody so when I do patreon bonus
content it is going to be uh non-grow
related content kind of fun content kind
of ways to just hang out with the crowd
and give them extra content that doesn't
exclude Growers I think you get my point
so I did ask for questions that were not
grow related and I did say I was going
to eat a bunch of Edibles allegedly
possibly I may have eaten those Edibles
before this podcast we're gonna do this
normal show see how long it takes those
to kick in then we will take a break
then of course we will shift to the
patreon only format so let's jump into
this first question here while things
start doing their magic this one goes a
little bit maybe a lot like this it says
yo Ross to Jeff and it go it comes from
my friend gruesome green on patreon big
up to gruesome green on patreon it says
Ross the Jeff would you ever consider
being a sponsor for a band and that is a
really good question also really good
ironic timing uh Saturday night I'm
recording on what's the date right now
do we have to be specific I'm recording
on September 28th uh Saturday night I
got to go see the lovely Natalie rise
perform at a club here in my hometown
she played at Brews Ale House in Pueblo
Colorado I got to take the lovely Miss
irie with me you also known her as dread
Vibes you also know her as Zara that is
Miss irie I took her with me we got to
go see Natalie rise minori opened the
show it was a wonderful an amazing
concert Natalie rice did a great job but
Nori did a great job I love the Rhythm
Section and Natalie rise's band but my
point is what you asked about is sponsor
the band ironically we worked out a
sponsorship deal with that band so the
next leg of the Natalie rise tour will
be brought to you by irie genetics I
can't talk too much about what that does
include but I am sponsoring that band
and they are not the first reggae band
which I have sponsored I have
contributed funding to tours and uh
recording mixing and mastering for other
reggae bands that I'm not sure if they
want me to say who they are and are or
not I can't say that I've done some work
with jamiri Morgan and I can maybe hint
and lead on that there may be a strain
being put together for jamery Morgan
with his flavor profile and some things
that he selected maybe doing some stuff
for our friend jamiri which may be
released here in the near future also
allegedly may be working on something
with Miss Natalie rice so the question
is would I consider being a sponsor for
a band Yes I love sponsoring bands when
I was younger and we're going to talk
about this more in these episodes these
personal roster Jeff episodes when I was
younger my original dream was to be a
rock star I'm a drummer I got drums for
my 14th birthday I've been playing
non-stop since then I never give it a
rest I never quit thinking about poly
rhythms and paradiddles and 12 16-0
triplets in 12-8 time and just weird
[ __ ] I'm always thinking about the drums
you guys so when I was younger my dream
was to travel and be a musician I got to
do it on a small level we didn't have I
wasn't successful I mean I had fun if
success is traveling around and having
fun with your friends and just partying
real hard we did that I didn't really go
anywhere with the opportunity that I had
because I was young and I kind of kind
of squandered that but my dream was to
play music if I would have had somebody
like myself to say hey here's uh funding
here's gas money for the next part of
the tour here's money for drum hats
guitar strings and most importantly food
because a lot of times on the road we
were hungry bro bands would promise you
money uh gas money gig money hotel room
and you would get there and you'd have
to sleep in the van and eat peanut
butter and jelly sandwiches it was worth
it I wouldn't change any of it but
um Ben that did suck if I would have had
somebody back in the day to fund my tour
I may have been more successful in the
music industry so that's why I do it I
love the music that the artists that I
promote and endorse and support and
sponsor I love their music I love their
Vibe I love what they're about so it
feels good doing that and I get to go
see my favorite reggae bands because I
helped contribute to their funding then
a lot of other people get to see them as
well get treated like a rock star when
you go it's a good time all right that's
the first part of that question I am
rambling maybe the uh the chocolates are
kicking in then there's a part B of this
question it says favorite place to visit
or vacation in Colorado
um we have four seasons here in Colorado
we get spring summer fall and winter
very noticeably different climates uh
environments here plus we got a lot of
different types of environment here
we've got the desert we've got the
foresty stuff we've got mountainy stuff
of course we got ski season we got like
Lake season and [ __ ] like that so
there's a lot of different things to do
and places to go here in Colorado
picking a favorite place to visit and
vacation would be very very hard to do
just one if you're going to come to my
neck of the woods Southern Colorado and
want me to show you around I'm taking
you to Bishop Castle I'm taking you like
Lake Isabel I'm showing you outside
stuff and real Majestic outdoor [ __ ] if
we're in Denver and it's nice out we're
going to go toward the downtown area
especially if it's getting like kind of
toward Christmas and it's not snowing
downtown Denver is [ __ ] beautiful it
looks great uh if it's ski season time
we may go up to a little ski Town
whichever we're closest to they're all
really adorable there's a lot of great
ski towns just kind of depends on what
the vibe is what you're looking for
we've got so much great [ __ ] here to
offer and it's so seasonal that you kind
of have to take advantage of the season
and do what's available at this time of
year so depends on when you're coming
where you're trying to go and what the
vibe is are you taking a lady out are
you showing the Bros night out on the
town you trying to escape on your own
that really makes a huge difference here
I'm going to say Bishop Castle is a
great place to take people meow wolf of
course is an amazing place to take
people I love Comedy Works I'm a huge
comedy nerd if you're into music you got
to go see a concert at Red Rocks but
that's all the cliche [ __ ] then once we
do all that then we'll go sneak off to
all the fun stuff that nobody knows
about that only the Colorado folks know
about I will take you there when you get
here but I'm not going to tell everybody
about it on a podcast because I don't
want to blow up all the spots and
overcrowd it and make it not as cool
anymore so
um we're gonna say meow wolf Red Rocks
Bishop Castle Comedy Works and then
um all the good restaurants I love to
just go eat good food in Denver go walk
around in Boulder that whole area is
beautiful so um yeah Lions is beautiful
Manitou Springs is beautiful a lot of
great [ __ ] I am rambling there's a lot
more to get to I couldn't pick one
favorite place to visit in Colorado
that's really hard this place is
gorgeous all right we're gonna keep
moving because I can get quite rambly I
already feel the chocolate kicking in
this next message came from our friends
soil 2 bowls
and it says I would like to know more
about your music past what led you to
the drums did playing drums and music
playing drums and music professionally
change how playing music made you feel
they wrapped the message up with gave my
mom a hug for you she said you seem nice
big shout out to Mom thanks you thank
you for hugging her for me let me slow
down and Catch My Breath we will talk
about this question you want to know
more about my musical past what led me
to the drums
I'm not sure exactly what led me to the
drums there's something when I would
listen when I grew up when I was younger
I have some uncles I often talk about
rest in peace Bros I love you and my one
uncle Troy is still alive two of my
uncles are gone uh they kind of were my
male role models male influences they
listen to a lot of rock music a lot of
classic rock a lot of metal uh Metallica
was played quite often amongst those
three Metallica was probably the main
commonality in those three uncles their
favorites would have been Metallica
together collectively
just hearing that music I was always
just bobbing my head banging my head to
the drums and then when I'd go to
concerts I'd just catch myself staring
at the drummer and then I fell in love
with the band of Metallica I mentioned
Metallica yes when I was younger I was a
huge Metallica fan uh so maybe my uncles
live music and just feeling the drums
and noticing that everybody just without
the drums you can't Bob your head right
like you could think you can but there
needs to be some drums to Bob your head
or dance properly so that's part of why
I filmed the drums fell in love with the
drums is probably Metallica I remember
my uncle had a Chevy El Camino if you
know what that is big up if you don't
you're better off my uncle had a Chevy
El Camino and he took me to a concert
and my two uncles smoked a joint in the
front of that El Camino and they played
The Black Album by Metallica that smoke
wafted into the back and I caught a nice
buzz and I heard the Black album on the
way to that concert by the time I got to
the concert I was convinced I was going
to be a [ __ ] drummer that was so
that's a big part of it right there I
did playing drums Musical and music
professionally changed how playing music
made you feel yes
um there's something about knowing the
dirty uh filthy side of the music
industry that makes you just kind of not
want to jump into it it's like jumping
into the pool but then finding out
there's [ __ ] alligators in there
you're like I want out of this [ __ ] it
was cool until I knew that was all
filled with [ __ ] alligators and
sharks
um it's a lot of fun but you have to be
the right minded person you have to have
the right drive you have to have uh just
you have to be a solid strong person I'm
a strong person and I developed
Addictions on the road I definitely I
was an alcoholic and I wasn't a specific
drug addict I was a whatever the [ __ ]
you got tonight drug addict let's do it
all I didn't care there's some drugs I
wouldn't do don't get me wrong but like
we're doing party drugs and [ __ ]
music drugs and I would do all of them
if you had them tonight that was what we
were doing tonight was all of whatever
you brought to the party so being on the
road uh it changed me a lot because
there were addictions there were
Temptations but also the music industry
is kind of Grody like you're lied to a a
lot you're manipulated a lot until
you're signed you're struggling you're
just struggling to get signed or make it
or have some support once you get
support and you get signed then you're
their [ __ ] you're working just you're
trying to find someone to work for and
then once you get someone to work for
you're just working for them they give
you money but every couple of weeks they
want to progress report like how many
shows have you played how many shirts
have you sold how's the recording going
have you booked the next tour is every
member of the band healthy how's your
drug habit going how's the van running
and it's that's just normal
responsibilities but also we're in a
band trying to write music play music
and enjoy this without so all of the
logistics playing a club playing at a
club all night long or three nights in a
row Friday Saturday Sunday or Thursday
Friday Saturday and then going to
collect the money from the club owner
and they're a total dick about the deal
that they wrote you and you've got it in
text message or email or between another
promoter and the promoter says the club
should pay you the club says the
promoter is supposed to pay you you just
played three nights in a town you don't
know where the [ __ ] you are you don't
have any friends there you don't have
any backup and the club just stiffed you
that kind of [ __ ] puts like a salty
flavor in your mouth so once you get
that sort of stuff when you're it sucks
the passion out of it when you thought
you were gonna have a hotel room at
dinner and gas money and you don't it
starts to piss you off and the music
isn't as good and then the four guys in
the van you're not as close anymore
because you're hungry and you're pissed
off and now when he farted in the van
before it used to be funny but now that
I'm hungry and pissed off when he farted
in the van I want to punch him in the
[ __ ] mouth and it just goes that way
and then it builds up and it kind of
sucks the passion out of it honestly for
me you could tell that I'm getting some
weird emotions out of it already I'm
talking about punching somebody in the
mouth just hypothetically you guys ain't
gonna hit nobody never did but being in
the van and being broke and hungry it
changes your mindset you're like do I
really want to do this I love the music
but like I could just go get a job and
it wouldn't be as bad as this is today
and that's only sometimes then there's
the one hour a night when you're on
stage and everybody's putting lights on
you and taking pictures of you and
screaming your name and singing your
lyrics that's [ __ ] cool but the work
that goes along with that you're either
working to get hired or you're hired and
you're somebody's [ __ ] once you you're
hired and signed then you're working for
a record company or a promoter and they
want a lot you're their [ __ ] and it's a
job at that point whatever your band is
went from like uh patreon the rock band
to patreon INC now you got to get
insurance licensing taxes it gets way
different then I got a job at Guitar
Center because with all my musical
knowledge and abilities I was like I
could definitely work at Guitar Center
dude I've been working at Guitar Center
for an eight hour shift and when you get
in the car most people when you get in
the car after work you crank up some
music and drive fast right I would
[ __ ] turn down the music I didn't
want to hear anything after working at
Guitar Center all day you would I could
hear the guitar Department playing Enter
Sandman AC DC [ __ ] back in black or
Welcome to the Jungle or uh walk by
Pantera all day long it'd be the same
five songs all freaking day long
um [ __ ] what's one the Crazy Train
you hear Crazy Train all the [ __ ]
time in Guitar Center or just some basic
blues solo from everybody in there they
all think that they're coolest they
never played it before uh you're the
third person today to come into Guitar
Center and play that lick I promise you
but uh bet between the music industry
and guitar center learning about the
music business and then learning about
the music equipment industry how they're
just kind of some they make you think
you're buying one thing and you're
really not the things that the artists
have you can't really buy that unless
you get it custom made and [ __ ] but that
I felt bamboozled by both the music
industry and the gear industry so yeah
it did make me a little bit bitter let's
see there is more uh change how you make
music feel now if I could play in a band
now with just like a bunch of old guys
around here local I'm not saying oh guys
I'm [ __ ] 40 something years old if I
could get a bunch of 40 or 50 year old
guys that just wanted to play for fun
and there were no contracts no alcohol
no drugs and none of that [ __ ] involved
it would be a lot of fun just to just
say hey learn these 10 tracks and we'll
go play them in the garage tomorrow so
that all of our wives can hang out and
watch us play like rock stars that would
be fun that's where it would be fun for
me but like being on the road and all
that [ __ ] the spotlight and [ __ ] with
music doesn't sound fun anymore so yeah
it did change how I feel about it our
friend wrapped this message up with gave
my mom a hug that is super cool thank
you bro
um tell Mama that you got your message
on the podcast all right I'm gonna keep
going this minute next message came from
our friend Uncle GG it says what's your
favorite song to play while in the
garden or while gardening in general
um
think the Edibles I ate are kicking in
because as I was reading that the words
got smaller and the lights got brighter
so something's happening over here
um what was the question I don't even
remember uh favorite song to play while
in the garden or while gardening in
general that's a very good question I
know I have vague answers for all of
these questions I'm going to say that
depends on a lot of things
um what is the mood that I'm already in
when I walk into the garden is that mood
the mood I need to be in or do I need to
shift my mood so maybe I just went to
lunch and like I came back to hyper and
I can't focus or something maybe I'll
put on like a Joe Rogan podcast just to
slow down my brain and just kind of get
me into what Rogan's saying and then
I'll slow down a little bit or maybe the
opposite maybe I smoke too many [ __ ]
dabs on my lunch break and I'm [ __ ]
goofy right duh can't figure it out
that's when I'll go in and put on some
[ __ ] like really fast fish like punch
you in the eye or something by fish tube
uh maybe sand or first tube or Sigma
Oasis or something [ __ ] say it to me
Santos put some [ __ ] like that on and
that'll give me some energy and get me
moved up but it all just depends on the
needed shift the needed change or the
needed Vibe if there's a lot of people
in the grow uh we'll just put on some
classic rock and turn it down kind of
low one thing that I like to do in a
commercial grow that really encourages
people to get there first is uh if you
were first in the commercial grow that I
manage if you're the first employee
there you get to pick the music for the
first quarter of the day so that means
from eight o'clock until 10 o'clock the
music is your choice we got guys that
listen to Country we got guys that
listen to death metal there's a guy that
listens to this weird math metal uh the
same Rhythm doesn't happen more than
twice and it's all in like really odd
[ __ ] time signatures but that's what
the dude likes if he's there first bro
we're listening to math metal for two
hours I got a guy that listens to Crazy
Rap we got a guy that listens to old
school hip-hop you never know what you
might get but the first one to get there
gets to put on the [ __ ] music
um so it does it mainly if it's up to me
and my personal grow it depends on the
mental state that I need to be in if I
need to if I'm like sweeping floors and
just doing like stuff where I'm not
paying super super attention I might
have some faster loud or funkier music
on it's going to be
um most likely some fish you never know
could be some Reggae it could be some
old school Grateful Dead it could be mo
I like to listen to a lot of Mo in the
garden that gives you a lot of energy
but like I said if it's something where
I if I'm cutting clones and I need to
slow down and like pay attention or
something then I may put on like a
slower podcast that just like kind of or
maybe even some slower older Grateful
Dead just to get my brain in that slower
Pace instead of zipping through the job
I want to go a little bit more patiently
have a little bit more Focus get the job
done a little bit more uh what's the
word I'm looking for mindfulness I want
to be more aware be there be here now
that's the thing I'm going for sometimes
but also when you're just doing that
labor work I want to check the [ __ ] out
so then you put on crazy music and jam
out all right Uncle Gigi I do thank you
for the great question keep the good
patreon questions going I've got another
one right here in front of me I feel
those uh them chocolates is kicking in
you guys my eyes are getting super warm
this one this this one see I can't even
talk anymore I said this one this
message this next one came from my
friend uh he calls himself all mixed up
we also call them 311 and the live feeds
in in the chats it says where's the
place you would like to visit that is a
really good question
um of course I want to go to Jamaica
just kick it on island of Jamaica then I
want to disappear into the hills of
Jamaica got to spend a day in Kingston
Jamaica let's go all over all over
Jamaica have I said Jamaica enough then
randomly I would love to visit Germany
there's a lot of cool [ __ ] in Germany
looks like a lot of cool castles a lot
of cool scenery a lot of great [ __ ] uh
then all over that Amsterdam area all of
that part of Europe I just want to go
hit all that start in Europe maybe and
just take a bus every day to whatever
you could get to or a train all that
area of Europe looks very interesting to
me gotta hit Italy because I want to try
some [ __ ] good Italian food
um where else would I like to go I wrote
down Sweden uh Miss irie or dread Vibes
or Zara as you know her is originally
from Sweden she's only been here in the
states for about 10 years I would love
to go to Sweden and see uh the things
that she tells me about she tells me
about her childhood and her life before
she came to the states and she tells me
how different it is there and like just
subtle differences and major differences
and a lot of things I would like to go
experience that smell the air see the
the mountain in the city and all the
stuff that she talks about go see
Stockholm because she tells me a lot
about that that would be a fun time just
another way to just I've never thought
of going to Sweden until I got with her
and it sounds like a lot of fun and it's
really random so that'd be super cool
um then a random place that I wrote down
which is really attainable it's just all
about timing and I've never bothered to
do this is the DW Factory in Oxnard
California
um I am a drummer I've played the drums
I've said this on the show maybe today
since I was about 14 years old I really
enjoy DW collector series drums that's
something I'm fond of they are made in a
factory in Oxnard California
occasionally they do DW day and you get
to go do tours for some reason I feel
giddy inside when I think about going to
do a DW tour it sounds great you get to
watch them simply make drum sets I know
it sounds crazy you could watch How It's
Made right but I want to smell the
different kinds of wood I want to hear
the machines I want to be in there I'm
fond of the guy that owns the company
his name's John good I want to shake
John Good's hand he's known as the Wood
Whisperer I want to talk to him about
wood I know that sounds crazy but I'm a
tone wood nerd if you know what tone
wood Maples and different types of wood
and Flame Maple and you could use all
kinds of wood for drums now but uh Sitka
Spruce and [ __ ] dude I'm in love with
that stuff so I'd love to I'm obviously
the [ __ ] Edibles are working I'm
talking about wood at the DW Factory I
would really love to go tour the DW
Factory in Oxnard California they quit
doing the tours uh because of the
pandemic but they've opened up again
it's on a very limited basis one day
when I'm in Southern California and the
wife's got some stuff to do and I'm
freed up that's what I'm gonna go do I'm
gonna go see the DW tour I don't need to
punish her and take her with me I want
to keep her I love it because you'll go
see DW drums you'll meet John good and
then you never know which of your
favorite drummers could pop in every day
they just show random people like look
who popped into the DW offices today and
it could be your favorite drummer
anybody from like Eric Moore to Thomas
Lang to Peter Erskine all kinds of great
people are DW endorses so you never know
who could pop in you never know I could
get a free Drum Lesson throw some
paradiddles with one of my favorite
drummers never know I am high as giraffe
[ __ ] and I am rambling about the DW
factory tour now that is great all right
so I think my favorite places I would
choose to go would be uh Jamaica Germany
I think that Germany trip I want to
alter it a little bit we're going to
start by Landing in Amsterdam and then
that'll be the home base and then of
course we'll hit coffee shops and then
just take day trips all to all the
places all around there uh gotta visit
Sweden because that's where the queen is
from and then that DW Factory in Oxnard
California of course is on the list just
for shits and giggles all right ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls it feels
like the chocolates that I ate before
this show are starting to do their thing
so it's time for me to wrap up this
YouTube portion of the podcast I'm going
to continue this show in just a few
minutes on patreon I'm going to take a
little bit of a break uh get a drink in
myself uh reorganize my notes Here get
some fresh air then I will be back to do
a patreon only podcast if you want to
check out the uh the Edibles version of
this podcast part two of this where I
talk a lot more about the chocolates
that I ate please do check out
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart of course there is a link in the
show notes and in the video description
the lights are getting brighter the [ __ ]
is starting to work ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
chuggers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
770 of the growth from your heart
podcast if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns I would
love to hear from you of course the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com make sure you support the
patreon I've said that a lot of times
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart everything else is on the website
at
iregenetics.com words are getting hard
my mouth is getting dry it is time to
wrap up this show for a moment take a
break slap myself in the cheek a couple
of times get my [ __ ] together and I'll
be back for that patreon show I'll be
back in a couple of days with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my friend B Bala and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]