[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
771 of the girl from your heart podcast
I've got a fun show lined up for us
before we get to the main topic let's do
a few shout outs to a few of those great
folks who continue to support the show
on patreon let's kick it off with the
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to a new supporter our
friend Kyle Hines let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to another new
supporter our friend Simeon I want to
send a thank you shout out to one of my
favorite photographers my buddy root 305
let's send a thank you shout out to
Elders Garden I also want to send a
thank you shout out to Anvil Gardens
listen to Big welcome back thank you
shout out to my friend Thor's trike
Factory on send a special thank you
shout out to my buddy trollin let's send
a fist bump and a thank you shout out to
curbside Gardens I want to send a thank
you shout out to a Colorado local my
buddy fish let's send a big thank you
shout out to Yee [ __ ] ha I want
to send a thank you shout out to another
great photographer my buddy Mobius I
want to send a thank you shout out to
rosin man then let's wrap it all up with
a big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy up north my
friend B Bala big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need to support the show will be right
there on the screen and you know I do
include a link in the show notes and in
the video description to make it nice
and easy for everybody to support the
podcast speaking of patreon I did put
out a patreon only bonus episode I ate
too many Edibles and I answered a few
fun questions I want to thank everybody
on patreon for the great response to
that episode code I will do more like
that I would like to do one a month but
I can't promise that at this time if my
production schedule and if YouTube
cooperates I will do my best to give you
at least one of those patreon bonus
episodes every month that was a good
time to record I can't promise you that
it will eat that many Edibles every time
on the show we will do something fun to
keep it entertaining so big up thank you
guys for the great response to the
patreon bonus episode if you haven't
seen it go check it out at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart I
also want to send a big thank you shout
out to everybody who has grabbed an irie
genetics t-shirt off of the merch store
also a big shout out to everybody who
has pre-ordered a hoodie that's right on
the merch store we are offering a
pre-sale for the irie genetics logo
hoodies it is a very comfortable black
hoodie with the irie Cross logo on the
front if you go to my website
irygenetics.com there's a link to the
merch store when you click on there that
will take you to the hoodies you can
pre-order them they will ship the first
of next month I am currently accepting
pre-order orders I'm going to accept
those pre-orders until about halfway
through the month then I will place the
order for the hoodies the company I work
with takes about two weeks to produce
the hoodies they will print them they
will get them shipped to me then I will
get them out to you as soon as possible
probably the day that they arrive on my
porch or the next day I will get them
right back out to the people who have
pre-ordered those hoodies so without any
more rambling please do go check out
iregenetics.com click on the merge tab
pre-order a hoodie grab a shirt that is
in stock now I look forward to filling
your order what else do I want to talk
about I got to harvest part of the
greenhouse if you've been following
along you know that I've been breeding
in a greenhouse this year that's right
we've got a greenhouse we do not talk
about the location nobody knows a lot
about it try to keep it secretive
because that's just [ __ ] that I've
learned along the way anyway I'm ready
to tell you about it now because it has
been harvested the plants are down they
are in bins they are drying they're
secure so now that those plants have
been harvested they're in a secure place
I do feel much more comfortable talking
about them let's talk talk a little bit
about what we bred this summer I did use
a Jack the Ripper mail I'm sure you've
if you've been following along you know
that I do have a Jack the Ripper mail
that I really enjoy the way that he
works I'm very fond of the outcome that
comes from that Jack the Ripper male he
made the blueberry butcher uh he made
the convergence he made the Jack the
Ripper f2s he's made a lot of great
things he made the dog Ripper uh there's
a lot of great stuff coming from him so
I took that Jack the Ripper mail and I
put him outside and I pollinated 10
females in Colorado in a grow space here
you were allowed up to 12 plants in most
areas if you have six of your
recreational plants six medical plants
that's your limit we put 12 plants
outdoors I put two clones of the Jack
the Ripper mail out there the same male
just two copies of him to make sure to
get plenty of pollen then we put 10
female plants out there we pollinated
all 10 of them very thoroughly
um let's talk a little bit about the
plants that were out there I've got to
leave some to the imagination I did make
more blueberry butcher seeds out there
so there will be more blueberry butcher
seeds coming very soon those were made
in the greenhouse this year I did cross
the uh the Congo the Roberts Creek Congo
the vision maker Congo has been
pollinated by the Jack the Ripper that
should make some uh extremely potent
really sativa dominant uh head Buzz uh
kind of paranoia panic attack euphoric
talk too much kind of weed that's really
what I expect from that the Congo did
not like being outdoors or in the
greenhouse in Colorado it did not react
as well as it does indoors indoors that
plant gets taller than everybody super
quickly it's a monstrous plant when I
put it Outdoors it kind of stalled out
it was like nah I don't think I'm gonna
grow like I normally do which was
disappointing but we still got plenty of
seeds from that one there are a lot of
seeds to play with a lot of seeds to
sift through you guys will have fun with
that also I pollinated once again I made
more of the Platinum tanji 2 Jack the
Ripper I made that a little bit ago we
made a very small plant to play with ran
a few testers we saw great success with
that so I did make a whole batch of
platinum Tangy 2 Jack the Ripper I also
had a Golden Goat pollinated by Jack the
Ripper and that Golden Goat produced a
lot of seeds that Golden Goat plant did
amazingly well Outdoors the Platinum
Tangy and the Golden Goat both did very
very well outdoors I made more Jack the
Ripper F2 seeds I'm not sure how much
else I want to tell you about I
pollinated the p91 with Jack the Ripper
um that's all we're going to talk about
for now but I made a bunch of great
stuff with the Jack the Ripper Outdoors
the plants are cut down it takes about
depending on the environment the room
and honestly how often I get to mess
with me it it takes about 10 to 14 days
for those plants to dry I let them dry
really really dry
once they're super bone dry and crispy
I'll remove all the stems and then I'll
start crushing it up with my hands and
gloves and just crunching it up into a
basically a fine dust it looks like
you're just going to roll a big old
fatty or a bunch of blunts I've got an
entire eight foot tall Plant worth of
material just in a bin and I just crush
it up until it's dust with my gloves and
then I've got a machine that I pour that
material into and it actually separates
the material and the seeds so I've gotta
I need about 10 to 14 days to get it dry
a day or two to get it all crushed up
and then a day or two it takes me a
while to run all these plants is a lot
of material and a lot of plants to work
through to run that all through the the
separator then it's got to go all
through the counter then it's all got to
go out to testers so it's going to be a
little bit before a lot of this is
available I'm sure right now my tester
inbox is going to start blowing up ah
send them to me you guys if you know how
to contact me about a tester if you're
interested in testing send me a message
include pictures of your grow and your
address when you do that it just makes
it so much easier send me all your
testing information if you want to test
the new [ __ ] that came out of the green
house a lot of it will get put in as
freebies in upcoming orders also so that
is my fall harvest report for 2022. I
feel like it was a great success we've
got a lot of seeds a lot of great
crosses big shout out to the people who
helped me out with the greenhouse space
the people that were out there early in
the morning sometimes late at night big
shout out to the person that had to hang
a light they did not expect to hang in a
high space in a precarious position
um big up you guys did a great job we
did a great job we're gonna have a great
year all right I do have more stuff to
talk about you may have noticed that my
content was a little bit weird on the
last couple of episodes I'm trying to
tread lightly
um YouTube is on uh they're basically on
the Rampage they're shutting down a lot
of the uh the Cannabis content the
Educators that are out here talking
about the plant the dude grow show has
been completely shut down uh newbie nugs
his page is completely gone a few of our
other friends have lost their YouTube
Pages simply for posting cannabis
talking about supporting condoning and
educating about our favorite plant or
least my favorite plant I'm sure it's
probably most of our favorite plant big
shout out to you monstera nerds but
YouTube has been on the Rampage taking
down content I've been trying to tread
lightly because I have gotten a couple
of YouTube strikes first they gave me a
warning then they gave me another strike
and they said he can't post for five
days and then they said if you get one
more strike this month we will take down
your channel so I try to not post for
the rest of that month so that I did not
get more strikes on Fresh content the
problem is that they are striking old
content I've got 770 episodes before
this episode and they keep finding
problems with old content like in the
hundreds like 100 200 300 they're
finding just random episodes flagging it
giving me
um Community violations for that for
some reason my content has been deemed
harmful and or dangerous which I don't
understand because I'm just sitting here
talking and unless my voice is that
powerful that I'm sparking some sort of
Revolution we are not harmful or
dangerous I'm teaching people how to
help themselves with a medical product
to ease and improve the quality of their
life we can look at uh we can see half
naked women we could see beer ads and
boner pills all day but if you try to
promote the plant deal we love that's
harmful and dangerous
um I understand it but I don't agree
with it let's talk about this a little
bit I've got
um I've got a nice little rant that I'm
gonna I'm gonna just skip my notes here
I'm gonna leave a note where I am and
then all right here we go I understand
this I've got a little rant that I've
kind of half done on a couple of other
podcasts but I wanted to save the big
part for this show here is what I feel
is going on with YouTube first of all
let me say I understand it but I do not
agree with it here's what I feel is
happening with YouTube this is just my
take on it
I didn't do any research so I don't have
an actual number YouTube is a billion
dollar company right definitely a
multi-million possibly a multi-billion
dollar company they do a lot of Revenue
they feed a lot of people they have a
lot of income a lot of interaction a lot
of support with the entire world
everybody on the planet knows what
YouTube is everybody has seen a YouTube
video if that's where I learn a lot of
things that's where I teach a lot of
things we all know YouTube so YouTube is
present YouTube is popular they've got a
lot of money the people that own and
work at YouTube like having a lot of
money they like knowing that paycheck is
coming in every month so now let's talk
about why they are messing with cannabis
content a lot of people say it's legal
in Colorado it's legal in California yes
but it's not legal in some other places
um so what would happen and I don't
agree with this but I'm just speaking on
General why I feel like this is
happening this is just my understanding
to make it sort of an explanation of
this
um they make a lot of money they they
don't want to get involved in any sort
of legal battle court case anything that
would tarnish their income anything that
would tarnish their reputation anything
that would tarnish their revenue Stream
So hypothetically this could work this
way if somebody were to learn something
illegal off of YouTube and they practice
that illegal practice and got in trouble
for it and they said I learned it on
YouTube guess who could be involved in
be part of it they could be an accessory
they could be implemented in that crime
because that person may not have
committed that crime without the help of
YouTube and YouTube doesn't want that
YouTube doesn't want to go to court
YouTube doesn't want the press for that
YouTube doesn't want to be involved in
that I can't speak for YouTube but I am
a company owner I have a company I've
got a Discord server
um I believe in free speech I definitely
believe that we should be able to say
what we want to say I also believe that
there will be repercussions and
consequences for what I say if I say
something completely Terror terrible to
somebody I wouldn't be too surprised if
they punched me right in the [ __ ]
mouth that's how life goes we've got
freedom of speech but we've also got
expectation of consequences uh
responsibility of words and action like
that is part of being a human let me get
myself back on track here so I do
believe in freedom of speech you cannot
go to my Discord server and start
dropping racial or homophobic or you
can't come in and talk you can't talk
about terroristic activities on my
Discord server I will not allow that
because that is very off-brand for what
I support you can come in my Discord
server and we'll talk about cannabis
we'll talk about reggae music we'll talk
about life love all the good [ __ ] but
we're not going to do anything negative
we're not going to hurt anybody's
feelings we're not going to attack
anybody if you do that sort of [ __ ] in
my Discord I will shut you down
immediately I'll warn you one time based
on what you say if you're dropping
n-bombs and f-bombs in there uh you know
the F-bomb I'm talking about you can't
say those words in there maybe even the
r word in the wrong way I'm going to say
something like hey bro you can't do that
here if you do it another time we're
just going to block you forever we're
not even going to remember you you're
gone I do that because I'm supporting a
community that I want to be a positive
Community I want hatred there I want it
to support my brand it's got my face on
it my company name on it I don't need
the n-word the f word and the r word
involved in my community and my company
and all I don't support that don't
condone that it's not what I'm here for
and if you're gonna say that you're not
part of our team you're not here for
what we're trying to do and you should
go play over there when you get your
[ __ ] figured out come back we may let
you hang out but when you're acting like
that we don't want you around so on my
server I do practice censorship and it
is because I don't want [ __ ] I don't
want terroristic activities I don't want
racism I don't want homophobia on my
Discord server I barely make any money
compared to YouTube I've got a business
that does generate Revenue but compared
to YouTube I am nobody I've got 10 000
YouTube subscribers YouTube's got
however many people watch all day every
day imagine the money that YouTube is
bringing in and imagine why they don't
want to to give any of that to core law
enforcement or anything like that now
think about this really does sound crazy
but think about if two people are in an
alley and one person says hey can you
find drugs and the other guy says I
don't have drugs but person number three
has drugs if one of those persons gets
caught selling or buying or carrying
those drugs and it goes down wrong all
three of those people are going to jail
for that drug transaction because person
two facilitated that transaction YouTube
doesn't want to be person two that is
basically what's happening I'm trying to
be careful with what I say here because
here's where I'm headed to this I don't
want to lose my YouTube channel for
saying something stupid I'm probably
risking a lot by talking about YouTube
and censorship the way that I am right
now but that's part of my job is to
[ __ ] speak up we're I'm ganja soldier
I've been here doing this for so long
I've been doing this since before
cannabis was legal I'm not brand new at
this
um people get mad that our YouTube
channels get taken down our Instagram
accounts get shut down bro back in the
day uh they put a drove a tank up my my
front yard tied a chain to my front door
pulled the front door off my [ __ ]
house my dogs went running down the
street 12 cops came in a flashbang went
off [ __ ] everybody Dives on the floor
they cut open every couch cushion they
cut open every pillow they cut open the
mattresses they cut open the speakers
they dumped all of our food on the floor
they didn't find [ __ ] but they swore
there was something in there that they
needed and they were not stopping
digging and destroying my house until
they found that [ __ ] so nowadays when
they take away my Discord or my YouTube
channel it goes that [ __ ] sucks but
they didn't [ __ ] pour all my food on
my kitchen floor they didn't tear my
front door off I don't have to rebuild
my life and find somewhere new to live
because once that [ __ ] happens the
landlord kicks you out you don't get to
[ __ ] live there anymore it's so
embarrassing you don't want to live
there anymore anyway but that [ __ ]
doesn't that's not happening because we
live in a legal place but
um yeah I'm I'm okay with losing my
Instagram I'm okay with losing my
YouTube knock on wood I don't want to
lose them but there are other options
other places to go if stuff like that
does happen I am going to find other
places to upload the videos I've been
told that cannabis does support podcast
videos soon I will be posting my videos
to cannibals it takes a long time to
upload those videos you guys be patient
with me I'm also going to try Vimeo and
there was another service I think it's
called Rumble I'm also going to try
those so if I disappear on YouTube look
for me on Vimeo Rumble and also on
cannabis and the audio platform will
always remain because the RSS feeds are
cool they don't they don't even censor
very much on those
um platforms all right let me get back
on track I look forward to legalization
so that we don't have to be censored I
look forward to all of the entire nation
legalizing cannabis so that I can teach
everybody without fear of my show my
hard work my dedication part of my
income being hindered because YouTube
has some silly rules I get it but I do
not agree YouTube
all right now what I want from you what
I need from you is I need help where do
I go if they do take me down on YouTube
I did mention Rumble I mentioned uh
Vimeo I mentioned cannabis where are all
the cool kids going to watch videos
where are you going for cannabis content
well websites what applications are you
using I feel like I'm a little bit out
of the loop because I'm so busy creating
content and trying to get it out that I
don't really have time to go discover
the new platform so if you've got a
recommendation a suggestion where I can
put the show where I can participate
with the Cannabis Community I would love
to join you wherever the cool kids are
I'll follow you there help me out all
right let me check out my notes I've got
more
um also I want to know what magazines
and cannabis content you are consuming
your other cannabis education and maybe
not videos but like what else are you
checking out I need some new cannabis
education cannabis content for myself to
consume fill me in where do we go for
that also you guys if they do shut me
down on any every platform keep keep uh
rest assured I am not going anywhere I
will not give up I'm here to support
cannabis to teach you guys how to grow
cannabis I'm here to breed the best
seeds that I can offer you I'm not going
anywhere even if YouTube shuts me down
if YouTube Vimeo Rumble cannabuzz if
they all shut me down bro we'll invent
our own [ __ ] we'll come back stronger
than ever you can't stop us can't stop
won't stop Viva La Revolution cannabis
can't be stopped bro we're legalizing
everywhere and if we do disappear it's
only going to be temporary because you
know that as soon as they do legalize
cannabis they're going to let all of us
come back and play but the question is
do we want to come back then if they
shut us all down do we even want to come
back to YouTube all right I think I've
rambled on long enough about this topic
I don't even know if this episode will
get to stay up because of YouTube's uh
scrutiny at this time please don't give
up on me I'm going to keep making
episodes I'll find some more to put them
keep hanging out keep clicking like on
the videos uh keep sending me all the
comments comment right down there the
comment section is crazy lately you guys
don't give up keep doing that I love
reading the comments I don't answer all
of them but I do read 90 of them most of
you people are amazing a couple of
percent of you are not so cool all right
you guys the next episode I do plan on
talking about Fino hunting and selecting
the phenotype for you and your garden
that should be the next episode
um that is all I've got for today's
episode I want to thank you once again
for hanging out I did have a good time
on this podcast didn't talk too much
about cannabis but I did get to rant and
ramble a little bit and that always
feels good to me if you enjoyed this
rant and ramble I do invite you to join
my Instagram because every Monday night
around 7 10 p.m Colorado time Mountain
time so it's 7 10 and the Mountain Time
Zone I go on Instagram live I'm irie
underscore genetics on Instagram i r i e
underscore genetics I read genetics on
Instagram follow that account every
Monday around 7 10 sometimes 7 15 ish PM
mountain time once again I go live and I
hang out I smoke some dabs I drink a
bunch of Kombucha and I answer cannabis
cultivation and cannabis culture
questions on the Fly you guys can ask me
almost anything you want and I will try
to answer every question that comes
through that live feed it's a lot of fun
for me it keeps me on my toes it keeps
you guys entertained also it keeps my
brain sparking and gives me ideas and
input for the podcast it inspires me to
write [ __ ] down and put it here on the
show so check out the Instagram live
irie underscore genetics I look forward
to seeing you on the live show every
Monday I've also been doing just random
live pop-ins I just pop in and say hey
what's up guys I'm taking a dab I got
about a minute hang out take a dab
answer a question and get out go about
with my day it's a lot of fun join me I
look forward to seeing you there also if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns my email address is
grow from your heart
hotmail.com don't forget about the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart also check
out the website iregenetics.com
everything you need is on
iregenetics.com there's a link to
iridirect so you can get fresh new seeds
there's a link to the merch store you
can get fresh new t-shirts there's a
link to the patreon so you can support
the show all kinds of great stuff and
irygenetics.com all right that's all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back next week with fresh new content
I'm gonna give a big shout out to my
buddy Rick R and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
foreign