[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
773 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun episode planned for us
before we get to the main topic of
today's show let's do a few shout outs
to a few of those great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to Paul K let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to Travis K and
Kells P let's send a high five and a
thank you shout out to Kyle H and danger
cat I want to send a special thank you
shout out to my buddy Rick Robinette
let's send a huge thank you shout out to
my friend B Bala I want to send a big
thank you to Doc grows listen to super
huge high five and a thank you shout out
to my channel Canadian buddy Caribou
Heart TV I want to send a thank you
shout out to another Canadian supporter
our friend JH then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to a long time
supporter my friend Glenn geroni big
thanks and big shout out to everybody
who continues to support the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart of course all of the info you
need will be right there on the screen
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast before we
get too far on this episode I do want to
make a correction I may have misspoke I
may have gave some uh semi-inaaccurate
information on a previous episode I got
an update and a message from a friend
here who was uh paying a little bit more
attention than myself we're gonna Jump
Right In we're going to read this
message this one came from our friend
used to be cool and it politely says I
am only writing to say I think you made
a mistake when discussing the Joe Biden
pardoning people with Federal
convictions for simple possession and I
do understand where I went wrong we will
get to that and thank you for gently
correcting me I'm not afraid to be
gently corrected I do always ask for uh
questions Corrections comments concerns
please do send those to me again the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com let's get into this one says
I think you made a mistake I watched
Biden make the announcement but I do not
recall him saying anything about a
release of prisoners which is what I
misunderstood and where I misspoke it
says his announcement was to say that he
was pardoning people with Federal
conditions convictions for possession
now the result of any pardon would be to
release anyone serving time but as you
pointed out and which Biden would have
already been aware no one was serving
time for a simple possession so that
makes sense so far it says a part in
Acts to wipe out any conviction as if it
never happened and that is what Mr Biden
has accomplished so that is a little bit
different that does make a big
difference that does do some different
things for a few people that may have
affected more people so we'll talk about
that briefly he does go on he says while
Mr Biden may have been fishing for votes
he still did the right thing yet I would
urge you to correct the record and then
he signs it with his cool name used to
be cool big shout out to my buddy used
to be cool you guys I appreciate these
types of updates these types of
Corrections the only way I get stopped
from saying crazy stuff on here is if
somebody does correct me so thank you
for the correction and the update now
let's talk about that real briefly here
I don't want to dwell on old news I
misspoke I thought that nobody was going
to get released from federal prison
which that is that is accurate what's
going to happen is some people are going
to be pardoned which means their Federal
cannabis crimes will be wiped away which
will help people out why would this be
beneficial to people because on a lot of
job applications it says have you ever
been convicted of a crime and now if you
don't have a federal cannabis crime on
your record you're probably open to a
lot more job opportunity you're probably
also open to a lot more educational
opportunities when you apply for
colleges it says do you have any drug
crimes right there you go I got a
federal cannabis crime guess what no job
for you guess what they do deleted that
more opportunity for also this could
give people the opportunity for more
loans more people will be able to start
their own business so the main thing
that this did is it wiped a uh a dent
off of a lot of people's record a lot of
people got a fresh start we erased some
junk some some cannabis crimes that will
help people out that will give people
more opportunity was which is what the
world especially the states need right
now we need more opportunity
so the bottom line is more opportunity
people will be able to get more jobs
they'll be able to get more loans
they'll be able to go to more schooling
they'll be able to better themselves and
make a better future for themselves and
not be uh stopped or blocked or have a
hurdle of a federal cannabis crime in
the way so my friend used to be cool
thank you for the great update my dude
uh thank you for keeping me on my toes
and keeping me straight I do appreciate
it you guys like I said before don't be
shy if you hear me say something silly
something you don't agree with send me a
message sometimes Jesse will send me a
text message he'll be like hey bro you
should have said 12 12. you said 24 18 6
or 19 5 or some [ __ ] and I try to
correct it and come on and say hey I
messed that up you guys pay attention
keep me on my toes I do appreciate it
I'm no wizard I'm no guru I just have a
show and sometimes I will make some
mistakes thanks for keeping me on my
toes all right I've been rambling enough
about that
um I do want to keep talking about some
things before we jump into the main
topic of today's podcast I do want to
announce that the blueberry butcher
seeds will be back on I redirect for
Halloween that is right blueberry
butcher seeds then packaging them up
getting them ready Halloween they will
be on the website at iredirect.com
anybody that gets a pack of blueberry
butcher seeds while supplies last they
will come with a free pack of platinum
Tangy cross to the Jack the Ripper
here's the catch you guys I need help
naming the Platinum Tangy to Jack the
Ripper cross what is a cool name for
that I need a cool name you guys always
have the greatest input the greatest
feedback and advice I want to see in the
comments section what do we call
Platinum Tangy it's a platinum Tangy
female to a Jack the Ripper male it's
got that Tangy candy goodness it's got
some spicy dryer sheet sort of Aromas to
it lots of lemon Tangy Aromas and a
really ripping soaring head high so help
me out with the name to that uh Platinum
Tangy female pollinated by a Jack the
Ripper male needs a cool name all right
where do we go from there oh also
everything on I redirect does get free
packs with every order right that's
enough advertising here let's jump into
the main topic I do have a great email
that came from our friend and I'm not
sure if he wants his name said or not or
they want their name set or not we got
to be careful but let's jump right into
this email it's right here in front of
me there's no need to stare at it let's
read it to the kind people this message
goes a little bit like this it says yo
what's up Ross to Jeff I'm just about to
listen to episode 590 and I'm super
interested in testing of your seeds yes
a lot of people are interested in
testing seeds there are a lot of new
things ready to be tested people are
contacting me if you've watched the
tester episode watch that before you
reach out another requirement will be
that you do join the Discord if you were
on the Discord you've got a much greater
chance of being qualified accepted and
approved as a tester because I have
everybody posting their tester logs on
the Discord that way I can just go to
one spot I can go Discord tester tab
scroll through and see what everybody's
doing that's how I start my mornings I
do some morning chores and I sit there
in my morning smoke and scroll in the
testers that's usually what I do anyway
go watch the episode let me know what
you think if you still want to be a
tester join the Discord we'd love to see
you there there should be a link in the
show notes in the video description it
goes on it says I'll get back to you on
that after I listen I'm in NorCal in
Shasta County and I grow for myself all
right we don't need to read all that it
says my main question right now is I see
that ethos genetics has a seed pack
called Colin OG yes they do a big shout
out to our friends at ethos genetics uh
big up to my buddy Colin the uh the head
[ __ ] in charge over there eat
those seeds
they do have a strain it goes on it says
I see ethos genetics as a seed pack
calling called Colin OG they do have a
string called Colin OG of course all of
us breeders name a strain after
ourselves we got the lemon Jeffrey for
me there's a Jeff so G that was really
rare maybe we'll remake some more of
those but yes there is a call in OG that
is made by the ethos Collective uh we'll
talk a little bit about that it says it
says it's got Grateful Dog in it from
irie genetics yes it absolutely does it
says I'm curious was this a collab on
your part or did he just buy a pack of
your seeds it's much deeper than both of
those bro you're gonna love this story
this is going to be fun since I'm
curious oh where were we uh then did did
he buy a pack of seeds then did the
breeding work uh made his packs and is
giving you credit after the fact and he
wraps it up he says thanks man I love
the podcast and everything you do for
the community thanks much love and
respect your way from Lucas big shout
out to our friend Lucas bro I hope it's
okay that I said your name on the show
because too late I'm not going to edit
that [ __ ] out so uh the first question
um is did he just buy a pack of your
seeds uh let's see clap was this a
collab on your part or did he just buy a
pack of your seeds that's a really good
question let me talk about the Grateful
Dog let me unpack this a little bit more
uh The Grateful Dog I made the Grateful
Dog from a so I got a pack of a lot of
people may not know this story a lot of
people are gathering around and turning
up their airpods to hear this one
because people have been requesting and
asking for this episode and I'm kind of
excited to deliver this story right now
this is going to be really cool here we
go Grateful Dog
um I bought a bunch of seeds
and within that bunch of seeds I got a
pack of seeds called Deadhead OG from
the Cali Connection yes controversial
company uh feel what you will think what
you may
um but that's where the seeds came from
the opinions and feedback don't matter
right now that's straight up history
that's what happened I'm not going to
change anything uh it's a pack of
Deadhead OG from the Cali Connection I
grew those out there were several
phenotypes that were fire there were a
couple phenotypes that were not fire in
my opinion but a couple of more hot
[ __ ] fire uh number nine was my
favorite uh phenotype out of that batch
out of the population number nine was
the best looking plant in my opinion it
had a gassy
um a funky gassy thing that when you
smelled it your eyes kind of squinted
like what is that but then it also had a
earthy musky thing that you went oh I
want some of that but then after then I
dried it and cured it and smoked it and
it had musky gassy skunky Funk but then
when you exhaled it a couple seconds
later a berry thing would hit your
tongue you'd be like well now there's
[ __ ] melons and berries in there it
was really confusing complex delicious
weed so that was number nine that was
Deadhead OG number nine is what that was
so I took Deadhead OG number nine I took
two clones of that plant because you
need two clones to do what I'm about to
do I put silver thiosulfate on one and
reversed it that made pollen that was
all female pollen I put that female
pollen on the other clone it is they're
both number nine it is Deadhead OG
number nine the seeds that came from
there I selected one out of that one and
I started calling that one Grateful Dog
then I grew a bunch of those my favorite
keeper out of that I called it Grateful
Dog it was Deadhead OG but I had felt it
and made my own out of that that one
became Grateful Dog we later took do I
even want to tell this part once again I
took that original pollen and put it on
my Grateful Dog and made another one
that I called 77 if you're a Grateful
Dead fan uh maybe I've talked about this
before 77 is just one of my favorite
years of the Grateful Dead uh 72 77 that
era but 77 is [ __ ] and awesome and
since I had Deadhead OG I made Grateful
Dog and then I made 77 from that 77
never got released that one's mine I
play with that you guys can't have it
but that is how grateful dog got made it
was a Deadhead OG reversed I selfed it
uh and then it's one of it's an S1 it's
one of the self from the Deadhead OG so
that is where that came from then I was
here's where the story gets fun I'm
checking my notes to make sure I'm
staying on track here because I'm high
and I get rambly big shout out to our
friends uh for the lemon Jeffrey uh
concentrates so I'm A Grateful Dog right
um I grow a bunch of seeds out I find
one that's a champ I keep this one champ
I'm growing it I'm smoking it everywhere
I go in town anytime I open up my bag or
pack a bowl or roll a joint or light a
bowl people go bro what kind of weed is
that it was getting a lot of attention
that Shield was fire in my opinion on a
lot of other people's opinion that was
top quality cannabis some of the best
herb I've ever bred and or grew and or
smoked so it's one of my favorites
that's why you people hear about it
that's why it's uh always sought after
that's why it's a legend so I went to go
see a concert at Red Rocks I believe I
was at either Reggae on the Rocks I
believe it was a Reggae on the rocks and
Revolution was the headlining act I was
way into Revolution at the time I ended
up going to this concert by myself the
person that was supposed to go with me
backed out they weren't able to make it
I went to Reggae on the rocks by myself
not a big deal I love a concert by
myself I'm there's going to be 9 000
other people there to make friends with
it's cool I'm gonna have a good time
don't worry so we go to the concert I go
to the concert
and anytime I go to a concert I roll up
a lot of joints back in the day they
used to be more strict about letting you
take weed into concerts I'm in Colorado
now they don't really care very much but
back in the day they used to be more uh
more they would scrutinize you more for
having your Wii they would pat you down
search you take your [ __ ] so my theory
was I'd put three joints in this pocket
three joints in this pocket three joints
here three joints here and I would just
be a walking joint dispenser that way if
they found these three they'd go I got
your weed and they'd quit and I'd still
have 30 more joints tucked away
somewhere in my clothing that I could
get into that concert so I took a bunch
of joints in there and there are several
bands ahead of Revolution so we're
smoking and just hanging out dancing to
the music I'm by myself just getting
down
I kept a joint burning the entire time
like I just did not put out a joint I
got there I got my space I decided
here's where I'm standing lit up a joint
started smoking it as soon as that joint
went out it flicked the roach light up
another one I had plenty I was by myself
I was not going to run out of weed I
knew that I noticed that this kid next
to me this this dude next to me about my
age he looked cool
um he was smoking weed too and I noticed
every time I would light a joint he
would look over like damn that smells
good and he would light his own joint
and I would smell his weed and go nah
mine's better and if it was better I
would have shared with him if he had
good weed that enticed me I would have
been like can I hit your weed you can
hit my weed we would add a talk but I
was like I got the good weed I'ma stay
over here and I just hung out by myself
uh eventually after a few joints and me
lighting up a joint that do lighting a
joint me lighting another and he
lighting another and all of my stuff
smelled better than his every time it
was just the Grateful Dog is all it was
smoking eventually he leans over and he
goes man you got some really good weed
and I was like oh thank you bro and he
asks what is that and I told him it's
called The Grateful Dog and he goes I've
never heard heard of that and I told him
I bred it and now this is like this was
Colorado around probably 2008 2009 maybe
2010-ish I could check and find the
exact date uh but I know when this
happened and I know the timeline around
that time this happened and around that
time everybody in Colorado every white
guy with dreadlocks was a new seed
breeder had some new hash company had a
new dispensary or something so when I
was like I bred this he was just kind of
like he was a little bit skeptical and
he's like where can I get a cut of that
and I was like ah man I don't really
want to sell a cut and then he
introduced himself and he was like well
my name is this uh should I say his name
his name is Noah [ __ ] it this is history
bro we got to get the history right so
my buddy Noah said my name is Noah and I
am the owner of Mile High Green Cross
and at the time so this was around the
same year that uh Mile High Green Cross
won first place and the Denver High
Times Cannabis Cup for their banana kush
or banana OG so if you want to reference
that date when Mile High green cross won
the Denver Cannabis Cup for their banana
kush or banana OG it's banana that's all
I needed to remember that's the same
year that this story happened and
Revolution was at Red Rocks that year as
well that's the year that this story
took place so my boy Noah says I own
Mile High Green Cross and I've been
smoking banana kush and it smells good
and it won the Cannabis Cup and I was
like nice and then he's like I'd be
willing to give you this much money for
a cut of that plan and I'd been thinking
that if anybody wanted a cut of that
plant that was the number that I wanted
he told me the number that I'd had in
mind and I said that's a really good
acceptable deal bro and I was like I
live here it's about two and a half
hours from where we are right now uh
here's my phone number I will cut the
clones for you as soon as I get home
from this adventure seeing reggae and
then in about two weeks give me a call
come to my house and we'll [ __ ] I'll
give you this colon for the money that
you offered and so basically that's how
Noah
um acquired that clone so he followed
through he called me into I came home I
cut the clones two and a half ish weeks
later he came down and picked up his
clones of grateful dog when he came down
he also brought me other clones he
brought other stuff that's where I got
the um the Action Bronson cut that is uh
silver chem uh Kim D two super silver
haze I'm not sure which order that's in
but that's where I got the Action
Bronson cut which made a couple of great
crosses some of my a couple of really
great plants actually came the hell's OG
actually came from our friend Noah he
would just trade me and bring me a lot
of stuff we established a pretty cool
relationship let me give Noah a big
shout out I knew that when I was giving
Noah clones that my clone technique
sucked I cut a bunch of clones of
Grateful Dog hoping to get a couple of
solid cuts to give to him I wanted them
to root and so that he could have
something fancy when he got here to get
him he looked disappointed in my clones
and to be honest I was my clone skill
was lacking at the time I wasn't where I
am now which I'm not sad to admit I'm
not afraid to admit you got to start
somewhere you got to learn everything my
clones really sucked at this time so
he's like bro what you need is an easy
corner and I was like an easy cloner and
he's like the clone machine I was oh
tell me about it so he showed me
pictures and videos I was like I need
one of those and then he wanted a bunch
of cuts from me some stuff that I wasn't
really excited to let go of you know
what I mean like sometimes you have
clones you don't want to get rid of some
I'll share some of them you can't have
he's like I want a couple of these and I
was like ah and then I said he made an
offer one of us made an offer he offered
to trade me an easy cloner machine for a
couple of cuts so what we did was he
bought an easy cloner and brought it to
my place where I was growing we went
into my mother room we've cut clones and
filled up the easy clone machine he
showed me how to get it running get it
dialed in get it PhD and set up how to
cut the Clones how to put them in there
then about 10 days later he got to come
back and pick up the Clones of choice
out of the cloner that's how he got paid
I traded him those cuts for the easy
cloner and the knowledge so that's how
my clone game got uh springboard it got
Leaps and Bounds of improvement was from
my friend Noah from Mile High Green
Cross if you hear this bro fist bump big
up I hope you're well wherever you are
we've kind of lost touch he had a child
I don't think he's in the Cannabis
industry anymore he's kind of doing his
own thing we kind of don't keep in touch
anymore I'm doing my thing he's doing
his
um he'll come around we never lose touch
for forever that's how this industry
Works anyway so uh my buddy gets the cut
um we we meet each other at Red Rocks he
comes to my place he gets the cut we
develop a relationship he teaches me how
to fill the easy clone her now he's got
his uh Grateful Dog clone that he takes
into a commercial facility he acquires a
commercial grow in that grow he had a
lot of my stuff he had a lot of my
plants in there uh I would give him seed
packs and let him run the seeds in there
and then he would bring me back the
keepers we had a pretty cool setup so
Noah's got my clone of Grateful Dog he's
running it in his commercial facility
eventually Noah decides he doesn't want
that commercial facility anymore this
just happens the rules change the laws
change so much that a lot of people that
were in it for the passion for the heart
uh we couldn't come up with the million
dollars that we needed for some of the
new rule changes so instead of doing
that a lot of people just sold out uh
sold their business got some money and
got out of the business because it went
to corporate they pushed out all the the
people with heart and they gave it to
all the people with suits and no
knowledge and that's why that's why it's
all commercial corporate crappy weed now
in the dispensaries because the people
that care about it we want to do a good
job but the people in the suits they
want money coming in yesterday and that
kind of messes it up so my buddy Noah
gets out of the industry and he sells
his grow to a guy by the name of Colin
Colin is the owner of ethos Collective
or ethos seeds
that is how Colin acquired my Grateful
Dog cut so at that point he's got full
access it's his it's in that grow
facility that's his plant he can do
whatever he wants with it anybody can
breed with my seeds if you've got my
beans
you're allowed to breed with them if
you've got a clone that came from me
you're allowed to breed with that I did
not invent cannabis I didn't just cough
or fart or sneeze or meditate one day or
pull them out of my dreadlocks I did not
make seeds out of thin air I had to use
seeds and or clones they came from guess
what other breeders they had to come
from somewhere nobody invented cannabis
we're all using other people's Creations
other people's platforms other people's
what is it Foundation we're all using
other people's seeds and clones so I
feel no uh territorial or no whatever it
is breed with my seeds I just want
credit if there's one of my plants in
there and you list it on the package
give me some credit maybe send me a pack
of seeds don't change names don't be
Shady if you do everything ethically and
cool it may be beneficial for you to say
that there is one of my crosses in there
that makes things desirable when you put
something good in it people want that
[ __ ] so uh Colin acquires my Grateful
Dog through the purchase of Noah's
commercial facility now he's got it at
this point he can do whatever he wants
with it which is where he bred it and he
created his own call in OG I'm pretty
sure that's Grateful Dog Sour Diesel and
the white I could be wrong there could
be more there's flow in there somewhere
I do believe I should have Googled that
but that is Colin's creation that's
Colin OG yes there absolutely is some
Grateful Dog in there and then let's
address that second part of the question
I kind of touched on it just a little
bit here
um did he buy I'm curious was this a
collab it wasn't really a collab and he
did not buy seeds he got the Clone and
then he did do the breeding work and yes
he is making packs and giving me credit
after the fact which is very uh
admirable and respectful of that guy to
give me credit after the fact now
um the part about is this a collab
technically uh no but untechnically yeah
we're all collabing anybody that I have
put their pollen and my seeds or their
seeds in my pollen or my plants and
they're pollen together we're
technically collabing it's not always an
approved or an endorsed or assigned or
whatever planned out collab for both of
us but yeah anybody that all you guys
out there if you use one of my plants a
female or a male and you breed it to
something technically basically I guess
you can say we collab I can't deny it
because my pollen is in your plants so
yeah technically we did collab but
untechnically no it wasn't like a uh a
planned thought out collab he just did
his thing
um and I can't be mad about it I breed
with a lot of his stuff the uh lemon
what is it the lemon OG Haze that I
worked with that came from Colin and I
made the sonic boom out of that one so
can't be mad about him working with my
stuff I'm doing it too big up Colin hope
you're well if you ever hear this bro
hope you're well I'm pretty sure he's
learning to play piano pretty well I can
play some drums a little bit let's do
some uh some funky as piano drums sort
of stuff together one day that should be
fun all right I feel like I'm rambling
let me check my notes and get myself
back on track
um yeah I think I covered the main uh
portions of this email we're all
collabing you guys
um there are other collabs when I do
call breeders and I say hey do you want
to do this or we talk about it and we do
plan projects but most of the time uh
it's just me selecting stuff it's really
fun when you talk to I can't tell you
who I'm trying to work with right now
but there's one breeder and I'm like hey
I want to use this and they're like let
me find the perfect Fino what are you
going to use and I'm like this and we're
kind of planning it out they're going to
select one end I'm going to select the
other we're going to breed that [ __ ]
together it's going to be Stellar I
can't tell you too much about it there
are a couple of those in the works
um that's all I think I should talk
about for this episode because I have
said a whole lot of stuff I talked about
the Grateful Dog I made a correction I
feel like if we just leave this episode
just Grateful Dog it'll be a good
Standalone topic on its own so ladies
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for hanging out
for another episode of The Grow from
your heart podcast again if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns I would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
or entertaining maybe you just like to
throw me a tip all you have to do is
visit patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart if I said any of that
too quickly if you need any more
information perhaps you want to join the
Discord maybe you're looking for seeds
maybe you're looking for Merch I
recommend you check out my website
irygenetics.com all right that's all
I've got for you I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content I
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
Sonic and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you