[Music]
thank you
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
775 of the girl from your heart podcast
I have a fun show lined up for you
before we jump in let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy Kip I want to send a big
thank you shout out to Route 305 and
Randy Farms listen to Big thank you
shout out to Mr mean green and f a plant
count I want to send a special thank you
shout out to my friends roll this nug an
ADHD grower listen to Big fist bump to
Noah n in growing Tennessee let's send a
big thank you shout out to William E
Downs listen to thank you shout out to
dreadlock farmer then let's wrap it all
up with a big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
Anvil Gardens big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit Debbie
uww.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast speaking
of support I do want to send a big thank
you to everybody who supported me on I
redirect I did a Halloween sale for I
redirect and I had a tremendous response
it took me a little bit to get all the
orders out I do apologize if you feel
like it was delayed it was just me doing
it check for a tracking number because
everything has been shipped up to this
time once again big thanks for the
response to the Halloween sale on
iridirect
now a little bit of an update the lemon
Jeffrey and Golden Goat feminized seeds
that everybody is asking for will be
available and in stock on iridirect for
Black Friday that's right if you want
more information or details or updates I
do encourage you to join the newsletter
you can go to iregenetics.com scroll
down toward the bottom there's a spot to
join the newsletter type in your email
address we will get you on the
newsletter get you updates when new
things do drop or you can join the
patreon if you're not already on patreon
go join us there of course the patrons
do get the first updates the first
cracks and of course coupon codes for
new drops so stay tuned because Golden
Goat and lemon Jeffrey will be dropping
very soon I know you're going to ask
about orange gasm next stay tuned that
one will be coming shortly after those
also when it comes to ordering on
iridirect or this may count uh just
about anywhere if you're ordering things
online if you're purchasing things
through the mail
um let's put um our real names on the
package or at least a friendly name a
usable name on the package I enjoy and I
appreciate and I respect the work you're
doing to create your own company you've
made a cool Instagram name that is
whatever uh something crazy hash company
that is your new name or something seed
company or something Farms that's really
cool I'm proud of you but you don't have
to put it on every shipping label when
you're sending and receiving something
the less information on that label that
is unnecessary is the better put your
name and your address on there what I'm
talking about is I get orders that'll
say like the order will be and I'm just
making [ __ ] up right here don't feel
targeted unless you did this it'll say
like to Bill Smith from ganja Farms
Incorporated in Plano Texas or Seattle
Washington it doesn't matter where it is
but when you put ganja Farms
incorporated or big fat weed farm or
whatever on the [ __ ] shipping label
that makes it a little suspicious and it
makes it gives me a couple of suspicions
first of all uh the mail off the post
office the mail carrier they're going to
be like who's [ __ ] ganja Supreme
ganja Farm 420 weed smoke who is this
they're going to want to know what the
[ __ ] is in there or maybe somebody in
your area knows that you're ordering
seeds and they see that name or they've
recognized that name come through
they're going to pop it open they're
going to start stealing your [ __ ]
because it's a very noticeable name
blend in be Bill Smith be Jane Doe when
it comes to the [ __ ] male be more
careful please that's my advice my
recommendation my suggestion I see a lot
of people type in random weird names
when they're ordering through I redirect
and I try my best to delete those I
don't pay a lot of attention to
correcting addresses but if I see that
you've got like weed grow Farms or weed
Warrior 420 or some [ __ ] in your name I
do try to remove that because we don't
need our packages opened up inspected
and taken sending seeds is not illegal
but don't encourage anybody to mess with
you steal from you or cause you problems
use your brain use your head then your
company will go further I'm proud of you
for having the company name but you
don't have to put it on everything I
don't put I read genetics on anything I
don't put grow from your heart podcast
on anything that's not what it says the
mail is discreet and careful and and
very adult that is my first rant for
this episode let's be more Pro when
we're putting our names on packages also
package [ __ ] more carefully I try to
package things where they won't get
smushed I send them in a priority
mailbox get a lot of seeds that come in
a bubble mailer and they're totally
squished be more careful be more
professional also on the other other end
of that if you've sent me seeds as a
gift recently thank you I got them and I
do appreciate it where do we go from
here I want to give a shout out to all
my friends in Thailand that's right I'm
not sure if I've mentioned this on the
podcast yet Thailand is now part of the
team legalization that's right Thailand
has legal cannabis I've got some great
friends over there I'm not sure if they
want their names said or not but I'm
going to say them right now you might
not even know who they are big shout out
to my buddy Steve big shout out to my
buddy Brett they are killing it in the
Thailand legal cannabis game they've got
commercial cultivations
they've got dispensaries they've got
clients they've got a flow going they've
got standard operating procedures for
selling legal legal cannabis in Thailand
I'm proud of you guys it's good to see
you doing it out there if you're in
Thailand to look for some irie genetics
uh the strains and the seeds are on
shelves out there in Thailand so big up
to everyone in Thailand who fought for
and succeeded with the legalization of
cannabis all right the last piece of
little rambling before we get to the
email portion of the podcast there are
fresh t-shirts on the irie genetics
website if you go to iregenetics.com
click on the merge tab that will take
you to the store where I do sell my
merchandise you will find new t-shirts
you will find long sleeve shirts you
will find hoodies and you will find
women's tank tops that's right they've
all got the cross logo on the front of
them so hit the website grab your shirts
all the cool kids are doing it one more
thing I said that was the last but I do
have one more this is just Shameless
advertising ladies I was talking with
your boyfriend and I heard him say that
he wanted some new Ivory genetic seeds
for Christmas that's right I'm sure he
said that the place to get them is
iridirect.com just in case you're not
sure where to get your man his Christmas
seeds that is the place every man that
smokes grows enjoys ganja wants some new
seeds for Christmas I read direct.com is
the place to go now let's do the fun
part of this podcast let's jump into the
email portion of this show I do enjoy uh
reading and answering listener questions
this is what I call listener generated
content I like this because I know that
if I'm helping uh my friend Chef who
sent me this message one person has this
question I know if one listener has this
question there are probably several
people out there that this could help
and be benefit to so I love the
questions please send those to me you
can use the grow help tab on the website
at iregenetics.com or simply use my
email growfromyourheart hotmail.com
anyway this message came from my buddy
Shep and it goes just like this if I can
pick it up it goes hey Ross to Jeff
maybe you've discussed this before and
if so my apologies you know what I will
repeat heat subjects on here because
I've realized that not everybody listens
to every single episode people don't go
back and listen to everything if you do
thank you that's a dedicated certain
kind of podcast listener I appreciate
you but most people jump in and they
just catch the future episodes they
don't go backwards so I have talked
about this possibly but we'll do it
again
it says I grow in a three by three scrog
and I recently had a cannabis variety
that is female including a female test
from a very reputable reputable and
well-known breeder in the community then
it says in parentheses it was not you so
this is not one of my lines we're
talking about here it says this is a 9
to 11 week variety at week five uh day
38 In Bloom I found two male flower
clusters so you're growing what you
thought and assumed and probably was
tested to be a female it sounds like it
was a feminized seed you thought it was
a girl and at day 38 guess what we see
some male flowers this female plant is
now showing intersex traits which is a
problem especially around week five of a
9 to 11 week plan it does go on it says
I found two male clusters below the
scrog screen very much in the shade so
those are the buds down below the scrog
so there's a screen the lights hitting
down here some of the light doesn't get
down here that part down there is where
we we are discovering the intersex parts
of this plant it says unfortunately I
miss these little bastards and two male
flowers have opened before I found and
removed them alright so you've got
opened up flowers They're popped open
you can see they've been expressed as
the word we used uh that's never a good
sign that means that they probably let
out some pollen into the air that pollen
is super light does not take a lot of
air for that pollen to move around it
says question since these male flowers
were below the scrog below the canopy
just how bad could this be how badly
seated do you think my buds will be uh
it says what are the odds that the
pollen will be fertile there's been no
male flower anywhere else on this plant
other than these in the shade by the way
thanks and best wishes all right let's
talk about that for a little bit the
first question
um since these flowers were below the
scrog uh just how bad could it be I said
a moment ago that pollen travels very
easily travel pollen is really light
unfortunately sometimes it goes up I've
seen pollen move up it doesn't always
fall if there's a little bit of airflow
the wind directed off something or
Ricochet something like that I've seen
pollen actually move up into the air so
it could have gone up into your full
canopy I don't want to make you paranoid
I don't want to give you any false hope
it could have gone up there also it
might not have I don't know how much
pollen those few male flowers opened up
but they did let some pollen out
possibly and it probably went up some of
it went down it went everywhere that's
the way that pollen works when they pop
open they kind of have a little pressure
to them it's like they just breathe out
just a little bit to let it go so it
could be bad it could be not bad at all
I really we can't tell until a couple of
probably a few days you'll be able to
tell you'll see little kernels happening
and that's where the seeds are starting
to form it looks like something just
went weird like your your calyxes are
swollen up uh what are the odds this
pollen could be sterile or fertile
that's uh yes both it could be either
way dude it could definitely be either
way and it says there have been no male
flowers anywhere else that's a good
thing cut those off keep an eye on it
pay very close to attention there may be
more you've got six more weeks to go
possibly I'd probably take this [ __ ]
down early and then not grow it ever
again is what I would do but uh pay
attention you may have produced a few
seeds you may have produced a lot of
seeds and that's where I go on that one
rant where I say uh grow those seeds bro
you may have just made a bunch of great
seeds for yourself to play with grow
them see what you've created you may
like I've said in a past episode you may
have just created gold you may have the
new chem dog the new Golden Goat the new
uh Gorilla Glue you may have the new uh
chefso G in there who knows what you
just made also you could have made a
bunch of intersex plants that stress out
and hermaphrodite and show problems as
soon as they get a light leak too much
temperature problem or too much shade or
whatever so grow those seeds if they do
happen but I honestly uh without looking
at the plants the room getting in there
with the light and kind of looking
around I can't tell you enough details
to give you any uh diagnosis or
prognosis you could have seeds you may
not
um they could have been fully fertile or
fully sterile flowers that opened up
that pollen could have been good or bad
did you see any dust
if you see any dust laying around those
male flowers like the leaves around it
may just have like it just looks like
you sprinkled them with powdered sugar
that's pollen that's going to be a bad
sign if there's no dust then chances are
a little bit better for you
um that's really all I think I've got
for you for this one keep an eye on it
and then if you do see seeds forming
you've got decisions to make do you want
to finish it or do you want to chop it
down and then definitely consider if you
ever want to run that particular
cultivar again because it did freak out
just from a little bit of Shade that's
not something that I would tolerate all
right let's keep moving Chef thank you
for the great message let's keep moving
there is another message that came from
our friend Matt
it says hey Ross to Jeff I hope you're
doing well I love the recent Grateful
Dog episode hey thank you for listening
I got a lot of great response to that
episode the number one question that
stemmed from that is can I get seeds or
buy a clone and the number one answer
for that is no not right now maybe in
the future but no I'm not selling clones
or seeds of that one right now I'm
crossing things with it but uh there
will be a Jack the Ripper Grateful Dog
cross available very soon it's called
Dog Ripper but we're not selling the
Grateful Dog right now it says also I
have got a question for you when would
you consider a home grower ready to
advance to the role of caregiver and do
you have any advice regarding scaling up
a grow over time so this is a great
question let me talk about what the word
caregiver means
most of what I'm going to say applies to
the Colorado medical cannabis market and
most of this is info from around 2008
2009.
since that time we have changed the term
from caregiver to provider but let me
explain this when we started medical
cannabis a lot of people wanted access
to medical cannabis without going to a
dispensary when you got your medical
cannabis recommendation from a doctor it
gave you the right to grow six or more
plants depending on the paperwork you
got
so people were allowed to grow six
plants now the catch was some of these
people were very sick they were
receiving medical cannabis for a reason
which also limited their ability to
produce their own cannabis maybe they
were sick maybe they were physically
unable maybe they just didn't have the
room the space and of course the
knowledge to produce their own cannabis
so what those people would do is they
would assign somebody that would be
called a caregiver to produce their
medical cannabis products for them so
when I go to the weed doctor the weed
doctor gives me a paper and it says you
can smoke and grow and have weed then on
that card there's a spot that says who
is your caregiver
I would find a friend or we would find
somebody a lot of people would find me
and they would list so we'll just put me
as the caregiver and Mike uh I've got
your permission to do this I hope I'm
gonna use Mike as an example when the
medical cannabis thing came up our good
friend White Mike he's a medical
cannabis patient he likes the way I grow
weed so he asked me one day want to be
my caregiver and I said I would be
honored to bro so then at that point he
wrote my name on his card and sent it
into the state and that gives me the
right to grow Mike's medical marijuana
plants for him so I could have those in
my possession in my cultivation area and
it would be fully legal because I was
Mike's caregiver now when that weed was
ready it was my responsibility to
provide Mike with that product
there were not many legal stipulations
or bylines or guidelines or bylaws or
anything about how I could give Mike his
medicine I wasn't supposed to make a
profit from it is what I think that the
uh the paperwork said but I could
definitely charge Mike for electricity
my time my seeds whatever I felt
necessary but I wasn't supposed to
profit off of Mike for it which I never
did Mike always got the hookups on the
weed but my responsibility and my role
as a caregiver was to grow safe
effective cannabis for Mike and Supply
it on the Rhythm that Mike expected is
medicine and he needed his medicine and
he would tell me what he liked the best
and I would grow that and I would have
it when he needed it at a price he could
for afford most of the time I just gave
it to him because that was just the the
bond that we had he liked the way that I
grew he gave me the ability to grow more
plants because I had his medical
marijuana card it kept me legal and safe
so I just grow enough and make sure to
set some aside for Mike and anytime he
needed it there it was and it worked out
that way one of the best parts about
that is
being Mike's best friend uh we're bros
we're in the car all the time we're next
to each other in the office we're at the
dab table together I know Mike's
physical ailments I know Mike's uh
mental state I know what Mike likes I
know what Mike what flavors Mike enjoys
so I got to really dial in Mike and I
together got to dial in what medicine
Mike was receiving and what I was
providing for Mike I know that he loves
Grateful Dog if he could have Grateful
Dogs seven days a week 24 hours a day
that's what Mike would smoke and I could
see it on him like I'd be like it's
about time for Mike to get some weed so
I could see his body and his facial
expression change time to smoke Mike out
so we got to develop like a real bona
fide caregiver uh patient relationship
which I think was great so that is the
caregiver idea we would be assigned as
his caregiver and then I could grow
cannabis for him and when he needed that
cannabis it would be ready for him and
if he needed Edibles topicals oils
whatever it would be my responsibility
as his caregiver and friend to make that
product available and ready for him for
his consumption needs to fix his
ailments to improve the quality of his
wife was the bottom line so that's what
a caregiver is the idea is to provide
cannabis for a medical marijuana patient
since then they have changed the term to
provider you just write provider in the
card and they've also really limited us
now in Colorado back in the day you were
allowed to have uh like unlimited counts
to where you could just get everybody
could be you could be everybody's
caregiver
so like everybody in the neighborhood I
would be Clint Mike my mom uh [ __ ]
the neighbor the neighbor down the
street I was all of their caregiver and
I was just growing so much Urban
providing herb for everybody so I got a
lot of experiences how I understood uh
what people like what people want how
often they do it I learned a lot by
doing that sort of stuff that got me
um that definitely worked well in the
medical cannabis Realm
so we would do what was called card
stacking is I would have everybody's
cards and I would just grow for all of
them and we'd put all their plants in
one cultivation area then the state came
down and said you can only have six
patients which limited me to uh that
would be six times six is 36 plus my six
that was 42 plants then counties started
saying oh you're only limited to 12
plants you can have your six
recreational and your six medical plants
but you're not allowed to grow more than
that which the states and counties or
the cities and counties are allowed to
do that sort of stuff within their own
boundaries and borders their own uh
what's it called their own Council so uh
that's what happened a lot here so now
we're just limited to 12. now I can grow
12 plants I basically keep it down to uh
10 females and two boys is what we
basically do you got the the 12 count so
um that was the role of the caregiver
that's what a caregiver does and is
expected to do now our friend Matt here
is asking when is the uh when do you
know it's time to consider a home grower
ready to advance to the role of
caregiver that's a really good question
question it's a really thin line that
you're skating there between caregiver
and home grower so let's talk about that
the way that it worked for me is people
enjoyed smoking the herb that I grew
people saw me out they're like you are
and this sounds egotistical but at the
time I don't know about now but at the
time around here I was one of the best
and most noticed weed growers that there
was I was working with dispensaries I
was growing weed everywhere I came up
real quick and people noticed it so a
lot of people wanted me to be their
caregiver also I was involved in a
dispensary so that put me out there a
lot and I got to be a lot of people's
caregiver so people knew that I was
growing good weed they knew that I knew
how to interact with people and have uh
conversations and build relationships
and that I'm compassionate and uh what's
the other word I've got empathy and um
yeah I just like to connect with people
and I care about you and I love the way
that uh when you smoke you feel better
and so that just made me I had the
caregiver mindset so
um people sought me out so what I would
say how you know when you're ready are
people
um are there people in need of medical
cannabis knocking down your door for the
weed are there people have you made a
relationship with one or two people who
just really love what you do because
that's all it takes like like I said my
buddy Mike so we'll say Mike Kevin and
Pops were probably three of my main
patients that I took care of that I was
provided their caregiver uh signed their
caregiver those three dudes will tell
you that I grew the best weed they've
ever smoked ah those three guys that's
why I was their caregiver I was their
friend and I also grew the best herb
they could smoke so if you got somebody
that's saying hey uh Matt do you have
any more of that we do group hey Matt do
you have any more of that we do grew
that one thing you grow is the only
thing that makes me feel better
that's when it's time for you to step up
and become a caregiver but there comes
great responsibility can you provide the
product which that patient requires on
the timeline which they require it do
they smoke an ounce a week do they smoke
two ounces a week can you handle that
demand sustainably maybe for a month or
two you can do it but can you do it for
the next three to five years without
missing a beat to keep that person
medicated perfectly and beautifully can
you grow like a what's it called a
surplus so that when you've got to go on
vacation or clean up the room or if a
power outage happens and you [ __ ]
lose a crop can you back up Surplus
enough stockpile enough to make sure
that person has got their medicine think
about what you're able to do think about
your realistic limitations can you
provide a quality a safe ethical quality
product for this person on the timeline
which they require it if you can build a
relationship with them find out what
they need find out what they like best
and start providing caregiver Services
don't get in over your head if you can
do one or two people that's cool how are
you going to cover the cost of this
product are you going to charge them a
little bit are you going to charge other
people like well a lot of so this is in
the past I used to give the [ __ ]
medical patients weed for really really
cheap if not free and I would sell black
market weed to the other people and the
people that didn't have any medical
recommendation or didn't even talk about
medical weed just the Stoners and my
Bros and the gangsters they'd pay full
[ __ ] price but the patience they
would get some free [ __ ] and they would
get some hookups so you've got to decide
how you want to run that it is kind of a
business you've got to run this like a
business uh but a little bit different
than a business because most businesses
kind of uh just run about money this is
all about compassion and taking care of
people so you got to pay attention to
the people how are you going to cover
your own costs you've got to buy soil
nutrients lights air water you've got to
do work all of that costs something are
they going to pay for that will it be a
donation basis will they give you so
much a month and you let them have what
they need think about that before you
even get into it talk to them about it
be like hey Ross to Jeff said we should
talk about this starting conversations
is awkward just say Ross Jeff said we
should talk about this before I be your
caregiver or [ __ ] play this episode
and be like hey here's the things we
should talk about are you going to pay
for it how much do you need how much do
you want how do I get compensated like
talk about all those things and figure
it out so that you can still be friends
if something does go wrong that's the
most important part of all that is that
we're all still friends after all the
chips fall so
um that's how I think you know when
you're ready when you qual you have a
customer or a client or a friend
requesting your product and you've got
faith in yourself that you can provide
that product consistently now advice on
scaling up
um
yeah one of the most important things is
electricity can your house handle it can
your building facility wherever you're
growing you set a home grower I'm
imagining you're in a home can your home
handle that also are you ready to have
um so cannabis is a commodity it's a
valuable commodity it's a profitable
product you're entering the area the
arena of having a profitable product on
hand in your home and it sounds like
you're about to upscale the amount of
that product you have and is being
produced which will make you double
triple quadruple the size of a Target
which you already are people may not
know you're growing law enforcement
thieves Crooks uh crackheads none of
them may know that you're growing but
when you start scaling up things will
become more obvious and more apparent
there will be more people coming and
going from your home there'll be more
electricity there'll be more sound
you'll be buying more products if you
make some money be careful that when you
make money you don't come up too fast
and show people that you got a brand new
car and a bunch of chains if you're in a
place where you shouldn't be making a
little bit of money that's when things
do happen to you
I think one of my first pieces of advice
would be to don't scale up maximize what
you have got dial it in get the room the
space the environment that you have got
to its full potential if you're pulling
uh one pound now try to get two pounds
out of it if you're getting two aim for
four maximize that before you even
consider moving up to a bigger grow and
adding more equipment more toys more
money more responsibility more
opportunity for failure you're going to
have people relying on you so if this
crop does fail it's going to be more
detrimental than if your personal smoke
failed you can go to The Dispensary you
can hit up one of the homies and get
some black market herb if you need to
but this person they're relying on you
so you have got to produce that product
I said Black Market is that politically
correct anymore is that the gray Market
the free market you know what I mean
that's where I'm talking about you may
have to go get your product if your crop
fails our patients do not have that
opportunity they're relying on us they
know that we are growing that product
safely we know that it's the strain they
want they know that it's the potency
they want at the frequency that they
need it so they're going to rely on you
don't scale up too big and [ __ ] things
up because that does happen quite a bit
when you are scaling up make sure that
you your electricity can handle it make
sure that you can handle it is it too
much work think about Harvest time do
you have a trim crew that can manage
that Harvest will that be possible I
would say scale up to one light next
don't go like from one light to four
lights go from one to two and then maybe
from two to four
I think for a one-man operation in a
good sized room nine lights and I'm
talking about old 1000 watt [ __ ] HPS
lights because I'm a dinosaur nine
lights is probably the limit that I
would do if you got like nine R specs in
a room that's gonna be a killer [ __ ]
room that's probably the amount of work
that I would expect I would expect one
person to do in a cultivation in a home
after that it's going to get a little
bit crazy and a little bit hectic so
scale up slowly dial everything in
before you add more learn everything get
it perfect before you add more
um learn how to scrog everything learn
how to Trellis everything beautifully
learn how to pop and twist learn how to
defoliate dial in your feed dial in the
light dial in the air dial in the water
get everything perfect before you expand
then expand slowly one light then if
you've got two then go to four if you
got four then go to nine that's just the
way that I would do it slowly scale up
make sure that your light your house can
handle it and then also I'm in Colorado
if I set up a grow in the summer it's
going to kick ass but right now in the
winter it's going to change everything
will be different before you scale up
run a small grow in that room and get
that room figured out get that
environment figured out for a solid year
before you scale up too big because you
might buy build a room that in the
winter it works perfectly but when the
summer comes it gets so hot that you
can't run it because you can't add
electricity you can't add air
conditioner because you cannot add
electricity that will be a problem so
build up slowly let it run for a year
build up again let it run for a year
build up again that is probably my
advice for that he wraps it up with
cheers man take a fat dab so fat and
round houses your eyes shut and give
your mom a hug for me I appreciate that
bro I do need a big fat dab got a little
bit more recording here to do than we
are going to get right on that one all
right Matt thank you for the great
question you did give me flashbacks to
my caregiver days got me sitting here
reminiscing thinking about some of the
old school times in the basement when I
had like 20 people down there trimming
oh those were the good old days or were
they all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
775 of the girl from your heart podcast
that's actually the correct episode
number I do realize I said the wrong
number on the last episode I apologize
thank you for all of the tweets and
emails regarding that I got it right
this time I'll be back in a couple of
days with fresh new content if you have
any questions Corrections comments or
concerns you know that I would love to
hear from you the email address is
growfomyourheart hotmail.com make sure
you support the show on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart everything else is on the website
irygenetics.com that is all I've got for
you I want to give a big shout out to my
buddy ass kickerson and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
foreign
[Music]