[Music]
thank you
all right here we go welcome back
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
777 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun show lined up for us
before we jump in let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the kind folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my buddy turt burglar let's send a
big thank you shout out to Indica Chris
and single T I want to send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to brohan78
and Luke let's send a thank you shout
out to Captain Mojo I want to send a
special thank you shout out to my friend
Rasta Greenthumb let's send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to trolling
and Kyle H let's send a thank you shout
out to Kells P then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my buddy Lefty's
Farm big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
show on patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com for forward slash grow
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen and you know I do include a link
in the show notes and in the video
description to make it nice and easy for
all of my friends to support the podcast
speaking of support I owe everybody a
big thank you for all of the support on
the early Black Friday sale that's right
if you are a member of the patreon You
Got a notification that came with a
coupon code letting you know that the
Black Friday sale is now active on
iridirect.com that's right check out
iredirect.com for all the current stock
things will last until Black Friday but
a lot of the new drops will be sold out
right after Black Friday I've got enough
on there to last about the week maybe a
little bit more but they will sell out
so make sure you grab the Black Friday
deals before they are gone at
iridirect.com all right that should wrap
up all of the business part of this
podcast let's move our way into the fun
part of this episode I've been doing I'm
not sure if it's been an experiment on
myself or if I've been noticing
something about myself
but I noticed that last week I could
smoke everything and not get the buzz I
desired I could smoke all the
concentrates I could smoke all the
flowers I ate some edibles and I was
just not achieving the level of
medication or the buzz level that I was
trying to achieve and I was getting
frustrated with it I was just smoking
more I thought maybe I need to take a
little bit of a break but then this week
I don't know what's going on but things
have balanced themselves out this week
all I have to do is take a little tiny
itty bitty little dab and I feel like
I'm just completely wrecked I'm getting
so lit off of my dabs I'm making up for
the excessive consumption last week and
I'm saving some this week just because
when I do smoke I'm getting extra lit so
my question to you is do you go through
phases where sometimes you can look at
your dabs and catch a nice Buzz or other
times when you can smoke all of the dabs
and not even get a buzz at all is that
just me is that something seasonally is
that something with my diet something
with my mood something with blood sugar
brain chemistry who knows what's going
on but I want to know is it just me does
that sort of stuff happen to you also
send me a message grow from your heart
at hotmail.com or hit me on Twitter or
social media let me know am I the only
one going through this weird phenomena
of where sometimes I can buy a few grams
of concentrates and they'll last me a
week and then sometimes I could buy the
same amount of concentrates and it will
last me a day is it just me or do you do
that also let me know because man last
week I smoked double what I normally
smoke and this week I'm smoking half of
what I normally smoke and I really
notice a huge difference but I'm not
doing anything uh differently diet wise
or life or physically Wise It's just
seems to be the only difference is it's
colder now and that doesn't really I
don't think that makes a difference it
is super cold today hasn't been so cold
I don't know if that makes any sense all
right where do we go from there all
right let's segue into our next topic
I've got something I think will be fun
to talk about my question to you is are
you doing things in your garden that are
completely useless because they are a
ritual they are a habit uh maybe you
were doing it because one of your
uncle's friends did it in the 70s and he
told you you could do it and you tried
it and you just never stopped my idea
and my question is are you doing things
in your garden just because you've been
programmed to do it because you think it
might be doing something because you saw
somebody else doing it do you have a
rhyme and reason and a method for
everything that is happening in your
garden I've noticed some people are just
doing some things just because it's a
habit and they don't know why they're
actually doing the steps that they are
doing we spend a lot of time money
energy and effort on our garden we hope
to have a beautiful outcome if we can
streamline the amount of time we spend
in there the amount of money and the
amount of energy that we have to put
into that garden and still get a quality
outcome I think that helps us out one of
my job is a jobs as a consultant is to
go to your commercial facility walk
around for a day view your grow your
employees your plants and see what's
happening and then it is my job to make
that grow more proficient if it's better
production less cost I am there to
increase productivity and save money so
there are several ways you could
probably do that in your grow I'm not at
your growth so I don't know what's going
on but the next time you're in there
think about it are the moves and steps
that I'm making are they necessary think
about from the minute you open the door
to that grow to when you start mixing
your nutrients when you check your pH to
where you do everything in that grow
when you touch the plants when you
whatever you're doing is there a rhyme
and a reason for it think about why am I
doing the action I am doing right now
what does this do to my plants what does
it do to my plants right now later today
tomorrow in three days and seven days
and two weeks in the long run before
Harvest Time think about the full
outcome of everything you were doing to
those plants
keep in mind that the things you do to
your plants today may not show you
results or benefits very soon it may be
two three five seven days it could be
two weeks five weeks maybe nine weeks
down the line before you see the results
of what you did is that consequences or
rewards we may not know so go slow uh
think twice before you cut anything you
can't put [ __ ] back on but you can cut
[ __ ] off don't uh over feed you can feed
more but you can't take back food so
think about every move you are making
before you make it in that grow and
think about does this have a reason does
this have a purpose why am I doing this
in the grow maybe like I said earlier
maybe maybe I told you something years
ago you should do this and you've been
doing that in your grow maybe your style
has changed maybe your room has changed
maybe your equipment changed that thing
I told you might not even be necessary
anymore micro evolves and changes uh
probably uh more quickly than a lot of
people because I have a lot more input
and also more experience I'm not as
afraid to experiment and maybe kill a
couple of plants that's another thing I
should talk about don't get so trapped
into your routine that you're afraid to
try new things be able to maybe risk a
plant or two and that's how you learn
and how you expand and how you improve
if you don't take risks you will not get
better so what I'm saying is are you
doing things in your grow because it's a
habit because you learned it from
somebody a long time ago and you've just
been doing it or does every step of your
grow have a purpose a rhyme a reason and
a method why are you doing that if you
can eliminate that step and save
yourself some time don't do it if you
can eliminate a product or a step
that'll save you money that's beneficial
right away we all like saving more money
you can buy yourself more things but try
to have a reason for everything you were
doing in that grow if I were there
watching you and I said hey bro why did
you do that you should have a solid
reason if I did that because of this and
I just I do that every time I've been
doing that for years okay why do you do
that every time why have you been doing
that for years what is your reason for
the actions you are taking Every Act
action has an equal and opposite
reaction are you getting a benefit are
you messing up your plants what are you
doing let's think about everything we're
doing in there now I want to give a big
shout out to my dogs because this part
of the show was inspired by my dogs let
me tell you a funny short story here
um I got into a relationship with the
lovely lady she had two puppies
um when you get out of the shower at
that house those two puppies they're not
puppies they're uh small Terrier dogs
they're adult small Terriers when you
get out of the shower those two Terriers
love to lick your feet when you are wet
they just want to lick your ankles and
your feet when you're wet recently we
got another dog probably close to a year
ago we got another dog that dog has
learned that he likes to lick feet also
the dog has no idea why he likes to lick
feet he doesn't know what it does he
doesn't know what he's doing but he
knows that every time I get out of the
shower he really wants to come into the
bathroom and lick my feet he learned it
from Tikka who guess what learned it
from the dog that was previous to that
one who has since passed away a dog
taught another dog something and now
that dog is talking another dog
something and that dog thinks it's a way
of life that if something is required
and it has absolutely no reason why that
is a requirement of its life I thought
it was silly to learn that one dog
taught another dog and that dog taught
another dog and that third dog has no
idea why he's doing it the first dog
probably doesn't either but I was like
that's like people in their Grow rooms
people are just doing [ __ ] because they
saw that dog do it and then that dog did
it and now guess what that dog's gonna
do it too and they don't even know why
so shout out to the dogs they definitely
inspired that portion of the podcast are
you being a silly dog or is there a
reason for you to be doing the crazy
[ __ ] that you're doing in your grow all
right let's do move forward because that
was a fun silly subject I really did
enjoy that one all right now let's jump
into my next topic I was recently at a
friend's grow and they were talking
about how they have switched to amended
soil and they're doing a living organic
amended soil so that they don't have to
feed bottled nutrients they went on to
talk about how their bottled nutrient
required them to do too much work so I
just kept listening and let them kind of
talk they revealed to me that they were
taking each bottle and filling a
container with water and adding the
recommended dosage of that nutrient to
the five gallon bucket mixing it up
pouring that into the plants then they
would take the next bottle that was
recommended and mix that into a five
gallon bucket and pour some of that into
each plant so this person was under the
impression that their base nutrient the
cow mag bottle the booster bottle the
enzyme bottle all had to be mixed
separately into containers of water then
fed to the plants if you were doing that
that is a lot of extra work I hope that
made sense the way I explained it there
are several bottles in your feed regimen
I don't know which company you chose
some people are under the impression
that each of those bottles needs to be
mixed into its own container of water
and fed to the plants that is not the
case let me teach you how I recommend
mixing your bottled nutrients if you do
choose to use bottled nutrients this
will work for reverse osmosis water this
will work for tap water this is just my
basic advice and uh method of how I
recommend you mix your bottled nutrients
I'm going to start with a five gallon
bucket here just a Lowe's bucket a Home
Depot bucket whatever five gallon bucket
you've got that's what I'm going to talk
about using for my starting container so
I've got my five gallon bucket I fill it
about 80 to 90 percent of the way with
water I need some mixing space I don't
want to Spill the [ __ ] everywhere I
leave uh maybe an inch inch and a half
at the top so that I've got some working
room so I fill my bucket with water now
I add my nutrients one nutrient at a
time by the recommended dosage what
you're going to feed it is up to you I
would start off with maybe fifty percent
of the recommended dosage on the bottle
maybe 70 you probably don't need a
hundred percent of what they recommend
you'll really be pushing your plants
that is another podcast we'll talk about
at another time but select your bottles
that you're going to feed understand how
much of each bottle you need to feed now
I'm just going to stay we're gonna we're
gonna start with one bottle measure out
how much you're going to use I'm going
to say 10 mils per 5 gallon container so
you put your 10 milliliters in your
measuring device and you pour that into
the five gallon container now you get
the next bottle and before you pour any
bottle always shake it that's something
that I should mention grab the bottle
shake it measure it Pour it into your
five gallon container now the next
bottle we're gonna you might want to
clean out your your measuring container
that's always a good idea wipe that out
give it a quick wipe with a paper towel
or a rag make that fresh and clean grab
your next bottle Shake It Up let's just
say we're going to do 10 more
milliliters of this product measure out
10 milliliters close your bottle back up
pour that 10 milliliters into the same
five gallon bucket we're going to put
all of our products into the same five
gallon bucket of water I don't know how
much water you need to water your entire
crop or your room or this run or this
light or whatever but mix up the
appropriate amount of water and we can
put all of the nutrients into that water
at one time we don't have to mix up
separate vessels for every product that
is highly unnecessary that is a lot of
extra work I realize now that a couple
of people we're mixing that way so they
were mixing if there was six bottles in
the products lineup they were mixing six
buckets of water and then trying to feed
a little bit of each bucket to each
plant that's a that's a struggle that's
a lot of extra thinking carrying and
mixing working that is a phing that's a
big pain in the ass so get your bucket
fill it with water get your first
nutrient I recommend and this is just a
suggestion or recommendation I recommend
you start with your silicates first get
your silicate bottle shake that [ __ ] up
measure out the amount that you need
pour it into your five gallon container
and stir it counterclockwise that's my
recommendation Stir It counterclockwise
get it a good spin make sure it's nice
and mixed in there then I would use my
base nutrient would be next clean out my
measuring container find my base
nutrient bottle give it a good solid
shake so nothing's at the bottom it's
all mixed up real well measure out the
amount that I need probably somewhere
between 25 and 50 milliliters possibly
100 milliliters if you're using a
Botanical product product pour that into
your five gallon container your
silicates are in there now your base
notes are in there once again give it a
stir give it a good solid stir so that
it's going to keep on stirring so that
when we add our next bottle which I
would recommend at this point will
probably be that bottle of cow mag find
the clean out your measuring container
find your bottle of Cal Mag measure out
the appropriate amount close your bottle
back up pour that into the five gallon
container it's still spinning from when
you stirred it up real hard a minute ago
still spinning so just rely on that spin
keep it going uh then I would add the
boosters then the enzymes and then I
would do the microbes last some people
will tell you to pH your water after you
add your microbes and some people will
say to pH your water before you add
microbes I've had Success With both
methods so get the water stirred up add
your potassium silicate or your silicate
nutrients then your base nutrients then
all of your add-ins your cow mag your
Bloom boosters your enzymes and then I
would recommend probably the microbes
last
um and you can adjust the pH before or
after those microbes let's talk about
that after you've mixed in all of your
nutrients everything you're going to put
in there give it a good mix make sure
everything is mixed in really well Stir
It counterclockwise then when you're
done give it just a couple of good
clockwise stirs to mix everything in
real nice there then we want to adjust
the pH if we need to this is where I
recommend a high quality pH pen I use a
blue lab pen and I calibrate it uh
probably every 10 days I should do it
once a week I hit it about every 10 days
two weeks to be honest with you
calibrate the pH pan then dunk that pH
pin right into your five gallon bucket
of water of your solution is what now
that is and measure the pH of that we
want that pH to be somewhere between 6.2
and 6.5 that is going to be the
acceptable range I like 6.4 myself I
really think 6.4 is a great spot for the
pH the way you're going to change that
if it's too high if you put your pH
meter in there and it says anything
above 6.5 you need a bottle of PH down
and put a couple of drops of pH Down
Stir It and measure that pH again go
slow with the ph up or down products
because it only takes a little tiny bit
to ruin the entire mix you can go too
high or too low very very quickly also
I recommend you wear gloves and eye
protection when you are using the ph up
and or pH Down products also don't mix
those if you put too much ph down in
there I wouldn't recommend putting ph up
in there to fix that only use one of
those products at a time that will cause
that could potentially cause you
problems depending on the nutrients that
you are using so we have filled our
bucket we have put our potassium
silicates in there we stir it put our
base notes give it a stir cow mad give
it a stir every other nutrient maybe
give it a stir between them unless you
can rely on that spin action that you've
created some there are some people
that'll put up a pump in that bucket
just to keep it moving that's a little
excessive if it's a five gallon anything
bigger put a mix bump in there get it
stirring add all your nutrients put your
microbes in there last then let's adjust
the pH get it somewhere between six two
and six five six four is The Sweet Spot
in my opinion I think nutrients really
absorb well at that point then adjust
your pH then something I really find
important write everything down what did
you put in there write down every
product that write down the date the
time every product that you put in how
much of it you put in then write down
the pH the next thing I would recommend
is measuring the EC or the ppms it
doesn't matter to me which one you use
as long as you pick one and stick with
it that's all that matters you can get a
pen that does EC and pH it'll change it
with the push of a button pick one go
with the EC or the PA or the ppms I mean
I apologize for saying the wrong letter
a moment ago lots of letters and
acronyms in my brain pick the EC or the
ppms write that down every time you mix
up a solution write down the ph and the
EC of that solution before you feed it
to your plants document it this may help
you in the future so we've mixed
everything up we have adjusted our pH
we've written down the EC now let's
water our plants
if you've got uh decent sized plants
that are healthy and they've got an
established root Zone within their pot I
recommend Watering your plants till
somewhere between 15 and 25 runoff you
want water coming out of the bottom of
your pots when you get that runoff
coming out of the pots I recommend
collecting some of it and testing the ph
and the EC of that runoff it's real easy
to stick the two pins in that container
and it will show you on the screen the
pH is this the EC is this at this time
don't stress worry or concern yourself
with those numbers until we see a
problem with the plants those numbers do
not matter once we see problems with the
plants we can start looking at the
numbers of what we put in versus the
numbers that came out if the numbers of
the EC is too high the plants aren't
eating if the pH is too low we can just
adjust and make Corrections based on
that but I do not make any changes to
the runoff until I see the plants are
angry if it ain't broke don't fix it
we're just going to use these numbers
for reference if we do have a problem
this is data this is Fail-Safe data for
if there is a problem don't rely too
much on this unless you see issues so
water till you get runoff then collect
some of that water and measure the EC
and the ph and Mark that down like I
said don't worry about the numbers now
but they're there if we need them in the
future so at this point you should have
everything written down every nutrient
that you fed it the amount of that
nutrient the EC and pH the date even
maybe write down the temperature if
that's something that one of your
devices will show you the more data the
better when things go wrong that way if
things go wrong we know where things
went wrong we can have an opportunity to
fix it but also if things go super good
now we can repeat those results next
time you've got a like a chart a map of
exactly what you fed just feed them that
next time and hopefully they'll come out
just as good if not better alright
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to episode
777 of the girl from your heart podcast
I hope you learned something if you have
any questions Corrections comments
concerns you know I would love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart hotmail.com don't be shy send
me a message let me know what you
thought of the show send me that
positive feedback that constructive
criticism or go ahead with the hate mail
if that's what you've got to do uh make
sure you support the show on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart don't miss the Black Friday sale
at iredirect.com anything else you need
will be at
iregenetics.com make sure you check out
the website everything is there the
Discord the merch the seeds it's all
there at
iregenetics.com all right that's all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content I want to give a big shout
out to my buddy Sonic and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
foreign
[Music]