foreign
if you look like a pirate because you
lost an eye to a grow room injury now's
a good time to click subscribe
[Music]
yeah welcome back podcast world I'm your
host my friends call me Rasta Jeff this
is episode
778 of the girl from your heart podcast
in this episode we're going to talk
about different light cycles before we
jump into that part of the show let's do
a few shout outs to a few of my friends
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend Dio let's send a
fist bump and a thank you shout out to
Canada Reaper I want to send a big thank
you shout out to Mobius grows let's send
a fist bump and a thank you shout out to
G7 and Aeron I want to send a big thank
you to Simeon and dreadlock Farmer
Listen to thank you to Noah n and Green
Goblin grows I want to send a high five
and a thank you shout out to my buddy
ADHD grower then let's wrap it all up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to stoned trout bomb
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
podcast on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast I do want
to start off by saying thank you to
everybody who supported the Black Friday
sale that's right if you listen to the
last episode I did mention a Black
Friday sale at iredirect that sale has
been great it will continue for a couple
of days after this episode comes out
there will be Black Friday Cyber Monday
and then it'll just be kind of Stoner
Tuesday and lingering Wednesday then
we'll probably have to wrap up the sale
pretty quickly after that but thank you
for the huge support the sale is still
going on everybody that did purchase
beans from that sale did get freebies
everybody gets freebies every time you
order from iridirect a lot of those
people will get freebies that are tester
seeds they are clearly labeled that they
are tester seeds a lot of them will come
with a plant a pamphlet that tells you
what I hope will happen and what I
expect of those testers see needs it's
not a requirement it's nothing I really
require you to do but it would be cool
if when you get those tester seeds if
you go to my Discord and post some
pictures of the progress post some
pictures to social media of those tester
beans they are a free gift to you but in
return I would love some photography
maybe a grow report so if you did get
those tester beans in the package
without the pamphlet please join the
Discord all the info will be there if
you did get the pamphlet that I recently
got printed it took a while to get that
here because of holiday shipping but
most of the orders did come with a
tester pamphlet if you got testers
please join the Discord and post your
pictures and I guess that is a good way
to segue into talking about my new
method of doing tester seeds I have been
overwhelmed with tester applications a
lot of people want to run tester seeds
for me I appreciate it I enjoy that you
are so enthusiastic about my brand and
that you've got so much trust in my
product that you're willing to run
testers before I've even tried them
we're putting out brand new [ __ ] thank
you for the enthusiasm one of the things
that happens is I select a lot of
testers I send them seeds and only about
maybe 50 or 60 percent of those testers
will actually reply and put pictures and
post pictures of the progress of the
plants on any form of social media it's
like a I make a lot of donations with
brand new seeds is kind of what it feels
like since I was making a lot of
donations with the seeds and people
would fail to continue correspondence
I've decided just to give the testers
away with orders if you're purchasing
seeds from iridirect there's a good
chance you'll get a pack of tester seeds
in that order those are free you've got
some brand new stuff you've got things
that a lot of people do not have you've
got things that are not for sale at this
time if you've got testers you're
getting those because I want those ran
you can run them at your leisure you can
run them now you can run them later but
when you run them just tag me post some
pictures maybe join the Discord that
will help me determine if those seeds
are worth putting out to the general
public I can grow them I know they grow
well for me but what do they do for you
are they successful in your garden are
there any problems is there anything I
should notice anything that may make me
not want to put those seeds out I need a
bunch of people to grow those in the
easiest way is to include them with paid
orders and let people get them as a free
gift as a free thank you in the future I
may add test receipts to the website for
a very low price I've learned that
people respect things they pay for a lot
more than free things so I will get more
communication more correspondence more
feedback if I just give them to you as a
gift with your paid order or if I charge
you just a minimum price for those
tester seeds so we will be changing up
the way we do testers here if you are
testing if you're running test seeds if
you've been involved I still want all of
your feedback all of your reports please
send all of that to the Discord server
join my Discord there's a link in the
show notes in the video description join
the Discord server find the tester Tab
and please post away post weekly grow
reports weekly pictures weekly updates
anything that you think I should know
about that strain that anybody else
growing that strain may want to know
anything that is helpful useful any sort
of advice guidance or tips you can give
if it was amazing or even if you saw
something terrible in a c line that I
gave you as a test or or please report
that I don't just want good feedback
don't worry about the ego this is real
testing we need to know if those seeds
are worth worthy and worthwhile to send
to other Growers if they don't work well
for you let us know so I can consider
holding them back and not putting them
out to the public that is what a
responsible breeder should do so that is
a long Ramble On you're going to get
some testers in your packages and the
testers may appear on the website in the
near future for a small price all I'm
asking for in return is photos and grow
reports you're going to get really low
priced and basically free seeds in
exchange for Quality grow reports and
high quality photos that's all I ask of
so please help me out all right well
let's move forward that felt like that
took a lot longer than it should have
did I mention that every order at I
redirect does get free beans I think I
said that but that is on the notes
wanted to make sure oh one more thing I
should mention I hope everybody had a
happy holiday season I am recording
right after the Thanksgiving holiday I
don't know if you celebrate that but my
family had a great holiday gathering we
had some good food some good time times
shout out to everybody who gathered for
that also after that I was gifted a
piece of medicated pumpkin pie when one
of my friends said that they made
pumpkin pie and they infused it with
ganja you know that I had to take a fat
slice of that I ate that about 40
minutes ago and I can honestly feel it
starting to work now as I'm doing the
intro to the show here I have no idea
how long I've been recording it could
have been 15 minutes or it could have
been three hours at this point I really
do not know but it's going to be a great
podcast because medicated pumpkin pie
all right I've got one more fun thing I
want to ramble about here before we
segue into the main topic of this
podcast I want to give a big shout out
to my friends at Comedy Works and I also
want to give a big shout out to Big Jay
oakerson I took the lovely Zara Miss
dread Vibes Mrs irie as you guys also
call her I got to take her to see big
Jay oakerson at Comedy Works on Saturday
night at the late show and it was a
great time the staff and crew at Comedy
Works treat myself and missed dread
Vibes like we are royalty they treat us
like rockstars it was a great time thank
you guys if anybody from Comedy Works
here's this thank you I always have a
great time at that club it is the best
comedy club on the planet you guys treat
me well you do it right it is always a
good show at Comedy Works you guys go to
Comedy Works free advertising for the
club right there but also a big shout
out to I should also give a big shout
out to Zara on his dread Vibes uh lovely
lovely date for the evening that was a
great time uh she's got dreadlocks I've
got dreadlocks Big Jay oakerson did
about an hour worth of material I think
the first 15 or 20 minutes of that was
just him roasting myself and Miss dread
Vibes Mrs irie Zara whatever you'd like
to call her we got roasted uh he made a
bunch of great jokes about our
dreadlocks about just cliche dreadlock
[ __ ] um that's the second time that I've
seen Big Jay oakerson in the front row
at comedy work so I should mention I was
in the front row thank you to Comedy
Works um I was in the front row for that
show that was the second time that I've
seen big J in the front row and he
actually asked me a couple of the same
questions as he did last time I was
giving him similar answers and hoping it
would trigger some memories but the dude
was so stoned there was no way he was
going to even remember any of that so
big shout out to Comedy Works for
treating myself and Miss dread Vibes
like a rock star big shout out to miss
dread Vibes or Miss Zara for being a
[ __ ] rock star then also of course
big shout out to Big Jay oakerson for
coming to Colorado crushing it throwing
down a good show you guys follow Big Jay
oakerson check out all of his podcasts
uh Legion of skanks the bonfire he's all
over the East Coast the Philly [ __ ] all
right that wraps up the rasta Jeff
portion of the podcast let's move in to
the email portion of this show I've got
a great email here in front of me this
one I don't know if they want their name
set but it goes a lot like this it came
from the patreon patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart it says here
is a good podcast question I agree with
you brother this was a great question it
says I was just thinking about this I'm
growing some stuff from another breeder
and some of the machine in the same tent
you have stated that the machine has a
very strong odor can that odor actually
change the flavor profile of other
strains being grown in a 4x4 tent the
other cultivars have a very different
profile than your machine they are more
fruity smelling that is a really good
question I have mentioned before that
the machine does make gassy chemical
Aromas that are very potent and very
pungent looks like you're growing other
stuff that makes a fruity terp profile a
fruity flavor and Aroma you're more
you're kind of concerned about those
flavors intermingling and Crossing you
don't want that stinky nasty machine to
mess up the fruit candy of the other
thing that you were growing that is
understandable I do not think that
you've got to worry about that during
the grow during the growth cycle I do
not think those Terps are and will
intermingle I don't think they'll
contaminate each other I don't think
that that will be a problem during the
grow phase that's nothing to worry about
the plants are going to produce Terps
the Terps revolatize the plant will
continue to produce terpenes as it grows
now when we shift into the dry and cure
phase at that point you can absolutely
contaminate and cross flavor the things
in the room by having maybe if you put
the machine next to a strawberry
flavored plant some of that chemical
Aroma and some of that strawberry Aroma
that may travel over and that's just the
aroma getting stuck into the dried buds
that's a little bit of a different
phenomenon there so I wouldn't worry
about it so much in the grow but when
it's when it comes to drying and cure it
keep those separate if you can don't put
them in the same container together you
can dry them in the same room in the
same space but when it comes to cure
them and you're sealing them that's when
I would keep them separate that's when
the aroma is going to transfer over and
it's not really uh it's not it's just
the aroma sticking in the other one like
if you've been around weed and it gets
in your shirt that weed smell is going
to stick in the other buds just like the
weed smell sticks in your shirt that is
my theory I don't have absolute science
on that but in my opinion I would not be
worried I've grown 20 different kinds of
plants in the same room in a warehouse
environment we'll run 20 or 30 different
strains in one room the Aromas and
flavors do not mix that way but when it
comes to drying and curing I would keep
them separate when you put them into
containers because that's when your
Aromas and flavors could get a little
muddled be very careful with the drying
and curing process that's where most of
the flavor and Aroma mistakes do occur
I'm not going to say your name but that
was a great question my dude thank you
for the patreon support let's keep it
moving I've got two questions here that
are going to segue us into a nice long
ramble here I'm going to read both of
these messages and then I will kind of
address them this one came from the
patreon and it says yo Ross to Jeff what
episode can I hear more about 18 6 in
late flower I'm very interested in
learning more thanks the answer to that
one is this episode my dude I'm going to
talk about it in just a second there's
another question it says quickish
question do you think plants finish more
quickly in the last two weeks of flour
if you switch to 18 6 or 10 14 that's a
very good question I think you once said
reducing light helps them finish more
quickly but in the most recent show you
said 18 6 helps them finish more quickly
I was surprised to hear this I've done
18-6 Mini many times and it definitely
helps re-vege and maybe more flower
development but faster finish which is
faster thanks again for the great shows
still hoping for more strain reviews
don't worry my dude more strain reviews
are coming but let's jump into this one
for now this is a good case of uh me
having been growing for quite a while
I've grown for a long time now I've been
in commercial environments I've been in
home grows I've been in giant grows and
small grows have been intense I've been
in garages LEDs HPS every kind of
lighting you could imagine one of the
things to notice here is that
um I've changed I've adapted things I'm
doing things differently than I have
before don't be afraid to adjust and
adapt and try new things so let's focus
more on the main part of this question
here this is about light cycles the
first question is talking more about 18
6 in late flour then we hear another
listener mentioned the 10 hours on and
14 hours off let's talk a little bit
about flowering cycles and flowering
times why we do the times we do and what
we're hoping to achieve by altering
these flowering Cycles now most commonly
we are using 12 hours on and 12 hours
off to flower our plants we're doing 12
12. that is equal amount of on as off
time the reason that we are running that
12 12 is because that's what we have
noticed works for most plants this is
what is called the critical period
plants need a certain amount of dark
time to initiate flowering now some
plants that may be 10 hours of Darkness
some plants that may be closer to 13
hours of Darkness but what we have
learned from what we are breeding from
what we have bred for indoor use most of
the plants we are working with flour
very well with a 12 hour on and 12 hour
off cycle so that works very well for
most of the plants now a long time ago a
breeder known as DJ Short came and he
taught us that we can see more
phenotypical expression and more
variation if we adjust our light timer
to give those plants a little bit more
darkness that extra hour of Darkness
we'll show you like I said a moment ago
more phenotypical expression more
variation in your plants sometimes more
Aromas sometimes different Aromas so
there are advantages to running an 11 on
and 13 off cycle that's very similar to
our 10 and 14 which our friend mentioned
here 11 13 10 14 very similar we're
going to get very similar results we're
going to get very similar effects the
plants are going to get more sleeping
time less daytime they'll be able to
express their characteristics a little
bit differently so we've got our basic
1212 cycle that most people run we know
that works that's been tried and true
for most of the plants that we've been
breeding for a few years we've been
breeding indoors with these plants that
works well for the stock we have been
working with we've adjusted our rooms to
work with the plants we've adjusted the
plants to work in our rooms most things
that take longer or shorter than that
have simply been eliminated by breeders
most of the plants are going to work in
12 12. now we've got our 11 13 or 1014
which is going to show you a little bit
more phenotypical expression now the new
thing that I have been working with is I
do 12 hours on and 12 hours off for most
of the flowering cycle just like most of
you guys are doing then at the end of
that cycle when I begin to flush my
plants which is a whole nother
controversial topic which we'll talk
about in the future when I begin to
flush my plants I will put my light
cycle back on 18 hours on and six hours
off now that sounds crazy to a lot of
people a lot of people have given me uh
negative feedback and a lot of criticism
about that but guess what the people
that said I'm crazy and that it's a
[ __ ] up idea have never tried it they
haven't done it because the only
feedback I've gotten from people who do
this is they say my Bud's finished more
quickly and they're more dense thank you
that was a great idea so I'm only
getting negative feedback from people
who refuse to try it the people who have
tried it are liking the idea so why am I
doing this what is my my goal what's my
intention what the [ __ ] was I thinking
light is the main source of energy for
our plants I am mostly making seeds in
most of my runs I discovered that I can
pollinate a plant after that pollination
is successful I can put my light cycle
back on 18 6 and I can use my veg room
as a veg room and I don't have to
continue flowering plants in there to
make those seeds come to full maturation
my seeds will finish under a veg light
those seeds will reach full maturation
under that 18 6 light I'm not trying to
grow flowers here I was trying to make
seeds in this run so I turned my light
cycle back to 18-6 I moved other plants
into that room so that they could veg so
I could have my next flower run ready
and at the same time I let those seeds
harden up under 18 hours on and six off
what I did notice was my buds where the
seeds would be they look like total [ __ ]
but guess what I did not care I was not
growing consumable smokable buds I was
solely focused on seed production so I
turned my lights on to 18 6. I noticed
my seeds were done a lot earlier than
normal these seeds took about 10 to 14
days less time to finish than they
normally did I had more viable seeds I
had a better average of germination I
had thicker fatter better looking seeds
from using the 18 on and six off light
cycle my theory behind this is that
light is the number one source of energy
for my plant if I can feed that plant
more light it will photosynthesize more
it will metabolize more it will make
bigger better faster seeds and that is
exactly what I achieved with that ideal
with that method so I thought since I'm
doing this with my seeds couldn't I
increase my lifetime a little bit in my
flower room and kind of bang them out
make them a little more dense get them
out here a little bit quicker so I
decided to try this when I started
flushing because we all know if we
change the light cycle too early you do
run the risk of re-veging your plants
that will happen if you let them go for
too long with this cycle that is why I
don't do this until I am flushing I know
it's the end and we've got 10 maybe 12
maybe 14 days before I'm going to cut
them there will be no re-veg opportunity
the hormones will not have that much
time to shift over it will not happen
that quickly so what I would do when I
begin to flush I simply adjust my timer
to 18 hours on six hours off and flush
my plants then I pay close attention to
the trichomes this is where it gets
really important when the trichomes are
ready cut down the plants you have to
pay close attention because they're not
going to be ready at the time they were
before they're going to finish sooner
than they did last time
they're also going to be a little bit
more dense there's going to be more
weight to your product so it's going to
be more dense and it's going to be done
earlier why wouldn't you want to do that
in my opinion that is a great thing to
do also if you do want the idea of
re-veging that plant you've already sped
up your re-veging process you're 10 to
14 days ahead of the game of reveging
that plant you can cut down the majority
of the plant leave a couple of thumb
size nuggets and re-vege those you're
already way ahead of the game because
you've been on a re-veg light cycle for
10 days all right so we have covered the
three main light schedules which I would
work with we've got 12 12. we've got 11
13 and we've got 18 6 for the end of
flower now let's talk about why I would
do each of those different Cycles 12 12
that's basic we know it works that's
what most of my commercial rooms run on
when they're in flower 12 12. that's
going to work for almost everything that
we have bread everything that's been
designed to put in an indoor cultivation
facility now let's talk about when I
would use 11 on and 13 off 11 on and 13
off is great like like I've said before
for showing different characteristics of
different phenotypes if I was doing a
pheno hunt of a seed pack I may consider
doing 11 on 13 off in my flowering cycle
because I will see more variation more
specific characteristics of those
phenotypes it allows the plants to
express themselves just a little bit
more that extra hour of sleep lets them
do different things maybe one will get
Fox taily one will get a little bit
fingery maybe one will turn purple you
never know what it may do but I see more
variation so when I'm doing a final hunt
I may do that 11 on and 13 off if I were
running something from DJ Short with the
blueberry in it I may consider that 11
on 13 off Flo responded very well to 11
on 13 off a lot of strains will like
this some strains may not react as well
but the only way to find that out is by
growing The Strain under that light
cycle so I would do the first run when
you grow something I would either do 12
12 or 11 13. so the first time you run a
pack of seeds either do that 12 12 or 11
13 both will be effective but you may
see some differences in that 11 13. I
understand we can't all change our
schedules our rooms that one hour May
mess something up for you that one hour
May throw everything else in your
schedule off you might not be able to
adjust timers I understand that but give
it a run at 12 12 or 11 13 for the first
time that you run a plant let's talk
about 18 6 now I never recommend running
18 hours on and 16 hours off on the
first try that you grow any plant ever
don't do that that's not my advice I
want you to do that the second third
maybe fourth time that you've run this
cultivar don't do it the first try the
first try I always recommend doing that
12 12 or 11 13 so we can see what the
plan expresses then we'll learn the plan
we'll see how long does it take to
flower when should I begin flushing then
once you know when to begin flushing the
next couple of times you run it you can
decide that is when I want to turn that
plan to 18 6. don't do that on the first
run you don't know when to do it so the
12-12 works always commercial grows I'll
probably do 12 12. final hunts I'm gonna
do 11 on 13 off the 18 6 comes in on
that second or third run don't do that
on the first try we need to learn these
plants then I will do the 18 6 and I
will see how the plants respond to that
like I said before some plants love it
some plants will not react well to it at
all plants that naturally grow dense and
they get big dense fat buds they're
going to get more dense fat buds the
buds that get a little bit larfy a
little bit fluffy they will tend to
dense up and get a little bit harder and
pack on a little bit more weight toward
the end if you use that 18 6. another
great advantage of the 18 6 is I think
that they do finish a little bit early
when you run that light cycle they're
just metabolizing more they're
photosynthesizing more they're able to
speed up the process when they do sleep
they go hey I've only got a few hours
let's get some [ __ ] done so they speed
up so that is part of why I recommend
using that 18 6 light cycle not on the
first run we need to find out how long
to flower them on the first couple of
runs then we can play with the modified
light cycle at the end so now let me
back up and actually answer the main
part of the question now that we
understand these uh optional light
cycles
um the main question was which is
quicker 18 6 or 10 14 and again I'm
going to recap and I'm going to go right
back to where I started with all this
and I'm going to say that's probably
strain specific you're going to get
different results from each light cycle
you're going to get sped up results from
both light cycles but it's going to be
plant specific on which works best for
your plants I've never done 11 13 into
18 6. I bet that would be extreme that
extra hour going to the extra hours
would be crazy I've always done 12 12 to
18 6 maybe try 11 13 to 18 6 at the end
to see how that does for you but
um really I'm not sure which light cycle
is faster if you could do the 1014 and
then switch it to 18 6 you're going to
to see huge results there but I have
never done that so it's going to be
plant specific strain specific cultivar
possibly phenotype specific is going to
be my answer for that one
um that message came from our friend
Marco s gwendolus Rye Ry Rocco bro thank
you for the great message I do look
forward to the reply because you always
do follow up with more great questions I
look forward to it ladies and gentlemen
the email address of course is
growfromyourheart hotmail.com don't be
shy if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
send me that positive feedback that
constructive criticism don't be shy once
again grow from your heart at
hotmail.com I think that is all I've got
for you for this episode like I said
before please support the show on
patreon at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart make sure you check
out the Discord of course there's a link
to the Discord and the show notes and
the video description don't forget about
that sale at iredirect everybody who
orders packs we'll get some freebies
possibly get some testers some
unreleased [ __ ] that nobody else has
ever seen seen before anything else you
might need will be at my website
irygenetics.com give it a click tune in
check out what we got going on over
there my voice is burning out I need a
drink I need a dab that pumpkin pie is
kicking in ladies and gentlemen thanks
for hanging out for another episode of
The Grow from your heart podcast I'll be
back next week with fresh new content I
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
JH and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you