[Music]
yeah oh my God that was the best thank
you do the rest keep going
dude I don't listen to you don't know
the the intro I'll be honest with you oh
man I come on and then it's hard listen
to the rest cuz you're a grower I'm
going at oh I see hey uh all you guys
that are uh Growers and stuff my it's
Clint I'm back this is going to be a
crazy episode I can already tell guys
it's time for 78 of the grow from your
heart podcast yes yeah 78 uh we're going
to skip the intro because Clint already
crashed the whole [ __ ] party and I
like it damn straight you said we might
have one mishap at the start and I was
like it's going to be a good mishap then
I'm going to make it
100% you wouldn't believe how many false
starts I had on this podcast when I'm
recording by myself it seems like I have
a really hard time busting out the intro
when I'm alone but when there are people
here it flows out like nothing yeah like
this time you did a real good job I did
thanks you didn't skip a single
word man you got everything you wanted
to say out I should have just turned
your microphone down and just kept you
down until I introduced you but uh I
just kept yelling sure I just got even
louder so ladies and gentlemen welcome
to the show joining me today is my
friend Clint uh he's a local comedian at
least that's what he claims to be you've
already seen his skills yeah
it's fun dude uh Clint is an amateur pot
smoker uh he usually takes two Puffs of
Sour Diesel and today he took three did
I we we have it's still undecided cuz I
can't remember if I took two or three uh
I hope he took three because you were
[ __ ] higher than usual yeah dude it's
super fun nice you okay you going to be
good no dude now we're here right now
with all these people this is [ __ ]
awesome all these people um you mean all
the people that are listening right you
don't think there are more people here
do you well it's just the ones behind
all right you guys you can already tell
what kind of episode this is going to be
I do need to send a huge thank you shout
out to cat and cot from the Mystic Roots
Manan they let me play their music on
the show I really appreciate that that's
really super cool uh I don't have any
advertising to do at the start of this
show I already [ __ ] it up anyway no no
dude you don't [ __ ] anything up I like
it when you're here you break up the
monotony you make it explosively fun you
make it
entertaining you good sorry Paul texted
me and I accidentally looked at it
I wouldn't normally I missed all that I
missed everything you said I'm a jerk uh
Clint Scott will we've been referring to
as goldfish brain [ __ ] yeah about every
30 seconds Clint resets so uh welcome to
the grow from your heart podcast yeah
there you go see he's back at the
beginning again so guys the first thing
that Clint and I want to do is review
the Doug Benson album on 420 Doug Benson
came to Denver Colorado and he recorded
uh he did three shows and recorded all
three of them for uh his new comedy
album which was called uh promotional
tool and it came out uh just a couple
few days ago here I think came out on
the 5th I think it was the ninth but
you're high so it's okay oh yeah it was
5'9 not 95 that's cool we you'll be all
right eventually God I hope this is
funny this is funny if this is just me
just being a [ __ ] dick and your and
your fans have to listen to it oh I feel
so bad I'm having fun so hopefully they
will too do you get a uh a certain
percentage or do you know anybody in
peblo listening uh a lot of our peblo
friends listen yeah uh actually I found
out that uh Drew listens and that uh
well Dustin's listening Joe listens Joe
and his new uh Joe and is a friend that
I just met I want to call him Kevin Joe
and Kevin listen I did not know that
those guys listen so shout out to Joe
and Kevin that I recently saw on baca's
couch Baka listens yeah we get a lot of
local listeners weing Arie listen so
Mark has been listening shout out to
Mark he's finally paying attention so
let's uh let's make this like a real big
deal you know what I mean like what if
this podcast became like a real big deal
just in PUO you know just like when a
comedian would come down or when a band
had come through it'd be cool for them
to like man it'd be cool to go do uh get
a little bit too high with roster Jeff
you know like like it's the morning
radio show before uh before the show
kind of but like more so like it's a get
for you
it's it it' almost be like that it'd be
great to have that radio show idea so
what you're saying is that since the
wild cousins are presenting a comedy
show with a man by the name of of Sam
Talent the funniest man I've ever seen
on July 23rd 2015 at the Rainbow Bar are
you saying that maybe we should have Sam
Talent come be on the podcast and be a
little bit funny and we could talk to
him about his cannabis experience maybe
he's got a funny weed story is that what
you're thinking we could do I you know
what let me ask him I I will ask him all
right and I would love for that to
happen all right well you got to come
too because I don't know the guy all
right guys so in the future Clint is
going to try to get a comedian by the
name of Sam Talent on the show here and
then he's going to do a show at the
Rainbow Bar July 23rd 2015 uh it is a
free show but donations are encouraged
check it out if you're listening to this
show show up pay $5 because that's what
I feel you should do the show will be
worth $5 pay $5 don't go be a cheap ass
it's a free show you'll look like a pimp
if you throw down five for the free show
I think you should do it for sure dude
all right that's a that's a fun show
that's got my buddy Paul Rosales and my
other buddy John Bueno on that show and
that is uh my little comedy crew called
The Wild cousins shout out to the wild
cousins appreciate it bro I was wearing
my wild cousin shirt yesterday and
people like to give me the weirdest
looks I love it dude the shirt has a
kitty cat shooting an assault rifle and
definitely I'm a 6' five dude with
dreadlocks and people look at me with
great confusion it's just such a weird
shirt I don't know I love it we got a
whole bunch of them and we just like
have never tried to sell them it's so
fun that we just gave up on them
immediately I am uh thinking about
getting grow from your heart podcast
t-shirts made here eventually I'd Rock
one of those man hopefully by episode
100 I'll be able to give a a couple of
them away you should talk to Barrett
shout out to Barrett yes shout out to
Barrett is that last Leaf does he work
last Leaf I think is uh mo mo right okay
yes I thought they were together they
not Mo's not doing shirts though Mo does
like I think unless Barrett bought up
Mo's [ __ ] and they just call it the same
thing all right so this just got real
local what's up guys we're going to go
back to talking about funny weed [ __ ] so
we went and saw Doug Benson yes on 420
we saw Doug Benson he did three shows at
The Comedy Works shout out to Comedy
Works that's my favorite comedy club on
the planet really quickly I always shout
out to Baker Baker was watching my
Periscope broadcast last night and
having a conversation with me and I was
slightly honored uh I like that guy dude
Baker's a good dude he came out and
shook my hand the other day I recognized
him and I waved at him and he recognized
me probably because I'm [ __ ]
ridiculous looking it's the tall thing
it's the tall thing yeah but he go I go
hey Baker thanks man and he uh that was
after the show cool cuz we had actually
moved pretty fast I'm I'm getting rambly
again that's all right you're nice super
high dude
guys this is great because I've never
seen Clint this high and he's almost
uncomfortably high and I can see him
like resituate himself every few minutes
so it's great and that's going to lead
into something that we're going to talk
about in a little bit here too if we
have time because Clint keeps uh talking
a lot so uh I feel like you're uh four
episodes
later yes uh I was going to make a
reference and then I forgot the dude's
name so we won't even do it it feels
like you are
um Pete holming me that's what's
happening here I'm being Pete Holmes if
you ever watch any of Doug Benson's
podcast Pete Holmes will love to just
interrupt and drag on
and yes you're you're Pete holsing me so
uh we're going to do a little on 420
Doug came and did those comedy shows
right at Comedy Works uh Clint and I and
a couple other people had the honor of
going to the third show that night um
which may have been a mistake I and
we've talked about that on the podcast
before yes yes we did so we downloaded
the CD on the day that it came out and
we listened to it and um so the fun part
that I noticed right away is he used the
opening from the show we attended for
sure he did uh yeah cuz he talks about
how he was trying to get too high oh
dude well yeah that that was definit and
it's not like you could have done that
twice no but even even later in the
album you can hear him and he's not that
high right and it's just like oh man I
wish I'd have went to those other shows
there were a couple of pieces that I'm
certain came uh from our show and then I
know that some I'm like oh he did not do
that at our show cuz he sounds awake but
one of my favorite parts of the entire
album is that on track one there are
multiple times when I can hear Clint
over laughing uh Clint is like a dick oh
no it's great dude because it's genuine
but your laugh you're such a big dude
and your laugh is so low that it just
shakes the entire Comedy Club when you
laugh and we're in the front row in that
little pit area and there's a lot of
sound right there and dude you were
coming through on the mic so well and
you can just hear Clint like ha
it's so [ __ ] funny hearing your buddy
laugh on a comedy album that's pretty
cool it was great now the the shitty
thing is the com Comedy album not that
funny you know what Doug's my friend you
know what sucks I might have been the
funniest thing on that
album the funniest thing please don't
tell Doug Benson I I think ball weed
might be the funniest thing on that
album God he would hate me he might but
you know you're being honest uh no I
just didn't think it was that good we
went and saw that show and that I had a
just against it already though you know
what I mean because I was already a
little mad at him so the first track is
25 minutes of Doug reading tweets on his
Comedy album like I know that's it's
what he does in his live show but he's
just riffing off of them yeah if I was
going to do a comedy album if I were a
comedian I would put together I would
Joe Rogan that [ __ ] I would put
together the tightest one hour that I
could comp and it might take you two
years to do it but you're real happy to
do it like that exactly yeah uh [ __ ] man
so the first album is 25 minutes of him
reading tweets the or the first track
the second track is called watch this
not that where he plays a game that he
normally plays on his podcast for free
for free and it felt like I paid $5 to
download a podcast basically because I
listen to his podcast frequently and it
didn't feel any better than that that
son of a [ __ ] turned 50 on us and all
of a sudden he became a money hungry
[ __ ] capitalist he doesn't even smoke
we this is all a a ruse oh no he is he
doesn't smoke nope
um all right so anyway about this
album yeah the album like I was saying
the first track is reading tweets the
second track is uh talking about
something that he normally does on his
podcast then he actually tells a joke
and then he tells a couple more jokes
and then he promotes his other podcasts
and then he promotes another podcast and
then he promotes his other podcast and
then he talks about traveling and then
he actually does a really good joke it's
not a well put together album and that
sucks because Doug's one of my favorite
people he's my friend I called Doug my
friend he knows who I am you know we
contact each other and to see one of
your friends put something out like that
it's almost like oh man you could have
you could have done a little harder on
that most comedy albums the comedian
will start with a decent story and then
tell you a couple jokes and then by the
time you forgotten about that first
story he'll tell you another part that
reminds you of that that refers to that
to make you laugh Doug has already
forgotten the first part of his act by
the time he's 20 minutes in he can't do
a call back that's what I'm doing right
now
we got Clint too high today Clint got
himself too high sorry guys that's all
right this podcast sucks uh out of if
you could give uh Doug Benson's album
the podcast doesn't suck bro we're going
to we're going to make it Rock if you
could give Doug Benson's album up to
five pot leaves one a scale of one to
five pot leaves how many leaves you
going to give him he's going to get one
pot leaf he's going to get one pot leaf
so I'll give him two uh maybe two and a
half or three but it definitely was not
a four or five star performance yeah
he's your friend and I think you're
being generous
I think I'm being mean too but there's
just so
many there's so
much to do out there now like I could
download anything yeah and if that's
that that album right there is my only
introduction to Dun Doug
Benson that's the only thing I know of
him other than his podcast yeah so I am
the perfect demographic to go dude like
I'm not a cult follower so I wouldn't
I'm I'm mad that I bought this I'm mad
that I went to that show a little bit
yeah those 25 bucks that you spent on
disappointing being disappointed twice
now yeah okay I could have done that
with a
hooker huh yeah that's why you're
disappointed you're paying $25 on a
hooker D dude that's got to be the
problem I am not getting any in you need
to upgrade J you're $25 hookers man
that's your problem all right so we're
going to move on from Doug hey Doug
sorry I had to bash your album dude uh
sorry man you got to you got to put it
together more like I still like you yeah
yeah I still love you bro I'm going to
come to your show on the 5th of July
I'll see you there at The Comedy Works
in Denver I've already got tickets I'm
not sure that Clint wants to go yeah I'm
not going but uh I got something else I
could take but I'll be there Doug don't
worry I just wasn't uh I like the way
that uh PS put together a comedy album I
like the way Ari put together a comedy
album it's got more uh uh continuity is
the word I'm looking for it flows a
little bit better yeah just and I I'd
prefer that out of a comedy album did
you watch that Bill Burr album you know
I did did see that one uh the black and
white one what's it called uh [ __ ] I
don't remember now but that was that was
great yeah that's what I expect out of a
comedy album that's a little bit better
that's that's hard to be like all right
well here's here's this guy who's
perfect at this like that's Bill bir of
me he's perfect at it he's he works so
hard at it and it's so exciting to watch
somebody be perfect at something Anthony
jelnick is damn near perfect at see it's
just I think that jelnick
has his
routine but Bill Burr could just go off
on anything okay it's [ __ ] lovely
it's so beautiful to watch and so most
of those bits that he has he's kind of
half improvising as he's telling the
joke he knows how long and what beats he
wants to hit but it's not like that
regimented I say it like this jezl neck
kind of way yeah and jezel neck is kind
of a robot in that that well you've said
it plenty of times like he counts yeah
counts I can see his throat moving when
he counts yeah I can see him say the
word 11 yeah yeah but that's that's what
I'm saying is like he uh Bill ber can go
in there and do his routine and then
break away and do some dance moves and
then go back to the routine yeah and I
love that about a comedian poops has
that ability as well oh he's so [ __ ]
smart Jesus well when we were talking to
him when he smacked you that day about
that story it was just so much fun just
he was just being in the room with him
was fun yeah he's got that Storyteller
personality they need to get uh Greg PRS
on this is not happening that would be
[ __ ] awesome that' be fun dude yeah
season 3 or two is coming out pretty
soon all right we're way off topic we're
rambly but that's all right Clint's
coming back around I could feel him
connecting a little more yeah the uh the
goldfish in his brain is not swimming in
such short circles the laps have gotten
larger I got Tweety Birds now going
around my head he upgraded the squirrel
that runs on the cage will be back
pretty soon yeah all right give him a
smoke Breck somebody sent me
[Music]
in [ __ ] dude see you're getting almost
funny that was
pretty no it was good I I almost tried
to talk over it then I was like we got
to give him credit for that
one somebody sent me a Facebook message
and it was uh a good question for Clint
because they said uh how much should I
be smoking oh yeah one one yeah today
Clint should have only taken one yeah it
seems like it that's I can't that's the
beauty of cannabis if you're using
medical marijuana the beauty of it is
that it's up to you that's why you have
chosen to medicate yourself with medical
marijuana because some doctor isn't
saying take two of these every so often
it's up to you to figure out how many
puffs off of this bowl or how much of
this joint I need to smoke to ease my
medical condition and then you want to
you're going to have to I guess if
you've never smoked light up a joint and
take two
Puffs and then see how that does if
that's way too much next time only take
one if that didn't do it take three next
time make a smaller joint yeah roll a
smaller joint and don't get as high but
it's hard for me to tell you how much
you should be smoking because we I just
watch Clint take three hits off of a
bowl of some pretty high grade Sour
Diesel and he is high and Jeff took two
I took two and then two [ __ ] dabs and
I'm about to take another dab like
[ __ ] dabs well I know dab dabs are my
friend Clint says dabs are drugs drugs
and I could see why he says that but
it's all about what you need are you
smoking to medicate yourself uh are if
you're smoking to prevent seizures uh
smoke as much as you want smoke all day
like there well it's it's it really just
smoke until you're comfortable yeah as
long as you're smoking isn't hindering
your ability to be a productive person
as long as it's not causing you a
financial problem a health problem a
mental problem a motivational problem a
relationship problem for sure uh if as
long as you're not using it as a crutch
as long as it's not an anchor or
something negative as long as it's not
causing a problem is my point here smoke
as much as you feel comfortable with I
don't recommend every day trying to see
how high you can get you don't need to
be Joey Diaz and try to see the [ __ ]
devil every day I don't know why people
want to do that but try it once you know
why not I didn't just push the limit
nope okay and if you don't want well
that's the thing because I'm comfortable
you kind of are pushing the that third
one was your limit you're kind of
pushing it now okay that was okay yeah
pushing the limit but not like going to
see the devil though no no yeah don't
get crosseyed and don't take seven dabs
your first try see that's what I get
that's that [ __ ] peer pressure is a
[ __ ] though you know what I mean
like not at our age but I remember like
when we were like 16 18 I'd have done
anything anything yeah like if you
wanted I for you to think I was cool I'd
have done anything i' have stabbed
[ __ ] especially if I was going
to get laid at the end oh dude if I
could get laid at I didn't get laid till
I was 18 and because I was just a late
bloomer but I'm just a skinny [ __ ]
white kid that's just it's okay I you
made up for it I'm doing okay now yeah
but it's just it's weird to see that
[ __ ] goldfish reset yep here he goes
new thought process for Clint want to go
for a bike ride buddy thanks buddy he
gets that 0d I did lose it buddy sorry
no wor I got your back I'm the host I'm
paying attention no edits I'm leaving
all that I'm leaving all your Rambles in
today you get to deal with this that's
your punishment you get to listen back
to yourself I'm into that I will too and
I'll be like H that guy's pretty cool
yeah he's whoever whoever was on the
show that day was [ __ ] great yeah so
like Clint maybe only the devil that's
what it go to see the devil yeah don't
do that every day but do it once in a
while if you need to if if you want to
see what's on the other side of that
wall take another dab or take another
puff off the bowl and see what happens
I'm going to take a puff off of this
dabri right here I'm smoking some Girl
Scout cookies uh made by the turpack
crew I picked it up at Green and healthy
wellness in Colorado Springs uh shout
out to the grimy Gatsby shout out to
damsel Hello beautiful and also shout
out to John randles Jr John randles junr
I'm going to take a dab but we need to
get Clint started on some sort of rant
before I do it all right what's on your
brain here he goes one two we do a uh we
do an open mic every Thursday at the
Rainbow Bar and I think I've told
everybody about this plenty of times and
uh we uh we have a lot of fun it's just
a comedy open mic and you know Jeff's
come down a couple of times I I got
friends that come down and it's real fun
and we don't charge anybody it's free
you guys yeah so it's uh I mean you can
buy alcohol if you want you can just
come in and sit around like I don't
drink I don't drink they don't ask me to
buy anything they don't expect anything
of you if you don't drink they're they
if you're there for the comedy you might
have brought somebody that was able to
drink that's all they like we're trying
to bring business into the rainbow and
get people in front of us that's the
tradeoff they have the building for us
to do it and they make plenty of money
the regulars are there at the bar
drinking and then you guys are bringing
in the other group and that are buying
drinks yeah but I'm just asking people
to start coming out please do please
come out I'm there occasionally I can't
commit to being there every night
because I a busy man I do a podcast I
grow I don't want anybody there every
week either dude like if you're if
you're not there to tell jokes every
week don't come out every week that
would suck well I see all of your
rehearsal material and then get bored of
you if I come every week it might dude
like but if you came out once every 3
months oh no I'm I try to go every not
you or twice a month is my goal once or
twice a month I'm not even asking that
do you know what I mean like I'm just
wanting once every 3 months out of just
one of my friends you know then and you
hear the sadness in his voice you guys
he n it just sucks cuz like last night
we went to go on it's uh we we were
going to do it last night today's
Thursday but we were going to do one
last night and no one showed up and it
[ __ ] broke my heart dude it's just we
get all everything all set up to go
bartender sitting there you know 10:00
comes around and nobody's there that's a
bummer I [ __ ] yeah I've been in bands
for several years and I've played to the
bartender for several shows and it's
yeah it's almost practice you know so we
didn't even [ __ ] do anything because
we're just like nah dude I don't I don't
want to [ __ ] do this yeah I don't
want to perform to Paul yeah and then I
just realized I'm just like uh this
[ __ ] weird old guy that's like
hanging out in bars not even drinking
not even drinking but not even drinking
smoking weed in the back of [ __ ] bars
all right so come out to the open mic
night you guys because if you don't uh
they might uh not let us keep doing it
yeah that's that's a real thing like uh
we're the only publo open Mike and uh
it's it's going to go away so we can't
even get like other stuff going on cuz
we can't get anybody to this one so
support local comedy guys because if you
don't support things they go away and
then one day you'll be like hey remember
that comedy group let's go there and
then it won't even [ __ ] exist because
you blew it off for too long so support
the local comedy uh as to how much you
should be smoking I'm done taking my dab
now so I can rant about that uh smoke
until you're comfortably High uh I have
there have been days and this sound you
guys are going to think I'm crazy there
have been days when I've smoked a gram
or two by myself like started a fresh
gram when I woke up got done with it
started another gram and finished that
one by myself through that throughout a
course of a day and you would think
those are days when I'm sitting around
not doing [ __ ] but those are actually
the days when I'm doing the most yeah I
don't know how I do it but I'll stop and
take four or five fat dabs and go right
back to work work for an hour or two
take four or five more dabs go right
back to work uh yeah cuz you're busy and
you got your mind going so like the high
doesn't stick around as much well at
least like you're using it though you
know how at the end of the day your back
hurts and you're all sore if you've been
doing work I don't get that because I've
been dabbing all day like my body
doesn't even my muscles stay loose and
relaxed I'm like I guess it's like going
and taking an a you know instead of
taking a leave or Tylenol or prickle
whatevers I'm just taking a few dabs and
keeping the pain away all the time for
sure and it kind of the dabs make my
head uh I talk about I prefer Indica
flower and sativa dabs dabs make my head
go really fast I take the Alpha Brain
take two dabs and drink a little bit of
caffeine and bro I can work for 12 hours
straight without a break [ __ ] let's just
go quit picking at your skin I don't
know what that was that was weird cuz
you started saying I can work for like
12 hours State and then you started
picking at your skin I said Jeff what
else are you doing in them dabs brother
so I ate a doughnut earlier and
apparently part of the frosting was
stuck to my arm hair and when I pulled
on it it really hurt oh my God you're
such a wuss well you pull on your arm
hair bro pull some of that [ __ ] out yeah
it's not a thing you're cooler than
me anyway I'm just so high couldn't feel
my arm like P had a donut frosting
dingleberry in my arm hair I like I like
that I like dut frosting dingleberry in
my arm hair because no just I just like
the dut frosting dingleberry I like that
I don't know why all I hope that you uh
consider that for the name of this uh
episode nobody will listen if we do that
I warned them I warned them immediately
when they were coming on if they're
still with us yeah you guys are soldiers
now let Soldier on what else do we got
all right so holy crap uh guys don't
smoke as much as Clint did but smoke as
much as I did and that's that's funny
because that's a good example I have
probably consumed uh since Clint's been
here five dabs I'm going to guess F four
or five Dabs at least since Clint's been
here four two Puffs off of that bowl and
of course I've been smoking throughout
the day you know it's 7:00 almost so
I've probably had 12 dabs by now today
oh and I smoked uh nothing all day today
and Clint is ruined I'm not going to let
Clint drive for at least another hour oh
for sure and uh I could pass any
sobriety test that you needed me to
right now yeah yeah like I'm not even
being a smartass I am going to burp but
I really could pass almost any sobriety
test you offered me at this point yeah
yeah it's all about your body chemistry
uh where you're used to being where
you're trying to be with how long your
dreadlocks are your dreadlocks are now
it's funny dude cuz I've seen some
people with dreads trying to be cool and
they can't keep up at all they think
that because they got the dreads they're
going to be able to party with me like
take a half gr Dad let's see who you are
you got to carry him to the couch yeah
all right somebody as me pull him by his
dread drag him by the dreads right to
the couch drag them out in the front
yard the spr somebody also sent me a
message about trim machines they said
how do you feel about trim machines uh
honestly you're going to think I'm a
prick but [ __ ] a trim machine a trim
machine ruins your trim uh it chops up
it makes a Messier buds uh high-grade
topshelf cannabis is hand trimmed uh
trim machines don't have fingers or eyes
they don't care they don't put in love
uh they mangle the buds I think if
you've got a nice bud and you run it
through a trim machine it's not going to
take off all the leaf in one spot and it
will take off some of the bud in some
spot and this is from experience I've
helped other people use trim machines we
use the spin Pro I've seen the uh the
Grim or the trim Reaper I've seen the
tsunami thing I don't like the way any
of them work also what it does is it
turns your trim into a mulch it chops it
up into this really funky Mulch and then
it almost creates too many Cuts so that
the moisture seeps out of the leave the
leaves or the trim in a weird way and it
doesn't it'll it'll mold up there's
almost no way to prevent that [ __ ] from
turning moldy so I like to hand trim
that way you can separate the big leaves
from the good trim and you can know what
you're making hash with and nobody's
gonna trim it like a person like uh at
the dispensaries they've got a whole
crew of trimmers that hand trim
everything and they don't go as quickly
as a trimmer but I think it's well worth
it you can see the difference uh it's a
whole bunch of like 22 to 28 year old
people that just want to trim all day
they're eager to get into the Cannabis
business and they just want to trim so
they just kickass all day in hopes of
getting promoted to a bud tender or a
grower and that's who does the trimming
uh I'd rather have those six or eight
people sitting around trimming all day
every day than two trim machines running
honestly yeah so uh [ __ ] auto trimmer
[ __ ] a trim machine trim it by hand yeah
use some scissors use your eyes I don't
want to trim I got [ __ ] carpal tunnel
dude I've got carpal tunnel I got thumb
calluses I got four finger cuses uh I
got wrist sores just from trimming I
just from my Xbox just from my Xbox
probably trimmed 100 pounds of weed I
don't know more than 100 pounds of weed
in my life I'm pretty sure I've trimmed
more than 100 pounds by myself um so
there was a second half to that question
that somebody emailed to me uh the
second half of that question is kind of
lengthy and I'm going to have to do some
research and give you a more thought out
answer for that I did not prepare enough
time for that answer it's a really good
question and I will get back to you I'm
not blowing it off that's just I want to
be accurate in a little more in depth
for you because that is a hell of a good
question uh let's see hey you know what
would be fun what's up hey if you uh if
you put out the call or like if maybe
somebody uh like that listens has a
friend that has like a really great weed
story from like the 70s do you know what
I mean like like one of those like we
had to get away from the cops kind of
things like and and how how how great it
is now so you want me to get some chongs
on kind of all right that'd be I don't
know I know a guy uh I'm actually his
medical marijuana provider and he's an
old cat he loves to tell me stories bro
and you know what I had him on the
podcast one time on 719 the blocks and I
remember that when we put on the
headphones on him and put the microphone
in front of him something lit up inside
of him
and his voice turned into like this and
he got all spectacular and charismatic
and at the end of the show I was like
dude have you done this before and he
goes I did College radio man and there's
nothing [ __ ] like it bro I was like
yeah he this is College radio isn't it
it kind of is yeah it's it's our it's
digital College radio now this is weird
and then we got our like cult little
followers and [ __ ] we listen and I and
I'm sure it's not for me but I mean
that's I'm here so suck it uh every
guest even though you're a dick every
guest that comes on uh brings their own
audience like you'll you'll retweet my
tweet that you're on here and then when
I tweet that hey tall Clint was on the
show I don't know maybe one of your
three Twitter followers yeah I don't got
a lot you know but maybe if you have 10
maybe two of them will check out the
show and one of them will probably like
it yeah so we'll get another listener
and maybe we can bring Sam Talent on and
then uh and both cross paths CU I really
want everybody to hear Sam Talent he's
really funny yeah we'll get him on the
invite him dude he'll be on the show
we'll come down pry we'll record 30
minutes and we'll put it out as one of
those Thursday episodes that's cool man
uh thank you guys for listening dude I
want to thank you guys all we were just
talking about our fans and our little
cult following and it really inspired me
to say thank you because I haven't said
that enough lately I've been caught up
in putting out a show and keeping the
guest entertained and keeping the flow
happening to haven't uh sincerely said
holy [ __ ] thank you guys we get so many
downloads so many listens uh the website
traffic I had to pay for more bandwidth
on my website because you guys are
killing it downloading episodes damn bro
uh the traffic on the website is
exploding uh it's going nuts we had to
fix uh the file type that I upload so
that it's more available for Stitcher uh
because people were downloading it so
much that it was slowing down the
stitcher application on their phone oh
[ __ ] so I change the file the type the
type of file that I upload it's a little
smaller it doesn't sound as good but
nobody's probably going to notice it's
just a voice podcast it's not like we're
putting out freaking dance music or
anything so but yeah people are
listening and I really really appreciate
it it's if you've told a friend like we
really appreciate that too yeah you know
I told Drew and uh Dustin about this
because I was like no this I was really
funny on this thing I thought I was
really funny back like jeez I've been on
this thing like eight times or something
probably time yeah we're [ __ ] this is
my favorite this is the [ __ ] nice the
one that you crashed the [ __ ] intro
to no no no this this just doing this
podcast is fun this is great man you
look comfortable you finally got your
head bobbing look you're loving it now I
feel good man no I just uh it is nice
but it's nice to tell one friend and
then they tell one friend and and then
they tell one friend that's all I'm
asking is tell your friend about uh Sam
Talent tell your friends about uh no
wait tell about the podcast yeah not Sam
Talent the podcast no Sam talent's
coming down to do the podcast it's going
to be aesome I got to get people out to
that show man it's so [ __ ] it's so
ridiculous cl's life is on the line if
you guys don't go to the show his life
is going to fall apart I'm just kidding
not really it'll just suck all right so
uh let's see do I have any more notes
that I want to talk about on today's
episode I think we can almost uh if you
want to [ __ ] ramble on about
something for a couple of minutes man
what's your uh how long how long have we
done now we've gone 33 minutes but I
imagine that 1 to 3 minutes will be
taken out so we got about 30 minutes of
usable material here Jesus there was a
there was a depressing part in there too
I hope that does not make the podcast
Jesus I'll make you look dignified
before this comes out that'd be really
funny if like just during that part you
go Clint wants you to come out to your
to the to the show and like you just
edit that in just just a bunch of
mumbles and then yeah please come to the
show please come to clch show uh I will
apologize for this air conditioner
that's making a whole bunch of damn
noise over my shoulder I'm going to try
to take that out of the recording but I
can hear it just going in my head and
it's driving the producer in me
absolutely Bonkers that's [ __ ] rad
dude that's good I'm glad you got such a
talent for this well thanks my friend
thanks for dude uh yeah I've been doing
this is my 78th episode on this show and
then I did about 50 on another show so
I've had a little bit of practice and uh
I think I finally got it figured out
that's cool man took a minute but thanks
for noticing and the uh the improvements
that I've done a lot of people have
actually said that they've gone back and
listened from episode number one up to
whatever the current episode is yeah and
part of me makes my hang my makes me
hang my head in shame like oh you heard
episodes one through five where I was
like not sure what I was doing at all
and then but then I'm like oh but that
means you also heard 75 where I knew
everything that I was doing by now like
I don't know everything about a podcast
but I feel like I can come on here and
do a show now I don't before it would
take me 3 hours worth of getting stuff
together and being nervous and three
different takes of putting a show
together and now I'm just like what up
Podcast time let's kill it see that's
[ __ ] cool man that's neat then and
I'll bet those people that have listened
to all of them like feel like they know
you pretty well uh and it's fun Meeting
those people cuz some people come out of
nowhere and they're like dude you're
roster they'll hear my voice at the grow
store somebody was like you're that guy
on the podcast and I was like yeah man
how'd you know they like I could
recognize your voice and I was like
that's [ __ ] awesome good to meet you
and I hang out with those guys I go to
their house and take dabs and [ __ ] yeah
no but that that's kind of what I'm
saying is if you if you listen [ __ ]
let us know dude we're just human it's
yeah it's I'm all over Colorado dude I
travel all over Colorado and I'll hang
out and take dabs with you I'm not
afraid I'm not worried if you're
listening to the show you're good people
I am I am not taking dabs with anybody
come on Clint they're all heathens Clint
will come with me and he'll not take
dabs and he'll sit there not take dabs
stare at you judgmentally that's right I
will I'll be like your dad you'll be
looking at me like God damn it I wish
that we hadn't brought Jeff's dad in you
some some dark glasses bro you can just
be my security guard that's security I
just need a mustache just a mustache
just a
mustache I got the hair for the 70s so I
think I could plan that you know I
wasn't going to mention your feathered
70s hair what's with that bro are you
filming porn when you leave here yeah I
got a couple of things going um since
we're way way off topic what would be
your porn name anyway uh Peter Frampton
I don't I don't think that's available
screen this screen name is not available
that'd be [ __ ] fun though an
[Music]
[Laughter]
underscore oh I like that yeah and spell
the word underscore N I was thinking
about it and I was like no CU then
that's a pain in the ass and then you
can't get the Twitter handle because
it's too long yeah okay you're right
Peter Frampton uncore oh Do You Feel
Like I Do all right I do what I can I
like [ __ ] Peter Frampton though that
would be great I bet it sells some porns
too maybe and then the next one on Brett
Michaels comes alive oh God yeah see see
you got it we got it all right we're
winning we're going to wrap up this show
here really soon it's almost 710 in
Colorado oh [ __ ] yeah big shout out to
the wild cousins big shout out to Clint
for coming on the show and getting way
too high I appreciate that that's fun
yeah so that was the uh answer to your
question is just don't get too high and
do a podcast yeah don't be recorded
while you're super high because you may
say some [ __ ] that you regret and to
regret any of hopefully your friend is
the producer and he'll take all of it
out for you I don't think I'm going to
regret anything we're all right I didn't
say anything stupid you're good hey I've
been doing this thing called Periscope
Periscope is an app that you can get on
your phone either your iPhone or your
Android device uh just go download
Periscope and then what you could do is
uh follow me I'm at rosta Jeff 420 on
Periscope uh occasionally more than
occasionally at least once maybe twice a
day I jump on Periscope and I will do a
live video uh where I sit here in the
recording area it does drugs I do drugs
I take big fat dabs sometimes take my
morning dabs or my afternoon dabs
whatever the first puff session of the
day is I'll get on Periscope take a few
dabs with you guys uh talk a little bit
of wisdom drop some knowledge on you
guys I'll answer a few questions if you
type it in the question box and once I
get good at recording the show setting
the phone here in front of the computer
getting on Periscope and forgetting that
Periscope is going uh and still paying
attention to the chat in Periscope I
will start doing a live show on
Periscope as I record
so you guys that are on Periscope with
me will be able to ask me questions live
and I'll be able to read them on the
screen I will read the question loud
into the microphone and i' be like so
tall Clint says how come you don't ever
brush your hair and then I'll answer the
question dude I hear that so much on
Periscope it's there's a lot of trolls
oh I'm troll proof dude I should have
not just said that on the podcast
because now they want to challenge my
Troll game I am troll proof on Periscope
it's my page I know I'm dirty I know I
got dreadlocks whatever you're not gonna
[ __ ] make me cry it's interet well
the thing is nobody's ever said anything
original anymore that's the truth I mean
that's that's I'm always like oh heard
that heard that that's that's tough
about comedy too CU there's a lot of
jokes that have been done that's why you
know we're just trying to do new stuff
that's all it is but troll proof is
[ __ ] awesome troll proof that should
I should make a screen name or something
that's troll proof cuz I feel like I'm
troll proof I'm a grown ass man I'm not
I'm quite secure with myself uh do troll
prooof on the Periscope right now just
type it in as the thing and then have
everybody just say mean things at you
that'd be a lot of fun not on the show
though yeah we'll do that right after
look for
us this is stupid yeah make sure you
guys check me out on Periscope once in a
while though because I come on late at
night early in the morning random times
just take fat dabs I'm on a really weird
schedule being employed and
self-employed uh and being a producer of
a show my hours are really random I go
to bed around 400 in the morning and get
up around like somewhere between 99 and
10 sometimes 11: if I'm lucky uh the sun
comes up and I just start getting up and
doing [ __ ] man it's the way it's got to
be done yeah you got to hustle quite
often I'm up by 9:00 cuz some of the
grow lights come on at 9: [ __ ] sometimes
I got to be at the spot by 8 [ __ ] I got
to get a [ __ ] job man Jesus yeah this
[ __ ] sucks yeah Clint had a a great
comedy set one day Clint got uh he got
relieved of his position as it at his
spot of employment and then we drove up
and watched him do comedy and that
comedy set was quite awkward yeah I'm
for sure I felt like I was the wife that
was about to get beat because you were
the husband that lost his job I was
pretty mad that day I could tell but we
were doing everything we could to put
you in a better head n you guys did good
you look like you're in a much better
space than like 40 minutes ago yeah no
we're just
uh no everybody's all in this all
together man everything's happening for
a reason that's what I believe that's
the damn truth you guys all right we're
going to wrap up this show we've been
rambling for sorry guys we warned you
immediately I warned you immediately too
he did he didn't warn me is the problem
he G you all got the warning at the same
time Jeff got the frontt to this one cuz
you guys had the opportunity to not
listen to this and I'm going to edit
some of this out so oh he's going to
have to listen to this again twice twice
because I'll listen to it as I edit it
and then when it's complete I'll give it
one full complete listen through just to
make sure it's yeah it doesn't sound
[ __ ] or I didn't do any hard PS or
anything like that I don't even fix the
hard PS and s's I think the software
does most of that for me really that's
pretty cool I bought good [ __ ] I'm no no
I'm just saying that's cool did you get
in help yeah yeah yeah well I got this
piece over here I got this piece over
here I got my daughter call me so oh you
want me to turn down your mic yeah cool
here you go all right guys oh wait was
that him no yeah cool I'm gonna wrap up
the show Clint's got to step away for a
second perfect timing um I got to find
the paper all right uh you guys now the
show's over go to iTunes uh search for
the grow from your heart podcast find
the review section give me a f star
rating after that type in a comment let
me know what you think of the show and I
will read your comment on a future
episode uh you can leave a comment on
Stitcher if you'd like but it's really
hard to find the comments I will go and
look but Stitcher is really weird so um
find me on all the social media sites
please I'm on Facebook it's at grow or
it's grow from heart podcast I'm on
Twitter it's uh gfyh podcast or it's
just gfyh no it's gfyh podcast I'm sorry
uh follow iy genetics on Instagram don't
forget that the show is available on
iTunes Stitcher and every single episode
is archived on IR gentics color.com
Clint has jumped back on the microphone
is everything cool brother yeah
everything's great it's just when when
your daughter calls you you answer I
totally understand I've got one myself
I've been bragging about her birthday on
the past couple episodes and if she
called right now we would talk to her
yeah yeah no that's what that's that's
the thing I got NY old that's what dads
do bro that's what we're supposed to do
answer when the girl calls yeah I
appreciate all your fans and everything
but that's the one thing that's going to
stop oh for sure yeah not many things
that we stopped recording for but the
the daughters yeah yeah is that great
we're actually good people too he's a
[ __ ] dirty hippie I'm a foul mouth
sailor of a like person I don't know
what's what was the analogy I was going
for there a comedian oh that guy's a
dick um but but the little ones first
bro cuz that's yeah we need to make this
can you edit out all the [ __ ] [ __ ] no I
back in the day I did what was called
the uh the dollar [ __ ] jar and the money
got donated to somebody actually the
money is sitting somewhere and that dude
has not contacted me so he doesn't
listen to the show anymore so my fault
but uh speaking of money there's a
donation button on the podcast page uh
if you go to the website it's IR gentics
colorado.com click on the grow from your
heart podcast tab at the top right
there's a donation button little PayPal
logo that goes directly to my Paypal
account guys I'm not begging you I'm
just letting you know it's there the
podcast is always going to be free this
comes to you from me as a gift because I
love you I love cannabis I want you to
grow better cannabis I want to break the
stigma and fears associated with
cannabis um I want to help out the plant
I want to free the plant so uh this is
all free but if you do feel like making
a contribution I would love it I'd give
you a shout out on the show I'd say
thank you uh just go to the website
click on the PayPal thing throw in
however much you feel like you'd like to
I'm not begging but it's there uh like I
said run all the social media sites um
Clint thanks for coming dude that was
fun dude it was a lot of fun dude I'll
bet your fans [ __ ] hate me now oh no
they're only going to get like 30
minutes of your ear bashing so it'll be
okay that was
brutal you guys thanks for tolerating
Clint I promise he won't be on the next
episode we won't have him back for a few
episodes we will get Spence here pretty
soon I'm trying to get a few other new
people on the show I've got a lot of
news lined up for the next episode
there's already stuff in the works I'm
trying to get shirts made by episode 100
there's a lot of stuff going on yeah all
right so uh shout out to my ninja Spence
until next time thanks again for
listening take a fat dab give your mom a
hug for
me lately busy and I haven't had a lot
to say yo T get the mic that's all right
not today but I like to write it night
and pick apart my brain just to see if
any little piece of art remains it's
hard to change cuz I'm getting used to
routine these days are all the same
wearing like my blue jeans I got a few
sches but I ain't made a rich sometimes
my mood swings sometimes I hate the
[ __ ] too many Lost Dreams none of my
plans met 26 and I don't feel like a man
yet I can't sweat it all the time cuz it
makes me sink sometimes I hate to think
it's just another page of a still scared
to fly sitting in my bird's nest never
dead to try but the sky is where you're
h best I deserve less I never thought
I'd say it but too many people in my
life have bought and paid it often
waited for a hand out to come to me
thought I had my plans now mapped out
comfortably getting older now that isn't
who I want to be looking in the mirror
I'm unaware of what's in front of me I
got a ton to see and I ain't getting
younger deciding not to jump was my
biggest blunder I sit and wonder about
what could have been and instead of
jealous hate these days I say good for
him [ __ ] [ __ ] you cuz all of that stuff
is worthless your [ __ ]
tell me what's the
purpose 100s now y are we're working
above the surface right cuz all of that
stuff is worthless and if your [ __ ]
ain't tight then tell me what's the
purpose me and T use one in 100 verses
if y'all are underground we're working
above the surface everything I see keeps
changing afraid of the day life sweeps
me away with it my old friends seem like
strangers I'm cold and alone but I think
I'm okay with it my mind says no don't
give in on a solo mission to be so
different I make mistakes but I don't go
fix it bounce from place to place like
I'm po sck started when I was a little
kid I don't know when it'll stop maybe
never cuz change is forever evolution of
man so it makes me better executing my
plans until my plate sees cheddar not a
mainstream rapper just an AC Setter
that's a crazy cracker with amazing
effort and though I know it' be nice to
be Filthy Rich and have 26 kids with a
Milky ch
I uned exclusive
sh a million and having children right
now it have me fing stuff 4 a.m. FS out
to W by I'm still out to get CL about to
spill out correct sounds a beat makers
with buildups to let down and even
though I know I speak intelligent I
still think this [ __ ] is my weakest
element I'm mostly known as that
graffiti felon kid and every MC knows
that my Beats are H I Get Buck Wild off
I can chew gum while I'm walking shoot
guns while coughing mom I know you're
worrying but don't I'm baring your
garden to me a PO yeah I don't like
police to this malevolent machine of shy
Beast hit that Bull's ey blindfolded
quite focused on the r like yeast theast
is my I'm devoted to being loaded or at
least noticed noted this whole scene's
vus every track I collab my my 16 doest
even my weakest piece of [ __ ] is so sick
I should go and name this song I'm on my
own dick hit me on my phone if you want
your p g r yeah standard fees apply
can't read or WR raps try these
[Music]
forze