[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
781 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to talk a
little bit about selecting male plants
for breeding we might touch on selecting
plants for reversals before we get to
that part of the show let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with the big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to Growing Old Man style let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to Guido's grow room and all mixed
up let's send a big old thank you shout
out to Growing Tennessee and f a plant
count I want to send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to roll this nug and
Randy Farms let's end up big thank you
shout out to Mid Michigan micro grow I
want to send a big thank you shout out
to Captain Luke de carb let's send a
thank you shout out to curbside Gardens
then let's wrap it all up with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to
babybot716. Big thanks and big shout out
to everybody who continues to support
the show on patreon if you are not
already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and of course there is a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast ladies
and gentlemen the I redirect holiday
sale is live on iredirect.com if you're
looking for packs and looking for deals
now is the time to hit iredirect.com
that sale will go through the end of the
year of course if you are a contributor
on patreon you did get a coupon code and
of course if you're signed up to the
newsletter you also got a coupon code in
a mail champ news letter so now is the
time ladies and gentlemen hit up
ireedirect.com blow that website for the
end of the year inventory reduction sale
clean out my office clean up the stash
get some good beans while they're still
available all right I don't want to
ramble too much here at the top of the
podcast I do want to talk about
selecting male plants for breeding we
may also touch a little bit about on
selecting plants for reversals which is
when I take a female plant treat it with
a solution that does make it make pollen
that pollen of course only makes female
seeds we may touch a little bit about on
how I select a plant for that let's jump
right into it how do I select plants for
breeding let's talk about breeding one
thing I'm going to say a lot here is
have a goal when it comes to breathing
if you don't have a goal when it comes
to breeding you're just pollen chugging
you wouldn't go into the kitchen without
some sort of goal and just pour a bunch
of [ __ ] in a bowl and mix it up and hope
that it tastes good that's kind of the
same thing if you just put plants in a
room and just throw plants in there and
let them do the thing you have no goal
no idea no path that's just Paul and
Chuck and they're doing the same thing
with the plants you may make some good
[ __ ] but also who knows you may not make
some good [ __ ] put some thought into it
have a strategy have a plan have a goal
write down that goal if you don't have a
clear Target how do you know if you're
hitting that Target if I'm saying I want
to hit that dot right there on the wall
with the ball and I throw the ball I
know I hit it if I throw the ball and it
goes way over there I know I need to
adjust and come this way then I can hit
my goal do the same thing with your
breeding project write down a goal write
down a Target see how close you get be
real with yourself and then adjust from
there so the first thing I'm going to
recommend in any any breeding project in
almost any project in life and anything
you're working on before you get started
have a goal and a desired outcome and
know what you're getting into the next
thing I'm going to talk about
understanding when it comes to breeding
is learn about Mendel charts understand
what Gregor Mendel was trying to teach
us there's a lot of good information in
Mendel charts all you have to do is
Google Mendel chart or Gregor Mendel a
lot of info will come up we may do an
episode here on this podcast but there
are plenty of videos about Mendel charts
out there Mendel charts will help you
far in your breeding they will help you
predict the outcome of your breeding
projects they'll help you see if you're
going to reproduce something that's
already been done they'll help you
isolate traits you're looking for when
it comes to line breeding in the future
Mendel charts will definitely help you
predict the outcome and anticipate
outcomes of your breeding projects
you'll have to learn about dominant and
recessive traits you'll learn about
co-dominant traits you will learn a lot
through Mendel charts and through the
practice of breeding will all make sense
once you put it into practice
so learn about Mendel charts learn about
dominant co-dominant and recessive
traits understand alleles and how
alleles are expressed and passed through
plants then learn which alleles you are
looking for in your breeding project by
this point you've got a good
understanding of what you want to create
and how to go about creating it one
thing I want to touch on is select your
plants by plant appearance and plant
traits don't select your plants based on
names we are not breeding names just
because two plants have cool names and
if you put those two names together you
get an even cooler name that does not
mean that those plants need to be bred
with we're not breeding names we're not
breeding for social media pictures we
are breeding biological material which
has to work well in a breeding project
with good results so Focus your breeding
more on the things you see from the
plants the things you observe and enjoy
more than the hype and the name and
things like that then you will have much
better success in your breeding project
so learn about Mendel charts understand
what Gregor Mendel was teaching us then
learn about dominant and co-dominant and
recessive traits learn about how those
traits are passed from plant to plant
understand as much as you can
biologically about these plants which we
are going to breed with then here's
another huge piece of advice once you
understand the Mendel charts the traits
the dominant the co-dominant the
recessive traits how these things meld
together when we are breeding once you
understand that forget all of that and
breed with love breed with passion and
grow from your heart once you understand
all of this stuff you'll be able to look
at two plants and go oh you and you I
should breed you two together because
you've got these traits and you've got
these traits and I see magic you'll
learn it you'll start to feel it I
understand a lot about music I
understand I can count time I can read
and write music I understand polyrhythms
compound time I can play with the band
very well I know a lot about music when
I get on stage I do not think about any
of my musical education I play with
Groove I play with funk I play with my
my heart I make sure that I'm matching
up with the bass player I'm making sure
that I'm using Dynamics when people are
singing I don't think about counting
time I know all of that stuff is in me
because I've got a solid education about
music when it comes time to perform my
intuition and my heart take over and I
can do it instinctually if you build a
solid education with these plants and a
solid education about breeding you'll be
able to grow and breed the same way
you'll just look at plants and you'll
know you'll feel it they'll tell you if
you listen the plants are already
telling you everything you need to know
so learn about those mental charts learn
about your co-dominant learn about your
dominant recessive traits learn about
how pollen works there's a lot of things
to read about pollen then once you
understand that stuff write down a goal
then just breed with love and grow from
your heart let's talk a little bit more
in depth about actually selecting a male
plant to pollinate these ladies with I
generally like to start with a male
plant that is way different than the
targeted female plants which I like to
pollinate so my example would be let's
just go with my main taking of a rise a
rise is a Golden Goat female plant
pollinated by a daybreaker male plant
that cross was such a huge success that
I chose a male from that to base much of
my sea lion on for the future that is my
King Solomon male he came from that
batch of seeds let's talk about why I
chose to breed those together
the Golden Goat is what we like to call
a sativa dominant looking plant I know
the terminology and the words are
changing every day in this industry but
we used to call that a sativa plant it's
got longer skinnier leaves when you
smoke it you get like a crazy head Buzz
that makes you kind of psychedelic and
freaked out a little bit it grows taller
it grows skinnier the daybreaker was the
complete opposite it put out giant wide
long droopy leaves you could build a
carport with these leaves you could
cover the entire house with just a
couple of these leaves and build a shade
canopy it also grew a little bit
stretchy kind of lanky the complete
opposite of the Golden Goat which would
get tall but it would keep tighter inner
node spaces and more uh more of a
compact structure where that daybreaker
would get a little lanky a little bit
stretchy have some more space in the
nodes more like that OG Kush sort of a
thing so when I bread them together
there was a lot of room in the middle
there for them to meet then I also could
see what the daybreaker male was doing
to the female so I like to use a male
plant that is way different from my
female plants that way I've got Opera
opportunity to make new [ __ ] one way to
describe it is if I'm trying to make new
stuff I wouldn't pour chocolate and more
chocolate in a bowl because guess what
I'm gonna get chocolate I'm gonna put
some chocolate maybe some banana in
there and get some chocolate banana
maybe put chocolate and strawberry in
the other and get some strawberry banana
chocolate do things like that get
creative so I want to do things that are
way different not two plants that are
super similar in genetic variety now
let's focus in on some of these specific
traits that I do look for in a male plan
things that are really important to me
are plant shape and size and structure
what is this plant shaped like keep this
in mind when you're picking a male plant
that is going to be 50 percent of the
outcome of your Offspring so do you want
these uh your seeds do you want them to
make tall skinny plants short squat
plants do you want short inner node
spacing do you want longer node spacing
do you want plants that Branch out real
far do you want plants that stay in kind
of skinny do you want them to grow real
tall or stay kind of squat you can kind
of set yourself up for this by selecting
a male plant that has these traits that
you are looking for this is when you
start making those decisions so plant
shape plant structure plant size plant
sturdiness are the branches of your meal
plan nice and sturdy or are they all
weak and wispy and shitty because if you
breed with that weak wispy shitty mail
guess what you're going to have the
opportunity for weak wispy shitty
Offspring so keep that in mind something
I think about is amount of branching
does it make a lot of lateral branching
does it keep going straight up how does
this plant Branch once the branches come
out do they make more branches do those
branches make a lot of shoots is that
the structure I'm looking for that is
something I keep in mind When selecting
a male plant I mentioned this a moment
ago internode spacing so you've got your
main stock coming up the middle of the
plant you got branches coming off of
there how far apart are those main
branches coming off the stock that is
internodal spacing sometimes they'll be
a half inch apart sometimes they'll be
four or five inches apart if you're
getting some older tropical [ __ ] maybe
some golden goat crosses they'll be
really close together the Jack the
Ripper stuff might be close together
some of the OG Kush crosses the
presidential Kush there's going to be
some space between there what do you
need if you're growing in a place with
high humidity you may want some more
space in there so you don't get big
chunky buds to get a lot of room for
humidity if you're in a tropical place
that might help you out if you're in a
colder drier area you might be able to
handle bigger nugs with more density
they're not going to get the humidity in
there it's all about what you're
breeding for what your goal is how much
inner node spacing do you want also
flower clusters are very important when
it comes to selecting a male plant look
at that big flower cluster to get one
big top do you get a bunch of flowers
everywhere that's going to show you what
your meal plan what your Offspring is
going to do let's talk about Leaf shape
Leaf shape is a big indicator of things
in my opinion Leaf shape is kind of how
I decide how long a plant is going to
take to flower for the first time that I
run it if it's got big wide broad leaves
you know it's not going to take you more
than 70 days most of the time if it's
got those long skinny tropic leaves
that's probably a 70 77 day maybe even
more on the flowering side of the plant
scale so leave shape what size of leaves
are you looking for do you like those
long skinny leaves do you like big fat
leaves what kind of product are you
looking for this is going to play
heavily this Leaf shape and size is
going to transfer into your Offspring
then what about amount of leaves I don't
like too many leaves on my plants I
don't want to trim all day every day but
I need enough leaves for production and
photosynthesis so amount of leaves if
that male plant is just banging out tons
of tons of leaf and not a lot of bud
structure not a lot of flour cluster not
building strong stems and not being even
with its energy distribution I may not
choose that male plant to go into my
garden if it's super duper leafy I don't
want to spend a bunch of energy on
leaves and trimming a bunch of leaves in
my flour product let's talk about
something super important flower time
how long did it take for that male plant
to start giving you submit sufficient
amounts of pollen how long does it take
for that male plant to flower out and
make make a big giant fat male cluster
let your male plants go I let mine go
for like eight or nine weeks maybe 10
weeks the first time I run them to see
what they're going to give me so keep an
eye on that flowering time how long
until they started giving you pollen how
long does that male plant continue to
give you pollen then how big did that
main top get how big do those side buds
get pay attention to the flowering time
and how long it does continue to flower
also while it's flowering pay attention
to how tall it gets does it have a big
stretch time did it do anything crazy
during that flowering phase note that
because that is going to correlate to
your Offspring now here's when we get
into some of the fun more obvious parts
are there any colors flavors Aromas or
visual appearances or other senses that
you can use to detect obvious things
does it smell good does it smell bad I
like a male plant this is a weird thing
that I'm gonna share with you a weird
piece of advice I like a male plant that
if I give it a stem rub if it kind of
smells like vomit or bar trash can
that's a keeper that plant is going to
be very good for breeding in my opinion
I really do like that so look for things
like colors Aromas flavors most people
don't smoke the males there is one old
school breeder out there who will shake
the pollen off dry them and smoke them I
don't do that if you want to do that
that is up to you you're a better man
than me
another thing we definitely need to pay
attention to is problems and resistance
to problems in the grow how does this
male plant react to overfeeding how does
it react to underfeeding If These plants
are little [ __ ] guess what you're
going to breed little [ __ ] plants we
want plants that can handle a little bit
of abuse we're going to put these plants
in Grow rooms where things may go wrong
so we don't want a hundred percent [ __ ]
plants we need some kind of robust
resistant plants so how do they handle
handle over feed how do they handle
under feed how do they handle over or
underwater can they take a little bit of
a drought can they get drowned a little
bit I make seeds for commercial uh for
commercial production and for retail
sales so if those seeds can't take some
abuse some of my retail customers May
murder the seeds and I wouldn't have a
good successful company so I've got to
breed with things that can take a little
bit of abuse how about resistance to
pathogens did you get any powdery mildew
in that grow did you have any bud rot
how did those male plants deal with with
that how about bugs did you get any
spider mites in there did you get thrips
or fungus gnats did those bugs go
towards your male plant if those bugs
and pathogens did Go Near That male
plant how did that plant take it we want
to breed with plants that can handle
problems very well because like I keep
saying that is going to pass into your
Offspring all right we've talked about
the traits I'm looking for now let's
talk more specifically about how to find
these male plants which we are looking
for for breeding of course the starting
point is to pop some seeds however many
seeds you've got however many you can
run I don't know the legalities in your
area I don't know how much space you've
got but grow as many seeds as you can as
my recommendation I like to run at least
one maybe two or three packs of seeds to
find a male plant if you've only got one
you will find a keeper in there I always
say that you will find a keeper in every
10 pack of my seeds which means you will
also find a good meal in there but of
course the more numbers you've got the
merrier the more opportunity to find
that outlier that amazing stud mail
that's how I found King Solomon anyway
step one is to get some seeds and
germinate them get them growing then
identify the males and the females
obviously is going to be our next step
if you want to run the females in
another room do that that's a whole
other conversation that's another
podcast in this episode we're going to
focus on the boys so we've germinated
some seeds we've identified the boys and
girls we're gonna move the boys to
another room and that's what we're going
to focus on for now before we get too
far let me recommend that if you do want
to repeat this process I recommend
getting clones from these plants as soon
as you can and before we go into flower
it is a little bit more challenging to
re-vege a male plant than it is a female
plant in my opinion in my experience it
is harder to re-vege the boys than it is
the girls so I would recommend you get
clones before we do go into flower with
these male plants so at this point we
have separated our males and females
we've gotten clones now we're going to
put these plants into flower
when it comes to selecting a male plant
I generally do not choose the male plant
that shows flour very first as a
breeding candidate sometimes so let's
say let me start with 10 seeds let's say
I started with 10 seeds a lot of you are
going to start with 10. we'll germinate
10 seeds out of those 10 we're going to
find probably five males five females
that's usually the way nature Works
about 50 50 sometimes you're going to
see 60 40. let's work with what we get
we're going to pull the females aside
let's say at this point we've got
approximately five male seedlings to
work with here I'm gonna put them into
if I'm gonna get clones like I mentioned
then I'm going to put them into flour
once they're into flour they're going to
begin to show me the sex from those five
I will not choose the first or probably
even the second plant to show me that it
is a male for my breeding male the
reason behind this is I find that that
male is probably usually most commonly
going to dominate my crosses of
everything that I make so what I'm
saying is let's just say that that meal
is chocolate like I used earlier I use
chocolate as an example if I use that
chocolate everything I pollinate with
that chocolate is going to be dominantly
chocolate even if I cross it too like I
said earlier strawberries bananas uh
whatever else I cross it to it's going
to kind of be more chocolate with a
little bananas more chocolate with a
little strawberries so I choose not to
use those first couple of males that
show me that they're male because
they're just going to dominate The Cross
it's going to be too much of them I
don't want to just make copies of this
male plant I want to make 50 50 crosses
or somewhere near there and that's not
going to do it so usually the first one
or two plants that show me their males
are not the candidates which I choose
for breeding it's also usually not the
last one it's usually the third or
fourth male to show me that it is male
that I choose for the breeding project
here's a hint also early in flower most
of the plants that are male are going to
show you their boys because they'll
stretch up above everybody else they'll
be the taller plants those males try to
get taller so they could drop the pollen
down on the ladies which are down below
them so pay attention to that that may
give you a little bit of heads up
something to look for all right so I
don't choose that first guy to start
showing pollen to start shooting his
load probably not the second guy it's
usually the third or the fourth plant
that starts making pollen and my reason
is because I don't want that super
dominant male that early flower with all
that testosterone all that male stuff
going on I don't need that going into
the cross so I generally choose that
third or fourth male it's usually not
the fifth one out of a pack of ten it's
usually not the fifth it's honestly
generally the third or fourth I'll
choose the one with the shape the
structure uh the pollen time the one
that is closest to the traits I'm
looking for between number three and
four that'll be the one that I choose so
let's say we've made our selection
you've got to choose now this is where
it comes time for you to make that
decision this is the plan you're going
to choose for your braiding project use
your education use my advice use your
intuition and choose that male plant
that looks the best the only thing
that's going to go wrong if you choose
the wrong one is you're gonna have to go
back and breathe again it's not a huge
mistake it's not a huge problem it's fun
we get to do it again if especially if
it's your first time you get to see what
you made if it's awesome [ __ ] awesome
if it's not awesome it's still going to
be great it just may not be [ __ ]
amazing you made a bunch of seeds you
get to grow and have fun with and you
learned a lot then you get to go and do
it again but now the pressure's on now
it is time for you to select that male
plant do you want number three do you
want number four make your decision now
it's time for the fun part now we put
the plants in the room we time it
perfectly so that those plants can give
and receive pollen and then we can make
seeds it's easy to time up those plants
the first time you put the mail you put
the female in the room on the same day
you put them into flour and you watch a
lot of times I'll put the mail in the
flower room a little bit before the
females sometimes I'll stagger the
females into the rooms at different
times you will have to figure out when
your male plant produces the most pollen
and when your female plants are ready to
receive that pollen when those pistols
are big and ripe looking like dandelions
that's when they want the pollen so the
first time you do the cross you can just
put them in there at the same time it
will work then pay attention when does
the pollen happen when does pink
ripeness happen then you can adjust your
schedule accordingly for future runs the
first run you'll get plenty of seeds
doing it just the natural way so get
your mail plant get your selected female
plants put them in the room and let the
pollen happen some people will put that
male plant in front of a fan let that
fan blow it around honestly that male
plant is going to pop open those flowers
and the pollen is going to go moving
around naturally I've also seen people
cut the top off and just shake that top
around and pollinate everything however
you choose to do it get that pollen all
throughout that room pollinate those
females
then it's really important to let those
seeds finish you can run my suggested
light cycle of 18 on and six hours off
or you can do 12 12 that is up to you
both of those will work the most
important part is let the seeds finish
then carefully Harvest those seeds get
them out of your plants that is a whole
other podcast episode I think I've done
that episode before now here comes the
fun part we get to grow out these seeds
before we grow these let's talk a little
bit about why I like to pollinate
multiple female plants with one male
plant and a breeding run the reason I do
this is because now I can see what that
male plant has contributed to the
breeding project to multiple different
females so if I did let's just go back
to my old chocolate analogy let's say
I've read chocolate to Banana I bread
chocolate to strawberry and just for fun
we'll say that I've read chocolate to
key lime now if I just bread it to one I
could get an idea of what is happening
in my project I could say this one came
out a lot of the chocolate traits and
some of the strawberry treats maybe it's
got the Leaf shape of the chocolate and
the tallness of the strawberry and 50 50
chocolate and strawberry Flavor now I
only have an idea of what the chocolate
plant is passing it's passing that leaf
structure or whatever I attributed to
the chocolate I know it's doing that but
is that an anomaly is that what's going
to happen commonly is that just one time
is that a recessive or a dominant trait
so what I want to do is check with other
female plants and see what traits so I
did uh strawberry right I said banana
when I did the chocolate to Banana what
was common with that strawberry cross
when I grew up the seeds from the
strawberry and the banana cross what do
I see which is common do I see things
coming from the male plant like Leaf
shape are there commonalities in the
leaf shape commonalities in structure
I know what the female plants look like
when we flower them now I need to take
those traits identify the trait that
came from the female identified the
trait that came from the male and learn
what that male is passing it's easier to
do if I pollinate multiple females so
now I put it to Strawberry put it to
Banana let's see what happens when I
crossed it to the key lime pie how much
of the key lime am I tasting am I seeing
that big leaf shape am I seeing the
skinny leaves where are the
commonalities if in all of those crosses
I get like this weird diesel fuel Aroma
that I didn't know about that's probably
coming from the chocolate if they all
have different flavors that's coming
from the mother plant probably that
flavor trait didn't get past so that's
how we learn what the male plant is
going to do in our crosses is by hitting
multiple females with it growing out
those seeds taking notes and observing
traits and then attributing oh those
traits go to the male plant those traits
go to the female plants and then find
the commonalities in those traits and
that's probably what the male plant is
delivering to that mix now here's
something that's really going to throw
you off you're going to see [ __ ] that
isn't in the male plant or the female
plan those are going to be traits that
came from the grandparents so maybe that
male plant didn't show you that it had
something going on in it maybe it didn't
show you that it'll put out red leaves
at week seven maybe you didn't know that
maybe that came from the purple Thai
plant that it was his mom or something
so the mom of the male plant put out red
plant two weeks or red leaves at week
seven we didn't know that we didn't see
that in the male plant but now it popped
up in The Offspring so that was a
recessive trait that we didn't find
until we bred they came from a
grandparent you're going to see things
like that in your breeding projects so I
like to know if I'm using plant a and
plant B I like to know the parents of
plant a and plant B uh and even further
sometimes I like to know their parents
so you're doing like four and then two
and then one on the family tree I like
to know that much info uh that'll help
me identify recessive traits dominant
co-dominant traits helps me a little bit
with my predictions in my mental charts
uh just helps me to know and then also
helps me not do do too much in breeding
and double crossing over Crossing back
Crossing on accident which I do on
purpose sometimes but I don't want to do
it too much on accident because like I
said before I have the best success when
things are more different if you cross
OG to OG you just get [ __ ] OG if you
cross
um not OG let's see something way
different I'm just going to say
strawberries to lemons you could really
tell you get strawberry lemons you could
tell those different flavors together if
you put gas and Candy together you could
tell candy gas if you put gas and gas
together we can just make more gas it's
hard to tell what you're making all
right let me keep going here because I
do want to touch on how that is
basically how I select a male plant for
breeding it's got to have specific
traits which I am looking for for the
breeding project it's got to have the
leaf shape the leaf size structure
flavor Aroma bug resistance pathogen
resistance it's got to have all of that
stuff it's got to make the right amount
of pollen at the right time uh probably
not the first or second male to show me
that it is the mail in the bunch and
then the only way to verify that is to
pollinate pollinate multiple plants then
grow those seeds out see what you have
created look for those traits that come
from the male plant like I've said then
attribute those to the male plant and
then that's how you know what that male
plant is contributing to your breeding
project that's how I select a male that
is exactly how I do it there's no magic
or no Voodoo I use uh intention and I
have a goal and I use my intuition and
my education to find a male that I think
will reach my goal again the most
important part is a goal now I do want
to touch on how I select a female plant
that I do want to reverse to create
pollen to use for a feminized seed run
it's very similar to the way that I
select a male plant for breeding the
plant has to be what I call a perfect
tan I don't know in your criteria what
plant is a perfect tan it's got to have
flavor Aroma Buzz the right effects if
it's a medicinal effect or a
recreational effect it's got to have the
effects I'm after it's got to have the
right height the right shape the right
structure the right flowering time then
some of the more important stuff that we
overlook
it's got to have pest resistance I don't
need to plant it waves hey hey to spider
mites I need a plant that goes hey
spider mites [ __ ] off there's some
plants the spider mites won't even go
near I like those plants breed with
those bad [ __ ] I like plants that are
mold resistant I've been sending seeds
and plants all over the country lately
and I'm starting to learn very well what
plants do work well in certain parts of
our country so plants that are mold
resistant are very sought after for
breeding descending those seeds to the
each coast of the north east coast the
northwest coast both of them need very
mold resistant plants so find something
that is mold resistant if it's powdery
mildew if it's Bud rot any of the molds
out there find a plant that does not get
that [ __ ] when you put it in that
environment find plants that are drought
resistant find plants that can be over
water a plant that can be drowned a
little bit plants that can take abuse
and stress plants it can take popping
twisting lollipopping defoliating it
needs to be able to take all of the [ __ ]
that I'm gonna throw at it when it comes
to reversing a plant I needed to be a
perfect 10 and I needed to have all the
traits that I'm looking for in a male
plant and even more it's got to be even
better than a meal plan because the
females I can grow them I can smoke them
I can turn them into concentrates I can
smoke them as flowers I can see what I'm
working with so I already know what
they're going to look like in the female
form so they have got to be super
Stellar let's talk about some examples
super Stellar plants that were tens
Golden Goat that's why I chose to
reverse Golden Goat that plant is a
perfect 10. it grows well it's got a
Killer Buzz it tastes amazing and if you
get a if you get it going strong and you
take care of it that plant thrives you
almost can't mess it up you could pee in
it you could kick it over you can over
feed it under feed it you could give it
a drought you could give it too much
water you can overheat it you can freeze
it golden goats Just Gonna Keep on
growing and produce badass flowers for
you so Golden Goat is a perfect 10 in my
opinion another one that I found to be a
perfect 10 and somebody else agreed with
me I've talked about why I reversed this
one the blueberry cookies that made the
turtle line was a perfect is a perfect
tan that plant tastes good it grows well
it's got a Killer Buzz to it it doesn't
get problems it grows with huge vigor
like I said before you could piss in it
and it will still keep on growing so
that's why I chose the blueberry cookies
and my third example of the Grateful Dog
The Grateful Dog is a perfect [ __ ]
tin that flavor the aroma the colors
that plant is a perfect 10. that's why I
chose those plants as reversals so use
those as your standard The Grateful Dog
the blueberry cookies and Golden Goat
those are the kind of plants I would
choose to reverse so when you're looking
for standards looking for a metric
looking for something to compare it to
those are the ladies that I would choose
that I did choose to reverse so those
are three of my favorite plants that
I've ever worked with those are my three
favorite reversals there are more coming
I am working on some things I haven't
shared with you yet but so far the
Golden Goat the blueberry cookies and
the Grateful Dog have been my three
favorite plants to reverse all right I
think that is all I've got for you in my
episode about selecting males and
choosing a candidate for reversals if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know I would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart hotmail.com
don't be shy reach out I look forward to
the constructive criticism the positive
feedback or even the hate mail if that's
what you gotta do it doesn't hurt my
feelings don't be shy let me hear it
also make sure you support the show on
patreon at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart everybody's
supporting the show on patreon did get a
coupon code for the Christmas sale of
course that code was adjusted based on
your patreon contribution level the 420
level got one code and of course the 710
and higher got another coupon code so
make sure you support the show on
patreon if you do want access to the
coupon codes info on the drops early
access to the releases I do recommend
you sign up for the newsletter on the
website
iregenetics.com at the bottom of the
page there's a little tab it says keep
in touch or join the newsletter I don't
remember exactly what it says I don't
stock my own website often enough but if
you go to the bottom there's a spot you
can type in your email address type in
your email address that will add you to
my newsletter when I put out new drops
new holiday deals cool [ __ ] that you you
may want to know about you will get an
update from my MailChimp newsletter that
is at
irygenetics.com everything you need will
be at iregenetics.com there's a link to
the seeds a link to the merge a link to
the podcast a link to the Discord the
patreon it is all there
iriegenetics.com well I feel like I got
rambly here at the end of the show
ladies and gentlemen that's all I've got
for you for this episode I may be back
next week depending on the holiday
schedule like I said at the top of the
show if I don't pop up for a week don't
worry nothing bad happened I'm catching
my breath enjoying some time with the
family and the dogs and the holidays and
the snow
I hope you have a great holiday
whichever one it is you choose to
celebrate I'll be back in a week or
maybe two weeks I want to give a big
shout out to my buddy Billy Podunk and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
foreign