if you have ever fed the dogs twice
because you're too stoned to remember if
you fed them the first time go ahead and
click subscribe
[Music]
here we go happy New Year and welcome to
the show everybody I'm your host my
friends call me Rasta Jeff this is
episode 782 of the grow from your heart
podcast I've got a great show lined up
for us before we jump in let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to my friend dude grows let's
send a fist bump and a thank you shout
out to my buddy fiscals Organics I want
to send a big thank you shout out to
Thor's trike Factory let's send a thank
you shout out to
groove2112. let's send a thank you shout
out to Big Bear Canada I want to send a
big fist bump to my buddy you betcha
let's send a thank you shout out to more
Terps let's send a big thank you shout
out to a long time supporter my friend B
Bala let's send a big fist bump to
Double D let's send a special thank you
shout out to a long time supporter our
friend Brian P let's send a thank you
shout out to Captain Mojo then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
Monster Mash big thanks and big shout
out to every everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the show I also want
to send a big shout out to everybody who
supported the I redirect holiday sale
there's been a holiday sale running on I
redirect and you guys definitely took
advantage of that sale big thank you for
all of the support there and an extra
big fist bump to everybody who bought
the random bundles the dudes bundle the
random bundle number one if you got a
random bundle that you didn't know what
you were going to get thank you for
trusting that I was going to hook you up
anybody that got those bundles did get
loaded up and I'm sure they are super
happy so once again big thanks for all
of the support on iridirect for the
holiday sale if you missed the sale
don't worry I do have a lot of new new
stuff coming soon I need to take a
moment to update the inventory update
pricing add some new things then we will
do some new drops and add some new
things to
iridirect.com the best way to stay
updated on what is coming to
iridirect.com is to join the newsletter
on iregenetics.com I know that's a lot
to handle there are two websites but
there are reasons to that go to
iregenetics.com sign up for the
newsletter there if you scroll almost
all the way to the bottom of the page at
iregenetics.com you'll see a tab that
says stay updated or stay in touch I
don't remember exactly what it says I
looked just a minute ago I cannot
remember what it says I think it says
stay in touch or stay updated type in
your email address right there that will
add you to my mailing list that way
every time I do a sale a new drop an
exclusive deal something fancy an event
comes up maybe I'm going to be somewhere
I will let you know through that
newsletter so go to iregenetics.com
scroll most of the way down you'll see
the tab it's fairly obvious type in your
email address sign up for that
newsletter I did mention that I was
going to be putting new things on I
redirect I'm also going to be doing
testing a little bit differently here in
the next year before I've been taking
tester applications through emails and
through the Discord I'm not going to be
doing as much of that if you sent an
application to be a tester those are
still in the running those will still be
considered I do go through those
randomly when I have some time and pick
out some folks but I do have a strategy
of how I want to do the testers in the
upcoming year my new plan is to do two
testers every month I would like to do
one regular and one feminized cross
every month so far I've got a few months
of test seeds planned out and prepared
from previous Harvest from Summer runs
and things like that I've got a lot of
seeds stockpiled that you guys have
never seen never heard of I want to get
those out and get those in testing so I
like to do one feminized and one regular
strain for testing every month for the
next six to eight hopefully even maybe
up to the next 12 months so that means
every month we'll have two new testers
some of those will not make it some of
those will make it but you guys will get
to see most of the testing that goes on
for the next year so I'll be putting out
two testers every month for the next
year these new testers will be released
in limited batches and they will be
available in a couple of different ways
a lot of them will be given away with
orders on I redirect so if you order
from ire direct every month you've got
the opportunity to get one or two new
tester packs from me everybody gets
freebies when you order on I redirect
part of those freebies will be free
tester packs a lot of people love
getting that brand new stuff you've got
something nobody else has because you've
got it before everybody because you are
a tester you may have the next big
winner you may have the next champion
from my line you may get to test grow it
before everybody else if you were
growing for a a profitable gain that may
set you apart from the rest of the
market that may really help you out so
they will be going out as freebies on I
redirect I will also add them to I
redirect for a very low price I'll be
putting I've been doing it I've been
putting Big Mountain fudge cake testers
on the website they went very very well
I put the testers clearly labeled that
they are testers I put them at a very
reasonable price there's a little note
attached to the package that lets you
know what you can expect lets you know
what I expect there's a link to the
Discord that way you can sign up to our
Discord and post all of your tester
photos and information to the Discord
tester tab so there are two ways to get
the new test receipts they will be
coming as freebies from orders on I
redirect and also I may add some of them
randomly to the iredirect website for a
very limited price and again those will
be at very limited quantities if you
have tested for me in the past don't
feel like you're going to get left out
I've got a list of testers I see your
pictures I see your names in my computer
in my phone don't worry you will not get
left out I do consider you for testing
in the future if you've already been
testing and you want more tester seeds
reach out either via email or on Discord
let me know say hey bro I finished up
the last run of testers here are the
pictures really love to run a new batch
for you I like repeat offenders if you
come back and test for me again that
means that you under understood the
assignment the first time he probably
did a good job I'll probably give you
seeds again and we'll keep it going
we'll keep your garden fresh keep it new
keep my photos keep my data coming we'll
work out together very well like that so
so don't feel like you're going to get
left behind or pushed out or forgotten
if you've been testing for me before I
just want to establish new relationships
with new testers because if you haven't
noticed I've been making a lot of seeds
and I need to get them out there and I'd
like to get them thoroughly tested so we
can get them to the people who need to
grow them I know I mentioned this just a
moment ago but if you do get tester
seeds please join the Discord and post
photos of those tester seats in the ire
genetics tester tab if you're on the
Discord on the left side if you scroll
down on the ire genetics Discord there
are a bunch of tabs different places to
go there's one that says testers click
on there you can post your pictures you
can post data you can scroll up and see
what other people are posting you can
either follow the kind of guideline or
you can set the standard and create new
trends post any of the information you
think I might want to know how long you
grew it how many of the plants
germinated how long you flowered it for
if you noticed anything weird let me
know any details you think may be
interesting to myself or other people
growing that strain in the future all
right I think that covers testers you
guys let's move forward to the main
chunk of this podcast of course we are
entering a brand new year here a lot of
people like that new year new me new
year new start sort of stuff why not use
this new calendar year as a new goal
setting phase a new time phase to start
fresh and get things going start
documenting doing things properly let's
jump into it and talk a little bit more
about creating a good start and a good
strategy for a brand new year in my
opinion everything goes better with a
good strategy with a good plan with a
good expected outcome with sort of a
plan of what could go wrong what to look
for and how to react to those things as
it happens if you go into things blindly
you didn't have no idea how that [ __ ] is
going to turn out not just in growing
but almost everything in life works that
way the better you prepare the more you
plan the better it's going to go of
course you got to be spontaneous and
have some fun the girl works that way
too but if we've got a strategy got an
idea have a an expected goal written
down it is easier to reflect on things
and see where we are with our progress
so my question to you is do you have a
goal for your grow this year is there
something you want to improve on is
there something you want to work on
let's talk about a few goals that you
could have in your grow room for this
year maybe the first thing I would do is
identify the weak spot what are you not
good at in the grow room for a long time
my weak spot was cloning I told one of
my friends I said hey bro I really suck
at cloning and I've done a full podcast
about this and he came over and he
showed me step by step how to make
clones guess what now my clone game is
on top of [ __ ] figure out what your
weakness is find out where you're
lacking in the grow let's identify that
and let's make that your strongest part
of the grow the next time we'll identify
the next weakness and we'll make that
the strongest part and we'll just keep
leapfrogging your weaknesses into your
strongest points in the grow so let's
identify the weakness maybe you're not
good at cloning maybe you're really not
good at lollipopping maybe you don't
know how to pop and twist maybe you're
no good at working a trellis maybe
there's things that you need to work on
in the grow that I'm not even aware of
so identify your biggest weakness in the
grow maybe you're not good at taking
clones maybe you're not good at popping
and twisting maybe you're not good at
lollipopping maybe you've never topped a
plant because you're afraid maybe you
don't know how to work a trellis or a
scrog identify your weakness and let's
fix that right here at the start of the
Year let's make that one of the first
projects that we correct some of the
things we do in the grow are are more
measurable than others the amount of
effort we put in the amount of time we
spend in there the amount of work we do
that's only measurable by hours and
actually by the outcome things that we
can actually measure though are how much
product did you produce last year do you
know how much herb you produced in the
last 365 days are you a flower grower
how much usable smokable flour did you
produce are you a concentrate maker how
much usable smokable concentrate did you
produce then the next question what
happened to all that do you have
something to show for it did you smoke
all of it which is just fine you grew it
to consume it but if you are somebody
who is making a profit or providing a
product to somebody what happened to
that product is was there income made
from that product what happened to that
money did that go somewhere did you put
that in the bank did you buy sneakers
with it are you living off a part of it
did you invest part of it into the grow
where did that money go so the first
question how much product did you
produce in the last year like I said if
you're a flower producer how much flour
if you're a concentrate maker how much
concentrate did you produce then where
did that go did you smoke it did you
move it then where did the money go now
let's think about these things did you
produce enough
out of what you produced did you have
enough to smoke did you have enough to
do whatever you're doing with it then if
money was made from that product did you
make enough money to cover your work
your energy your costs and then have
enough money to make it worth your time
those are things I would think about so
how much product did you produce in the
last year and the next question is how
much do you plan to produce in the next
year are you going to increase your
production or are you okay with the
amount that you produced can you
increase production with your space can
you increase production 10 20 maybe 30
percent with the room space you've got
if you put more time and energy into it
could you do that I don't know I don't
know how hard you worked last year but
that is a goal that I would set how much
more product am I going to produce this
year my next question is on a scale of
one to ten how good is your product and
this is where people get really messed
up in their heads you have got to be
honest with yourself about your product
on a scale of 1 to 10 how good is your
product you may say out loud it's a 10
because everybody's going to say their
herb is a 10 but you may know inside
that that shit's a four and you got to
work on getting it up to a six so be
honest with yourself give your herb an
honest assessment compare it to a lot of
other herb find other Growers that you
respect don't put yourself in a group of
Growers that you think you are better
Growers than them and compare your herb
to it because of course it'll be better
go find Growers that you respect that
you think are better Growers than you
also hang out with the Growers that you
think you're better than them all of you
put your herb in the table and compare
it let's see what everybody's doing find
out where you really stand in the game
and be honest with yourself if the
shit's not selling if it's not moving
that's a three or a four bro 10 level 10
weed [ __ ] moves itself level 10 weed
you don't have to sell it that [ __ ]
sells itself you just gotta drive it to
the next customer so give your weed a
reasonable assessment on a scale of one
to ten how good is it if you can get a
lab test a potency test which again
that's going to raise a lot of
controversy but maybe you've got a lab
test to compare it to what's your THC
percentage your CB D percentage what's
your terpene percentage can we increase
and improve on those numbers or can you
just grow herb that you think is better
than the herb you're growing now on a
scale of one to ten how good is your
weed if it's a five what would make it a
seven if it's a seven what would make it
an eight if it's an eight what would
make it a ten identify the issue was it
something with the nutrients was it
something in the dry and cure did you
over water it did the room get too hot
can you tell by looking at the buds that
there was a fungus nap problem or can
you tell by looking at the flowers that
there was a root aphid problem or can
you tell by looking at the shape of the
Clusters and the little tiny misshapen
buds that there was a a russet my issue
can you tell those things correct those
issues does it taste funky was it too
leafy did you let it get too dry correct
those issues you can see the problems
let's take your herb from a six to an
eight or an eight possibly to a ten if
you can do it of course you got to get
your ego out of the way to be able to do
that one now here's some more fun things
to talk about how many strains do you
want to try this year do you know what
you want to grow are you going to grow
the same old [ __ ] or do you have a few
strains Chosen and selected on your menu
that you'd like to try to run this year
do you have a schedule do you have a
plan do you know how many crops you're
going to turn this year have you divided
the amount of days you used to Flower by
the amount of days in the year to see
how many crops you can fit in that
flower room and see if you can cram One
More In by doing something weird by just
using space over here to move move this
room from Veg to flour a week early
while they're all in there and then
maybe I could squeeze in one more crop
this year have you done that math that
stuff that I start thinking about right
now at the beginning of the year which
breeders are you going to support this
year of course I recommend you buy irie
genetic seeds you're going to find some
good [ __ ] in there but there are tons of
other great breeders out there putting
out great products who are you going to
support this year what strains from
which breeders do you plan to grow then
my next question is are you breeding do
you have breeding goals uh what is your
breeding goal for the year do you plan
to F2 something are you going to F3
something or how far are you gonna go
are you gonna make a new cross how many
new two crosses are you going to make
how many overall seeds do you plan or
attend or intend anticipate making in
the next calendar year those are things
to write down if you're a seed breeder
what is your goal for seed breeding are
you trying to get those seeds to Market
are you trying to make seeds for you are
you trying to make seeds for the homies
what are you trying to do you're trying
to isolate a terpene a cannabinoid a
trait write down those goals and figure
out what you want to do as a breeder
this year as a grower you need very
specific calendars and ideas and goals
as a breeder those are even more
specific so let's get to setting some
goals writing down a plan setting up
some ideas so that we know where we're
driving we're not just running through
this year with no map let's get the map
printed out so we can all end up at the
same winning destination is there
something in your grow a chore a task a
mess a problem that you've been avoiding
let's do that right here at the start of
the Year let's correct it if it's a
problem that needs to be fixed and cost
some money let's throw some money at it
and fix it if it's a mess you need to
clean up get in there and clean it up if
it's shelf that needs to be reorganized
or a bunch of [ __ ] that needs to be
thrown away or lights that need to be
re-hung let's just do that right here at
the start of the Year let's bang it out
get it out of the way start fresh so we
can just rock this whole year nice and
smooth find that task you've been
avoiding identify it let's make it a
habit to do that task make it enjoyable
feel some pride when you do it now also
this is a good time to clean everything
up this is the first of the year all
that stuff that needs to be cleaned you
know what I'm talking about I like to
start from the top and work my way down
look at the lights the tops of the
lights are probably Dusty I don't know
what kind of Lights you've got the tops
of whatever lights you're using they're
probably Dusty and need a dusting so get
up there and clean those lights get a
ladder out you guys get a ladder a
couple of Rags some spray bottles some
cleaner let's get to work and clean all
this [ __ ] up start at the top and work
our way down just wipe everything down
if you've got air conditioning if you've
got ducting if you've got venting it
probably all needs to be wiped down
clean the tables clean the trays let's
clean everything of course course here
in Colorado it's like 20 degrees so
taking [ __ ] outside and hosing it down
is not a fun option right now but if
you're in a place where you can load up
the [ __ ] and take it to the car wash one
of those outdoor car washes go spray the
[ __ ] out of everything don't use too
much of that car wash soap just use the
water and the hose there and spray the
[ __ ] out of it rinse it real good let's
get everything super clean start off
nice and clean here for the start of the
Year also this is a good time to change
all of your filters
anything that's got to filter
everything's got to filter the air
conditioner the humidifier the
dehumidifier all those filters in your
hydro gear anything with the filter now
is a good time to change it it's the
first of the month the first of a new
year let's start off with all new
filters I know most of us are using LED
lighting now I do have a couple of high
pressure sodium light fixtures in one
grow space because it gets very cold in
that building and I use those HPS lights
to keep that grow space warm so at the
first of the year I would change the
bulbs and those high pressure sodium
lamps and what I would do is I would
take a piece of duct tape and I would
write new bulbs January 1st 2023 and I
would stick that right on either the
door to the grow room or I would tape it
onto the reflector itself out of the way
on the side of the reflector stick that
duct tape either on the door or on the
reflector to indicate new bulbs January
1st that way I've got new bulbs in there
most of you don't need to worry about
that because you've got the LEDs but if
you're running something with a
switchable bulb why not put new bulbs in
there and mark the date that you did it
do you remember when you switched bulbs
if you're using old lighting not
everybody's in a a legal growing State
not everybody has access to new Modern
Gear a lot of people out there are using
old magnetic ballasts and HPS bulbs so
switch those out you guys put on a new
bulb if you can do that here at the
start of the year and definitely mark it
down also mark down when you change all
those filters that we talked about
changing it's not that hard to write
just either in a notebook or a ledger or
a Google doc or somewhere change my
filters change my bulbs January 1st now
if we're changing bulbs and changing
filters you know it's also time to
calibrate all of our equipment if you've
got a pH pen now is a good time to
calibrate that pH pen also if you've got
any automation or room sensors that are
checking for moisture humidity
temperature I'm not sure which sensors
you're using but now is a good time to
clean them calibrate them and test them
let's make sure that all of the
expensive toys we're buying and using
are taking good care of and up to speed
and calibrated so they work the way we
are expecting them to so clean all the
filters calibrate all the gear I don't
know what filters I don't know what
needs to be cleaned in your grow that's
up to you but you've got an air
conditioner filter I'm sure there's
probably a dehumidifier filter a
Humidifier filter maybe go clean all the
fans all the fans are super funky I
promise you by now they're dirty Anita
cleaning so do a general inspection and
prepare for a big spring cleaning I
mentioned a moment ago that it's 20
degrees here in Colorado I'm going to
prepare for a spring cleaning I'm going
to bang out one more crop I know that
that crop will be done by March the
middle of March at the latest by the end
of that crop I'm going to tear down the
entire room and do a full spring
cleaning re-hang everything all over
again because of course when spring gets
here in Colorado we've got to redo some
of the rooms have to be redone and
reconfigured a little bit differently
because like I mentioned it's it's been
negative six uh somewhere between uh
it's been cold that you guys don't care
about specific numbers it's been [ __ ]
cold but it's going to get the opposite
here in about six months it'll be 114
degrees so I've got to reconfigure my
grow at the springtime to prepare for
that stuff so get yourself ready for a
spring cleaning if you are in a cold
area definitely inspect the air
conditioner the the dehumidifier the
humidifier all that stuff that moves all
the ducting all the ventilation if
you've got CO2 production equipment if
it's a burner or if it's tanks
definitely inspect all of that [ __ ]
another thing I like to do here at the
start of the year is order all of the
supplies I anticipate I will need for
the next couple of months shipping is
really expensive sometimes you'll get a
deal on ordering things in bulk so I
like to just place a big order and get
all of the stuff I need all at one time
at the start of the Year things like
nutrients pesticides and gloves we know
we're going to use those you have to
have those things why not order them
here at the start of the Year get them
out of the way that way the budget is
freed up for the rest of the year so get
nutrients pesticides gloves things like
scissors How many pairs of scissors will
you go through in the next couple of
months I know I'll need at least two why
not order two maybe if somebody comes to
help I'll need two pairs of scissors uh
ISO I go through a lot of isopropyl
alcohol here are not just for cleaning
[ __ ] in the grow but also for cleaning
[ __ ] my smoking accessories for cleaning
the table everything is sticky here so I
got to order a bunch of iso here at the
start of the year just to have it
available what are you using to clean
your scissors to prevent the spread of
hot plate and viroid are you cleaning
your scissors with anything maybe you
need a small container of bleach in your
grow maybe you need more cleaning
supplies in your grow I don't know
exactly what you need but now is a good
time to think about ordering those
things you're going to need some
cleaning supplies like a mop some sort
of a cleaner maybe Rags maybe spray
bottles I don't know how you do it but I
know that I need those products other
things I think about is refreshing my
mixing cups and measuring devices some
of my nutrients are powdered I use a
scale make sure that scale is nice and
clean make sure it's zeroed and dialed
in that way I've got a good measurement
my measuring cups are filthy I try to
clean them but after a while they get
stained I use Liquid nutrients with
colors the the Cups have changed colors
they look like [ __ ] it's hard it's not
completely easy to read the measurements
I will replace those here at the start
of the year just because I want to make
sure I'm measuring my expensive
nutrients as accurately as possible so
make a big order order all of the
supplies you need here right at the
start of the year now that leads me into
another part that we should talk about
maybe now is a good time to start
keeping a ledger or keeping track of
your income and expenses based on your
grow do you have a profit and loss sheet
for your grow or any other business
attached to that if you're in an illegal
area and you're growing it business-wise
maybe you don't want all this stuff as
easily accessible or readily available
that may be evidence but if you are in a
legal State and you are growing it is
completely reasonable to keep a ledger
and a profit and loss sheet based on
your grow what does your grow cost what
are you spending on electricity what are
you spending on nutrients CO2 all of
that stuff adds up and matters write all
of that stuff down then document how
much product you produced estimate how
much that product is worth and see if
you are making a profit profit or a loss
also include your time in there you're
spending time in the grow maybe it's
time to start keeping track of how many
hours a day or a week you are actually
in that grow space so let's start
documenting things like electrical
spending nutrient spending how much do
all those nutrients cost every bottle
let's write it down how much are you
spending on co2 did you buy a CO2 burner
did you buy a setup and are you
replacing bottles every week what are
you doing for CO2 augmentation also
people don't think about the cost of
water it comes out of a faucet you turn
it on it comes out we don't think about
paying for it at the end of the month
how much water are you spending do you
pay the water bill or does the landlord
pay the water bill
if the landlord pays it are they
noticing that you're using extra water
for the grow if it's a small grow
probably not if you've got a few lights
they might notice the increase in water
fees how about rent for the building if
you're growing in a building that is not
your home you're probably paying extra
rent for that building what does that
cost you is that eating up your profits
I know it's the only place you've got to
do it but let's include that into the
cost of doing business here how about
employees do you have a trimmer do you
have a bro that comes and helps you or a
lady that comes and helps you do you
have security do you have a dog that dog
that works security at the Grove that is
a cost you got to feed the dog it's got
to go to the vet that is part of your
cost of doing business for that grow
how about gas do you have to drive to
the grow or if the grow is located in
your home you got to walk down there
that doesn't cost anything but if you've
got to drive a few miles to it that does
add up over the year how much does that
gasoline cost speaking of gasoline how
about a backup generator diesel fuel
costs money did you buy a generator did
you have that attached to your breaker
box in your home do you have diesel fuel
in that generator do you have all the
switches and jump boxes you needed to
where when the power goes off in your
spot that generator fires up immediately
in your home so where you don't even
notice there was a missing power do you
have that how much did it cost how much
does the diesel fuel that's in their
cost if it comes on it immediately
starts costing you money that diesel
feels running cost any money tick tock
tick tock ching ching ching lushes coins
falling through the generator machine
right there how much does that cost you
what about security costs do you have
security are you security did you buy
anything to use as Security in case
something goes wrong all of those things
cost you money are you using cameras the
cameras are going to cost you money
write that down also if you use cameras
are you providing the service are you
providing the data or do you have a
service backing up all the video footage
for you most of us have a ring cam or
the the blink cam or some service out
there that you got to pay eight bucks a
month or something for are you paying
for that write that down document that
in your Ledger treat this like a real
business if you want it to be profitable
if you want to make money off of it if
you want to document your spending
income and outcome profit and loss
you've got to document all of this stuff
it's how real business does it and
you've got to start doing that what else
are you paying for I'm not sure the
other specifics in your grow but
everything costs money do you have to
put up new mylar that you have to buy a
new pen to film do you have to replace a
light document all of that stuff a pH
pen PH down all that shit's going to
cost cost money now is a good time to
start documenting things and keeping
notes for a whole year worth of
bookkeeping you can do this on paper you
can do it on Google Sheets you can do it
in uh whatever there's a thousand
different methods of doing this as long
as you're doing it in some sort of way
of making an effort you'll improve on it
every year and you'll realize there are
better easier ways to do it so start
making notes start keeping that profit
and loss sheet start documenting how
many plants did you grow if you can
that's another I've got the words be
careful written right here really big on
my notes
um if you can safely document this stuff
document as much as possible how many
plants did you grow this run how many
days did they go how much did each plant
Harvest what was your total Harvest
weight and then how much from that
Harvest weight do you think that would
be market value then look back and see
what it cost you to produce each gram of
that herb then look and see if like I
said before you've got to pay yourself
do you get a salary included in there
maybe including write down how many
hours are in there and see if you even
make a salary let's start marking all of
that down but again be very careful
because that if you're not in a legal
state that could be dangerous data so
the most important part here is have a
goal but my most important message is
have fun and then most importantly that
your mom is going to say be careful and
be safe so have fun have a goal be
careful be safe grow from your heart
breathe with love and let's kick some
[ __ ] ass in 2023. you guys we had a
rough couple of years I don't want to
get all weird on you here at the end of
the podcast but man the past couple of
years have been weird on everybody it's
been stressful it's been strange it's
been new and uncomfortable we've just
been stirred up and shaken up a lot of
us are getting back to normal from it I
still see weird lasting effects like you
see weird societal effects from being
locked down for [ __ ] two years the
world is just getting its [ __ ] back
together a lot of my favorite
restaurants and stores and things are
just [ __ ] gone things have
disappeared things are different now but
it feels like things are kind of it's
kind of starting to get back to as close
to normal as we're going to feel like
for a little while it's going to take a
while before we feel real normalcy again
but we're starting to get there it's
headed that direction so supplies are
coming back schedules are coming back
people aren't uh sick and [ __ ]
quarantining and hiding from each other
as much as we were before so the world
is coming back let's kick some ass this
year you guys let's not use any weird
excuses let's not let pandemic and weird
[ __ ] the c word I'm not even going to
say the c word let's not let that stuff
slow us down let's bang it out and kick
some ass in 2023. ladies gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
old school listeners new followers thank
you I want to thank each and every one
of you for listening to another episode
of The Grow from your heart podcast I
hope you guys all had as great of a year
as I did I wish you great success in the
next year uh let's start wrapping up
this show if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
my email address of course is grow from
your heart at hot mail.com don't be shy
reach out let me know what you think of
the show send me that feedback let me
make some adjustments to get the show
Top Notch uh make sure you check out the
website iregenetics.com like I mentioned
before there is a stay up to date tab on
the bottom of the website scroll on down
type in your email address that will put
you on the newsletter every time I knew
it would do a new drop or do something
cool or special you will be notified via
a newsletter I promise not to spam you
too much I usually do about one per
month sometimes I'll send you that
second one just to give you a reminder
that some cool [ __ ] is going on
um stay up to date with that newsletter
everything else you need is on the
website again iregenetics.com there's a
link to patreon there's a link to the
Discord there's a link to everything you
need is there you guys check it out
iregenetics.com that is all I've got for
this episode I'll be back next week with
fresh new content you guys have a safe
Happy New Year I want to give a big
shout out to my buddy Lollipop Farms and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
foreign
[Music]