[Music]
thank you
all right now here we go welcome to the
show everybody I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode 783
of the grow from your heart podcast I've
got a fun show lined up for us before we
jump in let's do a few shout outs to a
few of those great folks who continue to
support the show on patreon let's kick
it off with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to Canna
fugget listen to fist bump and a thank
you shout out to SC dung Slinger listen
to Big thank you shout out to one of my
favorite photographers my buddy ADHD
grower let's send a big thank you shout
out to grow dad listen to special thank
you shout out to a good friend and a
long time supporter my buddy OG purple
thumb let's send a big thank you shout
out to shoe trader101 let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to
Badlands and Jacob M let's send a thank
you shout out to Big Bear Canada then
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank you shout
out to Godfather Kush big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast once
again I want to send a big thank you to
everybody who did participate and
indulge and imbibe and partake in the I
redirect holiday sale thank you that
sale was a great success it would not
have happened without you so big shout
out to everybody who did participate in
the holiday sale
I hope you had a great safe New Year I
hope the holiday you chose to celebrate
was great for you I'm not concerned with
which holiday you celebrate I just hope
you did celebrate one with your friends
your family hopefully some good food
hopefully you got to smoke something
good with somebody strange maybe a weird
cousin or an uncle you never smoked with
hope you got to do that maybe that smoke
a joint before a walk kind of thing with
a family member hope you got to
participate in some of that action and
have a good holiday I had a wonderful
holiday but when I got home from my
holiday Shenanigans I went to my grow
space and I stepped in a small puddle of
water that was not supposed to be there
that's right I had to drain back up in
the area where my grow is and there was
a bunch of water in that space so I've
spent a couple of days getting some
water out doing some cleanup pulling up
some carpet still have a little bit of
stuff to do this podcast maybe a little
bit shorter than you're used to because
there is more work to be done I got to
get some [ __ ] out of there get some [ __ ]
cleaned up get myself nice and dirty get
back in action but that is not the most
important part we're talking about today
I want to know if you've got a plan if
you've got strategy what are the risks
of [ __ ] going wrong near your grow my
grow there was a flood and the water got
one inch from plants and the other way
it got inches from a drum set so it
could have been much more disastrous
than it was it did cause a huge problem
it did cause a big mess the only thing
it really really [ __ ] up was my
schedule I've got to throw away some
carpets and some small items and details
but most of the stuff will be recovered
and repaired but it really messed up my
week it's messing up my timing and my
flow like I said the podcast will be a
little shorter here but do you have a
strategy what if there's a water leak in
your grow space or where you are growing
or near there will that water make it to
your grow are you prepared for something
like that is there a floor drain has
that floor drain been maintained uh
what's going on are you prepared for any
sort of disaster in the grow like water
has been kicking my ass the past couple
of days are you prepared for water then
of course there's the opposite side of
that one there is fire are you prepared
for a fire so this is just my quick
heads up uh check on your [ __ ] make sure
all your drains are cool make sure no
water is coming up anywhere make sure
nothing's leaking make sure there's no
sparks no loose wires go ahead and do a
quick inspection here at the start of
the Year my friend John told me out of
sight out of mind and that's kind of how
I felt about the plumbing uh that's kind
of how we felt about the water it wasn't
a problem until it was a [ __ ] problem
luckily it didn't destroy anything too
expensive too crazy here but it
definitely slowed me down that's enough
talking about a flood talking about that
I just want to know if you are prepared
uh what are you gonna do if you get a
flood do you have something lined up if
the flood does come can you get the
people down in your area to work on it
without getting yourself in trouble
maybe you're not in a legal place I'm in
a legal State I've only got a few legal
plants in that area where I'm growing
the plumber the drain guy everybody was
able to go in there and they go nice
plants and I was like yeah quit [ __ ]
looking at them just because they're
over there in an area and they're cool
and they can see them it's not a big
deal maybe you're in a place where you
can't grow and can you quickly hide that
grow if some [ __ ] does go wrong in your
uh to your home your rental space
whatever you're doing where you got that
grow can you conceal that should you
need to take some quick action that is
my question to you all right that's just
a heads up that's what's on my mind I
got some ruined shoes and some wet pants
it has not been fun let's move on to
more fun stuff in this podcast uh
recently my friend Mobius Mobius I love
you bro I got nothing but love and
respect for you we've become really good
friends over the couple of years I
simply disagree with the comment that
you made on YouTube we're still good
friends bro I'll still smoke a fat joint
with you this is just a really good
topic of conversation so my friend
Mobius left a comment on a YouTube video
I did a video about selecting males and
reversals for breeding projects
I talked about just that how I select
male plants and how I select which
plants I do want to reverse for my
personal breeding projects my friend
Mobius uh he chimed in with his comment
and I fully respect this opinion I just
think this is great podcast material
this is so totally something we should
address I could talk about for a long
time on a podcast like I said I got
nothing but love and respect for my dude
Mobius don't get this Twisted alright it
says I think another great thing to
think about is if you are breeding to
sell wreck and Med uh to reckon Med
Growers and be a seed company don't get
too stuck on what you like and I kind of
touched on this before but we're going
to elaborate here
it says Instead try to make a diverse
menu think flavors and effects have
fruit have gas have garlic have mint
have Earth
but also have soaring highs along with
pile driver heavy stuff bottom line is
be diverse not only thinking about wreck
Market but Medical Market as well that
is that is very good feedback I like
that but I also disagree with that I
respectfully disagree with that as a
breeder as the person making the seeds I
don't think about the recreational or
the medical Market at all when I'm
making a cross
um
I'm uh maybe selfishly I'm thinking
about what I like in cannabis when I'm
making a cross I don't think that
um and I'm not gonna this will sound
egotistical but if you took
um Van Gogh and told Van Gogh make some
art that the people will like the people
aren't going to like the art that van
Gogh makes but if you shut the [ __ ] up
and leave Van Gogh alone and let Van
Gogh paint shit's gonna come out amazing
I'm not saying that I'm an artist or a
painter or anything like that but
um I breed what I like and it just
happens that I like plants with certain
terp profiles and certain Buzz types and
certain growth structures and those
plants also are desirable to uh the
general public the people that want to
grow my my followers my fans my
supporters the irie Army the people that
want to grow eye regenetic seeds you
guys happen to like those because I'm
growing it with passion with love for
what I like to do
um I got a couple of ways I like to
describe this there's an artist called
matus Yahoo he came up a couple of years
ago in the early 2000s 2005-ish the dude
was hot hot [ __ ] his first album uh
first two albums were a amazing but you
could tell that he had spent his entire
life putting those two albums together
and it was everything he had to put that
together it was all of his creativity
from when it started writing up to the
time when those albums were put out that
was everything he had that was his art
those albums are [ __ ] awesome two of
my most favorite albums shake off the
dust arise and of course live at Stubbs
there might be more stuff before that
but those are the two when he got
popular that's like his life's work
right there Ah that's what really got
him going he went on tour he got super
known he got super famous he was killing
it because his art came from his heart I
was his connection with his music what
he did he didn't do it for anybody but
himself so it was [ __ ] awesome after
that the record label came and said hey
bro it's time for that second record you
got to put some [ __ ] out
guess what that record kind of bites a
dick that second record no offense
Matisyahu you know what I'm saying
though brother that next record just was
not what we expected what we had hoped
for it sounded bubble gummy it sounded
way over produced it sounded like a
record company took over and demanded a
record on a timeline so part of my point
to that is I'm not doing records for a
record company I'm making records for
myself and I'm making sounds that I
think sound good and I'm making Terps
and strains and Crosses that I think
sound good another way that I like to
think about it is I'm a musician I can
read right I can play any kind of music
that's why a lot of things I talk about
I go back to music and that it's always
relatable for me so I'm a musician I can
like I said a moment ago I can read
music I can write music I have a deep
understanding of the way Music Works not
just I'm the drummer but not just in the
drums I understand the way the time
works the way the Dynamics work I've
been on stage I know how to make the
singer sound good by playing a certain
way I know how to make the bass player
sound better I know how to make the beat
feel a little faster even though it
isn't just by playing in front front of
or behind the beat just a little bit I
have a deep understanding of music I can
play any kind of music that you want me
to I like to play uh Funky Music I like
to get down and funky of course I love
to play reggae music I love to jam and
get improvisational it all sounds really
good but if you made me play country
it would sound okay but it wouldn't
sound like country music from the heart
it wouldn't have that country music it
would be country music but it wouldn't
be country music and the and for country
music you need something right in there
that's my opinion if you want it to
sound country music you gotta have some
I don't have country in my heart at all
I'm not a country boy I'm a [ __ ] city
boy I got dreadlocks and I wear sneakers
and [ __ ] I'm not I've got no boots or a
hat so I don't have that country feel I
could play the blues because I've had
the [ __ ] blues before but anyway if
you told me to put out a country album
it would be terrible because I don't
care it's not gonna have any heart any
Soul so what I'm doing is maybe it's
selfish of me but I'm breeding for what
I really like I have access to a lot of
plants you guys know that I've worked in
commercial facilities I've Got Friends
that grow I've Got Friends that breed
I'm in groves all the time helping
people out looking at things inspecting
investigating sometimes I see a plant
and I go what's that one bro and they'll
tell me they'll go that's this and I go
I'm gonna need a cut of that and they'll
go well okay and I'll tell them you owe
me this much money for coming here today
instead of paying me I want a cut of
that and they'll go okay because people
would definitely rather give you a plant
than money most of the time so I get a
lot of cool cuts and [ __ ] people send me
and give me and share with me really
cool cuts so sometimes I'll just see
something and I'll be like that girl
right there needs to be pollinated by
either like the Jack the Ripper mail or
the BC Lemon Skunk mail or possibly King
Solomon everybody's gonna get pollinated
by Solomon before the end of this it'll
be Solomon to everybody before the end
but I just see the plants and I go man
that one right there and that one right
there it's like uh just giving me
modeling clay or sculpting clay I don't
know [ __ ] about sculpting so that was a
bad example but it's like giving me a
big thing of paints and a paintbrush and
a fresh canvas and just letting me go uh
if you told me breed this I'd go I don't
uh I I don't know if I want to do that
like why am I doing that I need to like
smoke a plant or look at a plant or be
in the room with the plant and the plant
will say hey
bro and maybe this is [ __ ] crazy but
I can hear it the plant goes you shut
down
and I go huh I should probably breed
this strawberry Starburst plant to the
Jack the Ripper male and then I do it
and most of the time it's [ __ ]
awesome so Mobius I do like your idea of
having the diverse catalog and keeping
medical and recreational markets in mind
and that that's another thing we could
[ __ ] talk on but I do like that idea
but that is not uh that is not my style
I don't think that would work for me I
think me sticking with doing what I like
has been working pretty well and it
would be fake and it would be uh it
wouldn't be growing from my heart
breeding with love which is my motto
that's what it's all about for me that
would be that would that's one step too
close to breeding with my wallet I'm not
thinking about my wallet and my
pocketbook and [ __ ] when I'm reading but
also I like the fact that you said keep
the patience the medical and the
recreational users in mind that is a
great thing
um the way that I see that I'm gonna go
right back to music and I've used this
before
um Mobius is into I know my dude Mobius
you listen to heavier music than I do I
listen to fish and reggae and stuff like
that I think I got Moby ascended fish
because Trey is a [ __ ] Maniac but uh
we listen to different [ __ ] so the way I
describe it is uh some people want to
listen to reggae if you want to listen
to reggae that's irie genetic Seed
Company if you want to correlate music
to seed Brands if you want to listen to
reggae that's [ __ ] I'm that is me
right over here if you want to listen to
um I don't even have other breeders to
compare to [ __ ] different kinds of
music I should have not gone down that
route if you want to do some gangster
rap [ __ ] we all know that Masonic is the
dude for the Compton gangster rap kind
of vibe so if that's what you want what
I'm saying is if you want to diversify
the grow instead of expecting one
breeder to offer everything that's when
you got to go to different breeders like
I know that if I want like some cushy
stuff that I could go to DNA genetics
and those guys have all that cushy [ __ ]
if I want a Wilson cross I'm definitely
gonna go talk to Masonic smoker uh if I
want some jelly bean stuff I'm gonna go
talk to my friend Miss Jill if I want
some uh some of that Grandpa's cook
cookies or eat those cookies I gotta go
talk to my dude Colin if I want heavy
duty fruity which is in the garden right
now and bangs out I'd go talk to Adam
Dunn that is th seeds so you just gotta
instead of uh having one expecting one
breeder to diversify the growth for you
that's what I recommend and I know
you're doing this Mobius you've got
seeds from a lot of different breeders
and you kill it with all of them and
that helps you have a variety a little
bit of difference in the garden of
course I've got four or five three or
four four or five different males and
reversals that I work with but I'm still
limited to how many things I can produce
so I take my mail plan or my reverse
plant and I hit it to 10 or 12 different
ladies and then that's what I've got to
offer for this season or this section of
my I took up that much breeding time
until I do more breeding or whatever so
I can offer you so much but
the other breeders they've got totally
different [ __ ] than me so they can
definitely diversify your portfolio a
little more widely because they're not
breeding with the same stock so uh dude
I love your input I love your feedback I
love your idea
and I also love that I disagree and
we're still going to be [ __ ] good
friends all right you said what did he
say he said uh think about flavors and
effects bro flavors and effects that's
my favorite [ __ ] uh love good Terps and
I love to get straight up high but then
he said have fruit
I offer fruit I definitely offer fruit
fruit from me strawberry Starburst lemon
Jeffrey all kinds of fruity [ __ ] in my
lineup orange gasm Sun kiss it's all got
fruit in the name of it there uh gas the
machine is gassy the machine is
definitely gassy garlic garlic goat
um also what's the other one uh Dark
Hollow has the garlic in it mint
um the Mel Franks Urban Poison crosses
if you guys have been following along
you know that I've gotten access to a
bunch of plants the Mel Franks Urban
Poison is what the mfdp stands for that
is Mel Frank's Durbin poison that's got
the mint in there Earth
um the which one's got the Earth the
moon tower has definitely got the Earth
in there so I've got a lot of those
covered uh The Soaring highs most of my
stuff has got that soaring high the Jack
the rippered crosses they're all soaring
high the arise crosses the pile driver
heavy stuff that is kind of where I'm
lacking but I'm working toward that
direction that's not uh that's not my
favorite thing but as I'm getting older
um so it's funny I went to through a
weird shift in the weed that I like I
guess when I was younger I just wanted
to get baked I was so hyper and so
[ __ ] rambunctious that I just wanted
to get baked and sit down just [ __ ]
give me enough [ __ ] heavy heavy weed
enough Indica to just make me [ __ ]
normal just uh just chill me out just a
little [ __ ] bit and then as I got
older I started working more I was like
I can't smoke all this Indica I got [ __ ]
to do then I started smoking more sativa
started owning businesses and [ __ ]
doing podcasts and when you smoke a big
dab of some Indica that puts you down on
a podcast and you're just sitting here
like this
it's not a good podcast you got to be
[ __ ] sativit out and be talkative and
have the brain go and so I shifted into
that but now
um in the winter time I feel like I've
been going too fast I just need to chill
out I need some time with the lady time
with the dogs time on the couch just
chilling uh sometimes I know that my
lady's looking at me like you're just
going way too fast so that's when I need
like a big dab of some chilled out
Indica so I am kind of working toward
that Indica sort of cushy sort of stuff
in the lineup so many people are doing
it I want to do it uniquely I do have a
great strategy for that but it seems
like I'm offering most of the things you
ask for but still uh don't be afraid to
Branch out and have more breeders in
your garden there's no reason to lock it
in with just one I know a lot of people
try to do all irie all irie runs in
their Garden I appreciate that but don't
be afraid to grow other breeders Mobius
my dude that was a [ __ ] great
question a great comment you got me
rambling for at least 10 minutes on that
[ __ ] I do appreciate that thank you bro
I look forward to hanging out smoking
with you sometime soon you're just a
couple of stay dates away from me we
should get together alright I do have
another message here in front of me uh
this one came from the uh the grow help
tab on iregenetics.com if you go to
iregenetics.com there's a tab that says
grow help you can click on there and it
will give you the opportunity to ask me
a question I will print that out and
read it here on the show a quick update
that tab was broken for a little while
so if you sent me some grow help
questions and you feel like I ignored
you I did and it wasn't on purpose that
[ __ ] grow help tab had a major
malfunction I did some website updates
and that did not get corrected along
with the updates uh shout out to the web
guy he did correct it now there was a
short time it didn't work nobody's fault
we didn't notice there's a lot of [ __ ]
that goes on when we do that but anyway
it is corrected so if you've sent your
grow help questions and you feel like
you got ignored I apologize that [ __ ]
was broken send it again I'll do my best
to get in on the show as soon as
possible all right this one came from
our friend I don't know if they want
their name said it doesn't say that part
anyway it says Rasta Jeff at what point
do signs of nutrient deficiency become
fall colors that's a really good also
kind of a confusing question I can see
how you could confuse some nutrient
deficiencies and some of the colors that
the plants make at the end as it does
what is called senescence I will turn
into those fall colors when you start
flushing there are no nutrients left in
the leaves it will make beautiful fall
colors at what point do nutrient
deficiency become fall colors that
depends on if you're flushing or not I
guess it's kind of
um the fall some plants won't make fall
colors some will make fall colors uh and
some will show you those colors because
of a nutrient deficiency I think my
answer to this is mostly going to be
this is plant and strain specific I know
that the morning do if you let it go
long enough it'll start making orange
and goldish colored leaves but that
always happens during the flush that's
during the flushing phase so that's what
you're talking about the Fall colors
almost everything will start turning
yellow and pale if you don't feed it
so
um I think nutrient deficiency look out
for that you should know what that looks
like the Fall colors are going to be
phenotypical expression and vary by
plants so so I think the only way to
really determine that would be to grow
the plant a couple of times see if you
do get those weird colors see if you can
identify what that color could be caused
by try to correct it if you can't
correct that that's probably just the
plant expressing its funky end of life
beautiful fall colors
now there is more to this question it
goes on it says also how do you breed a
strain to finish faster is it as simple
as Crossing it with a faster finishing
strain because I have some blueberry now
that finishes in 53 days it's my
favorite I've ever grown thank you for
all of your info and your podcast it
really helps bro
you've got a blueberry that finishes
completely done in 53 days that is
impressive that is amazing
um I prefer plants that go a little
longer I think you get usually get more
herb and more potency but if that
thing's finished in 53 days and
satisfies you that is a phenomenal plan
you are a lucky dude to have found that
in a Fino hunt uh everybody wants a
clone of that I'll give you my uh my
address for a clone of that one let's
stay focused here
uh the question was how do you breed a
strain to finish faster and then he says
is it as simple as Crossing it with a
faster finishing strain it is that easy
but it's also not that easy it kind of
depends on what you plan to do with
these seeds because the first batch is
going to be a little bit uh unstable is
the word that I want to use here you're
going to find a lot of variation you're
going to find phenotypical variation and
in that variation we will find different
finishing times so this is a trait that
gets passed on so what I would do I
would find the female that you like but
you want to slow or speed up her
flowering time you want to take her from
70 to 60 or maybe even down to 50 days
you might not be able to do this in the
first attempt so let's talk about this
it kind of depends on if you want to
breed these seeds for yourself just to
play with or if you have some intention
of putting these seeds out to Market if
you find a good female plant that you
want to use as your female candidate I
would find a male plant that flowers
more quickly than that female I would
find a drastic difference if you've got
a female that goes 70 days you're trying
to chop it down to 60 I'd find a male
plant that finishes around that 55 day
Mark that way you got the ratio in there
right in the middle somewhere you'll get
that early finishing phenotype but
what's going to happen
or what most likely is going to happen
these are plants and this is nature and
I haven't drawn a Punnett square or a
Mendel chart to actually figure this out
completely perfectly but so you take
that long finishing female and that
short finishing male and you pollinate
now 33 percent of those seeds are going
to be shorter finishing phenotypes 33 of
those seeds are going to be longer
finishing phenotypes and the other 33
have the potential to be whatever when
we breathe like this we kind of unlock
Pandora's Box the F ones are going to be
wild so if you're reading this just for
yourself you do have the potential to
find that early finishing phenotype in
the F1 generation that you are making if
you are selling these seeds and you're
going to tell people that they finish
quickly the F1 generation will not be
stable or reliable you will need to make
an F2 F3 possibly even an F4 generation
so the first time you do it find that
fast finishing mail pollinate your
longer finishing female and you've got a
batch of seeds grow those seeds you may
find what you're looking for for
yourself in that batch of seeds if you
do find earlier finishing phenotypes in
that batch I would encourage you to use
those either for back Crossing or for
further filial generations to even
further reduce the flowering time of
this plant let me say that in a little
bit more clear terms because I know that
was a lot of crazy mumbo jumbo for some
of you so we've made this first cross
right we took our long finishing girl
our short finishing meal we made seeds
out of that
I expect that hopefully we find at least
one quick finishing girl also we're
gonna find one quick finishing boy this
is our F1 generation we've got F1 boy at
F1 girl let's put them together and
pollinate we have now made an F2
Generation from there let's find that
quickest finishing female and quickest
finishing male and breed those together
now we're making F3 guess what these f3s
are going to start getting a little bit
more uniform or they're going to be
completely wild depending on the
selections which we have made but we're
going to focus again we're going to find
that quick finishing phenotypes now
we're going to find the super quickest
finishing phenotypes we can out of the
boy and the girl we're gonna breed them
together now at this point we've really
started locking in that super fast
finishing phenotype everything from here
out should be closer to the goal amount
of finishing days that we're looking for
for the phenotypes which we have to
select from so you probably started with
that female I said started at 70 days uh
the F1 generation he found one and they
finished it like what 60 days we bred
those together then we found more that
finished at what 58 days then we found
some that finished at 55 and then we
kept working with those and breeding
them out and now we're all the way to
the F5 generation and we've got reliable
plants that finish in 55 days it will
take you several generations to get
there if you want reliable homogeneous
seeds or stable is the word we like to
use in the Cannabis industry but you can
do it or you could just do it the simple
way across it one time and hope to find
what you're looking for you do have the
potential to shorten that flowering time
every filial generation if you do proper
selections so here's another piece of
advice another hint another tip of what
I would do I would do parallel breeding
lines I don't talk about this a lot on
the show but I have mentioned it we're
focusing on faster finishing lines for
the first part of this question we want
to get down to you've got one that
finishes in 53 days I wouldn't go any
shorter than that but I would breed that
to other things and try to make that
other [ __ ] shorter I would reverse it
and breed it to some 70-day stuff and
then I would reverse the 53-day finisher
take the pollen from that put it on a
70-day finisher and see if I can reduce
that flowering time I would definitely
do that but let me get back into the
main topic of what I'm saying here we're
breeding on this line for flowering time
so keep directing that breeding towards
shorter flowering time then from the
same batch of seeds that F1 batch of
seeds you make so you took the 70-day
plant and the 55-day mail or whatever
you pollinated them you made a batch of
seeds we found that short finishing one
of the male and the girl and that's our
uh we're gonna call that the fast line
now on the other side let's focus on uh
potency
because not only do I want that plant to
finish quickly but I also need it to be
highly potent so I'm going to breed a
whole another project in another room
this is another project I'm going to
breed just for potency I don't care how
long these plants take to finish I don't
care what they taste like what they look
like I need potency so I'm going to find
a male and a female out of these seeds
I'm going to breed them I'm going to
find the most highly potent or I'm going
to grow them I'm going to find the best
looking most potent female I can and the
most potent looking male that I can find
that's a hard one to discern there but
find the best female the best dude and
breed them then I'm going to grow out
those seeds the F2 seeds I'm going to
grow those once again find the most
potent female and the most potent male
I'm going to breed them I'm gonna go F3
F4 F5 doing the same thing solely
focused on potency now when I get to F5
or F6 I'm going to take my fast
finishing version of this line and my
highly potent version of this line and
I'm going to breed those together and
that's how I make my own true F1 line
that is fast finishing and highly potent
and also has the other traits you're
looking for the reason I want to do
these two lines separately is because
it's really hard to isolate multiple
traits if you're breeding for
specifically that finishing time stick
with that fast finishing time get that
to a F4 F5 then find a male out of that
and use that mail to pollinate other
ladies to make that fast finishing time
so then on the other line I would focus
on the potency instead of focusing on
potency and flowering time just use two
different lines of the same thing so now
let's say that that tall longer
finishing plant is Strawberry Fields and
that shorter finishing plant that I want
to use for my mail is a rise he's not a
quick finisher and not a quick flowering
plant but we're going to say that for
the sake of this project let's say I
took that a rise and I pollinate these
Strawberry Fields or that makes
strawberry Starburst seeds it really
does now let's say that I want to focus
on breeding one for quicker finishing
and focus on one for that super potency
I would be feed strawberry Starburst a
the a line straight up for that quicker
finishing then I would breed the
strawberry Starburst b line for the
potency and while I was doing it if I
let the seeds out to Market or if I
shared them sold them passed them out in
any way I would clearly label them
strawberry Starburst F1 a line or
strawberry Starburst A-line F1 uh B-Line
F2 B-Line F3 just make sure that they
are labeled and then those seeds will be
great seeds on their own they're still
going to be potent they're going to have
all the other traits you're looking for
but I'm specifically breeding for one
thing and my plan and my strategy now
when I get that one to where I know that
they flower in 55 days and when I get
this one where I know that the potency
is off the charts I'm gonna use that
quicker flowering mail hit that super
potent female and hopefully I can get a
60-day finisher that blows your [ __ ]
mind so I hope that made sense because
yes it can be that easy it can be as
easy as pollinating a female plant with
a quicker finishing meal plan yes it can
be that easy but if you want to sell
those seeds if you want to put them to
Market if you really want to continue
that project there is more work to done
and that is breeding them to different
filial generations and if you're going
to focus on speed I would breed that b
line to focus on potency breed them
together at some point in the future all
right that message came from our friend
Michael once again that did come from
the grow help tab on the website Michael
thank you for the great question that
one really did get me rambling quite
well I do appreciate it all right ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters and pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast if you feel like
this episode was educational informative
and maybe even entertaining maybe you
just like to throw me a buck for
spending some time with me all you have
to do is check the patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from from your
heart at hotmail.com everything else you
could possibly imagine is an
iriegenetics.com yeah I know I said that
quite quickly everything is at
iregenetics.com there will be a link to
the Discord a link to the patreon a link
to the seeds a link to the merch
everything you could imagine is there of
course the grow help tab you can sign up
to the newsletter it's all on the
website
iregenetics.com all right I think that
is all I've got for you for this week
I've got to go clean up some water and
some stinky carpet I'll be back next
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Rusty
Nails and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
foreign
[Music]
thank you