foreign
[Music]
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
my friends call me Rasta Jeff this is
episode 784 of the grow from your heart
podcast I've got a fun show lined up for
us before we jump in let's do a few
shout outs to a few of those great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow from your heart podcast thank you
shout out to 420 and the 520. let's send
a big fist bump into thank you shout out
to nailed it indoors let's send a big
thank you shout out to my friends Tim
and Amy let's send a big thank you shout
out to one of my favorite photographers
doc grows let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to Double D and
Jacob M I want to send a big thank you
shout out to zardnock let's send a
special thank you shout out to Badlands
let's send a big fist bump to my buddy
phillipong let's send a special thank
you shout out to Monster Mash I want to
send a big thank you shout out to more
Terps then let's wrap it all up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to bee Bala big thanks and
big shout out to everybody who continues
to support the show on patreon if you
are not already supporting the show and
you would like to learn how to do so all
you have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it nice and easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast before we
get too far into the show I want to talk
about a great comedy show that I got to
see yesterday I want to give a shout out
to my friends at Comedy Works for
treating on myself and missed red Vibes
like rockstars we were treated like
royalty big up fist bump shout out to
everybody at Comedy Works thank you for
the great service the hospitality and
then extra thank you to all of the
comedians that we did get to see last
night everybody was on fire last night
it was such a great show the show was
opened up by a comedian known as AJ
Finney the dude was on fire he was
hilarious we definitely connected we
have a lot of [ __ ] in common if you ever
go see his comedy you will know what I'm
talking about the dude is called AJ
Finney uh then we are greeted by a dude
named Brant tobler I've seen Brant
tobler set several times he is hilarious
and last night he was on fire he's
getting even better and then of course
the show was headlined by a dude called
Ian Finance Ian is always super
energetic super uh Super Hyper it seems
like he's on drugs but he swears he's
not that's part of his gimmick he says
he hasn't done drugs in several years he
says that he just did enough to where
it's still in him and I kind of believe
it so the show was great shout out to
Comedy Works shout out to all of the
performers shout out to the crew at
Comedy Works for treating us like rock
stars extra fist bump and a big hug to
miss dread Vibes for making it a great
evening you guys go see some Live Comedy
I laughed so hard that my uh I don't
even really have abs but the the where
my ABS should go though they kind of
hurt today and the I laughed so hard
that there's I like was reaching to move
my sunglasses on my head last night
because it felt like I had my sunglasses
on my head too long and it because it
was hurting in a weird spot so you guys
go see some comedy go take too many dabs
in the car then go check out some good
comedy because that is a great time I
think that's all I really wanted to
ramble about here at the start of the
show let's talk some business this
episode of the show is brought to you by
our friends at seedshearnow.com our
friends at seedshairnow.com are going to
give away a pack of irie genetic seeds
here on the podcast we will talk more
about that later in the show I want to
jump into a YouTube comment I really
like this comment I don't read a lot of
YouTube comments on the podcast here
they've got to be good comments they do
uh I don't see all of the YouTube
comments there are a lot of them I don't
check them as frequently as diligently
as I should maybe but I did like this
one this one did stand out to me it came
from our friend Zachary Johnson big up
to Zachary Johnson thank you for
listening to the podcast my friend it
says I am loving the older episodes as
much as the new weapons episodes thank
you that's a reminder you guys this is
episode
784. there are 783 other episodes on
YouTube that you may not have listened
to I encourage you I invite you I
implore you is that the correct word
here is that the correct use of that
word somebody check my grammar uh
comment about it I encourage you to go
listen to those old episodes just
because they're old because they weren't
put out today doesn't mean there's not a
lot of gems a lot of gold information in
those podcasts it's still very useful
info uh very educational informative and
entertaining podcasting if I do say so
myself so I encourage you guys to go
check out all of those older episodes
people say hey dude I miss you putting
out two episodes a week I used to do
that it's overwhelming I can't do it uh
they say I wish there was more
podcasting there's a lot of old [ __ ]
that I bet you didn't even listen to go
check it out on YouTube it's good stuff
you will learn a lot it also goes on to
say it's also nice to see that your
opinions and methods have changed over
the years which means we are learning uh
yeah yes absolutely I wanted to talk
about that briefly here my opinions my
methods my Approach my understanding has
changed so much over the past few years
since I started this show I'm probably
coming up on I don't know if it's seven
or eight years since I've started this
podcast 785 episodes so that's at least
five six maybe seven years I've been
doing this show if I haven't changed my
ideas my methods my Approach my
techniques my understanding that I was
not doing anything right at all I was
standing still so I've learned so much
I've gone from being a a small closet
grower to a tent grower to a basement
grower to a trap house grower to a
semi-commercial quasi-legal commercial
grower to a full-on commercial
cultivator to a commercial cultivation
consultant I've gone a long way in my
cultivation career there was a lot of c
word letters in that sentence it was
really hard not to stumble over all that
but I've been in this cultivation game
for so long that if my methods
techniques and ideas didn't change over
all of those drastic shifts I would have
not gotten anywhere I had to learn on
the fly when I went from a tent from a
closet grow to a tent grow is a totally
different environment totally different
ball game everything was different the
airflow was completely different when I
went from the tent to the basement grow
or the one room in the basement grow
that was a full-on different ball game
than when I opened up the entire
basement and put the grow in there that
was a fully different ball game then we
started building trap houses and
flooding those with plants and lights
and that was a totally different
situation trying to deduct the heat from
one room to another because the other
room was getting too cold and I learned
so many things just by doing it trial by
fire is kind of how I say it happened
then I got thrown into the commercial
growing environment that was such a huge
learning curve when I jumped into that I
was doing I was hand mixing bottled
nutrients in a little cup and just hand
watering plants and then it was time to
go into the big boy grow and mix up 300
gallon reservoirs and make sure I'm
getting that [ __ ] right and document
everything thing and then water every
plant properly it went from hand
watering every plant myself to having
machines where I could push a button and
500 plants would get water all at once
and it was amazing but it was such a
learning curve if I did everything the
same now that I did uh back in the day
in my first couple of grows it would not
work things would fail the
um first of all my education just from
doing it being around the plant I've
learned so much it's like almost any job
or art or skill that you develop the
more you do it you're going to get
better at it you're going to see things
if you're paying attention you're going
to see things and start learning the
signs and the hints and you'll be ahead
of I may see a Calcium deficiency before
most people I may see a nitrogen problem
before some people I may hear an
environmental piece of equipment go
wrong before some people just because
I've been there so much I'm not saying
I've been there more than you I just
I've been there a lot so I've got a lot
of experience but having done all of
these tasks so many times I'm very
comfortable and very familiar with these
things and I see things and start
learning things and I take in data very
quickly and I've got a good data process
assessing Center in my brain and I can
just see I get warnings a little more
quickly my check engine light will come
on before most people's and it'll
identify a problem before most people
I'll see that Calcium deficiency maybe
maybe before the other grower I may see
that nitrogen deficiency I may notice an
environmental Factor went wrong some
machine broke down just being in the
growth so long has made it so easy for
me to identify things but what I had to
do quickly was adjust to new equipment
when I got into the commercial grow
everything was bigger everything was
industrial grade I'm not buying things
for uh just a whole bunch of small
Walmart dehumidifiers like we used to do
in the tent grow I have to go buy big
quests and Danby dehumidifiers it's a
big 30 to our three ton 30 ton air
conditioners now it's a big difference
than it used to be running the 12 000
BTU air conditioner in the basement so
so many things have changed so
everything has changed the plants have
changed I have changed the technology
has changed uh the technology has come
so far the lighting is way different
when I was first doing this everybody
was running HP s lights everybody was
using big gigantic fixtures now we've
all got a bunch of little tiny LED
lights back in the day was so much air
conditioning had to be used now that the
lights are better we don't have to use
so much air conditioning the skills the
growing the plants have come a long way
we've got better plants we've got better
plants available to us we've got better
nutrients we've got better technology
we've got access to so much information
with legalization now I can Google so
much stuff before people in non-legal
States would be afraid just to Google
how to grow their plants because they
may get in trouble for that somehow they
didn't know how but they knew it was
possible maybe they'll get in trouble
just for their damn Google search so
technology has brought us a long way I
have come a long way if you guys are
still trying to grow the way that you
grew two three five years ago
you've got to adjust and adapt learn a
few more things maybe find some new
equipment don't be the dinosaur don't be
stuck in the old technology I do believe
if it ain't broke don't fix it but if we
don't try new things how do we improve
how do we get better don't be afraid to
take some risks and try new things every
artist that you've ever heard about
every musician every filmmaker everybody
that's been successful that you have
heard of has taken a major risk in their
career and had faith in their skills
that they were going to do it so have
faith in yourself in the grow don't keep
doing the same [ __ ] you've been doing
for the past five years it's a new year
this episode is going to come out right
around the second week of January start
this New Year by learning some new
skills we said we were going to learn
some new [ __ ] take a risk what's the
risk you're going to take this year in
your grow to learn and improve so don't
be afraid to learn some [ __ ] I have come
a long way if you listen to the old
episodes and you hear that I was doing
this and mixing this way and watering
this way and doing this and I say
something different now don't say ooh he
changed he said something different say
oh that guy involved and he's doing
things differently because in his
experience his research he's noticed
maybe there was a better way and he's
trying something different and I try to
share that with you guys I know a lot of
people really follow my guidance my
advice you buy the products I recommend
I appreciate that that's why I don't go
recommending a lot of products because
um it's you can grow with a lot of great
things but I like some specific [ __ ]
find what works really well for you and
don't be afraid to switch it up and try
a new [ __ ] all right um there has been a
big evolution in me as a person in the
grow in my business and in the podcast
and thank you for noticing my friend
Zachary Johnson now I did say that this
episode was going to be about powdery
mildew I've gotten several messages and
emails about powdery mildew somebody
even brought it up on my Instagram live
show recently they say how can I get
this powdery mildew off of the buds will
spraying it get rid of the powdery
mildew what can I do the quick answer is
yes you can spray some products on your
plants to get rid of the powdery mildew
it will not look like it's there it will
wash it off your clients customers
whoever will never know that it was
there you can even do a bud wash at the
end make it super clean but guess what
if you don't correct the entire room the
entire situation that powdery mildew
will keep coming back there's something
more than just powdery mildew causing
the powdery mildew that is a a symptom
that is a sign that there's a problem
something is wrong in the room and is
being shown to you by powdery mildew it
is probably an airflow problem it's
probably a moisture problem it comes
down to most likely a VPD problem that
is a vapor pressure deficit problem that
is a math equation evolving your
temperature and humidity if you don't
understand that it's not too important
we will stick with temperature and
humidity a lot of times when the lights
go off in the grow space the humidity
spikes often times when the lights come
on in the grow space the humidity spikes
those spikes you're getting a high
humidity point in the room the plants
are not prepared for that your
ventilation equipment is not prepared
for that you're getting a big spike in
there that that is oftentimes what
triggers the powdery mildew so one thing
I would recommend is correcting the
spikes that happen when the lights come
on and when the lights go off I mean
temperature spikes because it's been
whatever degrees in the room and now the
light either goes off or comes on it's
going to change probably somewhere
between 7 and 12 degrees quite quickly
in that room the temperature is going to
spike or drop if the lights going off or
on and that's going to affect the
humidity tremendously depending on the
size of the room how many plants you've
got in there that will affect the
humidity really strongly I would
recommend getting some sort of a
monitoring system that will real time
monitor the relative humidity the
temperature and even possibly do the
equation and monitor the vapor pressure
deficit in your grow space at all times
then look at the chart after two or
three days of cycling on and off and see
what's happening it lights on and lights
off see how those spikes are going then
let's figure out if we can set up some
sort of airflow system is there an
exhaust vent or an exhaust fan or blower
that we can turn off or on at the
correct times to correct this spike in
humidity maybe it's a drop in humidity
depends on what's going on in your room
also it greatly depends on what's going
on in the adjacent rooms if you're if
your grow is up against the outside so
this wall right here is an exterior wall
if it grows up against that and it's
snowy outside you got different
opportunities for different climate
changes when that light goes off if it's
uh that's uh that's honestly a bathroom
on the other side of that wall so if the
Grove is in there it wouldn't be as
drastic of a change when the lights go
off because this room is temperature
controlled so that's also going to play
into some of your humidity and
temperature and uh VPD swings in your
light change another thing to think
about is something I kind of mentioned a
moment ago when the lights go off and
when the lights go on how drastic is
that temperature swing a moment ago I
did mention the temperature change when
the lights go off and on I did say that
it would be somewhere between 7 and 12
degrees I wouldn't like to do much more
than that when the lights go off or go
on I like to keep that daytime at night
time temperature is close to the same as
I can as possible but no more than 10 to
12 degrees in difference between your
day and night temperature if it's 87
degrees in there with the lights on and
it gets lower than 77 maybe like 75 74
73 that big temperature swing does give
you the opportunity to get powdery
mildew in that room the main things I
would think about is keeping the air
moving in the room don't let stagnant
air stay in the room exhaust and replace
that air in the room do you have an
exhaust fan removing the stagnant
humidity out of the room do you have
passive intakes do you have active
intakes bringing fresh air into that
room somehow I like to bring fresh air
in low and suck that old hot humid air
out at the top are you doing something
like that to replace replenish and
recycle that air you don't want that old
air in the room all the time we need
fresh air so let's have old Air going
out new air coming in let's keep plenty
of fresh air moving around then let's
avoid micro climates in a big grow you
may have fans every three to six feet or
something like that but there's so let's
say that there's a light right there
there really is a light right there we
don't have to pretend you could see it
reflecting off my hand there's a light
right there also they're about two or
three feet away from my hands let's say
that maybe right here where the iPad is
that might not get enough airflow
because there may be a plant here and a
plant here in a plant here in a plant
here and all around and hear a plant and
they're a plant everywhere a plant plant
but guess what right here by the iPod
maybe over here by the microphone just
maybe might not get enough airflow
because the canopy is built up so
densely you're going to create micro
climates and here is going to be a
completely different climate than over
there by the lights and up here by the
top of the canopy and over here and over
here this is going to be it's all it
might be slightly different everywhere
so have a good movement of air maybe put
a fan on the floor blowing the air back
up maybe get a Howitzer fan and hang it
from the ceiling what that fan does
instead of blowing the air left and
right it sucks the air up so the air
that is down low it pulls it up and
shoots it up to the ceiling and stirs
the air so if you're operating with CO2
2 the CO2 is heavier it will fall to the
floor the Howitzer fan will pick it up
bring it up towards your plants again
shoot it to the ceiling it's heavy so it
will fall again mixed with the oxygen
it'll keep cycling back in So if you're
running CO2 definitely use that Howitzer
fan or a fan on the floor pointing up
but my point is avoid micro climates we
want air moving around another way we
can prevent powdery mildew is to keep
leaves from touching each other the
plants need a little bit of space the
leaves can touch each other but not
excessively if you've got two plants
give them some Breathing Room think
about uh if I just walked up to you in a
room at a warm grow space and I just put
my hand on your shoulder all day it's
not that annoying but after a while it's
going to get hot it's going to get a
little bit sweaty it's going to get
uncomfortable imagine the leaves of the
plants just touching each other all day
they don't want that that also tells
them you shouldn't grow out any wider
you've got to grow up and get stretchy
because there's nowhere else for you to
go this way so go up so keep your plants
a little bit give them some growing
distance give them some space another
thing thing I'm going to recommend is
don't over water your plants understand
how much water to put into that room the
amount of water that you put into those
pots is how much water those plants let
back out into the air if you're over
watering they're going to let out more
water there's also going to be naturally
more water in the air so pay attention
to your watering and also your watering
schedule that could have something to do
with it I like to water if possible
right when the lights come on as soon as
they come on get them wet get them
watered right then that way they've got
all day to drink that water when the
lights go off they've got all night to
metabolize that's the most productive
way to water the plants in my opinion if
you're running Hydro if you're running
cocoa water as needed I understand we've
evolved so far we've changed like I said
a moment ago shit's different now people
are doing hydro and stuff also let me
stay focused here another thing you can
do is defoliate take off some of that
excessive leaves also so if your pot is
here maybe take off the lower six inches
of just leafy junk on the bottom of that
plant because that can trap a little
like I said before a micro climate that
lower area of the canopy all the water
goes into that pot the lights get warm
the water starts going up that area
right there at the bottom that's where
you're going to find a lot of humidity
you'll see a lot of powdery mildew start
right there in that area so you can do
defoliation you can do a little bit of
lollipopping and cleaning up the bottoms
of your plants that will definitely help
minimize the options of powdery mildew
but the main thing you've got to do is
treat the room if we don't repair treat
and correct the room the powdery mildew
will keep coming back get your exhaust
fan dialed in get your intake fan dialed
in get your airflow dialed in get all of
your fans in the right place get the
humidifier and the dehumidifier dialed
in so get that temperature dialed in get
your humidity dialed in get the overall
vapor pressure deficit dialed in in the
room then make sure that you've got
plenty of air movement air circulation
then make sure that you've got air
replacement make sure you've got an
exhaust fan removing that old Air make
sure you've got some sort of intake is
there a way for fresh air to get into
that that room also are you
supplementing with CO2 if you're
supplementing maybe don't get rid of all
that air as frequently but do keep that
air moving around as often as possible
then give the plants a little bit of
space give them some room defoliate them
don't over water and that should help
you with your powdery mildew problems
there are a thousand products that I
could tell you to spray on these plants
there are a thousand things I could tell
you to do to these plants but unless we
treat the room this powdery mildew will
keep coming back so the first thing
we've got to do is correct all of the
issues in the room maybe the first thing
we've got to do is identify why we are
getting the powdery mildew so we've got
to check that temperature the humidity
the VPD we've got to make sure we've got
circulation and air replacement then
let's also check on the temperature and
humidity changes when the lights go on
and the lights go off make sure the
humidity is not getting too drastic at
that time make sure it's not getting too
hot or too cold and that should help to
get rid of or at least to minimize
powdery mildew problems another thing
we've got to think about is strain
selection if you know that you're in an
area where you can't control the
humidity properly especially a
greenhouse or Outdoors that's when it
does come to selecting proper strains
for your environment all right that was
my quick report on powdery mildew I hope
I helped out your garden at the start of
the show I did say that we were going to
give away a pack of seeds this seed
giveaway is sponsored by my friends at
seedshairnow.com make sure you check out
seedshairnow.com for their current sales
their current inventory once again
seedshearnow.com now quickly it is real
easy to win a pack of seeds on this
episode all you have to do is comment on
the YouTube video let me know why you
think seedshairnow.com should give you a
free pack of irie genetic seeds that's
right go leave a comment on this episode
on the YouTube channel and let me know
simply why seeds here now.com should
give you a free pack of irie Genetics
seeds alright ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls pimps and hoes friends and
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Shuckers All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns I would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from yourheart hotmail.com don't
be shy send me your grow questions send
me all your feedback I would love to
hear from you also make sure you check
out the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else you could possibly need
is on my website at
iregenetics.com all right that's all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back in one full week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy newbie nugs and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you