[Music]
all right now here we go welcome to the
show everybody I'm your host my friends
call me Rasta Jeff this is episode
786 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to answer some
listener emails before we get to that
part of the show let's do a few shout
outs to a few of the great folks who
continue to support the show on patreon
let's kick it off with a big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to dreadlock farmer let's send a fist
bump and a thank you shout out to Canna
fugit and grow Dad let's send a big fist
bump to Simeon and ADHD grower let's
send a big thank you shout out to a long
time supporter our friend Nomi by my
guacamole listen to fist bump and a
thank you shout out to alarm Knight
Rises and Noah and I want to send a big
thank you shout out to Kip let's send a
thank you shout out to you betcha let's
send a fist bump to a long time
supporter our friend Jeff oh then let's
wrap it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to
levity love day big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
and you know I do include a link in the
show notes and in the video description
to make it super easy for all of my
friends to support the podcast in the
last episode I did talk about doing a
seed giveaway that's right our friends
at seedshernow.com are sponsoring a seed
giveaway the winner of the seed giveaway
on the last episode was our friend Zach
Voss congratulations to Zach Voss all
you've got to do my friend is send me an
email let me know which package of seeds
you were hoping for if I've got those
seeds in stock I will send them to you
however not everything is available and
in in stock so you may get a surprise
package you may get some extra packs you
never know what I may do but Zach please
do send me an email the email address of
course is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com if you did not win that free
pack of seeds on this episode do not be
discouraged because guess what we're
going to give away another pack of seeds
toward the end of the show so that's
right stay tuned keep listening because
seedshairnow.com and Irene genetics have
teamed up to give away another pack of
seeds on this podcast all right I don't
want to ramble too far it seems like I
get really good at that I've got a lot
to cover let's jump into the email
portion of today's podcast the first
episode on today's podcast came from our
friend who would like to be referred to
as Soul Train Big Shots my friend Soul
Train the message goes just like this it
says yo Rasta Jeff if you should happen
to reference on this show please refer
to me as Soul Train what's up Soul Train
thank you for all the support my dude
the message continues it says I am
working my way through all of your older
podcasts and I just listened to episode
number 580. that's a lot of catching up
up to do thanks for listening to all the
old episodes you guys uh people keep
asking me for more content new content
multiple podcasts a week it's hard for
me to do that right now with my uh my
work and living and my whole life
situation uh one podcast is a week a
week is what I can do but there are a
lot of older episodes that you can go
back and listen to there are many many
episodes there are apparently 785
episodes before this one that you can go
back and listen to unfortunately YouTube
has taken down a few of those if I show
plants in the videos YouTube likes to
take down those videos so there's a
video where I cut clones that they took
down there's a video about popping and
twisting and lollipopping that they have
taken down uh they've taken down a lot
of the videos where I do any sort of
consumption but YouTube takes some down
other than YouTube taking them down most
of the videos are still up and available
uh 785 other videos the first 20 videos
uh the podcast was called something
different it was called I grow culture
for a little while for 20 episodes then
I was informed politely and gently with
the uh by the form of a season desist
letter that I grow culture was already
something being used and I could not use
that so we promptly changed the name to
the grow from your heart podcast my
point is those first 20 episodes are
shared in a playlist on the girl from
your heart podcast on YouTube if you go
to my playlist you can find those or if
you search igrow culture podcast those
first 20 episodes do come up so 780-ish
episodes are available of this show so
you guys if you haven't had enough of
this rambling of this beautiful face of
this amazing voice uh please go back and
listen to those previous episodes our
friend here uh Soul Train just listen to
number 580 and they say in that podcast
you answered a listener question
concerning purple petioles and you
mentioned if the plan is also showing
crispy leaves it is likely too much
light yes uh that from what I've read in
the rest of your email that is
definitely the case of what's going on
here so let me just keep going it says
you will be pleased that the least
affected strains in the grow are the
machine and the blue pill with the blue
pill being far by far the happiest
looking plant in the tent
it goes on though it says well I'm only
in my first indoor grow with several
different strains and about half of the
plants have purple petioles and all of
them now are getting some crispy looking
leaves with this being worse on the more
purple petiole plants so the plants that
have the more purple petals are showing
the purple crispy problem I'm just
trying to put a bunch of peas into a
sense to be silly there we get what's
going on here it says however at six
weeks into 12 12 the buds on all of the
plants are looking good so this you just
keep us solidifying the idea that yes
the light is too intense is what's going
on here it says I am growing in a 5x5
tent with an hlg scorpion Diablo light
I'm not super familiar with that light I
have heard a lot about it I know that
hlg makes great [ __ ] I know a lot of
people run that line I know that it is
quite powerful it says I had the light
set 16 inches over the canopy at 50
intensity and things were getting crispy
about 10 days ago I lifted the light to
26 inches over the canopy at 50
intensity and the plants sure do look
happier so we're giving supporting
statements supporting evidence that this
is probably a light issue you've got
that light a little bit too close maybe
turned up too high you did the right
thing you raised that plan when you get
those new LED lights I would definitely
do whoever you are I'm talking to
everybody out there if you get a new LED
light
I highly recommend doing some research
research that particular light find out
how far they recommend you put that
plant or that light from your canopy and
then go a little bit further and then
also reduce the intensity a little bit
more than they recommend like we've seen
here these plants they've taken too much
light they will start to burn the leaves
will start to crisp up they'll turn
purple they will slow down the growth
things will go wrong if you get too much
light the leaves crisp up and you can't
fix that if you're not getting enough
light the plants will start to stretch
and get a little bit extended we can
turn up the light and fix that more
easily than we can take back the crispy
Leaf so start lower and slowly ramp
yourself up that's going to be something
we talk about here toward the end of
this message it does go on it says I did
spend a bunch of money did I spend a
bunch of money on the wrong light also
is there a strategy I can use for the
remaining four weeks that will will
allow me to increase the intensity
setting on the light for my next girl I
believe I will induce CO2
supplementation that will absolutely
help it'll help with food uptake it'll
help the plants take more light and also
help them manage a little bit more heat
but then it says thanks for all you do
signed from your friend Soul Train
there's a little personal joke in there
that I almost read out loud that is just
between us I cannot share that with you
fist want for the funny joke bro
so our friend Soul Train you are
absolutely right uh by moving that light
up by assuming that the light was too
intense one of the major questions that
you ask in here is did I spend a bunch
of money on the wrong light I don't
think so I think if you Ray if you
lifted the light to the top of the tent
and turn it down and the plants are
small that intensity for the small plant
should work out and then here's what I
want to talk about what I would have
done it's too late to do this now this
is what I'm going to suggest you do in
the future and on future runs what I
would do is raise that light all the way
up and turn it as low as it will let you
go that's probably 50 or 30 percent most
of those lights only go down to about 50
or 30. so raise the light turn it down
then start your seedlings or your small
plants down on the very low part of that
tent so you've got as much space as
possible then pay attention to how those
plants are acting do you need to lower
the light a little bit or do you need to
raise the intensity a little bit pay
attention if they're getting stretchy if
they're getting leggy they may want a
little bit more light I may recommend
lowering that light at this time just a
little tiny bit and do not increase the
intensity just lower the light down so
that you can get that light closer to
the plants then as the plants begin to
grow you can turn that light up just a
little bit I would say turn it up just a
small fraction just maybe five percent
maybe ten percent just a little bit as
they start growing then if you start
seeing shaded shadowy areas in the tin
the plants aren't growing the maximum
efficiency maybe turn it up just a
little bit then raise that light all the
way to the top and then now what I do
know is when I use the Canon LEDs is
that I like to have them about 50
intensity when I put my plants into
flour so I start I think those go to
like 30 percent then I start vegging I
slowly crank them up they veg a little
more I slowly crank them up they veg a
little more I slowly crank them up by
the time I go into flour my lights are
at 50 intensity then every week or two I
just knock it up just a little bit so
you're gonna get 10 weeks in flour in
there we want to go up to me I don't
even know if we need to go to 100 you've
got to pay attention to what the plants
need which is going to lead me into the
next part that I want to talk about but
I would slowly ramp that up don't go
from low intensity just cranking it all
up all the way I would start low and
then slowly over we've got these plants
in there for 100 days go from 50 to 100
percent over that hundred day period you
may not even need to Max it all the way
out there's something that we do need to
think about though
um we can give them too much light we
can also give them the wrong Spectrum if
they're not getting the right color then
that's too much wasted light but
something else we should talk about is
DLI the plants will take up so much
light and then they will simply have had
enough and they will shut off so you can
save electricity you can save lighting
by figuring out the DLI of your specific
plant The Daily Light integral hit that
point and then reduce or cut off the
lights to save that electricity and that
Photon energy now there's something else
we should talk about this is uh the
technical way to figure out if your
plants are getting enough light this is
going to take some equipment you need a
par meter here some sort of a meter that
will read how much light is getting to
your plants some of the cell phone
makers do have a decent app for a par
meter however I would recommend a real
power meter for this the cell phone apps
are not a hundred percent perfect yet
now if you're going to use a par meter
we are looking for a range of 500 to 700
ppfd now what is ppfd this was all this
term was all the rage all the uh this
was the hot phrase it used to be Terps
for a minute uh and then it was
phenotype for a little while and then uh
for a little while ppfd was the the word
in the grow industry what is ppfd that
is photosynthetic Photon flux density
what does that really mean
um I don't understand a lot about
lighting let me admit right now when it
comes to Lighting in cannabis that is
where I lack knowledge I know about the
plants I understand the processes of the
plants I understand soil I understand
most of everything that needs to be done
to a cannabis plant but lighting my
brain uh just doesn't want to absorb
that bit of information my brain isn't
interested and my brain's not interested
I just have a hard time learning about
that [ __ ] I have a very uh a rudimentary
understanding of lighting so let me try
to teach you a very General
understanding of ppfd photosynthetic
Photon flux density right I think I said
it correctly even okay think about this
this is how we measure say that you've
got your light above you imagine you
could see little raindrops of light
falling down that's basically what we're
measuring how many raindrops of light
are coming down from your light and
we'll measure at certain distances from
that light to find out the intensity of
that light at certain distances so at
your canopy I would use a par meter and
the desired ppfd at canopy level is
between 500 and 700 that is the range
that you were looking for you need a par
meter or an app or an app on your phone
to find that that is not something that
you can do with your eyes you need a
meter for that so you'd hold the meter
right at canopy level and see is that
between 500 and 700 ppfd if it's too hot
too much light of course turn those
lights down or raise the light if it's
too much do the opposite increase the
light or lower the light closer to the
plants the thing is when you lower the
light you get a little bit more Shadow
area because it's not spreading as far
but it is more intense if you raise that
light you will get less Shadows but it
is not intense so that's one of the
things that you've got to figure out
there so
um a thousand is really high if you're
hitting that thousand ppfd your plants
are going to start showing problems if
you're under 500 you're not going to get
that optimal growth once again uh it
seems to me in my studies and the
Cannabis realm and everything I've
looked at online uh they're between 500
and 700 ppfd is ideal for our ganja
plants so I think you are spot on with
your first assumption that these plants
are just getting a little bit too much
light then the second part of your
question was your concern that you spent
too much money on this light and you
wasted all that money on too much light
for your space I don't think that is the
case I think you've got a good quality
light I think if we figure out how far
to keep that light from the canopy then
we'll be in big business because that's
a quality life that's a good company and
I've never heard bad things about that
light so as long as we keep the
appropriate distance between the light
and the canopy and we turn that light
down onto the appropriate ppfd the right
intensity then we should get that dialed
in another thing the main thing I'm
going to recommend is slowly ramping up
the intensity of that light we don't
need all of the light on the seedlings
they just need a little bit of light and
as they get bigger then they can
metabolize more they can be more
functional they can handle more light so
maybe wait till they're a little bit
bigger to start giving them that super
intense light so my main advice is to
next time slowly ramp up that light and
then pay attention to the ppfd if you
can get that par meter and measure the
ppfd at canopy level you will be golden
my friend alright Soul Train thanks once
again for the great message uh you were
six weeks into flower when you sent this
you have probably harvested by now I'm
really curious how did this crop turn
out how did it look how did it smell
have you got to sample it yet and also
let's get that next crop on track if
you've got any questions please do reach
out we'll get you going all right this
next email came from our friend Zach J
big shout out to our buddy Zach J for
the good question this one goes a little
bit like this it says yoga pasta Jeff I
just discovered what I believe are white
flies and or fungus gnats the first
thing I would do there bro is identify
if you've got white flies and or fungus
gnats or both uh it's very possible that
you've got both it's very likely that
you've got both but if you've only got
one or the other it may be easier to
treat for just one if we know more
specifically what we are targeting or we
may have to use multiple methods of
attack here but the first step is
identify which one you are battling are
they white do they look like a little
piece of rice on the stems when you tap
the pots does it look like ashes come
flying out or are they little black bugs
those are the fungus gnats the white
ones are the white flies that should be
obvious let's identify which one we've
got in the grow then it goes on there's
a little bit here that we're going to
skip but then it goes on to say I've
already ordered neem oil without doing a
whole lot of research do you have any
thoughts on neem oil also does a new
layer of all-purpose sand on top of the
soil change the way I need to feed or
water my plants at all much love and
respect from Zach all right this is a
great question white flies and fungus
gnats are very very common in a grow
they come in house plants they come in
all of the soil if you buy a bagged
potting soil a soilless mix almost
anything in a bag from a grow store
whether it's like your local Randy's
grow or Mike's grow shop or if it's grow
generation or way to grow or if it's
Home Depot or Lowe's or even Target had
Fox Farm soil the last time I was there
all of that soil
people want to blame specific Brands I
got this bug from this soil that soil's
got this bug in it now bro all the bugs
are in all of the soil they are made in
different places but then they're
shipped to a warehouse where they're all
put on a pallet together on a dock
together put on a pallet put on a truck
and moved around the country together do
you think the white flies went I like I
like Fox Farms better or hey I like
Roots Organics better they went there's
a bunch of places to live and they went
in all the [ __ ] soil and they lived
in all of it it's just all about where
that soil came from was stored how it
traveled what it got exposed to it's
your responsibility as the farmer to
make sure that there are no bugs in your
soil anyway my point is the white flies
and fungus gnats they're very easy to
get they come from all over the place
they're very common I bet many many
Growers have had them in their grow the
fungistats are not that big of a deal
when there's only a couple of them
they're just kind of annoying they're
gross they bug you they make the
pictures look like [ __ ] they remind you
that you over watered a little bit but
once you get a lot of fungus gnats then
they can become a vector for disease if
you've got problem in one plant those
fungus gnats will just move that root
disease right over to the other plants
or whatever is going on if you've got a
small problem and fungus gnats the
problem compounds same thing with the
white flies
a couple of white flies they just look
annoying after a little bit get a bunch
of white flies and it's gross and you're
like I've got a major [ __ ] problem
that's just a hint of the overall health
of the garden so white flies and fungus
gnats are very common one of the most
common causes of these bugs is simply
well they come in they get in that's
they're not caused they arrive but the
reason they stick around is because of
over watering they like to be around in
that moist soil that soil right around
where your pot drips into the saucer
right around there where there's always
that little bit of there's a dry spot
for them to be safe but enough moisture
for them to lay some eggs have a party
get some water it feels like the Bahamas
there for them that's where they like to
chill the white flies like to chill just
above the top of the soil and climb up
your sticks they like to live right on
the the stalks of your plants there's a
very common bugs they're very easy to
get rid of now the first question the
first attempt here was that our listener
Zach Jay thought about using neem
I'm going to cut you off right there I
do not like neem oil for anything there
is no application for neem in my garden
in fact uh in the state of Colorado
according to the Colorado Department of
Health and environment and the Colorado
Department of Ag and the Colorado
medical are the Colorado marijuana
enforcement division all neem based
products are banned in commercial
cultivation we can't use Neiman cannabis
at all legally in commercial cultivation
in Colorado we can do it in our home
grow because we're not regulated but I
refuse to use neem for several reasons
first of all a tasting smells like [ __ ]
if you get neem on your gloves on your
skin on your clothes anywhere it's going
to stink so bad forever and it never
ever goes away if you've ever tasted
neem it is one of the worst tasting
things ever if you smoke flowers or a
concentrated product and it tastes a
little bit fishy and oily and maybe a
little bit spicy that possibly probably
was because there was neem oil applied
to that flower the neem oil never goes
away it's going to be there forever in
my opinion I think I can always taste it
that might be in my mind but I think
neem is gross and also there are many
toxic traits to neem neem has been
banned in many countries for many uses
uh it's known to do reproductive damage
to men and women and it's not good uh
for the environment or your body so
there are a few reasons why I don't
recommend to use neem
um it just tastes like [ __ ] and it
doesn't go away and there are better
options uh now that I told you I don't
like the product you said that you've
already ordered which I do apologize for
uh let's talk about products that will
help you to get rid of these white flies
and or fungus gnats the first thing uh
Step One is let's identify positively
identify what we are battling if we're
battling just white flies I'm going to
recommend uh just one product if we're
battling fungus gnats I'm going to
recommend a different product if we've
got them both we may mix up these
products together and spray them at the
same time it depends on how strong these
bugs are attacking uh and which one it
is if there's fungus gnats they're in
the they're more living in the soil if
they're white flies they're a little bit
in the soil and more on the stalks and
under the foliage of the plants two
different uh means of treatment two
different modes of attack but let's talk
about it let's identify the bugs that
you've got that is the very first step
the second step is let's stop over
watering these plants you did address
that here in the message you understand
that part of the problem is from over
watering let's reduce the water also is
there standing water I don't know if
your grow is in a commercial building if
it's in your home if it's in a hotel if
it's a train station if it's in the city
if it's on a farm I don't know any of
those environmental factors but possibly
you've got water standing somewhere else
or a source of moisture somewhere else
those white flies and fungus gnats will
be drawn to that source of moisture as
well as well as all of the other insects
they're going to come to the water first
Warm Water Aroma the bugs are going to
show up so let's get rid of the water
the over water the excessive water the
lingering moisture they're like
mosquitoes they're going to come where
there's water so let's get rid of that
now let's identify a couple of
pesticides that I would recommend mid
for let's start with the white flies if
you've just got white flies I would do a
little bit of defoliation you probably
need to defoliate anyway the white flies
are going to be hiding under the leaves
let's pull off some leaves let's glove
up let's put on some clothes we don't
really like a whole lot and go defoliate
let's just go manually remove a bunch of
the white flies from the room and also
remove their hotel take away their party
spot they won't come to party so let's
defoliate a little bit put all of those
defoliated leaves into a trash bag that
you can tie up and seal and remove from
The Grow environment if you've got a
fire pit put that bad [ __ ] in the fire
pit and burn those [ __ ] leaves get
rid of them we don't want those white
flies coming back let's do a little bit
of defoliation now here's another trick
that you may laugh at but this is
definitely going to work I get a shop
vac and I put the shop vac nozzles kind
of big I've got a little tapered device
that makes the shop vac nozzle smaller I
will smack the plants with a stick and
as the white flies come flying out I
suck them up at the shop vac they're
going to fly directly to the light stay
right there near the light smack the
plant they come flying out you're just
sucking them up as they come out that's
one good way to get rid of them you're
going to suck up a bunch into the vacuum
if you've got the shop vac with the
filter bag in there I recommend that
because they're tiny uh you want to
catch the little [ __ ] so defoliate
shop vac a bunch of them off then at
this point this is what I wouldn't
consider when I would consider a foliar
application of a product called Monterey
Garden spray I usually don't recommend
specific products nobody pays me for
this this is the product to use for this
um there is a beneficial bacteria in
Monterey Garden spray I call it BT it
may be pronounced bacillus thuringisis
or something similar to that I'm not the
best guy at pronouncing [ __ ] but I can
read well I can see it on the paper I
recognize it that ingredient and that
product is going to eliminate the white
flies it a fungus it is a fungus that
occurs and they bought in the bottom of
rum barrels and they've learned how to
make a pesticide out of that we apply
that to the plants it is basically
harmless to the plants but the white
flies they want nothing to do with it so
that BT will get rid of the white flies
the that will also slow down your fungus
gnats now let's focus more on the fungus
gnat and the white fly combination let's
say you got both of these bad [ __ ]
attacking the garden the white flies
like I mentioned are going to stay
mainly on the foliage they may go a
little bit into your dirt but they're
going to stay mostly on the foliage
mostly on the underside of the leaves
the fungus gnats are going to burrow
down into the soil so the fungus gnats
are going to be down in your roots so to
take care of them we need to do more
than just spraying a foliar application
we may need to do what is called a soil
dredge that is where you take an amount
of water how much you ever water your
plants usually mix up that much water
get that much water and to that mix of
water we are going to add 15 to 30
milliliters per gallon of Evergreen
pyrethrum spray the product is called
Evergreen it's mainly pyrethrum based
it's a very good product for getting rid
of fungus gnats white flies and most of
your basic common pests in the garden
honestly this is one of my go-to
pesticides one of my most recommended
pesticides it is simply called Evergreen
in my opinion it's affordable and it's
very effective and it is also approved
by the Colorado Department of
Agriculture the Colorado Department of
Public Health and environment and the
Colorado marijuana enforcement division
so the product is called Evergreen I
would mix up the water and I would water
the plants with the Evergreen solution
again somewhere between 15 and 30
milliliters of Evergreen per gallon of
water 15 to 30 per gallon so you're
going to mix up that water and water it
right through the plants this will
stress the root zone of your plants the
plants will show you that they were a
little bit bothered by this but one
maybe two applications of this will get
rid of your soil-borne pests most of
anything in that soil will go away
so depending on the level of the
infestation and the strength of your
plants that would help me determine how
much of this product to put in the water
somewhere between 15 and 30 mils if the
bugs are real bad you want that 30 mils
but if the roots aren't super strong go
closer to 15 milliliters you can figure
this one out mix that up water the
plants then wait a couple of days then
water it again with this same solution
do it again if they didn't look too beat
up the first time do it again if they
got the [ __ ] beat out of them on the
first try maybe wait on this but then
water them again with the same solution
that second application should knock out
all of the root-borne problems then
after that I recommend watering with a
really nice mix of nutrients and put a
bunch of microbes in there to resupply
the microbes to that rhizosphere get
everything back in action in that pot
the bugs are gone let's get the roots
banging let's get the roots healthy
again now while I'm doing these root
dredges I would also do a foliar
application of either the Monterey
Garden spray or the ever green let's hit
the top and the bottom if we just soak
the soil or the cocoa or whatever the
plants are in the bugs are going to go
up and hang out on the leaves and fly
around and just go other places and then
when all that [ __ ] dries they'll go back
we got to hit the foliage too so there's
nowhere for these bugs to go hit the
foliage with the Evergreen hit the soil
with the Evergreen I would do the foliar
spray and the dredge on the first day
and then wait two or three days maybe
four days depending on your wet and dry
cycles and do it all over again now all
the bugs should be gone with those two
applications if it is fungus gnats and
or white flies other pests may have a
little more resistance but that should
bang out your problem so really quickly
if it's fungus gnats then we're going to
use Evergreen at 15 to 30 milliliters
per gallon we're going to do a soil
dredge and to foliar application then
we're going to wait uh three maybe five
days and repeat the process if it is
only white flies let's just spray
frequently with the BT of the Monterey
Garden spray with the bacillus during
Genesis in there let's hit that like day
one day three day six and then we'll
wait and see how they look maybe do it
again on day 10 but they should be going
away by then if not you've got a bigger
problem than I realized uh we've got to
get in there and make take some nuclear
measures or perhaps start thinking about
letting go some of those Predator bugs
there are plenty of Predator bugs that
will get in there and destroy your
fungus gnats and your white flies all
right my friend Zach J I think I
answered most of your question on my
notes here it says Ah bacillus thuring
Genesis from Monterey Garden spray or
Evergreen stop over watering shop vac
another thing I wrote down was yellow
cards
I'd recommend putting some yellow sticky
traps in the garden some at soil level
some right below the bottom of the
canopy and some at the top of the canopy
that will help you identify the presence
of pests those yellow sticky traps are
not there to eradicate bugs in any way
they are there to alert and indicate the
presence of pests that will let you
monitor your progress in your battle if
there are more there uh yesterday than
there are today you're making progress
if there's more there tomorrow than
there were today they're making progress
so you've got to adjust your uh your
measures based on the progress which you
and those bugs are making it's a battle
and I wish you the best of luck you're
gonna win bro because you've got
technology and me on your side and you
were backed by the irie Army all right
Zach Jay thank you for the great
question uh thank you for the great
content if you have any more questions
please do reach out everybody else out
there if you have a grow question please
do reach out my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy there's also a grow help tab on my
website when you go to my website
irygenetics.com you will find a tab that
says grow help click on there we'll ask
you a few questions like are you growing
indoors Outdoors what strain are you
growing ask a few basic preliminary
questions then we give you the
opportunity to type in the problem with
your plants ask me your question let me
know what's going on there's also a
space to attach images you can send
photos of the garden if you need some
help or have some questions or something
just doesn't look right in your garden
send me a message I'd be more than happy
to help you out I may even use it here
on the podcast for Content all right at
the top of the show we did give away a
pack of seeds sponsored by our friends
at seedshearnow.com if you would like to
win a pack of seeds from ire genetics
and seedshernow.com it is very easy to
do so all you have to do is go to this
YouTube video that's right on YouTube
this is episode 786 of the girl from
your heart podcast find this video the
first thing you got to do is click like
make sure you click like on the video
the next thing you have to do make sure
you click subscribe subscribe to my
channel so far it's super easy now
here's the main thing you have to do to
win this pack of seeds
type in a comment and let me know which
pack of irie genetic seeds you would
like to win and also let me know why you
want to win that pack of seeds so here
are the three things you got to do like
the video subscribe to the channel and
type in a comment letting me know which
pack and why you want to win it super
easy shouldn't take you too long to do
it I look forward to all of the comments
on once again big shout out to my buddy
Zach Voss for winning that free pack of
seeds from seeds here now.com all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
really I do want to thank you for
hanging out once again this episode was
a lot of fun I had a good flow going I
felt like a great episode I hope you
enjoyed it as much as I did if you liked
it all you got to do is click that like
button make sure you click subscribe so
you don't miss any other episodes if you
have any questions Corrections comments
or concerns I'd love to hear from you
once again I think I said this part
already the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't forget
about that patreon campaign at patreon
on.com forward slash grow from your
heart I know that is a lot of
information so everything else you might
possibly need is on my website
irygenetics.com all you have to do is
visit iregenetics.com there's a link to
the patreon of course there's that grow
help tab there's a Discord link there's
a link to I redirect so you can get
those beans there's a link to seeds here
now to get the discounted beans
everything you need irie genetics.com
all right that's all I've got for you
for this episode you know I'll be back
next week with fresh new content I want
to give a big shout out to my friend
lemur priest and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
foreign
[Music]
thank you