[Music]
all right here we go I'm your host my
friends call me Rasta Jeff this is
episode 787 of the grow from your heart
podcast I've got a fun episode planned
we're going to talk about breeding later
in the episode I will give away a pack
of seeds let's jump right into the
breeding talk I do have a great email
here that came from our friend Jason
let's not waste too much time the email
goes a lot like this it says hey Ross to
Jeff my name is Jason I'm from Northern
Colorado nice to meet you bro it says I
really love the show and your hard work
to keep up the good fight bro can't stop
won't stop it goes on it says I'm a big
fan here and I really rely on your
information as far as breeding and
selections go ah thank you that's a huge
compliment knowing that you you uh rely
on my breeding you respect and trust my
guidance thank you that means a lot to
me so big up and fist bump and thanks
for that it does continue it says I'm
currently about to start a breeding run
which I am super excited about but I'm
not sure how to select which female to
select to spray and reverse so our
friend uh Jason has a breeding project
in mind they want to make some feminized
seeds they've got two plants but they
cannot decide which one of those two
female plants they should reverse to
turn into a pollen donor let's dig more
into this it says I have plant a that
checks all of the boxes to what we like
but it lacks Terps but it is highly
potent so we've got a plant that checks
all of the boxes it is a perfect
breeding plant it's a perfect female
except for the fact that it lacks Terps
however this plant is highly potent
which kind of sometimes may make up for
that lack of Terps we've got a highly
potent plant that checks all of the
boxes but it lacks terpenes so then it
goes on it says plant B is not as potent
but has a sweet grapefruit Kush flavor
that is Dynomite so this plant isn't as
potent it lacks the potency but it's got
that flavor that they're looking for it
says a sweet grapefruit Kush flavor
which sounds quite delightful in my
opinion that uh astringent uh bitter
almost citrusy grapefruit with some kush
on top of it to Mellow it out sounds
like a great flavor in my mind that
makes me think it's going to have a
great Buzz as well so that sounds like a
great idea we've got the flavor there
we've got the aroma there and it's
dynamite it says this plant just doesn't
give me as medicated properly like plant
a does I want to breed with a purpose
and add those Terps to the potent plant
so which plant would be the best to
spray with the STS and use the feminized
pollen from which is a very good
question I've got a couple of solid
answers for you it says I'm not sure if
I use the terpy plant as a pollen donor
since it's what I'm after essentially
please elaborate I hope this makes sense
it makes great sense brother this makes
a lot of good sense says thank you for
your reply it would be appreciated much
love from your neighbors up north and
you can use my name on the show if this
makes it I'm glad you included that
because I started this whole thing by
saying this came from our friend Jason
big up to my friend Jason this is a
great question so you've got two plants
and you can't decide which one to use as
the pollen donor I've got some great
advice
um I don't only do my selections based
on flavors Aroma potency there are a lot
of other things that I think about let's
look at both of these plants and think
which plant has got the structure and
shape you are after in your progeny uh
think about how far apart the nodes are
the node spacing is the branch spacing
how much branching does the plant make
how is the plant overall shaped do you
have a real tall skinny wispy plant or
do you have a short squat bushy wide
plant what do you want your plants in
the future to be shaped like that is a
very important factor to consider when
it does come to selecting your plants
also Leaf size and shape definitely make
a big difference in that plant do you
want a long skinny Leaf do you want a
big fat Broad Leaf do you want somewhere
in the middle that's something to pay
attention to also when it comes to
breeding think about the flowering time
of the selected plants you are going to
use that flowering time is going to
translate heavily into your breeding
project so do you have one that flowers
at a more appropriate time if one of
those plants flowers longer and one
flowers more quickly that trait will
pass if you use that plant in the
breeding project most likely the male is
going to heavily contribute to that
flowering time so keep that in mind or
the reverse male we'll say pollen donor
from here out I'll try to remember to
say Paul and donor from here on I make
no promises so also do these plants
handle stress does it handle grower
stress by grower stress I mean can you
top it can you pop it can you lollipop
it can you twist it can you defoliate it
can you make mistakes with it can you
abuse it can you beat it up can you over
water it can you under water it can it
handle environmental stress that's kind
of over water underwater but also how
about vapor pressure deficit issues
humidity spikes humidity drops
temperature spikes temperature drops
diurnal swings can these plants handle
those sort of things the one that
handles the stress the best is the one
that I would use as the pollen donor in
my opinion and in my experience now you
asked specifically which plant I would
recommend to use here this is my opinion
my advice and I will explain why I would
do this I've got a solid reason for it I
would choose the potent plant as the
pollen donor and allow that one to
pollinate multiple females it looks like
you've got one female plant that you
want to pollinate but I would pollinate
multiple females the reason for that is
when you pollinate one female you kind
of see what uh the plant a and plant B
you can see what that brought to the
table and what they made but if you put
plant a to plant b c and d put that
pollen on multiple females we can really
see what the boy is adding to the mix
because if you've got a female plant
that makes blueberry Terps a female
plant that makes chocolate Terps and a
female plant that makes banana Terps and
then you add gas to it did you get I
forgot the flavors already did you get
gassy blueberries gassy whatever else I
said and glassy bananas or is it all
bananas all gas see what that male is
adding to the mix in there and see what
it's contributing if you just make one
cross you only know how that male
interacts with that one female if you
cross it to multiple females we can see
how that male expresses itself on a
wider palette through more population in
my experience in my opinion that's
really helpful for selecting breeding
projects for selecting breeding males
breeding pears that really goes a long
way in my opinion in my experience I
know you're focused on making uh the
grapefruit Kush and the terpy plant
together or the potent plant on the
terpy plant together but also why not if
you're going to reverse one plant why
not put a couple of females in there
multiple females in the room with that
male to make multiple crosses a lot of
seeds to play with that's just more fun
to me also that way like I said you get
to really see what that male plant is
bringing to the mix if you just add
um let's just say chocolate and vanilla
together we know what chocolate and
vanilla tastes like but what if I put
chocolate and strawberry does the
chocolate diamond eat the mix does the
strawberry dominate The Mix or do I get
a nice Chocolate Strawberry mix let's
see what happens in there and see what
the plants do that way so I would start
by using the potent plant as my pollen
donor then what would happen in my
opinion what I think would happen and
I'm kind of doing this
um I used when I made the uh Ninja
Turtle line I'm not sure if you've been
following for that long I took a
reversed blueberry cookies plaque that
blueberry cookies plant was amazing and
I pollinated a bunch of other female
plants with that plant and I named them
after the Ninja Turtles what I noticed
is the blueberry cookies showed itself
very well in all of the other crosses
but it also Blended very well to a lot
of those crosses so what ended up
happening was that potency from the
Reversed blueberry cookies the potency
the Vigor the plant shape all the good
traits from that passed on to The
Offspring into the breeding project but
let's talk about I said Ninja Turtles
lion we'll use Raphael as a good example
here that is a reversed blueberry
cookies pollinated a strawberry fields
plant makes Raphael when I bred those
two together I could really see the
strawberry Starburst or the Strawberry
Fields traits I could smell it I could
taste it and then also it had the Vigor
the potency and some of the aroma and
flavor of the blueberry cookie so I was
able to get that potency the Vigor the
plant shape all that good stuff into
that other end of The Offspring and it
also brought a lot of that strawberry
Flavor now let's talk about another one
in the mix was I pollinated the Platinum
Tangy and that made Michelangelo again I
got that growth structure the shape the
Vigor from the blueberry cookies but I
also got that Platinum Tangy Aroma and
flavor mixed in with the blueberry
cookies so my idea my goal would
actually ended up happening what I'm
kind of recommending to you is use that
potency rely on the potency from that
reversed male then let the females
you're using change up the palate
throughout each plant so maybe you got a
strawberry a orange a lemon uh what else
did I use there's a bunch of different
things in that mix but there's
definitely strawberry orange lemon and
blueberry in there and I brought all of
those out and mixed that with the
original blueberry cookies cross so if
this were me if this was my breeding
project if I was in charge of this room
I would select the more potent plant the
plant with the more potency also don't
forget about Vigor plant structure
resistance are these plants resistant to
bugs pathogens do they get problems I
would find the best plant with the best
potency the best Vigor best resistance
that would be my pollen donor and then I
would rely on all those female plants to
be my my terp provider my flavor my
difference is because that male is going
to mix well with a lot of things if you
select the proper I said male once again
but that reversed female that pollen
donor plant so once you've done the
pollination once you've made seeds the
next step to do is to grow these seeds
out if you only pollinated that one
plant grow as many of those seeds as you
possibly can see if you've created what
you're looking for did you find the
terpy plant with the potency the Vigor
the shape the structure you're looking
for is it in there if so then you've
done exactly what you're looking for
you've reached your breeding goal I
would take that plant and I would find
something else to do with it to further
breed it maybe self that plant maybe
breed that to other things things but
that would be my new keeper to start my
new breeding project with if you've read
this to multiple females grow out a
bunch of those female seeds or seeds
from those other plants and see what
you've created see what that male plant
is contributing to that mix amongst that
population of females that's so much fun
that's my favorite part taking a reverse
plant or a male plant pollinating a
bunch of girls not just growing out the
this batch and this batch but growing
out all of them and seeing like oh the
guy does this the guy made all of these
plants get a chocolate Aroma but also
they also added their own but also some
of the plants got like this weird Leaf
shape that came from the guy plant
you'll notice what does cross and what
doesn't cross you'll notice you'll
figure out what's a recessive trait
what's a dominant a co-dominant trait
you'll just learn a lot about your
plants by breeding them two other things
now I said originally that what I would
do is take the most potent plant and
that would be my candidate for reversal
now you're really going to be blown away
by the next thing that I say after
you've done this cross after you've
taken your candidate that you've
reversed and you've pollinated you've
grown it you found out some you found
some seeds found out what you produced
found the keeper out of there now guess
what your next project is
do the opposite take that terpy one
reverse it pollinate the potent plant
then grow it out again if you've got the
opportunity like I mentioned before grow
out pollinate multiple females with this
reversal again if you can pollinate the
same females that you did the opposite
plant with and let's see what this plant
is contributing to the mix now we get to
see what plant a does when it's reversed
and pollinates multiple females and we
can see what traits deliver there then
we'll reverse plant B and pollinate
multiple females and see what traits
come up there then we can even see what
the male is delivering because now we
can really see what the female is
contributing to the Cross because we've
pollinated with two different sets of
pollen I know that's a lot to get to get
into that's really deep that's really uh
it's really in-depth that's in the mind
of a breeder honestly once I make a
cross once I reverse something that's
what I want to do I want to reverse the
other one that I didn't choose and
reverse that and then pollinate
everything and then grow both batches
side by side and see what I've created
it becomes really crazy uh but it is a
lot of fun it's a lot of passion once
you start this this could be a lifetime
project so don't ever Rush a breeding
project take your time do the
pollination let the seeds finish grow
out the population and find the plant
that you are looking for if the plant
that you're looking for is not in there
do it the opposite way pick different
parents never be discouraged with
breeding you'll always find something
great however the goal here is to
improve upon these lines if your cross
doesn't come out so if these plants are
both I don't know your plants I don't
want to judge you but if these plants
are both sevens the goal is to come out
with a plant that is at least an eight
maybe a nine hopefully a ten if you can
do it but if you haven't improved upon
the species of cannabis then that is
your responsibility to decide what to do
with those seeds if they're not amazing
maybe you don't pass them out to the
whole world don't share them with a
bunch of people maybe keep them to
yourself but if those are Stellar make
sure you do share those seeds with
people get those out so that more people
can grow high quality ganja all right
Jason Johnson I really feel like you got
me rambling pretty good on that one I
hope I answered your question uh don't
just focus on the potency don't just
focus on those Aromas and flavors also
focus on Resistance how does it handle
problems how does it handle grower
stress environmental stress think about
all that other stuff as well but then I
would recommend choosing the plant with
the potency and pollinating those terpy
females all right brother thank you for
the great question if anybody else out
there has any questions you know that I
would love to help you out my email
address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me those
grow questions I do have one more
question we're going to bang out here on
this episode then we will get to the
seed giveaway that's right our friends
at seedshearnow.com are going to give
away a free pack of irie genetic seeds
here on this podcast stay tuned it is
almost time to tell you how to win those
seeds let's jump into this next email
this one came from our friend something
different shout out to our friend
something different thank you for the
great question it goes what's going on
Rasta Jeff I hope your New Year is off
to a great start bro things are killing
it uh January was awesome February has
begun very well nothing to complain
about hope everything is going great for
you as well it says I have two questions
question number one I was under the
impression that if you sell a plant it
is a complete copy of the mom used but I
was recently told that this is not
exactly the case can you elaborate on
that so that's the part one of the
question says and I also remember saying
something a while ago about an auto
flower collab is there any movement or
updates on that also the fam and I are
planning I'm not going to read this part
they're moving near me and we're going
to hang out so I'm not going to read
where you're moving to because the whole
world doesn't need to know that but yes
we will hang out we will take dabs I
look forward to that let's address the
second question first let's do it
backwards the Autoflower collab
uh Daz with uh Night Owl seeds I'm not
sure what he's calling himself this week
does you change your name a lot but I
try to keep up with you nothing but love
and respect and congrats also uh Daz is
uh working some Auto flower stuff with
some irie genetic stuff in there I don't
have uh solid info on exactly how far
Daz has gotten into that but I know the
project is making great success I've ran
some of the f1s I've looked at pictures
I'm not exactly sure how far he's gotten
with that I haven't kept in touch I
haven't asked but Daz is working on that
feminized Autoflower project with the
irie genetic strains in there so I would
make sure to check with uh Night Owl
seeds check with Daz see what he's going
on he's probably got a lot more info and
updates on that those will be available
through Night Owl I won't even have
those seeds that's all his project he's
got my blessing but I'm not into
autoflowers if I made autoflowers uh it
wouldn't be very good I say it's like uh
I can play any kind of music you want
but if you put me in a country band I
can play country music but it's not
gonna feel like country music it's not
going to have whatever country he's got
that makes it feel country it's going to
be missing a little something it just
ain't going to have that feel that a
real country drummer could put to it so
that's why I don't make Autos they're
not for me all right let's answer the
first part of this email this is a very
good question it says I was under the
impression that if you sell the plant it
becomes a complete uh the seed should be
a complete copy of the mom that is a
good question let's take a little drink
here and then we'll answer that not even
gonna edit this part I'm just gonna take
a little drink keep moving shout out to
the kombucha gods for keeping me uh
kombuchulated is that a word that's a
new word add that to the Urban
Dictionary kombucha lated that is when
you're well hydrated and have good
microbes from drinking plenty of high
quality kombucha Rasta Jeff made that up
I want [ __ ] credit for it
kombuchulated I'm gonna quit rambling
and take a drink
okay maybe I cut out a couple of seconds
maybe I didn't let's answer this
question about reversing a plant when
you self a plant what does that mean
well we talked a moment ago about
selecting plants for feminized breeding
selfing a plant is when you take two
clones of the same plant so let's just
start with a Golden Goat plant I'm going
to cut two clones off of a Golden Goat
plant I'm going to let them grow we're
going to flower them before I flour them
I'm going to treat one with a solution
we don't need to talk too much about
that solution I'm going to spray it I'm
going to spray it several times I've got
a schedule I've got a program there's a
standard operating procedure eventually
this plant is going to produce pollen
the pollen that comes from this plant is
only female pollen because the Golden
Goat plant that I started with does not
contain any male chromosomes so this
plant is going to go sort of into a
panic mode it's going to create pollen
sacs those pollen sacks will only
contain female pollen then I will take
that female pollen from the Golden Goat
and put it on another female Golden Goat
plant this is known as selfie this is
called selfing I have S1 to this plant
it is a first generation of a soft plant
I took the Golden Goat and the Golden
Goat and I self them I call itself
because it's a self-pollination there is
no other there are no other genetics
adulterating this mix but now I can make
pure Golden Goat seeds those will be
feminized go Golden Goat S1 seeds now
the question that arises has arose has
been brought up that was asked I don't
even know what I'm saying anymore the
question here is I was under the
impression that they would be a complete
copy of the mom approximately 50 to 70
percent of the phenotypes that come from
those seeds will look just like the
original Golden Goat mother but some of
those plants are going to look a little
bit like the mother plot that was used
to make Golden Goat and some will look a
little bit like the father plant that
was used to make the Golden Goat so I'm
going to say 50 to 60 maybe 70 percent
of those are going to be right down the
middle they're going to look just like
that original golden go but you're going
to have some on this side that look a
little bit like the mom plant that made
Golden Goat and some on this side that
look a little bit like the dad plant
that made Golden Goat we may also see
phenotypes that Express traits of the
grandparents of the original Golden Goat
so we may see traits of the mom and then
also traits of the mom's parents and
traits of the dad and also traits of the
dad's parents the only way to really
identify that is to be familiar with
parents and grandparents of that plant
but when I grow it out I can identify it
because I know what used I know all of
the ingredients so I could taste that I
could say oh there's the cinnamon
there's the butter there's the maple
syrup I can identify every ingredient by
looking at it because I'm so familiar
with each parent plant so when you make
those reversals most of the time about
50 percent of them and I say most of the
time because these are genetics this
depends very much on the plant that you
are working with some plants reverse
very well some plants don't reverse well
at all some plants when you reverse them
they make a bunch of intersex problems
some plants when you reverse them they
make a bunch of amazing gold like the
Golden Goat it makes a whole bunch of
amazingness but some plants a lot of
chem cultivars a lot of the sour diesel
stuff if you reverse that it just makes
intersex garbage so in my experience
when I self a plant I generally get
about 50 percent of the phenotypes they
look just like the original mom and then
I've got that group that looks a little
bit like Grandma the group that looks a
little bit like Grandpa and then we've
got those outliers that look little bit
like the great grandparents now let's
talk about something else really quickly
not all feminized seeds are what are
known as self-seeds a lot of feminized
seeds are also known as reversals a
moment ago I talk about taking two
clones of the same Golden Goat plant we
reverse the Golden Goat we put that
pollen on Golden Goat we have self that
plant it did it to itself it got itself
pregnant it gave itself a selfie you'll
never forget that that plant itself
that's an S1 what if I put that Golden
Goat pollen on something different what
if I put that Golden Goat pollen on a
GMO plant and I make something we call
Garlic go that is no longer selfing
because I didn't pollinate itself I
pollinated another plant with reversed
pollens so instead of being an S1 that
plant would be labeled an R1 it is a
first filial generation of a reversed
cross so sometimes you're going to see
plants that say S1 sometimes they may
say R1 sometimes it may not give you any
indication at all if it is a golden and
go feminized seed and you know that it's
a clone only that is most likely the
original plant reversed and self done to
itself but if it is something like let's
talk about like I just said a moment ago
the uh the garlic goat that is a Golden
Goat to the GMO that is a reversal that
is going to show us phenotypes that look
like the 50 50 mix probably close to 50
50. it's going to be pretty close to 50
50. you'll find some that look just like
Golden Goat just like the GMO combined
we're going to see that phenotype then
we're going to see phenotypes that look
a little bit like GMO then we're going
to see phenotypes that look a little bit
like Golden Goat then guess what we're
also going to see some phenotypes a very
small percentage of the phenotypes are
going to look like golden goats parents
and some of the phenotypes will look
like the GMO parents and then you're
going to have a couple of phenotypes
that you can't tell what the hell is
going on and she's got traits from
everybody it looks like the mailman's
kid that does happen a little bit when
you start doing the uh the reversals so
that's the basic difference between
selfing and reversing and those are the
basic phenotypes and traits that I think
you are going to find with those femini
seeds with the self seeds most your
phenotypes are going to look like the
original mom we'll find some
grandparents and a little bit of great
grandparents with the reversals that are
not pure self you're going to see the 50
50 phenotype that looks like Mom and Dad
you're going to find some that look like
moms some that look like Dad some that
look like grandparents and then you're
gonna find some weirdos that looks like
weird mixes of each trait like you just
shook took all the traits that were
available from both plants the leaf
shape the structure the odor uh the
flavor trichome development took both of
those and just shook them up took all
the trade Counts from each plant shook
them up and just grew them and who knows
what what ornaments got hung on which
tree which alleles got given to each
plant but sometimes you're going to see
some that just looks like you just mixed
up Mr Potato Head and got the parts that
you got all right something different
thank you for the great question I hope
I was able to answer your question
within all of that rambling I hope you
were taking notes if anybody out there
has any questions Corrections comments
or concerns I would love to to hear from
you the email address is grow from your
heart hotmail.com don't be shy please do
reach out I love building shows based on
listener generated content now I have
been saying that we're going to give
away a pack of seeds here this is the
part of the show where we do give away a
pack of seeds to somebody watching this
podcast before I give away this pack of
seeds I do want to give a big shout out
to our friends at seedsherenow.com make
sure you check out seedshairnow.com for
their current stock of regular feminized
Autoflower seeds they've got breeder
bundles they've got seed packs under 25
bucks anything you're looking for should
be available at seeds here now.com if
they don't have what you're looking for
send them an email send me an email
we'll make sure to get them restocked at
seeds here now.com now real easily here
is how you can win a free pack of irie
genetic seeds just by watching this
podcast is really easy all you have to
do is go to my website
irygenetics.com that's right
iregenetics.com go to the website scroll
down most of the way on the website
toward the bottom there is a spot where
it says stay up to date with ire
genetics if you type in your email
address and join the newsletter that
will enter you into the contest to win a
free pack of ire genetic seeds that's
right I'll give away a pack of seeds on
every episode this month before I record
the next episode I will scroll through
and see who has joined the newsletter in
the past week and I will select a winner
from a new member of the newsletter so
go join the newsletter at
iregenetics.com scroll down it says stay
up to date all you've got to do type in
your email address hit enter it'll sign
you up to the newsletter I'll go check
that in a few days and I will select a
winner from the new newsletter member so
it's real easy a free pack of seeds just
for joining the newsletter thank you for
all of the support and now it is time to
announce the winner from the seed
giveaway from the last episode that's
right our friends at seeds herenow.com
are going to give away a pack of irie
genetic seeds to my friend Todd Miles
big congratulations to Todd hey dude you
have have won a free pack of pineapple
wine seeds they are already in the mail
I hope when you get them you tag me post
some pictures tag Irene genetics tag the
podcast most importantly grow from your
heart have fun with those seeds I really
hope to see pictures of the progress all
right ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers Growers
clone Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
thank you once again for listening to
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast I'll be back in one week
with fresh new content make sure you
support the patreon page at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else you could possibly need
is on my website at iregenetics.com of
course there's the tab to sign up for
the newsletter there's a Discord tab
there's a tab to get seeds all you got
to do is click on I redirect that will
take you right to the seed vendors
there's a link to seedsherenow.com once
again everything you need is at
iregenetics.com that's all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back next
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my friend smoke
but and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you