[Music]
welcome to the show internet world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 789
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode I'm going to give away a
free pack of seeds that's right I've
teamed up with our friends at seeds here
now.com to give away a free pack of irie
genetic seeds stay tuned later in the
episode I will teach you how to win that
free pack of seeds in this episode I
want to talk about stabilization in
cannabis plants it has come to my
attention that a lot of the Cannabis
World a lot of the Horticulture and
growing world does not exactly
understand what the word stabilization
means when it comes to our plants often
times I see people post to the internet
that they got a pack of seeds and they
discover intersex plants within that
package of seeds and they will attribute
that to what they call unstable genetics
now that may be part of the problem but
that is not exactly what stability means
when it comes to cannabis plants in the
Plant World in the Horticultural world
in the Botanical World stability means
that if we grew out a large batch of
seeds that we will not see multiple
phenotypes in that population that we
will see stability that all of those
phenotypes will be uniform if you drive
through a Farmland State one of those
States where there's a bunch of corn
maybe Nebraska maybe you see a bunch of
soybeans maybe you're going through
Kansas as you drive down the road you
will notice that every single one of
those corn plants looks exactly the same
and all those soybeans look exactly the
same now you're going to say that's
genetic modification that's probably
part of it but also that is breeding for
stability those plants have been bred to
be that phenotype to all be stable
because we can't run if you've got acres
and acres of corn or acres and Acres of
soybeans you can't have some corn that
gets really tall some corn that stays
really short we need uniformity it makes
it easier to water it makes it easier to
basically maintain and care for that
crop and it makes harvesting and
processing much easier if everything is
uniform and also the customers the
clients the people buying that produce
the corn the soybeans whatever produce
they expect uniformity as well so
uniformity is basically what we are
talking about when it comes to stability
in the Botanical world now let's talk
about how we achieve that creating a
stable line is all about selective
breeding and good breeding practices the
most important thing is starting with
quality plants plants that have been
stress tested plants that have been
through the ring or plants that you know
are a quality breeding plants so if we
are breeding cannabis if we're breeding
corn if we're breeding soybeans whatever
you are breeding one of the most
important things to think about is the
starting plants do we have quality
starting material if you start with a
plant let's just I like to refer to
cooking and baking or being in the
kitchen if you start with ingredients
that don't taste good your food will not
come out tasting good if you put more
crap and more crap in a pot no matter
how much you cook it how much much you
stir it how much you bake it still going
to taste like crap in a pot breeding is
the same way you have to start with
Quality Plants you can't start with crap
plants you can't start with intersex
plants you can't start with problematic
plants or guess what you're going to
breed more intersex problematic plants
so it is all about selective breeding
and selecting quality plants to begin
with now I said that one of the most
important things to think about when it
comes to breeding is starting with
Quality Plants another very important
thing to think about is having a goal
what is your goal what are you trying to
create what are you trying to produce
what's your goal with this breeding
project that you are working on
especially if we are going to work it to
F4 F5 if our main goal is to come out
with a strain where every seed looks the
same wouldn't it be a good idea to start
with a solid goal with the solid idea of
what we want so a couple of the most
important things to think about when it
comes to breeding or starting with
Quality Plants and the next thing I
always talk about having in mind is
breeding with a goal what's your purpose
what are you trying to create so now
let's say we've got two plants in mind
we know they are good breed leading
candidates we've tested them we know
that they are not intersex plants we
know that they handle stress well we
know that they handle environmental
change as well we know that they're Pest
and pathogen resistant so now we've got
two plants now we kind of have an idea
now let's write down a solid breeding
goal when we breed these plants together
we're going to see a lot of different
Expressions through the different filial
Generations we need to make a guideline
now of what we are looking for so that
the plants don't throw you off sometimes
you'll have an idea you'll grow the
plants and then you'll say you know what
I want to go this Direction that's going
to mess up your breathing stay on the
map that you made in the very beginning
and make that other direction a bee
project let's do that later let's do
that at another time maybe maybe
simultaneously if possible but draw that
road map and stay on your map because
the plants like to kind of give you
ideas and throw you off and your friends
are going to give you input and the
internet's going to give you input
follow the original idea and get to
where we are going and see how we can do
that with the map that we've drawn and
then later on we'll learn how to Branch
off and do other side shift but let's
stay fo focused if we're trying to make
a stable line here now let's talk about
stabilizing these plants we've got two
plants hopefully you've got a male and a
female that's the way that this is going
to work it's one of the things I would
also recommend at this time is starting
with plants that are completely
different from each other plants that
are too similar to each other just breed
more similar [ __ ] so find something that
maybe has let's talk specifically about
my cross arise arise was a very
successful cross because of this factor
I used a Golden Goat female let me
describe Golden Goat to you very briefly
Golden Goat is kind of known as a
tropical sativa but it also grows short
and squat so it's got a really nice
sativa kind of head Buzz really tropical
flavors and it makes really skinny
leaves but it doesn't get super tall
like most sativas and you can Harvest it
a little more early than most of the
other sativa plants it'll come down
around week nine which is a great trait
for a sativa kind of buzz type of plant
so it's got those skinnier leaves that
tropical flavor that sativa style Buzz
then I took a daybreaker plant which is
Joseph OG and chem D that puts off a a
lot of gassy chemicals burnt rubber
fresh tennis ball kind of smells and
Aromas completely different than that
tropical sweet candy in the Golden Goat
it also put off big gigantic leaves the
leaves are so big on that plant it also
makes a lot of crazy Purple colors so I
knew that those were completely
different so I bread them together to
create something brand new and in my
opinion in my experience it worked very
well so something I'll recommend at this
time is start with plants that are very
different if you can find a male and a
female that are very far apart in traits
and flavor Aroma growth structure I
think that is when you have the best
success in creating new lines so with
that in mind we've got two plants
hopefully they're vastly different if
not your breeding project will work with
your goal if you've got a goal in mind
but I have more fun when they're way
further apart so I've got my mail I've
got my female we've got a breeding goal
in mind now the first thing to do is
Chuck some pollen let's put some pollen
on this female plant then we're going to
make seeds this batch of seeds is called
the F1 generation the first filial
generation these are brand new seeds
they've never been made it's a new cross
that is the F1 so from that F1 batch of
seeds we will grow them out pay very
close attention to what you've done are
there any intersex problems are there
mutants are there freaks do you have
germination issues or are these quality
plants that you're enjoying the outcome
from or do you like growing them do they
grow well do they handle problems well
are you seeing the phenotypes that you
were hoping for so grow those out what I
would recommend now is finding the
phenotype that you were looking for when
you wrote down your goal you said I want
to find this you want to plant that
grows with this shape this structure
this flowering time this flavor this
Aroma it's got to work in your growth
some people run a scrog some people run
uh big wide open Plants some people top
them one time and let them Bush out some
people only veg them up six inches tall
and flip them do the seeds that you made
work for your grow style can you find
the phenotype that is perfect for your
grow oh if so let's continue with this
breeding project if you're not finding
the seed that you want the plant that
you want doesn't come out of there then
this is not a successful breeding
project which is not a big deal I would
abandon this for now keep those seeds
and then pollinate with different plants
and different females and try it again
until you do find the cross that you're
looking for not every cross will be a
winner every single time it definitely
might not be what you're looking for the
first time you make seeds so my point
here make that first filial generation
grow them out find the one that is
exactly what you're looking for you've
we've got to do very careful selections
at this point we've got to find exactly
what we're looking for so find a male
plant and a female plant that have got
the traits you're looking for like I
said the leaf shape the plank structure
the node spacing the type of branching
does it react well to what you want to
do find the girl in there for you also
find the male plant in there for you now
guess what we're going to do again we're
going to grow the boy we're going to
grow the girl and we're going to Chuck
some pollen we are now making the F2
Generation the f1s now just bred
together they make F2 now these f2s are
going to show you a lot of crazy [ __ ]
the phenotype variation in the F1 won't
be as wild as the f2s but you'll see a
lot of stuff and the f1s are going to
see uh plants that look 50 50 like the
mom and dad some plants they lean more
toward the mom and some plants to lean
toward the dad and then you'll see some
weirdos in there and the F2 we're going
to see plants that look like the mom
we're going to see plants that look like
the dad we're going to see plants that
are anywhere between one and a hundred
percent the mom and the opposite the dad
so you could have 50 50 60 40 70 30
either direction mom and dad in this
batch of seeds also we're going to see
grandparents represent themselves uh
whatever was used to make the plants
that you use the parents of those plants
they're gonna pop up now and they go hey
here we are do you remember me I'm the
great grandma or I'm the grandma you
forgot about on the grandpa that you
forgot about they're going to pop up and
say what are these weird traits and
you're gonna wire the plants doing that
that's from Grandma that's from Grandpa
on either side so we've got four
grandparents and two parents that can
represent themselves here on this cross
at this time also you're going to see
some weird [ __ ] uh we just took the
whole genetic gene pool and put all of
the traits in there every color of eyes
every color of hair uh every type of
skin and teeth you can imagine we just
shook it up and we're going to get some
weird looking cousins out of this that's
what we're going to see in the f2s so it
is your job in that F2 Generation to
find the plant that has the traits you
want I'm going to keep saying that find
the plant that is perfect to continue
this line this is the one that is going
to represent the next line so it's got
to be the perfect plant for you does it
have I'm going to keep saying it the
leaf size and shape the plant structure
the internodal spacing the branching
does it finish on time does it react
well to what you do if it does that's
the one that you want to keep find that
female find that male then guess what
we're going to do it's time for them to
get it on again we're going to make the
F3 generation in this F3 generation this
is where we start doing a little bit of
these stabilization we have gotten rid
of that F2 uh the wildness out of the F2
Generation the f3s are starting to lock
in a little bit we're starting to see a
little bit more uniformity which is the
idea of stabilization that is what
stabilization is so what are we going to
do again we're going to grow out these
f3s we're going to find a female we're
going to find a male like I keep talking
about with the exact perfect traits that
we wrote down the goal that we are
seeking we want to find that plant once
again if it's not in there that's not a
big deal go back and grow more of those
f2s and find those if you have to go all
the way back to the f1s and make F2
again do that never be afraid to go
backwards and run more of those old
seeds you might not have found what you
were looking for because you might not
even have known what you were looking
for at that time or maybe it just didn't
pop up but let's run that F3 let's find
the perfect one then what are we going
to do we're going to pollinate that F3
with another F3 that's going to make F4
now we're getting super close to
stabilizing this plan at this point you
should have probably 70 to 80 percent of
your phenotypes looking fairly uniform
if we have done the selection properly
and again the only way to tell if we are
doing this properly is to grow out large
batches of these see it grow out as many
as you can I would like to see a
thousand of them if possible I
understand that that is not possible for
everybody
I'm uh I'm spoiled I'm blessed I'm here
in Colorado where I've got access to
commercial growth facilities I've got
access to a lot of friends that grow I
can give them seeds I can actually rent
space from my friends who are no longer
growing and grow in their grow spaces
you know if I'm renting grow space from
you and I'm producing seed or flour in
your space big up and thank you that
does help me a lot so
um I recommend a thousand of these seeds
if possible I understand that's not
possible for most people maybe do a
hundred also I understand that that is
not legal for most people I'm going to
say follow the rules where you are don't
get yourself in any trouble but also
you're a [ __ ] adult do what you want
to do I'm just trying to keep myself out
of trouble
um if you can't run a thousand or a
hundred seeds at a time you probably can
run 10 at a time can you run 10 of them
maybe Run 10 find the best one for now
set it in a corner and keep it as a
keeper plant then run nine more and just
keep doing that until you just eliminate
a few until you are satisfied that that
is the one that you're looking for
there's ways to funeral hunt large
batches it just may take more time so I
think I was at F4 when I got off on a
rambly tangent there but from that F4 we
are going to do the same process we're
going to grow them out we're going to
find the plant that has the exact traits
that I'm looking for it should be easy
to find by now because by this F4
generation we're seeing a lot of
uniformity things are starting to really
stabilize and settle in so we're going
to find that female that looks exactly
like all of the traits we wrote down the
flowering time the growth structure the
node spacing the branching the leaf size
and shape colors Aromas we should be
smoking all of these have you found out
if it's got the buzz you want does it
have the Terps you want is this the
perfect plant for you find that F4
generation find a boy find a girl also
by this point you should be pretty good
at selecting male plans that's going to
be the real challenge but find that mail
find that girl let them do some pollen
Chuck and at this point you've now
created F5 and this F5 generation we're
going to see really uniform plants among
this population a lot of the plants are
going to look very very similar we are
now reaching our goal of stabilization
so at this point if you grew a hundred
seeds you should probably get get 10
plants that don't fit in but the other
90 are probably going to look just like
each other so now the next step
obviously if you want to lock this in
even more is to go to the F6 generation
I personally don't know any breeders
that go to the F6 or Beyond perhaps DJ
Short is hitting the F6 generation but
the last I read when he was selling
seeds he would take them to F5 and then
stop that way he would leave us room to
breed to them because if he goes any
further it kind of locks in all of the
traits that he created that he selected
and when we breed to it that's all
that's going to come out is those traits
because that's all that's left that
segues me into the next part of talking
about breeding and stabilization
um you can accidentally stabilize
negative traits if you don't pay
attention negative trades could be
intersex or whatever you're not looking
for if that is in your your population
of breeding anywhere if you see that and
you pass that on in the breeding you
could stabilize a negative trait that
you weren't looking for so make sure you
grow out a lot of seeds make sure you do
a lot of testing make sure that you grow
every batch a large population of every
batch if possible and select the best
plants from that batch if you're seeing
any problems maybe go backwards and
breed from other batches and select
better maybe you just selected the one
that carries an intersect straight or
one that doesn't speed up doesn't flower
quickly enough you can go back and find
better plants if you wanted to do it
again or you could also back cross for
one of those better Generations if
you've got a plant that's super close in
the F4 generation you could take a F1 F2
and pollinate that with it it'll give
you the traits you're looking for but my
my advice is to keep going forward and
keep making it better and if you make a
mistake go back to where you made the
mistake and then move forward from there
again now a second ago I did mention
back Crossing which leads me into
another thing that I would like to kind
of ramble about for a minute here when I
think about breeding sometimes I'm
thinking about locking in trades but
another thing I'm also thinking about is
washing out traits now let's talk a
little bit about washing out traits and
the reason I want to use back cross is a
kind of a guideline for this is because
it's really easy to explain it and
you'll understand it if I use back
Crossing as an example let's talk
quickly about what a back cross is and
it'll make sense of all of this let's
just say I've got a plant we'll say
Golden Goat because I've done that
people want Golden Goat seeds but I
don't have a male Golden Goat plant so
you can't make regular Golden Goat seeds
without making feminized seeds or
without adulterating that Golden Goat
plant in some sort of way so what I
would do what I did is I pollinated the
Golden Goat plant with another plant
like I said before a plant that was
vastly different than the Golden Goat
this way I could identify the traits and
the progeny so I pollinated the Golden
Goat with the daybreaker and from that I
could see those big leaf shapes I could
see those skinny Leaf shapes I knew
right away that all of the skinny
leaf-shaped plants were the Golden Goat
phenotypes and the bigger leaf plants
weren't even necessary to keep around
for the back cross project because those
were the uh the daybreaker dominant
phenotypes so now if I want to make a
back Cross of this Golden Goat my idea
is to wash out all of those traits of
that daybreaker now how do I wash that
that out by simply breeding the Golden
Goat to the Golden Goat multiple times
now it's basically like adding more
layers of paint until you can't see that
daybreaker in there anymore the way that
I did that was I took the Golden Goat
and the daybreaker I made seeds now I've
got my first cross which is Golden Goat
to daybreaker F1 from there I found a
Seedling a male that looked just exactly
like the original golden go I took that
mail and I pollinated that original
Golden Goat now I've taken that that
adulterated Golden Goat pollen it's half
golden goat half daybreaker and I've put
it back on Golden Goat now I'm basically
minimizing the ratio of amount of
daybreaker traits in there so that's
going to make the Golden Goat bat cross
one from there we grow out a batch of
seeds and I'll find another male that
looks exactly like the Golden Goat from
that batch of seeds and I'll put that
pollen back on the Golden Goat again and
make yet another batch of seeds now do
you see what I'm doing each time I add
this Golden Goat to the mix I'm just
washing out traits of that daybreaker
we're just washing out those negative
traits so something another thing to
think in mind another way to approach
breathing is by thinking about what
traits do you want to wash out and what
traits do you want to bring along with
you now I know I gave a lot of ratios a
lot of fractions and a lot of numbers uh
this is all good in theory a lot of
things to think about is uh this is all
plant theory if you write down these
ideas write this all down it will look
really good on paper but we've got to
keep in mind these are plants they're
going to do their own thing sometimes
genetics will do their thing you can do
uh alial charts you could write Mendel
charts you could do your predictions we
can do our favorite selections but
sometimes nature is just going to throw
a curveball at you so this is kind of a
guideline this is kind of a uh a quick
course on how to stabilize and what
stabilization means but keep in mind
when it comes to cannabis plants there
will always be variables because nature
always finds a way and guess what nature
always wins alright that is my support
on stabilization I did say at the start
of this podcast I was going to give away
a free pack of seeds of course that free
seed giveaway is sponsored by my friends
at seedshernow.com Big shout out to my
friend James Bean at seedshairnow.com
also big shout out to the entire crew at
seedshairnow.com I know none of that
would happen without everybody on the
team that's a big crew they've got there
big shout out to the whole team thank
you for all of the support I love
working with those guys big fist bump to
seeds here now.com before I tell you how
to win seeds on this episode I do want
to announce the winner of the last
episode however the way that you won
seeds on the last episode was by signing
up for my news letter I have selected a
winner but I don't feel that it is fair
to read your email address here on the
podcast because I don't want you to get
a bunch of spam so if you won the free
seed giveaway on the last episode I have
reached out to you via email uh please
do respond to that email send me your
shipping address put a real name in that
please if you win seeds when you send me
your address please put a real name on
there I don't like putting like ganja
Joe's weed farm on a package that I'm
sending to somebody with seeds in it
first of all that just looks Shifty for
the the mailman and then second of all
that encourages people to steal your
ship plenty of people are stealing the
mail and if they see like Joe's weed
farm or ganja Joe or ganja Bob or stone
or Dave or whatever on the package that
does encourage theft that just lets them
know there might be something smokable
or consumable in there or enjoyable in
there and that does encourage them to
steal that so don't get your seeds
stolen that you won because uh that's a
bummer I don't have to send them to you
again so you will get an email if you
won from the last seed giveaway of
course I've got your email address
because you did sign up for the mailing
list I'm not going to do it that way
this time if you would like to win a
free pack of seeds it is very easy all
you've got to do is comment on this
video this is episode
789 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you're not watching on YouTube I do
encourage you to go to the YouTube video
leave a comment let me know why you
think you should win a free pack of
seeds also let me know which pack you
would like to win if I select you and I
have got that pack of seeds I'll do my
best to give you that pack of seeds as
your prize however keep in mind things
do sell quite quickly not everything is
in stock and available so make your
wishes go make demands I'll do my best
to fill that
um so it's very simple all you've got to
do is go to the YouTube video this is
episode once again I said 789 of the
girl from your heart podcast leave a
comment on the video let me know why you
should win a free pack of seeds and also
let me know what strain you would like
to win and once again if you won from
the last episode you did receive an
email so check your email you might have
that sitting in your inbox also check
your spam because you never know all
right I'm getting rambly it is time to
wrap up this episode ladies gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast make sure you check out the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart everything
else is on my website at
iregenetics.com if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concern Insurance you can send me an
email the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't be shy
please do reach out I look forward to
hearing from you I think that is all
I've got for this episode thanks for
hanging out thanks for listening to me
ramble I'll be back next week with fresh
new content I want to give a big shout
out to our friend Stewie grows and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
stop
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign