if you have ever gotten seven minutes
into a podcast recording and realized
you never hit record go ahead and click
subscribe
[Music]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host my friends call me Rasta [ __ ]
this of course is episode 789 of the
grow from your heart podcast yes I know
I said 789 on the last episode I do
apologize I'm not the best at counting
but I am pretty good at growing in this
episode we are going to give away a free
pack of seeds that's right I've teamed
up with my friends at seeds here now.com
to give you a free pack of irie genetic
seeds stay tuned we'll talk more about
that later in this episode I do have a
lot of fun stuff to ramble about here at
the start of the show I want to start
off by giving a couple of shout outs I
want to give a big shout out to a
comedian by the name of Joe list that's
right I got to see Joe list live at
Comedy Works uh Joe list kind of
downplays his comedy he doesn't talk
about how many tickets he sells about
how many people show up to his show he's
kind of self-deprecating and then when
you show up to the comedy show you
realize he's doing much better than he
leads on big shout out big thank you to
Joe list for a great comedy show also a
big shout out to to Comedy Works for
hosting a great show and of course a big
shout out to Zara for being a perfect
comedy show date all right let's move
forward the next thing to talk about is
orangegasm seeds will be back in stock
on I redirect very soon that's right the
seeds have been harvested they are in a
little container all they need to do is
be counted and packaged into individual
packages and then I can put them on the
website and get them to you I will do
that very soon I don't have an exact
time or date planned or in mind for when
I'm going to do that life is very busy
I've got a lot of things going on I want
to get them out as soon as possible the
easiest way for you to stay in touch and
stay updated on how to get that drop as
soon as it happens is the first people
that will get the update is the patreon
members the people that participate on
patreon at the 7.10 above level will get
the first notification shortly after
that the people that subscribe to the
4.20 subscription on patreon they will
get a notification once I feel like
enough people from patreon have gotten
their seeds then I will send out a
newsletter to sign up for that
newsletter go to my website
iregenetics.com scroll down to the
bottom there will be a spot to type in
your email address you will get a
notification that says you have
successfully subscribed to that email
newsletter then when I do the drop for
the orange Chasm you will get an email
with a link directly to iridirect so you
can grab those seeds then I will also
make an update and post a link to the
Discord server I will go to Discord
somewhere in the ivory Army Discord I
will make sure everybody sees it it will
say hey there are orangegasm seeds here
click this link so it will go in the
order of patreon it will be the patreon
710 members then the patreon 420 members
then the newsletter then shortly after
that it will be the Discord server so
make sure you're either on patreon the
newsletter or Discord the newsletter and
Discord are absolutely free to join so
please do jump on that but of course
patreon will get first dibs at the new
drop of the orange gasm seeds all right
where do we go from there oh it says
here to remind you that every order does
come with freebies and some of those
freebies will will be testers if you do
get testers I do highly invite you to
join the Discord server on the Discord
server there is a tab that says I read
genetics testers if you click on that
you can see the progress of all the
tester seeds that I've send out from the
people that have decided to join and
participate in the Discord tester tab if
you want to post one or two pictures
there that is great if you want to post
a weekly update there that is awesome if
you want to post full written outgrow
reports there that is just as great I
want as much details and information as
you want to share if you're one of those
people that wants to type out a whole
bunch of [ __ ] I'm really interested in
reading all of it post all your details
your info type about your gear your
equipment your humidity your temperature
what you're feeding and then post photos
or just post a picture and say what
strain it is the most important part if
you are going to post on the tester tab
is please do include what strain you are
testing I try to include a name or at
least a cross on the package to identify
it so you can clearly talk about what it
is please do include that so we know
what you're talking about on the tester
tab but when you do order from I
redirect everything will come with some
free seeds some of those may be tester
seeds it will be clearly marked on there
if they are tester seeds you'll get a
little it'll say testers you'll get a
little card with a link to the Discord
there's a QR code you can scan that that
should take you right to the Discord you
can join hang out and talk about all the
testing on there I think that's all the
rambling I want to do here at the start
of the show I do have a couple of great
emails let's jump right into those the
first one says yo Rasta Jeff
I would like to start by thanking you
that's a good way to start a message uh
you're welcome bro it goes on to say I
purchased the bundle off of iridirect as
a Christmas gift to myself and man did
you deliver yes occasionally I will post
random bundles to I redirect
um and I put a bundle pack and I tell
you how many seeds comes in that pack
and I put a very greatly discounted
price on that bundle and then uh people
buy that bundle and they don't know what
they're going to get it's like a prize
bag it's like a grab bag there's just a
bunch of random seeds in there I make
sure to load it up and make it well
worth the price that you paid but you
have no idea what's coming it could be
new stuff it could be old stuff it could
be Rags it could be Femmes it could be
unreleased [ __ ] it could be over stock
[ __ ] either way I make sure that you're
going to be happy with what you get if
it's older stuff there's so much of it
if it's new stuff you're going to be
blown away by the cool [ __ ] you've never
seen I also sneak in some testers and
freebies and all of those but yes
occasionally I do throw out those
bundles and since you've got faith in me
and trust me just to load it up for you
that's why I really hook you up with
those anyway I should keep moving it
says the new packaging is awesome and in
a weird way it's seemed like you knew
what I want or what I don't have or what
I wanted to buy and eat through that in
there so thanks again there's a lot of
cool compliments in there the new
packaging thank you if you guys have not
seen the new packaging from ire genetics
uh I redirect grab some seeds there's a
good chance that uh the John lemons will
come in the new packaging uh the big
mountain fudge cake will definitely be
in the new packaging and then some of
the Femmes have their own custom package
designs on there so grab some seeds it
goes on any way it says on to my grow
question that is the point of this right
do you have any tips on keeping a grow
room warmer in the winter that's a
really good question I'm sure if you've
been following along you know that when
I switch from LED lighting I went from
HBS to LED lighting it kind of ruined a
whole entire crop I stupidly it was my
decision my move I did that in the
middle of the winter it was negative 17
degrees outside and I decided to take
down the HBS lights and hang up LEDs and
guess what that room got super [ __ ]
cold because I was relying on those HPS
lights to keep that room warm and it did
not work with the LEDs the LEDs put off
basically no heat compared to what to
compared to what the HPS lights were
doing so I have struggled with this
before I do need to keep that grow room
that grow space warm my solution and you
said you can't do that or don't want to
do that but my solution was to hang more
lights I just put the HBS light back up
so the LEDs are where they should be in
their area and then I just put HBS up
over on the side and that's what's
heating up the room now it's basically
working as extra light and as a heater
all right it does go on it says my wife
and I recently purchased a new home
congratulations brother that is a big
thing especially at this time it goes on
it says and in this home my new grow
will be in the basement that's that's
perfect we all started in the basement
abroads where most of us start it says
she is always hot and I am always cold
so we compromise and just keep the house
cold that makes sense uh it was 58
degrees in there yesterday morning that
is kind of cold for a grow space it says
the room isn't huge it's about 110
square feet so that's about a like a 10
by 11 room I also don't do not own HPS
or ceramic metal halide fixtures anymore
I'm hesitant to use a standard hot coil
space heater due to fire risks I have
some ideas but this is another one of
those what would Rasta Jeff do
situations from our friend and they call
themselves f a plant count I like that F
that plant count although I do strictly
follow the plant count here in Colorado
because of all of the rules but I know
what you mean have a plant count so that
is a great question how do we keep a
basement grow space warm in the winter I
did write down a few ideas of course my
first option would be just to get a safe
heater I know you don't want one of
those uh dangerous space heaters but you
can get a quality heater now it's uh
it's 2020 three it's not the 80s it's
not the 70s anymore or those heaters are
super dangerous there are quality
heaters available you can buy an
industrial heater or a residential
heater you can set it on the floor in a
safe spot or you can put it up on the
ceiling in a safe spot you can mount it
make sure you follow all of the
manufacturers recommended rolls and
safety precautions I got to say that to
keep myself out of trouble and
everything you do is your responsibility
and your fall so I should say that just
to keep that's for just for legal
purposes here but I would recommend just
a normal small heater it's a 110 square
feet room a very small heater should be
able to warm that space you can run that
heater when the lights are on you can
run that heater when the lights are off
that is one option I would get a heater
and something called a cap switch let's
talk about what a cap switch is many
people aren't familiar with these types
of devices they're great uh great
devices they make them for all kinds of
different things that do you can figure
out how to do you can operate a whole
grow room huh you could automate an
entire room with just a few cap switches
if you really think about what you're
doing so a cap switch the switch plugs
into the wall where the plug-in goes so
the first step is to get the cap switch
plug it into the wall it's got a
thermostat on it so you turn it to the
range that you want I think it'll be
within three to five degrees so you're
going to get like 70 to 75 turn it there
70 to 75 degrees maybe a little hotter
72 to 77 maybe a little hotter depends
on what you want to do
uh but turn it to where you want it set
it on the range at which you want it
then you plug the heater into that cap
switch then you turn the heater knob to
where it's on at medium or high however
much however much intensity you want
that heater to bang out maybe if you put
it on medium it won't be banging at high
intensity all the time it may last
longer less risk a problem less risk of
fire so you turn the heater on medium
it's got one of those manual uh those
switches that you have to turn don't get
a digital heater because that will not
work with your cap switch you got to get
the analog kind with the knobs that you
can turn so get the turning off turn it
on to medium get that [ __ ] going plug
it into the cap switch then there's a a
cord that comes from the cap switch
that's got a thermometer on it hang that
in the middle of the room maybe right
above canopy High then that thermometer
will hang right above the canopy and
whenever it gets too high or too low for
that temperature if it's too low if it's
under 75 degrees that'll say hey it's
under 75 degrees and it will turn on
power to that switch which will turn on
the heater the heater will heat up as
the room heats up that thermometer
hanging in the middle of the room will
say hey okay it's as hot as we need it
to be and it'll tell that switch hey
turn off the power to this this plug-in
right here so all you're doing is
turning off and on the power to that
plug-in by using a thermometer it'll say
I'm within the ranger I'm not within the
range and if you've got a heater that's
got a switch on it that you can turn off
on medium high low however that will
work but a digital uh heater will not
work for this situation you can also do
the opposite with an air conditioner if
you do a cap switch on an air
conditioner set it low set it high you
can tell that air conditioner come on
you can put as many devices on as many
cap switches as you want in the room
they sell them for humidity with a
humidistat on there they sell them for
heaters they sell them for coolers you
can automate all kinds of things with
cap switches so think about those things
a little bit I do have some notes that I
completely abandon here
um so the cap switch is your first
choice
a heater is your first choice heater
with a cap switch is your next choice
then um if you've got two rooms this is
what I've done before I've got a a
bedroom and a flower room next to each
other I simply vent the heat from the
bedroom into the flower room and the
flower room is dark so at night it's
just heating up that room using uh the
hot air so it's just venting that I'm
venting that hot air from the veg room
over there to the flower room wall to
sleep and that will help keep that room
warm a little bit and then that's got a
carbon filter and a dehumidifier in the
flower room so it'll clean that air up a
little bit and then send that out of the
room and it's just replacing there
constantly but invent that uh the veg
room heat into the flower room may be
another idea here's another thing you
can think about is flip the schedule I
know that may sound crazy but we do this
in the summer to keep the rooms cool why
not do this in the winter to keep the
rooms warm it's always going to be a
little bit warmer during the day maybe
only just a few degrees especially right
now it's snowing like a [ __ ]
outside in Colorado but it's only going
to be a few degrees but during the day
we're going to get a few degrees warmer
at night it's going to be a few degrees
colder what if you put your lights on
during the night to try to keep that
part of the cycle a little bit warmer
that may help you out that may keep
things dead even which may help you out
just a little bit a CO2 burner maybe
have you thought about adding a CO2
burner CO2 burner has a lot of good
benefits it's going to make your plants
grow bigger faster more robust it'll
help you use more nutrients you can use
a little bit warmer room in the
summertime but in the winter that CO2
burner will heat up the grow room it
hooks up to the Natural Gas it works
like a pilot light except it's like
multiple pilot lights in a room
depending on how big you buy you don't
need a big one for this room but you
could just use that CO2 burner it will
burn the CO2 and at the same time it
will heat up the room I know that's if
you're gonna do that do a heater but why
not a CO2 burner it's going to be just
as effective and if there's just as many
if not less risks it's probably equal
anyway here we go since I said risks let
me get to the next part of my notes it's
says smoke alarm and fire extinguisher
if you're going to use a heater if
you're going to use a CO2 burner I
highly highly recommend that you do add
a smoke alarm and a fire extinguisher if
you don't already have that in the grow
space you guys every grow space should
have a fire extinguisher available and
possibly a smoke detector either inside
or outside of that grow space put the
fire extinguisher outside of the grow
space if you have a grow space where the
door closes have the fire extinguisher
outside because if a fire does happen in
there you don't have to go in there to
get the fire extinguisher to put it out
you want to be able to kick the door
open and careful the doorknob may be hot
we've all seen the movie Backdraft but
open the door start spraying be prepared
so have that fire extinguisher and that
smoke alarm all right let me check on
the notes make sure I didn't miss
anything all right it looks like I
covered all of the notes for this
question my friend F of plant count
thank you for the great question I do
see your name on patreon all the time I
see your name pop up on the YouTube a
lot thank you for all the support bro
and of course thank you for the great
question I hope I was able to help you
out if you've got any follow-up
questions please do reach out you know
how to contact me all right I've got
another message here on the table that I
would like to read this one came from my
friend shoe trader101 on patreon and it
goes a little bit like this it says rust
to Jeff I'm not sure how this happened
but uh from my last run to this run I
noticed a lack of smell coming from the
plants during the flowering stage I'm
not sure what causes this my very first
run was successful with all the smell
and everything you could possibly think
of I haven't changed anything I still
use build a soil 3.0 along with insect
frass build a flower and other items
that you can purchase directly from
build a soil per their recommendation
big up to build the soil they don't pay
me they don't sponsor the show I
honestly don't use them but all of the
organic guys they grow with Organics and
do the build a soil program I hear great
success and great success stories with
that product with that product line and
they've also got great customer service
and they're cool [ __ ] people and
their Instagram is super cool so they've
never paid me I don't do a lot of
business with them but big shout out to
build a soil if you're a uh one of the
uh the bad guys the uh the beds that
does the live soil beds if you're a
regenerative guy what are the guys that
just pull the roots out and put the [ __ ]
right back in there I can't even think
of what that's called you guys are just
keep going the no-till no-till guys I
recommend building soil to those kind of
folks all the time
um so you're using a lot of build the
soil products and most of the stuff per
their recommendation it says a lot of
people would say that this is due that
the lack of smell is due to genetics but
I have your stuff lit Farms raw genetics
exotic genetics soulfire Top Dog and
more bro those are some of the best
breeders on the planet in my opinion to
hit some of my favorites in there so
it's definitely not a genetics issue and
your last run was good so it says any
feedback would help I'm in three uh five
gallon pots and one seven gallon pot and
I do pH my water all right so our friend
shoe Trader 101 from Instagram is having
a problem or their last run smelled
delicious everything was perfect but
this run does not have any Aroma and
flavor we're gonna try to diagnose and
figure figure out why with honestly the
little bit of information I've got here
I don't know the uh the uh the VPD I
don't know the lighting I don't know a
lot about this other than some Builder
soil products so let's uh let's dig into
some of my ideas
I started off by talking about uh temp
and humidity VPD how is the temp in
humidity in your grow space uh we all
know that he will also let's talk about
one thing before we get there something
I was just talking about with uh the
last ramble that I got on uh this could
be a seasonal issue
um I noticed that since I'm dealing with
different conditions Outdoors during the
winter and different conditions in the
fall and the spring and the summer
because I'm in Colorado our seasons are
drastically noticeable you can tell the
difference in Seasons so since I'm here
I do notice that some of my crops are
easier they come out better my winter
crop my fall crop the one that's done
since I've got them scheduled the third
crop of the year the one the one that
comes around Halloween that one's always
one of my best crops of the year if it's
uh for a smokable flour or for seeded
flour it's always the most successful is
my Halloween run for some reason I don't
know why I don't I think it may be the
gear and deal I don't have to cool the
rooms as much so that's what I'm getting
at let me talk about that now I've kind
of segmented my way into that I don't
have to cool the room as much so I think
I get a better stickier tastier product
is your room too hot was your last run
in a dry season in a warm season did the
room get too hot also maybe perhaps did
the room get too dry maybe you're
dealing with conditions outside that
it's hard to correct the indoors and
your room got a little bit different
maybe the last crop it was a different
season you had that outdoor or that
outdoor cool that Halloween crop like I
always get that's super good maybe that
was your last crop maybe you're
comparing that spring crop to your
Halloween crop and they're going to be
totally different just because of
outdoor environmental conditions that
just could be a thing I'm not certainly
sure that that is it but I've noticed
that my crops are different here at
different times of the year so it could
be temperature it could be humidity it
could be too wet it could be too dry too
hot definitely volatizes and burns off
Terps too dry doesn't allow turps to
produce as much too moist will
definitely stifle terpene production uh
too cold might not be too bad for Terps
but it is going to slow down some [ __ ]
so let's think about temperature
humidity
uh then let's also think about airflow
in the room is there too much airflow is
it too windy imagine if your Terps your
plants your trichomes are just sitting
there in the wind uh you know if you're
on the boat if you're on a motorcycle if
you've got the windows down if you're in
the convertible uh maybe you just got
too much wind on your face and you just
feel all chafed all day maybe the plants
are getting the same thing in there bro
maybe they're just getting beat up by a
fan again I'm not accusing I'm not
pointing fingers I'm just going through
my mind looking in the grow room going
what could possibly through my grow
space saying what could possibly be
diminishing Aroma and flavor and
presence of terpenes in this grow space
so I'm just checking off the list and
seeing what we can identify in your grow
um so we're talking about airflow is it
too windy is it too stagnant you're not
are you not getting enough air Exchange
in there do we need to get rid of some
air pull some fresh air in there that
may be part of the situation and I'm
just looking from the top down we're
going to get to the soil at the end here
we'll talk about all this stuff did you
have any issues were there any bugs if
you had any bugs at all that will
definitely slow down uh trichome
production aroma flavor all of that
stuff because the the plants will be
focused on different things they'll just
be more focused on protecting and
replenishing the damage that the bugs
are doing uh did you see any visual
problems uh did you get a microscope and
look for any problems uh did you spray
anything uh maybe something you sprayed
may have changed the aroma and flavor
then were you watering properly did you
have any dry spells were you over
watering did you
um you're using the build of soil did
you replenish everything after you
harvested some of that stuff needs to be
put back in did you add the bloom
boosters did you add the aroma and
flavor enhancers which they recommend I
don't know what that is from build a
soil but I'm sure there's a product they
say this gives you better flavor this
gives better Aroma did you use that
because that may have helped out with
you so
um did you over water I think I said
that did you underwater were you uh
checking the soil carefully it says you
ph'd it
um were you making sure that everything
was perfect in the soil before you were
watering so maybe there was an issue
with the soil maybe you didn't rebuild
everything after the last Harvest I'm
not a soil expert so maybe I could be a
lack of microbes maybe it could have
been a feeding issue there could have
been a lot of things going on there
something I notice uh you said this was
happening in the flowering stage but
something else I noticed is that a lot
of people will have really stinky plants
all the way up to the end and then they
don't dry and cure properly and that's
where they lose a lot of the flavor and
Aroma also that's where people do bring
out a lot of the flavor and aroma so I'm
curious I'm sure that my by the time
I've read this and by the time this
podcast comes out that it will be
Harvest time maybe it's dry cure and
smoke time how did these plants come out
bro now at the end now that it's time to
chop them down how does it smell how
does it taste once you dried it and
cured it then Eddie did any of that
flavor and Aroma come out uh it could be
a dry and cure issue once again that
comes to a relative humidity temperature
Darkness where they kept in the dark
also were the lights too close to your
plants when they were growing that could
be something to think about too were
they closer or further away than last
time did the plants grow taller did you
lower or raise the light did you forget
to raise the light or lower the light
for some reason I'm just throwing out
there all the ideas that I could come up
with
um the main thing to think about is what
changed what is different than last time
that's why I always recommend taking a
lot of notes did you write down
everything you did last time did you
write down everything you did this time
set those notes side by side and say oh
last time at week three I did this ah
[ __ ] I didn't do this in week three or I
did do this it could be something you
did or didn't do it could be an
environmental change it could be
something major or honestly bro it could
be something very tiny did a product
change did the airflow change did your
care change did your defoliation your
popping twisting what is different
that's once again that's why I recommend
taking a lot of notes do you have all
the nutrient notes from last time
um you say you're using the build of
soil like I said maybe that needs to be
refreshed and recharged maybe you need
to order a few packages that mix in
there for the next crop the only other
thing I can think of and this has
happened to me and other people think
I'm crazy when I say this but maybe you
have got what we call nose blind maybe
you just can't smell it or taste it
anymore because you've been around it so
much and you've become immune to it
stinky people don't know they stink we
all enjoy our own brand you may be
sleeping in the house where that herb is
you may sleep there you may wake up
there you may eat breakfast there you
may have lunch there you may go about
your whole entire day there by now you
are totally immune to the smell of that
ganja just because you're there so much
I I know that's extreme but sometimes I
just don't even realize that there's
ganja in the house and that you can
smell it and I'll pull up to the house
with a friend like Michael come over and
Mike will be like buddy you got to get a
new carbon filter I can smell it down
the block and I'm like what do you mean
bro I don't smell anything and then
Michael be like let's go somewhere and
we'll go run around in the car for a
little bit and not smoke and we'll come
back and I'll be like
ah bro I need a new carbon filter and
he's like yeah bro you just got to get
out because you didn't smell it at all
so maybe maybe hopefully that's the
situation you're having maybe all the
Terps are there maybe you're growing
like a pro and a champ and you're just
so good at growing you don't even smell
that crazy dank anymore you've got to
improve and make it even stinkier and
dankier
um there are a few uh products I guess
not products but a few things I can uh
recommend that may help improve that
stinkiness maybe a couple of these maybe
a couple of these and combo maybe one or
two by themselves I've always noticed
that kelp based products make my plants
that if it's got a skunky or an earthy
or a cushy or a coffee kind of Aroma
that uh kelp product well I'm not sure
what kelp product you're going to buy
there are a lot of them but see kelp in
a product will definitely bring out that
funky uh earthy cushy uh gassy those
Aromas are enhanced by kelp in my
opinion in my experience in my grow also
I may recommend adding more sugars and
more microbes that will help with
everything that's always a good idea
carbs microbes that will always help
then
something I've noticed that makes plants
funky and stinky all the time is fish
products any ocean products seabird
guano or fish products fish Emulsion
fish meal anything with fish in it will
make your plant I think if you put it
into the nutrient mix into the soil and
it's got a little bit of the proper
stank to it that stink does transfer
into the plants stank makes stank so
that's what I think so uh maybe add some
kelp add some fish products definitely
increase the amount of microbe activity
in there and that may help with your
lack of Aroma and flavor uh bro my
friend shoe Trader 101 I hope I helped
you out if you've got any shoes to trade
definitely do hit me up you all guys all
know that I'm a big sneaker fan so if
you got the correct dunk Espy lows hit
me up we'll do some shoe trading all
right podcast world this is the part of
the show where I do give away a free
pack of seeds I have teamed up with
seedshairnow.com to give you a free pack
of irie genetic seeds in just one second
I'll tell you how to win that free pack
but now let's talk about the winner of
last episode seed giveaway and the last
episode to win the free pack of seeds I
did say that you had to leave a comment
letting me know why you deserve a free
pack of seeds my favorite comment went a
little bit like this it says I should
win because I tried sending you a bunch
of hash and hot air balloons and the
government keeps shooting them down that
is such a great Comet big up fist bump
congratulations that is my friend JH you
do win a free pack of seeds brother send
me your address I would love to send you
some seeds so that you can have fun also
bro shout out for the amazing and
excellent strawberry Starburst that
you're growing I've seen your photos
I've seen what you sent me great work
with the strawberry Starburst I will
post some of your photos in the very
near future I've got a lot of photos to
post so once again big congratulations
to my buddy JH bro keep the great emails
coming also keep the great YouTube
comments going you are a champ alright
congrats to my buddy JH for the free
seeds I do look forward to the pictures
of those seeds Okay let's tell everybody
how to win a free pack of seeds on on
today's episode all you have to do is go
to my website irygenetics.com on that
website on the top right there's a list
of tabs it says home it says genetics
there's a bunch of stuff listed one will
say grow questions or grow help click on
that tab you will be brought to a forum
where you were able to fill in what
strain you're growing we ask a few
questions about the grow room your
nutrients and then at the bottom there's
a big space to type in your grow
question and you can even attach photos
send your grow question with your photos
and all of the details to the grow help
tab if I read your grow question here on
the podcast you will win a free pack of
irie Genetics seeds and of course that
is brought To Us by our friends at
seedshairnow.com Big shout out to our
friends at seeds here now.com for
sponsoring a free seed giveaway all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters and pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know I would love to hear from you the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
cannabis Culture Your cannabis
cultivation questions send me your
constructive criticism your positive
feedback or send me the hate mail if
that's what you think you've got to do
don't forget to support the patreon
campaign at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart everything you
could possibly need is at my web website
irygenetics.com that's all I've got for
you I'll be back in another week with
fresh content I want to give a big shout
out to my friend Alabama man and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you