[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 79 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host roster Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always I want to
send that huge thank you shout out to
the Mystic Roots band they let me use
their song on the show it's really cool
then big thanks to cat cot and the
entire Mystic Roots crew I hope you guys
are having a great evening sorry got to
clear my throat right at the start of
the show I'm already getting a frog in
my throat dude sitting across the table
from me you guys will have no you'll be
so surprised guess who's here Jesse's
back say what's up bro hey what's up
everyone you have no idea how hard it is
to get this guy on a podcast you guys
you have no idea what it takes to pull
Jesse away from his life to come be on
the show for an hour and get him high
out of his mind and then send him home
hungry as [ __ ] all right dude thanks for
coming bro really I appreciate it oh no
problem Jesse is a busy man he's a Ganja
Farmer he's uh running some [ __ ] over at
H gr indoor growing supplies what else
you got going on bro uh mechanic shop
mechanic shop hot rod shop hopefully hot
rod shop yeah this guy does a little bit
of everything you need to learn how to
do uh are you an electrician um okay no
if you ask somebody if they're an
electrician and they go well kind of no
they are not an electrician yeah it does
it need to be legal is the big question
there so that means no um so this is
something that Jesse is good at he is
the man at hyro indoor growing supplies
uh this podcast is brought to you by my
great friends at hyro indoor growing
supplies hyro indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado you
can check out the dinner store at 6271
Beach Street or my favorite store the
peblo location on 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful peblo Colorado check out Hy gr
for competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor grow supplies get
your favorite nutrients at Hy gr indoor
indoor growing supplies you guys that's
where I shop it's a grow shop ran by
Growers Jesse does a lot of the
inventory burn selects a lot of the
inventory based on what Jesse and I tell
her if you want something go to High gr
and or growing supplies tell them that
you listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast and they're going to give you
commercial pricing on everything that
you purchase just for listening to the
podcast and supporting the show and for
supporting the store so big huge shout
out to those guys I really appreciate it
big shout out to burn big shout out to
Jesse that's super awesome also shout
out to Ladonna can't blow her off uh if
you guys are interested in sponsoring
the show uh you can send me an email
it's gr from yourart hotmail.com I'll
get you all the information you need uh
we start the show with a freaking frog
in my throat it's awesome uh so Jesse is
here you guys we don't have to do a
whole bunch of technical formal
introductions let's get right down to it
uh we all wanted Jesse to come on the
show and do another grow lesson for us
because it's outdoor season uh we know
that growing outdoor is almost free uh
some people asked me kind of about doing
a budget episode like if they don't have
a lot of money so I figure we'll work on
getting the basics of an outdoor grow
going and then maybe if we have some
extra time we will talk about maybe how
to do a budget grow so that way people
don't have to break the bank to build
their grow and grow a whole bunch of
ganja oh yeah you totally do that too oh
yeah oh yeah we have some ideas Jesse
and I have been at this for a minute I
bet we could build a hoop house together
in probably two hours oh easily yeah
yeah Jesse's got the tools and I'll keep
the dab nail hot all right
so uh we're GNA a lot of what we're
going to talk about may be kind of
regional to Colorado you may have to
adjust a lot of what we say for your
area um if you're in California you may
be a little bit earlier than us if
you're on the East Coast it's going to
be a whole different story yeah a whole
different yeah I don't even know how to
teach you to grow in the South or in the
East where you've got a lot more
humidity the scheduling is a lot more
wonky the weather comes Midwest is uh
pretty similar to us just a lot easier
for him so all right so we'll get it
we'll get most of this stuff based on
Colorado grows but we'll try to get it
to where everybody can work with this so
I guess the first question we should
start with is where uh where should we
start growing where should we look at
growing our outdoor crop where would be
your ideal
space um you want a a south facing uh
you know or good southern view um for
for the sun um starting this one off all
stoned no it's all right Stone it'll
come out of you eventually and I can
edit some stuff for sure n no need for
that um you want you know probably six
hours a day direct sunlight I mean
they'll grow on less but you know for
proper you know you want six plus um for
big fat Lush PLS yeah yeah I I'd prefer
like 10 hours a day personally but I
mean can make it work Outdoors is really
forgiving so okay um they'll grow
anywhere yeah they will they'll grow on
accident sometimes so you want a south
facing uh slope if you can uh what if
we're stuck like in the city what if
we're in the backyard do we want to
avoid some
sheds avoid Street if you can street
lights most definitely sheds you know
you don't want to get too blocked in um
and that is mainly for airf flow I mean
if your area is you know like in the
middle of four sheds or something like
that all stacked together but it's 20x
20 you know you got plenty of air flow
there for a couple plants leav some
space for the plants to breathe you know
if it's like a 6x6 spot you know that's
enough for one plant maybe right so yeah
you guys your outdoor plants are going
to get big if you do this right and
we'll talk about that in a few minutes
when we talk about container size so you
you would like a southern facing slope
uh if you're going to grow in your
backyard or something don't grow between
the garage and the house and the shed
unless you can get plenty of air air
flowing through there that's going to be
a great show Jesse's too high and my
throat's all jacked this be wonderful uh
make sure you get plenty of air flow you
don't want your plants touching each
other so when you do plant them make
sure you give like expect the plants to
be 6 to 8 feet around each by the time
you're done maybe a little bit bigger if
you're a good grower and you know what
you're doing
yeah so expect a big plant um give
yourself plenty of room is kind of what
I was headed toward so we might be
behind on this question but uh here in
Colorado when should we put our plants
outside um pretty much anywhere in
America I think he could have been out
uh a couple of weeks ago probably oh
easily um uh you know the the summer
we've had here locally um you could have
been out first of May easily now I'm
going to ask a really random question
question uh locally we've been getting
beat to [ __ ] with hail yeah every for
two weeks we had hail every night how
does one deal with torrential hail
storms like that in a ganja store in a
ganja Farm um you get real good at
seeing hail storms coming okay and you
put the tarps up you watch yeah tarps
buckets um that's with our inground
plants uh the hell storm that actually
hit our place um we were able to put 55
gallon trash buckets
over each of the plants so okay just
flip it upside down and give it a little
Hut
yeah um you know if they were bigger
further in the season we'll talk about a
hoop house in a minute sorry I didn't
mean to interrupt you there really loud
you're good um did the who hoop house
get [ __ ] up from that hail um it had a
shade cloth on it okay so you cool um
we'll talk we'll talk about a hoop house
toward the end I'll write that down
because that's we talked about it on a
previous episode but we should uh kind
of re rewind on that one when we can
last year it totally got [ __ ] up by
hell though so it is very possible so
you guys you're gonna [ __ ] some [ __ ] up
Don't Be Afraid like shit's going to go
wrong but you always get next year oh
yeah and you'll you'll you'll Salvage
something out of your Harvest
yes yeah you almost always get something
unless thieves or cops that's the only
thing that's going to take it all that's
funny because I've got the word thieves
and cops written on a note later on in
this I'm glad we're on the same page
here this is awesome uh so so we've got
a few plants in
oh ideally ideally it would be on a
field in Humbolt county or somewhere
towarda or out in Ry on a south facing
slope with a big 18 foot tall chain link
fence where nobody can get in uh but
that that's not always going to happen
for you uh we're going to want these
plants plenty of space between them
you're going to want them outside you're
going to have to think about this
weather I'm kind of skipping ahead but
Jesse said you could put him out now and
then I thought about all the weather
we've been getting uh let's let's just
go right to the hoop house let's talk
about that it seems to be the ideal
outdoor if people want to go Outdoors
cheap uh to protect everything I think a
hoop house might be
uh yeah that's also the best way to get
the the best resin um okay production in
my opinion okay um out just straight up
outdoor tends to get dirty yeah and if
you're making concentrates you're going
to make dust concentrate beaten by the
sun um uh rained on you know all that
good stuff a simple hoop house covering
um can save you a lot of headaches it
can create a couple too but um as long
as it's tall enough you know realize the
strain you're you're growing do a little
research figure out how much you're
going to stretch or if you done this
before you know you'll you know what's
up yeah um so plan for that they're
going to get big outside yeah yeah plan
plan for the size um and make sure you
have plenty of air flow at the top as a
greenhouse and at the bottom so air
fresh air in and old stale air out you
guys it's just as important as in the
grow and the humid air too that's
because the plants are transpiring and
the plastic traps the water in there
yeah so that's you got to get that out
of there all right yeah so let's uh real
quickly if you could describe to me how
to build a you know just a hoop house
that would fit in my backyard you know
maybe just like a 10 x 20 at the biggest
would be the most the just just you know
two or three minutes it's worth of how
to build a hoop house for sure real
simple
um I'm trying to think how simple um I
mean start with the frame the the bottom
all right so take like uh what size did
you say uh like a 10 x 20 10 x 20 uh get
you 20 uh so you'll need 40 foot of
lumber there or 30 foot of lumber there
um no don't yeah 60 yeah there you go
but I get you um I I forgot to the
two um it uh uh so bu build your frame
um just like a big box um secure It To
The Ground you don't even have to secure
it to the ground but it'll help the way
shit's been around here lately I would
secure it um and uh inside that frame
just bend your your PVC tubes you know
use like probably 20 foot tube or
something like or 20 foot stick on that
um and you know that's going to end you
up with
I think somewhere around a s foot
ceiling I want to say I'm not sure on
that though um but uh and then just
continue down um you know this over 20
foot span you'd probably want i' I'd
recommend at least seven um probably go
for more like eight or nine so what
we're doing he's we so you've got a
rectangle you got a rectangle it's a 10
by 20 and then what we're going to do
why we call it a hoop house we're taking
uh PVC tubing and it almost looks like
you're just using hula hoops and
building a long tube you make an arch
from and we're doing it the 10 foot to
10 foot side not the 20 in or the 20
foot so you go from 11 10 acoss you just
make an arch and that way it makes it
about s feet tall and then it's 10 feet
wide and then you do those about every
two or three three or four feet yeah
depending on how much wind um I I here
you know here um in the prairie in uh
Southern Colorado I'd probably recommend
it 3 foot all right so so about every
3et put a put another PVC uh tube and
attach that to uh the Box somehow to
your base uh what what do you use to
attach it um like a conduit clamp
perfect that's what I yeah and then I
also run a lag bolt through there I only
want run one bolt through there and I
drill it out um I've had them what would
you call it wallow them wallow their way
out and it rips the PVC okay and then
that's always fun when you get a a
springboarded PVC pipe just clipping up
in the middle of the night yeah so
catapult some [ __ ] across the the grow
all right so then you got the supports
going over and then do you put one
across the middle yeah um I'd actually
recommend three um so if you're thinking
of it like a clock there'd be one at
12:00 uh one at 9:00 and one at what
would that be two or three yeah okay
yeah nine and three all right that makes
sense okay so now you've got this like
Arch looking building with a beam that
goes down the middle on the top and then
down the 3:00 angle down the 9:00 angle
uh that feels pretty secure how do you
attach that top hole and the side uh the
beams that come across um fence posts is
the easiest way uh just dig a a fence
post at the end of um each end of the
greenhouse on a 20 foot one you might
want one in the middle too um and just
arrange the size so that it meets up
with that skeleton beam and fasten it to
it with more uh conduit clamps okay
sounds like you've done this a several
dozen times yes all right all right so
now pretty much looks like we've got the
skeleton figured out basically right
yeah all right now how do we what do we
use for cover for a a top for this thing
to keep the hail and Rain off of our
beautiful plants it depends on your
budget um if you know uh if you're you
know low in budget
um a visqueen or just polyplastic from
Lowe's works great uh get the heavier
thicker Mill um and you know if you got
a better budget uh we sell Greenhouse
Fabrics lots of places sell Greenhouse
fabric so um and it ranges you know
that's I want to say it's
somewhere hell I don't even know I know
it goes up to like 10 bucks a square
foot so I mean it starts off way cheaper
than that okay but is high yeah yeah
yeah so guys you can afford this if you
guys work a little bit through the
winter you can build this next summer
and you can definitely have you an
outdoor all right so now we covered up
how do you secure the uh the cover there
um um whatever they call them
uh it looks like a a battery uh uh
jumper cable clamp Oh okay little
alligator clamp yeah yeah yeah but
better but stronger yeah we we call them
spring clamps but I don't think that's
what the the nipple clamps yeah yeah
yeah yeah framing clamps all right all
right so that makes a lot of sense yeah
I'm going get them for like 250 at
Harbor Freight all right so go buy a
whole bucket of those yeah literally
I've gone in there and bought like four
buckets of them yeah what are you doing
don't ask lady don't ask yeah all right
so you got this little hoop house uh you
should put a fan in the top guys like in
one of the Peaks at the end cut out a
the shape of the fan and hang a fan in
there because you're going to need to
get some air in and out if you can do a
blower like a grow room blower that's
even cooler those work great on the
ground um you can do one coming in uh
yeah one thing that sucks about those is
though uh they suck up rocks and a lot
of them have plastic blades in them so
take you a piece of ducting that's I
don't know like three foot long and
secure it to the side of the greenhouse
lift it up a little bit higher attach it
to the fan so that it can't soak any
rocks off ground oh man I can just I I
don't want to know what that sounds like
it yeah it's fun sounds like Keys like
keys in the blender I could imagine all
right so we've got air in we've got air
out we've got a nice little
Greenhouse um I don't want I'm going to
save that question right there what kind
of soil should we
use um that depends on your budget and
just your grow style really I mean
should we put them straight into the
dirt do you think or should we use pots
um it you know it also depends on your
location I would tend to recommend pot
even though I would rather be able to
recommend planting in the ground but um
there's a little more to that um if you
go get like a 30-gallon smart pot um
outdoors I recommend the fabric pots
um and they they sell the tan ones now
too which are great because um they
reflect heat a little better than the
black ones that tend to absorb heat um
but you know I mean if you just went
with your favorite potting soil
um just you know I recommend probably
going three times bigger than your
typical indoor container okay large
containers for you guys large containers
stick with your regular nutrient
schedule you know stick with what you're
comfortable with um you know if you want
to do Organics I could spend a whole
episode talking about there are some
episodes with sha you guys that are all
about amending soil and there are great
outdoor mixes in there and I mean that's
personally the way I grow um half of my
PL I I mean we do six plants in the
ground we do six plants in the light dep
Greenhouse um the ones in the ground
have been in that I've been grown in
that soil for eight years now um the
ones in the greenhouse get my homemade
mixture which is real similar to I don't
know Roots so Roots organic is good
stuff yeah all right and they get that
you know personally iow organic so they
get teas and I've been playing around
with ferments and stuff like that but
don't they love nice tea oh man you can
see the growth if you feed them a nice
tea those plants take off yeah
especially with the Ki juice yeah so all
right so now we've got these plants in a
nice Ki juice oh I yeah I could go off
on a whole rant about that that one it
almost flew over my head but as Ki juice
I still don't know what what is that uh
lab lactic acid bacteria yeah and it's
that purple stuff and the fungus stuff
looking stuff is basically great white
you're making great white shark yeah I
have all kinds of names for it that oh
dud it smells like vomit it smells like
beer bar trash can puke yeah all right
so we've got this uh nice little light
dep Greenhouse we've got some plants in
really large pots or not light dep it's
just a little hoop house I mean we
didn't do light dep on this episode we
may discuss that a little more in the
future we've done it once we may cover
if you're interested in the light dep
it's uh you put the plastic on you take
it off um you get another tarp to cover
up the Sun so that you can schedule the
[ __ ] to go to sleep every night at a
speciic you could teach anyone to do it
so and we talk about it in a in a past
episode yeah uh we we'll we'll go more
over that one in the future also uh so
you got them in this little hoop house
you've got large pots with decent soil
you're feeding uh nutrients that you're
familiar with or a bottled nutrient line
because that's uh probably
cost-effective if not our friend sea
will teach you a great soil recipe I'll
find the episode number and insert that
in the notes um outdoor plants tend to
use a little more food food um okay when
I've grown bottled nutrients Outdoors uh
we normally feed to the top end of the
recommendation if maybe even just a
little over um know this was with
General organic specifically yeah
because the plants can metabolize more
because of the sun and the more
available CO2 and the bigger root mass
so you think your gavitas are badass
they ain't got nothing on that one the
sun will kick your's ass uh somebody
asked me what kind of Lights to use and
I was like gas and they're like I've got
low ceilings I like yeah so stick with
your like lumex or
whatever yeah those Magnums or whatever
all right so now when should we expect
to see signs of
flower um Late July early August in
Southern Colorado depends on what
strains we're working with I'd imagine
that too um Inda seem to tend or I would
say in my experience indusco a little
quicker around here so very true the
flow will take off blueberry will be
almost done by the time Golden Goat
spits out pistols uh my my government
meal just kills It Outdoors like it's
it's
great all right um so speaking of mules
I'm just joking that is kind of good
though what kind of problems do you
think uh we should tell the people to be
prepared for um we get those damn little
moths yeah they lay eggs turn into
caterpillars yeah and they bore into
your bud
um if you're doing light dip and it's
early
season um you got watch out for molds um
Bud rot stuff like that um is that
something that can be stopped once it's
happened um mold um I mean we could
spend well I don't know PMS of a bastard
um yes I agree um I mean I personally
don't think you know a little on a fan
Leaf here or there right before Harvest
is one thing if it's on the bud it's
done in my opinion agree Bud rot um I
have just seen that for the first time
this year ever um and it was in it it
was in another light dep um that didn't
have good air circulation um once again
guys get that circulation up we've had a
very rainy spring um and lots of hell
and everything it just the humidity has
been so much higher than a lot of
outdoor growth ERS are used to dealing
with um around here so and we're using
swamp coolers to try to cool the house
on top of that his his loss or his
Harvest was by no means a total loss um
you know he probably lost a plant you
know combined out of I think he did 12
plants in there or something like that
so okay that's not bad yeah I mean
that's the the rule of averages with
growing weed it's not like it was PM
where like you can smell it on buds that
weren't even affected and stuff like
like or at least what I've seen so
far uh how do we deal with animals what
kind of animals do you think we're going
to get um you know depends on where you
live uh deer love it cows love it every
everything that eats stuff loves it um
especially when it's well cared for
so um if you know you know just prepare
for the animals in your area um even
cats and dogs going to say cats rabbits
squirrels all the domestic [ __ ] pest
animals are going to come at it too so
be prepared somehow like you got to
section it off somehow so these animals
don't get to it should we treat for bugs
Outdoors my theory on outdoor growing
you can correct me if I'm wrong you're
the outdoor guy I feel like if we don't
[ __ ] with nature nature will kind of
take care of itself for us like I feel
like if I spray I'm going to upset the
whole system and a bug that wouldn't
normally dominate will dominate because
whatever should have been there to eat
it will be gone is that kind of right
and like where I grow I totally agree
with that um we use very minimal
pesticides um very strategic timing um
in a
greenhouse um you know it depends on how
sealed up your Greenhouse is um a lot of
times it's just like a growroom
environment um
so uh just don't overdo it you know it's
um it is a lot harder for in insects and
parasites to survive outside um I mean
it's the best room in the world it's
it's got perfect air flow and everything
so and and the sun yeah as long as the
plants are happy aren't stressed out you
know I think ASM Max's probably the
strongest thing I've ever used Outdoors
so how do you feel about uh spin aad uh
that's great stuff um that's something
you can do to go after the moths and
stuff like that uh that's a something I
mean we have bees on our property too so
that's a you know always a consideration
um but spinosad is something that you
know we don't really worry about at all
um it's it's totally natural it's like
spraying a tea on the plants which we do
it's actually a it derives from a
bacteria found in the bottle of a rum
jar or in the bottom of a rum jar yeah
yeah yeah yeah or a Brum barrel barrel I
think is what it I think the wood has
something to do with it yeah for sure
for sure I read that a long time ago
somewhere all right uh Captain Jacks
yeah Captain Jacks to the rescue
sometimes so we talked about all the
weather you you guys be prepared for a
lot of weather you're going to get heat
you're going to get hail you're going to
get rain you're going to get wind it's
going to be treacherous out there uh
imagine being stuck outside all the time
and not being able to come inside you're
going to have to prepare for your plants
you're going to need to build them in a
dogghouse or something you're going to
need love all right also something I
thought we should mention is be prepared
for a lot of watering I don't know if
you guys are prepared or realize how
much water your outdoor plants are going
to take uh how often do you water your
outdoor plants Jesse
um well up until you know normally it's
once a day um this year has been a
little different I haven't had to water
as much we've got a lot of rain it's
actually been a pain in the [ __ ] ass
uh my some of my plants are severely
stunted because of it so um don't catch
up though so yeah it'll dry out here
pretty soon yeah yeah we'll be missing
that evening rain yeah so uh what else
was I going to ask you in the middle of
flowering when they start budding out in
the summer are you going to be watering
them twice uh probably so um inground
plants don't need to be watered as much
if you water them right you know okay um
15 20 gallons at a time um it's it's a a
workout when we do um outdoor in
groundwater oh [ __ ] I bet um in the
greenhouse I use the automated system so
I put little Sprinklers and everything
and sweet yeah that shit's yeah screw
that
[ __ ] but that just tells you how much
water um you know even smart pots in E
Outdoors um the the sun just bakes those
pots uh gutal Lowe's or something like
that just fill the side of one of their
you know of a rose pot or something like
that sitting outside um and I mean this
the sun just bakes it it gets so [ __ ]
hot and that gets your roots hot um
which they can survive they just need
plenty of water to be able to handle it
so okay U also you said to put Mulch on
top of your pots also to kind of shade
them a little keep moisture in yeah yeah
uh in ground or in the pots um another
thing if you do have black pots outside
I recommend uh wrapping them in Panda
plastic with the wh side out okay make
them a little reflective yeah yeah in
all that I did that three started doing
that three years ago and it it seemed to
make a difference so cool that's yeah um
what I'd like to figure out for these
people is uh some no till um talk with
Sean some future stuff about it so yeah
no till his NE I've been looking into
that this year it was kind of a last
minute opportunity for them so once they
got the Required licensing and
everything they just went with what they
had
so um which wasn't
much all right before my computer starts
tripping out too much here uh do you
have any tips for the people that are
starting to grow outdoors for their
first time this year um water a lot um
if you're in ground um just make sure
the water's soaking down into the soil
uh once it starts pulling up um give it
a minute you know see how long it takes
it for it to drain down into the soil
that that gives you a real good
indication of um how damp the soil is
cuz that you know a container is easy
you just got to pick it up um you know
and you should be able to through trial
ER figure out how uh how much water to
put in it how much it should weigh how
long it takes to dry out um the the
Earth can be a little more challenging
um uh to Aid in that water and put a
frame around the plant like a 3ft x 3
foot 2x4 frame and just put it on the
ground you can also attach uh the big
crazy uh tomato cages or you know plant
cages made out of fencing to them later
on so prune them out pull them out a
little stretch them apart get light down
in I'm I'm getting a frog in my throat
now all right well uh let's uh let's
wrap it up we've been going for uh 30
minutes now that's enough of a podcast
for these guys we'll let your throat
take a break my throat finally is not
blown out so it's a good time to do a
closing here take some tabs yeah we'll
take some dabs now we'll save some stuff
for next time here uh you guys thanks
again for listening to another episode I
will probably be back in a few days with
the news episode uh there are a couple
news articles out that I want to read
and talk about uh don't forget to check
out our sponsor high grow indoor growing
supplies go in there say what's up to
burn uh if you guys are interested in
sponsoring the podcast or if you have a
product that you would like me to review
send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com it'll get you all
the information that you need uh let's
see make sure you follow me on all the
social media sites you guys I'm easy to
find very easy to find it's a gfyh
podcast or roster Jeff 420 on Twitter on
Instagram it's @ I gentics uh on
Facebook it's grow from your heart I'm
all over the place I've been periscoping
a lot lately uh I go under rosta Jeff on
42 or rosta Jeff 420 on Periscope so if
you guys want to watch some Periscope
videos I mean taking dabs trimming buds
sometimes I'm in the grow room one day
I'm going to do a live podcast on
Periscope but if you want to check that
out follow me on Periscope uh Hey Jesse
how can we follow you on social media um
Instagram Jesse grow Jesse grow on
Instagram check him out he post some
good pictures of some good Colorado
Cannabis I try hey dude thanks for
coming to the show thanks for taking
like an hour and a half out of your
night I appreciate it for sure no
problem we're going to take some dabs
and hang out like Bros here for a minute
then I got to get out of here and give
somebody a ride home from work all right
so if uh let's see don't forget you guys
that every uh episode is no let's see
don't forget the show's available on
iTunes and Stitcher and every single
episode is available on iy genetics
colorado.com also on iry genetics
color.com there's a tab it says gr from
your heart podcast on the top right
button there's a PayPal logo that is a
donation button that goes directly to my
Paypal account I'm never going to charge
you anything for this podcast it's free
but if you feel like you'd like to make
a contribution to say Thank you so that
I could buy a new microphone cover so I
can quit spitting into this funky blue
thing uh that would be appreciated I'm
not trying to beg but I'm just letting
you know that it's there uh let's see I
think that's all I've got for you this
week you guys I'll be back with some
news here in just a couple of days we'll
try to get Jesse back in a couple of
weeks for more outdoor stuff it sounds
like I got to get Shawn on I also owe
you an episode with Spencer we've got a
Cannabis Cup winner that hasn't been on
lately uh him and I already have a
conversation that we want to talk about
we just haven't gotten to it nice so uh
shout out to my ninja Spence thanks for
thanks again for listening and until
next time you guys take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me it's right here it's absolutely clear
the gja herb is the healing of the
nation those
it always be here it be here for
Generation they want you to feel Tipsy
Derby
Tipsy puppy do come your
face they don't want to smoke the Sweet
Lemon
hit the smile up on the
children pick him
[Music]
up CH
it g coming right
back us s laboratory resource
so many illness they call it herb
[Music]
cure so why don't you give I and I the
per
oh so I
I
go rain fall make the G grow and the Sun
come Shin the Bree the falling BL you
pick him up lck him down like to run
down come right
back using your s love your
resource so many he they call
[Music]
never get to
like another get another Li I said I
take a to another
yeah they want us to feel
Tipsy puppy
doll your
[Music]
face it don't want you to burn the Sweet
Lemon
call oh my
Lord get the smile on the
children him up him down
off
[Music]
right rain
falling the Sun come shine in the bre
the Ping
blood up down up
[Music]
down