[Music]
thank you
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host Rasta Jeff
this is episode 790 of the grow from
your heart podcast in this episode I'm
going to give away a free pack of seeds
that's right I've teamed up with our
friends at seedshearnow.com to give away
a free pack of irie genetic seeds we'll
talk more about that later in this
episode before we go too far I do want
to announce that irie genetics will be
at the dude grows cup that's right the
dude gross cup is happening again this
year June 3rd in Fort Collins Colorado
make sure you check out dgcup.com for
all the information I want to send
another big shout out to our friends at
Comedy Works that's right I was back at
Comedy Works over the weekend I got to
see Ari shaffir we saw Brian Simpson and
of course the show was hosted and emceed
and opened by none other than Sam Talent
all three of the performers were amazing
everybody at Comedy Works treats missed
dread Vibes of myself like royalty so
big shout out to all of the comedians
big shout out to all of the staff at
Comedy Works and of course a big shout
out to miss red Vibes Comedy Works
doesn't pay me to say that I just have
so much fun going there that I do need
to give them a shout out and I know that
some of the crew listens to the podcast
so big fist want big love to the whole
crew at Comedy Works all right now let's
segue into the email and grow question
portion of this episode in the last
episode I said that if you sent me a
grow question on the grow help tab on my
website I said if I read that question
here on the podcast you would win a free
pack of seeds I want to give a big shout
out to my new friend Stuart for sending
me a great grow question and also
congratulations Stuart I would like to
send you a free pack of seeds because
I've read your I'm going to read your
question here on the podcast uh big
shout out to Stuart also big shout out
to seedshairnow.com for sponsoring the
seed giveaway Stewart has won a free
pack of irie genetics beans to go along
with his already packed Garden of irie
genetic seeds let's jump into the grow
question this one came from the grow
help tab on the iregenetics.com website
you go to iregenetics.com on the top
right there's a part that says as
questions click right on that tab it
will bring down a list of questions that
I want to ask it basically says what
kind of question do you have what strain
are you growing where are you growing it
what type of lighting I ask a few basic
questions that way I can answer your
question with more detail so go to
iregenetics.com there's a bunch of tabs
on the top there's one that says
questions click right over there that
will bring up this form fill this out if
I read that question on the podcast you
will also win a free pack of seeds of
course this giveaway does expire at some
time whenever I decide I haven't
determined that whatever the sponsorship
and the deal ends it ends but for now
send me your grow questions you may win
some free seeds congrats to our friend
Stuart Stewart's question let's get to
it finally it goes a little bit like
this it says what strains are you
growing Stuart is growing a nice Buffet
of strains it looks like we've got
Cherry Garcia early Berry Grandpa's
cookies uh spice and strawberry banana
more that he can't remember he's got
some Nuketown in there heavy duty fruity
to Afterglow testers the prize Scarlet
Begonias Lady Marmalade played and he
said all by the men the myth the legend
rosted Jeff well thank you brother I
appreciate that you're growing a nice
Buffet of great genetics in there it
says where are you growing these These
are being grown indoors under LED
lighting
um there's a lot of questions here that
don't really pertain I've already read
the question a lot of these details
don't pertain so I'm going to skip some
of this we're going to get right to the
technical part of this question uh it
says rust to Jeff let me start out by
saying I'm a big fan of the show I've
been listening since right before the
vid bro thank you for jumping on I got a
lot of new uh listeners and subscribers
right around the vid time by the way if
you haven't already subscribed do hit
that subscribe button everybody out
there there's a lot more to this but
then it goes on it says I'm a big fan of
your gear ran a few strains and already
I have more in the dirt it says my
problem is that my overall dried and
trimmed weight is not to my satisfaction
so he's grown a bunch of great genetics
but the overall finished product doesn't
weigh enough we're not getting enough
finished product here at the end we do
have more details here the message goes
on it says in veg I have a 600 B spec
and a 150r spec covering about 40
seedlings and 30 veg in three gallon
homes and one of the flower rooms I have
a 40 I have 48 3 gallon plants under two
600 Aura specs and one 350 R-Spec Diablo
which are all hlg those are good lights
but that's a lot of plants bro uh and
the other flower room okay then he
describes the other room he says I'm
using New Millennium nutrients that
should work well for you at the
recommended dosage along with h g root
accelerator and epsom salt at a low
dosage it goes on and says I don't test
my PPM I also just put four weeks but I
have everything from seedlings to plants
to week nine a flower and everything
between uh he says I am supplementing
CO2 and he says anyway I never did a
true Fino hunt and my plants dried and
trim weight goes from 16 grams of plant
to 38 grams of plant I've seen there are
a lot of plants in this room I've seen
pictures there are a lot in there this
is my overall yield is less than half a
less than a pound and a half I have lost
track with with the plants so he says
I've lost track with the plants that are
in veg when they flower I can tell
anyway should I start tracking in veg
when I clone and then next Harvest this
is kind of worded a little bit oddly and
I'm reading it very quickly says I need
weight to cover the cost and so forth or
is there something I'm missing or
messing up or any other suggestions
please feel free to read this for a show
I also worked okay so there's a lot of
details that I'm going to skip in here
in this question but there's also a lot
of stuff that I can explain very quickly
just from the little bit that I read my
friend sent a lot of pictures here of
this grow the first thing that I noticed
is that there are in my opinion I'm not
sure if you're going to disagree but in
my opinion there are just too many damn
plants in this room uh you're trying
you're kind of with all due respect and
I understand this because I'm guilty as
well you're being a plant hoarder you've
got too many different strains in there
in my opinion you got too many different
plants and really from reading what
you're telling me in this one paragraph
you don't have a strategy so if you
don't have a strategy if you don't have
a road map it's hard to get to the
destination it's hard to get to the goal
so the first thing I would do
I would minimize some of those plants in
every room there are too many plants in
every room I got a lot of photos every
room the plants are way too close
together that's why they look so tall
and stretchy and they're kind of there's
not a lot of growth at the bottom part
and they've really stretched out and I
know that you've cleaned up the bottoms
in a lot of those photos but they
wouldn't be so tall and stretchy if you
spread them out a little bit they're too
close together and instead of getting
tight nodes and developing the way they
should they're stretching to get up to
the light because there's just so many
of them crowded together instead of
being able to reach out and go ah yeah
I'm living the dream they're going hey
is there some [ __ ] light up there and
they're just trying to reach up as hard
as they can because they're frustrated
with life that's what it looks like to
me from the photos and that's simply
because you're just packing too many in
there and I know it sounds like a
numbers game you would think the more
plants in there the more product I'm
going to produce but there is a point of
diminishing returns and you've hit that
point my friend I would remove at least
one row along the outside one row along
the outside and the whole Square you've
got and just use all that space to
spread them out that much more I would
minimize a lot of plants in that room to
be be honest with you so there are too
many plants that are stretching and
they're competing for space because the
lower leaves are not getting any light
that's why you've had to clean up all
the bottoms and that's going to keep
happening as tall as they get the more
tall the taller they grow they're just
going to keep shading each other out and
they're just going to keep stretching
more to get taller and taller and tall
plants are great but you want plants
that fill in and produce a lot and they
don't have that option so you're not
setting yourself up for Success from the
beginning at the veg stage you're
already getting behind the plants are
already getting stretchy you need a good
foundation a good structure to have a
good weight producing plant so first
thing I would do I keep saying this too
many damn plants in all of those rooms
bro I know you got a lot of plants in
there you're just like me I'm a seed
hoarder I'm a plant hoarder I try to
grow as many as will fit in the damn
room that I am legally allowed but I
stuff the room dude
um so I get it but you've got to get rid
of some of those plants also they're too
close together spread them out also one
thing I noticed in your pictures there
are no fans there's no air movement in
any of those rooms which is also why the
plants are getting tall and stretchy and
spindly if you put some air in there
some air movement blow the plants around
they'll get a little stronger they won't
be so thin and wispy they'll get a
little bit thicker that will produce
bigger fatter buds a better Harvest a
better yield in the long run
um also they're not popped and twisted
nothing's really done to them they're
topped one time it looks like they
spread out and then you defoliate and
clean up the bottom shave the legs a
little bit but there's no popping and
twisting done if you spread them out a
little bit top them pop them and twist
them and put some fans on them that's
going to give you bigger beefier
stockier more robust plants you'll be
able to veg for a little bit less time
you'll still get big fat plants and you
won't need as many in the room so work a
little bit on the popping and twisting
uh I saw that I saw that the one room in
veg was heavily defoliated I probably
wouldn't defoliate that that much in veg
that is where you're getting the energy
I would wait a little bit more until the
flowering phase early flower mid flower
to do that default that heavy
defoliation that you're doing you can
still pull leaves but you're going kind
of hard in the beginning in my opinion
based on the photos so you got too many
plants in there they're too close
together there are no fans I'd spread
those [ __ ] apart get some wind on
them pop them and twist them I'm sure
you've heard the episode about popping
and twisting where you just uh I'll show
you kind of with this microphone a
little bit if this were the main stock
of the plant I would start at the bottom
right where it comes out of the dirt I
would grab it remember in school and we
tried to pick who goes first at baseball
who bats first uh you grab it down here
and then you put the other hand up here
and the other guy goes like this and
like this every time you do that just
twist opposite directions and pop the
cellulose structure of that plant it'll
sound like this
I don't know if that worked it'll sound
like that sound just like I'm popping a
knuckle that's what we call it on the
plants pop the knuckles what happens is
that will slow down that vertical growth
vertical right yeah slow down the
vertical growth of the plant it'll also
make the branch get a little bit more
robust and a little bit sturdier that
more robust sturdier thicker plant is
going to produce bigger fatter juicier
buds so it's going to make your stocks a
little stronger that's one thing that I
would definitely recommend less
defoliation and more fans is how I would
start then then something I want to talk
about is you said that you're using
um the new millennium nutrients with a
couple of additives are you using any
Bloom boosters in my opinion the New
Millennium is great but I like to add
something for a bloom booster if you
want to use something that is very
affordable and very effective in my
opinion I think that bud swell works
very well with the New Millennium mix
add some bud swell in there add that
around week five week six also I really
like a product called shine I talk a lot
about shine if I'm growing smokable
flour a lot of what I grow is for seed
if I'm I'm growing smokeable flour I put
a lot of shine in the mix I really think
that puts bulk in there it puts weight
to the product and it puts a lot of
trichomes and a lot of funk to your
product so the bud swell and some shine
and then a kelp product with that and
then also don't forget about the the
Ruby New Millennium doesn't sponsor me
or pay me but I think Ruby's a great
product it's fulvic acid use that five
milliliters per gallon with every feed I
think that'll make your feed more
effective so a bloom booster do you have
some sort of a balloon booster in there
something to push it something to make
it go she bang you've got all the uh all
the gas in there do you have anything to
make it turbocharged we got a
turbocharged this [ __ ] if you're not
getting enough we got a turbo charge it
the flower that you posted a picture of
looks good you posted some very
beautiful very colorful flower that
looks really good it looked healthy it
looked happy so I'm thinking we may need
just to boost these up a little bit the
topping looks good I would work on some
sort of scrogging or some sort of
trellis system or maybe some sort of
supports I would have less plants in
there and I would spread them out that
would make the plants get bigger they
would get beefy fat buds which are going
to need support so I would work on some
sort of a scrog net or some sort of
trellis or maybe tomato cages or maybe
just a bunch of sticks in there if you
do that be very careful but I would
recommend something to support them that
way they don't have to spend all of
their energy holding themselves up and
they can use more energy producing
flowers
also strain selection you said that you
haven't done any pheno hunts I think
strain selection is going to be a big
deal for you it's going to make a big
difference if you've got plants in there
that are not putting the weight you need
definitely remove those plants if you've
got plants in there that bang out the
weight you need put more of those plants
in the room that's kind of a no-brainer
there but that comes from a good Fino
hunt that comes from running [ __ ] that
also comes from not getting too attached
to those plants that are not performing
well they may be your friends they may
be green they may be beautiful but
sometimes we've got to call those plants
don't be afraid if you're trying to hit
numbers and pay the bills you can't get
too attached to things you've got to
remember that you've got to pay pay the
bills get rid of those low yielding low
quality plants that do not produce that
don't reach your goal set yourself up
for success bro so strain selection less
strains in there also less strains
overall and then I would dial it down to
like maybe two maybe three strains per
flower room that way you could learn the
strains if you've got too many plants in
that room how are you going to know that
this plant likes a little bit more
nitrogen and this plant doesn't like so
much Cal Mag and this plant would like
it a little bit cooler you'll never find
that out because you've got to run that
Baseline room all the time with no
adjustments no changes so I would
eliminate it to your few favorite plants
and then really build a relationship and
dial it in with a few cultivars in that
room that can definitely max out and
reach the potential and reach the goals
which you need to reach you've got too
many uh you're dating too many ladies in
there you're never going to learn one of
them to make one of them fully satisfied
you're going to be juggling to keep all
those ladies happy you just got to focus
on one and make that one lady super
happy and you will both win together so
one of my pieces of advice is to just
minimize is the amount of plants and the
variety in there and dial it in build a
relationship with a cut learn that cut
and maximize the [ __ ] out of that
um CO2 may help you said you have CO2 in
the room I don't know how much CO2
you're using but bang that [ __ ] out bro
turn it up get more of that
um then here's something that I really
think will help you a lot I think that a
little bit of a strategy a little bit of
a plan a little bit of a schedule a
little bit of a goal a little bit of a
standard operating procedure would
really help you out it kind of sounds
like you're you're growing you're making
flowers you're making product but you're
doing it kind of willy-nilly I would uh
write down when I picked these clones
I'm going to veg them is they're going
to be in the Clone stage for two weeks
I'll put them into small pots for three
weeks into bigger pots let them veg for
four weeks after that then we flour them
for nine weeks set a timeline decide how
tall in the veg you're gonna let those
plants get start setting some goals then
definitely start writing down when you
put when you cut the Clone when you put
it into veg when you put it into flour
start writing down what you feed how
often you feed it
create repeatables results by creating a
standard operating procedure and by
keeping notes and then keep the notes of
what you did
see what came out good see what came out
bad and then repeat what was good don't
do what was bad it looks like you've got
the right idea as a grower it definitely
looks like you know how to take care of
plants how to transplant things how to
build a room uh it looks like you have a
good understanding but I think you need
uh just a little bit of like a drill
sergeant and they're just saying what
did you do in here a soldier like write
this [ __ ] down Soldier get on a schedule
Soldier clean this [ __ ] up get rid of
these plants like you just need that
person over your shoulder and make that
person to you you're the only one in
there so you've got to be accountable
for that sort of stuff uh get on a
schedule I keep saying this but uh I'm
really OCD about I know I've got clones
in a cloner right now I've got small
pots somewhere right now I've got bigger
pots somewhere right now I've got a
pollinated room right now if I open up
my notebook in those rooms I know when
each thing happened in that room I know
what the last feed was in each of those
rooms I know what's going on I know when
the harvests are going to happen uh
knowing when the next Harvest is going
to happen allows me to know when to cut
clones for the Harvest to cut behind
that because I've got the Harvest coming
I've got veg plants going and as soon as
the Harvest comes down the veg plants go
into flour I've got to get Cuts so that
I've got those veg plants ready to go
once again so I've got a good tight
schedule written down I know exactly
when that [ __ ] needs to happen it's
basically when these clones go into
these pots these cups go into these pots
and they're going to veg but then the
first the old pots that were in there
going because I do it in two stages it
you'll learn your Rhythm So eventually
you'll be able to create a Perpetual
cycle you've got two rooms you should
have mother plants clones small veg and
then you should have veg lined up to go
into each flower room or at least a veg
in that room for a couple of weeks
you'll be able to create a great Rhythm
if you just plan a strategy and know
these plants flower for nine weeks that
means that every nine weeks I need to
have more plants ready to go into this
room figure out how long to veg when to
cut the plants that's a two-week clone
cycle you got seven more weeks to go you
got three weeks in a small pot four
weeks in a big pot then you go into
flour repeat that process dial it in
learn the plants learn the process learn
the Rhythm you will start banging out
the weight that you need so my friend
the overall diagnosis the prognosis my
my assumption in there is I think you're
just packing way too many plants in that
room and like I said it sounds like more
plants equals more weight but it doesn't
always equal more weight it equals more
fluffy Bud because all of the plants are
competing for that light that's in the
room it's like trying to feed a bunch of
people you could feed a hundred people
the same amount of food every day and
you're gonna have a bunch of skinny
people walking around if you cut it down
to 70 people those people get that much
more food they're going to get a little
bit thicker you start unfortunately we
can't just go cut out people but you see
what I'm saying if you cut it down to 50
percent of the people they get fed twice
as much they'll be able to thrive get
bigger build some muscle kick some ass
that's kind of what I'm recommending
happens in this grow also take those
[ __ ] notes uh definitely get a
schedule take some notes and get some
strategy going bro get a notebook get a
calendar we've all got Google devices
there are apps that'll take notes for
you if you need some help and want some
guidance on that please do Reach Out out
I'd be more than happy maybe I could do
a full episode on how to set up some
schedules and take some notes and then
also add those Bloom boosters that bud
swell uh the shine some kelp products
and definitely use that fulvic acid if
you are not all right my dude I rambled
on quite a while how long have we been
going I think I rambled out long enough
about that one Stuart thank you for the
great question I do look forward to
sending you a free pack of seeds make
sure the next email you send me has got
your address and if you've got any
requests for seeds please do make your
request if I've got what you request I
will kindly send it if I don't have it
you're going to get some surprises don't
be disappointed and just to burst your
bubble right now there are no orange
gasm seeds available for these freebies
those are gone all right podcast world
that is enough podcasting for me today
if you did not win the free seeds on
today's episode have no fear because
there will be plenty more opportunities
to win free seeds it is very easy to win
free seeds all you have to do is go to
my website
iregenetics.com on the top there's a
bunch of tabs there's one that says
questions click on that tab send me a
good grow question if I read your grow
question here on the podcast I will send
you a free pack of irie Genetics seeds
of course that giveaway is sponsored by
our friends at seedsherenow.com Big
shout out to seedshernow.com for
sponsoring a free seed giveaway if you
have any questions Corrections comments
or concerns you know I'd love to hear
from you my email address is grow from
yourheart hotmail.com don't be shy send
me those questions send me that
constructive criticism that positive
feedback even if you've got hate mail
don't be shy I'll still read it let me
know what you think of the podcast make
sure you support the show on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart anything else you might need is on
my website of course iregenetics.com
there's that grow help tab there's a
link to the Discord there's a link to
iridirect anything you could imagine is
on
iriegenetics.com ladies and gentlemen
that's all I've got for you for this
episode you know I'll be back in another
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to our friend
Lawrence Eugene Dunn and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]