[Music]
thank you
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host Rasta Jeff
this is episode
791 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun episode lined up for us
in this episode I'm going to give away a
free pack of seeds I've teamed up with
our friends at seedshernow.com to give
away a free pack of irie genetic seeds
we'll talk more about that later in this
episode before we get too far I do want
to remind you that I will be at the dude
Groves Cup this year that's right June
3rd we are doing the dude gross Cup in
Fort Collins Colorado make sure you
check out dgccup.com for all the
information I also want to send a big
thank you shout out to everybody who
participated in the sale on I redirect I
did a big sale over the past week a lot
of people got a lot of great deals a lot
of great orders and it took me a little
bit of time to get all those packages
out I do apologize for that all of the
orders have been sent by now you should
have a tracking number many of the
orders have landed by the time this
episode comes out thank you for all of
this support if you want to stay
informed stay up to date I know about
the next sale the next drop the easiest
way to do it is to join the newsletter
if you go to iregenetics.com or
iridirect.com and you scroll down toward
the bottom of the page there's a tab
where it says stay in touch or stay
updated with ire genetics type in your
email address hit return that will add
you to my newsletter when I knew it when
I do a new drop when I do updates when I
add new inventory of course you will be
notified of that stuff on I redirect via
the newsletter also the people on
patreon do get first dibs when I do a
sale the higher the tier the better the
uh the heads up you're going to get
sometimes the better coupon code this
time they got the first heads up the
deals were coming then they also got
free shipping so maybe join the patreon
definitely join the newsletter and if
nothing else do of course join the
Discord the Discord is free the
newsletter is free come hang out I do
encourage that also I want to announce
that we've done some changes on I
redirect by the time this episode comes
out all the web updates will have been
done we have now got a tiered giveaway
system so the more seeds you buy the
more freebies you will get we make it
very clear and it's indicated on your
shopping cart which freebies come with
your orders it's right there on the
screen if you spend this much you will
get this if you spend this much I'll
give you this and this those do stack by
the way if you spend 100 you get the
freebie 430 and the freebie for 100 if
you spend 200 I think you get a freebie
at 25 uh 100 uh 150 and 200 and I think
there's a 250 tier also yes there is uh
if you spend 250 on I redirect at this
time you actually get a free 10 pack of
big mountain fudge cake along with a few
other freebies that will come with that
so that is my Ramble On the updates on
ireedirect.com make sure you join the
patreon sign up for the newsletter check
out the Discord and then also look for
the new freebies on I redirect I know
that's a lot to ask for from you right
here at the start of the show but it's a
good deal you will appreciate it all
right that's a lot of rambling let's
work my way into the email portion of
today's podcast cast I've got a couple
of great emails here in front of me the
first one comes from our friend they
want their name set on there I'm not
sure they want their whole name oh they
do they want high off kebabs to be their
name on the show big shout out to high
off kebabs high off kebabs first of all
let me give you a big congratulations
because in the last episode I said that
if I read your message from The Grow
question submissions tab on the website
if you send a question there and I do
read that that you will win a free pack
of seeds so high off Kebab send me your
address because I do owe you a free pack
of seeds of course that free seed
giveaway is sponsored by
seedshairnow.com shout out to the crew
at seedshairnow.com so our friend high
off kebabs did send a grow question it
goes a lot like this it says roster Jeff
bless your soul brother uh big respect
many blessings back at you brother it
says I picked up the blueberry butcher
regular seeds I've planted all 10 of
them sounds like you're about to have a
party bro and thanks for grabbing the
blueberry butchers since they are in the
vegetative stage some are bushy and some
are taller yes that is a uh a
phenotypical expression you'll see that
I'm amongst the population that is very
common especially amongst the F1 filial
generation it says they are 10 to 24
average 24 inches tall on average I'm
going to take clones from each one and
then flip them to flower that is a great
strategy I recommend that take a clone
from everything before you flour it
because you may have the most amazing
cannabis you've ever grown there it may
be your favorite it might be the plant
that does the thing you need done and if
you don't have a clone of it it'd be
really heartbreaking to know that that
jar will be empty someday and you can't
reproduce it so always take a clone that
is my strategy that is my preaching then
it goes on it says how would I do this
that's a very good question it said how
would I control the males from not
throwing pollen how long would it take
for a novice Grover to realize the males
and then there's a little bit more
details we'll talk about later on in
this so this is a great question we can
talk very in depth about this one this
is basically about doing cutting clones
to do some sexing and not contaminating
the rest of the girl with pollen so
let's talk about this all right so it
sounds like you've got a good idea of
what you were doing already and you were
already on to a good path of being
successful with this uh the plants are
10 to 24 inches tall on average which
means by the time this episode comes out
it will be time to get clones from these
plants so how do we do this uh very
simply grow them you've got them in your
pots you've got them under lights
they're growing they're going to keep
producing branches I would recommend
taking three clones from each plant
that's going to be 30 Cuts if legally
and everything is that's possible for
you I recommend taking three clones from
each plant uh there's going to be one
really healthy clone at the top of the
plant that main top I would make that
the Clone that's always my favorite
clone then I always clean up the bottom
branches off of my plants if you've got
a couple of good healthy branches there
on the bottom make two clones out of
those now you've got three clones from
every plant I use I can make clones in
an easy cloner I can make clones in the
uh little root Riot plugs with the Dome
over it I'm pretty proficient at making
clones in just about any style that
needs to be done however when I do clone
making videos YouTube doesn't like it
and they take them down so I can tell
you briefly how I do clones I wait till
the plants are nice and healthy and then
I cut them at a 45 degree angle I dip it
in a I use the uh the clonex gel the
purple stuff I use that wear gloves when
you use that always
cut it at a 45 degree angle dip it in
the clonex and then if you're going into
an easy cloner all you got to do is put
it in the collar and then make sure the
water in the easy cloner is appropriate
I use a EC of 1.1 with the easy cloner
uh the clonex uh the liquid solution the
yellow one and then I will adjust the pH
to about six one six two and then I will
set it and forget it sometimes if uh I
know it's in a warm room sometimes I'll
add some of the what's the product that
prevents the algae from growing in there
can't even think of the name clearas I
knew when I gave up it popped into my
head add some clear Reds in there once
every five to seven days ish and just
Let It Rock uh maybe add some water in
there a few days later and that cloner
should Rock for you or clip it dip it
and then stick it into the uh a rapid
Rooter and then I feed those rapid
rooters I spray them actually to keep
them nice and wet but not too soggy uh
put this the cloning solution the same
solution 1.1 uh clonex at a pH of about
6.2 shake it up real good spray the the
root Riot plugs or the rapid Rooter
plugs so there so get those nice and
appropriately wet I spray them with a
spray bottle I dip the Clone in the
clonex solution then pop it right in
there I spray the underside of the Dome
so it's wet inside there then I put that
dome right on top of it at this point
all of the vents are covered up and then
I put it under a light to get a lot of
humidity happening in there and I
probably won't touch that for five to
seven days then I'll slowly start
popping it open for a little bit of time
slowly open the vents and increase my
open interval until I can get them into
their forever homes but that is a
quickie on how to do clones there are
full episodes on that however YouTube
keeps taking mine down shout out to
YouTube for that part
um so get your plants grow them until
they're big enough to get a clone get
three clones from each plant
I like to wait since you're kind of new
I would wait until those clones begin to
show roots that way you know that you've
got them they're going to be successful
you've got three opportunities for each
one as soon as you see Roots popping out
of however you're doing the Clones if
it's out of the bottom of the easy
cloner or popping out of the the rapid
rooters then I would put the main big
plants into flower now we can move the
big plants into flour we've got clones
we don't have to stress about having a
preservation or a backup they're already
rooting they should work out and also if
they don't you've still got a few days
to take clones there's also the option
for re-veg but I digress let's keep
going here uh we've got our clones we're
gonna put the big plants Under 12 12.
they're going to start flowering now in
about 12 days you should be able to
identify the males and the females it
may take a little bit longer and maybe a
little bit earlier but generally 10 to
14 days is how long it takes for a
cannabis plant to show you if it's a
male or a female this will depend on
several things this will depend on how
far end of veg this plant has been going
how long has it been in that pot how
root bound is it how tall is the plan
also some plants like to show you that
they're male way earlier than some other
plants like to show you males so just
maybe a real eager candidate to show you
that's a male also this will depend on
your lighting how much lighting have you
been giving these plants if they're
getting a lot of light it may show you a
little bit more early if they haven't
been getting a lot of light it may take
a little bit longer also one thing to
keep in mind that I noticed those plants
that get real stretchy right away and
grow right above everybody a lot of the
times those are male plants so get don't
get too excited about the taller plants
in the garden when you're in veg because
oftentimes those are the boys they want
to get above all the girls so that when
they get taller when it's time to flower
they can put pollen out and the pollen
will fall down onto the girls that's why
the boys try to get taller get above
everybody that's their whole intention
of that let me get back to the notes
back to the question uh that way we can
help you out a little bit more
accurately my question is how would I
control males from not throwing pollen
so they're probably not going to dump
pollen somewhere until about day 14 to
21 maybe right in that area about day 17
is probably when you're going to get
pollen they're going to show you that
they're males about day 10. so you've
got a four day seven day period of when
you're not gonna have any problems you
can pull them out of there they don't
just uh the male plants don't just pop
up and go poof I'm ejecting pollen they
start building uh you've got to look at
books and establish first of all learn
how to identify males and females that
should have been I should have done that
part should have guided you to do that
part way earlier in this episode learn
how to identify males and females that
should be in every cannabis book that
should be all over the Internet I've
done an episode on it learn how to
identify males and females they will
start popping up the males will start
popping up little Nubs and that little
nub will start to get a little a little
branch on it then on that Branch we'll
form a little ball then more balls will
form and then more balls will form and
eventually those balls will start to
open up and pollen will come out you get
plenty of warning that that is a male
plant before the pollen forms so pay
attention that is the way to prevent the
uh pollen from coming out
identify the males you can do that like
I said probably 10 to 14 days and you've
still got if you do it quickly enough
you will not get any pollen in the room
you got to go in there and do a visual
inspection of every single plant push
all the plants into a group on one side
of the room and then move them back over
into their spot to the left side of the
room as you look at them not a not a
male move it over not a male move it
over not a male move it over so put them
into flour and pay attention to them
your other option another option is you
can get a lab sex test you can order a
lab sex testing kit from farmer Freeman
or other companies big shout out to our
buddy farmer Freeman does not pay me to
support him but he's just a good got a
good product does good work so they will
send you a sex testing sample kit you'll
take a little sample of your leaf and
rub it on a little card I'm not sure how
farmer Freeman does it but you just take
a leaf rub it on a card fold that up you
mark that plan number seven or whatever
it says and then you mark that card
number seven or whatever it says you
send all your cards to the testing lab
they send you an email that says plant
one is a boy plant two is a girl plant
three is a boy plant four is a girl they
let you have a breakdown of every plant
that is male and female so then you can
use that lab testing or you can use your
visual eyes to go ahead and identify
male plants and when you do identify the
males if it's through a lab report or if
it's through your own visual
identification go ahead and cut down
that male plant but wait till you're
sure because a lot of people are new and
they see some stuff happening and they
think that the plant is a male and they
cut it down a little bit early make sure
you're certain that that plant is a male
and then cut it down as soon as you're
positive it is a male then the next step
is to go in the Clone room and remove
all of the Clones that came from that
plant so when you cut the Clones make
sure they are clearly labeled so go in
the room clearly label the Clones when
you cut them they came from plant a
plant B Plant C you can name them if you
want you can give them letters numbers
you could put colored stickers on them
as long as it matches red plant red
clones purple plant purple clones plant
number 57 clone number 57 as long as
that [ __ ] matches up and your code you
could draw hieroglyphics if you want as
long as it matches and you know that
I've got to get rid of the uh the
hieroglyphic that looks like an antelope
on the big plant and the hieroglyphic
that looks like an antelope on the
little plant so uh go in there once
you've identified the males and females
remove both the big plant and the little
plant then the other part of the
question is how long would it take for a
novice grower to realize the males if
you do a little bit of research on the
internet and look at a couple of books
and see what a male and a female plant
looks like it'll be very obvious in
about 12 days from flower I I really
think you'll be able to identify them if
you can't come to the Discord come to
the irie Army Discord and go to the
general help tab or anywhere in there
and just post pictures and say hey can
somebody help me identify if these are
males or females a lot of people will go
in there and they'll give you very
useful advice I trust the people in the
irie Army and if you really really need
help tag me and I'll go look at it and
I'll see if I can give you solid advice
but I do trust the whole crew in there
they will give you good advice
um how long would it take probably about
10 days side note I will be going on
vacation oh this is going to be the fun
part going on vacation March 22nd if I
flip to flower would I have enough time
to see the males and remove them from
the garden which should be about three
weeks or so from me writing this uh
you're gonna find out if you got males
or females in about 14 days I would flip
now and this episode comes out it's time
to flip do it that day it's going to be
the first week of March still when this
comes out so go ahead and flip now do
that now that's my advice to you all
right there is more to this he does talk
about the setup uh we don't need to know
about the setup right now we are still
sexting the plants so really quickly I
do have some notes here it says veg damn
uh clone them make sure you get good
labels flip the big plants also you guys
you don't have to flip the big plants a
lot of people will flip the small plants
uh and then you can find out if those
are males or females right away or
another way to do it I should have
mentioned this also you can just veg
them and then re or flip them into flour
and re-vege I've talked about that
however this listener does not have time
for that because he's got to go on
vacation
um keep the Clones you need keep the big
plants you need and then watch out for
the males and call the plants that you
don't eat I think I covered it I
recapped I think I answered your
question pretty well my friend high off
kebabs thank you for the great question
I hope we are able to identify your male
and female plants before you do go on
vacation like we said if you need any
help do send pictures to the irie Army
Discord we will do our best to help you
out but it should be quite obvious which
are boys and girls and also don't forget
send me another email with your shipping
address and a good name to put on the
box because you my friend did win a free
pack of irie Genetics seeds all right
I've got another message here in front
of me I don't want to waste too much
time I do get quite rambly this one came
from the irie genetics help tab on
iregenetics.com uh The Listener wants to
be called ripened bananas they've got a
problem in the garden they're growing
wedding cheesecake Auto cross to Jawa
pie that sounds delicious they're going
indoors under LEDs let's get to the main
part of the question here I'm not sure
some of this info pertains to the
question it says yo roster Jeff I'm
wondering about keeping regular mails
and auto to regular F1 males and the veg
light cycle to save on hold to
eventually breed with but not for a
while all right it's a long since I have
another breeding project going first all
right so there's a lot of stuff to
unpack there regular males are going to
be one set of answers in this question
Auto to regulars are going to be another
answer and F1 males just count on the
same batch as regular males also I think
Autos could be f1s as well but
um just wanted to clear some of that up
and then we're going to move forward it
says
um I have another breeding project going
will the male plants in veg typically
not pollinate any females around or will
they sometimes pollinate female plants
if they are held held for a long time in
a vegetative stage I feel like stable
genetics uh that's not the correct term
use of the word stable here we've talked
about that would mostly not pollinate
Less in flower light cycle but I also
wouldn't be surprised if it happens
sometimes trying to hone my skills with
stability and best practices thank you
so much for all of your awesome content
and info for sharing your expressions
and for your desire to help others
you're the man much love bro that is a
great message there's a lot to talk
about here
um oh by the way also you did win a free
pack of seeds I'm reading your message
here on the show which means that you
should send me your address as well so
that I can send you a free pack of irie
genetic seeds that that giveaway once
again is sponsored by seedsherandow.com
gotta remember to mention our friends at
seeds here now let's talk about a lot of
this
uh will the male plants uh typically not
pollinate
um in a vegetative stage if it's in a
true vegetative stage it will not
pollinate those plants will not
pollinate like I talked about previously
they'll need some time to shift into the
flower stage then they'll need time to
start developing pollen sacks then it'll
take a little bit for those sacks to
open you should be paying attention to
the plants you should be able to
identify that way before that happens
however
these are cannabis plants and [ __ ] does
go Haywire sometimes if you get a male
plant that is not getting enough light
it becomes root bound or is just not
getting fed enough sometimes they'll go
into panic mode and they will start to
flower just like a female plant uh some
of us have female plants that are of a a
more tropical variety a longer flowering
varietal sometimes if you don't give
them enough light if they get a little
bit root bound if they get shaded a
little bit or if you just over or under
feed it or if it gets bugs it may just
go into flower because it's in [ __ ]
panic mode and that's just what some
plants do so if your male plant does
experience any stress any drought over
feeding under feeding if it's too
crowded in it may start to stretch up
and then it'll go hey guess what you're
not treating me right I'm going into
flour and then it'll just flower at that
point yes it can pollinate plants but
keep in mind also the female plants can
only receive pollen once they've
developed pistols and the male plants uh
will only pollinate once they've
developed these stamens and those have
grown out and then exploded a little bit
so let me catch up read the notes Here
make sure I'm on the right track to
answering you a little bit
um they won't pollinate unless they make
some pollen you gotta put them into
flour or they've got to uh flour because
you've stress induced that flowering
stage then stability we've talked about
stability that is more stability means
uniformity amongst population more than
anything so
um any plants could express a phenotype
that will make pollen under uh not
perfect conditions if you're stressing
the plant that could happen with any
plant so uh keep the room right keep the
male plant happy don't a lot of people
just shove the mail off into the corner
and they're like I'll use them when I
need him uh treat him like he's the star
of the show the male plant is the
[ __ ] King my plant is called King
Solomon uh without without that male the
other girls aren't going to make seeds
so he stays right in the middle under
the light I've got to Jack the Ripper
mail we've got a King Solomon male I got
the BC Lemon Skunk mail there's a
chocolate male all just right under
their own light the boys get their own
little section because they're just as
important to me so don't overlook the
importance of taking care of your male
plant of uh pruning it lollipopping it
topping it taking a couple of backup
clones every now and then just in case
when I'm in the room cutting clones even
if I don't need a clone of the boys I'm
going to take a clone off the bottom
Branch as I clean up just because if
some [ __ ] goes wrong I want to have one
in the cloner one in a small pot and
then one under the lights because those
are the those are the pollinators bro
I've it took longer I spent more time
selecting the male plants than I did any
of the female plants because I need
solid male plants in my lineup I've
talked a lot about that but
um give them their space give them the
room the area the care that the male
plants that they deserve just like the
females they are all equal in that room
um trying to hone my skills and with uh
stability and best practices thank you
so much for your awesome content bro
thank you for the great question I hope
I answered your your question if you
give them proper care proper light they
will not throw any pollen until they go
into pollen or there of course is the
option to stress induce some pollen from
those male plants all right dude thank
you for the great question again do send
me your email address because I do owe
you a free pack of seeds because I read
your question here on the podcast all
right now it is time to tell you how to
win a free pack of seeds on today's
podcast we're gonna do this all over
again if you want to win a free pack of
seeds all you've got to do is send me a
grow question on the grow help habit I
read genetics.com go to iregenetics.com
there's a row of tabs it says like
contact seeds merch podcast Discord
patreon there's one that says grow help
or questions or you'll find it I'm not
looking at the page I don't remember
what the heck it says right now you'll
find it if you want to send the message
go click on there we ask you a few
questions like what kind of question do
you have what strain are you growing
where what kind of Lights uh what stage
what week what medium what PH what PPM
what uh just a few questions that way
when it comes time to answer the
question I've got all the info that I
need it makes it easier for me so go
there then at the bottom it says what is
your basic question please describe your
problem and then describe your problem
tell me what's going on if I read your
question here on the show of course you
will win a free pack of irie genetic
seeds in that giveaway again is
sponsored by our friends at seeds here
now.com shout out to all my friends at
seedshairnow.com not only for supporting
ire genetics but for supporting all of
the Breeders and all of the Growers
they're uh they're great for the
community unity and they're doing a
great freaking service all right you
guys I'm quite rambly I think it is time
to wrap up this episode of The Grow from
your heart podcast thank you for hanging
out I'll be back in another week with
fresh new content if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns you know I would love to hear
from you the email address is grow from
your heart hotmail.com don't be shy send
me all of your feedback make sure you
support the show on patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart anything else you could possibly
need is on my website
iregenetics.com all right I'll be back
in a couple of days with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy pig poop and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]