[Music]
thank you
all right now here we go welcome to the
show podcast world I'm your host Rasta
Jeff this is episode
792 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun episode lined up for us
in this episode I am going to give away
a free pack of seeds I've teamed up with
our friends at seedsherenow.com to give
away a free pack of seeds hang out we'll
talk more about that later in the show I
also want to remind you that irie
genetics will be at the dude grows Cup
this year that's right the dude grows
cup is happening again June 3rd just
outside of Fort Collins Colorado make
sure you check out dgccup.com for all of
the information all right I don't want
to ramble too much at the start of the
show I do have a fun opening subject to
jump into I do want to talk about
expired nutrients that's right I'm
working with a friend online who's been
asking me a bunch of questions we've
been trying to figure out why they're
grow just doesn't look right we've
checked on the water we've checked on
the soil we've checked on the nutrients
we checked on the uh the lights we
checked on the feeding we checked on the
scheduling we checked on the runoff we
checked everything we could think of and
today it was discovered that we were
feeding those plants expired nutrients
I'm not at that grow personally I'm
doing everything through email and
through FaceTime but they opened up a
bottle today and it smelled terrible and
they realized these nutrients are
expired they've been in the growth for a
long time they did not realize that
bottle has met its time so my advice to
you is go in the grow and make sure that
none of your products are expired
because we've been chasing a problem
I've been trying to help a friend in
their grow for quite a while and they
discover that the whole problem was an
expired bottle of nutrients I wasn't
there to smell it I wasn't there to
inspect it I don't know what it looked
or smelled like but maybe we would have
caught that earlier if we would have
just cracked it open given it a smell
because today they said it smelled
terrible and putrid we think and assume
that that has been the culprit of our
plant problem in that facility so once
again my advice to you if you've had a
big bottle sitting on the shelf if
you've got a bunch of bottles that are
sitting around that you don't use very
often maybe give them a shake see if
they're maybe they've gotten runnier
maybe they've gotten chunky see if those
products are still good maybe they smell
real bad maybe they're supposed to smell
bad and now they smell good it's hard to
tell with some grow nutrients but there
should be an expiration date printed on
those bottles my advice to you is go
check and see if your products are out
of date also check your pesticides and
while you're at it check all of your
other gear as well let's do an inventory
let's just do a regroup while we're at
it go check everything while you're
checking the pesticides and the
nutrients doing inventory let's do a
restock order off that [ __ ] add gloves
to the list while you're doing it all
right so the main piece of advice I want
you to take away from there is make sure
the nutrients aren't expired we've been
feeding a grow for the past few weeks
with an expired bottle and the plants
look like [ __ ] they don't look like [ __ ]
they just don't look turbo they should
be turbo by now they look kind of normal
and we wanted turbo so it's that expired
bottle that's making them slow down and
not perky go check on your stuff all
right I do want to segue into the email
portion of today's podcast I've got a
lot of great questions these questions
do come from the grow help tab on the
ire genetics website if you go to my
website iregenetics.com there's a row of
tabs at the top toward the right on the
right top part of the page there's a tab
that says grow help or grow questions if
you click on there it will bring you to
a it's like a little questionnaire it
asks you a bunch of questions about your
grow basically uh where are you growing
what are you growing are you indoors or
Outdoors what are your attempts what's
your humidity all of the things I need
to know to help me diagnose your problem
it really helps out if I've got more
info so fill that out the best you can
at the bottom it says type in your grow
question or tell us about your problem
fill that in the best you can give me
details then it also gives you the
opportunity to attach photos if you've
got good photos that may help send those
right along and if I do read your grow
question here on the podcast I will send
you a free pack of seeds in that free
pack of seeds is sponsored by our
friends at seedshernow.com Big shout out
to seeds herenow.com if you need regular
feminized Autoflower seeds I definitely
recommend seeds here
now.com I am rambling I was trying to
avoid that once again again this message
came from the grow help tab go check the
grow help tab send me your questions
this one says says first of all I love
and appreciate you brother big love and
respect back at you my friend it says in
some of your strain videos which we love
you say an early flower you use kelp to
enhance the Terps can you please
elaborate on how you use the kelp I have
age-old kelp and I have fed it lightly
once in veg and once in flower I'm
currently in week two of flower I've got
Shredder and orange gasm they seem to
love it I just don't want to overdo it
stay sexy my friend this one came from
our friend who wants to be known as
Billy D big shout out to our buddy Billy
D uh that is a really good question oh
and I'm going to mention they referred
to what I call what they call the strain
videos yes if you scroll through my
channel you will see that there are many
strain episodes strain videos I do I of
course am I re genetics premium seeds I
make seeds for high regenetics and I do
put out episodes that highlight those
strains will teach you how to grow them
give you advice about those strains and
set you up for success with the seeds
which we do make but in those episodes I
do mention a lot of kelp products I
don't mention any specific products but
I do mention kelp products quite
frequently I say that it's a good idea
to use kelp I feel like in
um in my opinion in my experience in
strains that are skunky funky earthy
cushy uh those strains that that smell
that Aroma that flavor that funk can be
enhanced and really brought out with the
addition of kelp products I just feel
like it makes it if it's musty and funky
kelp will make it mustier and funkier if
those are even real words as musty or a
real word it'll be more musty in my
experience if you use that kelp Aroma
and flavor are not the only benefits of
using a kelp product I also feel like
the proper use of kelp will increase in
Bud density and it always does help with
root development that think of that
natural sea life kelp grows kelp is one
of the largest growing organic bodies on
Earth if I read that correctly I didn't
recite that the way that I read it but
kelp grows large you guys and imagine
feeding that BioLife to your ganja
plants they're gonna grow live they're
going to grow large they're going to
love it so kelp is always good at
enhances root growth it enhances flavor
Aroma and I also think it helps with Bud
density so that is why I talk about kelp
in a lot of those episodes anything
that's skunky funky gassy cushy in that
realm give it more kelp the fruity
things will like the kelp as well and it
will make the flavor stronger but I
really think it enhances that funkiness
of a naturally funky smelling plant so
let's talk a little bit about it
elaborate on how I use kelp there are
several ways to make kelp available to
your plants there are liquid kelp
products there are dried kelp products
there's a kelp meal product it's all
about your approach to Growing it kind
of depends on how you want to do it
you've got age-old kelp which is a
beautiful product age-old is a really
it's an old brand they've been around
for a long time they make a quality
product and they've got a kelp specific
product so you're right in the right
wheelhouse there that is a liquid kelp
product another liquid kelp product I
would recommend that I really enjoy is
liquid Karma however that brand was
bought by somebody the Botanicare brand
was bought by somebody which we try not
to buy their products so no matter how
great that product is I'm still torn
sometimes when I do choose to buy it
that's called liquid Karma there's a
brand out there called raw that makes a
powdered kelp product raw nutrients
they're powdered it's raw is the name of
the brand they make a great powdered
kelp product and the folks that make Fox
Farms product make a kelp product that
is called kelp me kelp you all of those
products will be easy to use they're all
cost effective they're all quite
affordable the liquid Karma and some of
your liquid kelp products can actually
be used as a foliar feed I would imagine
you could use the raw powdered kelp as a
foliar if you shake it up and dissolve
it really well before you apply it don't
quote me on that because I have not used
that product but most Health Products
you can fold your feet as long as they
don't gum up your system as long as they
aren't too too thick when you apply it
so that it doesn't clog up your plants
so how to use it how to use the kelp it
says so far that you have used the kelp
once and veg and uh one time week two
and flower so that's a good start
depending on the products you choose to
use and how you were growing uh that
will kind of dictate how you use the
kelp let's talk about a couple of ways
that I would recommend using it I like
to grow in Cocoa so in Cocoa I would
probably add a kelp product once a week
throughout most of the entire cycle of
that plant once it goes into its big veg
pot then I'm going to start adding some
sort of a kelp product weekly all the
way up to probably about week six or
maybe even week seven of flower
depending on how long that plant is
going to go so from week early in veg
all the way through veg all the way
through flour up until right about
almost pre-flush time basically I am
feeding a kelp product now the trick to
that is I slowly increase that product I
can't tell you how many milliliters or
how many grams or how much to use
because I'm not sure which product
you're going to use but my advice is
start low and then just work your way up
a little bit don't go drastic don't go
crazy but do increase a little bit
toward by the time you get done with the
flowering stage that you were probably
at the full recommended dose which is
written on that bottle but most of the
time I'll recommend feeding 50 percent
of the recommended recommended dosage of
a product because the plants usually
don't need what they recommend the
nutrient company wants you to buy more
so they tell you to feed a little bit
extra start off with about 50 work your
way up by the time you're done with the
kelp product that's when I think you
should probably be at that 100 Mark so
about week six and just slowly work your
way up to there it's not going to be
huge huge steps just gradual increases
over every couple of weeks so with the
liquid product in Cocoa I would do Cocoa
uh once a week and I would slowly Step
Up start low and then work your way up
to the recommended dosage by the end
um then what else how else are we going
to grow we're going to grow in a
soilless mix with a soilless mix I would
probably do it once again once per week
but I may go a little bit heavier with
the dosage this time I may not go as
light as I do in Coco now what's left I
wrote down hydro hydro is our last
option to work with I would do Hydro
very similarly to the other two but in a
hydro Reservoir you can only feed
basically we're feeding once a week you
mix it up and let it run for the week
and in a hydro res so I would do it
basically every week from the time the
plants get big and established and get
sturdy and Healthy Start adding that
kelp product and just like I said before
start low and then work your way up and
those Hydro buckets and in Cocoa you're
definitely going to notice the kelp
products more quickly than you are in
the soilless mix now if you want to add
this to some sort of a living soil or
one of those no-till beds uh disclaimer
this is not my area of expertise when it
comes to no-till Organics things like
that that is not my area of expertise
but that is when you're going to want to
stir in that kelp product early in stir
that in before you I mix it into the
soil before you even start putting the
plants in then you might want to top
dress or top feed it later on with the
kelp product you could put the kelp in
with water feed it that way or you can
top dress it let it break down into the
soil that way once again I am not the
Organics expert but those are two three
very viable options to get plants the
kelp product if you are using organic so
quick recap up there Hydro basically
Hydro soilless mix cocoa almost
everything I would feed it once per week
and I would start low and I would
gradually taper up until you're going
about a hundred percent maybe a little
bit more if you really want to push it
120 of what the recommended dosage is at
the end start low and work your way up
you guys that's what I'm saying don't go
burning the plants and pay attention
just because I'm saying that you can get
to 100 maybe 120 doesn't mean that your
plant is going to take that all of these
plants are a little bit different so pay
really close attention to your plant are
the leaves curling is the growth stunted
is something going weird that could be a
sign so back off if you see too much
reaction from that all right I think I
answered this question elaborate on how
I use the kelp feed it just like any
other nutrient and feed it about once a
week and then start early and work your
way on up until you're going kind of
hard with the kelp I think the gassier
and funkier uh
cushier sort of varietals the chem dogs
and things they really love this sort of
treatment they really love the can of
the kelp products also the cushes and
chems if you're going to do some kelp
add some cow mag to that mix as well and
they will really love each other
together all right my friend Billy D
thank you for the great message I do
appreciate that since I read your
question here on the podcast that means
that you win a free pack of seeds that's
right you win a free pack of irie
genetic seeds again that free seed
giveaway is sponsored by my friends at
seedshairnow.com shout out to
seedshernow.com for giving you a free
pack of seeds all right let's jump into
one more message here this one came also
from The Grow help tab from does it say
what they want their name to be does not
have their name on it it goes like this
it says yo Rasta Jeff you inspired me to
start breeding and I'm not gonna lie to
you I'm going to start my line with your
line and I chose Saka souffle to start
my breeding project that is a huge
compliment many breeders out there get
pissy and get territorial when people
talk about breeding with their products
but guess what not me I agree I promote
it I endorse it I condone it I really
encourage people to breed with my
products first of all if you want to
breed with my products that that's a
compliment to me why would I be mad that
you want to use my Creations to start
your new Creations that's a huge
compliment to me thank you also why
would I be mad at a person for trying to
breed their own cannabis and make
themselves uh self-sustainable and enjoy
cannabis a little bit more enjoy the
plant the craft the art develop some
skills why would I be mad at anybody
about that and then the bottom line is
here you bought those seeds bro those
are yours you paid money for them or you
traded for them hopefully you did it
honestly uh if you got those seeds
honestly then you can grow them breed
them trade them sell them you could do
whatever you want with them I can't say
anything about it I've got the money
that I needed when you bought them and
after that bro it's all yours have a
good time that's like you telling me
that I can't skate my skateboard hard or
drive my car fast I paid for it I'm
Gonna Do My Thing bro you do that thing
with your seeds but I want to keep going
I I appreciate that and encourage it
breed with my stuff it goes on I chose
Saka souffle uh biscotti is my favorite
strain you're gonna find a great
biscotti flavored meal in there it says
I have a couple of questions for you
when you make seeds how long do you veg
your plants if you were in my position
and chose Saka souffle to start your
breeding project how long would you veg
it since you know that particular
cultivar very well there's a couple of
things that get my attention in here
first of all I would recommend if you're
going to breed with this plant that you
grow out several phenotypes of multiple
times and get a relationship with it
you're going to do a Fino hunt I'm
assuming you've got a 10 which probably
came with 12 seeds in the pack so you've
got 10 or 12 seeds maybe uh maybe you
share that with a friend but I'm gonna
say grow as many seeds as you can
identify the females identify the males
separate them
and then flour them out and find what is
the best for you you're going to find a
male
that looks like he's the St the dude the
stud the guy
keep him aside now we've got to run the
females a couple of times we want to see
unless you want to pollinate multiple
females if you just want to do one and
one you really have to do some careful
selection and you can't do that on just
one run I'd recommend running it two
maybe three times unless you plan on
pollinating everything so I would run it
the first time find the boys find the
girls kind of this is just an audition
run we're just kind of getting to know
them in the second run we're really
gonna isolate two or three girls that we
really like and see which one is the
best and then we'll breed to that let's
grow it a little bit find out if there's
any problems with this plant I doubt
there will be but I could have problems
it could be I bread this plant and I'm
still gonna say it it could be intersex
it could be a mutant it could be a
[ __ ] freak Show of a plant that
doesn't do what you want done so let's
not get too uh too attached to breeding
with this plant right away because it
may not fit the criteria which you're
hoping for just because your favorite
plant is biscotti and there's biscotti
in here doesn't mean that this is going
to be a breeding winner and I would like
to say it is because I made it but still
it may not be that's the chances of
reality that's chances of genetics
that's like it's like dating maybe we're
not gonna get along maybe you're the
plant and that and you aren't gonna get
along well that's the bottom line so run
them a couple times let's see if it's
really what you want before you do the
breeding now let's talk on touch on the
actual breeding question how big would I
veg the plants this is a really good
question
uh maybe I shouldn't tell you all this
information but come on in it's time to
uh reveal some some breeding secrets you
don't really need a lot of space or
really big plants to create a lot of
seeds honestly if you're going to breed
with the biscotti and you just want to
make seeds for yourself you can make a
hundred seeds from a plant grown in a
beer cup I am not joking I'm not
exaggerating at all a beer cup is this
tall you can veg the plant to be this
tall ish I don't know if you're watching
on the video but that's half maybe three
quarters the size of the beer cups This
Tall Veg it's about half three quarters
the size of the beer cup and then flip
it and then pollinate if you pollinate
two or three of those plants that are
the same size all of the same clone
you're going to make a couple hundred
seeds probably 100 to 200 seeds really
easily if the plant's real little you'll
still pull 30 to 50 seeds off of it you
don't need a lot of biomass to pollinate
the plants they can be really little if
you just want to make some for yourself
my advice is to veg them in cups get
them about what is that GI Joe is three
and three quarters of an inch all
vegetable GI Joe tall and then flour
them the male and the female at the same
time put them in there let them go
that's going to be a good first practice
breeding run you'll see what the flowers
what the male plant does all the way
through the flowering cycle you'll see
what the females do you'll see what
pollination looks like you'll see what
ripe and mature seeds look like you'll
see how long it takes and you'll have a
good batch of seeds to play with if you
really want to get Critical with it you
can time the male and female differently
I don't know when the male is going to
dump pollen I don't know when the female
will be ready for pollen exactly because
I haven't ran these plants yet but the
way nature works if you put them side by
side and put them into flour they will
the pollination will work you may make
more seeds if you do one earlier one
later but let's worry about that on your
second and third breeding runs let's
just put the appropriate boy and
appropriate girl in there and put them
in at the same time and you'll make
plenty of seeds for yourself so if you
want to make just enough seeds for
yourself to play with beer cups one
gallon pots small plants you just need
one top Cola the size of human and I
know I'm using [ __ ] toys from the 90s
and 80s as size reference today but uh
vegetal it's GI Joe and a he-man size
plant will give you 30 to 50 seeds if
you do it properly sometimes you'll get
90 to 100 seeds out of a little tiny
plant it just depends on how much
biomass is on that plant to receive how
many pistols are there to receive pollen
to create seeds out of those plants if
you want to make more seeds grow bigger
plants but honestly the beer cup method
is really simple to do and it does not
take a lot of space just make sure that
those seeds get time to finish that's
going to be one of the most important
things select your female or females
select your mail get a clone have
backups have backup plants of these in
case something goes wrong and so that we
can replicate this procedure in the
future you got your backups get clones
put the Clones into the beer cups get
those beer cups growing about the size
of GI Joe three and three quarters of an
inch tall put the male and female or
females into your flowering chamber I'm
not even saying flowering room at this
time because these plants are so little
they get a chamber they don't need a
whole room to themselves they just need
you can do this in a a very small a two
by two by four foot space you could
definitely bang out plenty of seeds with
the right light with the right cooling
with the right ventilation with paying
the right attention and timing things so
put them in that room let them pollinate
they'll get it on and then six seven
eight or nine weeks from there you will
have a small batch of seeds then here's
the fun part you get to grow all of
those seeds don't share them don't give
them away until you've ran a few and
verified that they're not problematic
until you're confident in those seeds so
let me check on the message and make
sure that I actually answered some of
your question here uh when you make
seeds how long do you let your plants
veg if I was in your position so yeah I
would do it in beer cups honestly you're
just trying to make a few seeds we don't
know if these seeds are going to be
amazing we don't know if they're going
to be intersex we don't know if they're
going to be Duds we don't know what
you're we're creating so let's not make
too many of them it's easy to throw away
90 seeds it really hurts your feelings
to throw away 9 000 seats trust me I've
had to do it before it's the only thing
you can do put them in the compost bin
because if I put those seeds out to you
guys you're going to be angry at me
you're not going to be happy it's going
to tarnish the reputation the level of
quality that you expect from me so make
little plants make a few and maybe to
you 100 is a bunch of seeds make a few
seeds to play with grow them then we can
always go back and make more and if you
did it right you probably found the
keeper that you want and that 30 to 50
seeds anyway there will be something hot
in there if you've done this properly
I'm really curious if you're going to
use my Saka souffle as a male plant
which females are you going to pollinate
are there is there more advice on that
yeah you're gonna use the Saka souffle
um what are you going to pollinate what
uh what is the other plant in the mix
here
no no advice on that one but um I'm
excited I and once again I do encourage
everybody out there to breed with my
seeds if you want to be a seed breeder a
seed maker my seeds are a great way to
start that now once you do make those
little uh little cups worth of seeds if
you really like something and you want
to make more obviously the next step is
to grow those plants bigger next time
and make bigger plants in a three gallon
pot you can make a lot of plants if you
let that plant veg up to 12 or 18 inches
tall time that pollination right you'll
have enough seeds to last you the rest
of your life just from one plant if you
just want to run those seeds by yourself
all right that question did come from a
person who did not indicate if they
didn't or did not want their name to be
said but if you're watching this podcast
episode guess what my friend you have
won a free pack of high regenetic seeds
and of course that seed giveaway is
sponsored by our friends at seeds here
now.com all you've got to do is send me
your email address say hey bro you read
my question on the podcast please send
me my free seeds and give me your
address and by the time this episode
comes out everybody who is one free
seeds will have their free seeds shipped
if they have sent me their address if
you've sent me your address the free
seeds are on their way if I've read your
question on the show and told you that
you won free seeds please reach out send
me an email tell me I won free seeds
send me your shipping address I'm going
to verify you guys I'm going to go back
and make sure I keep all the emails
right here they stay in a pile so I can
go back and look and see but if I read
your message on the show please do
remind me that I owe you a free pack of
high re genetic seeds and once again
shout out to seeds here now.com now if
you did not win seeds on today's episode
do not feel uh left out do not feel
forgotten because it is very easy to win
free seeds just like on today's episode
all you have to do is go to the grow
help Tab and send me a good grow
question go to iregenetics.com or
iridirect.com there's a grow help tab on
both of those pages click on that grow
help tab send me your grow question if I
read that grow question here on the
podcast I will send you a free pack of
irie genetic seeds
so keep those good questions coming if I
haven't read your question don't be uh
don't feel left out don't feel uh judged
don't feel like I'm hating on you I've
got this many questions that's a lot of
paper right there I got that many
questions waiting coming up on the show
I'm gonna work through most of them I'm
gonna do my best to get to all of them
it just takes time you guys so keep
sending those grow questions to the grow
help tab on iregenetics.com I think that
is all I've got for you for this episode
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns all you have to do
is send an email to grow from your heart
at hotmail.com let me know what's on
your mind maybe I'll read your questions
Corrections comments or concerns right
here on the podcast also make sure you
support the show on patreon patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart all
of the information you need will be
right there on the screen once again
make sure you check out the website
irygenetics.com everything you need is
on iregenetics.com there's a list a link
to the patreon a link to the Discord
there's a link to I redirect so you can
get those seeds make sure you sign up
for the newsletter so you can know when
the seeds go on sale
um that's all I think you need to worry
about for now that is a lot of info to
feed you all at one time check out the
website that's what I'm asking for
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast I'll be back next week with
fresh new content I want to give a giant
shout out to my friend Maverick and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you