[Music]
what's up
all right here we go welcome to the show
podcast world I'm your host Rasta Jeff
this is episode
793 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to give away a
free pack of seeds I've teamed up with
our friends at seedshairnow.com to give
away a free pack of irie genetic seeds
hang out we'll talk more about that
later in this episode I do want to
remind you that ire genetics will be at
the dude Groves Cup this year that's
right we are participating in the dude
Groves cup June 3rd in Fort Collins
Colorado make sure you check out
dudegroves.com or dgcup.com for all of
the information also make sure you check
out I redirect for a new restock and
reduced pricing I think that is all of
the advertising and business to cover
here at the start of the show let's jump
into the email portion of today's
podcast this question came from the grow
help tab if you go to my website
irygenetics.com there's a tab on the top
right that says questions if you click
on that tab we will ask you a few
questions about your bro what strain are
you growing where are you growing it is
it indoors Outdoors how are your temps
and humidity would you feed the plants
then we give you plenty of opportunity
to explain the problem in your garden I
do invite you to send those questions to
the grow help tab this question came
from our friend Brad in Canada big shout
out to my friend Brad in Canada for the
great question it goes a lot like this
it says hello Ross to Jeff if you read
this on the podcast you can call me Brad
from Canada what's up dude nice to meet
you it says I love the podcast I've
listened to every episode that's
available on Spotify and it has quickly
become my favorite growing podcast I do
appreciate that you are listening on
Spotify but I do highly recommend that
you check out the YouTube videos every
single episode is available on YouTube
well let me say that over because not
every single episode is on YouTube
YouTube has taken some down but there
are a lot more episodes available on
YouTube than there are Spotify there's
probably 785 episodes on YouTube uh
Spotify only gives us the most 100
recent I believe so there's a lot more
content on YouTube also come check out
the 4K video and see my smiling face let
me keep going I do appreciate that
you're listening on Spotify by the way
let me say that but I do invite you to
check out the YouTube channel let me
keep going it said I'm becoming my
favorite growing podcast your deep Dives
and out of the box creative thinking
such as 18 6 for the last 10 days of
flowering uh so thank you thank you for
noticing that I do appreciate that it
says or 18 6 for bigger stronger faster
finishing seeds is truly One of a Kind
information you can only learn here I
appreciate you dude those are great
compliments and I get a lot of
controversy a lot of uh feedback a lot
of uh a lot of flack I guess for
teaching people to run their plants on
18-6 at the end of flower a lot of
people say I'm crazy a lot of people
have sent negative feedback but guess
what the only people that tell me I'm a
lunatic the only people that tell me
it's a bad idea are people who haven't
tried it people that try to run their
plants 18 6 for the last 10 to 14 days
of the flowering phase they always come
back and they say dude my plants were
better they were beefier they were
chunkier there was more to it and they
finished a little bit bit sooner people
to make seeds under the 18-6 schedule at
the end they always tell me they have
great success with the seed so thank you
for noticing the 18 6 idea thank you for
trying that I'm glad that worked out for
you it goes on it says anyhow on today's
podcast you mentioned watching out for
expired fertilizers and how they can
negatively affect your grow I was hoping
you could go over how to properly
dispose of your gross waste products
such as bottles of fertilizer runoff
pesticides Etc thanks again for all you
do Brad from Canada this is a very great
question this is a very important
question this is something that I feel
is very overlooked in the commercial and
private production of cannabis I am
trained by the Colorado Department of
Agriculture to understand pesticide
handling pesticide application I
understand mixing nutrients safely I
understand applying nutrients safely
however in the state of Colorado for the
marijuana enforcement Division and the
Colorado Department of Agriculture and
public health and environment which are
two different entities I kind of
combined them but there is technically
no protocol for disposing of Wastewater
excess nutrients excess pesticides
there's no true protocol for that in a
commercial cultivation facility my main
concern is the pesticides I really
really try when we are creating a batch
of pesticides to apply I try not to make
too much I'd rather have almost too
little or just barely enough to coat the
room to get the job done so I don't have
to figure out what to do with the
leftover pesticides honestly we just
spray just keep spraying until you run
out because that's that's your best
option apply it to the plants apply it
to the walls if you need to hit the
floor I try not to waste it by pouring
it into the water supply or into the
ground so pesticides my main mission is
to just mix up just enough and coat the
rooms after several applications I've
been applying in several locations for
so long that basically we know exactly
how much to mix up per room for that
room I need seven gallons for that room
I'm just pointing at arbitrary rooms
that exist in my head I know that that
one room takes about seven gallons that
other room only needs about three and a
half gallons so most of my method there
is strategy and not mixing up too much
to where I have any waste or leftovers
which uh sometimes I nail it honestly
sometimes we don't and then we do have
to get creative with the disposal of
those nutrients the department of AG has
taught us that uh dilution is the
solution to pollution so if you've got
to pour it somewhere mix it heavily with
regular water and dispose of it that
does not sound like the greatest idea
but that's what I was instructed by the
department of AG was to pour it down the
floor drain and dilute it with regular
water now let's talk more about the
nutrients waste nutrients in a
commercial grow it would not be uncommon
for me to mix up a 500 gallon reservoir
of nutrients and then feed most of that
to the plants then there is runoff in
most most cases you hear me preach about
watering to run off fortunately
unfortunately once again there is not a
protocol with the Colorado Department of
Agriculture the Department of Health
OSHA nobody's given us a true uh
standard operating procedure of how to
dispose of the leftover nutrients
luckily I was going to say say
fortunately so fortunately at one of the
facilities where I spent most of my time
the facility was out in what would be
considered a big field in the middle of
a desert area so there's just a bunch of
brush out there a bunch of Sagebrush a
bunch of cactus bunch of Yucca a bunch
of dirt and that's what was behind our
facility so most of the time if we had
excess water we would pour that water
into the dirt and water those plants
which was amazing because all of the
vegetation behind our facility was Lush
and gigantic year round everywhere else
it would turn brown it would get Dusty
and crunchy our vegetation behind our
facility around our facility was
beautiful it was huge also we got some
giant rabbits and some giant
rattlesnakes and a bunch of giant life
because I think we were feeding the
plants so well there was a lot of food
food was abundant the animals were
abundant which made the rattlesnakes
abundant which made the birds abundant
there was a lot of [ __ ] happening in our
area and I think a lot of it was because
of the nutrients which we were dumping
out there in that field and feeding all
of those weeds all those plants we're
giving them high quality grow nutrients
and boosting the [ __ ] out of them so
that was how we were disposing of the
excess water the nutrients the nutrients
unfortunately we were told that that
should go down the floor drain I did not
agree with that but I did not know what
else to do so unfortunately there was
not a strong protocol by any of the
governing bodies that kind of oversee
the production of cannabis so we were
basically told that the standard
operating procedure and the thing to do
would be to pour it down the floor drain
or to continue putting it in the
backyard like I was doing it never felt
good putting a pesticide in a floor
drain but that's what we were instructed
to do and sometimes I did not have any
other options so just pour it down the
floor drain and pour a bunch of gallons
of water on top of it that way we kind
of dilute that a little bit I wish there
was a better answer to this honestly
because it doesn't feel good telling you
that the protocol was to portion in the
backyard and pour it down a drain but in
Colorado there is no rule we were never
fined we were never told to do any
differently we were never given any
guidance and when I said that's what we
were doing the department of AG
basically turned their head and said I
guess that's what you got to do so I
agree with you that's not the best way
to do it but that's the option that I
was given so that's basically how we got
rid of the runoff fertilizers and the
pesticides you did ask about a couple of
other products bottles of fertilizer we
would basically use the fertilizer in a
commercial grow we would use that to the
end there would never be anything left
nothing would expire in a commercial
grow that stuff comes and goes very
quickly if you're disposing of a
pesticide or a nutrient bottle the
proper protocol is to poke a bunch of
holes in that bottle near the bottom
around the sides so that nobody can
reuse that container and get themselves
sick a pesticide bottle a nutrient
bottle it's got to be punctured several
times
and then those punctured bottles would
go into a dumpster that had to be locked
also into that dumpster would go all of
our root balls a lot of our organic
waste a lot of the sticks the stems a
lot of the trim that we didn't use to
send out to get extracted any waste
would go into a big dumpster uh old pots
old soil just about all of the waste
would get put into one dumpster that was
required to be locked and only uh the
facility manager which was myself most
of the time and the person that picked
up the trash had a key to that dumpster
you would not believe how many times
people cut the lock off of our dumpster
tried to break into our dumpster
destroyed our dumpster to get what they
thought was product but it was actually
nothing but sticks and dirt and waste
when you throw something away if there
is plant material in your waist and you
throw that away in Colorado it's got to
be destroyed it's either got to be mixed
with bleach or they like it if you mix
it with kitty litter a lot of the times
what I would do is I when we harvested I
would save a couple of pots behind three
gallon pots filled with cocoa so that
way when it came time to blend in the
waste from all the plants I could dump
some of that cocoa on top of it put some
plants in there dump cocoa on top of it
put plants in there basically they
wanted you to make a lasagna of plant
waste and then something to destroy the
plant waste and then more waste so that
when the people do come in and break
into the trash cans if they do get
something they don't really get a
product they can make any profit or any
consumption off of they were trying they
were trying but some of the med rules
were completely ridiculous since I'm
thinking about it I've got footage I
probably don't have the footage on my
phone anymore I work for a facility it
was kind of tucked back off of the Main
Street
um any traffic that went by there was
just weirdo traffic looking for problems
a lot of people would come by on bikes
and shine flashlights in our grow
facility we had to build a 12-foot fence
around the facility and keep the trash
can inside the 12-foot fence and still
lock the trash cans because people are
crazy anyway one night a homeless person
climbed over I assumed they were
homeless I'd seen them around there I'd
never they they looked very maybe I'm
prejudging but this person that did not
look like they'd had a shower on a while
that part was quite obvious they climbed
our fence they tried to get into the
trash can they couldn't get into it so
they shimmied up one of the rain gutters
and got to the roof of the building
jumped off the roof WWF style and
shoulder bombed their way through the
top of our dumpster the metal lid of the
dumpster caved in a bunch of dust came
flying up you saw them fall through it
they looked disheveled for a couple of
seconds they got their [ __ ] together
they looked like they just won the
freaking Lottery but then when they
threw those bags over the fence they
left them there because they realized it
wasn't nothing but sticks and [ __ ]
kitty litter so this person climbed up
our rain gutter got all the way to the
roof of the building and WWE or WWF
style jumped off the [ __ ] building
through our dumpster to attempt to steal
our trash that's how ridiculous it was
so everything that went into that
dumpster had to be destroyed punctured
uh mixed with kitty litter ground to a
pulp and then the dumpster had to be
locked it was behind two gates in some
facilities the trash was a very uh it
was a huge Target I've never had my
trash targeted like that before so let
me recap and make sure I've answered all
of the aspects of this question dispose
of the grow waste products uh I
considered grow waste products to be
plants pots stuff like that that goes
into the locked dumpster uh bottles of
fertilizer we use all of the liquid
inside of those bottles
everything gets used in a commercial
facility when you're mixing up 500
gallons of nutrients if you've just got
a little bit extra just pour it in it'll
be fine it won't make a difference for
one feeding if it's a little bit guys
don't go get crazy but so the bottles
get punctured run off again we did not
have any guidance or expertise on what
to do with the runoff I was pouring it
in the field and feeding the vegetation
the pesticides we do our best our
absolute best to mix up enough for this
application so that none is wasted and
then if you need to over spray go spray
some foliage outside something like that
if you really have to so I think that
wraps up that question I do want to send
another big thank you shout out to our
friend Brad from Canada congratulations
to Brad from Canada my dude you have won
yourself a free pack of irie genetic
seeds this free seed giveaway is
sponsored by our friends at
seedsherenow.com make sure you check out
seedshairnow.com for regular feminized
Autoflower and photo period seeds they
carry all of your favorite breeders of
course they do have irie genetics in
stock but congratulations Brad from
Canada you have won a free pack of Irene
genetics seeds most of the time I do
limit the seed giveaways to the States
but I liked your question quite a bit so
I will eat the cost and ship that right
up there to Canada for you uh Brad
please do send me your shipping address
so I can get you a free pack of seeds
I've said before that if I read your
question here on the podcast you will
win a free pack of seeds all right let's
keep moving I've got another great
question in front of me this one came
from our friend Daniel big shout out to
Daniel it says what kind of grow
question do you have and Daniel said how
viable is a breeding project that is
solely based on using pollen from
reversed females that's a really good
question it says I want to get into
breeding but my current circumstances
greatly favor growing fam autoflowers
over photos I'm assuming I'm able to
readily reverse them are there
significant downsides compared to using
males this is a really good question
some of the info that I'm going to give
you this next piece of info comes from
my friend Mr Soul big shout out to Mr
Soul at Brothers Grim seed company go
support him really good dude uh very
very smart guy we I agree with 99 of
what he says when it comes to talking
about cannabis and almost anything else
which is very rare for me to agree with
somebody that much 99 is huge agreement
so big fist bump to my buddy Mr Soul Mr
Soul put it this way one time
the only difference between regular and
feminized seeds the main difference the
difference is the pollen the female
pollen is what is creating female seeds
on your plant basically imagine this is
not how it works but you can imagine it
this way imagine if I were able to
create a filter and put a filter in the
air and that filter only removed male
pollen from the air it knew it was like
female pollen you can go ahead and party
you could get through uh it's ladies
night but male pollen no way bro you're
staying outside so imagine I've got this
filter and then I make my plant produce
pollen all we are doing is eliminating
the male pollen from the equation and
that female pollen is hitting the plants
and making 100 female seeds my friend Mr
Soul put it that way he gave me the
analogy of using the filter that is very
much what it's like when breeding with a
reversed female the only difference that
you're going okay there may be another
difference I'll get into but the only
difference that you're going to notice
is that it's going to be all female
seeds because there is no male pollen in
the mix that's where we are reversing
the female plant because we're making
female pollen that's where the magic
happens the female pollen is the key to
all that feminization so it's all female
pollen I said there's one more thing you
may notice the thing you're going to
notice is more uniform phenotypes and
less transgressive segregation a lot of
times when we work with regular seeds
when we make further filial Generations
we will see expressions of the
grandparents and the the grandma and the
grandpa and the great grandma and the
great grandpa on both sides so you've
got the options of more things popping
up in your mix if you're using the
regular seeds using Femme seeds I think
we kind of cut some of that out we get
less phenotypical phenotypical
expression less variation and more
uniformity in my experience with the
plants that I have selected if you
select different plants and go a
different route and you're breeding that
could vary just because of the plants
that were chosen I feel like over time
I've developed a very Discerning Eye a
very keen eye for selecting breeding
Pairs and this far in my breeding game I
really do see very nice phenotypes
coming from the Femmes and less
variation than what I see coming from
the regular seeds I make plenty of both
I make a lot of feminized seeds and I
make a lot of regular seeds I grow a lot
of them out my test team grows a lot of
them out my testing is 100 transparent
we do it on Discord everybody can see it
then a lot of people grow out the seeds
that make it to Market I'm seeing less
variation in the feminized seeds than I
am in the regular seeds so that's
possibly an advantage I like the
variation that is coming from the
regular seeds that's why I like doing
rag seeds I like seeing how the male
expresses how the female expresses what
the difference is if I take this male
and pollinate four different females how
does that Express differently it will be
clear what that reversed plant is
contributing to your breeding project if
you pollinate multiple females with that
plant and see what the differences are
you'll be able to see oh when I
pollinated the strawberry plant with
this blueberry plant we got strawberry
blueberry but when I pollinated the
orange plant with the blueberry the
orange really dominated but if I
pollinated Durbin poison with the
blueberry the Durbin poison really
dominated you'll get to see what traits
and what dominates and what mix by
breeding to other plants but you won't
see as much variation as you would if
you were running the regular seeds in my
experience in that in that test right
there I do see more variation I see more
grandparents represented with the
regular seeds so let me recap the
question make sure I'm giving you a
solid answer
um how viable is breeding that solely
uses pollen from reversed females uh
lemon Jeffrey is one of my most popular
best-selling strains orangegasm is
definitely orange Chasm is my number one
selling sea lion that I've ever made
those two crosses are 100 percent
feminized and they are very viable very
potent very reliable seeds lemon Jeffrey
and orangegasm are probably those are my
two most popular strains I've ever made
and they're Femmes made from reversed
female pollen so you can start a seed
company that will be very successful
with Femme seeds if you do it properly
if you take the proper time for
selection if you make sure
test test test test I can't say that
enough test a lot of testing test every
female that you plan on putting in your
breeding project for all of the problems
that a female plant could represent
let's find out first of all does it
handle heat stress does it handle cold
stress does it handle over feed does it
handle under feed does it handle uh too
much heat does it handle too much cold
does it handle high humidity low
humidity does it handle drought does it
handle over water I may have repeated a
couple of those things but does it
handle all of that [ __ ] do these plants
that you intend to breed with do they
show any type of intersex traits when
you beat them up can they handle light
interruptions can they handle Darkness
interruptions can they handle problems
are they bug resistant are they pathogen
resistant are they friendly to the
grower that is something that I really
like to think about when I'm making
seeds that will go to other people are
these seeds going to be a complete pain
in the ass or will everyday consumers be
able to complete the grow with this
product think about those traits when
you are making seeds
but the short answer is that your idea
for a breeding project of feminized only
seeds could and will be very successful
if the selection is done properly if you
don't select plants that have been
tested try it and true that's when you
can run into problems if you put one
plant into this breeding program that is
intersex all of The Offspring from that
plant do hold the potential to be
intersex plants so let's test the plants
let's remove any intersex plants from
the gene pool before we do any breeding
intersex is the number one complaint
from a consumer when it comes to buying
seeds if those plants show nanners in
week three people are going to be pissed
if it shows nanners in week six there
are going to be extra pissed so let's
not release anything or breed to
anything that has the opportunity or
shows the potential to display intersex
characteristics but overall if you do
the selection properly if you pay
attention if you stress test all of your
plants before you breed pick your plants
now pick all of the plants you want to
breed get a mother plant of all those
plants have two or three clones of each
of those plants let's put all the
potential breeders in a room let's put
the light schedule on 12 12 and leave it
like that for a few days but then in a
couple of days I'm gonna [ __ ] it all up
and put it back on 18-6 then a few days
later from that I'm going to over water
then a couple of days after that we'll
put it back on 12 12 and wait two weeks
and see what happens if any of those
plants freak out guess what I'm not
going to breed with them the plants that
continue through and flower and finish
properly those are my breeding
candidates so run some testing verify
that you've got good quality breeding
candidates and then once you've verified
that that's when you do your pollen
Chuck and now that is only the first
step once you've done the pollen Chuck
and the next step is to grow out the
seeds that you have created grow
populations as large of a population as
you can from each batch and take a lot
of notes be very observant take
ridiculous notes if your plant does
something one weird thing write it down
if it does some very small thing write
it down if it does something drastic
definitely write it down but grow out as
many of those as you can see if this the
seeds you have produced like we started
with are they intersex did you meet your
goal did you have a breeding goal are
the plants that you have created better
than both of the parent plants if
they're not quality seeds I don't
recommend sharing them selling them or
giving them out maybe use them for your
own or maybe turn them into some sort of
oil or put them into the compost bin you
know if you hit your goal or not you
know if they're quality you know if this
is something that you would be proud to
share with the community or if it's
something you'd rather flush and act
like never happened don't be ashamed
it's all about selection if you did not
select the proper strains select again
get it going again now you did mention
that you want to use Auto flowers so
you're going to have to do this with
autoflowers you're going to have to find
an Autoflower plant that looks like a
good breeding candidate you're gonna
have to reverse that then put that on
several more females I honestly do not
have experience breeding with auto
flowers
the selection process there would baffle
me how do I know that that is a breeding
male if I haven't floured it out and
finished it and see what it looks like
so and you can't cut a clone and repeat
the process you're gonna have to pick
one that looks real good
reverse it uh right before a flower
right before it starts to flower once
again I don't mess with autoflowers so I
recommend spraying the plant for the
first reversal about 10 days 7 to 10
days before you put it into flour so
you're gonna have to time that spray it
then once it goes into flour you gotta
spray it every three days for about 21
to 24 days you've got a Time match where
the females are ready for pollen at the
right time this could be a whole new set
of challenges that I don't even know how
to adjust for because I'm not familiar
with autoflowers I wish you the best of
luck I do look forward to seeing your
breeding project if you do make seeds if
you do this send me an update let me
know how this goes because I would love
to know how my guidance helped you and
also maybe my guidance slowed you down
let me know what I did wrong for you all
right let me make sure I answered
assuming I'm able I'm able to readily
reverse them are there significant
downsides no I do not find any downsides
I think this is a great project I think
you're on to the right start and I'm
very excited for you to be making your
own feminized Autoflower seeds I look
forward to it all right my friend Daniel
you of course did win a free pack of
seeds because I read your message here
on the grow from your heart podcast
please do send me your address so that I
can get your seeds to you ladies and
gentlemen if I did not read your uh your
message your question here on this
episode do not be afraid have no fear uh
there are plenty more episodes coming
and I've got a lot more emails stacked
up here in front of me please continue
to send me the emails because I like
building listener generated content and
I absolutely like giving you guys free
seeds for helping build the podcast so
go to the grow help tab on
iregenetics.com find the little tab that
says help or questions I don't remember
what it says right now it says questions
click on the one that says questions
it's obvious from there send me your
grow question if I read your grow
question here on this podcast I will
send you a free pack of seeds brought to
you by seeds here now.com all right I
think that is all I've got for you for
this episode
um you know I'll be back in another week
with fresh new content if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns please send me an email the
email address is grow from your heart at
hotmail.com don't be shy let me know
what you think of the show if you've got
hate mail if you've got words of
encouragement go on send it to me I'd
love to read it also make sure you check
out the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everything else you could possibly need
is on my website
irygenetics.com there's a link to the
Discord a link to the patreon there's a
link to iridirect to get brand new seeds
by the way there's a fresh drop of
restock and a price drop on I redirect
go there before those are gone the
patreon members did get the first heads
up that's all I've got for you I'll be
back in another week with fresh new
content thank you again for listening I
want to give a giant shout out to my
good friends at Lollipop Farms and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
please
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you