[Music]
what's up
welcome back to the Show podcast world
I'm your host Rasta Jeff this is episode
794 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a great show lined up for us in
this episode I'm going to give away a
free pack of seeds I've teamed up with
our friends at seedsherenow.com to give
away a free pack of irie genetic seeds
we'll do that later in this episode
before we get too far I do want to
remind you that ire genetics will be at
the dude grows cup that's right the dude
grows cup is happening again this year
just outside of Fort Collins on June 3rd
make sure to check out dgccup.com for
all of the information also there will
be a fresh drop and a restock and new
items on iridirect on April 1st that's
right make sure you check out I redirect
on April 1st for a brand new restock
fresh drops new items and of course a
fat sale prize all right I think that's
all the business we've got to cover here
at the start of the show Welcome to the
podcast everybody let's jump into the
grow help part of this podcast there is
a grow help tab on my way website if you
go to iregenetics.com on the top there
are several tabs one of them says grow
questions click on there send me your
grow question if I read your grow
question on the podcast you will win a
free pack of seeds the first question on
today's show came from our friend who
wants to be called Johnny pot smoker big
congrats to my friend Johnny pot smoker
because you have won a free pack of
seeds for sending me this question this
question goes a little bit like this it
says hey Ross to Jeff thank you for
taking time to read this grow question
hey bro thank you for taking the time to
send to this grow question it goes on it
says can I start breeding with just
feminized seeds that is a really good
question a very common question I get a
lot it says I want to look into starting
a breeding project in my 2x4 tent my
issue is that my 5x5 tent shares the
same lung room should I even risk it
follow-up question can I take feminized
reverse pollen and cross it with an
Autoflower what would happen happy
growing from our friend Johnny pot
smoker this is a good series of
questions here let's jump right into
this you absolutely really can breed
with just feminized seeds that is the
first part of this you can use Femme
seeds for your breeding project however
there will not be a male in there if
you've got feminized seeds all of those
will be girls you will have to select
one of those and reverse it to use that
as your pollen donor or of course use
non-feminized seeds to find a boy to
breed with that plant but feminized
seeds work just like non-feminized seeds
other than the fact that you're not
going to get any males out of that mix
some people have a myth or an idea or a
misconception that they cannot breed to
a plant that came from a femme seed in
my experience those plants are great
let's talk about the uh I've read the
lemon Jeffrey which is one of my
favorite cuts that is a feminized plant
I created that I have bred that to
several other things the lemon Sunrise
is lemon Jeffrey to arise those are
great plants it brings out a lot of
traits from the arise a lot of traits
from the the lemon Jeffrey that's a
feminized to a regular and it works very
well so you absolutely can work your
Femmes into the breeding program any way
that you see fit the next part of the
question
um should I risk it because my uh my
five by five room and my two by four
share the same lung room with that lung
room being the commonality there I do
not think I would risk it because the
pollen will get into the air and it will
end up in both of those Grow rooms the
room you want seated uh will be fully
seated the room you don't want seated
will have too many seeds in it just
because there's no barrier there's no
there's absolutely no protection that
lung room is what is going to move the
pollen from one place to another the
pollen is very fine I would recommend
doing it a little bit further away which
we will touch on on another question
here in this episode so in your setup no
I would not even risk it because that
lung room is just going to move that
pollen right around everybody is going
to be pollinated so maybe you can learn
how to do the five by five room put it
into flower get it floured get it almost
done and then put the other room into
flower that way the next time you fill
the five by five it's only in veg and
then you can do your seed breeding in
the other room have that side flowering
while they're vegging then get that done
clean up all the pollen before these
plants go into flower that should work
out for you but you can't do both at the
same time because I do fear that you
will pollinate that entire room there's
a third part to the question it says my
follow-up question can I take feminized
reversed pollen and cross it with an
Autoflower you absolutely can what would
happen then you're going to make
feminized plants that show some traits
of Autoflower and some traits that show
Regular photo period plants if this is
the first time you're Crossing it to
that Autoflower there will be a
percentage I'm not in uh I'm not an
Autoflower breeder but there will be a
percentage of those plants that do come
out Autoflower so if you're okay with
having some of your Offspring be
Autoflower some of your Offspring be
regular photo period that is an
acceptable idea The Next Step would be
to cross that Autoflower to another
Autoflower again in the future to lock
in that Autoflower trait if that's the
route that you want to go only use
Autoflower if you are your main goal is
to make Autoflower plants because that's
what you're introducing into the gene
pool the short answer is yes you can do
this the long answer is only do that if
you intend on working that Autoflower
trait in and making that a stable trait
that pops up amongst the population so
uh question number one you can breed
with Femme seeds they are just like
regular seeds I would not do it in the
room with two tents because you're going
to get contamination and yes you can
breed you can use feminized reversed
pollen to an Autoflower and it will make
some plants that are Autos some plants
that are Rags my buddy Johnny pot smoker
thank you for the great series of
questions I hope I answered your
questions well I hope I helped you out
please do send me your address so I can
send you a free pack of irie genetic
seeds and of course that seed giveaway
is sponsored by our friends at seeds
here now.com shout out to my friends at
seedshairnow.com if you need regular
feminized or Autoflower seeds I
definitely recommend seeds here now.com
we're going to keep moving forward this
this message also came from the grow
help tab on iregenetics.com this one
came from our friend who wants to be
called shiggy smacks big shout out to my
new friend shiggy smacks before I get
too far shiggy please do send me your
address so that I can mail you a free
pack of irie genetic seeds if I read
your message here on the podcast you do
you do win free beans so I owe you a
pack here goes the question it says
let's say we take a female out of the
flower tan all right pulled her out of
the tent then we put it in a small
separate tent real real far far away and
pollinate it with the super dope stud so
far this is making sense now the
question is can I take that female after
I know it's been pollinated maybe just
blow it off a bit stick it back in the
flower tent and expect everything to be
just peachy or will residual pollen be
left on the plant and that pollen
fertilize the other females that is a
very good question
if if this is done correctly it will
work the way that you want it to but
keep in mind that pollen is microscopic
uh the pollen that got on that plant got
in your hair and your clothes and your
dreadlocks if you got dreadlocks it's in
your eyelashes it's in your eyebrows
it's in your hoodie it's everywhere so
we've got to get rid of that pollen
before we return to the sensimillia room
with no seeds in it so the main way that
I would recommend doing that the main
key to deactivating pollen is water
water deactivates pollen so I would
pollinate that plant in that other room
leave it there for a couple of days I
pollinate twice I just like to hit the
plant two times I just ensures that I'm
going to get full pollination lots of
seeds so I would do my pollination
process however you do that however I do
it put the plant uh you said Far Far
Away real real far far away we got two
reels and two fars so we're real real
far far away we're gonna put the female
in there we're going to pollinate I
would wait a couple days I would
pollinate again then I would wait a
couple of days then like you said blow
off all that pollen if you've got a way
to dust off all that pollen that is
ideal get rid of that then I would take
a bottle of just water and mist my plant
with water completely I would almost
drench that plant to where it's running
off
that water is going to deactivate and
kill any of the pollen that is left on
the plant but it will not damage our
seeds or the plant cannabis plants are
designed by nature to be outside part of
the trichomes purpose is to protect that
plant from rain and moisture and water
the plant will be just fine if you
drench it down one time don't leave it
locked in a room and get stagnant with
no air but let's spray it down one time
leave the fans on and that will help
deactivate the pollen and he won't get
any mold you won't get any problems then
when you're ready to move that plant
after it's been sprayed down also spray
yourself down change your clothes if
you've got dreadlocks like I do wrap
them up when you're doing this or water
them down spray them make sure you be
very careful because pollen is
microscopic and every little granule of
pollen can equal one seed in the flower
room so be very careful so we've watered
down the Plant spray down everything
wipe down the pot wipe down everything
that was in the room with the pollen
including yourself take a shower scrub
down get all that pollen off of you now
at this time when I'm taking that female
plant into the general population with
the other females I would go in that
room and I I would also spray down all
of those females just give them one good
dusting with water that way they're not
able to receive any stray pollen that
may be in the room then just go in there
and move that plant in there and just do
just a random willy-nilly spray just
coat everything with water that way if
there is any pollen that made it in
there that is floating around we've
sprayed it once in this room we've
treated ourselves we've brought it to
the room we treated the females now
we're treating everything in the room
let's just triple check and make sure no
pollen gets into the room so if you do
this correctly everything should be
peachy like you said but the residual
pollen that could be left over will
pollinate all of the pistols that it
comes in contact with so make sure that
you do get every bit of pollen either
off of that plant and or deactivate it I
don't trust I've seen people take an air
compressor and just blow the pollen off
I don't trust that I don't for some
reason I don't think that's good enough
I want some water in the mix as well so
get some water in there spray those
plants down water is the deactivator of
pollen that should rescue you I don't
want to be responsible if you try this
and it does not go wrong I'm telling you
pollen is crazy pollen travels in the
air pollen will get stuck in your nose
and then you'll sneeze it back out later
pollen is microscopic so keep that in
mind and it moves very freely through
the air if you dust a plant if you shake
a plant making pollen watch how that
pollen just lingers in the air some of
the smaller pieces will just stick
around in there they'll be there for a
long time much longer than you
anticipate so take good care of the
pollen be really careful and it should
be peachy but it is very possible that
you will pollinate the entire [ __ ]
room so be very careful all right my
friend shiggy smacks thank you for the
great question please do send me your
address because I owe you a free pack of
seeds all right let's keep the show
moving I do have another question here
in front of me this one came from our
friend [ __ ] dog that's a really cool
name big shout out to my friend [ __ ]
dog [ __ ] dog please make sure to send
me your address because I do owe you a
pack of irie genetic seeds of course
those seeds are sponsored by our friends
at seeds here now.com big thanks to them
for hosting and promoting and sponsoring
a seed giveaway here on the show this
question says I have a general grow
question my plan is to grow a pack of
Jack Tripper and do an open pollination
with all of the plants no individual
selection and then it says I know I
won't know the baby daddy that's fine if
you are doing an open pollination to
make f2s that's that's a great way to do
it you're going to make a lot of seeds
and you're going to see a lot of
diversity here you're going to see all
the phenotypical expressions and you
will find what you want in that F2
population by doing this it says
um I want to no individual selection
then hunt the highest potency of the
female to find High potency mail to
further breed with that's a really good
strategy but don't get too hung up on
the idea that potency is the only thing
you're looking for we need structure we
need plant Vigor we need resistance to
pathogens we need resistance to any kind
of bugs we also need to make sure that
there's no intersex problem in these
plants so don't stay too focused on just
potency there are a lot of other factors
that should help you determine if this
plan is worth growing let's continue
though so the question I have is have
you ever seen intersex traits on a
female after it has received pollen
um no I've never seen a plant that has
received pollen show me intersex traits
but most of the time when I'm working
with plants I've grown them multiple
times before I choose to breed with them
so I know that that intersex is not
going to pop up before or after
pollination so there's a little bit of a
vetting process to be done before I
generally breed it sounds like you're
going to take these Jack Trippers and
just go for it which sounds like a fun
project I have no uh you won't see
intersex traits in those Jack Trippers
I've never seen that nobody out there
has ever reported an intersex problem
with the Jack Trippers so I recommend
you do it you won't see any intersex
traits pop up in there but we'll stick
with the question have you ever seen
intersex traits on a female after it has
received pollen no I've never seen that
before or is that more common in Scentsy
but yes that is totally more common in
Scentsy but something happens with the
hormones once that plan has been
pollinated it's very unlikely to show
intersex traits in my experience uh
that's my opinion that's what I think I
don't know if I have any science behind
that
um it says I am just planning to do the
F2 then select a male I figured if I did
it this way I'm kind of mixing up the
breeding pot a little bro you are uh
shaking the breeding uh Lottery you're
getting everything that you could
possibly pull every phenotype imaginable
because you're not going to call any
phenotypes either male or female so
you've got the tall skinny one the short
squatty one the one that smells like
lemons the one that smells like dryer
sheets the one that smells a little bit
like piss uh the one that smells like
lavender the one that is real tall and
skinny the one that's super high potency
you're going to find all of those
phenotypes maybe different combinations
of those phenotypes by mixing up that uh
open pollination should we talk about
open pollination for a second we will
let me keep going so he does go on he
says by adding in the Pandora's box of
F2 I hope to find a Jack Tripper F2 male
that carries on a rocket ship potency
um yes that is a really good idea and
then he says I'm two years out ladies
first so he's going to final hunt the
ladies first which sounds like a really
good he's going to do the open
pollination grow some find the ladies
then look for a male with that rocket
potency that is a good strategy I like
this idea this is going to be fun when
you're ready bro I'd love to run a 10
maybe a 20 pack of these I'm in Colorado
so I will run 12 of them because that is
my legal limit but I would love to run a
few of these uh see what you've attitude
from my creation that's always fun to
see especially because now let's talk
about I said open pollination I usually
do not practice the open pollination
sort of technique I'm a very selective
type of breeder open pollination I may
have kind of touched on it a moment ago
that is when uh this person is going to
put an entire pack of Jack Tripper seeds
in a room and not select any boys not
select any girls but just let the pollen
fly there will probably be somewhere
between four and six boys and four and
six girls so we're gonna have I'm just
gonna say five and five because it makes
it easy to remember and balance we're
gonna have five male plants putting
pollen on five different girl plants but
it's not going to be male 1 to mail two
to a male L2 to mail 2 or however I said
that it's not going to be plan a and
plant a and plant B and plant B it's
going to be all of the mixes of those
male number a is going to pollinate
plant number one two three four and five
but also on the same plant will be seeds
that were made with the pollen from male
number two also on the same plant will
be seeds made from male number three so
we're gonna have five female plants with
five different baby daddy seeds in all
of them you're gonna see what is that
250 000 different combinations is the
way that I think there might be more
zeros on that
um there might be two million five
hundred thousand different combinations
that you go I'm gonna stick with the 250
000. it's got a lot of different
combinations of phenotypical expression
you could really come up with this way
so that's going to be a really fun
project that is open pollination you
guys when you open some seeds and just
put them all in the room and just let
them have a big uh big old orgy in there
no selection uh no elimination no
calling uh just letting it happen the
way that nature would do it that puts
off a lot of amazing interesting
phenotypes and it sounds like our friend
understands that they're going to open a
Pandora's Box and then from there they
will select their winners for their next
breeding project great strategy it
sounds like you're doing everything that
you should be doing and no I have not I
think the main question was if I've seen
the intersex traits on a plant that has
been pollinated no that's something I've
never seen and I've never seen intersex
and the Jack Tripper so you were off to
a very good start all right let's keep
the show moving I do have one more
question here in front of me this one
came from our friend Smurf groan of
course this did come from the grow help
tab on the irie genetics website so that
means that our friends Smurf groan wins
a free pack of irie genetic seeds Smurf
please do send me your address I will
get some seeds in the mail to you as
soon as possible and just a quick heads
up if you have won seeds if you've sent
me your address at this point in time
all of the seed winners are in the mail
if you have won seeds and you have not
sent me your address please send me your
address if you've already sent it and
you haven't gotten your seeds feel free
to send it again I will do my best to
get those seeds out to you and don't
worry I do verify that your question was
on the show before I send you seeds
don't try to scan I mean I'm paying
attention let's keep moving this one
says hey there roster Jeff in one of
your episodes you say an S1 is when you
take two clones of the same plant and
reverse one and pollinate the other can
the Reversed plant pollinate itself and
is this considered an S1 as well thank
you and keep the great knowledge coming
yes that is absolutely an S1 as well
that's the same thing the reason I don't
recommend or prefer that is because when
it comes to reversing a plant I like to
put the Reversed plant into flower a
little bit sooner than the plant that
will receive pollen that is just a
timing issue you have to start spraying
the plant two weeks before you put it
the pollen donor needs to be sprayed two
weeks before it goes two weeks to ten
days before it goes into flour so I need
to spray that at one time then I need to
put that plant into flour in seven to
ten days from the first spray then it
needs to be sprayed every third day for
the next about 21 to 24 days it's gonna
get about seven to ten total sprays then
um at some point I need to put my female
plants into flour to catch up with with
that male plant so the pollen comes out
at the right time when the pistols are
ripe on the female plant the reason I
don't prefer to do this to the same
plant is because those pistols and that
pollen don't time up as good as they
could if I wait to put my female plants
into flower when I see that male plant
just showing signs of being reversed I
know what a female plant looks like when
it begins to flower there's a little
variation when the reversal was
successful it'll start where the plant
will start to make a bud it makes it
just a little just a little thing that
looks different it's a nub and it's
going to be an anther eventually but I
can identify it soon as soon as I see
those that's when the female plant goes
into flower that way the pollen comes
out at the right time when the pistols
are ripe on the female plant to receive
that pollen if I were to do it on the
same plant the pollen will come out way
too early and the pistols won't be ripe
enough or the pistols will be over ripe
and the pollen won't come out soon
enough it's just plant dependent strain
dependent some plants really want pollen
earlier some plants want pollen a lot
later in the game
two plants to make a really good example
of that situation are the strawberry
fields which makes strawberry Starburst
and the Platinum Tangy which makes the
sun kiss also makes the orange gasm but
that's a whole other story those plants
they want pollinate completely different
times about a week apart the Platinum
Tangy is ready for pollen super early
she's like hey Paul and Amy Here I Am
the Strawberry Fields plant is standing
in the room going [ __ ] you early and
she's just looking like I'm gonna wait
for the good pollen so that strawberry
Starburst plant is a full week behind
the Platinum Tangy for when it wants
pollen it's just sitting back waiting it
gets bigger it keeps on growing uh it's
still developing it's still booming it's
still developing like a plant should but
those pistols those uh sexual organs of
that plant are just not ready to receive
the pollen yet so uh the reason that I
do my plants separately the reason that
I time the plant separately is just to
get them into the room at the
appropriate time if this is your first
attempt at doing any breeding if this is
your first attempt at making seeds this
will work for you you won't make as many
seeds as you could if you did this to
two different plants you could
definitely make more seeds think about
you're reversing one side and not
reversing the other you're gonna have to
spray a couple of branches or one branch
of a plant very frequently and make sure
not to spray the other branches of that
plant because the one you spray will
will reverse some plants are very
stubborn some plants if you don't spray
the whole thing it won't reverse the
hormones over here tell the hormones
over here nah and they just they argue
about it one this one will reverse
halfway this one will flower halfway
both sides will look like [ __ ] so
sometimes you'll be trying to reverse
the right side of the plant and keep the
left side of the plant non-reversed and
the plant just doesn't want to do that
the hormones are just not allowing that
to happen in the plant sometimes it's a
more sativa dominant tropical type of a
plant that that'll happen to sometimes
some of the OG cush dye plants don't
even want to reverse at all some plants
are stubborn some are not that's why
it's much easier to have an individual
isolated plant that you are attempting
to reverse then you can reverse that
plant you can get it into flour and
since I understand when my plants go
into flower and when they want pollen I
could get that male into the flower room
get him flowering then I could drag in
that strawberry Starburst plant and get
her a head start then a few days later I
could bring in the Platinum Tangy plant
get them right on schedule then when the
pollen comes both of those plants are
going to produce maximum amount of seeds
for me so your idea will work if it's
your first idea your first attempt you
will bang out some seeds as long as the
one side reverses and the other side
stays true you'll be okay sometimes that
doesn't work out that is plant specific
but it should work for you in most cases
however I do recommend two separate
plants however the main question was
will this still be an S1 yes this is
absolutely still an S1 we've taken
pollen from a specific cultivar and
we've pollinated that specific cultivar
with that pollen it's unadulterated it's
female pollen it's a female plant that
is a feminized S1 seed congratulations
if you do this let me know how it goes
let me know how you decided to do it did
you stick with one plant being the
pollen donor and the pollen Giver or did
you decide to use two plants how many
female plants did you put in the room
and then my overall question is going to
be how many seeds did you get have you
grown them and what are they like all
right that's what I want to know my
friend Smurf girl thank you for the
great question uh please remember to
send me your address because I do owe
you a free pack of irie genetic seeds
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends info smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there if you did not win
a free pack of seeds on today's episode
do not feel discouraged anybody that
sends me a grow question on the grow
Health tab at iregenetics.com does have
the opportunity to win a free pack of
seeds I'm going to continue this
giveaway until seeds here now and I I've
decided that we've given away enough
Siege which could be quite a while
because I like giving away free seeds it
feels good make sure you go hit that
grow help tab at iregenetics.com again
don't feel discouraged you guys since
I've started doing this the emails have
been pouring in I've got a nice it's
probably that's a lot of paper there I'm
not even going to try to measure that
there are a lot of pages of paper there
lots of questions coming up lots of
great content for the show thank you I
think that's all I've got for this
episode you know I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart hotmail.com don't be shy
of course send your grow questions the
grow help to the grow help tab on the
irie genetics website anything else you
could possibly need is on the ire
genetics website there's a link to my
patreon campaign please contribute to
the patreon uh the patreon contributors
actually get first dibs on new seeds
when I put new seeds on I redirect the
patreon patrons get the first heads up
on that if I put coupon codes the
patrons are always the first ones with
the coupon codes and they get the best
coupon codes so go check out the patreon
campaign go join us on Discord I've been
giving away free seeds on Discord
occasionally uh join us on Discord jump
into the smokers chat come join the
party it's always a good time in there
come hang out with my friends and I come
smoke also maybe win some free seeds
anything else you could possibly need is
on that website at iregenetics.com I
feel like I've started rambling here at
the end of the show so we are going to
wrap this up thanks again for listening
I want to give a big shout out to my
buddy Alabama man and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
thank you
hmm