[Music]
thank you
all right now here we go welcome to the
show podcast world I'm your host Rasta
Jeff this of course is episode
796 of the grow from your heart podcast
in this episode I'm going to give away
free seeds that's right I've teamed up
with our friends at seeds here now.com
to give away a free pack of ire genetic
seeds hang out we'll talk more about
that later in this episode before we get
too far I do want to announce that I was
on the dude grows Show recently by the
time this episode comes out that dude
Grow Show episode will be out and
available on YouTube so go to YouTube
search for dude grow show with roster
Jeff I will pop up make sure you listen
watch that video give it some likes
leave some comments let them know that
you loved me on the show so they will
have me back speaking of the dude grows
the dude grows cup is happening again
June 3rd just outside of Fort Collins
Colorado make sure you check out
dgcup.com for all of that information I
was hanging out with the dude grows and
they said that even as more than halfway
sold out so if you need your tickets get
them now because it will sell out and I
look forward to seeing you at the dude
grows cup that's right I will be there
team irie genetics will be there we'll
have a booth we'll have all kinds of
great seeds we'll have a good time come
say hi even if you're not shopping for
seeds
come by say hi give me a fist mop give
me a high five give me a hug take a
photo with me if that's what you're into
you don't have to buy seeds to come hang
out I invite everybody to come say hi
also if you're looking for seeds
definitely make sure you come by the
booth all right I think that's all of
the business we've got nope there's one
more thing to cover more business here
at the start of the show there is a sale
running on iridirect.com that's right
visit iridirect.com grab some regular
femini seeds at great prices
I put some of the Femme seeds down to
ridiculous prices a lot of the regular
seeds are at ridiculous prices and every
order does come with free seeds that
sale does last through this entire month
of April so make sure you check out
iridirect and catch that sale get those
Femme seeds get your garden started set
yourself up for a success all right now
we are through all of the business part
of the podcast it is time to jump into
the email and grow question portion of
today's show the first question comes
from the grow help tab on the ire
genetics website if you go to
iregenetics.com there's a list of tabs
at the top one of them says does say
questions or grow help you'll find it
I'm sure you're smart enough give that a
click it will ask you a few questions it
asks you about your grow space it's
going to ask you where you're growing
indoors Outdoors what strain are you
growing what's the temp what's the
humidity we ask a few basic questions we
want to know what's going on that lets
me get a heads up on how to help you the
more I know about your grow the easier
it is for me to diagnose correct and set
you up for success and help you with
your growth so we have some questions go
to the grow help tab after those general
questions we do give you the opportunity
to type in your full question what's
going on in the grow how can we help you
my friend JH has sent me a question on
the grow help Tab and it goes a little
bit like this hey Ross to Jeff can you
tell me about your easiest to grow
strain something I can really hit out of
the park without being an expert and
then he goes in parentheses and says and
don't say all of them that's really
funny because all of my strains are
pretty easy to grow and you should be
able to bang them all out of the park
but I will give you some specifics and
some more details it says what one of
your strains is the healthiest uh which
strain can't and won't be stopped which
strain is beginner friendly and what
strain is resistant to all then they ask
follow-up questions once I determine all
the answers for these they want to know
what does it smell like what is the
flowering time and what type of
morphology can we expect and then are
there more on the list then he follows
up with another great question let's
jump into the first part of this
question here from our friend JH in
Canada the main part of the question is
which of my strains are easiest to grow
and then he said don't say all of them
so that does limit me I often say that
Sun kiss is one of my easiest to grow
strains sunkiss is super easy it's very
forgiving if you make a mistake if you
over water underwater over feed under
feed the sun kiss doesn't get too upset
about that it can take some abuse it can
take some grower error and a new grower
is going to make some errors and cause
some abuse so Sun kiss is always one of
my very first recommendations when it
comes to successful plants for a
beginner grower I also recommend the
strawberry Starburst the only issue with
strawberry Starburst is it may get a
little bit tall for a new grower if they
are not prepared the good side to that
is it does grow super quickly in veg it
grows with Hyper Vigor and veg so it
doesn't take nearly as much flowering
time to get that plant big enough and
ready for a flower because it just grows
so quickly so your veg time is shorter
which gives you less time for problems I
feel like the quicker in and out we are
in that grow in that Garden the less
opportunity we have for problems so a
quicker vegging plant will definitely
help you out however those will get
quite tall just flip early you will be
okay I do have a longer list tier of
things that I think will grow well in my
in your garden from my lineup I always
recommend Morning Dew Morning Dew is a
great cross it's very resistant to
powdery mildew very resistant to Bud rot
it grows very well it's got a great
structure and it's super stinky and
super potent product in the end so the
sun kiss strawberry Starburst and
Morning Dew are three of the classics
that I would recommend those have been
in my lineup for quite a while they've
been tried and trued we know they work
well in all types of environments
indoors Outdoors greenhouses they work
well for experienced Growers and they
definitely work well for the noobs I've
seen new Growers push that strawberry
Starburst to beautiful limits I've seen
some gorgeous pictures of strawberry
Starburst the morning dew comes out
super Frosty super chunky no matter who
grows it and the sun kiss is Just
autopilot weed if you pour water and
nutrients on that and put lights above
it sunkiss is going to give you an
excellent amazing top shelf buds so
let's keep going because there are more
to the list I want to mention fist bump
fist bump is one of my newer strains
fist bumping is super easy to grow it is
a sour diesel to a rise cross once again
the only problem you may run into with
fist bump is it is going to get fairly
tall fairly quickly and it may need some
sort of supports but it's pretty easy to
grow in most cases now let's make it
real easy for people and let's talk
about some feminized lines that I do
offer that make it very easy for people
to grow one of my favorites that I
recommend for new Growers that you guys
love that everybody out there is able to
grow able to knock it out of the park is
Golden Goat Golden Goat is really easy
to grow it needs a little extra feeding
but most new Growers tend to overfeed
anyway so since the Golden Goat needs a
little extra nutrients you guys do it
just right the new Growers do that one
very well
Golden Goat is a feminized seed if you
get seeds from me if it says Femme seeds
on it there is a Golden Goat back cross
those are not Femmes however there are
Golden Goat feminized seeds available
you will have all female plants in your
lineup they will grow with great Vigor
they'll be nice and sturdy they make
beautiful plants with great colors great
Aromas they take about eight and a half
to nine and a half weeks to finish
depending on the room and the
phenotypical Expressions you achieve
which plants you get out of the seed
pack basically it's really easy to grow
and the buzz from Golden Goat is amazing
the flavors Aromas and Buzz are top
shelf that's why I breed it to
everything you'll notice there's Golden
Goat somewhere in a lot of my crosses
let's keep going more feminized stuff
the Maze and the wombat Maze and Wombat
are great strains for new Growers they
will work very well for you also
character Zero and Sunday show will be
great strains for new Growers those are
all four of those are feminized there's
Maize wombat Sunday show and character
Zero those are all Femmes they will all
grow very well for a new grower they're
all very resistant to problems the
mildew the mold bugs all of those will
be very resistant the problem with those
last four that I mentioned is they do
get a little bit tall that's the only
issue to worry about the thing to do
there flower early don't veg them for so
long which most Growers are pretty eager
to get the crop going they do want to
flower early so veg until they're about
maybe knee-high then flip them and I
think you'll do really well with those
plants so let me review that list
regular seeds Sun kiss strawberry
Starburst Morning Dew then we work into
fist bump fist bump is going to be super
stinky make sure you have carbon
filtration in place for the fist bump
then feminized Golden Goat is super easy
to grow Maize wombat character Zero and
Sunday show are very easy to grow
another great growing plant is the Lemon
Jeffrey however it does get really tall
and it's kind of picky on feeding in
some phenotype so if you want to really
push yourself try the lemon Jeff but
that's the next step up that one's not
going to be as easy so those are some of
my easiest and healthiest to grow those
uh can't stop won't be stopped they're
all beginner friendly and they're all
quite resistant to most of the problems
you're going to run into as a grower now
let's talk about some of the flavors and
Aromas of a lot of these plants
Sun kiss that is straight up oranges if
you're looking for oranges orange candy
orange Funk Sun kisses the way to go
Morning Dew is straight funky skunky uh
earthy uh I call it warmer notes those
are more earthy skunky gassier darker
sort of tones in my mind the strawberry
Starburst that's just straight up
strawberry candy uh fist bump that's
going to be fully offensive gas funky
diesel fuel gasoline sort of Terps
Golden Goat that one's very unique the
Golden Goat is kind of like a tropical
fruit a tropical fruit basket and Juicy
Fruit bubble gum that is my opinion of
Golden Goat and I love it maize maze is
uh blue raspberry truffle to the
Afterglow so you get that blue raspberry
truffle sorta
sort of it's like a a raspberry sort of
thing it's a sour uh Tangy sort of a
thing but then that mixes in with the
sweetness of the aftergone it makes
amazing flavors wombat that's the New
York City Diesel to Afterglow uh you get
hints of that diesel flavor and a lot of
orange diesel Lee Terps out of that one
character Zero that one's going to give
you those earthy terpy uh more earthy
turkey sort of stuff and then the uh
Sunday show that's also going to give
you cushy uh orange sort of flavors so
those are the flavors and Aromas from
those flowering time uh Sun kiss eight
or nine weeks morning do eight or nine
weeks fist bump nine or ten weeks
strawberry starburst on nine to ten
weeks on that one Golden Goat nine weeks
maze wombat character Zero Sunday show
those are all going to be nine to ten
weakers you will find some early
finishers and the sun kiss and morning
do some of those will go eight weeks 56
days finish the eighth week you guys
don't cut it down the middle of week
eight let 56 days happen I would
recommend 60 days but some of the those
are a little bit earlier morphology so
since a lot of these came from the arise
pollen donor King Solomon a lot of them
have that tall uh branchy takeoff sort
of structure the one that doesn't do it
as much is Sun kiss uh Sun kiss doesn't
take off as hard as the others but most
of them will get a tall skinny sort of a
structure Golden Goat is an S1 that one
uh should say depending on your light
and your environment sometimes it stays
a little bit shorter sometimes it does a
little stretching for people but it's
shorter and bushier for the Golden Goat
maze wombat character Zero and Sunday
show uh those are going to get tall on
you you're going to see tall stretchy
plants with a lot of branches but in
flower all of that tallness just fills
up with meaty beefy chunky trichome
covered nuggets I'm not really going to
dig too deep into the specific
phenotypes of all of these plants I gave
you the basic what to expect that's a
lot to talk about uh second best that is
the one two that's like the top ten in
my lineup right there I couldn't pick
just one that's like trying to pick your
favorite pair of sneakers but those are
a few that I would recommend for a new
beginner I think you'd really kick some
good ass with Morning Dew fist bump
everything on that list is great to grow
then it said are all of you your
restraints potent that is a very good
question is everything that I breed
potent
um since I'm using I do very careful
selection for male plants since I'm
using top quality male plants that leads
me to think that most of the progeny
should be quite potent it should contain
a lot of THC potential but that's also
up to the grower the environment which
phenotype did you select there may be
other terpenes or cannabinoids
dominating that mix toward the THC isn't
the most potent most prevalent compound
in that plant but it'll still be a very
potent plant so depends on what you're
looking for it depends on also how did
you grow it where did you grow it how
long did you grow it then there are a
lot of other things that come into play
was it dried and cured properly is it
the strain for you but yes in most cases
the things that I've bred the things
that I breed and create should be quite
potent because I'm smoking for more of a
head Buzz I want to walk into the store
and almost have a panic attack and think
oh [ __ ] I'm way too high to be in here
shopping and consider leaving that is
the buzz that I am seeking to achieve so
I do breed for that sort of head Buzz
sort of panicky sort of stuff uh there
will be some more uh some more cushy
variety stuff coming from me in the
future here because I miss those old
school cushy skunk flavors but I've
already said too much uh but yes
everything is quite potent you wrapped
the message up with from your friend JH
in Canada JH my dude thank you for the
great message of course I do owe you a
free pack of seeds ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls if you do send a grow
question to the grow help tab on ire
genetics or iridirect.com they both have
the same tab if you send a question to
there and I do read that question here
on the podcast that means that you win a
free pack of irie genetic seeds and of
course that giveaway is sponsored by
seedsherenow.com
all right let's keep this show moving I
do have another message here in front of
me this one is kind of a follow-up this
one is from JH again I know I'm spoiling
JH but these two questions came back to
back and this one was super easy to
answer it says hey Ross to Jeff J.H here
again if I like the flavor of one of
your 20 THC crosses more than one of
your 30 THC crosses should I go with the
flavor
um yes we often teach people here in
Colorado that the THC number isn't the
ultimate deciding factor and how good a
product is uh THC percentage in a plant
is what a lab detected sometimes you may
find that they're like I said a moment
ago there are better terpenes maybe
there's better Esters paleo it's
flavonoids there's a lot of other things
in this plant that affect the way we
consume it and the way we enjoy it uh if
you've got a 30 THC plant with zero
Terps I might not enjoy it as much as I
would a 20 THC plant with 0.4 Terps in
there uh just that little bit of Terps
is going to make a big difference and
make it taste good would you rather eat
cardboard or would you rather eat
cardboard that tastes like strawberries
and candy that's what I'm talking about
do you want some good flavor in the
mouth or do you just want blandness so
the nose always knows follow your nose
I've done a podcast called follow your
nose those Terps are super important so
the short answer
uh if I if you like one better smoke the
one you like better bro and then I'm
gonna wrap that up and follow up by
saying we are often fooled uh Bamboozled
if you will by just THC labeling on jars
when you go to The Dispensary when you
go to buy seeds everybody puts a
potential THC number or a lab tested THC
number on the product if you look at the
dispensary the jar says whatever banana
kush however much an ounce however much
a gram whatever they list the price on
the jar a lot of times and then it'll
have a big star on it 27 THC and I watch
people scan the shelf and they go oh a
32 I want that one I'll take it out to
that one and sometimes that may not be
the best product for you I give them a
smell because I believe that the nose is
what matters the most my nose is going
to know if there's something in there
that I am lacking or would enjoy my nose
goes no that's not the one no oh that
one when your nose lights up and your
eyes go damn that's the jar you should
buy that's the weed that you should
smoke the lab test is cool it gives you
kind of a good idea of how internet
could and potentially should be but the
other compounds in there are greatly
going to affect your Buzz I describe it
like this I haven't said this on the
podcast in a long time we got a lot of
new subscribers let's talk about it this
way I think that THC let's compare our
Buzz to a firework all right we all love
fireworks out there uh maybe some of you
don't but most of us love Fireworks we
all know what they are so this will work
let's just say that the THC is how high
up into the air your firework will go so
you're going to smoke THC your firework
is going to shoot up into the air it's
going to go straight up now my analogy
is if the terpenes are the colors of
that firework once that firework gets up
into the air it's going to explode is it
going to put off a purple ring is it
going to put off red yellow and green
Sparkles is it going to be the one that
just goes
and all the weird [ __ ] rains from the
sky after it is it going to be super
[ __ ] loud and fly up into the air and
go boom and then just put off one big
bright white ball of light for a second
is it going to be [ __ ] orange is it
going to be purple is it going to be
green is it going to be a lot of it
that's what the terpenes decide when we
get our Buzz the THC makes us go up the
terpenes decide do we get the munchies
do we get paranoid do we get the giggles
do you get a little turned on do you get
[ __ ] scared of Life do you get super
introspective do you just get really
weird completely weird altogether that's
the terpenes mixing with the other
compounds deciding what kind of buzz you
get so I think that shopping just for
THC and focusing just on numbers like
that can be very misleading and then my
my wrap-up statement for all this talk
about THC percentages and potency is
um I've had a lot of weed tested in labs
and I've had a lot of it come back
really high in lab results but you know
what I've never had I've never had a
machine come back to buy another bag of
weed so those numbers don't do me any
good those are good numbers for the
machine but they're not perfect numbers
for humans humans need other compounds
to enjoy our product properly all right
my buddy JH you only get one free pack
of seeds bro but I did double up and
read two messages uh bro thank you for
all the correspondence the communication
um I do like your ideas I can't respond
to every email that you send me bro
there are a lot of them but I do agree
with most of what you're saying and I do
appreciate your Insight and your uh your
education you teach me some things
sometimes that I had never thought about
you think in a different way than me so
big up to my buddy JH up there in Canada
send me your address bro I do owe you a
pack of seeds uh most of the time you
guys I try not to send free seeds to
Canada because it does cost me 40.40 US
dollars in shipping to pack up some
seeds and send them to Canada but JH has
been around for a long time he's been
participating for a while we're gonna do
that if you sent me your messages and I
have read it and you're in Canada don't
worry I will send you the seeds but I
will try to limit the amount of Canadian
messages I do read Because 40 bucks a
pop does add up quite quickly but shout
out to our friends at seedshairnow.com
for sponsoring a free seed giveaway all
right let's keep moving I do have
another great question here in front of
me once again this did come from the
grow Health tab on ire genetics this one
came from our friend who wants to be
called Striker can and it says what kind
of question do you have there's a
problem in the garden they're growing
strawberry Starburst strawberry bubble
gum and wedding cake that's a great
lineup uh they're indoors under LEDs
there in week five of flower they're
growing in Cocoa the pH was 5.5 the EC
was 300 the daytime temp is 73 nighttime
temperature is 65. the humidity is 65
things are looking good then we get to
the question part of this message it
says yo Rasta Jeff I'm wondering what
the best thing to add to cocoa for a
sweetener taste taste enhancer terpene
Adder could be I just ordered Bud Candy
from advanced nutrients that product
will work however it is not my favorite
I don't like to bash products on here
but honestly uh here's the truth when I
grew with Advanced Nutrients products I
felt like all of my flowers tasted the
same I could have OG cushion one part of
the room strawberry Haze and the other
blueberry cookies in the other part of
the room feed them all advanced
nutrients guess what they all taste like
Advanced Nutrients it all has that
really once you grow it smoke it a
little bit you'll start to recognize the
flavor you'll be in smoke circles you'll
hit a joint you'll hit a bowl and you'll
go ah an advanced nutrients grower
you'll start to taste it so there's in
my opinion I all tastes the same
otherwise there's nothing wrong with
that brand it just doesn't at all tastes
the same and I breed weed to taste
really unique and then when it all
tastes like the same Bud Candy to me I
don't enjoy that let's keep moving it
says I do already add tiger bloom
booster and ocean marine Cuisine that
ocean marine will definitely help you
out enhancing the Terps and the health
of the plants said I'm drying for about
10 days the first four days at 50 RH
then the rest down to 40. I may stay at
the 50 for a little longer but that's
all right do your thing since I use a
dehumidifier on low with added
ventilation in a 5x7 closet so you're
making the best with what you've got
that's that's great uh I just got the
lemon Jeffrey as well so I really want
to bring out that sweet Citrus smell and
flavor thank you for any advice Rasta
Jeff my dude thank you for the great
question let's jump into this let's talk
about how to enhance flavor a little bit
in these sweeter strains in previous
episodes I did talk about adding kelp
products to make things taste that off
to enhance that skunky earthy funky uh
cushy Aroma and flavor I think the kelp
really brings that out that will also
bring out the aroma and flavors and most
of your other strains it's just not
going to be I feel like it kind of it
helps more with the cushy stuff but it
will help with your other products let's
talk about more specific products that
are available I don't use a lot of uh
terpene enhancer products I kind of just
try to grow an overall healthy plant
with a good balanced diet and a good
environment and then dry it and cure it
properly and select good genetics but if
you want products that you can add there
is a product called turbinator I have
not used terpinator myself but I have
heard good reports and good results from
the products turbinator and it's
expensive so that [ __ ] better work
there's also a product called sweet from
Botanicare they offer a couple of
different flavors
these are exactly what you're asking for
these are sweetener products to add to
your nutrient mix and they claim that
these products will sweeten up the
flavor of your end product I've never
used the sweet sweetener product with
the flavor I've used the sweetener
without flavors to work on sugars and
carbohydrates in the plants and those
plants did come out quite tasty another
product I could recommend is humble
honey humble honey is great [ __ ] I used
to use Humboldt honey way back in the
day before I made the switch to the New
Millennium maybe after thinking about
this myself I might start adding that
back into the mix The Humble honey had a
a lot of different things in there and
it definitely made a difference in the
flavor and Aroma of my product once
again I did mention kelp now let's talk
about just basic things instead of
recommending products once again those
companies do not pay me I'm not
advertising I'm just saying [ __ ] that
I've used and [ __ ] that I've read and
seen work I've not given any money by
any of these companies
um sugars and carbs are definitely going
to help increase the flavor of your
cannabis plants
carbonaria is a great product from New
Millennium that I would definitely
recommend adding to your product don't
over feed the carbon area especially if
you're in a hydroponic system that
carbon area will gum up the works it
will suck if you're using a hydro system
I may choose a different product carba
load from Advanced Nutrients is actually
a pretty decent product then to all of
that stuff if you're using the
turbinator the sweet The Humble honey
don't use all those together pick one
the carbon area and the carbo load also
to that I would add Bud swell that is a
liquid bat guano product it'll make your
plants go shipping in multiple ways
they'll get beefier and fatter and they
will taste and smell good because of
that product I do believe in my opinion
now I'm going to say something that may
be controversial because this is not how
I grow but sometimes Organics will bring
out the most amazing flavors in your
plants it's all about the plant and the
phenotype some plants so let's talk
about a couple of things I've got a sour
diesel that grows okay in soil less mix
it does okay it doesn't have the flavor
and Aroma that I can achieve when my
friend grows it in Hydro I've got a
friend that grows the same cut and a
hydro bucket and a hydro system and that
[ __ ] comes out so stinky that it makes
my eyes feel weird I've got to put it in
multiple baggies and that's just the
difference in how he is growing it so
maybe some phenotypes will make a
difference if you grow in Hydro soilless
mix with bottled nutrients and maybe
some plants will benefit from growing it
strictly organically so we got different
options we got to figure out what the
plant likes or you've got to find the
phenotype that works best with your grow
environment that's why I talk a lot
about you selecting the phenotype that
works best for you instead of asking me
my favorite phenotype my favorite might
not work well in your grow it probably
gets too tall too fast for your grow
environment so growing the right
genetics in the right environment with
the right system will definitely help
you enhance the flavor and Aroma
genetics are very important some plants
just don't have a lot of flavor and
Aroma maybe some plants have got the
wrong flavor and are Aroma for you so
it's all about finding again the correct
genetics for to meet your goals they
meet your needs flavor and Aroma wise
and also grow well in your system you've
got to find that and then dial that in
and perfect that flavor so also another
thing that can definitely affect the
flavor and Aroma of our plants is the
dry and cure process we can grow these
plants perfectly for seven eight weeks
in veg nine or ten weeks in flour and
then once we cut them down we can really
destroy these plants I've seen a lot of
people mess up huge beautiful harvests
just by not drying and curing them
properly something else I should mention
is that there is not really One Magic
Bullet to making our cannabis perfect we
have to get everything right this is
like a giant chess board and everything
on the chessboard has to be in place if
you want to get that Checkmate so don't
rely on just one bottle one product one
trick one Silver Bullet to make our
product uh top shelf everything has to
be in line we need to start with the
right light if you don't have the right
light the right Spectrum the right
intensity the right duration then
nothing will work at all then we need
good air how is the VPD and the room is
the temperature right is the humidity
right if it gets too hot in the room
guess what start volatizing terpenes if
it gets too dry guess what terpenes
start volatizing if it gets too wet
terpenes won't produce so we have to
keep everything in line from day one not
just in flour from the veg phase we have
to get it started in veg and take top
shelf care of this plant all the way
through whatever you got like I said six
to eight weeks of veg 9 10 maybe 11
weeks of flour take perfect care of that
plant every single day every day matters
if you've got one day where the vpt VPD
got off just a little bit guess what
that will show in your end result it
could have been one two maybe three
percent better not three percent more
THC just overall a three percent better
product all right another thing to think
about is the environment in which you
are drying curing and storing this
product a lot of people are growing down
in a basement or in a shed or in a
garage or in a backyard if that room
stinks and smells funky when you hang up
your plants once all the moisture and
everything goes away from your plants
it's going to start absorbing that
stinky funky musty grandma's basement
sort of smell and that will be stuck in
your plants if you're drying in the tool
shed in the garage and it smells like
old lawn mowers or it smells like old
moldy house that will end up in the
flavor of your product so think about
where you're drying and curing it have
so a week or two weeks before it's even
time to harvest start planting your
drying and curing room have that ready
look how much product you've got think
about how much space you're going to
need to cure it dry it hang it up think
about how you're going to move the air
in that room keep the humidity and the
temperature proper in that room plan
that now because a lot of people like I
said a moment ago have destroyed crops
after the Harvest phase I've seen
commercial grows take down Giant
harvests and not know what to do with it
and end up throwing half of it away so
half of their work got destroyed after
the Harvest phase I'm gonna check my
notes make sure I got everything here
yeah dry it cure it store it properly
and again there's no not one single
Silver Bullet that you can shoot that's
going to make this gross smell amazing
look amazing uh level 10 weed comes from
growing that weed perfectly every day
consistently several cycles and then
achieving that Masterpiece of a crop of
cannabis all right my friend Striker can
I want to thank you for a great message
please do send me your address because
guess what my friend I owe you a free
pack of irie genetic seeds and again
that pack of seeds is brought To Us by
our friends at seeds here now.com all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast if you did not win seeds on this
episode do not feel discouraged do not
feel discluded I've got a lot more
emails here in front of me and there are
a lot more podcast episodes coming up so
you do still have plenty of chances to
win more seeds if you're impatient and
you want to get those seeds right now
all you've got to do is go to
iridirect.com a lot of great things are
on sale those are blowout low prices
prices will probably never be lower than
they are right now so grab what you need
now get those Femme seeds get the garden
going
um if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know that I
would love to hear from you the email
address of course is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com the easiest way to
get your grow question on the show is to
send it to the grow help tab at
iregenetics.com or iridirect.com but all
of the feedback questions stuff like
that you can of course send it to the
email address that you've already got
saved there on your computer make sure
you check out the patreon page at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart support the show the patrons do
get Early Access they get warned about
new drops they get told what's coming up
and most importantly they get the best
coupon codes all right everything else
is on the website iregenetics.com
there's a link to the seeds a link to
the Discord come hang out on the Discord
group chat take some dabs with us
um yeah check out the website tune in
tap in that's what all the cool kids say
come hang out with us that's all I've
got you guys I'll be back in another
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy easy057
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you