[Music]
Braxton Jeff you bad [ __ ]
welcome to the show podcast world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 798
of the grow from your heart podcast I've
got a fun show lined up for us in this
episode we're going to give away free
seeds that's right I've teamed up with
our friends at seeds here now.com to
give away free eye regenetic seeds hang
out we'll talk more about those free
seeds later in this episode I do want to
remind you once again that team irie
genetics will be at the dude grows cup
June 3rd just outside of Fort Collins
Colorado I do invite you to join us
comes grab some beans come join the
community come give me a fist bump come
say hi at the dude Groves cup June 3rd
check out dgccup.com for all of the info
to that event also I want to remind you
about the sale at iredirect.com the 420
sale is live it is still going through
the rest of this month that I redirect
there's some new [ __ ] there's some fresh
[ __ ] and there are definitely some
reduced prices so make sure you check
out
iridirect.com before we jump into the
Cannabis part of this podcast I do want
to give a big shout out to my friend
Natalie rise and Rise nation and
everybody and Natalie Rises band uh the
past weekend I got to see Natalie rise I
got to see three concerts and also a VIP
private party where I was treated like a
rock star where I was treated like
family so big shout out to Natalie rise
and the entire rise Nation the rise crew
you guys if you are not already
listening to or following Natalie rise I
highly recommend you put some of that
into your life put some of that energy
into your music go check out Natalie
rise that's enough of that just wanted
to make sure to give them all a great
big shout out and a big fist bump much
love much respect to rise Nation all
right now let's jump into the Cannabis
related part of this podcast I do have a
message here in front of me this one
came from my friend Richard and it goes
a little bit like this it says hello
Rasta Jeff I love the podcast by the way
you have taught this old gorilla grower
so much that goes on it says I do have a
question how can I access the
descriptions of your strains on I
redirect thank you for your
contributions to make the world a better
place you give me hope for more Humanity
alright that is a very good question
also thank you for the compliments on
the hope for the humanity and it's
awesome to know that I've taught an old
gorilla grower a lot of tricks uh thank
you for Learning and listening and
watching now let's talk about this
question the question here is how can I
access the descriptions to your strains
which are available on iridirect that's
a really good question if you go to
iridirect.com to buy seeds you'll notice
there are not a lot of photos there are
not a lot of descriptions there I cannot
put those photos and descriptions on the
sales page that accepts a credit card
the credit card processors do not like
too many details there they just want it
to say a strain name and some seeds and
if it's rag or fam and a price is
basically all the info they want up
there on the page I do have another page
iregenetics.com is my main website where
everything is hosted the Discord is
there the podcast is there
links to all of the strain descriptions
are there on that website so you can go
to iregenetics.com click on genetics
it'll take you to regular or feminized
and you can go and read a lot of details
about the strains there on the website
that is of course a forever evolving
work in progress some strains have not
been updated some have been heavily
updated there's a lot of details there
on iregenetics.com another great option
is to join the Discord and you can find
a Discord link on iregenetics.com
actually hey web guy if you're listening
to this we may need to update the link
on Discord I'm not sure if that link
works it may have expired we may need to
fix that he watches the show this may be
a good way to get him a message and if
not it will remind me when I do some
editing I'm not even going to cut that
out but there is a Discord if you go to
iregenetics.com there will be a link to
the Discord server on that Discord
server there are a lot of photos of the
plants being grown on the left tab if
you scroll down there will be a tab for
every strain that I have put out it'll
start with the rise and it goes all the
way down to whatever the last
alphabetical and what is there are a lot
of strains listed there on the Discord
server those are updated by people
growing those strains that's not just
done by mean by the web guy that is a an
open source a community sourced platform
where everybody growing that strain is
free to go and post their reviews their
pictures their experiences they can ask
questions they can tell you details so
if you want more info my first
recommendation is to check out
iregenetics.com then after that I would
recommend checking out the Discord
server where you can get a lot of extra
information also since we're talking
about it if you go to iregenetics.com
and you notice that one of the strains
listed in the strain section does not
have a high quality photo if you happen
to have a high quality photo of that
strain send me that picture also make
sure to label it so I know which strain
that is send me your name also send me
your social media so I can follow you
stalk you and give you shout outs then
most importantly send me your address so
that I can send you the gift of free
seeds for trading me that picture for my
website it's always great to have high
quality photos up there for advertising
advertising send me your favorite photo
if I do use it I will send you a pack of
seeds if I use it on the website I may
just repost it to social media and give
you credit still may send you seeds but
no promise there if it goes on the
website you'll get a free pack of seeds
all right I've been rambling where was I
we're talking about the descriptions on
iregenetics.com some of those
descriptions will be heavily detailed
some of those will not be as super
detailed some of those are still
evolving I'm still learning about some
of these strains also some of them I
posted a long time ago and forgot to add
descriptions so if you need a
description if there's something I've
forgotten also go ahead and send me a
heads up and I will do my best to update
those strain descriptions on
iregenetics.com
all right this message came from my
friend Richard and this did come from
the grow help tab on iregenetics.com
which means guess what Richard you win a
free pack of seeds that's right on
iregenetics.com on the top there's a
bunch of tabs one of those tabs does say
grow help or grow questions if you click
on there and send me a grow question to
the podcast if I read that question here
on the show you win free seeds and that
free seed giveaway is sponsored by
seedshairnow.com big shout out to the
team at seedshearnow.com for sponsoring
a seed giveaway but my friend Richard
please do send me your address let me
know where to send a free pack of irie
Genetics seeds all right let's keep the
podcast moving I do have plenty of great
questions here in front of me the next
one also came from the grow help
submission tab on iregenetics.com the
name they want to be called is nostos I
think I said that properly
they have a general grow question and
the question goes a lot like this it
says Dear roster Jeff first and foremost
I'd like to take a quick second to thank
you for you and the wonderful Ivory Army
for representing the best of what this
community has to offer bro thank you so
much for noticing thank you for being a
part of the irie Army uh you're a big
part of that just sending me this letter
means you are definitely irie Army it
goes on to say in our current 2023 clown
World filled with inflated Egos and cash
hungry snakes it's beautiful to know it
is beautiful to know that there are
still folks out there who are doing the
good work and humbling themselves daily
for the benefit of others dude I try to
make the best seeds I can and keep them
affordable and grow from my heart and
breed with love so thank you for
noticing exactly that yes there are a
lot of snakes and a lot of clowns out
there
just do my best to avoid them I stay
neutral I stay peaceful and I stay out
of all the [ __ ] keep my head down
and keep working on my growth so thanks
for noticing that part bro it does go on
there is a question it says now my grow
question with a bit of context that
always helps a little bit then it says
let's say hypothetically that someone
was fortunate enough fortunate enough to
snag a pack of the cream which was
cookies and cream to arise a great
strain which has been worked into Big
Mountain fudge cake and we'll continue
that uh project going on anyway it says
it says what if I were to find an
incredible phenotype from this F1 batch
yes that wasn't F1 the cream I made was
an F1 uh what if I find an incredible
phenotype from this F1 that has a strong
pungent Aroma flavor of fresh ginger
with the effects that has one laying on
the floor due to intense OG like stoned
that comes on like a tidal wave bro that
uh what if hypothetically uh sign me up
bro I would hypothetically take two of
those let's turn it into dabs and see
how melted into the floor we can
possibly get
now the message goes on it says let's
hypothetically imagine that this Fino
produced less than a half a dozen seeds
which he labeled S1 with no noticeable
tissue issues of intersex or anthers
during late flower
so this person has grown the cream and
they have produced half a dozen seeds
now when it says with no noticeable
issues of intersex or anthers during
late flower I'm assuming right now that
those plants that the seeds came from
were not showing any noticeable issues
of intersex or anthers during light
flower I don't think we've grown the
seeds to find out what those do until
the next sentence and the next sense we
do that part so we had a cream plant
that did not show any problems but it
did produce half a dozen seeds and this
person labeled those seeds S1 I'm not
sure are those S1 are they F1 are they
R1 or would we label those bag seeds
since I don't know the pollen donor
those seeds in my mind in my world as a
breeder as somebody who puts seeds out
those become bag seed I only know one
parent I only know one part of the
equation so at this point I would not be
comfortable calling it an S1 because I
don't know what pollinated that plant if
it was a self-pollination then possibly
but we don't know that we didn't reverse
anything so there's no way to confirm
that
um it's not an F1 or it could be an F1
if something else pollinated it and we
don't know what else is in the room we
don't know where the pollen could have
came from it definitely could be bag
seed as what I would label this so far I
would label it the cream bag seed is
what it would say on my bag if I had it
with the date on it also now let's go on
to the next sentence and said now fast
forward to the soft seeds being grown
out these s1s which I'm not sure they're
s1s honestly bro these bag seeds happen
to carry the ginger flavor of the aroma
with a nice body Stone so you got some
winners out of there that's pretty cool
that's why I always say grow those bag
seeds you guys you never know what
you've got they could be amazing they
could be trash in this case it looks
like we've got winners so now we move on
to the question if these S1 seeds which
we're still kind of skeptical on that if
these S1 seeds were hypothetically produ
to produce their own set of self-seeds
would these be classified as cream S2 or
cream S1 F2 all right I understand the
question but since we don't know what
pollinated that cream plant
it's hard to put proper labeling onto
these seeds
I want to call it bag seed that's that's
what this is and then you've got like a
bag seed let me see what the did you
self it let's see growing those out uh
if these seeds were hypothetically
produced to produce their own seeds
um you could call those self seeds if
you want to those would be an S2 more
than an S1 F2 that would be an S2 s is
the indication for self so I'm not sure
how I would label these because I
probably wouldn't continue with the bag
seat if if a plant is making seeds on
its own I probably wouldn't continue
that that's not good for a breeder
that's not good for a production grower
this is something I would have gotten
rid of uh probably the second time I
realized it made seeds it would
disappear and I don't know if I would
have gotten this far with the seeds as
you but now we can talk a little bit
about the labeling and how this would
have been labeled let's say
that that cookies that that cream plant
was given pollen that we know it was
given pollen if it was given pollen by a
regular plant a regular male plant that
would make it an F1 that's a new filial
generation it's actually a poly hybrid
but that's a further podcast that I'm
ready to have right now uh so that would
be an F1 if that plant was pollinated by
the same plant if we cut two clones of
that cream plant and pollinated that
plant with the same stuff that would be
self if that plant was pollinated by
anything else that was reversed that is
in R1 that's a reversal so we change the
indication from S1 to R1 because self
gets the s1r gets the reversal
indication that's what I would do then
if we take an S1 so we self-applying you
self it S1 Golden Goat S1 that exists I
took a Golden Goat female and a Golden
Goat female a reversed one made pollen
put it on the girl now I've got Golden
Goat S1 seeds if I were to pull my
favorite Golden Goat phenotype out of
there and repeat the process cut clones
of that one use one as a pollen donor
one is a pollen receiver that would be a
Golden Goat S2 the second self
degeneration so I see what you're asking
and you were correct and you're thinking
that it would be an S1 or an S2 or an F1
or an F2 you're correct with that
thought process but I don't want to
label it that because the original bag
seed is where it came from I would call
it cookies and cream bag seed would be
what it started as that would be its own
brand new thing because I'm not certain
about the pollen donor there is another
part to this question it says
additionally oh this is a whole other a
whole nother category a whole other
Branch off of this question so I think
I've answered the first part
um we've talked about breeding labels
now let's talk about the second part of
this question additionally if you could
pick any land race varietal outside of
the modern OG cookies alien gene pool to
hybridize with the above project and add
more stimulating narrow Leaf uh Buzz to
it what land race would you choose
that's a really good question uh but to
be to be frank honestly I wouldn't read
with this plant because it's producing
seeds and it's going to be problematic
in the future but if I were to breed
with the cookies and cream plant that's
got that lay you on the floor sort of
feeling that you're talking about you
want to put more headbuzz into it
I've got three options because I would
want to see the phenotype that you're
breeding with before I make my decisions
and then I would narrow it down but
sight unseen I would probably pollinate
that plant with a Brazilian plant but
the problem with Brazilian plants uh
they grow wild they get real tall
they're branchy they're out of control
they're just a [ __ ] mess they go
every direction they're not really tame
the Brazilian land races go all over the
place but the buzz that [ __ ] buzz
from a Brazilian plant it gets to your
brain it gets me all wild it gives me
that weird tunnel vision feeling that
would be awesome the next option would
probably be a tie cross it to a tie
because again the tie is going to have a
real psychedelic head Buzz that real
like energetic euphoric sort of mind
[ __ ] sort of thing which I really love
but that tie is going to be so much
easier to grow than the Brazilian it's
going to be more uniform more classic
shaped it's not going to be all over the
place and branchy and stretchy and crazy
uh like that Brazilian another option
um I recently was given a Nigerian Haze
clone which I've only got in veg so far
but that thing is crazy it's vigorous uh
it's got a really nice structure to it
the leaves are beautiful the stem rub
smells good I may consider Crossing it
to that Nigerian Haze once again those
three the Brazilian the Thai and the
Nigerian I know that those have a crazy
psychedelic head buzz those plants have
that kind of buzz that when you smoke it
you get that psychedelic feeling you get
a drum circle going you get the fire
going and next thing you know it's the
next morning and everybody's like it was
a great night hanging out with you and
you're like where did time go I've been
so high that sort of Buzz comes from
those uh Brazilian the Thai the Congo
the Nigerian regions like that will
provide that crazy crazy buzz in my
experience so let's see where we are in
this question
um I probably wouldn't breed with this
but S2 is what I think you would call
that there I would choose Brazilian Thai
or Nigerian to breed with this I've also
got a Congo plant to be fun to breed but
I'm keeping that a little bit on the
down low for a while you guys haven't
seen much of my Congo work yet all right
this message wraps up with thank you for
offering this spot on your website for
those of us who choose to avoid social
media and chat servers I can respect
that a lot of people out there in
prohibition land don't want to be on
Instagram on Discord posted pictures of
their ganja plants when they shouldn't
be growing it at all and I understand
that the chat servers can make you a
little bit paranoid we try to be safe we
do respect the people in prohibition
land but I'm glad you were able to reach
out and ask this great question uh they
wrap it up with love and respect from
your friend from prohibition land
allegedly bro I know you're in
California where it's legal you're just
trying to trick us into not knowing
where you are my buddy nosto's I think
that's how you say that I owe you a pack
of seeds that's right you win a free
pack of seeds because I read your
message here on the podcast once again
that free seed giveaway is sponsored by
our friends at seedshernow.com make sure
you check out seedshairnow.com for
regular feminized Autoflower and photo
period seeds and lightning fast shipping
all right I've got another message here
right in front of me this one came from
our friend Michael and it goes a lot
like this it says hi Ross to Jeff hey
bro it says I am so happy and grateful I
found your show which was recommended in
the depths of a Reddit cannabis AMA that
is awesome big shout out to everybody
out there uh supporting cannabis and of
course supporting irie genetics and the
grow from your heart podcast on Reddit I
did not realize that I had a following
or a ganja Community out there but I'm
glad somebody mentioned my podcast thank
you whoever that was and or is it goes
on it says I really appreciate your
podcast as you knowledgeably convey
expertise that most would take years to
realize if ever well thank you that's a
huge compliment I feel like I've got to
give the this info out if I didn't give
out this if I didn't share my experience
and share this info uh it would be bad
karma or something and it wouldn't work
right so I've got to keep this going for
you it says Google Scholar has a quote
on their website that says stand on the
shoulders of giants and advancing my
cannabis journey and improving my future
grow through your podcast feels very
much like this I appreciate that bro
thank you come along for the journey
um I just have ADD and I read a lot and
I talk a lot so it ends up being a
podcast is really what's happening here
I got a lot of passion for cannabis and
I want you guys to all grow and smoke
and have access to the best ganja in the
world that way whenever I go to a
concert and somebody lights up weed and
passes it to me I can smoke it with
confidence because we spread the good
word and everyone's growing good ganja
all right let me stay focused because
obviously whatever I smoke just [ __ ]
working
but says I am an American living in
Germany oh that sounds interestingly
exciting and Germany may very likely
trial legal cannabis before full-on
legalization for this reason I'm
planning a grow operation for both
medical and recreational and exclusively
on quality my goal is to bring the ethos
of the medical Growers to Europe and
demonstrate in Germany how an indoor
living soil system can shine bro this
sounds like a huge uh awesome project
I'm proud of you and I wish you the best
for this also be safe be careful and
stay legal it sounds like you're doing
it right but well I wish you the best
for this this is hugely ambitious and
I'm proud to be a part of this honestly
I feel like I'm helping you out already
it says I've already done Dr Elaine
Ingram Ingram's soil food web course
which was recommended by our friend Sean
of several hundred episodes ago big
shout out to our buddy Sean and also big
shout out to Dr Elaine Ingram uh Ingham
there's no honor in there I've been
saying it wrong the whole time I just
read it Elaine Ingham anyway it says I'm
currently tackling soil mineral balances
and beneficial insect IPM regimens to go
fully organic that's hugely ambitious as
well and I hope that works for you I am
not the organic grower I find there a
whole set of different problems when it
comes to Growing organically but I'm
sure you've got a good team to help you
figure that out now it does say I'm
working backwards through your podcast
so I apologize if these topics have been
covered already I have about five
questions about your cultivars and
terpenes for you this is going to get
fun you guys I love talking about the
strains I bread Terps are one of my
favorite subjects so this is going to be
good this is a great message oh and also
thank you for listening to the catalog
of podcasts you've got a lot to catch up
on you guys don't ever feel afraid to
ask a question that you feel I may have
answered already because I may have
learned something I may have changed my
opinion technology equipment something
may have changed since the last time I
talked about that so feel free to ask
your question I may give a different
answer I may give a totally more
in-depth answer I may give a shorter
answer and also not everybody listens to
every episode so feel free to ask your
question that you've got don't be
worried about a repeat question I may
answer it I may filter it right on out
let's get to this person's questions it
does say as Germany will be a new market
I'm betting it will likely be initially
flooded with flashy names like gelato
and blue dream or the old school names
like white widow and Jack Herer and
medium quality at best that's probably
going to be accurate you're also going
to have a lot of older folks looking for
uh Panama red and purple haze all the
old Stoner dudes are going to want that
one that's what they all ask for here in
the states goes on though it does say
for this reason I'm seeking to stand out
from the crowd and focusing so heavily
on quality that's a good way to focus
most people are just going to produce as
much as they can and try to get it out
if you produce a top shelf product from
the beginning and maintain that you will
stand out your dispensary your sales
will be top notch let me stay focused
now I can imagine that your cultivars
are your babies and you love them all
equally but differently so which of your
cultivars would you recommend for a
diverse for a diverse city of
experiences
as well as medical applications in a
brand new and uninformed market and why
that's a really good question I like
this this gives me the opportunity to do
a little basic cannabis education and
also pitch a couple of my lines which
will work very well so if you're opening
a dispensary if you want a good menu of
flour uh this goes for anybody around
the world any dispensary I kind of
believe that there are a few key flavors
or ranges that you should keep on the
shelf and those things I wrote them down
here I've got fruit you should always
have fruity stuff a lot of people love
fruity wheat especially the girls the
younger people really like Fruity weed
you should also have gassy weed I like
weed that smells like gas a lot of the
older more experienced seasoned smokers
we have learned that the gassy stuff is
where the good Buzz is and I really like
a good guess the aroma other things you
should have are floral something that
smells like flowers some people really
love a floral smelling cannabis other
things I really like is a hazy cannabis
those are kind of spicier they're going
to have your sandal wood your lavender
sort of smells that's going to come from
the hazes that may also play into the
floral side of things then another thing
I really think you should have is that
cushy and chem sort of Aroma that that
OG cush that chem dog chemical sort of
stuff that's different than the fuel so
those are things that kind of range is
what I think you should start with
fruity gassy floral cushy hazy Kimmy
sort of stuff now let me tell you things
in my lineup that I can recommend from
each of those flavor categories let's
start with the fruit category a lot of
my stuff is really easily labeled to
identify into the fruit category one of
the first I would recommend is
strawberry Starburst it tastes like
strawberries it smells like strawberries
it grows gigantic Buds and it is also
very potent when grown dried and cured
properly it also makes amazing
concentrates so the strawberry Starburst
is one I would recommend then of course
the sun kiss that is platinum Tangy to
arise it tastes like sweet oranges and
once again you're going to get a lot of
good medical benefits from that good fat
Harvest and that one is is super easy to
grow another fruity one that I would
recommend maybe the blueberry butcher
that one's got that blueberry candy
turps and a really serious head Buzz the
next category we're going to work into
is the gassy stuff the gassiest one in
my lineup would be the machine the
machine puts out super gassy Terps uh
you can smell it for miles away and it
grows super easily another one that
would fall into that category is fist
bump fist bump is sour diesel to a rise
that Sour Diesel is super fuely you're
gonna get those feel Aromas and field
Terps out of the fist bump the next one
I wrote down is floral the character
Zero will have floral Terps to it
Scarlet Begonias will have the floral
Terps to it a lot of people really seem
to enjoy that floral Rose lavender sort
of a terp that really gets a lot of
people's attentions the next thing I
talked about was a haze it's going to be
harder to produce a quality Haze in a
commercial environment something like a
Neville's Haze a real good Haze will
take a long time to produce something
like a uh like a silver haze or
something like that if you want that
real hazy flavor something like that
does take a little bit longer to flower
but something like a Super Lemon Haze
will give you that hazy Buzz without the
length of flour those are usually 10 or
11 week flowers which is short for a
haze you guys are saying 10 or 11 weeks
a long Haze can go 16 weeks I I've got
one that takes quite a while I've got
two that take a long time so if I wanted
to recommend a hazy flavor something
that would have that hashy spicy flavor
from my lineup I would say Sunday show
is probably the plant that you're
looking for for that Flavor now let's
move forward the next one is Kush and
Cam that cushy kemi flavor I can't even
describe Kush properly it's swampy it's
funky it's earthy uh it's got some moth
balls and some some funk to it some
dirty foot and then also there's the
chem that falls into this same category
which is similar but just kind of
chemically and kind of just funkier you
have to smell some good OG cushion some
good chem dog to actually I can't even
describe it properly it's that weed that
when when you walk through the concert
and you go that one that's probably a
cush or a Kim you need those sort of
Aromas and flavors that earthiness that
chocolatiness those sort of fall in the
cushy category so things for that uh
category that I would recommend from my
lineup the first one would be something
that is very new that will come out in
May is called Kingston Kush another one
that falls into that category again is
the machine those will both give you a
lot of chemi a lot of cushy sort of
Terps uh you may find some chocolate you
may find some chemicals in there lots of
great flavors and Aromas so I would
start with the fruit the gas the floral
the cushion the chem and then if you can
fit it into the grow I would work some
Haze into their next I would definitely
have something
um that gives people a major major head
bust something to get their heads spin
in and then I would also recommend
something more on the Indica side to get
them sort of chilled out then I may also
recommend something with some CBD in it
I'm not sure the market for CBD in
Germany but here in the states a CBD
product definitely would sell and of
course first the one I would recommend
for you there would be purple heart I'm
not sure how to get you Purple Heart
seeds in Germany but we can do our best
to allegedly make that happen there was
more to this question my friend it says
which of your cultivars would you
recommend to a new breeder to start
breeding unique phenotypes and then it
says you will be credited on all of
these phenotypes
um wow that is a really
um that's a really good question the
first thought was that I don't know that
I would breed with just my stuff because
that kind of locks you in to a trap I've
only made so many things and there are
only so many plants to work with from my
lineup uh that I don't want to
accidentally steer you down the path of
inbreeding and breeding yourself into a
box and not having options so my first
idea would be to pick a male plant or a
female plant I would say pick a male
from my lineup something that's got the
traits you're looking for then I would
pick a female from other breeders
lineups or other several females from
several other breeders that way we can
create diversity
I've only got so many male plants in my
lineup so everything is going to have
Golden Goat in it everything's going to
have a rise in it everything is going to
have either blueberry cookies or BC
Lemon Skunk in it because I've only got
so many options which is fun I could
find a couple of things that are not
related and we could breed those but
then if you wanted to work with anything
else in my lineup you've kind of worked
yourself into a trap because it's
already got most of that [ __ ] in it I
think you understand what I'm saying by
now I did write down some good ideas
though
um I would take one for myself and then
I would take a mail from my stuff I'd
probably pick like a um a Jack Tripper
or a fist bump mail at this time I think
those would both be really fun to find a
good male so the fist bump mail and then
like something fruity from Miss Jill and
then something really Frosty from ethos
and then uh something really candy
flavored from seed junkie and then just
pick something from everybody else out
there something really Frosty and terpy
from exotic
just go find something from every
breeder out there that you enjoy I don't
know who you're into uh breed it to the
Cindy 99 from Mr soul but use my mail
and pollinate a bunch of different
females to create diversity is what I
would do but if it had to be from my
line I would breed the uh I would choose
a fist bump male and I would pollinate a
John Lemon female is what I think I
would do right now I think those would
be really awesome uh you would get a
lemony Sour Diesel Kush Haze combo sort
of a thing that would be all of the
amazing [ __ ] that would have all of the
good stuff that you need and it would
grow vigorously I would taste super dank
and I would have an amazing [ __ ] buzz
and then I would do it the other way
also I do fist bump to John Lemon just
to see what the difference is all right
then there's another question it says
how would you recommend increasing
terpene content as a whole this one I'm
gonna say that I've recently done
multiple podcasts about increasing Terps
it's not just one thing that you can do
to increase terpenes everything has to
be correct the the light has to be right
the air the water the soil the nutrients
the dry backs the Harvest time
especially the dry and cure process
everything has to be perfect to get the
terpenes dialed in you can't just add
one Silver Bullet you can't just do one
thing you've got to get the whole chess
board dialed in and Checkmate that
[ __ ] to get yourself the perfect
terpenes then it says do you know to
increase any particular terpenes yes
um I've noticed that in lemon strains
strains that naturally Produce High
limonene if I get them too close to the
white and give them a little bit of
light stress especially with an HPS that
will heavily increase the limonene
production in plants that naturally
produce limonene so put them a little
too close to the light watch them freak
out a little bit when you smoke them
they're going to be [ __ ] super
tremendously lemony also
um cold a little bit of cold at night
will bring out temperature I don't want
to tell you to go too extreme don't go
more than 10 degrees in your diurnal
difference your day and night swing but
if if you can get it kind of warm during
the day and then a little bit colder at
night that will bring out some flavors I
don't know the science behind that but
in my experience that has been a good
way to bring out some flavors also get
all your nutrients styled in add some
kelp add some carbs carbs and sugars are
definitely going to help with that
flavor so I've already done a full
podcast on getting the flavors and
Aromas but I'll get it all dialed in
feed a lot of carbs a lot of sugars a
little bit of kelp in there and then dry
and cure properly and also it's proper
uh strain selection you have to select
the proper strains for terpene
production all right there is one more
part to this question it says have you
noticed any influence from either
companion plants producing different
soil exudates or if the terpenes and
pheromones of other plants in the room
influence the terpene profile honestly
um I don't grow like this I just grow in
a very sterile grow room environment I'm
not doing living soil I don't use
companion plants uh there are ganja
plants in my room so I don't really have
any useful information on this part here
but I honestly don't have any useful
information on uh if companion plants or
their exudates or their terpenes will
affect the other plants in the room I
really don't know that part I don't have
any science behind that that is above my
pay grade my dude if anybody out there
does have any feedback on that send me a
message I will read the feedback on the
show because that is one part I
definitely do not have a good answer for
they do wrap this message up though it
says also influenced by you I now send
mental hugs to my mom in Texas daily
every time I finish a podcast of yours
I'll feed her Zane bro that is super
cool that I make you think about your
mom that you're sending her a hug every
episode it's almost Mother's Day you
guys by the time this episode comes out
I think we've got like two and a half
two maybe three weeks before Mother's
Day day so heads up Stoners set an alarm
on your phone write it down on the grow
room calendar get Mom a card get Mama
some flowers get that [ __ ] lined up now
you guys because we all know without
Mama there ain't [ __ ] happening all
right and friend Michael don't go for
the great message I do appreciate it
thank you for the great content you gave
me a lot of stuff to read and talk about
here on the podcast
um I cannot send you seeds to Germany
unfortunately however if you do have an
American address I would be more than
happy to send those seeds to you in at
an American address if you think you can
legally receive those seeds in Germany
please do Reach Out explain your method
explain that neither one of us are going
to get in trouble maybe we can help you
out but I'm not comfortable sending to
Germany to be quite honest with you but
I do owe you some sort of a prize if we
can't get you seeds to Germany maybe
I'll send you some t-shirts or something
because I do appreciate the great
content once again thank you my friend
for the great message everybody out
there if you did not get your message
read on today's podcast have no fear
because I've got a lot of messages in
front of me and I plan on doing a lot
more episodes if you want your
opportunity to win a free pack of C
leads all you have to do is go to the
grow help tab on iregenetics.com find
that grow help tab click on there send
me a good question if I read your
question here on the podcast I will send
you a free pack of irie genetic seeds
and once again that free seed giveaway
is sponsored by my friends at seeds here
now.com big shout out to everybody at
seeds herenow.com for keeping everyone
stocked with seeds all right everybody I
think that's all I've got for you for
this episode if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns I would
love to hear from you of course my
direct email address is
growfromyourheart hotmail.com don't be
shy send me that constructive criticism
that positive feedback or if you got
some hate mail send it my way bro I'm
not scared
um what else do we have patreon make
sure you support the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart today I put a bunch of new stuff
on iredirect.com and guess what
everybody on patreon got the very first
heads up there was some stuff that was
very limited and I think it's sold out
through Patron members through patreon
supporters at so sold out before the
civilians even got access to the drop so
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart sign up there get access to Fresh
drops get coupon codes so patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart tap
in is what all the cool kids say get
those coupon codes get access to Fresh
drops come hang out with us
um everything else you could possibly
need once again is on the ire genetics
website go to iregenetics.com there's a
link to get seeds there's a link to the
Discord a link to the patreon anything
you could possibly imagine there's a
link to get irie genetics t-shirts which
are on blowout sale prices that is all
at
iregenetics.com all right that is all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back in a couple of days with fresh
new content I want to give a giant shout
out to my buddy petro and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
[Music]
thank you
hmm