foreign
[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the
podcast everybody I'm your host Rasta
Jeff this is episode
799 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun episode lined up for us
in this episode I'm going to give away
free seeds that's right I've teamed up
with seedshairnow.com to give away free
eye regenetic seeds we're going to talk
more about that later in this episode I
do want to start off by sending a big
thank you shout out to everybody who did
support the 420 sale on iridirect.com
thank you for the support I do
appreciate that of course by the time
this episode comes out the April sale
will be over we are working on a fresh
sale for the month of May there will
also be a fresh drop there are two new
products that will be added to the
website possibly more I know there are
two coming out that you've been waiting
for make sure you check iridirect.com
they will be on the website very soon if
they're not already there by the time
this episode comes out also make sure
you join the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart patreon does get the very first
heads up when seeds drop they get the
first heads up when there are new Sales
New Stock or just things that you might
want to be aware of patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart also don't
forget to sign up for the newsletter or
the mailing list you can sign up for
that at iregenetics.com simply scroll
down to the bottom of the page there's a
little tab that looks like an envelope
it says stay tuned or stay up to date
type in your email address that will add
you to the mailing list when I do new
drops or promotions or updates to the
website I do send out updates to the
mailing list of course patreon does get
that first update but it will go patreon
then the mailing list then after that
it's Discord then I go to the social
medias But be sure to join the mailing
list or the patreon campaign so you
don't miss the fresh drops at
iridirect.com
speaking of fresh drops I will be at the
dude Groves cup June 3rd in Fort Collins
that's right the friend our friends at
the dude grow show are throwing the dude
Groves cup once again just outside of
Fort Collins team irie genetics will be
there we'll have a bunch of fresh new
products with us a bunch of the familiar
stuff a bunch of new stuff a bunch of
regular a bunch of feminized things that
I think you will really enjoy so come
join us at the dude grows cup just
outside of Fort Collins on June 3rd make
sure you check out dgccup.com for all of
that information all right I feel like
we've covered all of the business part
here at the start of the podcast I do
have something I kind of want to segue
into I'm not sure if you pay attention
to the news but recently A man was
executed in Singapore for possession of
2.2 pounds of cannabis that's right A
man was executed for cannabis I don't
believe that that is right I don't
believe that that is fair I think that
that is wrong I think that's terrible uh
being somebody who promotes Advocates
supports and thoroughly enjoys cannabis
this is [ __ ] heartbreaking to hear
that somebody was put to death for
possession of an herb that causes no
harm in my opinion or experience and
makes people feel better in a
recreational and a medical way this
person is gone they had children they
had a family and this person is gone the
government in their country decided that
they needed to kill this person for
cannabis that is [ __ ] crazy to me now
another thing I want to add to this and
you'll see how they connect in just a
moment is I was talking to a friend who
was recently traveling around the world
and they went to Australia and they
found themselves in Australia smoking a
little bit of pot in front of a bar
somebody walked up to them and said hey
mate I'm not sure they said hey mate but
they're Australian so they probably did
they said hey mate you can't smoke that
the cops are already on the way looking
for you they smelled it down the street
and my friend said you can't just smoke
a joint in front of a bar here and they
said no you will go straight to jail for
having cannabis with you here so you've
got to get rid of that you've got to
hide you've got to get rid of the smell
so my friend had to get rid of his
cannabis he had to get rid of the
Cannabis he was smoking he had to get
rid of his stash and his success series
he had to go somewhere make sure he
didn't smell like cannabis because they
were looking for this person where I am
headed with this you guys
I'm here in Colorado my friend was from
Colorado uh don't forget sometimes that
it is not all Colorado it is not safe to
travel everywhere with cannabis it is
not safe to consume cannabis openly
everywhere you've got to keep your heads
up you've got to learn about the rules
the laws the regulations before you go
somewhere and find out what type of risk
you're putting yourself in if you do
travel with cannabis or consume or
acquire cannabis in a foreign or Strange
Land it could be a different state if
I'm going to a different state I do
research before I go there can I take
cannabis what happens if I do take
cannabis what happens if I take
concentrates what kind of trouble am I
going to get into if I get caught with a
couple of joints what kind of trouble do
I get into if I get caught with a couple
grams of cannabis what kind of trouble
do I get into for traveling with it I do
all of that research if I'm going to a
state next to me a few States over if
I'm flying somewhere I think about all
of that stuff before I travel do extra
research on that if you are traveling
abroad going to another country with
different laws rules and regulations
whatever you you think works here may
not work there things are different in
other countries and once you're in their
country you are under their laws you've
got to follow their laws you may be a
privileged person here you may not fit a
certain criteria here where you're going
to get searched and hassled in another
country you're probably exactly who
they're going to search and hassle so my
point of this is somebody has been
executed for cannabis in another country
a person I know was almost arrested and
given a really hard time for consuming
cannabis just a little tiny bit of
cannabis outside of a bar in Australia
my point here is be very careful you
guys I don't want you to get put in a
foreign jail where we'll never hear from
you again dude they're going to feed you
terrible food and treat you like [ __ ]
forever because you're An American in a
foreign prison in a foreign jail good
luck with that and I definitely don't
want you executed for enjoying our
favorite plant don't be a statistic in
another country I know it's fun to smoke
it's fun to get high and enter at your
own risk but I'm saying understand the
risk and be as careful as possible all
right that's enough of the news talk I
wanted to cover today let's segue into
the cannabis cultivation and cannabis
questions portion of this podcast I do
have a lot of great questions that I do
want to answer this question that I'm
about to read did come from did come
from the grow help tab on
iregenetics.com that was harder to say
than it looked if you go to
iregenetics.com there's a row of tabs on
the top one of them says questions or
grow help if you click on that tab
you'll be given the opportunity to fill
it to fill out a questionnaire asking
about your garden then at the end you
are given the opportunity to ask a grow
question
this grow question came from our friend
Paulie two fingers said what kind of
question do you have it is a general
grow question the question from Polly
two fingers goes a lot like this it says
what's up Ross to Jeff what's up Polly
good to meet you bro it says I love your
podcast thank you Brooks I love you too
it says seriously it is one of the best
for real knowledge I appreciate that
thank you it says not just Bro Science
some of it is Bro Science but it's also
I've got a lot of experience so I feel
like I can talk from experience I read a
lot and then there is some Bro Science
mixed in it says it's actually quite
quality info thank you brother I do
appreciate that I try hard to give you
real reliable accurate info I feel like
you guys are gonna use the advice that I
give you in your garden and I would feel
like a real uh a terrible person if you
messed up your garden based on the
advice that I give you
um I'm I try to be better than that so
it goes on it says my question is this
this is a really good question here also
why why oh why does my pH drift in my
reservoir that's a really good very
common question and I've got a good
logical explanation but let's go a
little further I did say explanation on
purpose just so you know you're paying
attention oh it says I've heard it will
go down if there is a bacteria but mine
wants to rise slowly as days go by I'm
using fluorflex nutrients they are salt
based and I run a sterile system they
claim their nutrients are stable for
weeks I'm just curious if you have any
good info on this issue I've not heard
anyone tackle this issue and I feel like
this pH drifting will affect my final
product it will it goes on it says I'm
looking at getting a blue lab pH
controller with the pump to keep it
dialed in any help is greatly
appreciated from your friend Polly to
fingers Polly I've got a really great
really logical really rational
explanation for what I think is
happening here in your grow why your pH
is rising this could be a reservoir for
Hydroponics this could be a reservoir
for an auto watering system it could be
an Evan ebb and flow table it could be a
drain to waste table I don't know
exactly what you've got set up but I
imagine a large Reservoir
um and from that Reservoir water will be
pumped out of that into your plants
um over time there will be evaporation
right the water the water is going to
evaporate from that vessel from your
Reservoir so the water level is going to
go down but as that water evaporates
guess what happens the salts from your
bottled nutrients do not evaporate so
they're becoming more concentrated
you'll also notice if you measure the pH
or the EC it is probably slightly Rising
as well because water has evaporated and
none of the salts that you have added to
that water are leaving they're solids
they're not leaving so the water is up
in the air now it's up in there is vapor
it's becoming clouds it's becoming rain
it's becoming humidity it's a problem in
the grow maybe it sucked right back up
into the dehumidifier but those
nutrients are still right there in your
Reservoir so you've got less water they
might be very minute difference amount
of water but it can make a big
difference in the pH in the EC so you
got a little bit less water and you
haven't reduced the amount of salts so
that's going to make the EC go up and
the the pH are going up because it
doesn't seem like you're losing a lot of
water but over a couple of days you're
probably evaporating a little bit of
water especially if you've got bubbles
in there because the bubbles are adding
a lot of oxygen to that and putting the
uh the water into the air and giving it
more opportunity to become a vapor and
humidity into the room so what I really
think is happening here is just the
water is evaporating it's making your pH
rise because there's still salts
remaining there's less water the ratio
has changed that's throwing off your pH
the way to fix that is just keep monitor
monitoring that pH and if it gets lower
out of your range add a little bit of
water and that water should bring the PH
down right where you wanted it you may
need to add a little bit of pH Down that
may also be the solution maybe consider
checking the EC or the ppms while you're
doing this they may need to be adjusted
as well all right my friend Polly two
fingers I feel like I've answered your
question thank you for the great
question here's the best part my dude
since I read your question here on the
podcast that means you in a free three
pack of irie genetic seeds and those
seeds are sponsored by our friends at
seedsherenow.com so please Paulie Polly
two fingers please send me your shipping
address and a real name to put on the
box I can't put Polly two fingers on
there the post office will make a funny
face when they receive that box so send
me your real name or at least a good
name to ship a package to and an address
and I will happily get you a free pack
of irie genetic seeds that's right
everybody if I read your message here on
the podcast that means that you win a
free pack of seeds to get your message
here on the podcast once again go to
that grow help tab on iregenetics.com
there's a tab that says grow help or
grow questions send me your question
through that tab if I read it here on
the show you in a free pack of irie
genetic seeds and of course if you have
sent a message and I have not read it
here on the podcast do not feel
discouraged I've got a lot of messages
here in front of me I've got a big stack
of messages in the office I am trying to
work my way through the pile there in no
particular order I kind of give them a
proofread and say this show next show
this show next show that's far as I go
let's stay focused because I've got
another one for this show the next
message on this episode came from our
friend Dave Skylark big shout out to my
buddy Dave Skylark thank you for the
great message this one did come from the
grow help tab so my buddy Dave you do
want a free pack of irie genetic seeds
sponsored by our friends at
seedsherenow.com please do send me your
mailing address I'd be happy to send you
out a package of seeds this question
goes a lot like this it says yo Ross to
Jeff I hope you are doing amazing I feel
like I'm doing quite well bro thank you
for asking says I definitely look
forward to testing out the many strains
you offer I am a huge sativa fan oh
you're definitely going to enjoy my
products if you like sativas I like that
head reckon head tripping Buzz uh if I
if I can walk into Target and not have a
panic attack I did not get high enough
before we went into Target I need to go
take a couple of more dabs but let's
stay focused which is hard for me today
it says I'm just curious what are your
thoughts on Predator bugs versus
chemical or organic sprays for when
pests show up possibly indoors I haven't
ran into pests yet but it's best to be
prepared yes because now that you've
said you have not ran into pests guess
what
they're coming you've invited them by
saying that
goes on it says I would love to hear
this on an episode of the podcast well
here you go bro it is on the podcast it
is happening bro uh it wraps it up with
thank you so much my buddy Dave Skylark
thank you so much for the great question
this is a very good question uh how do I
feel about Predator bugs versus chemical
or organic sprays uh indoors I actually
use a combination of sprayed pesticide
applications and Predator insects in a
commercial grow environment I don't do
it as much in a personal grow because
there's not as much uh as much at stake
in a personal grow in a in a commercial
grow there are millions of dollars at
risk at stake per Harvest and a personal
grow it's not as much and the the
Predator bugs get a little bit expensive
the budget is better for the commercial
grow it's more worth it more worthwhile
let me delve into what I'm talking about
here in a commercial grow I like to
start with spray applications just basic
sprays uh evergreen or um what's the
other one that I like to use in the
commercial girl evergreen's my favorite
go-to most of the time for preventative
I probably talk about that that one a
lot azitrol I think is still allowed in
the commercial girl environment venerate
is still allowed I like to use products
like that as just a basic and a rotation
for my basic integrated Pest management
system and we're going to talk a lot
about Pest Management and another future
episode I'm going to do a full episode
about it but I like to spray those
products through veg I like to spray
those products right at the beginning of
flower but as soon as I have flower
formations I don't want to apply any
more sprayed pesticides I don't want to
mess up the flowers in any way I don't
want to slow down their growth I don't
want to mess up the flavor I don't want
to do any damage to those flowers once
they start developing I just want big
fat healthy flower clusters so I need
some way to stop bugs from attacking
that grow once I stop using those spray
applications because some of the grows
that I work with in the Colorado area
they're in the middle of basically the
middle of the desert and there are bugs
out there and there are bushes out there
and we can't we can only do so much to
the outside environment and the building
is only so sealed so bugs are able to
get in so I've got to do do things to
make sure they cannot get to my plants
so once I have hit the threshold that I
feel like my plants are too beefy and
too chunky to apply a spray pesticide
that is when I begin to release large
batches of predator and sex there's a
very large variety of Predator insects
you can release in a cultivation
facility to eliminate bugs eradicate
bugs keep bugs at Bay you can get rid of
almost any insect with other insects you
just may have to be aggressive about it
it's all about a numbers game also just
like pesticides it's just as important
when I use a pesticide my first question
is what bugs are we trying to attack
what pest is coming what am I spraying
for because if you're fighting guys with
AK-47s you don't want to send in karate
guys that's not going to work you've got
to send in guys with [ __ ] missile
launchers to take them out you've got to
know what you're battling so that you
can win the same thing applies for
attacking a pest problem with another
pest you need the appropriate pest so
you have to do your research on that
part also so it is very environmental
and regionally dependent some past some
of your Predator bugs will not stick
around if your humidity is too high or
too low some of the Predators will not
stick around if the temperature is too
high or too low so you've got to find
the bugs that work for your environment
and attack the pest you are trying to
eradicate now to some people it may
sound crazy that I'm going to apply
sprays and then release bugs but I'm
going to time it properly I'm going to
spray all the way up to about day 10 of
flour and then I'm going to stop
spraying then we're going to do a heavy
defoliation one last time and we're
going to order the insects the bugs will
show up about day 14 or 15 then we'll
release all of those bugs by this time
all the sprayed pesticide applications
have broken down they've been broken
down by the Light by the wind and they
are no longer going to be a problem for
the incoming Predator bugs so I will
spray all through veg once or twice a
week if I see I spray once a week no
matter what and if I see a problem we
step it up we spray twice a week if I
still see problem then I really need to
step my [ __ ] up because I am failing
twice a week should get the job done no
matter what bugs I'm facing then I will
taper off the sprays if I don't see any
problems as we go into flour taper off
the sprays do another defoliation and
release the Predator bugs those bugs are
going to work like an army like security
guards they're going to get in there
hungry when they come in the mail they
are hungry bro when those bugs show up
they are ready to [ __ ] go so release
those strategically spread them out
through the canopy if you've got a hot
spot of bugs you're trying to get rid of
focus some of your bugs on that hot spot
and get rid of those bugs they will come
in they will start eating the [ __ ] out
of the bad guys they will take over they
will colonize and then once all of your
pests are gone basically all of your
good bugs will die too if they don't
have a food source you can feed them if
you like or you can let them dwindle off
and die a lot of times if we have extra
bugs from the flower rooms I will go put
some of those in the mom room because I
do believe that the mother room is where
it all starts if you don't have healthy
moms you can't have healthy clothes then
you can't have healthy veg you'll never
have healthy flour so I'll go spread
some of those in the mom room just to
give that Mom room a little bonus get
some Predator bugs in there and that way
they're already started they're
colonizing in there and we can move them
around yes perhaps a lot of them are
going to get destroyed by pesticide
applications in the future but they're
like little backup Guardians for the
time that they do survive all right my
friend Dave Skylark thank you for the
great question I do appreciate it my
method use those sprayed applications
right up till the last minute then
switch to those bugs if you do want to
use bugs the whole way let me talk about
that you definitely can use predator
bugs the entire time through the grow
side through the growth cycle if you
don't want to add spray applications and
there are some spray applications that
will not harm beneficial insects they'll
keep some of your uh your beneficial
Predator bugs around you do need to do
the research on that if you're going to
spray something read will it kill
hypoaspy Smiles will it kill Green Lace
Wings see because some of your
applications are only going to kill the
insects that bite into the leaf and some
of these guys don't bite into the leaf
they just crawl around on it so you may
be able to spray some applications even
after you do release the Predators once
again you'll have to do your research
for specific predators and specific
sprays but you definitely can use the
Predator bugs through the entire
duration of the grow once again I will
list off some more because I think I
went through them quite quickly a moment
ago there is the California kiss or the
Swarovski the hypoaspis miles the Green
Lace wings
um there's another one that I just
cannot think of right now that is
voracious
um yeah the minute pirate bug is
definitely a hungry little bastard I
like the green lacewing eggs they come
on little cards they hatch and they turn
into these little uh it looks like a
little microscopic crocodile those guys
are hungry as [ __ ] they will eat the
[ __ ] out of all of the bugs in your
garden I recommend not to waste your
time with ladybugs a lot of people are
going to say just buy ladybugs and
release those nah bro ladybugs are
[ __ ] lazy compared to more aggressive
bugs there are much more aggressive
Predators out there if you're going to
pay money you want to get the good get
the aggressive bugs the bugs I mentioned
before and also ladybugs for every
thousand ladybugs you release I think
500 of them fly into the lights into the
ducting into the blowers and get they're
suicidal they Kamikaze themselves right
the [ __ ] away the ladybugs are really
cool for about 30 minutes you get them
in there take a bunch of photos oh
ladybugs cool they're everywhere and
then the next day it smells like [ __ ]
because they stink so bad you walk into
the grill and it sounds like you're
walking on crunchy popcorn because
there's dead ladybugs on the floor and
they're just you're just busting them I
don't like the ladybugs I think I made
my point on that I'm Ross to Jeff and I
vote no on ladybugs and the grow use a
more aggressive Predator that's my
stance on [ __ ] all right where are we on
time I think we've got time for one more
question here also did I say this
already my dude Dave Skylark yes I said
this please do reach out because I owe
you a free pack of irie Genetics seeds
all right this next message once again
came from the contact form submission on
I redirect this one came from our friend
Greg big shout out to my buddy Greg I
don't know if you want your full name
set here buddy you wrote your full name
I'm just gonna call you Greg today big
shout out to my buddy Greg Greg says I
want to know what strains you have that
are powdery mildew resistant that is a
really good question a lot of people are
going to be growing Outdoors this year a
lot of people on the coastal areas are
always looking for that mold and mildew
resistant strain a lot of people have
been asking me this lately because they
are going outdoors I have got some
recommendations for you have no fear
roster Jeff has got answers one of the
strains I can recommend to you that has
been proven to be very resistant to
powdery mildew in indoor and outdoor
environments is Morning Dew Morning Dew
is one of my favorite strains that is a
Grateful Dog pollinated by an arise
plant I made both of those plants and
then I bred them together so that is one
of my favorite Creations the morning do
makes a kind of a skunky chemically
cushy sort of Aromas and flavors with a
really nice Buzz so that one is Morning
Dew that one is going to be very powdery
mildew resistant the next one is
character Zero character Zero is an
Afterglow cross a lot of the Afterglow
crosses that I made um about a year ago
those crosses are all very powdery
mildew resistant but some of the
standout crosses in that lineup were the
character Zero and the Sunday show those
are both very powdery mildew resistant
those both have a very specific very
special plant in there which is a
Nigerian cross two and Afghani cross to
a Nepali while I'm surprised and glad
that I remembered all of that and
everything that comes from that plant
that is crossed to that plant does make
very powdery mildew resistant plants so
that plant was crossed to the Afterglow
that CR that plant was also crossed to
the Fire OG and then crossed to the
Afterglow both of those Offspring create
very powdery mildew resistant plants and
once again those are the character Zero
and Sunday show I've got one more for
you that we're going to talk about here
that is very powdery mildew resistant
and that one is called fist bomb fist
bump is sour diesel to arise
that one is super stinky it's got a
super Sour Diesel chemical Dirty Feet
sort of a funky thing to it and the buzz
on it is amazing it'll make your eyes
nice and heavy make you nice and
red-eyed give you that old school
cottonmouth and the flavor is just right
so some options for powdery mildew
resistant strains from my lineup I would
say Morning Dew Morning Dew is regular
seeds by the way male female seeds uh
the character Zero and Sunday show are
two more recommendations those are
feminized seeds and my final
recommendation for you was fist bump and
that is regular seeds uh my friend Greg
I do thank you for the great question I
hope I answered your question thoroughly
of course I do owe you a free pack of
irie genetic seeds so please send me
your address so I can get you a pack of
powdery mildew resistant seeds for your
garden all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters and pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts and activists out there I do
want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns you know that I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy once again if you need grow help if
you have Garden questions please do
reach out go to iregenetics.com scroll
down to that grow help tab type in your
grow questions just like you saw today
if I read your grow question on an
upcoming episode that means that you to
win free seeds and I will send those
right to you that is sponsored by our
friends at seeds here
now.com uh make sure you check out the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart of course the
patreon members at the 4.20 level do get
the first notification of new drops and
new updates on iridirect.com so make
sure you check out the patreon campaign
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart everything else you could
possibly imagine or possibly need from
me will be on my website at
iregenetics.com there's a link to the
there's a new and updated link to the
Discord server big shout out to the web
guy for fixing that for us guys if
you've been trying to get to the Discord
server and that link did not work please
try again go to iregenetics.com click on
that Discord server tab hey Ross to Jeff
while you're editing this go fix that
tab on linktree also I'm not going to
edit that out but I need to fix my own
link tree link because I think the
Discord link is dead there also guys
come join us on Discord it would be
great to see you uh there is a link to
get this seeds there's a link to
merchandise there's a link to the
podcast everything you can imagine once
again is on
irigenetics.com all right I think that
is all I've got for you for this episode
I'll be back next week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy the real Mick Blunts and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you