yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 80 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new SM ER or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host rosta Jeff thanks
again for joining me as always you guys
I need to send a huge thank you shout
out to the Mystic Roots band for letting
me use their music on the show right now
you're listening to the doggy dub off
the album the constant TR struggle big
shout out to cat C and the entire Mystic
Roots crew I'm going to turn down that
music before we get too far this podcast
is brought to you by my friends at hro
indoor growing supplies H gr indoor
growing supplies has two locations to
serve Colorado make sure you check out
the Denver store it's uh 6271 Beach
Street or the P location on 618 East 4th
Street in beautiful peblo Colorado check
out high grow for competitive pricing
and a great selection of indoor growth
supplies get your favorite nutrients at
H gr indoor growing supplies a grow
store ran by folks who grow check this
out you guys when you go to High gr
indoor growing supplies let them know
that you listen to The Grow from your
heart podcast and they will give you
your entire purchase at commercial
pricing which is a huge saving so let
them know you listen to the podcast
support a local business I would really
appreciate that so big shout out to Hy
gr for sponsoring the show if you guys
are interested in sponsoring the podcast
send me an email I'll get you all the
information you need it's grow fromy
heart at
hotmail.com all right I'm going to turn
down that music there we go there we go
it's a little better how you guys doing
today I got a bunch of news articles for
you uh before we get to the news
articles I want to talk about something
that I watched this weekend uh I didn't
get get to go but I definitely uh jumped
on the internet and saw some replays The
Grateful Dead did some shows in Santa
Clara this weekend anybody that knows me
knows that I'm a huge Grateful Dead fan
uh The Grateful Dead has a lot to do
with who I am and why I am who I am and
what I
am uh I've been a Grateful Dead fan I've
been a Jerry Garcia fan I've been a
Jamrock fan since uh the early 90s
probably 93 no I'm going to say 95 cuz I
moved here late '94 or early '94
whatever but anyway my first fish show
was $69.95 so I've been listening to the
Dead uh fish all of that stuff heavily
heavily since 95 I did a whole bunch of
fish shows uh me and my best friend Rob
the dude did a whole bunch of Widespread
Panic shows one summer uh summer tour
2001 uh we did about 20 shows that was
pretty epic so uh The Grateful Dead is a
huge part of why I am who I am uh I
learned a lot of things on fish tour
lots and uh further Festival parking
lots and what have you so I watched
these uh so the Grateful Dead go back
together and of course Jerry Garcia is
no longer with us he's been gone for
several years now uh so filling in Jerry
shoes was Trey from fish which you would
think that's like most of fish and
Grateful Dead F biggest wet dream but it
almost it was so overhyped and so big
that it just seemed weird to me it
seemed like a big commercial thing it
seemed right Trey was the dude to choose
but it was almost it put up so much hype
and so much expectation and so pressure
that it was just weird so watching the I
didn't I didn't go to the shows uh I
should have gone but that was it's hella
expensive I got a lot of
responsibilities I didn't feel like it'd
be right to go take a week off to go to
some shows right now uh but I did watch
them online it's the first two shows
that they've done uh these guys have
never done a show together so it's the
first two shows they've done in public
and they've got three more shows coming
up over the Fourth of July
weekend I was totally satisfied with
what I saw but it seemed really weird
watching it it was like watching A
Grateful Dead cover band do Grateful
Dead songs they didn't feel natural they
didn't flow something wasn't meshing uh
there's not a leader to that band is
something that I think I noticed uh that
band doesn't have a solid leader um
bobb's trying to lead the band but it
doesn't seem like he's able to get
control because no one wants to listen
to him uh Trey seems timid he doesn't
want to let loose and solo like he
should but by the end of the show it
felt like everything was right but that
was the end of the second show and that
was the end of the weekend and
everything was wrapping up so I'm hoping
that by the time they get to the Chicago
venue uh By the time this show comes out
they will be in Chicago and they will be
setting up uh they may have already even
played I'm not sure if this will come
out on Thursday or Monday we'll see how
things go but I hope I can get it out
for you by Thursday so uh yeah the
Grateful Dead they've got some
improvement to do hopefully they talk
about what didn't work while they're on
the road and then they figure it out by
the weekend I'm thinking that they saved
up the better songs that they practiced
for not I'm not saying the set list over
this weekend wasn't amazing all of the
songs were great but I'm hoping that
they saved up some of the more uh Trey
didn't sing but for one song this whole
weekend so I'm hoping they uh got more
Trey songs lined up for the Chicago
shows I'm hoping that we get to hear
terpin station with trayon vocals um
there are several that I would like to
hear Trey sing so I'm probably boring
the hell out of a lot of my fans with my
Grateful Dead talk a lot of people
listening but the Greatful Dead's a big
part of who I am so I really wanted to
talk about that the Greatful Dead
they're going to Chicago over the 4th of
July weekend check that [ __ ] out that'll
be really neat uh so my next uh topic I
have a friend named uh his name is Tim
and he actually has a company that sells
a product called a torchless nail and is
a torchless dab nail and I've been very
curious about this product so uh Tim was
passing through Tim does not live in
Colorado he lives in another state but
he was passing through my town and he
was kind enough uh I always in Tim if
you're passing through dude you're
always invited here to come take some
Dabs at my house even if you don't have
cool toys with you even if you don't
have top shelf extracts with you you're
always welcome uh I did not purchase one
at this time but I will in the future um
it's not something that's in my budget
or my need right now but when I'm ready
for it I'm going to grab one of these
things it's called the torchless
Nail uh it is a dab nail that attaches
to any rig that is basically B
operated um so you it's got a battery
pack the battery pack is kind of big and
kind of cumbersome to be honest with you
it's the size of a remote control but it
is heavier than a remote control uh if
you used to drive RC cars it's like an
old RC car battery is what it reminds me
of so you plug in this thing has a
plugin that comes undone so you don't
always have to have a cord hanging from
it but you plug it in it charges then
the coil attaches to it and then the
coil attaches to a bowl piece which fits
onto your bong or your rig or whatever
you want to call it whatever you're
using uh it attaches to your glass piece
then the battery pack has a button when
you hold the button uh that heats up an
element inside of the bowl piece that
makes your hash uh your shatter you know
what we tried on it was shatter and
butter and wax I did not try solventless
I did not try uh the I didn't try
anything else so I only know how this
works for Shatter wax and some buttery
type hash so we put plenty and you can
stuff this thing with plenty of hash too
we put a lot of hash on there like
probably a half a gram and then you push
the button and hold the button and as
soon as you push it the hash starts
melting it takes like it's very little
DeLay So you start token and you once
you start getting smoke into your lungs
once you start feeling it then I started
kind of Feathering the button just like
Let It Go hold it let it go hold it let
it go hold it because I like to take a
big chunky dab but what I noticed is as
soon as you let go of the button it
stops cooking like it as soon as you let
go so you can really control your dabs
it is kind of nice now the part that I
was concerned with and it did pass my
inspection let me say that before I go
too far the part that I was concerned
with is we've got a wire that goes to a
bowl and uh that bowl is heating
something inside of the bowl where I'm
keeping my extracts I was worried about
heating polyurethane wiring or whatever
was inside of that bowl so my friend Tim
gave me the Liberty to take this piece
apart and inspect it completely so
inside of there it's a glass bowl it
looks kind of like your normal bong bowl
or if you've got a health stone pipe
it's very similar to that it's a glass
bowl with basically a titanium screen
inside of it and wrapped around that
titanium screen is and we weren't sure
if it was copper or brass but wrapped
around that titanium screen is a copper
or brass coil it almost looks uh it
almost looks like an alligator clip or a
battery clip for your car like where
your car battery goes in it almost looks
like that wrapped around a titanium disc
placed inside of a glass bowl so as soon
as you press the button that that copper
or brass uh element essentially heats up
around that titanium disc because of the
electricity flowing through it it heats
up and that's what melts your dabs and
then as soon as you let go of it you can
touch the glass and it's not hot you can
hold the glass while you take your dabs
and it won't burn you so
if you were to maybe think about dabbing
in the car on the road and you didn't
want to use the torch this device would
be perfect uh you just push a little
button and you inhale and you get pretty
healthy pretty chunky rips uh I have to
say the torchless nail is rosta Jeff
approved I'm going to give it at least a
solid four stars if I could play with it
again I would give it five full Stars
I've never done a real full rating test
or anything you know what I mean we
don't have a rating scale but on a scale
of 1 to five I'm going to give it a
solid four and then if I get to play
with it a couple more times and learn
the button Feathering the technique how
much to push and let go that sucker just
might get five stars you know I want to
compare it I want to take my normal rig
with me for a day and take the torchless
nail with me for a day and see which one
I end up hitting on the second day like
day one maybe I'll get tired of torching
maybe day two or day one I'll get tired
of pushing the button and just see which
one I like better but that's enough
ranting about the torchless nail uh if
you're interested in a torchless nail
let me know I will put you in touch with
my friend who distributes them we'll try
to get you the best deal possible since
I just advertised them very well on the
podcast for him let me say this he did
not pay me to say any of this he brought
the nail to be kind to let me check it
out because I told him I was curious
about the inside so big shout out to Tim
if you're listening uh thanks for
bringing that big shout out to Zach
happy late birthday bro but I hope
everything's going well for you so let's
get into some news articles you guys um
on two podcasts ago our buddy Mike was
here and we talked about a raid a raid
where the police officers uh used a
battering ram to bash in the door of a
dispensary that the dispensary was open
and the door was unlocked then they
proceeded to treat all of the customers
uh like criminals when nobody was
committing a crime they were actually
there to serve a cease and assist order
is what they should have done but
instead they went in uh they treated
every like criminals they destroyed most
of the dispensary oh excuse me I'm
burping uh the these cops were complete
[ __ ] what I thought they did was
completely disrespectful and apparently
some other people did too because there
is a news article uh this news article
comes from abc7.com I found this on a
lot of different places but uh this
article was the best written and the
most understandable and it kept to the
point the most and it mentioned some
things that a couple other articles did
not
mention EXC excuse my coughing I'm going
to get into the news article here right
after I take a quick drink and then we
will get into
it oh that was a long drink but [ __ ]
yeah it was worth
it all right this news article comes
from abc7.com and it is written by a man
named Greg Lee this article was posted
June 15th 2015 it says Long Beach
California a lawsuit was filed Monday by
attorney Matthew Papas on half of
Skyhigh holistic accusing Santa Ana
Police Department the city of Santa Ana
and Santa Ana mayor Miguel pulo of
taking bribes from marijuana
dispensaries in exchange for favorable
treatment this following a controversial
police raid at the marijuana dispensary
on May 26th that was caught on
surveillance video and shows police
playing darts an officer making
demeaning remarks about an amput and
another officer eating what appears to
be pot laced Edibles you guys if you
listen to the podcast we watched the
video last time and I'm 90% sure that
that dude ate an edible right off of the
Shelf two cops ate Edibles right off the
shelves I'll continue with the article
it says it's deplorable that City
officials and people seeking financial
gain would use the police to accomplish
their self-serving goals Papa said at a
news conference in Long Beach Papas
outlined the lawsuit he filed in federal
court the suit alleges that podo and
other city employees favored certain
dispensaries over others the city of
Santa Ana used a lottery system to
select 20 pot shops to operate legally
under a new voter approved plan the
lawsuit alleges that at least one
dispensary which paid PLO was selected
so this dispensary paid for their
[ __ ] spot in the lottery which is
shitty and this dude allegedly allegedly
I have to use the word allegedly this
dude allegedly took the damn
money the article goes on Skyhigh
holistic did not win a spot in the
lottery and its patients alleged that
because PLO and other city employees had
Financial ties with competing marijuana
dispensaries they Ed their positions to
close down the competition including
including shutting down power and water
surfaces the suit said Pap has released
an edited surveillance video last week
showing what the lawsuit describes as
excessive and unreasonable actions by
police officers during the raid and I
will agree with both of those statements
excessive and
unreasonable uh the suit said that uh
the suit said officers cost more than
$100,000 to video surveillance equipment
safes Furniture doors and other property
an internal investigation by the Santa
Ana Police Department is ongoing retired
la uh LAPD deputy chief Steven Downing
echoed at echu the accusations at the
news conference Monday police officer
should not behave that way it was
unprofessional Downing said PLO released
the released the video statement Monday
afternoon in response to the lawsuit
these allegations are unequivocally
false and the city will be responding to
this lawsuit he also said he has no
financial interest or stake in any
dispensary this article was from the
associated the Associated Press did
contribute to this article I have to
mention that part at the end so they are
suing they are going to file a lawsuit
they have filed a lawsuit against the uh
cops that did this [ __ ] so hopefully
they don't get away with this hopefully
this uh sets a new standard you know
maybe this will make a
difference and we can't have cops
raiding places and eating Edibles so
they did over a
$100,000 in damage I hope they sue these
guys for what like three or four times
that because you're going to have to fix
it and then you're going to have to
recoup your losses you're going to have
to uh catch up from all the business
that you missed yeah I hope they sue
them for at least three or four times
this part all right I'm going to move on
to another news article here which one
is
next all right here we go this one is
from oh right here at home the peblo
chieftain this one says uh Colorado
workers can be fired for using pot off
duty uh this article is from Denver it's
written by Kristen Wyatt of the
Associated Press it says pot may be
legal in Colorado but you can still be
fired for using it the state Supreme
Court ruled 5 to1 Monday that a medical
marijuana patient who was fired for
failing a drug test cannot get his job
back the case was being watched closely
by employers and pot smokers in states
that have legalized medical or
recreational marijuana Colorado became
the fourth state in which courts have
ruled against medical marijuana patients
fired for pot use Supreme Courts in
California Montana and Washington State
have made similar rulings uh so I'm
going to jump in here for a minute this
uh this article kind of frustrated a lot
of people but honestly nothing has
changed with this new ruling Colorado
has always been an at will state which
means you can be fired for anything or
nothing you don't have to be given a
reason your boss can walk up and say
guess what you're fired by here's your
last paycheck so at any minute you can
be fired for no reason it's an at will
state uh so even if they did find
Cannabis in your
system and it was legal they could still
fire you if they wanted to they could
just say haha you're fired but all right
let me get back into the article where
the hell was I now all right the
Colorado worker Brandon coats is a
quadriplegic who was fired by Dish
Network after failing failing a drug
test in 2010 the company agreed that
coats wasn't high on the job but they
said they have a zero tolerance drug
policy coats argued that his pot smoking
was allowed under state law intended to
protect employees from being fired for
legal activities off the clock coats
didn't use marijuana at work but pots
intoxicating chemical THC holy crap
excuse excuse me uh pots intoxicating
chemical THC can stay in the system for
weeks and once again these guys used
chemical I don't think the word chemical
is appropriate there but we'll just let
them do their thing they are
professionals he I'm going to go on with
the article the Colorado Justice ruled
that because marijuana is illegal under
federal law coat's use of the drug
couldn't be considered legal off-duty
activity there's no exception for
marijuana use for medicinal purposes or
for marijuana use conducted in
accordance with state law the court
wrote coats and his lawyers said after
the the ruling that the decision at
least clarified the matters for workers
although I'm very disappointed today I
hope that my case has brought the issue
of use of medical marijuana and
employment to light coat said in a
statement attorneys for Dish Network and
the state of Colorado which filed a
brief uh filed a brief in support of the
company were not immediately available
for comment 23 States and Washington DC
allow medical marijuana Alaska Colorado
Oregon Washington State and Washington
DC have legalized recreational sales
though court cases so far have involved
medical patients the Colorado
Constitution specifically states that
employers don't have to amend their
policies to accommodate employees
marijuana
use coats was paralyzed in a car crash
as a teenager and has been a medical
marijuana patient since 2009 when he
discovered that pot helped calm violent
muscle spasms he was a telephone
operator with dish for 3 years before he
failed a random drug test in 2010 and
was fired uh he said he told his
supervisor
in advance that he would probably fail
the drug test so big shout out to what's
his name Brandon coats was that the
guy's name I read it so quickly yeah
Brandon coats big shout out to this guy
he did lose his job but he tried to
stand up for himself and he took it like
a champ dude he said well [ __ ] at least
we know now at least it's not an
ambiguous law so I'm going to jump in
right now and say something you guys I
am on Periscope while I'm recording this
podcast I am on an application called
Periscope where it's a video app where
people are just watching me record and
throwing comments and questions at me
and I just want to tell
them I'm not watching the comments right
now you
guys I'm just uh doing the podcast I'm
focused on this part uh if I need some
questions to fill in some part of the
show I may look to you guys for a
question or two but I'm keeping away
from the Periscope chat sorry if it
feels like I've been ignoring you I'm
pretty focused on the podcast over here
and getting this part done well so I'm
going to move on to one more news
article let's see how long we've been
recording here all right perfect yeah I
got time for one more news article uh
but thank you guys for watching on
Periscope if you are watching there I do
appreciate that I just don't want to be
rude and make you think I'm ignoring you
I'm just trying to stay with the show
here all right so this next article I
found this I apologize also for all the
throat clearing you guys I do fat dabs
and I drink caffeine and then I talk for
20 minutes straight and then the throat
just goes to [ __ ] I'm gonna take a big
chug of water and hopefully it'll help
out shout out to water I got to love
that [ __ ] all right so this article
comes from the cannabis it is written by
of course it's written by our good
friend Ricardo
Baka and uh it got my attention because
it says Oregon police compare piles of
weed to a voodoo donut as visual aid and
they actually do this it says if you're
in Oregon and passionate about marijuana
reform Wednesday is legitimately a
mammoth day starting July 1st adults can
possess and use grow and share cannabis
in Oregon the shops won't be open just
yet that comes in the fall officials
think but July 1st will represent to
many the beginning of a new era in the
Pacific Northwest state but how much
marijuana will a person be able to
legally possess in Oregon as our handy
Oregon marijuana guide says anyone over
21 in Oregon can possess up to 8 ounces
of usable usable marijuana such as dried
buds at home and up to 1 ounce outside
of the home but especially since weed is
coming out of a very dark grow Closet in
Oregon an average polander portlander
sorry might not know the how much
cannabis makes up an ounce or an eight
or 8 ounces okay sorry this article's
written it's all squished into one
little uh frame here I'm trying to read
it right though and perhaps they don't
have a laboratory grade digitally
calibrated scale in their desk drawer
either oh they should if you're in
Colorado everyone's got a Digi scale now
but then it says fear not legal weed
offici afficionados the Portland police
are here to help in a very
straightforward and almost sweetly
maternal Blog the department encourages
community members to be responsible and
considerate with recreational marijuana
they tell people that stone driving is a
crime public consumption could result in
a citation and bringing Washington
bought weed into Oregon is a federal no
no uh with that last note being a bit of
a turnaround from the Department's
previous statements so they must have
went back on something they said earlier
we'll have to research that so the best
part of the Portland Police memo the
visual aid that compares a pile of weed
to a voodoo donut one of the state's
most celebrated Edibles which is not of
course is not infused it's one of the
most popular snacks in Portland if you
ever go there you have to have a voodoo
donut it is defitely super popular all
my friends in Portland always talk about
it I hate you guys that are eating them
right now send me one anyway so it says
so how much weed makes up an ounce the
legal amount you'll be able to have on
your person in Oregon about the size of
a doughnut if not a little bigger so
imagine that you guys in Oregon you're
allowed to have a dut pile sized amount
of weed so if you get pulled over by the
cops and you got some weed on you
they're like how much weed you got and
you're like this much is that cop going
to go to his car and pull out his donut
and [ __ ] set the donuts cuz you know
the cop's got a donut in the car is he
going to go get a dut and set that donut
down and set it next to your herb and be
like E I think you're cool bro you can
get away with that that's going to be
[ __ ] funny all right and then it says
what about 8 ounces the legal amount
you're able to have uh at home in Oregon
about the size of a pile of donuts it
doesn't completely dwarf the dut uh he'd
be able to climb oh he'd be able to
climb that pile of weed if he could
climb so you'd have eight Donuts worth
of weed right if you could have 8 ounces
you'd have about eight Donuts so you'd
have a dozen donuts plus two extra worth
of weed so just visualize that next time
you want to know how much weed you can
carry around in Portland this is weird
all right the article goes on to say
it's a genius Ploy on the police's part
and the inclusion of donuts inside
Official Police marketing material
surely isn't lost on anyone checking out
the truly modern graphic it takes us
back in fact to Wi Denver's police had
some 420 friendly fun on their own when
they dropped a smart hipop reference on
their official Twitter account on this
last 420 weekend and I think I remember
that they said uh we see you rolling and
we ain't hating but then they talked
about all the rules that you had to
follow to uh smoke weed in Colorado all
right so the article goes on to say
Portland and Denver will share more than
just legal weed on July 1st in December
2013 the city's beloved Voodoo Donuts
open its first shop outside of Oregon in
Denver of course so the next time I'm in
Denver I'm definitely going to go grab
myself from some Voodoo Donuts if
there's not a line there's always a line
at that [ __ ] all right so shout out to
the Cannabis uh thanks for letting me
read articles from there so be careful
you guys if you go to Oregon make sure
to get some donuts and that way you can
measure how much cannabis you can
legally possess you can have one dut on
your person or eight Donuts worth of
weed at your home let's see how long
we've been recording I might start
wrapping this up yeah we're going to
start closing up the show dude uh let's
start closing this up what do I got I
got some notes somewhere here I know I
got them I did that I did that I did
that um let's see somebody told me
something that really uh that really
stuck to my head they said a good Ganja
Farmer will never put something off for
tomorrow if you see it needs to be done
today get get in there and do it that's
the difference between growing top shelf
Buds and mids and I've never agreed with
a statement more that's definitely
something that I agree with so uh you
guys Spencer should be on a show pretty
soon I'm going to do a show about uh
improving your garden pretty soon we're
going to do I'm going to try to find a
photographer to come on here and talk to
us about cannabis photography if you are
in if you're local to me and you're a
cannabis photographer I would love for
you to come on the show and teach my
listeners how to take better pictures of
their ganja plants I take pretty decent
pictures but I don't think I am an
experienced enough photographer to come
on here and teach everybody how to do it
uh we're also going to talk about ways
to improve your crop I think I said that
Spencer will be on here that'll probably
be an episode or two we've been talking
about what we're going to do trying to
schedule that that dude is heavily
scheduled big shout out to Maddie Maddy
invited me over tonight mty made
blueberry muffins that were freaking
delicious uh Maddie actually ran a batch
of hash for me she took some of my nugs
and she made me some beautiful shatter
let me show you what she did let me show
you what she did if you're watching on
Periscope I'm going to hold this up to
the cam nope it's
stuck it's over here it's so stuck here
we go Maddie did that so big shout out
to Maddie she made some super fire
shatter for me I appreciate that let's
see I got a couple of shout outs to give
I want to give a huge shout out to the
spot I want to give a big shout out to
everybody that has started listening to
the podcast who found me on Periscope I
really appreciate that also big shout
out to everybody who is listening on
Periscope and watching on Periscope
right now it's super kind of you I will
be back this episode is going to come
out on Thursday so I will be back Monday
with a whole fresh episode I got a
couple more news articles I got some
things I want to talk to you about so
you guys big shout out to my ninja
Spence until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me put the flower in your grinder and
you crank it and bed with Mary you can
find her in my blanket you got fire on a
play it call it rise to the occasion fat
shatter patties butter drying in the Bas
I don't need no provocation to smoke my
occupation the toe even though it's also
making me broke come on Barack Obama got
to lend some change with a stroke of a
pen quit persecuting all of those you're
supposed to defend how to be taking toes
of the sour d hourly call like a falcon
on the balcony I'm tripping when I'm out
of weed I need a budha sack that pre98
Bubba headband the super Jack rolling
get far opening the fresh jar little
Skywalker choking on the Death Star
spoil bragger enil coil rapper Royal
Shad rapper spitting hotter than my oil
spatter my whole click keeps blowing all
the glass growing all the grass and
smoking all your hash it's a gream brush
but we ain't in it just for cash We're
In It For The Love till death D I'm in
the kit and I'm frying chicken I Chinese
been getting honey since the '90s C
honey in a p from paper hit the nail now
I'm gone like when the wind hits theil
mommy keep the bill for me cuz she know
that I be doing wrong not the be look
like it got on move strong my [ __ ] is
Jewish with a blue thong dabing a w went
around thejust the nail on the rig now
I'm sweating keep the pen in my pocket
I'm always rapping seven dabs open my V
at the table I'm know to order duck like
Don click keeps blowing all the glass gr
all the grass and smoking all your hash
it's a green brush but we ain't in it
just for cash We're In It For The Love
death Recession Proof I'll never need a
bail out I'm waiting for the postman my
drugs are on his mail route I can do
anything myself except for self-doubt so
I don't ever seek help I only help out
it's mad work we doing lots of trimming
then getting stoned like Islamic women
when cops slipping the system is FL
isn't it odd your God's given us PL and
your stance is that your law forbids
them and watch out if you're black and
you speak in Spanish cuz that racist law
was made to attack and defeat Hispanics
it's propaganda we laughing at re for
madness but the privatized prisons will
propit when people vanish that's why I
feel like the lonliest dude the only one
out of my friends without a mobious tube
it's rude I don't collect I just buy and
I use I kind of abuse my glass clog try
and defuse you lose whole click keeps
blowing all the glass gring all the
grass and smoking all your hash it's a
green rush but we ain't in it just for
cash it for the
[Music]
[Applause]
love
been I'm on that
[ __ ] I'm on that baby qu with the eggs
man I seen you on some mother [ __ ]
fabulous makes me want to beam aboard
the mother [ __ ] the mini to Mafia and
Derby guns it's a takeover Spitting Fire
like my man baits glass flamethrower
smoking in my bathtub cuz [ __ ] the damn
club I'm home alone taking Dabs out my
hand It's All American no phony is my
only wish is I had a never ending Supply
in my baton dish stay at the Rison
taking dabs with Addison San Francisco
stop to meet with Julio and Dav again we
link with chatting them staying in San
Diego backstage at the b cup blazing
with Danny Dango piece to Mago to and
the to Daddy Funk Master cush Let's
Twist up a bush and smoke fatties and
Big Ups The Weezy for like every show
you seem to always save our ass yo
wherever we go hey yo my bloody jugy
acting funny off a hubby bar looking
like a poo bear with his head stuck in
the Honey Jar h e TI sweet at the Hard
Rock rock stars carving out our spot
from the bar stop my life's one big oil
Adventure I'm laying Honeys and making
monies like coil condenser let's go my
whole clip keeps blowing all the glass
growing all the grass it's smoking all
your
[Music]
hash