foreign
[Music]
yeah welcome to the podcast everybody
I'm your host Rasta Jeff this is episode
800 of the grow from your heart podcast
of course I've got a fun show lined up
for you in this episode I'm going to
give away free seeds that's right I've
teamed up with my friends at
seedshernow.com to give away free irie
genetic seeds we'll talk more about the
free seed giveaway later in this episode
I do want to remind you that team irie
genetics will be at the dude grows cup
June 3rd just outside of Fort Collins
Colorado come say hi to team irie
genetics I'll be there I'll have Mike
with me come say hi come give me a fist
bump shake my hand take a selfie grab
some seeds if you need them I cannot
wait to meet you with the dude grows cup
make sure you check out dgccup.com for
all the links Deets details and ticket
information
also I want to send a big shout out to
everybody who supported the iridirect
420 sale that sale was amazing it was
overwhelming you guys did a great job on
that sale I appreciate it many of you
may have noticed that for a moment
everything on redirect was marked sold
out that was because I got so many sales
on the 420 sale that I could not keep up
we had to Mark everything sold out so
that we could catch up and actually get
the orders caught up and get to zero we
were doing an inventory we are
regrouping we're rebuilding part of the
website I'm going to make sure that all
these sold out stuff is removed in the
insta in stock items are updated then I
will send you a newsletter and we will
do a fresh drop in a fresh restock here
for the month of May I've got a lot of
great things ready to put out a lot of
great things planned for you so if you
did notice that everything was out of
sale on I redirect have no fear by the
time this episode comes out there will
be plenty of new stock on the website if
you want to stay updated for those new
updates new drops new restocks make sure
you join the patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
everyone on patreon does get the first
heads up on drops and then of course
there is the newsletter on the website
at
iregenetics.com you guys let's get
excited because this is episode number
800. I cannot believe that I have done
800 episodes of this podcast a big shout
out to everybody who's ever been on the
show I've got a I've had a lot of great
guests in the past of course Mike has
been the uh most dominant most prominent
guest on the show big shout out to my
buddy White Mike for joining the podcast
and being on the show uh big shout out
to Maddie and Spence and Sean and Jesse
and everybody who's been on the show
there's so many people that if I try to
work through the list I will miss some
people we had Addison damora on the show
we've had John Hunt the terpy boys on
the show we've had a bunch of great
people here on the podcast big shout out
to everybody who's been on the show big
shout out to everybody who has sponsored
the show a lot of people and companies
out there have sent uh Financial
contributions to the podcast and many
companies and brands have sent products
for me to use abuse review and enjoy
here on the show or just do my normal
dabbing life lots of dab equipment uh
dab nails from Highly Educated big shout
out to Highly Educated one of my first
sponsors also shout out to oil slick a
handmade apparel some of the folks that
have been sponsors since the beginning
uh big shout out to all the people that
have been on the podcast thank you
thanks to everybody that has sponsored
the show but most importantly you guys
thanks to everybody who listens to the
grow from your heart podcast I
appreciate it if you're a new listener
if you're a long time listener ah thank
you I appreciate all of the clicks all
of the listens I appreciate the
interaction uh thank you without you
guys this would be uh this would be a
mental problem it would just be me
talking to a camera for no reason so
thank you for listening thank you for
watching thank you for subscribing I
appreciate it with that being said let's
keep rocking bro there's no reason to
stop the show you guys keep sending
amazing questions cannabis keeps
evolving there are more States and more
people uh growing every single day so
I'm going to stay here and keep rocking
this cannabis podcast to make you guys
the best Growers that we can all
possibly be together so thank you guys
for 800 episodes of support that's
[ __ ] tremendous I appreciate it now
let's move off of the ramblings and
business part of the podcast let's jump
into some grow topics I was talking to a
friend earlier today and we're talking
about just rebuilding Grow rooms and
designing spaces and ideas and goals and
then every time we talk about adding
more [ __ ] to a grow my brain says keep
it simple Stoner the more [ __ ] in that
room the more operating pieces you've
got the more [ __ ] can go wrong I work in
commercial facilities
I train people to work in commercial
facilities when we have a new hire the
first thing I tell them so I have them
meet me at the door to the facility on
day one I unlock the door we walk in
together we clock in together I teach
this person how to run the grow they
walk in right with me before we walk
into the grow on the very first day I
tell them the first thing we are going
to look for today is to find out what
broke last night and I know that sounds
uh very not very optimistic but when you
run a commercial facility with somewhere
between two and 500 lights or maybe even
more in some cases there are a lot of
lights a lot of fans a lot of pumps a
lot of random equipment humidifiers
dehumidifiers uh cameras sensors
detectors emitters there's a ton of [ __ ]
that can go wrong and guess what
something is going to go wrong no matter
how much maintenance you do no matter
how much care and upkeep you give these
are constantly moving pieces in a
commercial facility something will go
wrong the first thing you need to do
when you go in I teach is go look for
the [ __ ] that broke so my theory is the
less moving Parts you have in a personal
grow the less [ __ ] you've got to break
so kind of keep it simple Stoner another
thing that reminds me of and brings me
to is when I started growing we did not
have all these monitors and devices and
technology and toys I had to learn the
plants the plants are what was telling
me I'm over watered I'm under watered
it's too hot in here it's too cold in
here you've given me too much nitrogen
you haven't given me enough nitrogen the
plants are what I have learned as my
monitors my meters I don't use a bunch
of technical stuff in my grow space I
have a pH pen I have an EC meter I've
got monitors to tell me what the
temperature and humidity are in there
but I don't really use a lot of super
overly complicated technical [ __ ] if I
need to know if it's too hot or too cold
in my grow I look at the thermometer if
I need to know if the humidity is too
high or too low I look at the hygrometer
those are two really easy pieces of
equipment to read that tell me what my
room is sitting at the temperature and
humidity those are two of the most
important things if those are cool then
I look at the plants if the plants look
like this and they're green nothing to
[ __ ] with if they're yellow if they're
going side sideways if the leaves are
twisting there's something to deal with
and guess what those leaves are telling
me exactly what the problem is I look at
the leaf I go it's kind of yellow in the
middle it needs some nitrogen or I look
at the leaf and I go oh it's getting
crispy at the tips I'm feeding it a
little bit too much I can identify all
of those problems so what I'm kind of
getting at is you guys don't rely on so
much of that equipment keep it simple
Stoner learn the plants learn how to
identify what the plants are telling you
learn how to identify it early and how
to react to it if you see this how do
you respond to it to correct that
because another thing once you identify
the problem how are you going to correct
it many new Growers see a very small
problem and they turn it into a big
problem by trying to over correct that
problem they say oh I need a little bit
of Cal Mag but I read that when you give
Cal Mag you need to give phosphorus or
potassium or also maybe I should add
some of this and they just get these
bright ideas what if I put this in there
also guess what you had a Cal Mag
deficiency add a little bit of Cal Mag
it was probably calcium and not
magnesium but they're sold in the same
bottle so you see what I'm saying you
see that little bit of a problem and you
want to fix 12 different problems or
throw 12 different things at it and then
you throw everything out of whack just
carefully fix that one problem what I'm
rambling about is you guys learn the
plants keep it simple Stoner don't rely
too much on monitors equipment Gear toys
tools and Technology when we've been
doing this for hundreds of years growing
plants without all that [ __ ] we've just
been looking at them and going hey Bill
this plant's yellow what should we do
give it more nitrogen perfect it's been
it's been that simple for that long so
let's learn these plants there are
plenty of charts on the internet that
will tell you if your leaves look like
this here is the problem if your leaf
looks like this here is the problem
those charts are quite accurate if you
learn how to read them and become very
Discerning because of course a couple of
them look similar and can be confusing
but really pay attention to the details
and pay attention to what you fed also
and you'll know did I give it too much
nitrogen did I not give it enough
phosphorus you'll be able to tell based
on what the leaves are doing and what
you have fed that plant so that's how I
wrap up that section where I call it
keep it simple Stoner let's not not
focus so much on the toys and the
technology but let's learn how to pay
attention to the plants because after
all the plants are the boss in our Grow
rooms all right now let's segue into
everybody's favorite part of this
podcast let's get into the email portion
of today's podcast I've got a stack of
questions here in front of me this first
question did come from the grow help
submission tab on iregenetics.com if you
have a grow help question go to my
website irygenetics.com there's a row of
tabs at the top one of them says grow
help or grow questions click on that tab
we'll give you the opportunity to fill
out a little questionnaire then you get
to tell us what's wrong with your plants
if I select your question and read it
here on the podcast guess what you win a
free pack of seeds so this message came
from my friend chivo Del Norte big shout
out to chivo you have won a free pack of
irie genetic seeds please send me an
email with your shipping address and
also include a real name that I can put
on the box for those seeds because I
have to hand deliver these packages to
the post office and when they see where
weird random names they look at me kind
of funny and I don't want any problems
let's put a real name on the package
please you guys this grow question goes
just like this it says yo Rasta Jeff
what's up bro good to meet you I think
I've met you before online thanks for
the great message it goes like this
first of all I want to say that I really
appreciate you and what you do for the
community and that you bless us all with
your knowledge and passion much respect
bro it's comments like that that
recharge me that keep me going that make
it all worth it knowing that I'm helping
at least you because I'm answering your
question but knowing that I'm helping
people uh making Gardens better making
cannabis better as a whole that means a
lot to me and the reminders like this
those recharge me and those keep me
going so thank you bro I do appreciate
that much respect back at you as well
big fist bump now it says my question is
in the area of white hairs those are
called pistols my friend those are the
reproductive organ of the plant it says
is there a way to tell from the hairs
that the plant has been pollinated I
know some cultivars do produce red hairs
so I was wondering how I can tell the
difference thanks again for your time
and passion and Aloha big Aloha my
brother thank you for the great question
let's talk about these pistols about 14
to 21 to 28 to 32-ish days into flower
your plant is going to be showing
pistols those are the dandelion looking
or the cluster of those pistols looks
like a dandelion forming on your ganja
plant that is the start of flower those
little pistols are the reproductive part
of the cannabis plant cannabis is number
one goal we think it's to get us High
that's that's the bonus that's the side
effect but the number one goal of the
cannabis plant is to reproduce it wants
to make more plants to continue its life
next year and then continue next year so
cannabis's number one goal is to
reproduce and those white hairs are the
reproductive organ on the plant those
hairs stick out the male plants grow a
little bit taller than the females
hopefully they drop pollen that pollen
lands on that uh that hair that pistol
slides down that pistol into the ovule
where a seed is formed there's a brat
involved in there but we're just going
to stick with the ovule into the a Brack
to see this form that's where the seeds
will happen now the question is how can
I tell if the plant has been pollinated
by looking at the pistols that's a
really good question once the plant is
pollinated so we'll say the pistols are
sticking up like my fingers like I'm
giving you a high five
shortly after pollination they'll turn
kind of a brown color and start to
crumple inside on themselves and just
dry up and wither away that's how to
identify that they have been pollinated
now it is true that a lot of plants do
produce red hairs but that is later in
flour once those hairs have turned red
that plant has basically passed its
prime point for pollination and it can
no longer receive pollen its lady parts
are dried up basically and it can no
longer reproduce now most of the time I
can tell the difference between a dried
up pistol that has been pollinated and a
plant that has gone beyond its time just
by kind of looking at the plant first of
all there will be a seed if it's been
pollinated it will start forming a seed
I won't take very long from pollination
for the seeds to start forming you'll
see seeds in seven to ten days they
won't be chunky fat healthy seeds but
you'll be able to identify that that
plant has been pollinated by the
formation of seeds now when they get
pollinated they kind of curl in and
shrivel a little bit differently if they
go unpollinated and they're left just to
die on their own and wither away they
kind of just die and stay not withered
and curled in but a little bit
straighter they do have curls and
textures to them but they don't curl as
badly I keep saying the word curl maybe
that's exactly what to look for when it
like claws up a little bit when the
pistols they just fold in on each other
that's when they have been pollinated if
they're still kind of long and wispy
like eyelashes then they're probably not
pollinated but the number one indicator
obviously is going to be the presence of
a seed in that plant now a lot of people
are going to freak out
a lot of times people send me messages
they say hey bro what do I do my plants
are filled with seeds and then I say
let's investigate more send me a picture
send me a video let's do some tricks we
go squeezing around on the plant we go
looking around and we realize those are
not seeds those are swollen bracks which
is what we want we want the plant to get
swollen calyxes big fat brats those are
the parts that we're going to smoke
that's going to be the flour that is the
flower cluster forming every one of
those little clusters makes a big flower
so we want that to happen a lot of
people freak out they see it the nodes
right where the leaf the big petiole
comes out sometimes there's a little
Brack right at the bottom of there
people really freak out and say I've got
seeds guess what that's just a brat you
probably don't have seeds so look at the
plants and you can tell if they're big
and white and fluffy those are ready for
pollen and have not been pollinated if
they get brown and curl in a little bit
like a cat Clyde yes or like the like
the yeah it's a cat climb making right
there bro that's what that is they curl
in like a girl on Instagram trying to
show you her fingernails if they curl in
like that that makes sense right then
it's probably probably been pollinated
if they just die and lay across the bud
like that and they don't curl in like
the cat claw then they're probably just
expired pistols is what I would call
them at that point I just made that
phrase up expired pistols I don't know
if that's even real you heard it first
turn on the grow from your heart podcast
episode 800 we're making up new [ __ ]
words have fun with me um so I think I
basically covered that I know some
cultivar cultivars produce red hairs
that's going to be later than flour so
um you'll know you'll you'll probably
you should probably be able to tell the
difference if you don't see any seeds or
anything then it has not been pollinated
so just go ahead and give it a squeeze
don't go destroying your buds but give
it a squeeze if there's a seed in there
it'll pop like a pea or it'll have some
juices inside of it if there's not a
seed there won't be anything inside of
those bracks or calyx is all right my
buddy chivo thank you for the great
message I do owe you a free pack of irie
genetic seeds once again please do send
me your shipping info I'll get those out
to you right away if I do owe you seeds
as a prize because I've read your
message here on the show and I have not
sent it please be patient with me I was
overwhelmed with the 420 sale I've just
caught up with all of that got a lot of
stuff going on but I will get your
prizes out have no fear uh everybody
does get their prizes sometimes it just
takes a little bit of time all right
we're going to move into the next
question here on today's podcast this
one came from our friend cronker as how
I think I would say that
k-r-o-n-k-o-r that's cronker that's what
I'm calling you from now on but I hope
that's how I say it so this message says
yo Rasta Jeff I love your show and I've
been watching since at least
2018. that's a lot of episodes bro thank
you for watching also kind of
embarrassing because I wasn't a super
good podcaster back then but thank you
for growing with me I hope you notice
the growth and improvements in the
podcast I hope you're watching the video
as well uh then it goes on it says thank
you for all of the wonderful information
you put into your podcast I have learned
a law like I said before bro that is the
kind of feedback and encouragement that
I need to keep me inspired to do the
shows so thank you it says now on to my
reason for writing I have a few
potential questions for you to maybe
answer on your podcast have no fear my
dude I'm gonna answer your questions
right here on the show this is a quick
one it says I've been wondering if you
know if there are any benefits to
watering cannabis plants with coffee
left over from our morning maybe not
every morning but sometimes my quick
answer to that is the uh the pH is way
too acidic I wouldn't do it because uh
we try to stay in a Pacific a specific
PH range and I'm certain that coffee is
going to be very acidic first of all
when I drink coffee it tastes very
acidic to me I'm not even a huge coffee
fan anymore but it's too acidic that's
going to be my that's the short answer
now it says uh keeping with the coffee
questions what about top dressing with
coffee grounds again uh no now my short
answer was no then it says for these for
any of these questions does it matter if
we use uh coffee beans if the coffee
beans are caffeinated or not thank you
from your friend cronker the final note
that I wrote on this paper was just
drink the coffee it sounds like you
really enjoy coffee sounds like you
really enjoy cannabis let's just roll up
a fat join a cannabis and have a nice
fat cup of coffee and enjoy them that
way
um I don't see the benefits I think
you'll probably cause more harm than you
will benefit if you try to induce the
coffee into the Cannabis it's a really
good idea I understand you want to be
useful you've got these coffee grounds
you've got some waste you want to use it
if you really want to do it I recommend
putting it into the compost bin compost
it but otherwise you're just going to
totally disrupt the pH of your
rhizosphere for your cannabis plants my
dude cronker thank you for the great
message once again send me your address
so that I can send you a pack of irie
Genetics seeds of course that seed
giveaway is sponsored by my friends at
seedshearnow.com make sure you check out
seedshairnow.com for regular feminized
photo period Autoflower any seeds you
could imagine they are available at
seedshearnow.com go check them out let
them know Rasta Jeff sent you all right
we've got another question right here in
front of me this one came from our
friend fridge Raider bro you're telling
me bro smoke a few dabs and go raid the
fridge that is a great name this is a
general grow question it says Rasta Jeff
I'm very excited and happy to have your
gear I'm glad you're able to get your
hands on my gear Brother since I've been
listening to the podcast for at least a
year now I pick up I picked up a few
packs from you recently I got Nuketown
very great strain uh Nuketown is
Chernobyl to a Golden Goat it says I got
chemical cocktail which is lemon chem to
Afterglow and we've got the maze which
is which is blue raspberry truffle to
the Reversed Afterglow once again so a
great lineup of strains that are
Nuketown chemical cocktail and the Maze
says I'm very excited but I would be too
that's a good run and also
very good strain selections the chemical
cocktail in the Maze will run
beautifully together and they're going
to have very different very different
effects and flavors and aroma so that's
great the Nuketown will go well in there
but it's going to be a little bit
shorter than the other plants uh so if
you're going to run those together I do
the chemical cocktail in the Maze and
then consider the Nuketown on a
different run do your thing if you're
going to run them all together it will
work but the uh the Nuketown is going to
grow a little bit differently more bushy
less tall than the other plants in the
room I'm sure you can manage it it goes
on though it says I'm very excited I
would like to preserve genetics by
cloning the issue is I've never cloned
anything before and I've been through a
few runs all right now it's time to
learn how to clone bro that's a great
step unfortunately I put out a wonderful
cloning podcast it was great in my
opinion it was a wonderful show
YouTube didn't seem to think so because
after it got about 2 000 views in just a
few days YouTube Took the video down so
my how to cut clones and uh cultivate
clones episode with a step-by-step video
I was clipping them dipping them and
sticking them and getting them going
YouTube took it down so I can't refer
you to my clone cutting video I hope and
I'm sure there are several other clone
cutting videos out there on YouTube I
recommend watching a good video getting
a good education on cloning
but I'm sad they took mine down I
digress let's keep moving here it says
how would you recommend one to clone
without using a store-bought tray and
Dome what do you think about putting
clones into tap water to root no that's
uh these plants are too high performance
too valuable too precious and we expect
too much out of them to just drop them
into water and expect them to root they
may some of your healthier plants May
root most of them are just going to
shrivel up and get rotten and die
without some sort of movement without
some air in there they want more than
that and they deserve more than that
they also say also what about putting
cuttings into reused soil to root using
cups so I understand what you're saying
you want to use a beer cup like a solo
cup with holes in the bottom for
drainage then use a clear cup up top to
work as a humidity Dome so far out of
all of your ideas that is the best one
that I think I would go with
um you say that the store-bought domes
and trays and everything are expensive
those are super affordable and that is
the way to clone if you want to get
expensive look into buying a turbo
cloner or an easy cloner with a manifold
and a sprayer and a big body and
replaceable collars that's when cloning
gets [ __ ] expensive I honestly think
you could buy the cloning Dome and tray
and some rapid rooters and you're going
to need however you do this you're going
to need some clone gel of some sort I
recommend the orange the purple clonak
[ __ ]
I think for the price of the cups You're
gonna buy depending on how many clones
you want to make you could probably buy
most of your clone Dome set up for the
same price if you go to a hydroponic
shop or if you even shop on Amazon if
you have to you can get a dome and a
tray for about 15 bucks probably get
some rapid rooters those are going to
run you about 30 bucks for a bag of
Rapid rooters it's really not that much
funding compared to buying cups and
hoping that they work I would encourage
you to encourage you to set yourself up
for success and do this the best way
that you can I understand 45 bucks may
be a lot of money to somebody who isn't
going to make any money off of these
clones you got to wait at least 120 days
before there's any profit any return on
investment but I would just buy the tray
I would buy the Dome I'd buy some rapid
rooters or something similar they don't
have to be rapid rooters there's root
riots there's [ __ ] 20 different
brands out there pick the one that's on
sale they're all mostly reliable they're
all close to the same thing just get the
one that's on sale so you got the tray
maybe the insert you got a dome you got
some rapid rooters and some clone gel
and then you need scissors and then a
way to label these plants and maybe some
alcohol to clean up or something you
don't need a lot of things just invest a
few bucks that's what I would totally
recommend I know it sounds like you own
a business you got some money you're
saying spend it I definitely recommend
it's going to be a more enjoyable
process you're going to have more pride
in it you're going to enjoy it more
which means you'll make more time for it
you'll put more effort into it which
means you'll get a better product in the
end so spend a few bucks and when you
spend money then you're going to work
harder because you put money into it
this shit's got to work so that's my
recommendation but the other option was
using recycled soil putting it into a
beer cup and using a clear cup or maybe
even a bag to cover it to keep the
humidity in I can't find a good dome and
tray on Amazon there expensive and weird
sizes and fragile they'll get them to
you bro Amazon will not destroy your
clone clone Dome I've gotten plenty
delivered in the mail myself allegedly
and they're not that expensive in the
size you can get a 50 cutting tray it's
only what is 14 inches long 15 maybe
that's about 16 inches long by eight or
nine inches wide that's really not that
big bro and then you just put the dome
right on top of it if you've already got
a grow space with a veg room you can
probably put these in the floor and the
peripheral area where the light goes
they don't need a lot of light just
spring for the good gear bro but if you
insist on using soil
in cups and domes uh by using a cup or a
baggie you can absolutely do that but
make sure you use that root gel I still
recommend cutting them and putting them
in some sort of a root gel before you
put them in the dirt that will encourage
root growth much more drastically than
if you just put them in there without
any sort of root hormone also if you
decide to do this I would clean out that
soil so it's not overloaded with
nutrients that are going to burn your
plants you've been feeding that soil
hopefully maybe you flushed a little bit
at the end but maybe you didn't get all
the nutrients out of that soil there's
still stuff in there I would rinse it
out if you've got any enzymatic products
some slf-100 some hydrozymes something
like that I would run a little bit of
enzymes mix it in water and run the
enzymes through that soil to help you
flush it out that way it's fresh and
clean there's no pathogens no problems
because basically think of it like this
when we cut clones we are severing a
limb off of that plant would you like me
to just cut your arm off and stick your
arm into just some random dirty dirt and
hope there's no pathogens that take over
and prevent you from growing your arm or
would you rather me give you some sort
of sterile environment with a Chance
if it was my arm bro I would definitely
recommend that sterile environment and
get a chance but I understand budget may
be the key issue here in the garden so
you can use that recycled soil but rinse
it out make sure you put holes in that
bottom cup so the dirt can or the water
can drain out of the dirt then if you
put a clear cup or a baggie on top make
sure you just seal it up there and then
you're gonna have to learn how to adjust
the airflow to that after a few days
it's going to need some air if you've
got a cup you could poke holes in the
cup the baggie I'm not sure what you're
going to do but your idea will work but
you wouldn't be you will be much more
successful if you just spring for the
Dome the divider thing the little insert
that holds the plugs the plugs and the
tray part I said that backwards the tray
the insert the plugs on the Dome and
maybe like a spray bottle
so you could spray them to keep them
moist that always helps you out a little
bit some clonex gel for sure you're
going to need some kind of cloning gel
and clean scissors make sure you clean
the scissors that's definitely important
but I think you can make this happen but
my advice is just spring for the proper
equipment set yourself up for Success
enjoy the grow a little bit better
invest in it you're going to spend that
45 bucks on silly [ __ ] anyway go ahead
and put it into the garden it will
reward you all right my buddy
refrigerator I do want to thank you for
the great message thank you for getting
me to ramble for a few minutes once
again you have won a free pack of seeds
so please do send me your address I
cannot wait to get you a free pack of
seeds and once again that free seed
giveaway is sponsored by my friends at
seeds here now.com all right I've got
one more message here in front of me
this message also came from the irie
genetics grow help tab on
iregenetics.com this one came from our
friend Sean from Massachusetts what up
Sean good to meet you bro thank you for
the great question
you of course do win a free pack of irie
genetic seeds please send me your
shipping address cannot wait to get you
a free pack of beans and get those in
your garden our friend Sean has a
general grow question that goes just
like this it says hi Ross to Jeff hi
Sean it says I have a quick breeding
question for you everybody knows those
are my favorite says I have a plant I
want to breed with and it was from a
feminized seed is it okay to use STS to
make her the pollen donor yes absolutely
yes
also would it be okay to then pollinate
another feminized plant with that pollen
donor
yes
thank you in advance I appreciate all
the info you could bless me with bro yes
uh I have done this I do this uh what
strain do I use that is feminized let's
pick something oh uh lemon sorbet
somebody else has used the name lemon
sorbet since then but a long time ago a
very very long time ago before the rain
and before the snow I took my Grateful
Dog which is a feminized seed project
that plant is a feminized plant and I
reversed Grateful Dog and I put that
pollen on Lemon Jeffrey lemon Jeffrey is
a feminized project from that reversed
pollen from a reversed from a female
plant put that pollen on another plant
that came from a femme seed guess what
it made it made [ __ ] hot fire that's
one of my favorite crosses that I have
never put out when I first made that
cross I put out a bunch of tester seeds
and right after I did it my social media
account got squashed and I lost contact
with a lot of people I was very
discouraged I lost excitement for that
cross and guess what I put all the seeds
in the vault and I've never let them go
to anybody other than those testers I've
got a few of them left myself at the
time I wanted to call them a lemon
sorbet I'm pretty sure somebody has
taken that name by now but it was a
Grateful Dog reversed onto the lemon
Jeffrey and both of those are feminized
and it made amazing [ __ ] plants so
yes you can do this sometimes if we go
too far with generations of selfing a
plant things can go weird if we do like
S2 or S3 sometimes we start going the
wrong direction and losing Vigor and
losing the quality traits and we start
seeing slow weak plants but most of the
time taking a feminized plant and a
feminized plant that are not related to
each other that have not been inbred
that have not been worked together and
you breed those together that's a new F1
that's a new uh S1 or an R1 whichever
one you want to call it but that new F1
is going to have hybrid hybrid Vigor and
I definitely recommend that sort of a
project so have no fear grow your Femme
seeds reverse your Femme seeds breed
with your Femme seeds have fun with them
the most important part is to pay
attention to what happens to the progeny
you've got to grow those out sometimes
you're going to make some wonky [ __ ] but
sometimes you're going to make some
amazing [ __ ] most of the time it'll come
out just like you anticipate if you
could see the traits that come from
plant a and the traits that come from
plant B and you know you've grown them
enough times and you've identified what
they do when you breed them when you
reverse one and pollinate the other you
can easily predict what they're going to
do if you've developed a relationship
with both plants so I recommend breeding
with regulars Femmes breed breed breed
have a good time thank you for the great
question my dude once again please do
send me your address so I can send you a
free pack of irie Genetics seeds all
right ladies and gentlemen boys girls
pimps hoes friends foes smokers Growers
clone Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis activists out there I
do want to thank you once again for
joining me for an episode 800 of the
grow from your heart podcast it feels
really good to say 800 episodes that
puts some some pride inside of me puts a
smile on my face puts a new spark in me
for podcasting also new spark I hope you
guys have been enjoying the new format
I've been trying to cut out some of the
nonsense I cut out the advertising and
the shout outs at the front of the show
I try to get in give you guys the info
you need and get out so that you guys
can learn some stuff and not have to
listen to me ramble for too long if you
do enjoy the rambles check out my
Instagram live show every Monday that's
right every Monday around 7 10 p.m
mountain time I go on Instagram live I'm
irie underscore genetics you'll have to
type in the whole name to find me set
your notifications Monday night I'll go
live that's where I get rambly I'll
smoke a bunch of dabs and just talk a
bunch of [ __ ] we'll listen to reggae
music we'll talk about growing ganja
we'll talk about music we'll talk about
sneakers who knows what we might say on
the Monday night show but I really hope
you enjoy the new format of the podcast
I've been trying to keep it flowing a
little bit I noticed that people check
out about 36 minutes into a podcast so I
definitely keep it around 30 minutes for
you guys that way you guys don't get
bored on my rambling but I hope you've
been enjoying the new format I've been
trying to keep it flowing get in give
you some info and get out without
rambling your face off so thank you for
the words of encouragement the great
feedback that I've been getting and also
we've been getting more views so I do
feel like the new idea has been working
ladies and gentlemen I am rambling once
again let's start wrapping up the
podcast if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns I would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your feedback your
constructive criticism if you've got
hate mail sit in my way I could take
that as well also make sure you check
out the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart of
course the people at the 420 level and
higher do get the first notifications
when there are new drops on I redirect
the 710 level does oftentimes get
coupons for sales on iridirect and of
course they get heads up of new drops
and Etsy codes for the irie merch also
make sure you check out the merch store
because shirts and hats and things are
on sale for ridiculous blowout prices
I'm having a get this [ __ ] out of my
office sale so help me out get some of
these boxes out of my office
move the merge all right where else are
we the website everything you could
possibly imagine is on my website
irygenetics.com there's a link to the
seed store there's a link to the merge
store there's an updated link to the
Discord uh everything you could ask for
is at iregenetics.com tune in check it
out is what I think all the cool kids
say that is all I've got for you for
this episode really thanks again for
listening to 800 episodes of the podcast
that really does mean a lot to me like I
said before if you're a new listener if
you're an old school listener if you're
a dedicated listener or if you just
listen when you're bored thank you guys
I appreciate each and every one of you
make sure you click subscribe make sure
you click like I'll be back in a few
days with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Diddy
dankerson and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
hmm
thank you
[Music]