if your dog has ever convinced you to
feed it dinner again because you got too
stoned to remember if you fed it the
first time
go ahead and click subscribe
[Music]
you bad [ __ ]
here we go podcast World welcome back
I'm your host Rasta Jeff this of course
is episode 801 of the grow from your
heart podcast thanks again for joining
me I've got a fun episode lined up for
us in this episode we're going to talk a
little bit about white flies and we're
going to talk a little bit about
pollination and we're also going to give
away free seeds that's right I've teamed
up with our friends at seeds here
now.com to give away free irie genetic
seeds hang out we'll talk more about the
seed giveaway later in this episode
before we get too far I do want to send
a big thank you for all of the comments
the love and support on episode 800.
thank you that was a big milestone for
me I'm super proud to have made it that
far thank you for all the compliments
the words of encouragement all of the
feedback I do appreciate that cheers you
guys here's to another 800 episodes keep
listening there's no reason for me to
stop can't stop won't stop thanks again
for all of the support I also want to
remind you that team Irene genetics will
be at the dude grows cup June 3rd in
Laporte Colorado just outside of Fort
Collins that's right team irie genetics
will be at the dude grows Cup come hang
out with us at the dude grows cup give
me a high five give me a fist bump take
a selfie grab some seeds if you need
them I look forward to seeing you at the
dude Groves cup June 3rd in Laporte
Colorado of course all the information
is that
dgccup.com if you can't make it to the
dgc cup make sure you check out my
website irydirect.com there will be a
fresh restock and a new drop on
iridirect.com by the time this episode
comes out there is brand new stuff on
iridirect.com there will be two new
strains and a fresh stock of orange
gasum the orange gasm will be back by
the time this episode drops there will
be orange Chasm lemon Jeffrey Golden
Goat there should be some chemical
cocktail up there by the time you get to
the website there is some bubble goat up
there there are a lot of great feminized
options and two brand new regular seed
offerings so make sure you go check out
iridirect.com and of course join the
newsletter so you can stay up to date
with all of the fresh drops restocks and
of course the patreon members do get the
coupon codes at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart ladies and
gentlemen go check I redirect now
because of the a lot of the things will
sell out very quickly all right I think
that is all the business part we've got
here at the start of the show let's jump
into your favorite part of the podcast
The Listener email portion of the show
I've got a bunch of great emails here in
front of me the first question here in
front of me came from our friend Shannon
this one did come from the grow help tab
on the irie genetics website that's
right if you go to iregenetics.com there
are a bunch of tabs at the top one of
them says questions or help click on
that tab you'll be able to answer a few
preliminary questions we ask what kind
of question do you have where are you
growing what kind of Lights what stage
of are you in veg or flower what week
are you in we ask a few questions just
to help me answer your question a little
bit more clearly I get some details so
this one came from our friend Shannon we
can skip all of the preliminary
questions they were answered because
these don't really affect my answer I do
understand this question and I do have a
good solution our friend Shannon says
Rasta Jeff I think I have a problem with
white flies and I've begun treatment as
such but I am wondering if there's
anything that can be mistaken for white
flies that's a really good question it
does go on to say however I do know the
difference between fungus gnats and
white flies it is definitely not fungus
gnats because I have done a podcast
recently in the past trying to talk
about fungus gnats and white flies we're
trying to treat for both I said it's
very important to identify the pests
which you are attacking that way we can
attack properly so they do know that it
is not fungus gnats there's a big
difference there It also says also I've
become quite a fan and I appreciate your
work and efforts in the pot world the
first episode I ever saw was number 713
about mother plants well I'm glad you
discovered the podcast I'm glad you're
watching thank you for joining us thank
you for Learning and extra thanks for
the great question here because this is
a great topic to talk about here on the
show it says PS you can use my name too
I'm digging your work from Canada so big
shout out to our friend Shannon from
Canada thank you for the great question
um it sounds like you do know the
difference between fungus gnats and
white flies there are not a lot of other
things that will be confused or look
like white flies sometimes an aphid can
look like a white fly but here is the
main difference aphids do not fly the
main difference is that these white
flies are going to fly if you take
something your hand your arm or maybe a
stick and you hit the plants do little
white things come flying up and out of
the plant that look like ashes if so
those are white flies they look like a
little piece of rice they look like an
ash and they fly around in the grow they
fly around a lot now if we have
definitely identified that those are
white flies let's talk a little bit
about treatment because just identifying
them is only the start of the mission
let me talk about one thing here A
friend of mine was facing white flies
and he said I put yellow sticky traps
all over the room but it is not working
absolutely yellow sticky traps are not
meant to eradicate a pest yellow sticky
traps are there to to indicate the
presence of a pest those yellow sticky
traps should be yellow and pest free
maybe one day you'll see a couple of
bugs on there you'll go hey there's
something in here I need to pay
attention you mark down how many you saw
make a mental note there were about 10
of these specific bugs on this yellow
sticky trap yesterday morning pay
attention how many there are there in
the evening how many are there tomorrow
morning how many are there the next day
are a couple Landing you're gonna get a
couple of bugs stuck to your yellow
sticky trap but if you've got
10 the first day 50 the next day 150 the
next day we've got an increasing problem
it is time to do something those yellow
sticky cards are only indicators of the
presence of pests they are not there to
eradicate eliminate or minimize a pest
infestation anyway that is to let you
know hey there's bugs here bro that's
like having some Footsteps in the snow
is all that those guys are so let's
start by identifying the white flies we
know they're there we've seen them on
the yellow sticky traps now let's talk
about ways to eradicate these white
flies the first thing I would do is
defoliate the white flies are on the
leaves let's take off the leaves any big
leaf you don't need any leaf with a
purple petiole let's get that leaf right
out of there let's strip the plants
clean it up let's put all of those
leaves into a sealed container and get
that as far from the grow as possible if
you could burn that [ __ ] that would be
ideal but I understand that is not
possible for everybody don't just go
throw it in the backyard don't throw
that bag of leaves in the basement don't
just abandon that bag that bag is
contaminated let's get that [ __ ] far far
from our ganja plants far far from The
Grow then also once you're done doing
that change clothes clean up let's not
take a bunch of white flies right back
into the grill after we just did work
step number one let's heavily defoliate
any plant that is affected by the white
flies and also consider defoliating the
other plants that may not be as heavily
affected let's minimize the
opportunities let's take away their
hangout spots let's not leave a lot of
opportunities for them to go so the
first thing we want to do is do some
defoliation so the next thing I would do
is kind of a wild idea it's super fun to
watch somebody do this if you've got a
buddy that can get you on camera record
this post it tag me it will be really
funny this sounds wild but I do this I
have done this this is how I get rid of
white flies I haven't had white flies in
a long time I have done this there's
actually video somewhere on Instagram of
me doing this I get a long stick
whatever kind of long stick you've got a
couple of feet long is what I needed for
my grow space I also got a shop vac with
the long wand on it that way I can
control where I'm pointing you guys may
be able to see where I'm going with this
I turn on the shop vac I start smacking
the plants with the stick and then I
hold the shop vac up toward the light
guess what all those white flies fly out
of the plant they head up to the light
then guess what right into the shop vac
and they're gone sometimes I'll kind of
wave that shop vac around the canopy be
careful not to suck up plant matter
don't get leaves stuck in there keep it
moving be careful about it just kind of
feather across the top of the plants
brother and you will suck up a lot of
those white flies keep tapping they'll
keep flying give them a minute to settle
watch where they land get the uh the
vacuum kind of near there again and then
tap them and they'll go flying right
into the vacuum this is very effective
make sure that you've got a vacuum with
the filter in it some of the shop vacs
will shoot those white flies right out
of the other end of the shop vac and
just shoot them into your other grow
space don't do that have a filter on
there have some sort of way to catch
those white flies once they're sucked
into your shop vac if you don't have a
shop vac a normal house vacuum will work
put that attachment on it to where the
one you used to clean the curtains or
the corners or whatever put that
attachment on there get in there suck up
those white flies so now we have
defoliated we've taken away most of
their home now we have also shot which
was kind of an assassination we went in
there and just got rid of most of them
we took out a lot of them there's still
going to be a few uh stragglers people
are going to hang out let's talk about
spray applications that I would
recommend to help minimize and eradicate
this white fly infestation the first
product I'm going to recommend is
Evergreen Evergreen is a great product
it's a pyrethrin based product the
reason Evergreen is going to work very
well for the white flies is because they
like to congregate on the bottoms of the
leaves if you spray the Evergreen on the
underside of the leaves it'll be sticky
it'll be an undesirable habitat and
undesirable environment for the white
flies they simply won't want to be there
also it's toxic to them they're not
going to want to hang out so get the
undersides of your leaves when you apply
the pesticide get it I'm going to
recommend somewhere between 15 and 30
milliliters of Evergreen per gallon of
water in a pump sprayer shake the [ __ ]
out of it and apply that to your plants
when you spray it start at the bottom of
the plant and work your way up and make
sure to spray the undersides of the
leaves and since we're dealing with
white flies also spray the main stock in
the stalks if you can what this is going
to do you need to spray the bottom of
the leaves because that is where the
pests hang out the most start at the
bottom and work your way up this way we
know that we're coating the entire plant
we're getting everything covered in
pesticide and by starting at the bottom
you spray it start at the bottom and it
doesn't drip from the top to the bottom
it'll actually work your way up and you
can see what where you've applied a
pesticide you can make it more effective
that way by starting at the bottom and
get the undersides of the leaves is very
important so I would start off with an
evergreen spray then if that didn't work
or if that is not available to you the
spray product from Mammoth bio control
the mammoth pesticide spray I cannot
think of the name I think I wrote it
down what's it called Mammoth Canna
control is a great product that will
work for your white flies one thing
we're going to have to do we're going to
have to spray every third day until
these white flies are gone you have to
be persistent they're not going to go in
on the first application we'll defoliate
we'll shop vac we'll get rid of a nice
percentage been our first application of
Evergreen should get rid of a lot of
them there should be a few stragglers
they're going to be eggs they're going
to be babies they're going to reproduce
produce we got to kill them it's going
to take a couple of sprays
first spray I would go for is Evergreen
then in three days I would rotate I
would use the uh what is it called the
mammoth Canon control if that's
available to you if not go right back in
with that Evergreen and spray that again
that will get rid of them also botanic
garden Max is another great pot product
to put into the rotation here now let's
talk about some more uh gentle and
simpler products that we can use to
eradicate the white flies something that
works very good very well in my opinion
is a product known as mosquito dunks
they are sold at most places that sell
anything to do with plants or gardening
all of your big box stores your Lowe's
Your Home Depot whatever's in your
neighborhood they will have mosquito
dunks you can also get them at Target if
you can get them at a mom and pop
hardware shop in your area we always
recommend that go spend your money in
your community don't give it to the big
corporate box store but they got all the
[ __ ] that's why we go there so I
guarantee that those stores will have it
they're called mosquito dunks they're
sold on a red card and they look like
little Donuts I think there's about six
Don Donuts in the package there could be
three three to six donuts in the package
they look like a little like a donut or
a hamster lick or a bird feed or
something like that don't eat it don't
lick it don't feed it to your pets we're
going to use this to kill white Flies
what I recommend you do with this
I put it in a baggie a thick baggie not
like a sandwich baggie a dope baggie I
use a gallon Ziploc bag it's kind of
thicker then I wrap that in newspaper
then I use a mallet to crush up the
mosquito dunk I want it into small bits
then it will take those small bits and
put that directly into water I'll stir
it up I'll let it sit I'll let that
mosquito dunk kind of break up after a
while it just starts to fall apart like
a turd in the water it'll just come
apart it'll become flaky and
disintegrate in there then I'll get a
stick and I'll stir it up then I'll add
my other nutrients to the mix I might
just put my nitrogen phosphorus
potassium calcium molybdenum I'll throw
it all in there whatever I'm feeding
might just go right into this mix right
along with my mosquito dunks then I will
water that into the soil and that will
definitely help get rid of all of those
white flies they will not want to go
back into the soil so at this point
we've defoliated we've shop vac now
we've sprayed the leaves the leaves are
now undesirable for these white flies
and we've also drenched our soil with
the mosquito dunks which has got a
beneficial bacteria in there that
product will work very well to help get
rid of the wife flies it's very cost
effective it's very affordable and very
effective also another product that will
work very good for your white flies is
Monterey Garden spray Monterey Garden
spray contains a bacteria called
spinosad and spinosad is very effective
against most pests that we're going to
encounter in our cannabis grows so let's
recap a little bit because I feel like I
gave you a lot of information and I also
feel like I'm going super duper fast the
first thing I would do defoliate get rid
of the leaves if there are no hotel
rooms there's nowhere to stay the bugs
will leave then hit them with the shop
vac tap the plants shop vac those little
[ __ ] as they come flying out then hit
them with the pesticide then maybe also
get in there and hit them with the shop
vac again if you've got time why not
shop back the [ __ ] out of them then in
three days hit them with the pesticide
also the first time you hit them with
that pesticide give them a soil drench
from those mosquito donks now we've
taken away their hotels we've made it
undesirable we've shot backed the [ __ ]
out of them to eradicate okay most of
the population now we're spraying a
pesticide to make the leaves undesirable
and we're also drenching the soil
there's nowhere for the white flies to
go they're going to get the [ __ ] out of
there now our other option if you are
opposed to spraying a pesticide or maybe
you're too late into flour and you don't
want to do that the other option of
course is to release Predator bugs the
Predator bugs will come in and eradicate
those white flies and if you do choose
to go the beneficial insect route I
definitely recommend Green Lace Wings to
get rid of the white flies also there's
another Predator mic called the swirky
the swirky I want to say swirky
s-w-i-r-r-k-i very close to that that
guy will definitely get in there and
eradicate those white flies this worky
those guys do thrive in warm
environments so if you've got a hot grow
space which you probably do which is
probably contributing to the white flies
the sworkies a DOT swirky those bad
[ __ ] will get in there and eat
the [ __ ] out of your white flies of
course my first recommendation is the
Green Lace wings and if you do release
their lace wings I may go for the live
lace wings that are active already
because you've got a white fly
infestation any other time I recommend
the cards I like when they hatch the
eggs come on the cards they hatch they
turn into these little dinosaur
alligators and those things are super
hungry and they're interesting to watch
most of the time that's what I recommend
I may go for straight for the living
lace wings at this point just to
eradicate these white flies that's what
I would use to eliminate these white
flies white flies are not a huge problem
but they can become a huge problem they
carry more pests if you've got a small
problem the white flies will compound
every problem and if you've got a
problem with one plant the white flies
will definitely move that problem to all
of your plants now I do understand that
a lot of us will be in different phases
of the Cannabis production we may be in
veg we may be in early flower mid flower
or late flower that does make a big
difference of course later in flower
that's when I recommend those beneficial
insects in veg early flower that's when
I will recommend the Evergreen or the uh
what else was the other one that I said
the botanic guard Max or the botanic
guard uh WP which has also got the
Bavaria bassiana in there which will be
very effective against the white flies
so early in flower I would go with the
Evergreen I would go with the mammoth
Canon Control Spray later in flower I
may go with the botanic garden Max
products the botanic garden products
because they don't have oils they're
focusing more on the beneficial bacteria
and the fungus which is in that product
and I would rather smoke that than the
oils honestly it's going to have a less
detrimental effect on flavor and less
detrimental effect on the final product
those beneficial bacterias will
dissipate they'll get destroyed by the
air they'll get destroyed by the wind
and the light those oils are going to
stay there they're going to taste
terrible in your final product so I
would recommend something like the
botanic Gard Max of course if you have
to go late in flour I never recommended
spraying Laden flour but sometimes
you've got to do what you have got to do
if the white flies are not destroying
your garden later in flower maybe write
it out unless of course you've got a
Perpetual cycle that's always something
to think about but earlier and earlier
in the phase I would go with Evergreen
as it gets a little bit later I would
work my way into the botanic guard and
the Bavaria bassiana beneficial
bacterias as my defense all right I
think I've covered this question the
main question was can I identify that
they are white flies I don't have a
picture but if they fly around like
ashes if they look like little uh just
white bugs flying around that's a white
fly bro we've got to treat for the white
flies all right my friend Shannon thank
you for the great content I do want to
remind you that you win a free pack of
seeds that's right if you send a message
to the grow help tab on ire genetics or
iridirect.com and I read your message
here on the podcast that means that you
win a free pack of irie genetic seeds of
course that giveaway is sponsored by my
friends at seedshearnow.com Big shout
out to seedsherenow.com Shannon please
do send me your real name for the
shipping box and an address to ship
these seeds out to you I appreciate your
support all right I've got another great
question here in front of me this one
also came from the grow help tab on irie
genetics this one came from our friend
flaccid Jack
that's an interesting name let's keep it
moving it says roster Jeff I just
discovered your podcast and I love it
thank you for listening bro there's a
lot of episodes to go catch up on so
head back toward the back of the catalog
and start listening and listen to all of
the episodes can't wait to see what you
think about some of the older content it
says you've got more actual grow talk
than most podcasts thank you I know I do
get rambly I cut out the shout outs at
the start of the show because I noticed
that was throwing people off and people
wouldn't listen but I try to stay
focused and talk about cannabis
cultivation I don't try to overload you
with commercials and [ __ ] to buy of
course I want you to buy my seeds but we
covered that at the start of the show
there's no reason to keep rambling about
that and I also feel like when you have
a problem and a grow I don't need to
sell you a product I need to give you of
course I just told you things to spray
on your [ __ ] for the last problem but
I'm not sponsored by those companies
they don't pay me nobody gave me any
money to recommend those products I
recommend them because they work and
that's what matters I want you to grow
the best cannabis you can grow I've got
this gift of I can read something and
comprehend it and put it to use and I
feel like I can repeat and regurgitate
uh things that I've read and my
experiences in an educational way that
everybody can follow along so thanks for
thinking there's more grow talk than
most other shows I'm not paid to
advertise anything but seeds here now
and of course I try to advertise my own
seed line because that's what I'm gonna
do but but you're right let's stay
focused and get to more actual grow talk
it says recently I started some Autos
which I've saved to make seeds so you've
got some Auto flowers going that is fun
I'm not an Autoflower grower or a
breeder but more power to everybody out
there working with autoflowers there's a
seed and a plant for everybody and a
grower for every seed is how I feel it
does go on it says I saved one seed from
each pack to do this I'm wondering if
you have any experience using colloidal
silver no I do not use colloidal silver
I strongly heavily highly prefer silver
thiosulfate it's much more effective it
works much better on the plants it
doesn't take as many spray applications
and I think it's less stressful overall
to the plant so I don't use colloidal
silver I make my own silver thiosulfate
which I've done a full podcast on making
STS it's called My STS mix or something
like that you can watch that episode
I'll put a link in the video description
then it goes on it says I only want to
Herm one branch and not the whole plant
let me drop this paper and talk about
this if that plant is a Herm in any way
you do not want to breed with it let me
explain this when we're making feminized
seeds there is no hermaphrodite no
intersex that word does not exist when
it comes to making Femme seeds if you
are working with a plant that is a Herm
a hermaphrodite an intersex plant you're
going to have a failure of a feminized
project I know in being very critical
but I want to make this clear a lot of
people think that Femme seeds have some
sort of intersex or hermaphrodite trait
or gene or magic to them that is very
untrue let me explain this when I I make
seeds I make a lot of Femme seeds I sell
a lot of Femme seeds you guys grow my
Femme seeds you're very satisfied with
them that tells me that I'm doing it
right so here's what I'm doing
before I use a plant to make Femme seeds
or any seeds with it I grow that plant
and I purposefully stress the [ __ ] out
of that plant I want to cause that plant
problems and turmoil because I want to
see how it reacts Under Pressure if the
plants that I'm growing with show me
intersex traits hermaphroditism uh what
else did you call it Hermes is the other
word I saw today if the plan is intersex
in any way it does not get used in a
breeding project because that intersect
straight will carry through into my
breathing and you guys do not deserve or
want intersex plants in your garden so I
eliminate those the female plants I'm
using in my feminized projects are
stress tested to a rigorous level they
are not intersex what I am doing is
spraying the plants with silver
thiosulfate what is happening is the
thiosulfate is helping the silver enter
the plant and get into the plant system
that silver then disrupts the copper
movement in the plant that plant then
has an ethylene reaction which causes is
it to produce anthers which contain only
female pollen here's an important part
the pollen is only female pollen because
that plant is only a female it is not
intersex it is not a boy it is 100
percent a female so I'm taking a female
plant and I'm doing science to it
science magic and nature all meat I
treat it with the chemical that plant
then creates pollen sacs which only
contain female pollen there's no male
there's no intersex there's no
hermaphrodite those words are not
involved at all then I use that female
pollen from that tried true tested
female plant that's been reversed and I
put that on another tried true and
tested female maybe the same female
maybe a clone of the same female and we
make Femme seeds so that is my rant and
my disclaimer to get me started here to
talk about your Femme seed project now
let's talk a little bit about more about
what you actually asked now for the sake
of this conversation I am going to
replace the word Herm with reverse
because that is what we are attempting
to do we want to reverse a plan we want
to turn it from a female into a pollen
donating female plant that is what we
call reversing it so let's talk about
that I only want to reverse is what
we're going to say so now it goes on it
says I only want to reverse one branch
of each plant not the entire plant I'm
not Crossing just pollinating the plants
themselves any advice would be awesome
if you already have an episode
discussing this I will check it out I
probably have done a full episode
talking about this but we're here let's
talk about this the first thing that got
my attention is it sounds like you've
got multiple plants you want to work
with I highly very highly recommend you
only mess with one reversal at a time
pollen is microscopic pollen can travel
pollen can get from one reversed plant
over to the other reversed plant and
then we've got what I call a Mori Povich
situation who is the baby daddy was it
this plant or was it this plant we're
never gonna know so what I recommend is
only one reversal at a time don't mess
this project up we want to know what
you've made you want to self this plan
is what you want to do you want to take
let me read and make sure yes so you've
got let's just say you've got this
doesn't exist don't get excited let's
say you've got Golden Goat Autoflower
plants you want to make Golden Goat
Autoflower plants what I would do now I
did also just come up with another catch
in my mind I'm not familiar with
breeding with autoflowers so I'm not
exactly how this is going to work but in
your scenario if you want to self this
plant which is what you're doing you're
taking a hypothetically a Golden Goat
Autoflower and you want to make more
Golden Goat autoflowers since you've
only got the one plant you've got to
reverse part of that plant and pollinate
the other branch of that plant with the
same pollen on the same plant otherwise
you've got to get more seeds and put
pollen from that plant onto another
plant but because you can't cut clones
from the autoflowers I'm a little bit
confused when it comes to breeding with
autos because I don't ever do this
normally you would take one Auto reverse
it pollinate Autos other autos and that
way you've got that pollen donor and you
can just pollinate all the others you
don't have to worry about cloning
anything but you've only got the one
plant so you're going to have to reverse
one branch or half of the plant and then
take that pollen and carefully apply it
to the rest of the plant yes that should
work in theory notice I did say should
let's talk about what happens sometimes
when you attempt to reverse a plant you
will spray just a couple of branches to
do what you're trying to do get some
pollen from one side to pollinate the
rest sometimes that works
sometimes it's perfect other times the
plant does not want to reverse the
hormones in that plant are so stubborn
that when you treat these few branches
the hormones from the other part of the
plant go nah we're not going to let it
reverse it's just so so dominant or so
powerful and who that plant is that
you're not going to change it then other
times we get the opposite you try to
reverse this one branch and the plants
just got those hormones and it goes
watch me in the whole [ __ ] plant
reverses so you've got three options it
may work beautifully you may spray a
couple of branches and isolate those and
spray those and those will pollinate and
you may be able to pollinate the rest of
the plant or when you reverse that one
side the entire plant could reverse or
when you go to reverse that one side
nothing could happen so you got three
potential outcomes here like I said
normally if you're working with the
autoflowers you would reverse one full
plant and then use that as your pollen
donor for multiple females so that's
going to be the catch here and like I
said I'm not an Autoflower breeder so
this is the the closest I can get you
with my experience with what I know what
I would recommend what you're going to
have to do probably to reach the goal
you want is grow that plant reverse it
pollinate reverse one-sided pollinate
that other side of that plant with that
plant there's going to be a lot of
obstacles I don't know the timing of
that most of the time I know I trigger
the flowering phase I spray the plant
before a flower and then I can spray it
at certain times during flour unless you
know how long that plant veggies or how
tall it gets before it goes into flour
it's going to be hard to anticipate when
to start spraying unless you spray
immediately when you see pre-flowers or
right when it goes into flour but it's
going to be a little bit challenging
your question and your plan will work
but you're gonna have some obstacles
number one I recommend doing these two
plants separately the next catch is that
you're worth working with the
autoflowers you get one shot per seed at
this because you cannot clone it so
you've got to grow it reverse half of it
and successfully pollinate the other
side and you get one shot you get two
shots but man I hope this works out for
you let me make sure I'm answering the
question here I want to reverse only one
branch not the whole plant not Crossing
just pollinating themselves that should
work that is the way to do that that
should work but like I said you got
three options for outcomes any advice
would be awesome if you already have
I've done an episode similar to this but
it is not about Autoflower so there's a
lot of new caveats and obstacles in here
I hope I've answered your question let
me give the disclaimer I'm not an
Autoflower grower or a breeder so I'm
just talking about the experience I
understand from photo period breeding
the hardest part is going to be the
timing in my opinion knowing when to
start spraying if you use the silver
thiosulfate you've got to spray it one
time about a week before flower and then
day one of flower which how do you
determine that with an Autoflower just
kind of keep an eye on it and I guess
you get to decide when that happens
right but you got to spray it the day
one day three six nine twelve fifteen
eighteen and twenty one it's going to be
challenging to time that there is
another spray out there I cannot think
of the name of it I have not tried it
but they claim
that you can spray a plant one time and
it will reverse the plant so maybe
that's something worth looking into it
is quite expensive but if it does what
you need done I've never thought of an
instance where that spray would be worth
the money suddenly this may be the
appropriate application all right my
dude flaccid Jack that's a great name I
hope you're able to solve the flaccid
problem I hope I helped you out making
some Autoflower seeds if you've got
follow-up questions dude please do reach
out because like I said I'm not an auto
flower breeder so there are some things
I'm going to miss in this question if
anybody out there has some feedback any
updates any details please leave it in
the YouTube comments or send me an email
at grow from your heart hotmail.com and
flaccidjack please do send me your
address because guess what I owe you a
free pack of irie genetic seeds that's
right I read your message here on the
show seeds here now and I would be happy
to send you a free pack of irie genetic
seeds please shoot me your address
ladies and gentlemen if you did not win
a free pack of seeds on today's episode
don't feel left out don't feel
discouraged I've got a lot of emails
here in front of me and there are a lot
more podcast episodes coming simply stay
tuned keep hanging out keep tuning in
maybe you'll win free seats on a future
episode that is all the questions I've
got for today's episode I feel like I
rambled on quite a bit on today's show
thank you for hanging out thank you for
listening if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know I would love to hear from you the
email address is growfromyourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy of course if
you have cultivation or cannabis culture
questions send those to the grow help
tab go to my website irygenetics.com
click on the grow help tab send me your
questions I will read that on the air
and guess what you'll win free seeds
don't forget about that new drop coming
to I redirect it should be live by the
time this episode comes out go scoop
some new [ __ ] at ireedirect.com there
will be orangegasm lemon Jeffrey Golden
Goat bubble goat chemical cocktail and a
whole bunch of other great [ __ ] uh
what's the other one I forgot about I
can't even remember right now so many on
my mind it's up there go get you some
there might even be some new [ __ ] if
you're quick enough make sure you check
out the patreon campaign at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart
support the show of course all the
patreon members do get the first heads
up when things drop and sometimes they
even get cool coupon codes and free
shipping all right let's wrap this
podcast up everybody thanks again for
hanging out I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a giant
shout out to my buddy totally Dave and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you