if you woke up right on time and were
right on schedule getting ready we had
to stop and take a couple of dabs and
now you're late for work go ahead and
click subscribe
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 803
of the grow from your heart podcast do
bear with me because the episode numbers
will be messed up for the next couple of
shows I apologize I just can't count
we're gonna have a lot of fun in this
episode I've got some great emails
planned out for us we're also going to
give away free seeds that's right I'm
going to give away free Ivory genetic
seeds on this episode hang out we'll
talk more about the free seats later in
the show I do want to remind you that
team ire genetics will be at the dude
grows cup June 3rd in Laporte Colorado
look forward to seeing you there come
hang out I will be there Mike will be
there the dude will be there Scotty real
will be there there'll be a whole bunch
of other great people to come hang out
with stop by the booth say hi I look
forward to meeting you at the dude grows
cop also make sure you check out that
sale and restock on iridirect.com
there's orangegasm available there's
bubble goat available there's lemon
Jeffrey available and a lot of other
great restocks on iredirect.com
all right I feel like I've covered all
of the business part of the podcast
let's move into everybody's favorite
portion of the show that is the question
and answer part of the podcast this
question came from the grow help tap on
the irie genetics website that's right
if you go to my website irygenetics.com
on the top there's a row of tabs one
will say grow questions or grow help
click on that tab we do ask you a few
preliminary questions and then we let
you type in what the problem is in your
grow this message came from my buddy
Dave G from Ontario big shout out to my
buddy Dave G from Ontario hey Dave
please send me your address because I do
owe you a free pack of seeds because I
read your letter here on the show this
one goes a little bit like this it says
hey Ross to Jeff it's Dave from Ontario
what's up dude it's been a minute since
I've heard from you I hope all is well
up there it says happy belated birthday
my friend yes the birthday was in March
I'm reading this a little bit after that
but thank you for the great birthday
wishes I do appreciate that the birthday
was wonderful
there is more it says you may remember
me I sent a few emails about a year ago
yeah bro I definitely remember you your
name stands out does a couple of which
have appeared on the podcast I was
growing Raphael and sunkiss at the time
yes great work bro I do remember you
totally recall you it says we share the
same birthday that's a great fact thank
you happy birthday bro uh it says we are
both comedy nerds yes I'm a huge comedy
nerd uh comedy is one of my favorite
things one of my favorite ways to spend
an evening is to go see a live comedy
show it says we've both acquired brain
injuries yes
um we may have some new viewers new
listeners new followers here on the
podcast in 2015 I suffered a major
traumatic brain injury it messed me up
so bad I didn't know my name I couldn't
do math I missed a bunch of appointments
and people were calling me saying hey
bro where are you and I was saying I
don't even know who you are why are you
calling me I really messed me up that
was in 2015 there were a few months
there where I was not myself it was a
long year of recovery there are still
weird uh glitches ticks and problems
that arise from that brain injury
occasionally but I've mostly recovered
from that I'm sure it messed up my
personality my memory
um right after my brain injury I didn't
give a [ __ ] anymore there were things I
should care about but I just stopped
giving a [ __ ] about a lot of things
after my brain injury so anyway just to
bring some old listeners up or some new
listeners up to speed in 2015 I did
experience a major traumatic brain
injury that uh it caused me some big
problems I had visual problems memory
problems I was hallucinating a lot I was
saying weird [ __ ] and eventually the
swelling in my brain uh healed up and I
am much better now but sometimes you
guys that's why I'm [ __ ] weird that's
part of why I'm [ __ ] weird I was
already a little bit goofy before the
brain injury the brain injury just kind
of Amplified that weirdness let me stay
focused also the lack of focus is from
the brain injury let me keep going it
says we both love cannabis cannabis at a
maximum level yes that is absolutely
true I am completely in love and uh
infatuated and passionate about this
ganja plant that we all love here I love
that it's got so many great uses
uh I smoke it for
um medical and recreational purposes
somewhere in the middle I say I always
say my first dab that's a medical dab
that's second dab that's that's kind of
a supplementary dab that third dab that
one's all recreational the first two
cure all the problems the third one is
just to have a good time so I'm a
recreational and a medical cannabis
consumer I not only love the relief and
um the fun that it gives me but I love
seeing other people smoke cannabis and
feel better I was part of the first
dispensary in my neighborhood the first
dispensary in my city and I got to see
uh all walks of life come through that
shop young dudes old ladies and
everything in between and I would see
people come in and they would say hey
I'm suffering from this condition and I
would develop a relationship with them
and recommend cannabis products if it
was smokables Edibles whatever topicals
we'd get them going
in a few weeks when we figured out the
right products for them they would come
back and I could see an improvement in
the quality of their life and that is
amazing that this plant can do that it
can improve the quality of Our Lives
then we've got the social aspect who
doesn't like to hang out and smoke with
a bro or a lady or both or whatever
smoking with people is one of my
favorite experiences and then I also
love the creative aspect of this ganja
plant when I smoke I'm a musician when I
smoke I want to go play music music
sounds better food tastes better life is
just a little bit better with this ganja
plant and I love how multi-faceted this
plant is and how many great positive
benefits we get from the same plan so
you are absolutely correct with the idea
that we both love cannabis I can tell
that you love cannabis as much as I do
because you've been around for a long
time you've sent a lot of messages and
we've interacted a bit and it's been
over a year so that means that you are
definitely committed to this ganja plant
now like I said before I do have that
brain injury so I get a little bit
rambly let me get myself back on track
there's more to this message it says are
you and I the same person on different
planes of existence I don't know man
there are some interesting coincidences
anyway that is really funny I do believe
in parallel universes and I do believe
in weird things like that so maybe
somewhere along the line bro we've got
some of the same timeline programmed
into us maybe the Matrix spit us out at
the same time whatever human printer you
believe in maybe we came from the same
human printing Factory I don't know bro
but I love that we're such good friends
and we don't even know each other that's
[ __ ] awesome did we just become best
friends bro there's more to this it says
cool if you remember me no big deal if
not bro I remember you how would I not
remember my best friend it says I'm back
and growing some fluff head which I
acquired from the dude's world big shout
out to dudes World check out the dude's
world if you need some irie genetics
beans up there in Canada big up dude I
hope you're doing well bro also there's
more it says I'm running three plants
and noticing some differences and
similarities that's a good thing to
observe then it says I have a question
regarding powdery mildew and its
resistance this is where the spark gets
fun now it goes on it says is powdery
mildew resistance a phenotypical trait
meaning that two plants from the same
population can possibly display
different levels of resistance the quick
answer to that is yes that is a
phenotypical trait just like one of
those plants May smell more like one
thing the other one may smell like
another thing
that is absolutely a phenotypical trait
so you could put both of those plants on
the same room we could introduce powdery
mildew on purpose and you'll see one may
decimate one plant and one may not touch
the other plant that is absolutely a
phenotypical trait now he does give an
example he said I've got fluff head uh
could my fluff head number one and fluff
head number two have the same PM
resistance no they're it's very likely
very possible that they will be
different uh those are bred from two
vastly different parents we've got the
Afterglow which grows kind of tall and
skinny and it's got those long thin
tropical leaves and then we've got the
chem 4 which grows differently than that
it's shorter squattier bigger leaves
totally different flavor profiles and
since we've started with two vastly
different ingredients we can expect
vastly different outcomes in some of
those phenotypes some of them may be
completely powdery mildew resistant and
some of them may be susceptible to
powdery mildew resistance I do know that
the Afterglow is generally resistant to
the powdery mildew but compared to other
phenotypes you are going to see
differences in in that level of
resistance the message says hopefully I
worded that well for you I'll be back
with more questions especially now that
you're giving out seeds for the
questions that's right guys I'm not sure
if I mentioned this but if you send me a
grow question on the grow help tab at
iregenetics.com and I read that question
here on the show you in a free pack of
irie genetic seeds so my buddy Dave up
there in Ontario has won himself a free
pack of seeds Dave you worded this
perfectly bro I totally understand the
question you're basically one and this
goes for every strain we highlighted
fluff head here in this uh question
because that's what my buddy is growing
but this goes with every strain now do
keep in mind that many strains are
powdery mildew resistant if they're bred
in areas where powdery mildew is common
over several Generations those plants
will build that powdery mildew
resistance that just naturally will be
in there a lot of plants do have that
some plants on the other hand just are
naturally susceptible to the powdery
mildew now within those two categories
we're going to see the plants that
really get it and the plants that don't
get it that's just a phenotypical trait
or for an expression all right let me
make sure I wrapped all this up thanks
for the great content it has helped me
out on my journey bro that is what the
the whole point of this is to get
everybody on a great cannabis Journey
growing can be very frustrating there
are a lot of trials and tribulations
that come along with cannabis growing
there's a lot of [ __ ] information
out there I'm trying to get everybody on
a good path and growing the best
possible cannabis they can grow and
enjoying it while they do it because we
can all grow good weed and struggle at
the same time let's try to make it easy
for everybody the last line is my
favorite it says you are my cannabis
hero sincerely from Dave bro I didn't
know that I was anybody's hero but that
does mean a lot to me much respect big
fist bro bro thank you stay cool up
there in Canada and send me more
questions Dave also send me your address
I think I may have it already but please
do refresh my memory because we talked
about that brain injury bro you know
what I'm talking about I'd love to get
you a pack of seeds up there in Canada
land all right we've got a good flow
going there's no need to take a break
now let's keep going I've got another
question here in in front of me this one
also came from the grow help tab on the
ire genetics website this one came from
our buddy phillibong I like that name a
lot what up philabong you fillabong I'll
rip a bong all right the question goes
first of all I love your podcast thank
you bro that is a great compliment and a
good way to start a message that says
they are extremely helpful and you are a
great person for sharing your knowledge
I appreciate that
um I know that it's kindness and all
that stuff that does it but also there's
some weird thing inside of me that I
feel like I would explode if I didn't
share my knowledge and kind of help you
guys in this way I was given the gift of
being able to uh receive information and
also filter out the [ __ ] that's one
of my big gifts I can receive
information I can read I can research
and I can hear a bunch of things and
then I can put that into a small package
and redeliver it in a way that everybody
can understand it that way you guys
don't have to stay up till six in the
morning reading the internet I already
did that for you and I'll come put that
out for you I feel like I'm I'm
compelled by I don't know what you
believe in they call me Rasta Jeff I
wear red gold and green colors all the
time you know what I believe in that's
not important whatever you believe in
that compels me to share this message
with you that just and if I didn't share
that message it would be disrespectful
to whatever gave me this gift and this
energy so thank you for noticing uh
thank you for mentioning uh that I share
this knowledge so it does go on there's
actually content to the message that
says I've been growing for a couple of
years and a 4X4 tent and I've been been
searching for some prime females and I
now have a few so far including lemon
Jeffrey and an orange gasm that is very
promising at this point all right so
we're grown in a 4x4 you've been
searching for some stuff and you've got
a lemon Jeff and an orange gasm I'm glad
I'm glad you found those those are great
lines they're going to do very well for
you it also says I've always wanted to
create my own strains since I started
smoking 28 years ago bro we're on the
same team we're OG veteran smokers and
also I understand that feeling of
wanting to create strains something
about it you just know you're like I
could breed something and then it's in
you so you're ready to do it bro let's
get it on anyway it says I found a male
that I've been keeping for a while and I
really like and I'm going to do a pollen
run in the next month after I finish up
this flower run sounds like a good
strategy this male has a structure I
want and the smell is exactly what I
want I want to collect as much pollen as
I can and hold on to it that's a good
strategy I don't collect pollen most of
the time I honestly just do live plant
pollination plant porn if you will but
your collection an idea will work it
says at what point in flower should I
pollinate the female's four best results
I know it won't be the same time for
every pheno and plant but a general idea
is all I need and I can play with it
from there thank you for all you do from
the community peace from Phila bong big
shout out to my buddy philabong this is
a great question I don't remember if
I've said this or not but phillabong
please do send me your real name and
your shipping address so that I can get
you a free pack of irie genetic seeds of
course that seed giveaway is sponsored
by iridirect.com make sure you go check
out iridirect for all the recent
restocks and drops but now let's answer
this question about pollination timing
this is a really good question so the
parts on the plant though we like to
call hairs a lot of Growers call them
hairs those are pistols the little
dandelion parts that is the part of your
plant which will receive the pollen the
pollen will hit that little uh that
little hair that's sticking up the
pollen will travel down that hair and
inside once it gets down to the bottom
there it'll hit the ovule inside of the
bract and that is where the seed will
begin to form now you are right with the
idea that not every plant and phenotype
is going to be ready for pollen at the
same time but it is generally between
days 18 to 23 ish all the way up to
about day 32-ish depending on the plant
I often talk about my strawberry fields
and my Platinum Tangy plants because
they want pollen at very different times
the Platinum Tangy plant that I breed
with is ready for pollen approximately 7
to 10 days before that Strawberry Fields
plant so it's ideal for me to stagger
those two plants when I put them in the
room so I can get them at their Peak
pollination times at the same time they
don't go in the same time so I'll put
that Strawberry Fields plant in there on
one day and then I'll wait about a week
or 10 days then I'll drag that Platinum
Tangy plant in there now they're both in
flour and they will both be ready for
pollen at the exact same time now what
you're looking for my friend as a new
breeder those pistols will receive
pollen as soon as they begin to form but
what I recommend is watching that plant
and learning that plant you should be
breeding with the plant you have grown
several times you've got a few Great
Cuts in this this room you should be
watching these plants get an idea when
do those pistols look the biggest the
fluffiest the most available when are
there the most of them you can tell by
looking the pistols are going to start
off by popping out of the buds and
they're going to get longer then they're
going to get thicker when they are at
their longest and thickest point that is
Peak pollination time those are the
plants pollen receiving parts that was a
lot of peas in one sentence there but
those that is Peak pollination time when
those pistols are nice and ripe you'll
have to look at the plant there is no
perfect day for pollination you've got a
nice window there's a nice time frame of
when these plants will receive pollen
they'll receive pollen probably all the
way up from about day 17 all the way up
into like day 35 or 40 maybe even later
that are able to receive pollen if there
are pistols available they can probably
receive pollen eventually those pistols
dry up and weather up and they can no
longer take it but as long as you've got
pistols on there you can pollinate them
what you've got to do is the breeder is
pay attention to those female plants and
see when you've got the maximum amount
of pistol healthy viable pistols
available another thing I'm going to
recommend is don't touch those pistols
if you plan on pollinating a plant don't
touch those pistols if it's with your
hands with your shirt with anything try
not to touch them we want them healthy
and viable and active also I don't like
to spray plants that I'm going to
pollinate I feel like those sprays can
disrupt those pistols and I want as many
as I can have now I know you would like
a closer number a more accurate a more
precise number of when to pollinate
these plants I'm going to say sometime
between day 25 and day 32 is usually the
best time you've got about a week window
there that is usually Peak pollination
time here's what happens if you
pollinate too early you don't get as
many seeds as you could have you could
have gotten more seeds here's what
happens if you pollinate too late you
don't get as many seeds as you could
have if you pollinate right at the right
time you get the maximum amount of
perfect beautiful ripe seeds if you
pollinate too early you're just not
going to get as many if you're making
these seeds for yourself that will not
be a problem if you pollinate too late
it will not be a problem if you're
making seeds for yourself if you if it's
your first run you can put the plant in
there and whenever it's got enough
pistols you can pollinate it or you can
put two plants in at the same time and
they will pollinate on the right time
and you will make plenty of seeds to
play with it's that second third and
fourth run is when you're going to want
to learn how to dial things in and time
it more perfectly so that you can get
the maximum amount of seeds I breed for
production people are buying my seeds I
need the maximum amount of seeds that's
why I drag plants in at different times
and I really get the timing nailed down
if you can't do that that's fine put a
plant in a room put another plant in a
room put some pollen on those [ __ ]
and make some seeds it's not as
technical or hyper critical as we would
like it to be this happens in nature
outdoors with no control nature just
does it and it [ __ ] works every year
on its own so don't stress too much
don't be too hyper critical about the
timing fall in love with the process of
breeding watch when those pistols are
ripe watch when that male plant starts
dumping his pollen make documents make
notes of both of those things these
plants look really ready for pollen
about day 23 about day 27 and they kind
of started looking withered up I should
probably pollinate around day 24. make a
note of when your male plant really make
a note of when he starts dropping pollen
day 14 he started putting out pollen day
23 he was dumping by day 32 I couldn't
walk by him without pollen flying
everywhere then at day 45 he quit making
pollen document that [ __ ] then do the
math equation in the future and you know
I need pollen at this time I need
[ __ ] female plants will be ready at
this time do the math and get them in
the room at the same time and get them
going but honestly like I said a moment
ago it's not hyper critical if you've
got pistols and you've got pollen you
will get seeds my dude all right my
friend Phila bong I hope I've answered
your question this was a great question
here once again please do send me your
shipping info so that I can get you a
free pack of irie genetic seeds and I
know I've said this on a couple of
episodes but it keeps happening if you
have won free seeds and you would like
me to send them to you please include a
real name it doesn't have to be your
real name but like a logical rational
name for me to put on the package I
don't want to put filabong on your box
no offense to fillabong that's a great
name but if you want the USPS to go
through your package fillabong is a
great way to get your [ __ ] investigated
and cause everybody in the chain a few
problems all right so send me your real
name please I'd love to get you a free
pack of seeds all right I've got another
great question here in front of me this
one also did come from the grow help tab
on iregenetics.com which means my friend
Scott has won a free pack of seeds Scott
you know the drill my dude please send
me your real name and your address so
that I can send you a free pack of irie
genetic seeds this one again came from
our buddy Scott he has a general grow
question and it says I run a six two
light schedule during veg and 12 12
during flower okay so he's got the
lights on for six hours on and two hours
off it sounds like during veg which
sounds one monkey but I understand why
that works I already know people are
going to be triggered by that six hours
on and two hour off light schedule
during veg they're going to say why
don't the plants go into flower because
that two hour dark frame is just enough
to let the plants go to sleep and then
he wakes them up right before they're
actually in the sleep mode or it would
trigger them to go to flower I
understand that then 12 12 like normal
and flower the question here is could I
do something like 6 2 6 12 during flower
six on two off six on 12 off
um I understand the question my main
answer I wrote this on the paper it says
why why would you try to do that why do
you want to do that that two hour off
period is basically making your plants
hungry for life that is two hours that
they could have gotten photons uh Photon
energy in the plant in the room and they
could have done that much more work so
over 60 days that's 120 hours of photons
which you are neglecting to give these
plants which they could have gotten
think about it this way if you are a a
um a gym rat let's just say you're going
to the gym and you're trying to work out
I'm working out two more hours a day
than you every single day so at the end
of this 60 day cycle I've got 120 more
reps or whatever you want to call them
under my belt my plants are going to be
stronger my plants are going to be
bigger better more robust because
they've gotten more light that is my
opinion and my experience
um so if you're doing six two in veg and
they're not going into flour six two
six is definitely not going to work for
a flower cycle you're doing that
basically and it's I don't I don't think
that that would work for a flowering
cycle and I don't I don't get why you
want to do that so I guess I've got a
follow-up question my dude if you really
want to do this please explain to me why
why do you need to do this what is the
method to your Madness but my quick
answer is why why are we Reinventing the
wheel in this way and I do understand
that I've introduced the 186 light cycle
at the end of flower but I can give you
a very rational and well spoken and well
thought out reason as to why I'm doing
that I don't see a rhyme or a reason for
this new technique unless maybe the room
is getting too hot you need to save some
electricity but there are other ways to
work on that strategy my first answer my
dude is why and then I want some
follow-ups I want to know why you're
going to do this why that's straight up
it why what you thinking bro send me a
follow-up I look forward to it but you
still get a free pack of seeds so please
do send me like I said a real name and a
shipping address alright I've got one
more more a question here in front of me
we're going to bang this one out right
here at the end of the episode this is a
quick one also came from the irie
director irie genetics website the grow
help tab this one came from Monsoon City
big up to my dude Monsoon City it says
quick question I got some rhombus
freebies a while back are those Femmes
because I only see fem rhombus on the
website yes that is correct the rhombus
is a feminized line I have not made that
in regs I don't think I will make reg
seeds of the rhombus
it's possible but I don't have any plans
for that at this current time so those
are feminized seeds the website is quite
accurate at this time I think if there's
something missing on the website that
you'd like to see if there's a detail
please let me know I'm working on
updating the website it's mostly me that
does I've got a web guy that does this
stuff but I've got to create the content
and then I'll send it to him but if
something's wonky or wrong please let me
know I will correct it but my dude
Monsoon City those are feminized seeds
thank you for asking thank you for
verifying I do appreciate that ladies
and gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast like I said
before the numbers got jumbled in my
recording schedule so if I said the
wrong number at the start of this
episode or the wrong number at the start
of the next episode please forgive me
we've been taking dabs you know how [ __ ]
goes also we talked about that brain
injury sometimes things get a little bit
mixed up if you have any questions
Corrections come comments or concerns
you know that I would love to hear from
you my email address is grow from your
heart hotmail.com don't be shy of course
please do send all of those grow
questions to the grow help tab that way
you can win free seeds if I read your
question here on the show also make sure
you check out the patreon at patreon.com
forward slash grow from your heart the
folks on patreon usually get the heads
up on the restocks and drops that I
redirect before anybody else they also
get quite a few coupon codes and I do
intend to give you some extra special
bonus content here in the summer I've
been overwhelmed no excuse I got to get
my [ __ ] together and deliver for the
patrons patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart for coupon codes and
updates on restocks on I redirect stay
up to date I think that's all I've got
for you everything else you could
possibly need is on my website
irygenetics.com make sure you check out
the website I hope to see you at the
dude grows cup the dude grows cup is
happening next weekend I look forward to
seeing you there if you need a ticket if
you need info check out dgc
cup.com all right that's all I've got
for you I want to give a giant shout out
to my buddy Smokey Joe and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
foreign
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you