if you have a hundred unopened packs of
seeds in the vault but you're still
trying to explain to the wife why you
need this one new pack go ahead and
click subscribe
[Music]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 803
of the grow from your heart podcast in
this episode we're going to talk a
little bit about feminized seeds I'm
also going to give away free seeds
that's right stay tuned we'll talk more
about the free seeds later in this
episode speaking of free seeds this
episode will come out the day of the
dude gross cup I'm going to try to put
it out just a bit early if you listen to
this episode before the dude grows Cup
starts come to my booth and say the word
kangaroo and I will give you a special
prize if you can't make it to the dude
gross cup make sure you check out my
website irydirect.com there's a lot of
great seeds up there at a lot of great
prices and every order does come with
free seeds all right I think that's all
the business I need to cover here at the
start of the show let's move our way
into everybody's favorite part of the
podcast that is the question and answer
section of the show this question came
from the grow help tap on the irie
genetics website if you go to
iregenetics.com there's a row of tabs on
the top one of them does say grow
questions click on that we will give you
the opportunity to ask your grow
question and if I read your grow
question here on the podcast guess what
you win free ire genetic seeds our first
question came from our friend just in
case big shout out to my buddy just in
case I see your name pop up a lot on
social media a lot on the patreon I see
your name thanks for all of the support
also please do send me your real name
and a good shipping address because you
my friend win a free pack of irie
genetic seeds let's jump into the grow
question it goes a little bit like this
it says yo Rasta Jeff I'm loving the
genetics bro I'm glad they're working
well for you bro it goes on it says I do
have a grow question good because that's
what we are here for my bro it says I
want to make some feminized seeds that's
a good Mission he says I have the
ingredients for the STS solution so
they're going to make their own silver
thiosulfate solution if you want full
instructions on how to make that in my
method I've done a full podcast it is
called my St yes mix go to YouTube
search for that or I should drop a link
in the YouTube video or possibly in the
wherever you're watching or listening
there should be a link all right so
there should be a link to the STS
solution video I'll tell you where to
buy everything how to mix it and mostly
how to apply it this question does say I
would love to know what to expect and if
you have any tips do I spray just the
nodes before there are flowers expecting
both sex parts to develop on the area
sprayed or is this whole plant going to
respond ah thanks for the answers from
our friend Justin Case bro just in case
thank you for the great question I have
recently done a podcast that covered a
lot of this but I realize that I may not
have talked a lot about actually
spraying the plant so there are a couple
of questions here I would love to know
what to expect well when you start
reversing this plant what I would
recommend and I've done a full episode
on this so this will be kind of just a
quick refresher what I recommend is
spraying the plant seven to ten days
before you put that plant into flour
pull that plant out of the room maybe
put some newspaper or something on the
floor if you're doing it where the floor
needs to stay clean because when you
apply apply the solution it may turn
white walls or white things a little bit
of a purple color so maybe put something
down move the plant out to there spray
it now wait seven to ten days and do
this again we're going to spray the
plant seven to ten days before flower
then we're going to put it into flour
we're going to spray it on day one three
six nine twelve fifteen eighteen twenty
one and if the plant is being stubborn I
will spray it again on day 24 that's my
own personal preference there I just
experiment with that last day sometimes
it's not necessary sometimes it is
necessary so what to expect
um when you first spray the plant you
might not see anything when you first
spray the plant that plant May react
strongly plants react very differently
to different dilutions and dosages of
the STS application sometimes you spray
a plant you don't notice anything happen
sometimes you spray a plant and tomorrow
it looks like those leaves are going
crazy they're balled up they're curl and
they're twisting they're changing colors
that does look stressful but keep in
mind we're not growing this plant for
photogenic purposes we're not going to
make buds out of it we're not going to
make flowers we're disrupting this
plant's entire hormonal system so we're
going to see weird reactions from this
plant the main focus is that this plant
does produce pollen for us so sometimes
like I said those leaves are going to go
crazy crinkly twisty wild that's to be
expected in some cases with reversals
sometimes that plant didn't want that
much silver sometimes it needed more
sometimes they just basically freak out
when we do reversals so you may see some
weird [ __ ] don't worry too much unless
the plant is dying if you're not getting
any reaction to cause the pollen sacs to
form and the plant's looking like [ __ ]
then you're probably over spraying but
that it's hard to tell until you're
actually doing it how much spray to give
that plant I do have recommended dosage
rates in my podcast that I made earlier
but you do have to do some experimenting
and some adjusting so things to expect
you may see some weird [ __ ] from the
leaves eventually you'll see little
nubbins pop up where your flowers
normally form so let's say this
microphone is the top of the flower
normally you get little pistols starting
to pop up and little a little braxal
form instead you're going to see it's
going to look like little balls popping
up and those are where the pollen sacks
are going to form so that's mainly the
first few things to look for and to
expect do I spray the nodes before the
flowers expect okay the question is do I
spray the nodes when I'm spraying silver
thiosulfate I spray the entire plant I
spray it from the bottom up I start at
the bottom I work my way up and I spray
the tops of the leaves and the bottoms
of the leaves and I definitely spray the
center stalk and every Branch let's get
as much of this silver into the plant as
we can when it comes to pesticide
applications I may focus more on the
leaves when it comes to the silver I am
trying to get the entire plant I don't
want to spray it till it's dripping off
maybe just a little bit of droplets
coming off but not running off I want
that silver to stay on the plant I don't
want it all to drip off and fall off the
plant and end up in the floor so spray
the entire plant then it says Ah do I
spray just the nodes before there are
flowers you're going to want to spray
early do I expect both sex parts to
develop on the area sprayed so that's a
good question sometimes I've talked
about this previously sometimes if you
spray one branch of a plant sometimes
that plant is real sensitive and the
entire plant will reverse sometimes if
you spray one branch of a plant the
plant is super stubborn and it will not
reverse at all sometimes if you spray
one branch of a plant it will do the
magic best thing you could happen it
will make pollen on that one branch and
the rest of the plant will stay female
you can either smoke the rest of that
plant I don't recommend it if you spray
it with silver but it's possible or you
can pollinate the other side of that
plant with your one side that is
reversed so the part that you spray is
going to reverse the part that you don't
spray possibly will not reverse I've
said it before this part is very plant
specific very phenotype specific every
plant will react differently to this so
like I said I'm going to recap that part
sometimes you will select one branch and
spray that one branch sometimes it
doesn't do anything sometimes it
reverses the entire plant sometimes it
just reverses that one branch it kind of
depends on that plant and how it reacts
to the silver now part of your question
was what can I expect now since we've
learned how to spray the plant properly
other things that you can expect are
around Day 26 to 32 you should start
seeing pollen I don't move the female
plants into the breeding room until I am
sure that this reversal is working so
what that means to me is when I see
you'll be able to tell you'll say
something's way different on this plant
when the female flowers don't look like
female flowers they look like male
flowers popping up when I am sure of
that when I can verify that the reversal
is working that's when I put the female
plants into flower and that times it
pretty well because by the time the
pollen starts dropping from that
reversal those females will be reaching
their Peak ovulation time so that is a
big big tip a big hint and definitely
something to look out for make sure the
reversal is working now I've talked
about that extra day of spraying some
cultivars are stubborn if you stop
spraying they will revert and go right
back to female it's going to be your
longer flowering cultivars that need
that extra spray so if you've got
something that goes a little bit longer
maybe you've got an 11 or 12 week
flowering plant those are the plants
where I would consider that one extra
spray of the STS solution so I think
this should answer the bulk of your
question the main part of the question
was uh do I have any tips and what to
expect uh yeah look out for those male
parts to form on that plant that's the
most important part then work on the
timing once you see those male parts
forming move the females into the room
with that plant and then you should time
everything beautifully all right just in
case I feel like I've answered this
question pretty good the first part is
what to expect expect that female to
start showing you signs that it is
reversing into a male as soon as you see
those signs move that plant one thing I
recommend is document when that pollen
drops that way if you want to make more
seeds also document everything document
how you made the STS solution what
dilutions it was when you sprayed it
document all of that then also document
when that pollen starts to drop so if
you do want to make more seeds we've got
a little bit of a guideline a little bit
of a timeline a little bit of a heads up
some experience and documentation to
remind us what happened last time
um do I spray the whole thing we talked
about that and we talked about which
part is going to reverse then after you
do all the pollination then the next
important part is to let those seeds
finish and then you get to the fun part
Harvest them grow them and then see what
you've created that is always the fun
part my dude just in case thank you for
the great question once again please do
send me your address because I owe you a
pack of irie Genetics seeds all right
let's keep this party moving I do have
another great question here in front of
me this one also came from the grow help
tab on the ire genetics website once
again if you've got a grow question go
to the ire genetics website find that
grow help tab send me your question if I
read your question here on the show
guess what you in a free pack of seeds
the next free pack of seeds goes to our
friend Smurf groan big shout out to
Smurf groan please do send me your
address and a real name so that I can
get you a pack of seeds this question
goes a lot like this it says yo Rasta
Jeff I have a breeding question when
making Femme seeds do you chop down and
remove the Reversed plant like you would
a regular mail and if so when do I do
this thank you for all the help from
Smurf groan this is a very good question
because a lot of us are limited on plant
count and we don't need that mail
sticking around too long because we want
to fill that plant count space with an
actual female plant that we can do
something with or maybe you have that
extra mail sticking around putting you
in limbo for your numbers I understand
why you may want to get rid of that mail
and not have them around too long we
want to clean up and get the next
project going with the mail around that
does kind of slow things and give you
some obstacles so what I like to do when
I make seeds most of the time I like to
pollinate two times I like to let my
pollen donor develop a nice big batch of
pollen then I do the pollen tap I tap
that plant or shake that plant let the
pollen get into the room sometimes put
it right in front of the fan let's just
get some pollen in the room do a
pollination then I'll wait five to ten
more days usually it's about seven days
I go in there a week later and that
plant has developed more pollen that's
right it's built up more pollen he's had
some time to chill out he had a sandwich
and a Gatorade he's ready to make
another mess go in there and sprinkle
that pollen around after that second
pollination I generally cut the plant
down I'll take that big main top and
I'll cut that down if I want to gather
the pollen I'll put that big top in a
Pyrex dish and just let it sit for a
couple days and get real dry then I'm
able to remove that pollen store it
collect it and keep it for future uses
oftentimes if I don't want that pollen
for the future because most of the time
I honestly don't store pollen I've got
live plants I like to do live breeding
that is my breeding style a lot of times
what I will do is I'll take that the
main top of that plant and a couple of
the other bigger buds the male flowers
and I will hang them in the room
strategically over other plants and I'll
just hang them there for a couple of
days and they will dry up very quickly
there's a lot of airflow there's a lot
of heat in the room the plant has been
cut it will dry as it dries that pollen
naturally falls out of the plant onto
the other plants that need to receive
pollen so that's just one more way to
get a little bit more pollen out of my
reversal because honestly the reversals
do not make a lot of pollen compared to
a regular male plant I think I get about
maybe a third as much pollen from a
reversal as I do from a regular male
pollen donor so I pollinate two times I
Chuck the pollen the one time give them
a week to build another pollen load
check that other second load of pollen
then cut the tops off and hang them
upside down let them hang for a couple
days they'll naturally drop a little bit
of pollen but then after that once I'm
tired of seeing them there I'll pull
down the tops and I'll smack it against
the fan or against the other plants or
something just in an effort to knock out
that very last bit of pollen and get it
in the room so I can get as many seeds
as possible because like I said
reversals are stingy you don't get as
much pollen as you could from a regular
male plant it just doesn't give you the
big cloud the bunch of dust sometimes I
have to use multiple pollen donor plants
just to fill the room with enough pollen
to make it happen so that is when the
plant goes in my experience in my room
uh he gives me one load of pollen he
gives me another one then I cut him down
and I actually actually am able to get
more pollen from him a third time by
smacking against the wall or the fan or
something like that or just beating it
on the other plants but once he's done
he's done we can get him out of there I
usually do it after the second round of
pollination all right my dude Smurf
thank you for the great question please
do send me your shipping address and
like I've said before I will not send a
box to Smurf groan Noah offense but
that's how we just cause problems for
ourselves put a real name on there
nobody will have any questions and it
will make it to you that way everybody
wants their seeds to get to them all
right I do have one more great question
here this one also came from that grow
help tab this one came from our friend
Marley's grow room big up to my friend
Marley's grow room guess what Marley if
you haven't caught on by now you win a
free pack of seeds so please do send me
your shipping address and once again a
real name so that way I can get your
seeds to you promptly the question does
go a little bit like this it says good
evening Rasta Jeff good evening bro
thanks for the great message it says I'm
sending love and good vibes from the
show me state big shout out to all my
friends in the show me State uh big
shout out to show me cannabis it goes on
it says I've been listening to your
podcast for some time now and I
absolutely love the vast variety of
information you give out there's a lot
to unpack there are a lot to be thankful
for uh thanks for listening for a long
time and thanks for thinking that I'm
giving you a vast variety of information
I like that I noticed that sometimes I
do get stuck into the breeding questions
because those are my favorites but I
really do try to mix it up have a
variety of info that I'm sharing with
you guys so thank you for noticing it
says much love brother much love to you
so all as well it says so I recently
found a female plant that I would love
to breed with and I'm still pretty new
to that side of growing
um that's the way it works bro somebody
was asking me recently how I do
selections for breeding and I was like
it just sometimes they just they just
talk to me I don't know exactly what it
is they don't talk to me that sounds
like a crazy person but the plant I'll
be looking in a grow room of a thousand
plants and I'll go that one and there's
just something about a plant that speaks
to me as a breeder as a grower that just
says hey you should breed with me it
sounds like a plant just jumped up and
said hey I need you because these plants
are here doing their own thing and it
knows that it needs you to breed to it
so that plant called on you and got your
attention I'm glad you're paying
attention it does go on it says
um I absolutely dig this girl and how
well she handles stress that's a great
trait for a eating plant and even smokes
and produces some flower rosin it sounds
like you got a true winner there it says
I absolutely dig this girl oh wait I
skipped some [ __ ] there we go now I'm on
the hunt for a good male to bring into
the party
um so that brings me one quick question
right away uh if this plant is so
amazing and so perfect why do you want
to breed to it like is that uh do you
want to improve it do you want to
reproduce it do you want to add those
traits to something else I'm just
curious what your goal is because a lot
of breeding is all based on that goal so
I want to know what you plan to do with
this perfect plan if you want it to be a
contributor to a project if you want to
carry that line on if you want to see
what it does when you mix it with other
[ __ ] I'm just curious what your
intentions and your goal are now it goes
on it says for the strain I love would I
be better to hunt a male to breed with
or stick with the female to carry on the
traits I hope this makes sense in some
way thank you for the good time sir and
much love from Marley's grow room no
this totally makes sense and that's kind
of what I was touching on you've got a
few options here if you just want to
reproduce this plant for preservation
purposes if you want to make more seeds
of this plant just to see what it does
we've got a couple of options one of our
options is to make feminized self seeds
that's one of the first things I would
do for preservation since this plant has
really got your attention it would be
heartbreaking if we lost this plant of
course we could take clones we can have
a mother plant that's always great but
[ __ ] happens sometimes the power goes
out sometimes we have fires floods and
disasters I hope you don't but that [ __ ]
does happen if one of those things were
to happen it would be great to have a
backup supply of seeds of this plant a
really easy way to do that is to cut two
clones spray one with silver Don't Spray
the other apply the pollen to the other
you will make feminized seeds of your
favorite cut approximately 30 percent of
those seeds will grow to look just like
the plant that you used there will be
some outliers there will be some plants
that look like the moms some plants look
like the dad and there'll be some plants
that look like some totally weird [ __ ]
but the plant that you are seeking will
be in that preservation pack that's what
I would call it that first batch of
preservation pack now you've got other
options here if you want to do true
breeding to a male to a female I would
find a male that compliments that female
there are several ways to go about it
one thing that I always find successful
I find a plant that is the opposite of
the plant I am breeding to so I don't
know anything about your breeding plant
let's just say that it is tall it is
Slender and it tastes like lemons I
would find something short and squatty
that tasted like chocolate just because
they're so vastly different than when
you combine those you're going to make
brand new amazing [ __ ] with a lot of
great opportunities a lot of good
potential if you bread your tall slender
lemon plant to a tall slender lemon
plant we're just making more [ __ ]
tall slender to lemon plants if you
bring that tall slender lemon to a tall
slender strawberry you're going to get
tall slender strawberries and lemons
let's try to make something new and
different instead of just copying the
[ __ ] that we've already got unless that
is your goal if you just want to find a
male that just helps you to produce
seeds from this plant just to see what
it does but one of my favorite things to
do is to take one male plant and
pollinate multiple females that way I
can see what that male plant is bringing
to the mix so you've got options you can
reverse it and if you reverse it you can
actually pollinate more females as well
that's always fun different females and
you can still see what that reversal
adds to the mix as a breeder but your
first option one of your options is to
reverse this plant make Femme seeds out
of it or you can breed it to a male that
is vastly different then that is going
to give you brand new crosses once
you've got that brand new cross then I
would consider doing a back cross find
one so you've got the perfect female
then I would find a male plant that
looks just like the original female that
you've got and I would breed that male
to the female now you made your back
cross one then I would find another male
out of that batch of seeds it looks just
like the female read it back to that
original mom again you got a back cross
too keep going eventually you're going
to make exceeds that make exact copies
around F5 F6 you should make exact
stable copies of the plant you were
working with so this does make great
sense this is a great question but
without knowing what your overall goal
is and without knowing what you want to
do with this plant what your vision is
what your dream is I don't know exactly
the ways to guide you but I know that
your options you can reverse this plant
or you can pollinate it with the male
your selection of the mail is going to
make a big influence on the future of
this breeding project you want to open
it up and bring out brand new [ __ ] or do
you want to dial in the traits that you
already like that's where you make
breeding decisions I do love that you're
inspired to breed and I love that you
come to me for questions please do send
me a follow-up so that we can give you
more and better guidance on this to get
you in the direction that you're trying
to go send me some specifics let me know
your goal let me know what you want and
the outcome and I'll help get you there
all right my dude I almost said your
real name my dude Marley's grow room
thank you for the great question once
again please do send me your mailing
address because I would love to send you
a free pack of irie Genetics seeds
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you for listening to another episode of
The Grow from your heart podcast this
one may be a little bit short after some
editing but we've got the dude grows
coming up and I've been killing it the
past couple of weeks so thank you for
listening to a short episode I'll be
back in another week with fresh new
content if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
the email address is grow from your
heart at hotmail.com don't be shy please
do send all of those grow questions to
the grow help tab on iregenetics.com
also when you're at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the patreon campaign
there's a link to the Discord there's a
link to iridirect there's a link to the
merchandise click around you may find
something that gets your attention all
right that's all I've got for this
episode I'll be back in a couple of days
with fresh new content I want to give a
giant shout out to my buddy Joe the bud
tender and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you