foreign
[Music]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is a very fun
a very special episode of the girl from
your heart podcast joining me today for
the first time in nearly 100 episodes
I've got my buddy White Mike on the mic
on the camera with us welcome to the
show bro what's up buddy thanks for
having me back dude it is an honor a
pleasure a privilege and a lot of other
words that probably start with P to have
you here on the show thanks for taking
some time out to join us dude yeah man
I'm so glad I was able to get away and
uh get into the studio this is a lot of
getting away bro let's jump right into
it we're gonna kind of [ __ ] chatter
here at the start but you said getting
away uh dude you got away you got away
for a full weekend to come to the dude
Grove
some good times we got to travel up to
the dude grows cup you guys have you
been listening following along you know
that the dude gross cup was coming up
I've been advertising heavily on every
episode guess what it was Saturday it
was Friday and Saturday I got to take
Mike with me uh we rolled up to Fort
Collins uh bro it all started with a
crazy eventful Drive
um people of Colorado hey let's not die
on I-25 getting to places please let's
chill the [ __ ] out let's just get there
bro more of the gas pedal less of the
brake pedal and way less of that middle
[ __ ] finger you guys oh we
gotta center that because YouTube
doesn't like it when you say the word
[ __ ] middle finger in the first
10 minutes we can't monetize this
episode it's a good thing we're already
Shadow banned bro that don't even matter
but
we drove up
um had a crazy drive up there got to the
hotel we didn't get past checking into
the hotel before we were meeting
somebody that would come into play in
this story very as a very big key player
in this story so as soon as we got out
of the car we're meeting up with cool
people we check in I turn around from
the check-in desk to walk up to the
hotel room and somebody goes Rasta Jeff
and I was like yo and he introduced
himself as my name is hi check out my
weed so we're in the hotel smelling his
weed
excellent amazing weed that'll come into
play later on this here's story but as
soon as we get into the hotel we meet hi
we walk uh out of the hotel and then how
do we bump into Billy Billy came down
the stairs Suddenly at some point we ran
into Billy uh good he was coming off the
elevator as we were headed up yeah so
we're only at the hotel for 90 seconds
we run into a half dozen people yeah
we're already seeing parts of the crew
that put a really cool uh uh a party
under the whole thing the drive wasn't
stressful up there but the drive wasn't
the most relaxing drive we could have
asked for two near-death experiences it
was raining it was wild so once we got
up there we kind of shook all that off
we saw High we saw Billy and as soon as
we saw a billion High we knew yeah we're
like there was a party you guys so we
checked in with everybody where's the
pre-party there was a VIP party but uh
as the dude grows cup goes there's
always a pre-party before the VIP
pre-part it's just how we do it
everybody flew into town so uh we
figured out where everybody was going uh
we went to the hotels and kind of
dropped off some stuff and then uh went
to Food bro we went and got some tacos
man how were the tacos tacos were edible
tacos were not like I wouldn't head back
back there real fast but they were good
enough to get the the party started
notice I didn't say the name of the
place before I asked you to talk to us
uh so we got some tacos they did the job
you know we weren't starving but this
job done then we gathered up and we went
down to um a little place in Laporte a
little farm a beautiful Farm in Laporte
I don't know the name of the folks that
let us use their Farm but thank you if
you ever see this if you hear this uh
your farm is beautiful that's a
wonderful place thanks for sharing that
with us it was a perfect place for the
dude gross cup just the right size I
like how it's uh three left turns to
make it secluded three right turns
whatever and then you're just kind of in
the middle of nowhere but right there in
the middle of everything it was super
beautiful uh great place uh did The
Little Creek running through really set
a good vibe the the division that the
creek created was pretty cool uh so we
pull up and as soon as we park you could
just feel the vibe of the pre-party
everybody was in there others most of
the time at this event they do those
little individual 10 by 10 pop-ups every
breeder every brand has their pop-up
everybody's got their own little island
not this year not this year they did a
big what was probably a hundred was an
awesome change I don't know a big ass
tent just one big circus tent for all of
us uh crazy stoners to go party under
there and then they sectioned off little
sections for each breeder to have their
table but we showed up to the pre-party
and uh I grabbed just a table I saw an
Open Table I was like right there Mike
let's go dab I had my rig with me I had
a bunch of stuff exclaimed a spot
claimed a spot
um a couple minutes later all the irony
Army arrived 10 minutes yes so we made
the smoke Circle a nice big boy scout
circle with their camping chairs and
they were eating uh they served fried
chicken and all kinds of good food to
the guys they were all grubbing uh I
already got a plate everybody Mike and I
just went eight so I wasn't hungry but
they served a bunch of good food
everybody grubbed down I've got a really
cool family picture of everybody just
sitting in a big circle eating dinner
yeah I felt super cool that's when the
vibe really started kicking in you know
like uh we're here we're doing it yep
that's what that's when it got real it's
like it's really Cannabis Cup time like
let's go yeah so everyone but he's
chilling in these circles I'm taking
pictures of everybody and then after
everybody ate we smoked and we smoked so
much at the pre-party uh that when I
woke up on Saturday uh my eyes were
redder than uh the growth from your
heart logo that's probably down there in
the corner my eyes were redder than that
little red spot uh I felt like I had
drank a mouthful of sand in my sleep it
took me about an hour to get my life
back together I want to shake off that
buzz I'm not complaining but wow that
was a a fuzzy night yeah put ourselves
through some stuff I woke up in the
middle of the night my voice still isn't
right you felt like my throat was just
PVC I had to go drink hot water until I
could breathe you're drinking hot water
yep just got the top hot started just
splashes the hot water on the thing I
could breathe again man drinking hot
water to breathe again just is the
opposite of what I do it's crazy how we
handle things differently that made my
body feel weird I know tea is hot chick
it's the secret man if you get a sore
throat or Smoker's throat a little warm
water see I fired up the shower and got
that steam in there that's what David
for me so if you're right and that's hot
water bro but you were fighting dabs and
Paul and I was fighting dabs that's true
that is true I was sneezing before we
left anyway
um we woke up quite crispy in separate
hotel rooms we're gonna add uh quite
crispy yeah it was uh I don't want to
listen to this dude snore it's funny if
they put us several rooms away from each
other at the hotel but it still worked
out yeah I got a quarter room it was so
quiet as soon you left the room you
could hear people in the hotel but in my
room it was perfect silence yeah my room
sounded pretty busy was facing a parking
lot because between VIP party and cup
day I was like six hours of blackout I
was so lit that uh yeah I didn't even
hear all the traffic outside I slept
with my window halfway open at the hotel
because it was raining and it was so
nice out there such a beautiful time it
rained the whole time you guys but it
did not matter nobody even cared uh we
didn't even notice the rain it kind of
uh chilled out for a little bit but it
was constantly sprinkling so we had a
big old tent nobody even cared people
stood in line for their uh their taco
trucks and their Kona Ice and their
pizzas didn't even seem to care that it
was raining so the first night was a big
part of you guys we hung out we smoked I
got to take dabs with a lot of the cool
kids that I've been hanging out with on
Discord Billy bong was there Petro was
there uh the infamous hobbit feet was
there I'm gonna miss somebody if I try
to list off all the people so I'll stop
there but big shout out to all the
people that came I got to take dabs with
uh the whole crew that hangs out on
Discord people that I didn't even
realize were going to be there they
popped up I was like bro it's you you're
not driving the bus today so it's cool
to see some of those people that are
always on Discord with me I got to see
them face to face shake their hand give
them a fist bump smoke a dab smoke a
joint with them uh Mike was quite
popular too Mike hasn't been on the show
in nearly 100 episodes and I was shocked
that people were looking for me I was
like oh man I gotta get back on the show
now I feel really guilty yeah well
that's part of why you're here now bro
no more yeah no it worked y'all
so the pre-party was great the VIP party
was an excellent time we got to see a
lot of great people
um yeah that was the VIP party it was um
was really nice it was
you know the growing up they wore this
so many times like don't meet people you
bet on the internet in real life and
that was such a blast oh yeah sometimes
you need to go meet some internet
friends and have a real good weekend we
had a real good weekend with some
internet friends so that's just a
pre-party guys oh that was just Friday
night eventually the dude came and he
turned on the lights and turned off the
lights and made us all pack up and go
home boo to the dude no I'm just joking
bro
um he said it was because of the city of
Laporte we know it's because the dude
was tired uh he came and shut down the
party made everybody go home
um dude I love you bro I'm just picking
on you so uh we all went back to the
hotel some people went out and partied
and stuff I realized it was probably the
best move to go hydrate and go get some
rest because not everybody else was a
vendor they were all competitors and
chilling so they all went to breakfast
the next day and stumbled in hours later
yeah uh we were there uh for all the
vendors we showed up kind of toward the
middle of the vendor arrival we weren't
first we weren't last but it took us a
little bit to get set up because we kind
of had one of the more elaborate extra
extravagant boots I felt like yeah the
that nice heavy Banner takes a second to
set up looks really really good but uh
the folks with a little cloth Banner
like I understand those advantages that
look really light oh yeah I've got a
I've got a couple people on my team
helping me out shout out to Mike for
helping me out the whole dgc club shout
out to all the people that helped us
carry [ __ ] too yeah everybody threw it
it's it's such an awesome little
community and for the dgc cup it's all
family people it's not a huge open to
everyone event so
that's just like a whole bunch of
brothers and sisters and uncles and
cousins helping out with everything it's
awesome I think there were 320 tickets
sold plus whatever VIPs and vendor
passes and whatever I guess there was
about 350 people there at most times at
times it felt like way more but it it
always felt like the right amount of
people it was perfect yeah they were
talking about if they want to expand it
or if they want to keep it the way that
it is and my vote you guys dude uh
Scotty if it matters at all uh keep it
the size it was it was perfect if you
make it any larger you have to add more
infrastructure which will mean that you
have to add too many more people to it
to keep the vibe that it's got to make
it to add more infrastructure is going
to cost enough money to offset that cost
you got to add too many more people keep
it the way that it is that's my vote but
it's your event dude I'll keep coming
dude one thing we should talk about is
what I call the murderer's row of
vendors in our section uh it was our
table and then
um who was to the right of us that was
lemon hoko yep and then to the left of
us was Ike yeah Ike breeds and his Boy
locomotive we're gonna work together in
the future guys don't worry and then
next to them was JJ and Top Dog yes and
then the guy who had his girl won hot
rod hot rod Dramatics yeah we don't
expect Mike to remember yeah
hot rod
um uh hot rod actually placed in the cup
and when he went up and took his award
uh he said that he could not have done
it without his wife so that was super
cool it made a lot of people in the
crowd all mushy that's kind of nice so
we got a nice husband wife teams get it
right yes we got like uh so to One
Direction we've got hot rod JJ uh icon
locomotive uh Ike and locomotive did not
even bring anything to cell or vend they
got a table because they wanted to have
a cool place to party and they asked
specifically for a booth next to irie
genetics so they were next to me last
year too is this that was so awesome
yeah thank you big shout out to our boy
Ike big shout out to locomotive awesome
eventually the irie Army just invaded
their table everybody was hanging out
there I'm burping from kombucha excuse
me you guys a big shout out to Ike also
for setting up half the booth with Mike
Mike did most of the work but Ike was
like I'm [ __ ] bored give me something
to do and yeah he's like you want this
centered move this over here and I was
like bro this guy's pretty awesome so I
got us going
um then to the right of us if you're
facing out to the right of us was lemon
hoko and then to the right of lemon hoko
was [ __ ] the king Duke Diamond
big shout out to Duke diamond we did
talk
um Duke and I spoke there may be a
collab in the future I also spoke with
Titan uh Tardis if you're listening to
this put in some earplugs uh Titan and I
have spoken about a collab in the future
uh that made my buddy tardis's head
nearly explode when I mentioned that
shout out to my dude Tardis
um I don't remember the booth
immediately after that to the right
but I do know that one more Booth over
was our boy tenaci with sacred three
mushrooms yeah so that was I thought
that was a super great row of people I
knew everybody in that row basically uh
they're all irie Army all people I've
hung out with before I was the first
time I met lemon hoko but I've I heard
nothing but good things about lemon hoko
that dude is super cool right we were
having fun all day yeah yeah super
humble guy uh very soft-spoken
well-mannered dude
um so we're in our little murderer's row
there and none other so I'm helping a
customer an irie Army member buy some
seeds helping them go through their seed
selection process talking about like I
don't remember we talk about flower
times Terps grow advice right and so
that customer walks away that person
walks away and I look up and I'm like
hey can I help you bro oh [ __ ] guess who
showed up you guys James Bean showed up
to the party nobody knew the dude was
coming uh he's just standing there at my
booth just waiting to talk to me I was
like oh James Bean is right here it was
so great to see James Bean so that was a
really cool surprise
um so yeah I wanted to cover that
murderer's row of people that we saw
there it was a lot of fun
um it was a fun group to be a part of
the the whole party was just nuts the
from start to finish it was it was just
awesome yeah from the moment he puts out
a really nice event that is definitely
true also uh we should give a shout out
to little real for being a uh an awesome
camera person uh Scotty Real's daughter
little real ran around a little real as
a camera person do you get that joke uh
little real ran around as a camera girl
camera person uh and carried an iPhone
around all day and filmed most of the
events so there's a lot of great footage
from the event that were on Instagram
live a lot uh she went by all the booths
and showed off all their cool stuff she
was really fascinated uh by my Banger
with my face in it you guys have got a
banger uh dab Banger that's got my face
etched into it when she saw that she
thought I was people love the drip yeah
yeah that she's like that I don't have
one of those and I was like nope that's
just me bro all right so that covers
what I called Murderers Row there that
big group of vendors a group of Colorado
folks uh people that we see at all of
our favorite shows oh there were also a
bunch of other great vendors there uh
hlg was their Horticultural Lighting
Group was there J.R Tolkien had a booth
there I'm gonna miss a bunch of people
if I try to talk about all the boots
that was Murderers Row also I mentioned
it a minute ago the irie Army was out in
full force you guys the dude came up to
me and was like really an army and I was
like what else do you want to call us
there's a ton of us brought the whole
Army brought the whole Army bro we had
somebody to fill every position if you
needed the hiring Army there we had
everything under control
um but they uh they kind of infiltrated
and took over this little seating area
right in front of the booth and it was
just uh it was the ivory Hood right
there the army sets up a little Biv
whack and that fully happened at the cup
okay teach me this word Biv whack Biv
whack is that spelled like I think yep
pretty much it's sort of like the the
tents and the latrines and like the
place for lunch and we had everything
set up we even had like our own little
spot for trash bivwack OG coming your
way guys look for that bib wack OG the
Army set up camp man we definitely set
up camp the whole party yes we'll speak
talking of irie Army Let's uh big shout
out to the whole Army that made it out I
keep saying that you guys I was uh there
was more than one or two or three times
when I felt like uh like a proud dad or
something dude sometimes uh I forget
this little army that I Inspire and have
created and you guys are all a part of
and I forget dude and to be there and to
look out and just to see the Army
supporting your Ivory genetics t-shirts
and hats and [ __ ] all of it uh bro
that's a huge feel I can't put it into
words
um it made me yeah I had a couple of
tears in my eyes you guys what are gonna
move forward uh let's talk about the
winners of the dude grows cup yep time
to name some winners
um first of all let's talk about how the
winners are determined let's kind of
back up just a little bit so the yeah
the cup if you're unfamiliar uh entries
were what one big fat jar nugs I'm sure
they lose a specific weight I think it
was either an ounce or two ounces you
had to enter probably and I was
announced yeah enter one ounce I had a
conversation with somebody one everybody
had a nice fat jar to enter and then uh
each jar was randomly assigned a number
the jars are sort of lined up with a bun
tender in front of each one helping
people you know load up their little
one-hitters and if you enjoyed that
strain you had a little wooden tote
everybody got what five little tokens I
think and you got to vote for different
strands you liked and uh whoever had the
most tokens wins super simple setup yes
uh I owe a big shout out to miss blue
kiss Thank You Beautiful
um blue kiss was kind enough to go
package up a bunch of the entries in a
um you know those pill containers it's
like Monday Tuesday Wednesday noon
whatever time they had the month-long
ones so we could get 30 samples 30
samples in that bad [ __ ] they broke up
30 little samples and put them in their
corresponding numbers and brought them
to me so I got to smoke 30 samples thank
you blue kiss you're a hero that was
amazing I hope you hear this I got to
sample uh 30 of the samples without even
leaving the booth and a couple of them I
did a couple of the winners I did say
this one is a good one right here I
definitely knew that yeah I called
number two I was uh I called number two
uh I said number two was going to top I
picked one that I was wrong with number
one and number two definitely came in
second but I was like this one stands
out but anyway
um I keep saying we're going to talk
about the winners uh they did so we had
the cup right people smoked people voted
they tally up the votes I'm super proud
because they announced the top 10
winners at the dude gross cup and I was
super excited because this was my friend
Project's very first year entering in
any sort of competition he's never
entered his cannabis his grow into any
sort of uh event before he's uh said
that he's never been proud enough to
think it was good enough he entered into
the dude grows cup the kid is 26 years
old and he won 10th place out of I think
47 or 53 entries I heard
50-ish his house you know it wasn't 50
on the button but there were supposed to
be 50 competitors and they sold out so
there should have been at least 47 or
50. they sold out of competitor slots
but my dude won 10th place out of
approximately 50 and he's 26 years old
uh he uh he beat out a lot of the uh the
former Champions and a lot of the
current irate Army members and a lot of
really
um older more experienced Growers and
he's 26 years old so I'm super proud of
that dude uh big shout out to my buddy
project great work with your girl oh I
wrote down what you grew on another
paper I know what it is
[ __ ] it's from raw genetics I could no I
can't remember what you grew bro but it
was fire it was good [ __ ] we all knew
you stood a good chance no slurricane is
coming up we'll talk about that was a
different winner yes that definitely was
a different winner
um so many good strains at the cup there
were a lot of good strains never been to
a cup y'all make plans for next summer
uh yeah but get your tickets early
because that [ __ ] sold out super fast
this year um so let's work our way so
they announced on those winners 10 uh
one through ten and 10 stood out to me
because that was a good friend of mine a
buddy that I hang out with on Discord
all the time a member of the irie Army
it was super cool for that to be the
first announcement too right yeah that's
just set the tone starting off the
announcements yeah set the tone with one
of our kids well one of our I called him
a kid he's a [ __ ] kid dude I'm 20
years older than this kid and he's one
or winning Awards and he told me it's
because I taught him how to grow he said
I couldn't I couldn't have done it
this year yeah the youngsters are
killing it uh you old guys got to step
your [ __ ] up
um so let's move our way down to to
third place
um third place was won by Christopher
and Christopher I apologize I did not
write down the strain that you won with
but great work big shout out to our
friend Christopher that's what he uh
listed his name as on the winning sheet
so big up to Christopher Christopher did
receive a big irie genetics gift pack I
stacked him up a bunch of packs three
got a nice prize if I remember yes they
sure did uh so big shout out to
Christopher for third place and now
here's where it gets fun you guys
um I like to build some suspense but I
guess we're good yeah there you go drum
roll please
um second place was won by uh Trey K dgc
that's right the first lady grower to
win an award with the dude gross cup has
won second place second second yeah uh
Trey K dgc uh it's really great that she
won an event she's had a um a
frustrating month with social media
social media keeps messing with her
taking down accounts
um so that's that drives you nuts when
you're trying to build a brand and get
things going she wasn't going to come to
the cup and I gave her a weird pep talk
Rasta Jeff style I said just because you
don't have social media doesn't mean you
can't come to a Cannabis Cup in order to
a Grower's cup and win and guess what
she did not need any social media she
won the cup it would have been awesome
to share that on social media but it's
really just it's social media she still
wins we're still proud of her she still
kicks ass so she came she won second
place big shout out to my friend Trey K
dgc so awesome uh there's a great
picture on social media of me giving her
a big hug us giving each other a big hug
after she won
um it's just great to see your friends
win cups it's so awesome especially when
they're um supporters of your brand and
you've been supporting them it's pretty
rad so shout out to Trey kdgc for a
solid second place win with the
sluricane that's the slurricane that
we're talking about uh she grew that all
organically she said she said she just
added water and a little bit of crime uh
the crime is what got her second place
now let's work our way into the first
place announcement here this one's
awesome because
um my friend hi shout out to hi we ran
into high first thing as we walked into
the hotel we weren't even checked in yet
he's like roster Jeff I'm high when I
saw that's funny I'm high I never
thought of that
um when I saw his weed I was like bro
this weed is potential Cup winner this
is really good weed and he's like nah
it's okay weed I I kind of I could have
done better that's what everybody does I
was like no this is good weed dude and
I'm not sure that he took me seriously I
only told a couple of people this is
[ __ ] like quality weed one guy didn't
enter and I was like if you were to
enter this weed with a one and I think
I'm right but
um so I see my buddy hi and I'm like
that's good weed bro and guess what you
guys first place goes to my dude High
that's right a member of the irie Army a
good friend of mine my buddy hi has won
first place in the dude grows cup and
guess what he won with he won with
gelato runs that weed was good that was
Top Shelf herb number one I agree uh
rightly deserved congratulations to my
buddy hi also second and first place got
big old stacks of free seeds of eye
regenetics
yeah they uh nice prize pack huge win it
was a fierce competition I had people
running me samples for most of the event
they would run out pack me a sample run
it back to me and not one of them was
bad right they were all delicious they
all hit well they all elevated me quite
nicely
is a fierce competition man it
definitely wasn't to take first in that
group is huge yeah there were 50 quality
entries all of them stood a chance of
winning
um
it was pretty interesting that the
winning uh plant got 98 or the winning
strain got 98 votes most of them got
closer to 30. so that says a lot about
the quality of that strain it definitely
stood out yeah they uh the competition
was pretty Fierce for I remember the
numbers for the middle of the pack but
first it was first uh so really well
done but again well done first place was
well deserved yes shout out to all of
the winners also shout out to everybody
that entered their product into the
Cannabis Cup I talked to a lot of people
over the weekend friends of mine new
Growers that would show me weed and they
would say I don't think it's good enough
to enter the cup bro some of those
people showed me product that was better
than stuff that was entered and placed
well yeah there was
from the second we walked into the hotel
to the moment we they started announcing
winners people just kept showing us
awesome herb awesome herb I've got a
nice a collection of really nice weed
that people gave to me this weekend yeah
so does Mike we both got gifted so much
friendly uh Mike had a little I don't
know what you were doing you had a
little uh setup over there with Hobbit
and with Petro that every couple of
minutes they would just show up with a
one-hitter with fresh weed for you I
don't know what was going on I was
talking to people trying to sell some
seeds and having a good time I look over
and Mike's got little [ __ ] minions
and [ __ ] I'm like what are you doing for
these guys oh speaking of people
bringing us things I'm going to totally
derail this and cut this off I owe a big
shout out I don't remember the name of
the pizza company I know it is rasufa's
friend's Pizza Company dude we were
working our butts off Mike was working
his ass off I was talking my ass off
that's my job sell the seeds right but I
realized at one moment I was like I
haven't eaten and I'm gonna die we
talked to people continuously from 11AM
to 4 P.M without a bite to eat yeah we
just continuously one one person after
the next power talking and many many
dabs and then Matt yeah lots of
consumption and then pizzas arrived out
of nowhere rasufa came by and he said
roster Jeff what kind of pizza White
Mike what kind of pizza and we thought
that pizza line is is quite long it'll
be a little while and we'll have pizzas
dude suddenly it wasn't that long
suddenly pizzas appeared and they were
freaking delicious I don't I'm not
doubting the quality of that pizza it
might have been half because I was
starving like a [ __ ] hostage but also
that [ __ ] was so good right like you
have to take into account that we were
at a Cannabis Cup and for the hour
before we were able to eat we definitely
wanted to eat and the wind had changed
so that the smell of the pizza ovens oh
yes drifting across us so by the time
the pizza showed up we were definitely
ready for the pizza but that was a 10. I
was hypnotized I was hypnotized by the
pizza that [ __ ] was so good shout out to
rasufa and the pizza guy I apologize I
cannot remember the name contact us on
social media we will give the pizza dude
a proper shout out yeah he deserves at
least two of those yes he does one one
from each of us that was good pizza
thank you thanks for feeding us you guys
if you've got a booth at the uh at any
sort of event like that think about the
vendors see if you can uh see if you can
check on them it was super cool super
super kind to them and they're giving a
shout out on the show for it
um let's see we've got a couple more fun
things to talk about kangaroo bro
kangaroo kangaroo or hippopotamus or
hippopotamus so that's a kangaroo if you
guys watched the previous episode I said
come to me and say kangaroo I'll give
you seeds so many people got so many
cool free seeds I was giving out packs
of red line which is red Lebanese hash
plant to arise once I ran out of those I
gave out White Chapel which is the
Golden Goat to Jack the Ripper you'll
see why it got named that you'll
understand that
um then one of our friends we got
Nuketown some people gotta rise yeah
we've got whatever was in our hand when
people are going away somebody just said
wait they got a rise somebody out there
heard that and they're panicking they
got a rise you guys they're not
available right now but I will get them
up on I redirect very soon I need to
unload and recount things and get those
up on I redirect I do have a few very
few very limited number of packs of a
rise B grade seeds they're not top shelf
looking seeds uh they're just ugly
they're not as big and round and colored
as uh those seeds are that I think are a
grade so I couldn't sell them as a grade
C's like that's what I call some B
grades they still grow amazing plants
they just they're ugly seeds
um but ugly seeds make pretty plants
you'll never know in a couple of weeks
bro but they'll be up on I redirect
pretty soon so when Mike said people got
a rise he meant they got the B grades
um there's like 12 seeds 13 seeds per
pack or something and they'll be super
affordable we'll put those up uh but so
many packages of kangaroo the funny part
about kangaroo some uh beautiful smart
ass I love this joke somebody told his
friend that the password was
hippopotamus so this nice kind gentleman
unsuspecting gentleman walked up three
unsuspected before the guy came up and
owned his joke they said with confidence
they'd walk up to us and say
hippopotamus
yeah
I just laughed and gave them seeds
because I knew what had happened I was
like hey you're you're close bro you're
close but first person that came up to
me and said hippopotamus I walked him
through until they got kangaroo and the
second person I was just like oh man
it's a trend now the third one I I knew
what had happened immediately I was like
somebody told somebody the password but
they did it like they got telephone and
eventually that kangaroo became
hippopotamus which hey whatever I'll
give you free seeds this is some random
old Stoner that was like you know what
this will be funny I'm gonna start
telling people I run into to go talk to
those two and say the wrong animal it
was great you guys I'm going to do
something similar at The Groovy gravy
secret stash event coming up in Denver
uh make sure you check out my social
media I will be posting more info on The
Groovy gravy event coming up very very
soon our tickets still available for
that I'm not sure the tickets are
available yet for that but yes and
better yes
um I'll be there I know that Mace will
be there a big shout out to Masonic
seeds there'll be a lot of great vendors
there come hang out grab some seeds edit
straight up just a seed swap event
there's no Cannabis Cup involved so
coming out of the secret stash
um like I said before check my social
media I'll be posting more about that
all right Mike one of the things I've
got listed down here on my list of stuff
to keep us kind of on track on this
podcast it's kind of working it's like
the map I spilled coffee on I can't
figure out where to get through this
Canyon over here but we're gonna talk
about it
um I've got the word cup moments are
there any uh significant moments you
want to tell the people about here on
the podcast that you remember from the
cup
um well there was the one of my favorite
Cannabis Cup
moments there's always little cup magic
there's
serendipitous little moments that can't
be explained with rational anything and
there was a moment with
Tardis and a gentleman by the name of
John I believe yes
um who are from a different state
and uh John walked up to the booth and
said hey Jeff sorry I missed you last
year
um check this jar of Vortex that I have
out you've got to smell it and that's
just sort of how the high Jeff
conversation went at this at the VIP
party
um Jeff laughs and goes Vortex huh if by
Body Tardis shows up you're gonna have
to show them this and then Jeff sniffs
the jar and says that's awesome hands it
back and gets distracted by something
next to us
as he gets distracted Tardis appears out
of the [ __ ] Vapor there's like he was
summoned he was goes hey guys what's
going on and we all kind of laugh and
I'm like no way we literally just said
your name you gotta smell this and he
looks at John who's holding a jar of
Vortex and they look at each other funny
and he smells the jar of Vortex and gets
excited and it happens to be his
favorite Fino of the vortex and they're
giggling like school girls and then it
Dawns on them that they know each other
from home because they were accosted in
public by a crazy person together as
strange they're strangers they both
happen to be on a street together and a
crazy woman accosted them
and it happened insanely enough that
they registered like oh I looked at you
and I remember you from that and here
they are a whole other state away at a
cannabis a cup a highest giraffe [ __ ]
and one of them has the other's favorite
herb and Jeff summoned the moment out of
the vapor like it was beautiful everyone
asked about it the whole weekend oh yeah
that was great that was amazing just
weird cannabis Serendipity the best part
about that is
um if I'm on Discord in the evenings and
I'll be like Hey where's Tardis like
it's Tardis time we haven't seen Tardis
in a couple days if I say his name he
will pop in he's probably popping into
Discord right now going why are you
saying my name Rasta what's going on
like or
or the other option with Tardis he's
eaten like 8 000 milligrams of THC and
he's taking a nap with his camera on uh
Tardis likes to pass out with the camera
on uh but here's a good story about
Tardis we're just going to talk more
about my buddy uh Tardis ate one of
those I think it's 840 milligrams
honestly what I think his edible dose is
uh he ate that early in the morning he
had an edible that our friend Terps gave
him Terps warned everybody eat this when
you go home and go to bed but Tardis is
like I'm a robot so he ate it
um I looked over a little while later
and he's sitting at Duke Diamond's Booth
straight up asleep he was out it just
done but like an hour later he walked by
my booth and he's like what's up roster
I'm alive the dude looked like nothing
ever even happened to him he was fine
weed naps will recharge you dude
ah now you owe Scotty real 50 bucks
every time you say recharge it's okay or
the Scotty reload you 50 bucks every
time either way one of the ways shout
out to Scotty reel get some recharge get
some grow dots uh dude that little VIP
bag was pretty cool came with grow dots
a little pipe
um
the little one hitter for the cup it
came with a little poker that everyone
lost immediately immediately I have no
idea where mine ever went immediately
um yeah the the trick with the little
one-hitters was trying not to clear it
into somebody else uh I just kept
spinning it into the floor like shooting
it into the ground next to my boots like
a spitball yeah there was so you said
most of the samples were good there was
one that I lit it up and I was like like
I don't know which sample you were I'm
sorry I'm not calling anybody out I'm
not going to say what number but the
Terps disagreed with you dude when it
hit my tongue I had to blow it out and
then uh it was still burning in the
one-hitter so I just shot off this
flaming ball of weed out of the one
hitter I was like no dude we're not even
smoking that I had to stomp it out I
apologize for that
um they can't all be winners but
everything I tried was phenomenal I can
admit that I did not try them all I
could not try them all I think I tried
about 40 out of the 50. I definitely
knew I said number 30 I was like this
one stands out to me so tray K's herb
stood out to me High's herb stood out to
me uh there's a lot of quality Herb in
that event
um we're talking about cup moments uh
man the whole thing I feel like this
year
um I was able to connect better with the
people that sounds so weird to say it
that way but the people that come to the
booth uh the irie Army the customers the
fans the new people the old people the
Friends The Returning friends uh the
internet strangers that I just met in
person I feel like at this cup I was
much uh more present more able to
um of course I was smoking and there was
some of that barrier sometimes but
um I feel like I was more able to look
people in the eye and meet them and make
an actual connection with people at this
event it was really cool the the length
of the event and the the size of the
event population wise worked really well
together
um a nice long VIP party Friday night
and then a good cup Saturday was just
enough time for 350 people to group up
how they wanted to and really socialize
not just yeah hi how are you awesome
catch you later like there's a lot of
that at big events but this event was
now you was big but it wasn't like a a
big event you know right you really
gotta hustle to do what you want to do
there was plenty of time to chill and
chat and I don't think I felt like we
had to rush anybody no that's three yeah
everybody got their seeds I forgot and
like I was selling seeds I was giving
seeds taking money throwing it in the
money spot but I forgot that that was
like as the business went to we went
there as a business I forgot that part
dude we were having so much and there's
not a problem with it we were having so
much fun as the irie Army as just roster
Jeff and Mike that we did business but
we had so much fun that it wasn't even
like we were working we're just there
having so much fun you know when when uh
it wasn't until the wind shifted and the
pizza smell was going right over us that
I looked at my watch really for the
first time and I was like oh damn we've
been going for five hours non-stop yeah
just loving the flow having fun with
people coming up
um every person was happy excited having
a blast I didn't see like one sad face
the whole country no it was awesome it
was all good fun people that did not win
the cup whatever they were still happy
with themselves they still had a good
time they entered and they were proud
about it there was one dude who stopped
by a couple of times you actually gave
him his first stab oh yeah and I saw you
know a little soldier at the the pizza
line waiting for his spot like four
hours later just glazed like a Christmas
ham you're smile on his face
but this dude entered a jar for the cup
he he didn't think it was that good but
it was some of the best that he put
together he was excited that he entered
he thought it was kind of silly and I
remember at the end of it he was like
six people voted for me bro like I you
know can you believe that like I got a
vote that's Brad yeah and it's that's
what it's all about like you don't have
to win winning is amazing coming in
second third fifth like you guys worked
so hard you put so much love into that
herb and you can really really taste it
when people do that quality of a job
with cannabis but like this dude placed
almost I mean not dead last but like in
the very last
uh you know dregs of the race but
still he's among some of the best herb
in Colorado which is among the best I
remember I remember exactly the guy
you're talking about I could see a smile
he had a really wholesome smile just a
cool guy so I was like six votes man
that meant the world that was his first
time traveling for a weed event that was
his first weed event his first time
entering uh then bro this made him super
excited he took his first dab with me I
gave that kid his first dab and he was
wrecked I watched it hit him like I
watched the first phase of the dab hit
him and he was like I got high and then
he realized like 30 seconds later like
Whoop I'm [ __ ] getting higher like
and then he was just smiling and he was
like I don't even know what to say and I
go bro you don't have to say anything
just be high and enjoy yourself or I
could just see it it's just like I don't
have anything left to talk about and I
was like yeah you just [ __ ] erased
your brain with the dab dude it's okay
so he went wandered it around and then
you pointed him out he's like look at
this guy over here so happy in the pizza
line I was like [ __ ] yeah I got it so
high he's just over there just [ __ ]
melted trying to get pizza there was a
table with like condom comments and
napkins and stuff and he was just at the
end of it just like the happiest little
camper ever waiting his turn for a shot
at him yeah that's a great dude bro I
don't remember your name I apologize
I just said that I tried to connect with
everybody and I don't remember your name
I'm not sure that you remembered your
name that day brother but we had a great
time I'm gonna give a shout out to one
of our new friends Justin Justin's been
hanging out on the Discord uh but I'm
super proud because Justin also made it
out to his very first weed event uh he
allegedly came from Texas and he
allegedly also brought some beautiful
cannabis I was a cool dude it was great
to meet you Justin uh welcome to the
party bro thanks for coming and hanging
out with us
um we're talking about cut moments the
entire cup dude was magical I know that
so Drew Barrymore of me but it just felt
true it had like I said in the morning
is we're packing up there's a little bit
of rain and it was vendors just hustling
to get ready but we're all in a good
mood like hustling to get ready carrying
a heavy box with one hand smoking a
joint with the other like that's
hustling to get ready at the dude it
wasn't stressful we had offer or people
offering to help us carry stuff to load
in before we had the trunk of the car
popped you know who was parked next to
us offering to help us carry [ __ ] from
the very beginning of the event it was
high the guy that won the Cannabis Cup
right
the winner of the cup was like hey can I
help you carry stuff in before the event
guys that's how cool it was like the
winner the champion the guy had the best
weed was trying to help us carry stuff
in uh people just wouldn't watch Us
carry [ __ ] if they saw stuff like give
me part of that give me part of that it
was kind of cool so uh it felt like a
fish festival or some sort of like I got
those like you cannabis festivals
yeah we do bro yeah we do it was such a
great time
um it was one of the one of the things I
loved is
when we started setting up we realized
that our organization and our prep might
have not been as organization is
organized and prepped as we might have
liked so we had to you know rearrange
and reorganize and part of that
if I was working a different kind of
event would have meant a security risk
oh yeah just having that much Pro or
merchandise on a table at one time
within Arm's Reach of 350 people
um who are some degree of intoxicated
and it was not a problem the whole day
yeah seeds of bins just opened and I
never saw a hand go near them never yeah
people aren't going to do that there so
that that is Magic it was just everybody
took care literally I didn't see anybody
having a bad time like nobody was bummed
they had to wait in the line nobody was
bummed that you know people were rude or
whatever everybody was helpful everybody
was cheery everybody was jamming and
having a good time I mean there was a
little you know too much Supply in the
mix but you know I was just gonna
actually always is I was gonna
compliment them that the music wasn't so
loud we couldn't talk there was Sublime
but it sounded like Sublime that was
over there and that was perfect you had
to sing along in your head a little bit
with the music rather then shout over it
which is very nice if you guys ever
throw an event as a vendor as a host as
a sponsor whatever
um and you're responsible for the music
remember I'm trying to sell [ __ ] over
there and I paid to come have a booth
don't make me yell over the music like
we're already talking all day yeah we
want to get down but also the customers
would like to hear us the Shoppers would
like to hear us we're all paying money
let's uh let's turn it down just a
little bit I don't want to sound like an
old guy but I also don't want to sound
like an old guy all right Mike I
honestly have gone through uh most of my
notes Here is there anything else you
want to add to this part of the podcast
we can just freestyle at this point if
you got anything to say
um we should probably talk about the
bell of the ball a little bit oh yeah I
did skip over there is that it was uh
Friday Night of the Vib party we were
there maybe 15 minutes before it was
obvious that the Sherry Paloma was gonna
be the bell of the ball uh for every
three people that came up just show us
herb two of them had a cherry Paloma cut
yes it was either Cherry Paloma or
cherry Paloma cross to something I'm
sure Paloma was super popular also lots
of emergency out there this year a big
shout out to Jr token for making that
cherry Paloma super popular
um that it looks like the gelato runs
and slurricane are going to start
dominating the scene now because those
won the Cup this year that's what we're
going to hear about for the next year
those three I would expect to hear about
regularly for the next while yes yes
irie Army let's enter a whole bunch of
stuff next year from the ire genetics
lineup if you entered the dude gross cup
or any competition for that matter and
you win first second or third place I
promise you a big fat freaking prize
pack you'll get a bunch more seeds we'll
feature you'll put you on the podcast
and if you weren't able to make it to
the dude gross cup don't worry you guys
I do have a bunch of seeds at discounted
prices on iridirect.com I did make sure
to make some fair pricing uh to make
sure that the people that got seeds at
the cup don't feel slighted and also to
encourage you to get the seeds if you
were not able to make it to the cup make
sure you check out
iredirect.com Mike I think that's all
we've got for this episode do you have
anything else you want to add before we
start wrapping up the podcast here
win over winners we win over cup moments
we shouted out that awesome Pizza dude
yeah
um man it feels like we covered all our
bases uh
we consumed a lot of cannabis this
weekend y'all if we forgot to mention
the awesome interaction we had or
anything like that please forgive us we
uh we enjoyed ourselves we hope you
enjoyed yourself and uh sometimes
forgetfulness as part of that that's the
truth I wanted to mention all the uh the
ivory Army that came out and all the
cool people that we saw so many awesome
people yeah you guys know who you are
bro you guys that Core Group there that
came that partied uh you guys know who
you are and then the other group you
guys know who you are thank you for the
support thank you for the love it was
cool to have such a cool presence with
our booth art I felt like there were a
lot of people surrounding us uh between
Northwest 47 uh and our booth there's a
lot going on so big shout out to the
whole crew all right that's all I've got
for this episode Mike I do want to thank
you once again for coming and hanging
out on the podcast taking some time away
from the kids also bro thank you a lot
for helping me at the event could not
have done it without you that's [ __ ]
serious you did a lot of work thank you
you're very welcome man it was an
awesome time I love Cannabis Cup day um
y'all if you've never been absolutely
put it at the top of your priority list
um if you can make it to the Growers cup
uh next year dgc throws a hell of a
party yes
planning on representing again next year
yeah we'll come Soldier up and we got
first and second this year we're taking
all three next year you guys dgc Army
let's do it how did I forget this shout
out to the two people who magically
appeared in front of us with flower from
your lineups oh yes I've got some
amazing Raphael
um I've got some great um orange gases
people brought us a lot of great flowers
so a big thanks to all the people that
grew that worked hard to grow product
and then gave it to us that is Super Rad
we do appreciate that
um that does not go overlooked thank you
for all the gifts thank you for the
kindness and the support you guys it was
huge support a lot of people that are
supporting irie genetics a lot of people
that are supporting ganja Mike said
something a minute ago Mike said if you
uh haven't gone to an event go to one it
doesn't have to be the dude gross cup go
support the local events in your area if
there's an event there go support that
go see what it's like go uh even if you
can't grow and enter just go support the
vibe go buy a ticket go support the
vendors go see what you can see go be a
part of the Cannabis Community it's a
bunch of great people uh ladies
gentlemen and everything in between most
the people are super chilled out and
they're to have a good time so go
support the plant
oh excuse me I'm burping so go support
the plant go support the community and
go support ganja worldwide all right
that is really all I've got for you uh
make sure you check out the uh patreon
at patreon.com forward slash grow from
your heart check out Mike's patreon he's
got a patreon also it's patreon.com
forward slash White Mike is that correct
yep no yeah go check him out help out
White Mike for being on the show also
that's how you can contact Mike if you
need to get a hold of him go to patreon
send him a message there that's nice and
easy that's the easiest way if you have
any questions Corrections comments
concerns things you didn't like that I
said uh you could email me the email
address is grow from your heart
hotmail.com anything else you could
possibly imagine is on the website at
iregenetics.com there's a new updated
link to the Discord join us on the
Discord come hang out on the live chat
the winners of the dgc cup they hang out
on the Discord chat you'll find them on
there quite often I'm on there Mike is
on there uh there's no gatekeeping here
come hang out with us guys we're all
part of the community come hang out with
us I'll help you grow the best that you
could possibly grow I treat everybody as
an equal and as a friend there so come
join the party uh there's a link to the
merch there's a link to the seeds
everything you need is on the website
I've said enough
iregenetics.com I do want to give a big
shout out to the dude Scotty Shelby and
the entire dgc crew and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you