bless our family this is Natalie rise
and you are tuned to the highest
frequency the growth from your heart
podcast with rusted Jeff yeah big up
yourself every time Rasta Jeff Ira
genetics this is the place you want to
be you know you gotta grow from your
heart to know from your heart so keep it
loved the girl from your heart podcast
that's now
thank you
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
I'm your host Rasta Jeff this is episode
806 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun show lined up for you in
this episode we're going to give away
free seeds that's right I'm going to
give away free irie genetic seeds hang
out we'll talk more about the free seeds
later in this episode before we get to
the free seeds I do want to apologize
I've had to make an adjustment on I
redirect we can no longer ship to Canada
the Canadian border patrol has sent me a
letter saying please stop then they sent
me another letter saying no really
please [ __ ] stop I don't want that
third letter so at this point I have
stopped sending orders to Canada I
apologize if your order did not make it
to Canada send me a message I will
gladly send you a refund also you guys
who are expecting seeds for prizes in
Canada maybe they'll make it maybe they
won't I apologize send me a message if
you don't get them maybe I'll send you a
t-shirt or something up there in Canada
again I apologize it's not my decision
it wasn't my move this is the decision
of the Canadian border patrol
and I don't want to mess with the
Canadian border patrol any more than I
already have so I apologize no seeds are
going to make it to Canada and the
foreseeable future but we will work on
something as soon as possible also I
want to send a big shout out to my buddy
White Mike White Mike was on the last
episode if you have not watched the
previous episode I encourage you to go
back and watch the episode with white
Mike we talked about hanging out at the
dude grows cup it was a wonderful time
to have white Mike on the show first off
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to White Mike then thank you to
everybody who commented on white Mike's
uh reappearance on the podcast a lot of
people were excited to see Mike on the
show a lot of people were requesting hey
bring Mike back there you go guys Mike
was back on the show I do plan on having
Mike back on the podcast in the future
because I've got a uh a setup idea a
little production idea that'll be a
little bit different I was cool with the
way we did it side by side but it kind
of looked like uh the Cannabis version
of are you garbage if you get that joke
you're [ __ ] awesome but I was hard to
edit that one a little bit symmetry
problems there I found a new way in my
head that I think will work better look
better on camera so Mike I can't wait to
get you back over bro we're gonna change
the setup a little bit and I have a good
idea to make us both look sharp on
camera it's going to be great so Mike
you'll be back you guys Mike will be
back on the show big thanks to Mike for
being on the show and like I was saying
thank you for all of the great words of
encouragement on Mike's appearance on
the show it was fun taking Mike to the
dgc cup uh so many people their new Mike
Mike felt like a rock star at the event
so shout out to White Mike let's keep
moving I got a lot of energy today
um ladies and gentlemen coming up on the
24th of June I will be at The Groovy
gravy secret stash seed exchange that's
right come check it out there will be a
link to that event in the details of
this podcast if you're watching the
video uh listening on Spotify or
wherever in the notes in the video
description there will be a link to buy
tickets to The Groovy gravy event also
while you're there getting tickets use
coupon code irie20 to save 20 off of
your ticket that's right irie i r i e 20
i320 will save you 20 off your your
ticket to The Groovy gravy secret stash
in Denver on June 24th come say hi I
will be there white Mike should be there
with me also rumor has it that my buddy
Billy bong is going to fly in from
Hawaii hang out at the booth with us
help us vend a little bit uh shout out
to my buddy Billy for traveling from
Hawaii that's a good dude you guys big
shouts to Billy uh also not just irie
genetics will be at that event but
um who else will be there top dog will
be their ethos seeds will be their
capillator will be there uh Cali
Connection will be there I think raw
genetics has a booth there all of your
favorite seed vendors and breeders will
be there so join us at The Groovy gravy
secret stash if there is a pack of seeds
on the market that you are looking for
right now this is the event where you
can come get them get them straight
direct from the breeder Masonic will be
there with a bunch of Wilson crosses I'm
sure I'll be there with a bunch of great
[ __ ] I'll have White Chapel seeds
available I will have Redline available
and the first I think approximately 125
130 ish people to buy a pack of seeds
from the irie Booth will get a free
tester pack of p91 cross to Jack the
Ripper that's right an unreleased new
tester pack I know kind of what they do
my friends kind of know what they do
they haven't gone out to the public at
all so it's time for you guys to grow
those give us some feedback so join us
at The Groovy gravy event grab a pack of
seeds in my booth you'll get a free pack
the first 130 customers will get a free
pack of the Jack the Ripper crossed to
our notes the p91 crossed to Jack the
Ripper and if you do get those freebies
they come with a little card I really
look forward to seeing your grow on
Discord if you've got a freebie pack of
seeds please go to the Discord and post
pictures of your progress in the tester
tab there will be a link to the Discord
and the show notes in the video
description click on that that will take
you to Discord you'll find the tester
tab go ahead and post all your pictures
of your tester products there please all
right I think I've covered all of the
business part of this podcast it is time
to jump into everybody's favorite
portion of the girl from your heart
podcast that is the grow question and
answer part today I'm answering a
question that came from the grow help
tap on the irie genetics website if you
go to my website irygenetics.com there
are a bunch of tabs on the top one of
them does say grow help or grow
questions click on there that will take
you to a little questionnaire we ask a
few questions about your grow and then
we give you the opportunity to type in
your main concern main question about
your grow this one came from our friend
Gabe on the grow from your arm the irie
genetics website grow help tab the
question goes roster Jeff thank you for
reading my question and I hope you and
the fam are having an amazing year bro
everything is irie so far thanks for the
well wishes I hope you and your family
and your garden are killing it as well
it says I've been watching a lot of the
podcast with other breeders like
yourself one topic that has caught my
eye was breeding out the Herm Gene then
he said I have a strain that was fire
but had a super high Herm rate an
intersex rate is the word I prefer to
use what would be the best way to breed
this out would it be worth reversing
stable female who knows if that Gene is
recessive P.S if you do read this on the
podcast my friends call me Panda big
shout out to my buddy Panda what's up
bro thank you for the great question
um as a breeder so I've got a couple of
different answers on a couple of
different levels you have to keep in
mind I make seeds for a somewhat
commercial level I'm selling seeds to
people on the internet I need my seeds
to be top-notch reliable uh not have any
intersex traits hidden in those seeds in
any Generations in any form because uh
my customers my clients my friends the
ivory Army do not deserve intersex
plants it's my job to weed that out so
if this were me
this strain that is fire but shows
intersex traits would disappear I would
cut that [ __ ] down I would get rid of
it it would not last in my garden with
all of the seeds all of the strains all
of the Clones all of the options why
would you pick a plant that's got
intersex traits to breed with set
yourself up for success is my opinion
that's my situation in my breeding
company in my grow uh in my rules but
you may not be selling seeds you might
just be making seeds for yourself these
seeds aren't going to go anywhere if
you're making seeds for yourself it may
be worth breeding out that intersex
trait and but on somebody who's putting
seeds out to other people I don't want
to do that but you could breed it out
you could find another plant so you've
got the female that you know makes
intersex trades I would grow until you
find one that does not make the intersex
if you can find out if you've got
several seeds if you can find one test
it if you finally get one that doesn't
make intersex trades I would pollinate
it with a different male and then start
working on the bat cross make sure every
generation is test tested thoroughly to
make sure it does not have that
intersect straight hidden in there you
could also reverse it if you find a
phenotype that you really like but like
I said a moment ago this is like
um this girl is really pretty she's
pretty nice to you but on the weekends
she stabs you with the butter knife in
your nut sack like why don't you just
find one that doesn't stab you with a
butter knife in your nut sack it would
be that easy in my opinion uh this plant
can't be that good that it's worth
having this intersex trait so you asked
um what would be the best way to breed
out that intersex trait
um find one that is minimally intersex
which doesn't even make sense to me
that's intersex intersex is intersex
it's got to go but find one that doesn't
uh show intersex traits or minimal
pollinate that one with a stable solid
male and then repeat the process keep
back Crossing with that mail and then
eventually you could wash out that trait
but uh the first thing I wrote is why
don't you have other options like you've
got to have other options you're going
to get a free pack of seeds since you
sent me a question so you could start
with my seeds and not have to run those
intersex plants would be my theory uh my
dude I wish I had a better answer for
you my friend panda instead of telling
you uh don't breed with something that's
intersex that's not setting yourself up
for success that's uh trying to work out
a problem with the plant that you know
that's problematic when there are
thousands of packs of seeds available
that probably aren't as problematic so I
get one that doesn't stab you in the
nuts with the butter knife is my theory
and then breed with that so I'm going to
send you a free pack of seeds because if
you send me a question on the grow help
Tab and I read that question here on the
show you in free seeds my friend panda
as long as you are in the states and I
don't have to ship to Canada please do
send me your shipping address with a
real name I can't call you panda on your
box it's not gonna fly but send me a
name and an address and I will send you
a free pack of irie genetic seeds my
friend if you are in Canada let me know
and I will send you a T-shirt and some
stickers I apologize like I said before
you just can't have any seeds up there
in Canada until I get your government to
play nice with me also I wish I had a
better answer for you but as a breeder
who puts a lot of work into this plant
has a lot of passion for this plant I
can't find the heart in me to tell you
to breed with this intersex plant I tell
you to get the [ __ ] away from that
that's what probably what a therapist
and a good breeder and a good grower and
a good podcaster should tell you to do
run from that problem you can do better
all right let's move forward also bro
thank you for the great question and I
hope to see pictures of those seeds when
you do get them I've got another
question here in front of me this one
also did come from the grow help tab on
the irie genetics website this person
also is going to win a free pack of irie
genetic seeds congratulations my dude
this one is a general grow question and
it goes just like this it says Rasta
Jeff I love your podcast thank you for
the great info you are very welcome my
friend thank you for being a great
audience member and sending a great
question it says I have recently
embarked in pollen chucking just for fun
that's a fun Endeavor I hope it goes
well for you then it says can you please
explain how to finish a seed harvest the
first detailed question is should the
light schedule stay at 12 12. of
um I've done several podcasts on
changing my light schedule from 12 12 to
18 hours on and six hours off four
seated crops if you've bred made
completed several crops of seeds before
and you know what you're looking for in
a seated crop I always recommend turning
that light to 18 6. on your first time
maybe wait a little while to do that
just so you could see what happens with
the plants understand it before you [ __ ]
with it but the first few times you
breed do that 12 12 all the way till the
end then eventually you're going to want
to change that white timer to 18 hours
on and six hours off after pollination
if my plants are seeded I generally do
that about 10 days after pollination
that's my goal so I'll pollinate 10 days
later I'll flip that timer back to 18 6.
now you're gonna freak out you're gonna
say that's gonna [ __ ] up my plants no
that would [ __ ] up your flowers if you
were growing for usable smokable
photographable buds as photographable a
word anyway photogenic buds that that
would [ __ ] up your buds these plants are
going to look like [ __ ] these plants are
going to look like [ __ ] they're going to
start to re-vege but that's not a big
deal because we're not growing for buds
I'm not growing for buds when I'm
seeding my plants my 100 focus is seed I
want as many and as many healthy and as
many high quality germinating seeds and
as few crappy white seeds as I can
possibly have in my Harvest and I
achieved that by pollinating two times I
pollinate at the peak pollination time I
let that male plant build up a load
again pollinate one more time cut him
down let the plants absorb that pollen
let them adjust for about a week then I
switch that light to 18 6 and I get a
tremendous amount of positively healthy
amazing beautiful seeds so that's the
way I do that now the reason I like to
give those plants more light is because
I believe light is the number one source
of energy for these plants so I give it
more light that lets more energy into
the plant they can metabolize more guess
what they can feed that seed more also
you can cut down on several days of the
flowering cycle most of the time it'll
take about six to seven maybe eight
weeks for some seeds to be done you'll
have them done by the end of week six
with this method so by changing the
light cycle back it does make the plants
look a little bit wonky they start to
re-vege they get a little bit fluffy
they start growing kind of crazy but
that's not the point we make a bunch of
amazing seeds is what I'm going for now
if you don't want your plants to look
crazy if you don't want them to grow
wildly if you don't want them to re-vege
only change them back to 18 6 for the
last 10 to 14 days at the end of your
flowering cycle this will still speed
you up this will still give you healthy
fat seeds but it won't make the plant
room look like [ __ ] as bad alright so do
change the light cycle is something I do
same temperature and humidity basically
yes sometimes I don't like the room to
get too humid when the seeds are in
there I may let it get a little bit if
you've got struggles if you can get it
too humid or too dry I would prefer to
dry with the seeds in there also don't
spray the plants once they've been at
all I was going to say once they've been
pollinated don't spray them and I spit
as I said it which is pretty ironic I
sprayed it and saved it but don't spray
the plants if you're going to breed to
them you want all those pistols to be as
healthy and fat and robust as possible
so avoid any sprays on those plants
especially thick oils before and or
after pollination you may want to use
predator bugs in there if you're going
to use a pest prevention program The
Predator bugs may be ideal so same tip
in humidity keep the feeding flour
nutrition or some NPK ratio thanks in
advance so generally you don't need to
add the bloom boosters because you're
not making big fat buds we're not
growing for the buds like I was talking
about earlier we're growing for seed so
you don't need the bloom boosters in
there as much all the the bat guano the
uh what's what's the product the bud
swell I would take out the buds well
because I don't need the buds to swell I
want seed swell which is a totally
different feeding regimen so I kind of
stick to a vegetative nutrient with a
lot of microbes and add a little bit of
more calmag than usual
and I said this on another podcast
recently I don't think I've ever talked
about this publicly until I was on that
cannabis podcast but add some Amino
products to your seed regimen when
you're feeding the plants that are
seated and those Liquid Aminos will help
you create more healthy fatter more
robust seeds which will also be more
resistant to problems when they do grow
so add that uh the liquid aminos uh
boost up the Cal Mag just a little bit
and then feed that vegetative nutrient
is basically what you want to do put
some microbes in there feed whatever
else you feed to keep that plant
optimized and healthy but basically base
notes a basic NPK from your vegetative
nutrients a little bit of extra Cal Mag
just to boost that up and then some
liquid amino products would definitely
help in there if you can so I think that
is most of how to finish the seed
Harvest do you mean like when they're
done so eventually the seeds are going
to start getting harder right you'll
start seeing them popping out of the
plants uh they'll just start peeking out
at the top the plants will pop open the
calyx will pop open a little seed will
pop out of there the Brack will open up
it'll be peeking out like I'm almost
ready daddy uh pull some of those seeds
out of there from different parts of the
plant and give them a squeeze if they
rupture they're not ready yet if you can
squeeze it pretty good to where you get
a dent in your finger a little indention
a little Mark that seed is probably done
you should know by now what a done seed
looks like you've played with so many
seeds right you've grown them you could
roll it on the table and press it it
doesn't pop that's what you want but you
can also go too far so once they start
heart being hard enough to where they
don't crunch you want to take them out
pretty soon after that because if you
wait too long they'll become too hard
and they'll be hard to germinate and
when you put them in the water or the
root cubes or whatever they won't pop
open you'll have to scar them or crunch
them a little bit to get them pop to pop
open so when they're hard enough that is
about when it is Harvest time you'll
have to determine that on your own the
way that I harvest this is just how I do
it there are a thousand ways to skin a
cat you pick your way I'm gonna tell you
the way that I do it a few days before
Harvest time I'll go in the grow room
and pick off all of the big leaves any
Leaf I can pull off I just take it off
right now I don't need that coming in
the dry room with me at all that's just
gonna keep humidity in the room and I
don't want that with my seed drying so
just get all those big leaves off
anything I can take off chop it off then
I stop watering I let the plants get
kind of dry before I cut them down I
don't need all that extra humidity in
the grow room or in the dry room so I'll
let them dry a little bit don't water
them then I cut them down then I take
the plant tag that is in the pot and I
attach that to the plant just use some
duct tape or a wrap or whatever and make
sure that plant tag stays with my plant
I don't want to [ __ ] this part up it's
very important to me so I got my plant
my plant tag traveling together I put
that on a I've got a little hanger thing
that I use and I hang those in a spot in
the dry and cure area I chop all of the
plants down and I spread them out a
little bit and I just let them hang dry
I've got these um they're sterlite bins
they're actually bins that are made to
put like store your clothes or your
shoes in and they slide underneath the
bed they got wheels on one end these
bins are made to slide under the bed
they're kind of shallow I like these
because I can set them underneath the
plant and as the plant dries if any of
the seeds do fall out it'll fall down
into that bin eventually these plants
are going to get real real dry I don't
really pay attention to
um temperature humidity airflow or
anything like that in this room the room
is just naturally ambiently acceptable
it's a cool it's a decent room it's cool
it's dry it's dark it's very acceptable
for having plants I don't have to adjust
anything for the drying and curing of
seeded plants in this room so in this
room they'll be drying about 10 to 14
days I want to get them real dry so once
they start getting dry enough to where
I'm worried about the buds crumbling and
the seeds falling out I will take the
plant and basically cut the sticks off
and take a glove and just grab the
bottom of the branch and just pull the
branch out to where all the buds fall
off into that Rubbermaid or that
Sterilite bin that I was talking about
earlier just catch all the and seeds are
going to fall out as this happens
depending on how dry those buds are
it'll just go crunch crunch crunch
crunch crunch and it'll fall right into
that bin I'm collecting all the buds and
all the seeds into there I'll do that
with every plant and carefully do not
cross the sea seeds from one bin to the
other make sure that you move the bins
when you're pulling [ __ ] so seeds don't
fly into the wrong bin so I'll get all
of the buds off of the sticks now I've
just got a bunch of bins with sticks
then I'll put on fresh gloves because by
now my gloves are caked and torn put on
some fresh gloves then I go to those
bins and sometimes I wear a mask too
because this can get very dusty then I
let it get super dry and I just take the
buds in my hands and just crunch them
crunch crunch crunch crunch crunch just
rub all the buds through my hands
there's other ways to do this I've
thrown the buds into a five gallon
bucket and use the paint stirrer paddle
on a drill it is and that'll go ahead
and spin all your [ __ ] seeds out of
your buds real quick but uh try to be
gentle with the seeds break them up with
my hands break them up with the drill
bit I've used a big spoon and gone in
there and just used a spoon to break up
the buds I want to get that turned into
dust I want to beat all that bud
material into dust then I take my bin
and shake it now at this point all the
seeds that fall into the bottom most of
the weed material is up at the top we
call that the chaff at this point I
basically kind of scoop that off
um don't go too deep to where you're
getting to the seeds and just scoop the
chaff right off the top set that to the
side give it a shake make sure there are
no seeds in there you'll be cool then at
this point you've got to get the seeds
out of all of that weed or the weed out
of all of those seeds is how I look at
it at this point but I use a machine to
do it I've got a little machine that's
got a couple leveled angles and a
computer fan and it catches all the junk
in one drawer and the seeds go into
another that machine was quite expensive
you could probably build one I'm sure
there are seed sorter machines available
online but you're gonna have to figure
out a way to sort all the seeds out of
that junk I've seen people use a vacuum
don't turn it up super high and don't go
hard with it but you can if you've got
the seeds in a bucket or a bin with
material on top you can gently just kind
of feather that vacuum through there and
stir things and you can pick up the weed
material and leave the seeds because the
weed material is much lighter than the
seed so if you get the feel for it if
you're clumsy if you're a goofy kind of
person don't try that when you're going
to suck up all the [ __ ] seeds but if
you got some Faith In Yourself kind of
you can suck up the chaff material
without sucking up the seeds so at this
point I've separated all of the material
from all of the seeds I will leave the
seeds sitting out in a cool dry dark
safe place for a little while I have had
a friend sort his seeds before this was
not me this was really a friend I would
admit it If This Were me he had a bag of
seeds on a tail or a cup of seeds on a
table they were open and a [ __ ] Mouse
stole the seeds I'm not joking a lot of
good seeds we never got to grow that
plant we don't know what he even made
because the mouse got all of his beans
so think about that put him somewhere
where Critters won't get to them but I
leave them open for a while and let them
get really dry sometimes I put one of
those desiccant packs in there to suck
up the moisture not a Boveda pack a
desiccant pack something to suck up the
moisture not add moisture but I want to
get all the moisture out of there
then I either put them depending on how
many I've got sometimes they go in a big
one gallon bag jars and carefully label
that bag I will write the new strain
name so let's just say frequency shift
I'll put frequency shift then I'll label
about I've got a seed counter also I run
them through the seed counter I'll put
how many seeds are in that bag frequency
shift 20 000 seeds then I'll put the
cross New York City Diesel to a reversed
Golden Goat then I'll put the harvest
date on there so I know when those seeds
were pulled I just like to Mark [ __ ] so
that I know how many seeds when they
were pulled though if there's a problem
if you say hey bro if several people say
hey bro I bought a bunch of these seeds
and they're not working I can look at
that whole batch and then I can run
those myself and see if there's a
problem in there that I missed before
that you guys happen to discover because
you grow a lot more of those seeds than
I do I run small batches and then you
guys run I run 50 or 100 you guys Run 10
each and there's thousands of you doing
it so that's a lot of [ __ ] seeds
being grown but so that's basically how
I do a seed Harvest
um I pollinate I change the light skin
schedule I feed them pretty solid I
defoliate heavily toward the end let
them get dry chop them down let them get
super [ __ ] dry pull off the buds into
the bins crunch up the buds uh pull out
the seeds count the seeds put them in a
jar and get them dry as [ __ ] that's the
basics
um I hope I answered your question if
you have any follow-ups please do send
me a message on the same Avenue which
you sent this grow question and also
while you're at it my dude please do
send me your address with your real name
so that I can get you a free pack of
irie genetics premium seeds ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls if you did not
win a free pack of seeds on this episode
have no fear I've got a big old stack of
emails here in front of me there are
more in my inbox that need to be printed
maybe just maybe I'll read your question
on the next episode don't be shy don't
feel discouraged also you can get seeds
at
iridirect.com if you're looking for a
specific pack if you don't want to take
the gamble on me sending you a random
pack check out iridirect.com there's a
bunch of great stuff up there also I
just added quartz dab bangers on
iridirect.com that have got my face on
them that's right custom made DCS quartz
bangers they're high quality bangers
made in California with my face etched
into the bottom of them there are 10 mil
and 14 mil available there are 90 and 45
degree of both sizes available very very
limited Supply you guys had very few of
them made I want to see how they sell if
they sell if they do well I'll get more
if not this was a one-time run and if
you got them you're a very lucky person
but go check out iridirect if you're
interested in a quartz Banger with my
lovely face on it also there's a bunch
of great beans there I think I already
mentioned that part all right I think
that is all I've got for you for this
episode
um if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns my email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy please send me an email let
me know what you think of the show of
course if you have grow questions or
cultivation questions or need help go to
the website go to thegrowhelp tab send
me your question there that's how you
can win the free seeds make sure you
check out patreon at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart everything
else is on my website at iregenetics.com
there's a link to the Discord server
there's an updated link to the Discord
server there's a link to the merchandise
the shirt store is closed down for a
minute we are re-adjusting the inventory
that will be back after The Groovy gravy
event I'm taking the shirts with me
there I will sell a bunch there then we
will fix the inventory but the uh the
Discord is there the seed sales is there
the podcast is there everything you can
imagine it
iregenetics.com tune in is what all the
cool kids say all right that's all I've
got for you for this episode I want to
give a giant shout out to my friend
8-bit and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
thank you
dig up yourself every time Rusty Jeff
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]