foreign
[Music]
here we go welcome to the podcast
everybody I'm your host Rasta Jeff this
is episode 808 of the grow from your
heart podcast in this episode we're
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about the free seeds
later in this episode also if I owe you
free seeds from a previous episode they
should be on the way if you do not
receive free seeds by the time this
episode comes out please send me a
gentle reminder my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com in the
subject line please do put the word
prizes also include the episode number
in which you won those seeds and also
give me your real address with a real
name so I do know where to ship those
seeds also I am proud to announce that
irie genetics premium seeds is now
available on Neptune's seed bank that's
right go check out neptuneseedbank.com
they should have regular and feminized
irie genetic seeds in stock they
recently picked up a bunch of orange
gasm Golden Goat and lemon Jeffrey seeds
also by the time this comes out they may
still possibly have big mountain fudge
cake Femme seeds in stock so go check
out our friends at
neptuneseedbank.com also I want to give
a big shout out to everybody I met at
The Groovy gravy secret stash I had an
amazing time at the event I took Mike
with me we drove up from Pueblo up to
Denver uh early Saturday morning we made
it into Denver uh we got to unload our
gear right in front of the event I went
and parked the car and then Mike helped
me carry everything in as we were
carrying things in guess who showed up
my bro Billy bong showed up to the event
he said he was flying in from Hawaii to
make it uh Billy had quite the adventure
getting from Hawaii to Colorado uh every
flight was delayed everything that could
have gone wonky went wonky but guess
what my dude Billy keeps a positive
attitude he made it to the event we had
a great time at the end of the event I
was like hey Bill you want to go get
dinner and he looked at me with these
glazed eyes and he's like bro I'm so
exhausted I need a hotel so Billy took
off after the event he went and crashed
out Mike and I went got some food and
then headed home it was a great weekend
it was a great event very success
successful event for ire genetics and
team irie Army we had a really good time
we sold a bunch of seeds but more
importantly we got to see the community
the crew it was another great
community-based event a lot of the irie
Army comes through a lot of people that
know me uh kind of peripherally that's a
big word for the show here they know
it's from other breeders and just the
seed industry they finally got to see
him come say hi shake my hand check out
the booth get some stickers I get
introduced to Mike and myself learn
about the podcast to see how we set up a
booth it was just a great time to go uh
Network and get some exposure and meet a
lot of great people if you came by the
booth at The Groovy gravy secret stash
thank you thanks for popping by if you
gave me seeds weed uh hash concentrates
Edibles ah things I shouldn't mention
here on the show thank you for all of
the amazing gifts that we were given at
The Groovy gravy secret stash also I
want to send an extra special shout out
to my dude at Bubba's cheesecakes bro
those cheesecakes I shouldn't even be
eating cheesecakes either some dietary
restrictions that I do break because
cheesecake that's the only answer there
dude those cheesecakes were delicious
Bubba if you ever see this thank you for
the delicious cheesecake my whole team
was happy with the cheesecakes we all
ate I honestly bought two
I thought I'm gonna eat about half of
these and then I'm gonna offer them to
other people so that I don't eat both of
these cheesecakes they're little
cheesecake guys don't think I'm a real
huge Savage here just a half Savage but
I got about halfway through the first
cheesecake and I realized um I don't
like my friends as much as I like
cheesecake and they're gonna have to go
get their own so I devoured two
cheesecakes they were quite delicious
shout out to my buddy Bubba so before I
go too far I want to give a big shout
out to my buddy Mike big shout out you
guys know him as white Mike I just call
him Mike these days big shout out bro
thank you uh Mike has been helping me
out a lot with the irie genetics trade
show booth last year I had the vid I
couldn't make it to the dude grows cup
Mike took the entire booth in his car he
set up the booth he sold the seeds he
did a really good job he made a lot of
friends he left an impact on the
community because this year at the dude
grows cup everybody knew who Mike was
like what's up Mike good to see you
again welcome back so that was super
cool to see Mike uh making a step up in
the Cannabis Community people know who
he is you guys remember him uh you go
show him some love that is great but
also Mike went to The Groovy gravy
secret stash and I love how Mike is just
falling into place and learning exactly
how to run the booth I don't know how I
want the booth exactly ran Mike doesn't
know exactly how I want the boothram but
we're figuring it out as it goes through
different trade shows and we've built a
really nice flow together uh we can just
kind of look and point and grunt at each
other and we know what we expect he
watches me interact with customers he
knows I'm going to ask for a t-shirt to
give you or he knows to pass me some
stickers or whatever so big shout out to
Mike Mike has been uh Mike has been
coming to all of the events with me he's
been my right hand man for a long time
he knows how to run my booth without me
uh I can take a break and go use the
restroom or go buy cheesecake or just go
roam around at this event you guys I
just roam around roamed around and gave
away free packs of seeds to people who
looked like they could use some seeds
who I'd never met before it's a good way
to introduce myself and my brand so I
just went and gave away seeds and I had
faith that Mike and Billy were holding
down the booth so big shout out to my
buddy White Mike he's becoming a really
reliable Booth uh manager a booth dude
for me and it's working very well thank
you bro it's making the event lot more
fun when I can relax and interact with
the customers they want to come talk to
me I'm kind of the face of the company
they have a lot of questions Mike can
keep business moving and keep things
flowing for me and I appreciate that
while I'm giving people shout outs I
want to send another shout out to my
dude Billy bong smoking like I said that
dude flew in from Hawaii uh he was on
the plane probably four times as long as
he got to hang out with me and Mike we
hung out from about 11 to about six
maybe five thirty I got about six full
hours in hanging out with each other of
course we were working most of the time
it was a a retail event so we started so
many conversations we would ask a
question and get started on a
conversation then have to stop and help
whoever was coming up to the booth not a
problem but we started so many
conversations and did not finish a lot
of them so Billy we got a lot more
hanging out to do bro but big shout out
to my buddy Billy he's trying to take a
step up in his cannabis knowledge his
trade show knowledge he learned a lot
this weekend and met a lot of great
people so shout out to Mike and Billy
also I want to send a gigantic shout out
to my buddy wolf uh it's wolf it's
groovy gravy without wolf these events
would not happen wolf put this one on uh
from what I noticed it went on without a
hitch it was Flawless parking at the
beginning was a little questionable they
got that figured out it flowed like a
dream after that they got us in uh we
got right to the booth we got set up the
customers came they shopped so the way
they did this one you bought tickets for
a one-hour time slot you were allowed to
shop from noon to one then they uh
sequestered you is that the word
escorted you out to the back of the
event where there was plenty happening
in the backyard there was a band out
there there was music there was plenty
of food there was tacos uh there were
sandwiches there was ice cream there was
cheesecake there was hash to be smoked
out there there was a lot going on out
there in the back patio so it wasn't
like you were forced to leave but you
got a one hour shopping spot inside and
then you were kind of escorted out to
the outside part where you could hang
out with everybody and chill make
friends and mingle if you wanted to but
I feel like the event went super
smoothly all of the time blocks came in
all of the time blocks shot they left
like they were supposed to between the
shop time slots the vendors get a 15 a
10 or 15 minute break between each wave
or time slot and that makes it super
nice I can rearrange my booth I could
take a quick drink of whatever I'm
drinking I could go take a piss if I
need to honestly a lot of the time when
it was a 10 minute break I would just
take a big fat dab it was a
non-consumption event you guys so
allegedly I was taking dabs it's
different when you're a vendor they're
not going to kick you out when you paid
a bunch of money to be there but it was
a great event and it could not have
happened without our buddy wolf also
known as groovy gravy bro if you ever
see this I don't know if you watch the
show I don't know if you ever hear the
shout outs but bro thank you I was an
honor to be a part of The Groovy gravy
secret stash and I hope I'm invited next
year it is uh to the best of my
knowledge I think it's kind of like an
invite-only sort of an event there are
very minimal amounts of Booth spaces in
the small venue which we choose and I
think it's full it's it's pretty full
and we get basically it's all the
top-notch breeders in there so it's kind
of an invite only I hope I keep my
invite next year and if you guys did not
make it this year if I'm there or not
next year you guys gotta go so plan your
trip you're gonna have to choose or
maybe come out for a long week a long
month and stay for the dude grows cup
and The Groovy gravy event come hang out
it's a good time we'll all go to dinner
afterward also shout out to Mike for
enduring I took Mike to a vegan
restaurant Mike is not vegan I'm not
vegan I'm just a vegetarian but it's way
easy to go pick out food for me when I
just go to a vegan restaurant I can eat
everything on the menu Mike actually
found some stuffy thoroughly enjoyed so
shout out to Mike for enduring that now
I do have two more people I want to give
a shout out to maybe another group of
people that I'd like to send shout outs
to from The Groovy gravy event I know
I've been going on for quite a while
about that event but it was a good time
it's great to go bond with the community
go see old friends and new friends where
I'm headed is uh shout out to uh swerve
from the Cali Connection before I even
got completely set up sort of popped out
of nowhere I don't even know where he
came from it's just right in my face
it's like what's up bro you look good
you were killing it the logo looks good
I like your booth swerve was full of
compliments uh very encouraging uh
swerve is the Cali Connection he's been
around for a long time swervin I made
friends a while back uh several years
ago at an event
um at the High Times Cannabis Cup in
Denver was the first time we really hung
out since then he's been inviting me to
hang out at his booth at events
um there was one couch at the Cannabis
Cup in Denver uh and it was at swerve's
booth at the Cali Connection booth and
Adam ill myself and little Kev and
swerve sat on those couches and smoked
dabs for 4 20 at the Cannabis Cup I'll
never forget that big up to my buddy
swerve
um swerve came by and gave me a lot of
compliments pulled me aside we had a
long talk about the industry about life
it's good to see swerve doing as well as
he can bro I hope the health stays
strong uh big shout out to my buddy
swerve from the Cali Connection then
also uh big shout out to JJ uh JJ from
Top Dog JJ stops by and shakes my hand
every event he sees me it's like we're
building this extra family that I really
enjoy I love the irie Army but then it's
also cool to build bonds with all of the
other breeders in the industry I don't
feel any uh animosity or intimidation or
competition with any of them we're all
doing our own thing and I love building
the relationship with all of them I'm
gonna collab with every anybody in the
future
also speaking of collabs I can't say too
much but I got to see uh the one the
only the man the myth the legend uh the
Ghetto Superstar my buddy uh big shout
out to my buddy mace mace was at the
event there I got to see mace uh mace
was a little bit under the weather
wasn't uh hanging out as much as he
could have he didn't want to get
everybody else sick so I understand and
a respect and appreciate that [ __ ] but
got to see me he's got to give him a
homie handshake you know when he slap
hands you do the fist bump thing we did
that we talked for a moment uh looked
like mace was selling a bunch of seeds
so shout out to mace I love the uh the
community that we're building there it's
so awesome too I get more excited to get
there early just to see what the crew
was doing and catch up like how are you
man what if seeds have you made this
year where have you been uh how's the
industry treating you we've got our own
little like private conversations before
the party even happens I love the
relationships that we're all building I
love that the uh the weirdness in the
community seems to be going away for a
little while there was some hatred some
uh some jealousy some animosity in the
Cannabis industry now it feels like
we're really we are united lighting
which we've all got the same [ __ ]
goal you guys we all want to grow
cannabis we all want to sell seeds and
get good seeds out to the world let's be
chill with each other that's my theory
there all right I've gone on far too
long about The Groovy gravy secret stash
it was super awesome it was super
exciting I had a really good time and I
look forward to doing it again next year
shout out to the whole gang shout out to
everybody if you brought me seeds
flowers stickers a high five if we took
a selfie together yo please post the
Selfies if we took one together but
everybody thank you for showing up thank
you for making it a great event I feel
like it went off without a hitch I was
talking about those those time blocks
they all went super smooth it was a
great event let me get myself back on
track let's move into the part of the
podcast which everybody loves and enjoys
this is the grow question and answer
portion of the podcast this is where we
give away free seeds that's right
if you go to my website iregenetics.com
there's a list of tabs on the top one of
them says questions or grow help I don't
remember what it says right now I've had
too many dabs you will find it go to the
website if you've got a grow question
click on there scroll down answer the
preliminary questions if you've got a
general grow question just go ahead and
type that in if I read your grow
question here on the podcast that means
you win a free pack of irie genetic
seeds if I read your question here
please go ahead and send me your
shipping address with a real name and
also let me know what episode number you
won the seeds on that way I can mark
that off my list I am keeping track of
who I send seeds to but send me an email
with your shipping address I will get
you a free pack of seeds this message
came from the grow help Tab and it came
from my friend Terps what up Terps Big
Love bro this message said I think this
is the place for a question this is
absolutely the place bro the question
says what are some steps you take to
sexing a new regular beam and I'm gonna
call you out you actually typed in the
word sexting so what's your phone auto
correcting [ __ ] for bro I see you anyway
it says uh what's what are some steps
you take to sexing a new bean I have a
couple of strains that are very shy and
do not want to show me their goodies you
got some plants that are some prudes
over there uh we're trying to make these
plants show you their sex
um the main thing I focus on when I'm
trying to get plants to show me their
sex is an uninterrupted 12-hour dark
period that's basically what's going to
put our plants into flower so I would
change the timer from 12 from either 24
hours on which a lot of people do or 18
hours on and six hours off which is what
I recommend so I would go ahead and I
would change that timer to 12 12. I
would put it on a flowering cycle that
12 hours of Darkness will tell the plant
hey fall is coming it thinks the end of
the world is near and it wants to flower
so it should go into flower if your
plants are in this uh 12 12 situation
for about 10 days 14 days and they do
not begin to show you flour I would say
expect you've got some light leaks or
these plants have got what we call a
very strong critical period the critical
period is the amount of Darkness of the
amount of uninterrupted darkness which
it takes to trigger a plant to go into
flower these plants could be from a
region on the globe where it takes a
little longer to trigger them but most
plants the reason why we chose 1212 is
because it seems to work with most
plants to put them into flour I do have
some notes Here let me get onto the
notes uh give them 12 hours of daylight
and 12 hours of uninterrupted Darkness
for 10 to 14 days they should start
showing you sex if not like I said
before I suspect a light leak they're
not getting that dark period they're
probably stretching more than you want
them to that should be an indicator so
put the plants in 12-12 wait for sex
they should show you by day 17 you
should definitely know what you're
working with then once you've made your
determinations which are males or
females uh coal which ones you don't
want I'm a seed breeder sometimes I I do
a female hunt just for boys once you
found the boys or girls get rid of what
you do and do not want keep the rest
then return them to either 24 hours on
or 18 hours on and six hours off of a
lighting cycle now I do understand that
some people are not going to want to put
their little tiny plant into flower and
then shock it make it show us sex and
then put it back they find that to be
too stressful for the plant really it's
not that big of a deal but if you don't
want to do that I do have an option for
you you can veg your plant from seed
until it is large enough to take a clone
when you take that clone you can then
put the Clone directly into 1212
lighting and that clone should go into
flower like I said in 10 to 14 maybe 17
days at the most it'll start showing you
if it is a boy or a girl when you take
those clones be very careful I should
have mentioned this already Mark your
plant label your plant somehow you can
give it a number a letter you can give
it a people name it could be uh a32 Jack
if you want you can get as creative as
you want but when you label that plant
a32 Jack make sure you label the Clone
came from it a32 Jack as well so we know
which is which that way when your clone
shows sex if you're going to toss the
males like most people do you could toss
the male clone and you could toss the
big plant at the same time then you've
just eliminated all the boys the clones
and the potted plants now you've just
got females left in the room another
option kind of on the same boat here you
can take you can veg your plants out
until they're big enough to get a clone
label them we got Jack a32 this time
we're going to use Jill 52b and we're
going to take a clone of Jill 52b now
we're going to put those clones under
lighting under the 24-hour lighting and
we're going to let those root but then
we're going to take our big plants and
put those into the flower room and flip
those because we've been vegging them
for a while anyway they're already big
enough to grow and produce a little bit
and they're just the first time we're
running them I don't want to veg them
too big because they could be intersex
they could be ugly it might not be
something I'm interested in so let's
just grow those in that original of
they're probably in a one a three gallon
pot they're big enough to get a clone
own let's just flip those as soon as
those plants show you sex you can flip
you could toss the males and also go
back and toss the Clones that went with
that now something I should mention if
we go from 12 12 from seed if you sprout
seeds put them immediately Under 12 12
uh lighting it may take two or three
weeks for those plants to adjust their
hormones to even really go into flour so
it may take you three to four weeks to
actually see the sex if you go directly
12 12 from seed not every plant every
strain is going to do that but it is
very possible that it could take a
minute for those hormones to develop for
the plant to go I'm growing I know I'm
under 12 12. I'm not sure what to do yet
then the certain hormones the correct
hormone will hit that plant and it'll go
I know what I'm supposed to do this is
12 12 lighting I'm gonna flower so they
may need a little bit of time just to
adjust if you're doing this straight
from seed if the plant has grown big
enough and you've taken a clone from it
it's already developed enough of those
hormones that those clones definitely
will flip right away okay so the main
thing we're talking about here is
something called critical period that is
the amount of time that a plant takes to
decide that it needs to go into flour
the amount of uninterrupted darkness
that that plant requires to trigger the
flowering phase I think 1212 is the
trick for most plants that's why we the
general rule of thumb is 12 12 that
should work if not like I said before my
first suspicion is that these plants are
not getting that uninterrupted Darkness
they may be getting a light leak again I
don't know what's going on you said
they're just being stubborn they're
being shy and not showing you their
goodies it may be a light leak make sure
they're getting that uninterrupted
Darkness also they may just be too young
to show you their goodies you might may
need to wait till they at least reach a
little bit of more hormonal level then
they'll start to show you what they've
got going on my dude Terps I'm pretty
sure I know who this message came from
please do send me your address I'll send
you another pack of seeds because I love
what you do with them in the garden all
right I've got a lot of great more
messages a lot of great more messages
that's pretty good wording here I'm not
even going to edit that part out we're
I'm just going to leave that in the show
one of the great more messages that I've
got here in the pile comes from a person
who wants to be called pot casso or
potty o toker they gave me two names to
call them
um feeling frisky are you bro I like
this message anyway this one uh my
friend uh what are we gonna call you pot
casso please do send me a real name and
a shipping address because like I said
before I owe you a free pack of seeds
because I'm going to read your message
right here on the podcast the message
goes a little bit like this it says yo
Rasta Jeff thank you for all you do
especially the education I learned
everything I know from you the irie Army
and the dude grow show bro thank you for
the great compliments ah thank you for
supporting the irie Army and also big
shout out to the dude grow show the
message goes on it says I love your work
and your brand you are bringing the
knowledge and the fire to the people
thank you for noticing dude also thank
you for noticing then it says my
question is how often would you
defoliate when you are scrogging I do a
two trellis system in play the first one
is to fill the canopy the second is to
support that's a great strategy that's
basically what I do use the first one to
spread them out then you get those
chunky colas use that second one to hold
them up great strategy there it says is
there a particular time and frequency
you defoliate your personal or
commercial grow I basically handle
defoliation the same in a personal and
Commercial grow whether I'm growing for
seeds or flowers or whatever I basically
do the same method schedule and strategy
so it goes on I lost my place to be
honest with you it says I've seen other
recommendations of heavy Leaf strips the
week before flip at day 21 and at day
42. honestly dude that's a great
strategy that's basically what I do uh
very close to what I do says personally
I clean up the skirt and any potential
Bud sites the week before flip and then
nothing till day 21 I lollipop to my
first trellis and then only a light
cleanup again uh for blocked Bud sites
and heavy leaf on Leaf areas for airflow
you're doing it pretty close to how I
would do it but I go I've got notes so
I'll talk about that more let me read
the rest of what you've got it says
periodically I'll take a leap for two
when necessary until week 10 where I
strip her bald headed into Harvest yes I
love a uh a pre-harvest strip that way
you just get all those leaves off there
turn the lights off come back the next
day chop it down you don't have as much
junk to clean up yes I do appreciate
that he uh starts he finishes up with I
love going 18-6 the week 10 of flower
bro thank you for saying that because so
many people are skeptical and so many
people have sent me basically hate mail
and told me that I'm ridiculous and wild
and crazy and uh basically [ __ ] for
recommending to go 18 hours on and six
hours off at the end of flower I've
noticed the people that have tried it
[ __ ] love it everybody that tries it
sends me a message and they say hey bro
I tried this [ __ ] awesome the people
who haven't tried it tell me I'm [ __ ]
crazy there's something that I notice
about that anyway thank you for trying
it thank you for having faith in me and
thank you for saying that it is working
uh then it does go on it says the next
cycle in an attempt to really try to
maximize potential I'm doing a main line
into a scrog any recommendations uh no I
don't really [ __ ] with the main line
just fill that scrog don't worry too
much about the main line scrog just like
you are I think you will be happier
the main line
um no offense the main line to me is for
people who are only allowed to have one
plant they just don't have [ __ ] to do
all day so they're doing as much as they
possibly can to that one single plant
that's how I feel about mainlining it's
just a lot of work to one plant when
what you've done with one plant
mainlining I could have done that with
the whole garden just scrogging it
trellising it popping twisting and
cropping it properly
if you got one plant go for it if you
got all day but I don't have all day to
[ __ ] with one plant that's just me I'm a
commercial grower I think on a much
larger scale it says any recommendations
yeah that was my recommendation we'll
talk more about the the defoliation also
then he wraps it up with take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me hey bro
that's my line what do I say now what am
I going to say at the end of the show
you stole my line man no I'm just joking
I'm confident here we go
um so the main question here is about
defoliation and your strategy you said
that you uh do it a week before flip
which is basically I would do it the day
of flip mainly because
um just strategy for the rooms it's
easier for me to defoliate in the bigger
room I do start defoliating a little bit
in veg but not heavily just some of the
giant leaves those will come off and veg
then day one a flip I'll give it a nice
defoliation then basically like you said
you said day 21 and 42
um yeah that's basically what I would do
uh two weeks in about four weeks in but
about two weeks in is when I do the
shave and the Lolly popping and a heavy
deleting so flip it uh do a d-leaf not a
major but a pretty good one let it ride
then two weeks in I'll do a major
lollipopping I'll shave the legs I'll do
some defoliation I'll do a bunch of
popping and twisting and a lot of
working into the canopy if anything is
getting too tall so week two is really
when I go kind of hard I'll do it again
at week four and then I do continue all
the way up into week six if I see [ __ ]
down there underneath the canopy that
just doesn't look good I'll just take it
off I don't want to waste that I don't
want to trim it I'm definitely not going
to trim that [ __ ] later I just want to
pull that off and let it actually put
that energy that feed those nutrients
that love somewhere else in the plant up
top where it's going to be worth
trimming is basically what I'm thinking
so one of the things I really wanted to
mention was
um I don't like to do one super hard
defoliation keep in mind I kind of come
from a commercial cultivation background
so I've got a room uh let's just say a
hundred foot by 100 foot room with a I'm
gonna say five or eight hundred plants
in there I'm just guessing and making
[ __ ] up I I wouldn't go in and super
hard defoliate one section what I would
do is I would set a timer and I would
try to spend I would divide the day in
quarters and make sure that I did a
quarter of the day on this part of the
room and a quarter over here and a
quarter here and a quarter here so that
I don't have one section that's heavily
defoliated and the rest looks like the
70s Bush I would rather go around the
room multiple times and take off light
layers every time around the room and
just continuously do that other than
just go take if you got multiple tables
that's how we do it we just say don't go
strip that table naked strip all the
tables a level two then come back and
strip all the tables to level four don't
just do one section at level [ __ ]
eight right away go lightly all the way
around the room that just creates uh a
better airflow it creates less micro
climates more even and it's better for
your mind I think also you just see the
progress differently instead of getting
all these naked and then going I got all
that left to do you go oh we kind of got
part of the whole room and you get to
move around the room instead of being in
one place I like to put on a podcast put
on some music and just defoliate I could
defoliate all day it's very Zen for me
pulling the big pedials seeing how many
big ass trash bags or five gallon
buckets of leaves I pulled just feels
real good to me I don't know it feels
like I'm accomplishing something so
honestly it feels like you've got the
right idea there's no uh no right or
wrong way to do this if you're pulling
too many leaves that is the only wrong
way and you'll be able to tell because
the plants will slow down uh you're
doing it a week before day 21 and day 42
I go day one day 21 and day 42 basically
um give them that good leg shaving give
them the lollipopping I think you're
doing everything just about perfectly do
you do any popping and twisting
um some super cropping that may be the
only thing that you may need to
implement in your scrog game my dude pot
casso or potty oh toker I love the two
names dude that's three names I got here
for you thank you for the great message
I will take a fat dab I will give my mom
a hug for me in the meantime here's a
reminder please do send me your shipping
address with a real name and also a
reminder what episode so you did win the
free seeds on so I could scroll back see
that I do actually owe you prizes guys
don't try to scam me I am paying
attention we're better at this than you
think all right we're gonna keep moving
I do have another great message here in
front of me this one came from our
friend who wants to be called Daft
Punk's luggage that sounds like a heavy
uh task right there you got helmets and
dance gear in there anyway let's stay
focused here on the podcast Daft punks
luggage my dude I owe you a free pack of
seeds so like I've said before please
send me your real name with the shipping
address and also remind me what episode
number I read your message on and I will
send you a free pack of irie genetic
seeds the question from our friend Daft
Punk's luggage goes a lot like this it
says roster Jeff I do know the
difference between f1s f2s f3s Etc so
those are just filial Generations it
says each being a new filial generation
selected from a mating pair from the
previous generation all right so it
sounds like you do understand it says
theoretically each generation is getting
closer to stabilization if good
selections are made by the breeder yes
that does all make sense that is
accurate it goes on it says what do you
see when you self with silver
thiosulfate using a strong female from
each generation that is a very very good
question it goes on there is more it
says you have mentioned in previous
episodes that you have seen greater
variation in f2s more of the grandma and
grandpa than and some weirdos than you
do in the f1s does this prove true
through selfing f2s as well I may have
stumbled through reading that but that
is a very good question let me try to
explain what this person is asking when
you are breeding regular seeds with male
and female seeds the second filial
generation often shows what we call
transgressive segregation well we will
see as we will see progeny that
outperform both parents we will also see
uh representations of the grandma on
both sides and the grandpa on both sides
and possibly weird recessive traits F2
is kind of like the Pandora's Box we
kind of open up a lot of weird stuff F3
is kind of weird also F4 you start
mellowing [ __ ] out by the time you're at
F5 you're getting a lot more stable so I
do talk about the F2 showing a lot more
phenotypical variation some of us are
into that I'm a breeder I want to see
that weird [ __ ] that I can find in there
some of you guys don't like it but
that's what happens we get that weird
wildness that comes from the f2s now
they are asking if I were to take an F2
one of those f2s that came from that
batch of seeds and reverse that one and
self it am I going to find as wild uh
different phenotypical variants in that
F2 if I make in that S1 from that F2 I
know that's a bunch of a bunch of
different numbers there but it does make
sense if you're following along the
simple answer to that is no I'm not
going to find as many different
phenotypical variations and very
variances because I have not really
introduced anything to unlock Pandora's
Box I'm just taking one plant and I'm
just taking its chromosomes I'm taking
the pollen from that putting it back on
there it's just going to replicate that
plant if I were to take
um a plant from that a female from that
F2 and take another female from that
same filial generation and not self it
but reverse it and put the pollen on a
different phenotype at that point I may
see more phenotypical variants than I
would normally do with the selfing or a
reverse project but I think that would
be the only way to open up that
weirdness again is if I put it on a
different plant or if I pollinated one
of those reversals with something from
another generation but so I think the
short answer of what I'm trying to say
is no we will not see the wild
phenotypical variation if we were to S1
and F2 and if you're following along
with breeding class that does make
perfect sense there is more to this
question it says the reason I ask I like
that you've got a reason for the
question
it says I just bought a pack of yours
and sub cools Jack the Ripper F2 number
four and I'm interested in exploring the
genetics I wonder if I should open
pollinate the group to improve my
chances of getting a winner or should I
call the males and then self the best
looking female to see what she has in
her that is a great question that's all
about how much time how much space how
much energy uh what you really want to
do with this I've done in my opinion
I've done a pretty good selection on
this breeding project I know that the
Jack the Ripper F2 number fours are
really good seeds so you will find a
good winner in there there will be a
female in that batch that meets the
criteria you're looking for will have
all the Jack the Ripper traits the limey
dryer sheet flavor the head ripping Buzz
the strong growth I will have all of
that for you
if you want to open pollinate that to
take it to the F3 you will make
something amazing that would be a really
fun step to take these seeds but that
will take more time space and energy if
you just want to select the female
you've still got to grow out all the
seeds you've still got to find the
winner female you got to call the Boys
At this point you probably could have
just done the open pollination project
right here so
why not do both why not uh veg them get
clones of everybody do the open
pollination in that process you'll see
the female in there that stands out to
you you will notice even though it's
pollinated you'll see it it'll be
visually appealing it'll smell great
you'll know what the keeper out of that
project is I know you will have faith in
you so veg them take clones of everybody
do the open pollination select your
favorite female out of that you've got a
clone of her and backup in the clone
machine or in the Clone Dome keep that
one Harvest everybody else go back take
make two clones of your favorite keeper
and then do the selfing project again
that's in a in a [ __ ] Ideal World in
a fantasy land right there I'm not sure
which would be best for you both would
be amazing uh you've got two totally
different projects in there you could do
the open pollination with the entire
packs you've got probably five males and
five females just tossing all those Jack
the Ripper genetics around you'll make
some amazing [ __ ] uh or you've got the
option to do selective breeding you
could pick your favorite male and
favorite female will breed those
together and make a selectively bred F3
the open pollination will also be F3 I
would just call it open pollination F3
that's what I would call that uh the
selective breeding would be better for
the the F3 but your other option there
is to find your favorite female and self
it all three of those sound like very
fun projects for their own reason I
don't want to decide for you which one
you should do you're kind of asking
which one should I do but uh should I
call the males and then yeah I would do
them all this is like a a five-year
project but I would do all this [ __ ] if
I were you it does go on it says I do
have a plant count limit and I would
love to grow 100 plants do a proper Fino
hunt but I have kids and that is that
I'm going to stay within the bounds of
the law bro that is respectable and
respectful I did not write this down but
let me jump in and talk about something
here that you just said uh you want to
do a final hunt and you've got a small
plant count and you don't have time or
the ability to sift through a large
population of seeds uh me too bro I am
in an area where my plant account is
limited to 12 plants also I've got a
podcast a seed company and a five foot
long dreadlocks everybody in my city
knows who I am I'm pretty sure law
enforcement knows who I am by this point
I've got to be very careful I do not go
over my plant count because they would
love to make an example of me at this
point so I am only able to do 10 or 12
plant final hunts at a time just like
you the way that I work through a
hundred seeds is I will start 10 seeds I
will grow them if something doesn't look
right in the beginning I immediately
toss that [ __ ] get rid of it I don't
want it then I'll grow them out
sometimes those mutants are winners but
if I'm breeding and doing certain [ __ ] I
know what I'm looking for so I'll grow
them I'll get rid of the boys if I'm not
looking for boys so at this point I took
10 seeds I probably narrowed them down
to five before we get like into the
flowering phase then I'll flour those
out
as soon as they go into flower if I
popped if I got five in the flower room
I germinate five more immediately now
I'm back at my plant count why am I
wasting numbers I'm just gonna pop more
seeds to replace those uh so out of
those five I'll probably keep one or two
now I've got five more coming up I'm
gonna repeat the process keep one or two
I'm also gonna pop more seeds until I've
got one or two more Keepers and I can
only grow so I'm gonna have five Keepers
and germinate five more seeds then I'm
gonna pick my favorite two out of these
five and I'm gonna eliminate the other
three and just start over so it's kind
of like a bracket system uh Casting
Couch audition process grow ten of them
find your favorite grow ten more find
your favorite compare that top one out
of that one to the other top one before
who wins make them battle it's a battle
royale it's a bracket system I just keep
going and replacing as I find something
better so you can do a small Fino hunt
it just takes more time so the email
does go on there's more to the question
it says uh if I could have a fully
female population that would be better
if if I could get the same results or
better results from using your STS
recipe and selfing a strong female from
the population that would be ideal what
do you think well it sounds like you've
came up with part of the answer there
you want all female seeds because it
would be easier so at that point I would
say grow out the entire pack and find
your favorite female and then sulfur and
make your own feminized seeds out of her
that sounds like a really fun project so
it sounds like the best bet for you
maybe to make these Femme seeds and that
strategy would be to veg out these
plants get a clone from everybody put
them all into flour as soon as you
identify males get rid of the male plant
get rid of the male clones uh pot those
clones as soon as they're ready have
them on reserve they are now your backup
Keepers that's your genetic preservation
uh grow out the plants that you've got
in flour find your favorite female smoke
them dry them cure them finish them out
find your favorite female and make your
selection now you've got backup clones
toss everything accept your favorite one
grow that one out make two clones of it
now we're on to the selfing process
you're gonna treat one with the silver
you're going to pollinate the other and
now you have just done your selection
and made your Jack the Ripper F2 s ones
for yourself now the fun part of that is
growing them and seeing the uh the
variation that does come from that
you're not going to get that wild
variation like when you cross male and
female plants you're definitely not
going to get that wild F2 variation but
you're gonna see some cool stuff you're
gonna see some of what made the Jack the
Ripper some of the moms some of the dad
and you're going to get a bunch of
phenotypes that look just like that
female that you selected so my friend
Daft Punk's luggage I hope I answered
your question I got quite rambly on this
one there were a lot of good details to
talk about I look forward to knowing
what you decide to do with this project
are you going to go with the open
pollination are you going to go with
selective breeding or are you going to
do the feminized project it sounds kind
of like the uh the open pollination and
the Femme project like I said a minute
ago would work hand in hand you've
already got to do the final hunt let's
just do the open and pollination while
you're doing that you'll make so many
fun seeds to play with and then then you
can take your favorite one out of that
the original batch and you can self that
then also you can grow out all those
seeds and find your favorite from that
batch that you made and then you can
self that one you can make an F3 S1 also
then then do some plan then just start
back Crossing and going back in circles
you'll have a lot of fun with that if
you just open it up Don't Be Afraid have
a lot of fun if you see a plant with
potential and a plant with potential put
them [ __ ] together or line breed
parallel lines and then breed them
together in the end I give you full
permission to play with the Jack the
Ripper I came from sub I was given full
permission by Miss Jill to breed with it
my theory is once I make a seed I have
no right in saying what you do with it
if you've paid for it if you've bought
it or acquired it ethically if you stole
it piss off don't grow those no I know
you didn't but I'm just saying if you
got those seeds in an ethical manner I
have no control over what you do with
them have a bunch of fun also you got
some more free seeds coming your way so
like I've said before please send me a
real name and a shipping address I'll
get you out a free pack of irie Genetics
seeds if anybody out there has sent me a
message and I have not read it on the
show please do not feel discouraged I've
got a mountain of questions here in
front of me I'm working my way through
them the best I can I try to get three
or four per episode I did ramble quite a
bit through this one question so we only
covered three in this show but that's
just how it goes keep listening keep
watching maybe I'll read your question
on the next episode also if you have
grow questions out there please do go to
iregenetics.com find the grow help Tab
and please do send me your grow
questions if I read your question on the
show I will send you a free pack of irie
genetics premium seeds all right that is
all I've got for you for this episode I
want to thank you once again for
listening to episode 808 of the grow
from your heart podcast that is so many
shows thank you guys for all the love
and continued support make sure you
check out the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash girlfriend
your heart everything else you could
possibly need is on my website
irygenetics.com there's a link to the
Discord server there's a link to the
patreon there's a link to iridirect so
you can get seeds there's a link to
contact us everything you can imagine
all the vendor links are there
everything is at
iriegenetics.com all right my voice is
burning out my 80d is kicking in it's
time to wrap up the show I want to give
a big shout out to my buddy Billy bong
smoking and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
big up yourself every time rush the Jeff
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you