hey everybody this is Doug Benson and
you're listening to the grow from your
heart podcast hosted by my buddy roster
Jeff
[Music]
you bad [ __ ]
welcome to the show podcast world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 809
of the grow from your heart podcast once
again we've got a great show lined up
for you in this episode I'm going to
give away free seeds who doesn't want
free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about the free seeds later in this
episode if I do owe you free seeds from
a previous episode please send me an
email at growfromyourheart hotmail.com
put the word prizes and the subject line
let me know what episode number you won
the seeds on and send me a real shipping
address I will get your seeds out to you
I do know how a couple of people some
free seeds still thank you guys for all
the love and support and great feedback
and comments you've been leaving on the
YouTube channel there are so many great
comments every comment has been positive
I do appreciate that you guys keep the
conversation going down there in the
comment comments hang out meet one
another it's been so positive to see
good comments all right I don't want to
ramble too long I've got a lot of great
messages here in front of me of course
this message came from the grow help tab
on iregenetics.com this one came from a
new friend that I recently met in the
Discord server big shout out to my new
friend you did not put a name which you
want said on here so I will not say a
name you will know who you are when you
hear the message uh this one came from
the grow help tab if you go to
iregenetics.com there will be a tab it
says grow help or grow questions click
on that type in your grow question send
me your question if I read your question
here on the podcast that means that you
win a free pack of ire genetics premium
seeds so this question came from my new
friend who I also met on the Discord it
goes a lot like this it says Hey Rasta
Jeff hey my new friend it was a pleasure
and an honor to meet you I hope your
vacation goes well by the way it does go
on it says I hope this email finds you
irie everything irie it's been a
beautiful day a beautiful month it's
been great it goes on though it's says
I've been an avid listener for about a
year now and I finally have a question I
feel would be worth an email and maybe
even to read on the show I thought this
was a great question and a timely
question as well also I should mention
that part of the font got cut off so
some of the words here at the end of the
sentence are gone I don't know why my
printer made new margins uh technology
got me this time I'm just going to blame
it on the printer but I'm going to do my
best to read the message it says shout
out to you and the irie direct Discord
gromies for always being so generous
with your knowledge uh that's what we
are there for we're trying to make
everybody uh the best grower that we can
all be so thanks for joining us it's a
great time to have you there everybody
else if you're not on the Discord server
come join us come hang out discord's a
good time there will be a link in the
show notes and in the video description
come hang out it is a good time over
there also if you're testing my seeds
please do Post those on L Discord server
where was I there's more to this I'm
getting myself way lost it says I credit
you all for so much of my grow how not
to mention a bunt answering a bunch of
questions that have helped me out
through this grow I'm glad that we were
able to help you out I'm glad you found
us I'm glad we found you now it says for
my question this is a really good
question also I'm glad somebody brought
this up it says this is my first I rerun
ever well thank you thanks for growing
my stuff it says I'm growing a round of
lemon Jeffrey orangegasm and chemical
cocktail you've got quite a beautiful
variety there says I'm currently 41 days
into flower this was received quite a
while ago uh you were PR probably by the
time I'm reading this by the time this
comes out you will be about 55 days into
flower I estimate by the time this comes
out I'm sorry I was a little behind on
the recording schedule already had shows
planned and scheduled and recorded had
to catch up I apologize you guys if I
haven't read your message have no fear I
try to do as many as I can in a show and
I'm recording ahead so your message may
have already been read just not put on
the podcast yet may not have put it up
on YouTube stay tuned to let me get back
into this message this is going to be a
long question if I don't get focused
here it says um so they're about days
she's about day 55-ish into flower
it says I attend the garden while I'm
away so that leaves me with limited oh
let's see
um so there is part of this cut off some
part of the sentence is cut off here
because I said my printer went wonky on
me uh that's a good excuse I do know the
situation here I'm sure it says I plan
to go on vacation uh and I have no one
to attend the garden while I'm away so
that leaves me with limited options I'm
sure that's what it's meant to say just
based on a conversation we had I says I
would hate to cut the girls down early
but I would also hate to have issues
while I'm gone uh then it's cut off but
then it goes on with should I and this
is where they present a few options I
love this when somebody has already done
some thinking put some thought into it
they just want a little bit of
affirmation encouragement reinforcement
on what they're thinking this is a
beautiful strategy uh so the options
that our friend has come up with on
their own says uh should I harvest early
and turn my bedroom into a moist fridge
for two weeks now if you're going on
vacation very soon I don't know exactly
when you're leaving but I remember based
on our conversation on Discord that I
was thinking this was not the option
You're Gonna Leave way too early if you
chop them down before you leave uh
you're just cutting down plants way too
early I would rather do one of the
options I see later on the list because
that way we do at least get an option
for Success at this way when we cut them
down this early you've still got
somewhere between 12 and 20 days to go
by the time this episode comes out and
you're going to be on vacation when that
happens uh these plants will not if you
cut them down early they will not be
worth a [ __ ] in my opinion and I would
rather uh you've already wasted veg time
and you've wasted 55 days of flowering
time that means electricity nutrients
also possibly felonies based on your
location I'm not sure exactly where you
are in the rules there but
um you've already gotten so far let's
not cut it down early let's go too long
if that is our option it says I can also
even Harvest earlier and try to dry it
before I leave no that's cutting you
down like another 10 to 14 days even
earlier I still don't like that you're
going the wrong direction I like this
option that you came up with uh this one
says should I water the day before I
leave yes this is what I would do when I
read this I got got excited this is how
I would do it water the day before I
leave let the 1212 light schedule
continue for a week then have them
scheduled to turn off and start the
plants drying and darkness then of
course it does cut off part of the damn
sentence here but I understand what
you're going to do let the plants dry
whole Darkness for two weeks while I'm
gone I had 60 uh per 60 relative
humidity and 60 degrees Fahrenheit
um that is that is probably what I would
do I would even this may sound weird
because I preach a lot of opposite stuff
but to make this crop even more
successful to stretch out your watering
time and prolong the life of these
plants while you're gone and make this
plan work I would water them the day
before you're like right as late as
possible before you leave the very last
option
um I like to put larger saucers under my
plants if I'm growing in a three gallon
pot I'll put a five gallon like a saucer
that would normally go under a five
gallon pot I'll water the plant heavily
then I will over water it until that
saucer is completely full so I've got
the the soil or medium is completely
saturated then I've got that tray
underneath it which is also saturated
that'll just keep waking up into that
plant you'll get a couple of days out of
it that way depending on the size of the
original pot and the size of the backup
water people are going to say you're
going to over water and drown the plant
not if they're big established plants if
they're big enough this won't be a
problem just a little bit of them is
down in the water the top part will dry
up they'll get plenty of oxygen this
will work so I would water them right
before you leave over water them a
little bit
put those big saucers under there you've
got the right idea flip the lights to 12
12 but I would put them on 11 hours on
and 13 hours off I know I preach a lot
of different things but in this
situation this is going to be ideal what
this will do is this will extend your
water that is in those pots by just
maybe even a day maybe two days but
that's what you want you want that water
there as long as you can get it at this
point that's going to buy you over six
days that's six days less light that
you're getting to these plants that is
going to create humidity and heat in
that room it's going to make the plants
uh drink more the water is going to go
away is what I'm saying so maybe
consider going to 11 hours on and 13
hours off to extend that water in the
room DJ Short has taught us to turn the
lights to 11 13 a long time ago it seems
to work for a lot of plants I do preach
an opposite technique but guess what
both do have their pros and cons this
time it is a pro for the 11 13. so this
does go on it says uh water them the day
before I leave uh flip the light
schedule to 11 13 is what I would do
then yeah then you're going to have at
least a week of them getting watered
four or five maybe six or seven days
depending on again I don't know the uh
the conditions in the room the amount of
soil the size of pots but you're gonna
get four maybe five maybe seven maybe
ten days worth of water out of this then
while you're gone the plants will run
out of water then they're going to
slowly die on the stick uh but that that
could be probably your best option right
because you're not going to cut them
down early they will finish uh it does
sound sketchy the leaves are gonna look
like [ __ ] when you come back the plants
are going to look a little bit funky but
you're not growing for leaves we're
growing for harvestable smokable buds
the buds are going to be great this is
what we're gonna do anyway we're gonna
let the plant grow we were going to cut
it down and hang it upside down until it
died we're just not going to cut it
we're going to let it do I've done this
a long time ago I called it stick curing
I felt like I may have invented
something new honestly I just I had I
poorly timed some [ __ ] and I didn't have
a dry room so I let this room flower and
then there's other other [ __ ] in my dry
and cure room and I was like well I'll
just let that plant [ __ ] stand there
and die it'll die eventually and it did
the plant definitely did die and then I
just went and cut the leaves off of it
and we smoked it we dried it cured it
and smoked it I called it stick curing
it already started drying on the stick
it tasted really good that weed got us
really really high it was quality weed
for what it had to go through I would
rather you have this weed that goes a
little bit long and gets dry and kind of
falls apart when the leaves already fall
off of it by the time you get home then
cut down something that's just fluffy
dandelions not even fully formed a buds
worth looking at worth smoking this I
think this would be a better option so
um yeah steak cure it water that [ __ ]
right before you leave let it grow it'll
die while you're gone depending on how
long you're gone I wouldn't imagine
you're gone for more than two weeks
maybe 17 days is what most people go out
of town for uh you'll be right back
so yeah I think it'll dry up it'll start
to get a little bit crispy by the time
you're gone when you come home leave it
standing and pull off all the leaves any
leaf that is still on there just take it
you might want to put some supports in
it if you can get some steaks some
steaks because as they die they may
start tipping over so stake them up if
you can that may be your best bet there
give them some support but uh water the
[ __ ] out of them go out of town set your
conditions to go off in about a week let
that light go off let it cook for a week
with no lights if you can put a camera
in there and watch it uh that wouldn't
be a bad idea you can get a cheap camera
on Amazon that you can open up on your
phone while you're in Italy and you can
look and see like are the plants are the
leaves up are they down are they all the
way down are they yellow are they Brown
are they falling off then you can decide
how to adjust that timer I don't know
what your timer is on I've got timers
that attach to my phone and all kinds of
other [ __ ] so maybe you can adjust to
that but you've got the right idea water
them if I can go home when you get back
pull off all those leaves then chop them
then dry and cure and harvest as usual
the be a little bit dry already you're
getting a little bit ahead of yourself
especially in that 60 60 room that is
going to be great so there are questions
with the question it says is it possible
to trigger self-seeding if the whole
plant is left in darkness for too long
anything is possible but I don't think
it's going to happen within that week if
it does happen the seed won't have any
time to form you're going to cut it down
before that seed even does anything it
takes six to eight weeks to make a seed
fully form so with just a few days
you're not going to have much there to
worry about I doubt that it will happen
that is more likely more common if you
were to leave the pla the light on too
long and let it flower too long I think
the dark will kind of actually may help
you prevent that from happening so that
may be a good thing but like I said
anything is [ __ ] possible these are
cannabis plants and nature does find a
way is another thing I always say but I
think uh I think you'll be just fine
there something else I haven't thought
of no I think uh I think you've got the
right idea I've met you you're a very
intelligent person you seem to think
things through you've got the right idea
the team give you a lot of feedback and
input the day that we were there I think
you're going to make it through I really
hope you just go have fun on your
vacation I know where you're going I
hope you have a beautiful time I may
have accidentally said where you're
going here on the show if I did I'll try
to bleep it but go have fun enjoy
yourself
see the sights eat the food meet the
people uh see the art I know where
you're going it says let me know how my
girls look when you think oh I looked at
the pictures you've got a ways to go uh
you definitely have a little ways to go
those plants are all uh longer finishers
than a lot of the other stuff so you got
plenty of time uh then it said would
love to know your thoughts yeah uh great
question great Garden uh your house is
beautiful we saw your video on the
Discord there everything looks great
um there are a lot of grow details here
I don't need the grow details really
we've got a strategy is what I think uh
we needed if you had some way to auto
water these plants that would be all the
grow details I needed but I feel like we
answered the question I hope you have a
beautiful time on your vacation if you
see this episode before you go uh join
us on the Discord if not I hope to see
some pictures and details of the trip
when you get back jump in the Discord
let me know how it goes also let me know
how the plants look when you came back
and also let me know what strategy you
chose to go with maybe you'll hear this
podcast while you're on the plane
that'll be really awkward if you've
already left
I try to time it well anyway thank you
for the great message also I will send
you a free pack of seeds I can wait
until you get back so send me your
address when you do return from your
vacation I will get you a free pack of
irie genetic seeds it looks like you're
running some irie now it'd be an honor
to get you some more irie gear that you
could run without an interruption all
right I'm quite rambly today this is
going to be a long podcast if we don't
get my [ __ ] focused up I've got another
message this one also did come from the
grow help tab on the ire genetics
website once again if I read your
message on the show you will get a free
pack of seeds if you've got a grow
question please go to iregenetics.com
find that grow help tab type in your
question hit send when I read it on the
show ding ding ding ding ding you will
get some free Ivory genetics premium
seeds this one came from my friend Billy
Billy un seeds dude Billy D please send
me your shipping address because I want
to send you a free pack of seeds this
one says I just finished a small
breeding project with your gear and I am
very excited very excited me too bro
it goes on it says I hit a Golden Goat
leaning Fino of Shredder oh that's
[ __ ] awesome dude uh the shredder is
a great one it's goat leaning with
orange gasm pollen so you've got uh
you've got blueberry cookies you've got
Platinum Tangy you got Golden Goat times
two in there uh bro that's gonna be a
vigorous potent and terpy freaking plant
that is a good mix they're a good idea
I'm glad you did that uh Vinnie says I
only got five seeds but they are huge
and then he sent me a picture uh the
seeds look like uh small marbles these
are gigantic ganja seeds uh he said have
you ever seen seeds this big from either
parent uh the true answer is yes some of
the Golden Goat back cross seeds come
out very huge and you've got Golden Goat
in here twice so we're putting a lot of
that Golden Goat Vigor in there so that
probably is a Golden Goat trait also the
blueberry cookies makes giant seeds
you'll notice the blueberry Butcher and
blue raspberry truffle seeds are all
huge also uh yeah those seeds are huge
is that the where's the blueberry via
the Golden Goat Shredder uh yeah that
was the blueberry cookies all right just
making sure over here I make so many
things you guys I get confused but the
blueberry cookies does make giant seeds
so yes there was a lot of potential for
Gigantic seeds in there
um on the opposite anything I cross with
the Durban Poison makes little tiny
seeds most of the time so uh that's just
a variation that's going on there but
sometimes when I do the Durban Poison
outside I get bigger seeds it's just the
way that science and nature want to play
together there's more it says I can't
freaking wait to pop these for the next
grow bro I hope to see pictures if you
get a winner uh maybe name it something
cool and send me a [ __ ] cut bro what
was the bad Ninja Turtle remember there
was a ninja turtle and they made one
that was like their cousin and he came
out with fangs and [ __ ] he was still a
turtle but he was kind of wild there's
like a snapping turtle name it that okay
um it goes on it says for size
comparison that is a shredder seed next
to one of the dinosaur eggs yeah they
were giant bro I will give you credit
those were big seeds I said I can't wait
to see what Sprouts I'll also be running
some table seeds as well hope you had a
great fourth bro my fourth was excellent
It's good to hear from you I hope to see
pictures of the table seeds people are
going what are table seeds bro
if you have not been following along for
a long time I do put out a product I
call table seeds sometimes I sit at my
desk sometimes I sit right here
sometimes I got another cozy location
with a chair where I will package up
seeds all day I'll spend all day just
getting a jar of seeds or a bag of seeds
or a bin of seeds and putting those into
packs of either 5 6 12 50 depends on
what I'm doing right but I just package
up seeds all day sometimes when I'm done
I will discover that maybe like right
along here along the iPad stand or maybe
along here by the microphone stand I
dropped a few seeds along the way I
don't know what they are because I may
have worked with multiple batches of
seeds throughout the day and I do not
have confidence to say that these seeds
are whatever seeds they are I don't want
to mislabel them sell them to you and
you get something that is not what you
purchased I put them in a bin and I call
them table seeds just seeds that I
picked up off the table that I'm not
sure what they are then I package them
up in just different batches depending
on what I'm in the mood for sometimes
it's 10 packs sometimes it's 15 or 20.
throw a few in a bag and then we sell
them on the website for a very low price
so that everybody can get some seeds you
don't know what they are but it could be
anything from the irie genetics lineup
it could be it could be orange gasm it
could be lemon Jeffrey it could also be
Mach 1 to a rise it could be Jack the
Ripper to a rise it could be a ryze f2s
it could be anything that I've had on
the table within the past amount of time
which I was playing with seeds it could
be unreleased [ __ ] it could be uh
pre-release of things that will come out
in the future but you never know what's
in that bag because it's just [ __ ] that
I scooped up off the table and I don't
uh I don't scoop them up like these from
today's batch go into a pack of table
seats they go all into one jar I've got
one little section of table seeds I
shake it up we mix it it's like a big
bag of uh it's like a jelly bean bag
there you never know what flavor you're
going to pull out when you grow those
bro do let me see let me make sure that
I've recovered all I read all of this
that I've covered all of this question
uh the reason I feel like they are so
big is what we're going to call hybrid
Vigor I bet those seeds are going to be
vigorous they're going to make giant
plants to grow super fast and I'm sure
you're going to have some crazy amazing
Terps come out of that the blueberry
cookies makes this like Tangy fruity
sour funky terp the Platinum Tangy of
course is oranges and Funk and then you
got that Golden Goat in there to give
you that tropical stuff all of those
plants are vigorous and super potent
that plant's Gonna Be A Winner bro good
idea to cross that I hope it goes Super
well for you I'm excited to see how it
goes as well also my dude please send me
your address because I do owe you that
free pack of irie genetics premium seeds
alright let's keep this party moving
I've got one more question here right in
front of me this one also came from the
grow help tab this one came from
somebody who wants to be called Owen big
shout out to my new friend Owen I do owe
you a free pack of seeds so once again
please send me your shipping address you
guys when you send me your address
please do put a real name on there I
don't want to send to like Bill's ganja
Farm or [ __ ] weed smoker 5000 put a
real name on there please it just made
makes me feel more comfortable packaging
up your seeds this question goes a
little bit like this it says in regards
to cocoa and perlite mix versus a peat
and perlite mix what is the main
difference there is a major difference
there that I can notice right away if
you were to grab a scoop of let's start
with the peat if you just reached into a
bag and grabbed a scoop of peat that is
going to be a spongy gooey moist organic
feeling substance in there kind of like
you got some uh some Earth some foliage
some uh it's kind of like grabbing a
sponge it's got that spongy texture to
it when you squeeze it it'll fluff back
up it'll squeeze it's soft it's earthy
it's got that organic feel to it perlite
on the other hand is like grabbing a
glass uh grabbing a handful of small
glass rocks it's really light for its
volume so it takes up a lot of space and
provides air the peat will suck up water
and hold in water and not provide any
air space the reason I use the perlite
and a cocoa mix is to put some
separation in the cocoa fibers there's
not enough oxygen in there so I'll put
at least 30 percent perlite in a mix of
cocoa to make it fluffier make it a
little bit more oxygenated that way I
feel like when I water all that cocoa
it's going to compress it's going to
compact all of the oxygen gets pushed
out of the top The Roots get squished in
there I feel like those roots strive
more strongly if I put some perlite in
there and allow just less crushing space
and put some air in there I think that
that's what works best for me so that's
what I do that's the main difference in
a perlite NP mix it goes on it says can
you use microbes in both yes absolutely
you definitely can and should use
microbes in both of those mixes all
right the last part of this question
does say are there any pros and cons
versus cocoa versus Pete
um yeah I think if you do the peat in
there it's a different texture different
consistency than the cocoa it holds
water uh differently it's got a
different porosity is that even a word
we're going to make that a word now ding
that's the word of the day but uh it
holds water so you're going to have in
consistent water spots you're going to
have some spots that are more dry some
that are more wet in your container and
I don't like that I'd rather have smooth
even consistency wet all the way down
this way drier up toward the top that's
just how it works that's what I'd rather
have other than pockets of pee over here
that are more wet than the cocoa that's
over here I just that's not what I would
prefer so the pros and cons are just
more consistent watering more consistent
uh watering inside the rhizosphere and
more consistent wet and dry times you're
going to get more dry back time with the
cocoa also I believe you get better
airflow and better root development if
you put a little bit of perlite in there
a minute ago I did say that I like to do
approximately 30 percent per light if I
had my way I would do probably somewhere
between 20 percent uh perlite and 10 to
15 personalite the bigger one the
chunkier one just to put some chunks in
there then we would do a whole bunch of
the cocoa I think that gives me about 70
to 65 percent cocoa left then while I'm
making that mix I would put a big scoop
of azos in there give myself some some
microbes to get started then we would
plant into that my dude Owen thank you
for the great question please once again
do send me your shipping address because
I owe you a free pack of irie Genetics
seeds ladies and gentlemen if you have
sent me a question please do not feel
discouraged if I did not read it on
today's episode I've got a lot of
messages here in front of me and I've
got a lot of podcasts coming out got a
lot of stuff to look forward to keep
listening keep watching maybe I will
read your message on a future episode if
you have not yet sent me that question
that you're thinking about you're going
roster Jeff I should ask you this bro go
to your computer go to your phone right
now go to iregenetics.com find that grow
help tab type in that question I will do
my best to get your question here on the
podcast and you will win free seeds one
big disclaimer if you're driving wait
till you're parked bro don't do that
[ __ ] on the interstate I want you to
live to see another show I think that's
all that I have got for you for this
episode I want to thank you guys for
listening to another episode of of the
growth from your heart podcast if you
have any questions Corrections comments
or concerns you know I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
from your heart at hotmail.com don't be
shy send me that feedback if you got
some hate mail send it my way we'll see
what we can do once again be sure to
send those grow questions to the grow
help tab if you want the free C it's
also support the show on patreon I've
been giving out patreon coupons for
iridirect if you're trying to buy seeds
you can save a lot of funds by joining
patreon thank you for the patreon
support at patreon.com forward slash
grow from your heart everything else you
could possibly need is on my main
website at iregenetics.com there's a
link to the Discord server there's a
link to the seed vending uh there's only
two other vendors there's a link to
everything you could possibly ask for at
iregenetics.com that is all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in a
couple of days with fresh new content
I'm gonna give a giant shout out to an
old friend John bend it and until next
time take a fat dab and give your Mama
hug for me
[Music]
every time
thank you
[Music]