so keep it locked the girl from your
heart podcast that's now
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 810
of the girl from your heart podcast once
again I've got a great show lined up for
us in this episode I'm going to give
away free irie genetics premium seeds
hang out we'll talk more about the free
seeds later in this episode I don't want
to waste too much time let's jump right
into the question and answer portion of
this podcast this question came from my
friend Anthony it did come from the grow
help tab on the ire genetics website go
to the ire genetics website at
iregenetics.com there's a tab on the top
that says grow help or grow questions
click on there send me your questions
this one came from Anthony and it goes
just like this it says hey Ross to Jeff
in Fino hunting is it best to naturally
see how the plants develop
simultaneously organically mixed out
with other stresses or is it best to
push them to their fullest potential
with salt and stress and maximize their
capabilities or both and or why that is
a lot of question in there there's a lot
to think about in that question this is
a lot of fun so let me break this down
we're going to start from the beginning
and answer this step by step and talk a
lot about this question this one's very
fun for me uh in Fino hunting what's a
final hunt that is when we get an amount
of seeds a population it could be five
it could be ten it could be a hundred it
could be a hundred thousand anywhere in
between there that is when we are
running a population of seeds and
looking for the phenotype which is most
desirable for our situation if you've
got a commercial growth you've got a
home growth you've got a big space a
small space indoors Outdoors your
phenotype selection may be a little bit
different maybe you want the one that
tastes a lot like strawberry maybe you
want the one that tastes a lot like
mango maybe you want the one that grows
taller maybe you want the one that grew
real wide and short that's your
phenotypical selection that you're
looking for the variation that you will
see amongst the pack will vary uh based
on the uh the plants that you're growing
if you're growing something like an F1
you may see a lot of variation if you're
going in F2 you'll see a lot more within
the F3 it may start tapering off it
maybe even more wild depending on what
the breeder did but that is going to be
a final hunt when you're running a pack
of seeds and looking for the specific
plant within that package within that
population to meet your needs a Fino
hunt let's find the phenotype for my
garden for my specific needs so that's a
pheno hunt when Fino hunting is it best
to naturally see how the plants develop
simultaneously organically maxed out
with other stresses or best to push them
to their fullest potential okay so if
I'm running a final hunt if I'm looking
for a specific phenotype first of all
I'll probably run all of these seeds
exactly the same on their first run I've
got just like a basic nutrient mix a
small little tester grow area I would
put all of the seedlings in that run in
that first little room kind of like the
casting couch the auditioning process
before I put them into a great big room
and see what they do I do a small Fino
hunt in a small room so I would run
everybody in the same conditions that
way I can see what they do under just
normal conditions if you normally grow
Organics grow them organically if you
normally grow with bottled nutrients
grow them with bottled nutrients if you
normally do it hydroponically do it
hydroponically if your regular routine
is to do it in Cocoa with perlite and
New Millennium nutrients and a gravity
fed drip system do that because that's
what we need to find the plant that
works the best in the system which we
are working with you've got to find the
plant that's going to perform in your
system so why not run it run it in the
system so that's the way I do it I run
them all the same in a very basic system
then I will make my phenotype selection
then once I've made that selection I
will grow it a couple of times in very
similar conditions and take a lot of
notes and then I will start adjusting it
based on what I see could be possible
does it need more does it need less of
something of anything can I push
something a little bit harder would
something make it a little bit happier
do I start noticing that right at week
six it really starts to beef up so maybe
at week five I could start feeding it a
little bit more that way I could beef it
up a little bit heavier maybe I noticed
that if I over feed it a week seven it
starts to turn yellow and stops eating
maybe I'll stop over feeding it so much
learn that plant and then adjust to that
after you found your phenotype so you're
saying in Fino hunting is it best to
naturally see how they develop
simultaneously yes I do the same thing
to all of them then you say organically
maxed out with other stresses or best to
push them no I don't push them uh very
super hard until I actually have made a
phenotypical selection I kind of run
just a basic mix I've got a real good
New Millennium balanced mix that I know
works for just about every plant I will
run all the plants in that under the
basic lighting system that I've got and
sometimes my basic lighting system
changes sometimes I've got different
ideas sometimes it changes uh seasonally
in the winter of course I hang up an HPS
light I don't want to put a heater in
the room I just put up an HBS and add a
few more plants under that in the summer
it's way too hot I couldn't run that
thing right now it roast the entire room
so the HBS just comes down in the
summertime I make a few adjustments like
that but I really don't change a lot but
also I do what I'm going to do to them
in the future if I plan on topping them
if I plan on lollipopping them if I'm
going to spread them out if I'm going to
scrog them if I'm going to just see if
green them is little tiny plants I do
that to the whole run and if that's
going to be my plan for the future for
these plants then that's what I'm going
to do in the starter run because I want
to know what I'm going to get when I put
this plant in the big room so I want to
know what to expect it's got to be able
to handle my basic nutrient feed then I
can work from there if it can take my
basic just my basic feed my basic
nutrition I know how to boost it from
there and make it even better if it can
handle my pesticide regimen if it can
handle my lighting schedule if it can
handle uh being lollipopped way far up
the way that I like to do it and then
have a lot of the little sucker branches
taken off and a lot of popping and
twisting and bending it over and putting
it into a scrog can it handle that sort
of stuff that's the phenotype the Fino
hunt that I'm going to give it so if it
can handle all of that stuff I need to
find that out in the first run before I
go put it into a bigger room so I think
what I'm trying to say is run the final
hunt just like you're going to run your
main run if you're going to top it top
it if you're gonna scrog it out scrog it
out that way we can find the plant that
works the best in that situation of
course that is if you've got time space
room all of the Necessities to run a big
final hunt and do all of those things to
those plants oftentimes we may get the
phrase Fino hunt and testers mixed up
because I do them differently but
sometimes it happens very similarly
sometimes I'll be doing a test run and
find a phenotype that is [ __ ] magical
in there so sometimes they look similar
but they are actually different uh
projects with different goals a test
batch I'm just seeing what we have did I
hit my goal do we have any problems uh
what do they look like what did we
create with a final hunt those have been
tested we know that those have been
narrowed down to where they're going to
be acceptable quality seeds uh then we
just have to find the works find the one
that works the best for for our needs a
lot of times I can't do that by running
a small plant finding something that I
like but it is much better and I do
recommend to manipulate it however
you're going to manipulate that plant in
your big room I guess I would say train
how you're going to go to battle or
practice with the drumsticks you're
going to play with at the gig is what I
think I'm trying to say all right my
buddy Anthony he does wrap it up with a
couple of other things here uh sort of
some private stuff to me and then he
says thank you for keeping me safe wraps
it up with the word peace my dude
Anthony thank you for the great message
I do realize you come from prohibition
land so if you have any more questions
please do reach out also if you would
like a free pack of seeds or a free
t-shirt please do send me your shipping
information if you want a t-shirt let me
know what size I do understand you're in
prohibition land there you may not be
able to rock the t-shirts with pride
maybe better if I send you seeds I'm not
sure which one you would like let me
know my dude we will get you taken care
of I look forward to the reply let's
keep moving you guys I'm super rambly we
got a good flow going on here let's move
into the next message of course this one
also did come from the grow help tab at
iregenetics.com this one came from our
friend New York green shout out to all
of our friends out there in New York
enjoying and supporting cannabis
legalization
um New York is killing it you guys a lot
of things are taken off out there a lot
of people out there to make a lot of
cool things happen uh this one is a
general grow question and it says what's
up roster Jeff what's up bro I'm
chilling out doing a podcast with my
friends I hope you're doing well ah
thank you for watching listening if
you're watching out there on YouTube
please do click like on the YouTube
video also click that subscribe button
that just takes you a second it does
help me out quite a bit thank you for
the opportunity for the Shameless
advertising it says I just want to start
off by saying thank you for all that you
do for the community I'm currently
running Sun kiss for the first time I'm
in late veg and I will be all right let
me back up because I just glazed right
over uh thanks for all I do for the
community thank you brother you are very
welcome thank you for noticing thank you
for the great compliments but thank you
I do appreciate the uh the words of
encouragement and the positive influence
in the words of affirmation those do go
a long way so thank you for noticing uh
that I'm putting in some work for you
guys it goes on though it says roster
Jeff I am currently running Sun kiss for
the first time that is a great plant you
will enjoy it it says I am late in veg
and I will be flipping them here shortly
all right that sounds like fun my
question is when would the best time be
to start implementing the flour
nutrients I know I shouldn't start them
until they have been flipped but about
how many weeks after the flip I've read
so many different answers on the
internet yes the internet is wild that's
what part of what inspired this podcast
is I would read all of the crazy answers
that people gave you for this simple
question and my head would explode and I
would like to uh bash my head against
the wall and drive my car to each one of
these people's houses and ask them why
they wrote what they wrote and I it just
drove me crazy so yeah I tried to filter
out all the [ __ ] for you and give
you solid answers is what inspired me to
do this podcast so oh where were we
there there is more I know it is right
here I appreciate any insight you may
have and maybe any tips you might have
for my first run with sunkiss uh thanks
in advance from New York green stay irie
bro always irie forever irie can't stop
won't stop thank you uh tips for sun
kiss yes
um you guys there are 800 episodes of
the girl from your heart podcast
available one of those episodes is
titled
Sun kiss so if you search the word Sun
kiss and grow from your heart podcast on
YouTube it will bring up a full uh
somewhere between 30 and 40 minute
episode all about growing Sun kiss it
will tell you so much so I recommend
checking out that podcast not just to
blow you off but I already did it and it
seems like a lot of people don't realize
there are a lot of old episodes so go
check out the back catalog while you're
here while you're subscribing go see
some of the older stuff that we put out
a long time ago we've been doing this
for 800 episodes quite a few years go
check out that but there's an old
episode now the question when would you
start implementing flowering nutrients
that's a very good question there are a
couple of options for this you can start
uh day one the day that you flip that
plant into flower you could just set
that veg bottle right over there and
bring that flowering bottle over start
using that you are now officially in
flower you were using your flowering
nutrients or you could gradually taper
it off you could phase out that uh
whatever so if you're feeding I don't
know how much I don't know the amounts
but I'll say a hundred because it's
easier to keep track if you're feeding a
hundred mils while you're in veg maybe
drop it to 50 mils 50 milliliters of
your veg and 50 milliliters of Bloom for
a week and then cut out that veg and go
a hundred percent all the way onto the
bloom nutrients or you could phase it
out as long or slowly as you would like
I would recommend over the first two
weeks I wouldn't go longer than two
weeks that's as long as you need to
taper that process off some strains some
cultivars do need a little bit more
nitrogen to get them all the way through
the flowering process so it's not a bad
idea to keep that vegetative nutrient
going get a little bit more nitrogen
into there some plants however some OG
cush type cultivars dog walker uh
specifically does not like too much
nitrogen a little bit early into the
flowering phase you got to cut that one
out a little bit earlier but that's just
some strains dog walkers some of the
cushier type stuff it just won't let it
stack up properly sometimes it does what
I call the stairway or the spiral
staircase your buds should stack and
then stack and then just stack up but
sometimes it'll make Just a Little Rock
nugget and then right around the pole of
the stem it'll make a little another one
and then right around the pole make
another one It'll like Spiral up the
stick up the stock of the plant instead
of making a big bud like it should that
could be from over feeding nitrogen uh
too much into the flowering phase but if
you Fade Out phase out that nitrogen
within the first two weeks you will be
just fine so if you're growing something
from my lineup a go to go cross and a
rise cross maybe even the Afterglow
crosses I would recommend possibly
keeping some of that nitrogen in there
at least the first week of the flowering
phase while you're feeding because the
plants I make are super hungry they are
hyper vigorous they do eat a lot and
they do go nine to ten maybe even a
little bit longer than 10 weeks in some
cases so those plants may need that
nitrogen your plant is going to eat most
of the nitrogen early on in the
flowering phase and it's going to store
it up in the vegetative phase so you
need to get that in there early once it
starts fading once the nitrogen is too
low it's hard to catch up we're calling
it chasing is what we call it when you
can't get enough nitrogen in there let
me take a look at my notes see what else
we could tell you I would you can either
just cut it off right at day one when
you flip the light to 1212 that is day
one a flower and you can also flip to
your flowering nutrients or you can take
up to two weeks and slowly gradually
replace them as you feel necessary so
this is going to be plant specific you
do have the option to either just cut it
off at day one or like I keep saying you
can taper it off over a week or a two
week process if you do the taper off
just make sure that you're doing like
whatever percentage of one and the
percentage of the other bottle and work
from 100 this way to 100 this way use
the sliding scale do the math as long as
it takes as much percentage as it does
take you maybe just go in quarters
replace it go like 25 flowering nudes 50
75 then 100 flowering nudes over the
course of a week or two that'll get you
there beautifully all right I think I've
rambled on enough about this one my
friend New York green since I read your
question here on the podcast cast that
does mean that you win a free pack of
ire genetics premium seeds please do
send me your address so I can send you a
free pack of seeds when you do send me
that shipping address please include a
real name that I can put on the box or
at least a a legit looking name I can
put on the box I don't want to put New
York green on there no offense that's
just what I'm using for now if anybody
else out there wins free seeds from me
please do put a real name in the email
so that I can send you your seeds and
not have to send it to weed smoker 5000
and Ganja Farmer 420 just makes me
uncomfortable when I go to the post
office and the lady scans the box and
looks at it and goes Ganja Farmer 420
huh that sets it down and scans the next
box Stoner Dave 5000 huh sets it down
and like she sees a theme and I don't
want them to get any ideas you know what
I'm saying so let's just send a real
name now there's no need to kill the
momentum let's keep the party moving I
do have another great message here in
front of me this one also came from the
grow help tab on the ire genetics
website this one came from a person
called pineapple long tooth big shout
out to pineapple a long tooth for the
great question we've got a breeding
question this time and it goes a little
bit like this it says hey Ross to Jeff
I'm a long time listener and I owe parts
of my growing success to you you don't
owe me anything bro this was enough we
are even now thank you for the love
thank you for the question now all you
got to do is grow the best you can make
me proud all right it goes on it says
I'm now looking to do some breeding yes
I'm glad I've inspired you to do some
breeding it says I have identified which
male I want to use I'm now curious on
when to pollinate that is a very good
question uh the next part of the
question is would you suggest flipping
the male and the females at the same
time or would you stagger the flowering
that is a very good question I've got a
very long drawn out answer we'll get to
that don't worry it says I would like to
chop the mail down after he drops pollen
and I have collected some as well is
there another time I should pollinate
the females again thank you for all your
help and work with the podcast your
information is help so many and I
consistently re-listen to shows for the
information thanks again your pal
pineapple long tooth pineapple that is a
great message my dude thank you I
appreciate it
um I'm glad you're listening to the
podcast multiple times I'm glad you're
learning I'm glad you are breeding now
let's answer some of these breeding
specific questions the first part of the
question is would I stagger the
flowering of the male and female plant
for a breeding project in an Ideal World
if you're trying to make a lot of [ __ ]
ton of seeds if you're trying to sell
them yes you would want to learn the
Staggering time of these plants it would
be better you just make more seeds to be
honest with you but but if you can't do
that they will work perfectly fine if
you put the male and females in the room
all at the same time guess what will
happen you will make a bunch of seeds
the only difference will be you could
make a lot more seed if you time it
better the only reason I stress on
timing it differently is because I make
seeds for commercial production in I
want to make as many as I can because of
course I want to get them out there I
want to sell them that is my product if
you're making seeds for yourself you
will make plenty of seeds if you just
throw them all in there at the same time
now let's talk about your options here
if you do want to stagger them I would
get the male pollinating you want him
making a big fat cloud of pollen when
your female plants have big fat ripe
pistols those dandelion looking flowery
things popping up on your plants those
are what's going to get pollinated you
want as much of that as possible on that
plant you want them as healthy as
possible on that plant this could happen
anywhere between somewhere around
approximately day 23 to day 32 it could
be a little earlier it could be a little
later I want to say day 23 to day 32
this just depends on the female plant
I've got two plants that I like to use
as examples in this occurrence quite
often I have got a strawberry fields
plant which makes strawberry Starburst
that also makes the red pill it also
made Raphael well it makes a few other
things coming up there's Jack the Ripper
across to the Strawberry Fields we'll
talk more about that in the future then
also I've got the Platinum Tangy that's
what makes the orange gasm that's what
makes the sun kiss there's a lot of
stuff that came from the Platinum Tangy
uh the Michelangelo came from that one
they're awesome amazing plants they both
make a lot of great seeds they both big
both make a lot of great crosses but I
have to time them completely differently
in the breeding room if I want to
maximize their seed potential the
Platinum Tangy plant will accept pollen
much earlier when I put the Platinum
Tangy plant into flower I only have to
wait three maybe three and a half weeks
before I pollinate that plant the
Strawberry Fields plant that plant needs
at least four maybe five weeks before
it's fully ready for pollen and then
they create the same amount of seeds so
now I have learned to put that
Strawberry Fields plant into the
flowering room a week 10 days maybe two
weeks ahead of the Platinum Tangy plant
if I want them both to receive pollen at
the ideal time also I would start
flowering the male plant just a little
bit early maybe a week or 10 days
earlier than everybody else if you can
keep him away from everybody if you can
keep him from pollinating everybody else
get that pollen going in there so he's
building up a big load of pollen then
when all the females are ready take uh I
would take him in there if you can take
the top in there it just depends on what
your situation is get the top off that
plant get that plant get it in there and
pollinate maybe take off the top leave
the rest of the plant let it build up
more pollen chop down the rest of the
plant you asked another part should I
pollinate a second time yes five to ten
days later pollinate again don't wait
too long maybe five to seven days later
pollinate again about a week I generally
do it a week apart that way the plant
can build up more pollen a few more
pistols or what didn't get pollinated
will receive some more pollen go in
there and smack it around so wait until
your female plants are all ready for the
pollen get your mail plan in there give
them a good Shake get that pollen in
there cut them if you need to get parts
of the pollen moving around do whatever
you need to do to fully pollinate that
room get all of the females get every
pistol let that male plant build up
another load for about seven days then
at this point you can cut them down and
carry them and touch each plant with him
and get that pollen everywhere you're
going to make a mess now clean up the
room that is the worst part of pollen is
that it's [ __ ] everywhere and it
tastes like [ __ ] and it sucks to clean
up but that is breeder life so do that
then once you've got everything cleaned
up you've done your second pollination
that's when you can decide if you want
to run those lights on your regular 12
12 or if you want to do research and
watch my 18-6 after pollination video
where I talk about changing the light
cycle all right let me check in on this
see if I've covered all of your
questions when to pollinate
um I would pollinate when the pistols
are the ripest that's going to depend on
a lot of different things the cultivar
the room the environment the feed the
lights the VPD will make a big
difference on that what you've sprayed
them try not to spray anything if you
can that's going to make it a big
difference
um would you suggest flipping them male
and females at the same time if you've
got a perfect world I would flip the
male seven to ten days ahead maybe two
weeks ahead of everybody then start
flipping the females as you know that
they go into the room with their
flowering routine then I would Paul
there's more let me stay on track would
you stagger the flowering yes if you can
but if not it's all gonna work out have
no fear people want to make breeding too
hard put them in there and let them [ __ ]
it's gonna happen dude kids have babies
all the time plants have babies all the
time animals have babies all the time
nature wants babies to happen creation
is all of the world's whole purpose
everything just wants to breed and make
more put those plants in there and don't
watch them let them have some dark time
they'll do the thing bro don't worry
there is more though it says I would
like to chop down the mail after I've
collected some I'm sure I've done a
pollen collection episode is there
another time yes about a week after the
first pollination now I do think I have
covered all of this which means my
friend pineapple long tooth you win a
free pack of irie genetics premium seeds
so once again please do send me your
shipping address address I'm not sure if
I would want to ship it to Pineapple
long tooth but if that's what I gotta do
I'll put that name on The Box everybody
else out there if you want free seeds
once again please do send me your name
and your shipping address I'd love to
get you a free pack of irie genetics
premium seeds if I did not read your
question on this episode please do not
feel uh ignored rejected uh discouraged
keep sending me questions or keep
listening I may read your question on
the next episode if you have not already
sent in your grow question please go to
iregenetics.com click on that grow help
tab fill out the grow questionnaire send
me a question maybe I'll read your
question on an upcoming episode that is
all I've got for you for this episode if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would definitely
love to hear from you the email address
for that part is grow from your heart
hotmail.com don't be shy send me your
feedback your constructive criticism or
like I said before if you've got some
hate mail go ahead and send that my way
maybe we'll make some adjustments but
probably not make sure you check out the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart stay updated
on patreon for coupon codes early alerts
on drops and exclusive offers on
iredirect.com anything else you could
possibly need will be at my website
irygenetics.com there's a link to ire
direct so you can get the seeds there's
a link to the Discord server so you can
join us and hang out come on you guys
join the Discord server come hang out in
the Smokers Lounge I'm over there taking
dabs Billy bong is over there taking
dabs Miss blue kiss is over there taking
dabs there's a lot of great people Trey
K dgc may even be over there taking dabs
who knows who you might run into at the
irie Army Discord uh what's it called
The Smokers Lounge video chat that's a
lot of words it's not that hard to find
it you guys there will be a link in the
bio and in the video description and in
the show notes I said Link in the bio
I'm so used to that not even going to
edit that out all right go join the
Discord you guys I look forward to
seeing you there in The Smokers Lounge
I've got to wrap up this show I don't
know if I'm having a stroke or if I just
can't figure out how to talk anymore I'm
pretty sure I'm going to be okay check
on me next week you guys see how it went
I'm gonna give a big shout out to my
buddy Norton smokes too much and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
foreign
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you
hug for me