so keep it locked the girl from your
heart podcast that's now
[Music]
all right here we go welcome to the
podcast everybody I'm your host Rasta
Jeff this is episode 811 of the grow
from your heart podcast in this episode
we're going to give away free seeds
we're also going to talk about flushing
our plants before Harvest is Flushing
real is Flushing a myth is Flushing Bro
Science we'll talk more about that in
just a minute before we talk about
flushing I do want to remind you that
everybody that participates in the
patreon campaign at the 25 level or
higher in the month of August we'll
receive a coupon for a free pack of
seeds from ire Direct that's right join
us on patreon at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart everybody
that contributes to the 25 level or
higher tier will receive a coupon code
for free seeds and I redirect of course
you will have to pay the shipping on
that free pack of seeds but free seeds
for the month of August I will be giving
away a free pack of Jack Tripper a 10
pack of Jack Tripper to everybody who
supports the patreon campaign at the 20
five dollar level or higher all right
let's jump into today's main topic of
this podcast today's question came from
the grow help tab on the irie genetics
website if you go to my website
iregenetics.com there is a row of tabs
on the top one of them does say grow
help or grow questions click on that tab
send me your grow question if I read
your grow question here on the podcast
you will win a free pack of ire genetics
premium seeds so if you've got a great
question please send it to me there's a
good chance I will read a good question
here on the show if I have not read your
question please do not feel discouraged
I've got a mountain of emails here in
front of me we are slowly working our
way through them I may get to your
question in the next episode it may be a
couple of shows don't feel discouraged
also please do keep sending those
questions even though I've got a bunch
there are a lot of great questions they
keep coming in all right let me stay
focused the person that sent me this
question did not send me a name please
do send me a real name and a shipping
address and I will happily send you a
free three pack of irie genetics premium
seeds you never know what you may get it
may be something new it may be something
old it could be regular it could be
feminized it could be unreleased it
could be something that's been sold out
on the website that I discovered I had a
couple of hidden somewhere you never
know what you may get as a prize for
sending a question to the grow help tab
anyway send me your address because I do
owe you a pack of seeds if you sent this
message this one goes just like this it
says hey Ross to Jeff I got a pack of
fist bump good choice bro fist bump is a
great cross it says it came with a free
five pack of Tangy Ripper that is also a
great cross the Tangy Ripper is of
course Platinum Tangy the Platinum Tangy
female cross to a Jack the Ripper male
it makes a super orange candy flavored
buds a Big Pine Cone big donkey dick
buds that have some orange flavor with
like a lemon lime background sort of
that terpenoline dryer sheet hint to it
really uh really zesty flavored but
really nice head Buzz real social weed
real easy to grow flowers in my opinion
let me stay focused it says uh these
plants are in week six and it seems as
if they may finish super late all right
so you're in week six and it's looking
like they may finish super late uh most
of those plants do go about nine maybe
ten weeks maybe 72 days so you got a
ways to go I'm not sure what you
consider super late some of my stuff
some of the plants I grow for myself go
14 weeks so I'm not sure what some
people consider super late but you're
correct they may take you 72 days now
here's where it gets interesting and fun
here's where our question arises it says
since you are the creator of this
cultivar when do you think I should
start flushing these plants I don't want
to flush too early please give me some
tips so I can be successful now this is
the part of the podcast where things are
going to get very interesting a long
time ago I did a full episode about
flushing our plants I preached it we
should let me talk about what I mean by
flushing let's start there what I'm
referring to at this point in this this
episode throughout this episode when I
say flushing right now I'm talking about
usually uh 10 to 14 days before Harvest
I would preach to water our plants with
just water with no nutrients in an
attempt to clean out whatever the plants
are in if it's cocoa if it's soil
soilless mix let's get rid of the
excessive nutrients if we've been
feeding bottled nutrients let's wash all
that out of there so that the plant will
then begin to cannibalize and starve
itself so that there are no nutrients
left in that plant so that when we cut
it down we don't taste nutrients in that
plant that's what I used to preach it's
what a lot of Growers used to preach
that has been the idea the philosophy
the school of thought for many many
years now at this point in time I'm not
sure that if I agree or believe in the
idea of flushing our plants I've got
some notes Here I want to try to stick
to them of course I'm going to wave
freestyle off of that but let me start
now the notes say I'm still studying to
determine if flushing is real I'm not
even sure if I believe that that's real
my notes say you can flush the medium
you can starve the plant and it will
cannibalize itself but here's the
question what are you flushing out I
don't have the scientific or organic
chemistry background to really explain
this in a scientific way but hear me out
go on this journey with me let's just
say that you are going to eat me okay
nobody wants to eat me but just come
along with me for the ride I'm gonna
taste terrible we already know that but
let's just say you were gonna eat me if
you ate me right now do you think I
would taste any differently if you
poured if you made me drink 100 gallons
of water and piss a lot for a couple of
days and then eat me am I going to taste
any differently I don't think so because
all of the stuff that I've eaten over
the past however many years I've been
alive however many days however many
meals I've had that has created me that
has become skin blood teeth hair
eyeballs uh fat that I've burned off
which the plant is creating using energy
as well I've used that to it's the stuff
that I ate are the building blocks that
made me who I am and not who I am but
what I physically am it created my
physical being the minimal amount of
muscle that is here that came from the
things that I ate my skeletal structure
my blood everything that's all in here
this bag of meat that I am as a human
that's all from the food and the
nutrients that I have consumed it's all
here it's on me I got a little extra
right now uh because it was a good
winter I ate a whole lot for the winter
I'm burning that off in the summer but
my comparison is what are we flushing
out of these plants the stuff that we
the nitrogen phosphorus potassium
molybdenum so sulfur everything that
we've put into these plants the 16
Elements which they have absorbed have
turned into plant it is now a stem it is
now a vascular system within the plant
it is now branches it is leaves it is
buds it is chlorophyll it is trichomes
it has become all of these other things
it has become it has been metabolized
into plant so I'm not sure what we
really what I even thought we were
flushing out of that plant so I know
that this could become a controversial
episode this could be a topic that stirs
up a lot of controversy by the way get
the comments going down there in the
comment section please do type a long
paragraph and let me know what you think
about this am I crazy am I correct do
you have any real science do you have
some Bro Science do you have any
thoughts inputs information Corrections
comments concerns throw those right down
there down there in the YouTube comments
let's see what you guys think but I'm
really I don't know what we could
possibly be flushing out the plant takes
up food it turns it into buds it turns
it into leaves chlorophyll it turns it
into all all of the things that are
required to be a happy living plant it
creates exudates those exudates come out
in the soil the microbes interact with
those repeat process basically in a much
much more fancier form that was the
crude version but I don't know what we
could possibly be flushing out it's not
like the nutrients the the Cal Mag the
nitrogen bottle the phosphorus bottle
the bloom booster bottle that we fed the
plant it's not like we poured those into
a can and they're still just existing
they're Loose as bottled nutrients or
even maybe into a little baggie and we
got nitrogen and phosphorus molecules
just hanging out in the bag I don't
think that's the way that it works I
think all of that stuff has been however
you want to put it science terms uh Bro
Science terms it's been turned into
digested processed metabolized and it is
now plant it's not stuff you can flush
out I don't really think we can flush
out the nutrients and the things of the
plant you'd have to it's not like a
sponge we can't just rinse it out you
can't just clean it out I don't think it
works that way so maybe that's a comfort
controversial ramble maybe that's a
controversial idea but I don't know that
flushing really does anything so if you
don't believe me if you want to argue
with me if you want to back me up
support me I appreciate either one of
those I love free thinking human beings
that's a beautiful thing but I challenge
you in your garden grow two plants the
same the same everything the same clone
don't do it from seed get a clone have
two clones put them in the same type of
soil put them
um not in the middle of the light but
off center of the light both of them one
to the left one to the right to where
they're getting basically equal amount
of light feed them the exact same thing
lollipop then pop and twist them any way
that you normally would do the exact
same thing to both of these plants treat
them like they are twin brother twin
sisters love them both exactly the same
then here's where we're going to get
scientific let's do this extreme so that
we really see a difference in case there
is a difference let's make sure we don't
miss it let's flush one plant for 4 14
solid days let's excessively flush it
maybe in most cases I consider a flush a
lot of you have the wrong idea on how to
flush also let me touch on that a lot of
people think that a flush is by
completely over watering that plant
until all kinds of water is falling out
of the bottom and he got a big mess of
just runny drippy plant with mud coming
out of the bottom that is not a flush
that's an over water you can do that if
that's what you want to do but that's an
over water in my opinion an end of
harvest or an end to flowering flush a
pre-harvest flush is just water it until
you get somewhere between 10 and 30
percent runoff if you can pour in a
gallon of water and get a quarter gallon
of runoff out of your pot that would be
perfect that would be beautiful that's
an easy amount of water to dispose of to
manage it's not going to be a big deal
you don't need to go running 10 gallons
of water through a three gallon pot at
one time what you want to do is water it
till you get run off so you know you've
cleaned out that soil then let it dry
like you normally would however long it
normally takes then repeat that process
as May many times as possible over a
14-day process if you do flush that's
the way to do it if you do choose to
flush that's the way that I recommend to
do it so take one plant give it that 14
day flush process with just water you
can pH that water if you want don't pH
it if you don't want to that part
doesn't matter to me I've got a whole
other school of thought on that we pH so
that the plants will take up nutrients
we don't want them to take up nutrients
right if you don't pH it it's not going
to take up nutrients why bother
adjusting the pH at this time that is my
theory there they're going to get the
water that they need they won't get more
food if you are a flush person so do the
flush phase to one plant and don't flush
the other one mark them if you're going
to flush one and not flush the other one
put a little sticker or a little tag or
something on the one you are flushing
and the one you're not so that you don't
mix that up so once we've completed the
flowering phase and we have done this
flushing process on one and we have not
flushed the other what really matters to
me the most in my opinion this is my
personal opinion in I've grown a lot of
weed i've smoked a lot of weed I've been
around a little bit I've been in big
rooms little rooms I participated in a
lot of cultivating and a lot of
cultivation allegedly
um I think that drying and curing is
more important than flushing the drying
and curing phase is where we get rid of
that chlorophyll that's where the
chlorophyll gets removed from the
flowers and the dry and cure process oh
we seal it up the anaerobes begin to eat
the chlorophyll we open it up the
chlorophyll gas is released once again
that's the crude version but that drying
and curing process in my opinion is more
important than the flushing process you
can fix or completely ruin flowers in
the dry and cure process you can take a
crop that was grown okay and you can
make it pretty good by drying it
properly you can also take a crop that
was grown superbly perfectly beautifully
every attention paid to every detail all
the way up until Harvest and you can
ruin that [ __ ] in the first four to six
hours of the dry and cure process or
within the first week of the dry and
cure process drying and curing is super
important in my opinion more important
more so than the flushing phase so I'm
still curious I'm still skeptical if
flushing is even necessary is Flushing
real as flushing a myth is Flushing Bro
Science at this point I kind of want to
think that it's Bro Science I don't see
anything that supports it so with all of
that being said if you do choose to
flush your plants that does happen in
the final 10 to 14 days of your
flowering phase if you have a package of
your seed says to go 77 days start that
14 days before the 77th day let that
77th day finish then tomorrow go in
there and chop those plants down now I
do know that I said a lot of
controversial things here in just a
couple of quick minutes I look forward
to your questions Corrections comments
and concerns please do all of that down
there in the comment section in YouTube
if you're not on YouTube you can send me
an email the email address is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I truly do
look forward to all of the feedback
whether it's hate mail constructive
criticism whatever you've got to say I
look forward to the comments questions
Corrections concerns I have fun with all
of that stuff keep it coming all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
each and every one of you for listening
to another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast I will be back in a few
days with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy robot
Dave and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for me
thank you
[Music]
build yourself every time rush the Jeff
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign