so keep it locked the girl from your
heart podcast that's now
[Music]
welcome to the show podcast world I'm
your host Rasta Jeff this is episode 812
of the grow from your heart podcast I do
apologize for a short Hiatus YouTube did
have me on restriction I was not able to
upload a video for a week I am back
thank you for being patient thank you
for coming back to the show of course I
do have a fun show lined up for us in
this episode I'm going to give away free
irie genetics premium seeds hang out
we'll talk more about that of course
everybody that does join the patreon
campaign in the month of August will get
a coupon for a free pack of irie genetic
seeds from ire Direct that's right if
you join patreon at 25 or higher in the
month of August you will get a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from ire
direct all you have to do is pay for the
shipping at iridirect.com make sure you
check out patreon.com forward slash grow
from your heart for all of the details
on how to sign up for that all right I
don't need to ramble too much here at
the start of the show I do have a bunch
of great messages to read here on
today's podcast I did mentioned that we
were going to give away free seeds on
today's show if you go to my website
irygenetics.com there is a tab on the
top that says grow help if you click on
that grow help Tab and send me a great
question if I read your question here on
the podcast I will send you a free pack
of irie genetics premium seeds this
question of course came from the grow
help tab this one came from a person who
wants to be known as Michigan Mike big
up to Michigan Mike great to meet you
thank you for the great question Mike
please do send me your shipping address
uh the question goes a lot like this it
says hello Rasta Jeff hello Mike good to
meet you bro it says I am a grower here
in the Great Lakes State I've been
growing outside for about three years
now in this short season that we have
here I bet that's a struggle bro it goes
on it says I'm growing in fabric pots
but the problem is that the pots get
really nasty on the outside from year to
year yes I've seen that like a white
crusty build up that'll grow on there
that's from the salt nutrients I'm not
sure what you're using to grow but
sometimes they'll get algae on there and
of course if you're growing outside
you're going to get dirt and mud and all
kinds of junk and Gunk built up on the
outsides I completely understand bro
we're playing with dirt and organic
stuff and nutrients and all kinds of
[ __ ] here anything could go wrong
anything is possible but it does say is
there a way to clean these pots year
after year after the growing season ends
or should I buy new pots each and every
year I would like to reuse them each
year if possible that's probably the
most cost effective most eco-friendly
way we don't need to throw away a bunch
of stuff if we can clean it and reuse it
it goes on it says also that we've got a
second question here let me talk about
the first question then we will jump up
to the second question the first one
here
um I don't know how big your pots are
I'm not sure if you're using I grow
indoors I use a three a five maybe a
seven gallon pot indoors those aren't
too much to manage you could be using a
30 or even 100 maybe even a 250 gallon
fabric I I'm not sure what you've got
going on I've got a couple of
suggestions that work for me that maybe
you can modify for yourself here's what
I would do
if it were me and they were small pots I
would take them to the laundry mat and
throw them in the washer throw them in
the big commercial washer if they've got
it don't unless you're brave don't do
this in your washer at home where your
lady is going to come home if your wife
or girlfriend or maybe even your mama or
even worse your baby mama is going to
show up and find that you've got a bunch
of pots from the garden in the washing
machine maybe don't do that take them to
the laundromat and wash them in there so
they're not in your your ladies washer
where she's going to throw a fit and
then also rinse out run that washing
machine after one time when you're done
at the laundromat to get all your gunk
out of there for the next person but my
first option my first suggestion is take
them to the laundromat throw them in the
washer give them a good solid Hot Water
Rinse if you want to throw some organic
detergent in there of your choice maybe
do that I don't know that I would put
any sort of detergent in there just give
them a good jostle in that washer you
can even throw them in the dryer when
you're done if you really want to that's
my first idea idea number two throw them
in the back of the truck if they're big
and take them to the car wash go use
that car wash wash sprayer don't put any
soap in there just pay for the the power
hose I got at the car wash just use that
just spray them down with that uh put
them in the they got the thing you can
hold your car mats the floor mats clip
them into there spray the [ __ ] out of it
let it hang for a few minutes throw that
one on the ground uh maybe bring
somebody with you and make them carry
that one over and [ __ ] shop vac it
out if they can do that for you give you
a little backup maybe even shop back it
out first ah then hang the next one up
spray the [ __ ] out of it let them let
them dry in the sun after that or put
them in the back of the truck and drive
around they'll probably drive that way
put something heavy on them so you don't
lose any my next idea of course I'm just
coming up with [ __ ] to help you because
I would use the uh the washing machine
at the laundromat is what I would do or
the car wash
the other idea maybe you got a big farm
maybe you have your own space hit them
with the pressure washer bro uh lay them
out in the driveway lay them out in the
sun or out somewhere and just hit them
wow you guys that was lightning uh
thunder so loud I Heard it Through the
headphones through all the noise
canceling I apologize I'm not even gonna
cut that part out of the show I'm in
Southern Colorado we're getting beat
with hail and crazy storms all day that
was wild freaking lightning I apologize
for the shock and distraction uh that's
real life big shout out to the outdoor
growers in Colorado this year you guys
are working guys and gals are working
for your money let me get back on track
uh power wash your pots if you're out in
the yard if you got a big driveway maybe
an open space maybe go to a parking lot
I don't know what you can do but get the
power washer out there and just power
wash the [ __ ] out of those pots those
are three solid ideas that I think would
work for you everybody's got a washing
machine or a laundry mat near them most
people have a car wash near them and
some people uh that live near a Harbor
Freight probably have a power washer or
know somebody with a pressure washer and
they love to use those things you're
friends with pressure washers love to
just [ __ ] blast stuff with them so
they'll want to do it for you so um my
dude Michigan Mike those are the first
three recommendations for part one of
your question uh part two of the
question is a really good question that
I get asked a lot of the time so let's
jump into part two it says also are you
ever going to make Auto flower seeds
sometime in the future uh the answer to
that is a strong no I do not make
Autoflower seeds I am not interested
excited nor passionate about passionate
about Autoflower seeds so I feel like I
would not do a good job making
Autoflower seeds
there are plenty of people out there
making amazing Autoflower genetics that
are readily available I have mentioned
in the past that my friend Daz from
night owl and I were kind of collabing
and working on an Autoflower project
with a half his stuff half mine the F1
generation has been made and no blame no
finger pointing at anybody we both kind
of pushed it to the back burner and have
been working on other [ __ ] uh neither
one of us have put any energy into that
I'm not blaming anybody we're both busy
dudes with uh seed companies and wives
to live but that project it exists but
it has not moved forward in any way I'm
not super involved in the Autoflower
project because like I said it is not my
passion I like Photo period plants
eventually Daz and night allergenetics
will put out some irie crosses that have
some Autoflower that are Auto flowers
that have irie in there also my buddy
icon Loco are making autoflowers out of
some of my stuff I don't know if they'll
ever release it but
um if you do want the auto stay tuned
and check out Daz from Night Owl because
he eventually one day he will release
autoflowers that do have eye regenetics
in the lineage but not straight up eye
regenetic stuff I'm just not into
autoflowers sometimes I describe it as I
play music I'm a musician I could play
any kind of music you need played if the
band if a band called and said hey bro
our drummer I don't want to give a
drummer a problem but if he disappeared
if he got abducted by aliens because
that's rare and cool
um if you got abducted by aliens we'd
talk a lot about you so that's cool so
if you got abducted by aliens and they
said we need a drummer I feel like I
could probably fill in for most basic
gigs you know what I mean not like some
I probably shouldn't try to fill in for
Dream Theater or Meshuggah or some [ __ ]
but most basic [ __ ] I could do it but I
don't have a lot of passion to play in a
country band you know that just doesn't
do it for me reggae I gotcha Jamrock I
gotcha rock and roll let's do it country
music I could do it because it needs to
be done but it's not going to be it's
not gonna feel like real country because
I don't have a real country music feel
my autoflowers will just be me playing
country it'd just be really just doing
it for a paycheck and I'm not into that
girl from your heart breed with love
that's the way that I do it there's more
to this message I'm getting rambly and
nostalgic today it does go on
it wraps up with uh thank you for the
great podcast and for giving me so much
information and for the ideas that help
me grow bro thank you for the great
compliments thank you for the great
question thank you for the interaction
thank you for being part of the irie
Army it says keep up the great job that
you guys are doing bro big respect thank
you for noticing once again uh my buddy
Michigan Mike please do send me your
shipping address uh put a real name on
there Michigan mic isn't Gonna Fly for
me put a real name on there because the
lady at the post office uh she wears a
mask down underneath her nose she just
wears it over her mouth but she always
gives me a snide look when the names are
like Michigan Mike or like Big Mike
smokes weed or dabaholic 5000 she does
notice that stuff and I don't want any
problems all right let's keep the
momentum moving here on today's podcast
I've got another great question here in
front of me this one also did come from
the grow help tab on the irie genetics
website this one came from somebody who
we are going to call Crystal today day
Crystal thank you for the message it
says hello Rasta Jeff hello Crystal it
says I just wanted to say thank you very
much for bringing quality genetics at
affordable prices uh thank you for
noticing um I'm gonna ramble here for a
minute I think that seeds are overpriced
on a lot of websites in a lot of places
by a lot of breeders
um a lot of what was making seeds
expensive back in the day was the idea
of scarcity because the idea of the
legalization the illegalization of seeds
now cannabis is legal in a lot of places
we can produce our product we don't have
to worry about so many things without
all that fear and without the the legal
uh without the justice system involved I
don't think that this product should be
so expensive the price of cannabis has
gone down uh the cost of living has gone
up people don't necessarily need ganja
seeds that's like a secondary and
ancillary product that's like a bonus
you buy food you get all the groceries
you get the baby taken care of you get
the family taken care of the car or the
phone all that stuff maybe you buy some
some extra good groceries or something
but the the seeds are like at the bottom
of the list of [ __ ] that you've got to
buy so I try to keep them affordable
there's no need to charge a whole bunch
of money for uh seeds that I can make
I've got a lot of them I want to get
them out there I'd rather get the seeds
out there and get them grown and make a
few bucks than have a bunch of seeds in
a box and make a million dollars that
doesn't make any sense to me I told you
I was gonna ramble thank you for
noticing that my seeds are affordable I
want everybody to have access to high
quality seeds that seems very reasonable
and very fair to me I see no reason to
charge exorbitant prices all right let
me move forward it says
um uh being a medical patient it has
really helped me in many ways and I am
very grateful so they're talking about
the affordable seeds uh thank you for
noticing I started off as a medical
marijuana patient myself I started off
as a pot smoker became a medical
marijuana patient then I became the
manager at the only medical marijuana
dispensary in my city so I got to see a
lot of people's uh need for cannabis
their medical their recreational need I
sought to improve the quality of
people's lives so I do have a lot of
appreciation for getting these seeds out
to medical patients thank you for
noticing once again all right let me get
focused that seems to be a challenge
today why do they call dabs concentrates
when all you cannot do is concentrate
after you smoke I could do anything but
concentrate right now let's get back
into it it says is there any way to know
when certain varieties will be back in
stock on iredirect as I was told by a
good friend of mine that you're strained
the machine would be a great one to help
me and my nerve pain issues which I deal
with thank you once again for your time
and for everything you do best regards
from your new friend Crystal Crystal
thank you for the great question uh
there is a great way to stay up to date
and informed uh when new things will be
added to the website of course I do have
a newsletter if you go to my website
irygenetics.com probably where you sent
this email if you go to iregenetics.com
if you scroll down there's a little tab
that says stay tuned or stay up to date
or stay updated that is where you can
join the newsletter type in your email
address whenever I put out new stuff or
give out coupon codes I will send you a
free newsletter I try not to spam you I
try to send a newsletter about once a
month at the most you'll get it every
two weeks if I'm really doing something
cool or if I forgot something you'll get
a newsletter two weeks in a row but I
really try not to do that try not to
overload you I try to be respectful of
your inbox so go to iregenetics.com
maybe even on ireedirect.com I think
it's there go to the bottom type in your
email address hit enter you will join
the newsletter and I will add you to the
newsletter everybody that was on the
newsletter last month did get a coupon
code for 50 off and I redirect so make
sure you join that newsletter you never
know what kind of crazy deals I may
offer also another great way to stay
updated is to join the patreon at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart I did mention that everybody that
joins at 25 a month or higher for the
month of August will get a free pack of
seeds you will get a free pack of Jack
Tripper a 10 pack a retail regular
10-pack of Jack Tripper I'm not doing
anything weird they're not strange packs
not small packs it's the normal
packaging you're getting a pack that
most people would pay for on the website
is a patreon contributor for 25 you will
get a coupon code for that free pack of
Jack Tripper seeds of course you got to
pay for the shipping but not only do I
give out that free pack of seeds but
also I will give out coupon codes on
patreon occasionally randomly to people
on patreon it does depend on the tier
level sometimes it's just just five or
ten percent off sometimes it's free
shipping sometimes you get the first
heads up and the first notice that there
is new stuff coming to the website so
the patreon members can get first dibs
since they do contribute to funding the
website so patreon is your second bet on
getting updates and notifications of new
drops the third option is to come hang
out with us on Discord I will put a link
to the Discord server and the notes we
hang out on Discord I hang out on
Discord and I talk about like I'm
packaging up this brand new [ __ ] I'm
gonna put it on the website Friday like
I talk about that in real time you can
ask questions about it you can hang out
Discord is a great place to stay updated
and the Nerds on Discord I call them
nerds they know who they are I love them
they're my own they're my favorite nerds
the army of irie Army of nerds they're
great those nerds out there will keep
you updated when I have new stuff coming
so those are three options I like to
give you damn that lightning was awesome
as Thunder I guess I heard but it is
awesome it's really banging out there
those are three great options on how how
you can stay updated for new drops and
of course I will put more of the machine
out in the very near future and I hope
to get some feedback on how that does
help with your nerve pain my new friend
Crystal once again thank you for the
great message and please do send me your
address because I do owe you a free pack
of irie genetics premium seed all right
podcast world that is enough emails for
today's episode I'm not sure if YouTube
is going to let me load this video so
this is just kind of a test run here
we're going to see what's going on this
may be a quick episode thank you for
hanging out if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
my email address is growfromyourheart
hotmail.com of course if you have those
grow questions please do send those to
the grow help tab you know I'll be back
in a week with fresh new content I want
to give a big shout out to my friend can
Amanda and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[ __ ]
[Music]
pick up the stuff every time
foreign
[Music]