so keep it locked the girl from your
heart podcast that's now
[Music]
all right now here we go welcome to the
show podcast world I'm your host Rasta
Jeff this is episode 813 of the grow
from your heart podcast hangout because
in this episode we are going to give
away free seeds before we talk about the
free seeds I do want to say thank you to
all of the people who have been asking
where is the podcast I've been on a
restriction on YouTube for a couple of
weeks so I've not been able to post new
episodes I do apologize YouTube did not
like some of my older contents they put
me on punishment I was on a little time
out but I am back and I am excited to be
here back with you guys thank you to
everybody who checked in on me also big
thanks to everybody who has been asking
about I redirect I redirect is currently
under construction we're working on a
few things doing some inventory doing
some updates working on some stuff
behind the scenes doing some changes
have no fear I will have updates very
soon while I redirect is down I do
recommend checking out the other vendors
on iregenetics.com of course I highly
recommend seeds here now.com mom also I
want to send an update to everybody who
contributed 25 on in the month of August
on patreon everybody who contributed 25
on patreon in the month of August was
promised a free pack of seeds if you did
not get your free pack of seeds please
do send me an email iridirect went down
right in the middle of that free seed
giveaway so I understand some people may
have been screwed out of a pack of seeds
if that did happen to you please send me
a message and I assure you I will get
you the seeds that you are owed also I
do want to continue this party uh let's
do another pack of seeds for the month
of September anybody who contributes 25
or more to patreon in the month of
September we'll get a free pack of White
Chapel seeds of course White Chapel is a
Golden Goat female pollinated by a Jack
the Ripper male that's a great strain
lots of crazy terpenoline Terps a lot of
lemon lime spicy tropical fruit kind of
Terps and an amazing crazy headbuzz and
of course big fat Harvest so check it
out that is White Chapel that is
available to everybody who contributes
25 or more in the month of September on
patreon that was a mouthful I feel like
I got past most of the business I've got
one more important thing to cover then
we're going to jump into the email
portion of today's podcast the last
order of business to cover on today's
podcast before we get to these emails is
to let you know that I will not do an
episode next week I'm going to take a
small mini vacation I'll be out of town
for several days I don't want to cram
another episode in before I take off
from my little trip I want to just enjoy
my week enjoy my time off not stress
over a podcast I think you guys will be
just fine growing ganja without me if
you missed the podcast that much go
listen to some of the older episodes
there are 800 and something episodes to
listen to go catch up on some older
content but for all the people that
check on me when I don't put out a show
I'm going to skip an episode on purpose
I will not be here next week I'm going
to go on an adventure on a little trip
I'm honestly gonna go see fish in Denver
for four nights my favorite band is fish
they're doing four nights in Denver I'm
gonna check out and go have some good
times go regroup and refresh a little
bit then I'll be back in a week after
that with the content that you are used
to so I think that is all of the
business where do I want to go now let's
talk about some really cool [ __ ] that's
been happening in my garden recently I
popped a few new seeds that's right I
moved some plants out time to move some
new [ __ ] in so I popped some new seeds I
have got some of my own crosses going
and I've got crosses from some other
people going I wanted to run some of my
seeds so that I can open up my breeding
projects and add some of my lines to the
mix and I also wanted to introduce brand
new stuff so what would we talk about
let's tell you that I put some Double
Dragon seeds in my bedroom their
seedlings they're about this tall at
this point if you're only listening I
think that's six or eight inches tall
they're little tiny babies but they're
looking good there's some double dragon
babies in there uh what else could I
tell you about there are big mountain
fudge cake babies in there those both
came from my lineup I think those are
two great strains then also there is
some banana God version 2 from my buddy
Masonic smoker big shout out to mace
also big shout out to my buddy Billy
bunk smoking for giving me the pack uh
also shout out to my buddy Terps there
was a conspiracy involved there in
getting me that pack of banana God uh
Terps and Billy bong conspired said that
I should breed with the banana God Terps
told Billy to buy me the pack Billy got
the pack from mace Billy handed me the
pack in an event with a big smile on his
face and I knew what was supposed to
happen from there have no fear you guys
the banana God has been germinated it is
growing strong and it looks really good
there should be some great winners in
that pack I don't know if we'll find a
male or a female hopefully there's a
breeding candidate in there so we can do
some breeding with the banana in the
future also in this same run of seeds
are some Jamaican Lamb's bread f4s that
are growing but they don't look as
vigorous as the rest of the batch I need
to let them go a little longer we'll see
if they come around I've recently fed
them a little more heavily I've also
increased the DLI in that room uh to get
them a little bit more light we can see
if we could turn those plants up just a
little bit but so far the Jamaican
Lamb's bread those are kind of older
seeds that were kind of smaller and
those seeds aren't looking as good as
the rest of the room but those are the
strains I'm going to tell you about in
that room right now there's the uh the
Double Dragon there's big mountain fudge
cake there's banana God and there's the
Jamaican Lamb's bread there might also
be something else Secret in that room
because I don't share everything I gotta
have some Secrets but I like to let you
know kind of what's going on in that
grow room also an update on that grow
room here's something I really wanted to
talk about recently I purchased an
iPhone app that is called Photon let me
make sure that's really what it's called
because I just wrote down Photon off of
memory I want to make sure that I'm
giving you the correct info yes it is
Photon
p-h-o-t-o-n-e it is the photon app in my
iPhone so the photon app is basically a
par meter or a DLI meter you download
the app the application is free then you
will need to buy an add-on for the app
depending on what kind of light you have
you have to buy an add-on for that spec
Trump not every Spectrum comes for free
but it's like somewhere between three
and five bucks I don't remember what I
paid it didn't hurt at all I just paid a
couple of bucks to buy a download to
have the appropriate Spectrum for the
lights I'm running in my room so I
downloaded the the appropriate LED
Spectrum then it teaches you how to make
a little light diffuser for your phone
you basically just wrap a piece of paper
around your phone and then you can use
your phone as a light meter you hold the
light right at canopy level and it will
tell you your DLI then you can also use
the internet or books or your common
knowledge to dial in your lights to the
appropriate DLI I did notice once I got
that DLI dialed in on my seedlings they
quit stretching they started bushing out
and they look much better so I highly
recommend the photon app for your iPhone
it was free other than the download it
was like somewhere between four and five
dollars for the download I just double
tap on the side of your phone you'll
download it it installs right away it's
pretty quick it only took a minute or
two the diffuser only took a few seconds
to make the uh taping it together was
the hardest part because I'm clumsy and
then you just get in there and read the
settings I hold the phone at canopy
level I say oh it's too low and then I
go up to the LED light and I crank up
the knob and the LED light until it gets
to the reading which I want it on my
meter it was super simple
um I started off at 13 and over the past
few days I've slowly adjusted to 20. uh
the plants are adjusting very well with
the light once the plants get a little
bit bigger I'll turn it to 25 when they
get bigger I'll go to 30. uh we'll just
slowly increase and then by the end of
flower I should be somewhere between 45
and 55 DLI is what I expect I will hit
by the end of flower but I really do see
an improved performance in my seedlings
since I've got that DLI dialed in so if
you are experiencing things like
stretchy laggy seeds or if the seeds are
just growing too tall and tipping over
maybe just maybe probably most likely
you need more light and the way to
determine that would be some sort of a
light meter light meters are very
expensive they're not cheap at all the
photon app is working very well with my
iPhone and it was like I keep saying it
was about four or five dollars if you
were burning the tops of your plants if
your plants are looking yellow and
crispy or if they're getting bleached
and turning white up at the Top If the
top leaves are getting crispy but
nothing else is you may be giving those
plants too much light which doesn't seem
possible because they go outside in the
sun right but our grow lights are
indoors they're just a few feet away
from the plants so they're really
punishing that plant all day long so
maybe just maybe perhaps you were giving
your plant too much light and a light
meter would definitely be an easy way to
tell you if those plants are getting too
much light another thing I recommend
when you play with a light meter write
it down I've got an app in my phone it's
just basically the notes app I've got a
note in my phone all about that grow
room everything I do in that grow room
gets documented in that note so I know
that on this day I fed it this much food
on this day I defoliated on this day I
increased the DLI from 13 to 14 on the
next day increased it from 14 to 17.
document all of the things that you do
in that room especially when you were
adjusting the light that way if you see
him starting to act weird you can look
back and say four days ago I changed
this light and now things are going
weird take as many notes as you possibly
can all right I feel like I've been
rambling on for a few minutes and we
have not gotten to everybody's favorite
portion of the podcast which of course
is the grow help portion of the podcast
this is where I read your grow questions
and I do my best to give you some useful
advice on how to improve your grow now I
did say earlier in the podcast that I'm
going to give away free seeds that's
right I'm going to give away free seeds
and the way to win free seeds is to send
me a grow question if you go to my
website iregenetics.com there is a tab
that says grow help if you click on that
grow help tab you send me a question if
I read that question here on the podcast
I will send you a free pack of irie
genetics premium seeds today's question
came from my friend pig poop what's up
brother I hope all is well shout out to
my buddy pig poop uh Pig poop's a good
dude he's a long time irie Army member
and irie genetics supporter he's also my
friend we hang out on Discord we take
dabs together we talk about life pig
poop is just one really cool dude so
shout out to my buddy pig poop Piggy's
question goes a lot like this it says
Rasta Jeff I recently heard a theory
that the sex of our plants is determined
during the germination process and that
cooler temperatures will give out more
females I've always believed that the
seed sex has been genetically coated at
the time of the breeding as the seeds
are developing what are your thoughts on
this and then it goes on it says can we
germinate in cooler temperatures to get
more females or even just have our
breeding tints cooler to get more female
seeds that is a very good question I've
heard a lot of different opinions on
this I've seen people say that
germinating in lower humidity gives you
more males or germinating and lower
humidity will give you more females I've
heard the opposite I've heard about
higher temperatures I've heard about
lower temperatures however all kinds I
have heard all kinds of gimmicks and
ideas and tricks and Bro Science behind
this here is my two cents and this is
just my understanding based on my
experience if you've got a different
idea a different approach different Bro
Science different white papers than me
hook me up let me know I am very open to
ideas and feedback argue about it in the
comments right down below or send me an
email at growfromyourheart hotmail.com I
love feedback I love the conversation
keep it going but here is my two cents
and here is why I think that I strongly
believe that the pollen determines the
sex of the seed now why do I say that
what is my supporting evidence every
statement should have some supporting
statements right why do I believe that
because I make feminized seeds when I
make feminized seeds what am I making
what is the main ingredient feminized
pollen the pollen I'm starting with is a
female that is the feminized ingredient
so that makes me think that the pollen
is the one deciding the sex of the plant
it could be before the pollen something
before the pollen could be determining
that but from what I see what I am
making Femme seeds by creating female
pollen by creating pollen from a plant
with only female chromosomes so I feel
like if I can make female pollen and put
that on a female plant any female plant
I put that on I'm going to create female
seeds right so in my mind in my theory
that says to me that the pollen is doing
the selection the pollen contains that
female chromosome or the male chromosome
the pollen is the one carrying the uh
the deciding factor the gender reveal
comes with the pollen now like I said I
don't have any real science behind that
my science is that I make Femme seeds
I'm making Femme pollen I'm not doing
anything to the female plants that
receive the pollen I am manipulating the
pollen donor to give me female pollen so
in my mind it's the pollen if you have
some sort of different varying opinion I
am very open to hearing that I'd love to
be educated if there's a different
education on this like I said get at it
in the comments or send me an email grow
from your heart at hotmail.com so now
let me make another supporting statement
since I talked about breeding with
Femmes if I breed with another plant
that is not feminized it is spitting out
pollen right and that pollen will hit
plants and it will make males and
females right most of the time you get
50 50. so that that says that that
pollen is making male and female plants
to me and that the feminized pollen is
not so again that just supports my
statement so I really do believe that
the pollen is the one carrying the
chromosome and like I said a moment ago
the pollen is the one with the big
gender reveal that's the one that lets
you know if you're a boy or a girl when
it hits that stamen climbs down into the
ovule and it goes boy or girl and it
starts making that in there uh fills up
your back with the seed and then you get
to grow and find out later but I've been
rambling on long enough about that one
my dude pig poop I really do believe
that it is the pollen and like I said
I'm very open to arguments conversation
and education pig poop I do owe you
another free pack of seeds my dude I've
got your address check the mail in just
a couple of days all right let's keep
moving I've got a lot of great questions
here in in front of me this one came
from somebody who wants to be called
giant grasses big shout out to Giant
grasses giant grasses please send me
your shipping address with a real name
because you did win a free pack of irie
genetics premium seeds this question
goes a lot like this it says yo Ross to
Jeff how would you go about reversing an
outdoor plant since things become to
bloom slower Outdoors I'm just wondering
about the timing of my silver
thiosulfate sprays the plants have been
stretching Outdoors the bud should be
showing before too long thank you for
your help this is a very good question
uh they're asking about making feminized
seeds in an outdoor garden and an
outdoor run they said how would you go
about reversing an outdoor plant my
quick answer is I wouldn't I just simply
wouldn't do that reversed plants don't
make enough pollen in my opinion to
really make it worth reversing an
outdoor plant that's a project I would
rather keep indoors because Outdoors a
lot of that pollen is just going to blow
away in the wind and I need as much of
that feminized reversed pollen as I can
get because the plants don't make as
much as a regular male plant would make
when it dumps we're manipulating a plant
uh depending on how much you spray it
it's plant dependent but you're not
going to make as much pollen in my
experience so I would not do it but let
me try to help you out and tell you if
you insist this is how it would probably
work the best for you when we are
applying silver thiosulfate to a plant
for a reversal we need to start applying
that solution about 10 days before that
plant goes into flower so the only way
to really determine that is to grow that
plant last year and mark down the date
when you started seeing it show signs of
flour and then about 10 days before that
then maybe 10 days before that start
spraying that plant because if you're
seeing signs of flour you're about 10 to
14 maybe 15 days in that tells you two
weeks ago I went into flour which means
10 days before that is when you need to
spray gray so I would document what you
did last year hopefully you wrote it
down when did the plant go into flower
last year or write down when you noticed
the plant was showing signs of flour
this year here in Colorado it's fairly
easy for us a lot of the plants will
start showing signs of pre-flower just
going into flour around August 15th
which means flowering day one is usually
August 1st in some plants in some
cultivars it takes till the end of
August to show a little bit of
pre-flower but many of them most of them
they start August 15th you can really
see that pre-flower coming on that tells
me that August 1st was probably the day
they really started to flower which
means 10 days before that was when I
needed to apply my silver thiosulfate
solution for the first time you're gonna
need to hit it day negative 10 is what
we're going to call that and then day
one and then also 3 6 9 12 15 18 21 and
if you're Outdoors I'd probably go day
24 also but the timing of that is going
to be weird because the problem outdoor
doors is because now your male is
spitting pollen
um around day 32 it would have been
nicer to have the females a little
further along in the flower to receive
more pollen they're not going to have
the ideal amount of pistols to receive
that pollen they will impregnate they
will make seeds but you could have made
more if the timing was better that's why
I recommend doing this indoors first of
all that pollen is going to get away and
then second of all the timing isn't
going to be as good as it could have if
you did it indoors making rag seeds
Outdoors isn't as critical because you
dump so much more pollen Outdoors that
male plant's ready to go he's just
dumping right away the female plant cell
every granule of pollen will make a seed
it's hard to make enough pollen unless
you're reversing multiple plants reverse
every for every one male you would do do
two reversals that way you get enough
pollen out there to make it worth it so
where was I got off on a nice ramble
there
um I Wouldn't Do It Outdoors but if you
do uh spray it day negative 10 I know if
you didn't flower it out last last year
you don't know when that date will be
maybe ask around maybe ask local ganja
Farmers around there say hey when do we
go into flower here use your best
judgment and adjust from what they did
what they say whenever day one they say
is Go that negative 10 spray then and
then start your routine every third day
for about 24 days then you're gonna have
the problem of the pollen flying away
then we're gonna have the problem of a
bird is going to land on that plant and
[ __ ] Shake all of your pollen off too
early you're gonna pollinate all the
girls too early
um I would keep the feminized breeding
projects indoors unless you insist on
doing this if you've got a greenhouse
environment where you control the
airflow and control things that may be
more ideal but what I would almost
recommend is flowering the reversal
indoors collecting the pollen and then
putting it on those plants Outdoors if
that's really what you insist on doing
anyway my friend giant grasses I really
do hope I helped you out here this was a
fun question I love talking about
reversals and Femme seeds and please do
send me your shipping address because I
owe you a free pack of irie genetics
premium seeds when you send me your
shipping address again please send me a
real address with a real name so that I
don't have to send seeds to somebody
like Wild Bill's ganja Farm or something
like that I don't like that send me a
real name with the real address I'll
keep it secret you'll be safe I ship
discreetly Let's help each other out all
right let's keep the momentum moving
because I do have another great question
here in front of me this one came from
our friend dankasaurus what's up
dankasaurus hope you're doing well what
do you call dankasaurus's dog
dankosaurus Rex right that's good all
right this is a general grow question
that did come from the ire genetics
website on the grow help tab which means
my buddy dankasaurus you do win a free
pack of irie genetics premium seeds send
me your address again with the real name
and I'll get you a free pack of seeds in
the mail ASAP this question goes just
like this it goes yo what's up roster
Jeff what's up dankasaurus I hope you're
well my bro it says I'm a long time
podcast listener and a Discord lurker
bro I've seen you on there that's why I
know your name says first off I'd like
to say thank you for all of the great
genetics you have created and all of the
great content which you have put out
dude you are so welcome thank you for
the great compliments that sort of stuff
keeps me moving thank you thank you
thank you a lot it goes on it says uh
you truly are a teacher when it comes to
cannabis I appreciate that then it says
now to my question I have several
Keepers from a few different breeders
some have it all bag of Peel smell
potency and some are just good for their
medicinal values that that matters also
it says one of my favorites is your Dark
Hollow that is such a great strain if
you like that funky garlicky mashed
potatoey bar trash can funky sort of
terp that is a great one it says I am
not a breeder and not even really a
pollen chucker but I would like to cross
the Dark Hollow into some of the other
Keepers just to see how they will turn
out I love it when I inspire people with
a good strain it inspires them to want
to Chuck that pollen that's how you know
sometimes people are like how do I pick
a plant to breed with this is how you
just [ __ ] know you're like this plant
right here bro it talks to you it says
something to you like a crazy person
that's how you know to breed with that
one follow that intuition you guys that
always works it goes on it says I want
to
um I really like to cross the Dark
Hollow uh if you were to look for a Dark
Hollow male to breed with what
attributes would you look for I know
what to look for in a female but judging
males is a whole different deal I know
that's probably just going to be a trial
and error kind of deal but I figure the
best way to start would be to ask the
man himself this is a very good question
I really like this one it says anyway my
man thanks for your time and all you do
for the community I look forward to any
advice you may be able to give thanks in
advance my bro I've got a lot of male
selection advice first of all I've done
a full podcast on selecting male plants
it's like a 40 minute episode just on
selecting males I would give that quick
listen or maybe a 45 minute listen
unless you can time travel put it on 2x
make it a 27 minute listen right anyway
I am rambling but I would recommend
checking out the mail selection podcast
I'm not trying to shine you on I'm not
trying to blow you off but that podcast
has been done and it was very good with
a lot of great info now let's focus here
specifically on the breeding with Dark
Hollow because that is a great plant to
breed with and to work with it's going
to pass along a lot of great traits Dark
Hollow is a GMO female GMO is known to
get fairly tall kind of stretchy a lot
of long internode spacing and a lot of
big giant leaves with a lot of dark
colors and the Aromas and flavors are so
disgustingly delicious on the GMO I love
it but it does get kind of tall and it's
super potent it does get kind of tall
and it needs a lot of attention when you
grow it so I crossed that one to my
Arise My King Solomon cut of a rise that
is a Golden Goat to daybreaker my arise
plant my King Solomon plant is very well
known as a male breeding plant he adds
Vigor he adds structure he adds potency
he adds Aroma he adds flavor he adds
everything you're missing from any cross
you could ever need so I crossed the GMO
to the arise that made Dark Hollow some
of those phenotypes are going to be kind
of taller if you're going to breed with
it I would find one that is not super
tall I'd find one of the shorter a wider
branching phenotypes so you can pass on
that shorter more branchy phenotype that
more branchy trait to the progeny
because that tall one is going to make
even taller plants so one of the first
traits I would look for is a shorter
branchier plant with closer internodal
spacing compared to the tall stretchier
plants the tall stretchy one is going to
be a way more GMO dominant the shorter
squatty one is going to be a rise GMO
cross it'll have some Golden Goat traits
in there it will breed very beautifully
also look for the one with the really
big dark colored leaves there will be
leaves on some phenotypes that are as
big as my hand that'll turn like plum
purple colors use that phenotype for
breeding and I would also give it a nice
stem rub and look for the one that kind
of smells like early in flour it should
smell like like baby [ __ ] and vomit and
bar trash can and as it gets older it
should turn into like uh garlic and fuel
garlic and jet fuel garlic and gas kind
of is the aroma that I would look for
for a breeding a potential breeding male
from the Dark Hollow progeny now once
you've selected that Dark Hollow mail
what I would recommend is to breed it to
multiple females and try to find female
plants that are as far different in
traits like in structure Aroma flavor
Leaf size and shape even color of the
plant read it to stuff as far away from
those traits as you can that way when we
grow out those seeds we can see what
they did together and then grow out
multiple seeds of each cross like if you
did what else do you have in the room
did you tell me what other strains no
you didn't tell me what else you have
but if you've got Dark Hollow to ice
cream cake and Dark Hollow to Cherry
Paloma and Dark Hollow 2 Big Mountain
fudge cake
grow all those out and see what traits
from the Dark Hollow crossed carried
into each cross and see how much ice
cream cake you get in this cross see
which Dark Hollow ice cream cake traits
sort of mixed and then see what else did
I say cherry Paloma see what Dark Hollow
and Cherry Paloma did I think somebody
may have bred that already that's going
to be fire but see how much of that
garlic comes out how much of that cherry
or how much of that orange Turf comes
out and then the other one that I forgot
what I even [ __ ] said over here uh
see what traits and flavors come out
then we can see what the boy is doing to
different crosses we can see uh if the
short structure comes through on all of
these that means he's passing that if
some of them are really tall and really
short that means that he's not passing a
lot of his height trait to the progeny
if they all smell like mashed potatoes
he's passing that trait this way we can
learn what traits he gives to his mix
and then we can see if he mixes well
with others if he plays well with others
then we can continue breeding with that
once we kind of see what it does it's
like finding out uh it's like like
tasting the first batch of the mix by
tasting the first half of the batter
does it taste like chocolate vanilla
cinnamon if it tastes like chocolate
don't breed it to more chocolate breed
it to vanilla if it tastes like vanilla
breed it to Cinnamon you know what I
mean find out what you're working with
then learn where to go from there with
your breeding bro I got super rambling
on this question I hope I helped you out
I would look for the short one with the
tighter node spacing uh the giant dark
leaves the colorful leaves the bar trash
can smell that puke accurate gross kind
of Aroma one that dumps a lot of pollen
and if it makes trichomes that is the
one to work with all right my dude
dankasaurus I do want to thank you once
again for the great question also make
sure you send me your shipping address
so I can get you a free pack of seeds
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls if I
did not read your question on this
episode please do not feel discouraged I
have got a mountain of emails in front
of me that I do plan on getting on the
show eventually it just takes time and
there are always new messages coming so
be patient keep sending your grow
questions to me at that grow help tab at
iregenetics.com and if I do read your
question on the show you will win a free
pack of irie genetics premium seeds
alright everybody that is all I've got
for you for this episode my throat is
burning out I think it's time to start
wrapping up I'll be back next week with
fresh new content please make sure you
check out my patreon campaign at
patreon.com forward slash grow from your
heart once again everybody who does
contribute 25 or more in the month of
September on patreon we'll receive a
free pack of White Chapel premium seeds
again that White Chapel is a Golden Goat
female pollinated by a Jack the Ripper
male that's an amazing cross with a
super cool name make sure you check out
patreon if you have any other questions
send me an email the email address is
grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy anything else you could
possibly need is on my website
irygenetics.com you guys my voice is
burning out it's been a great time I'm
glad to be back I'll see you in about
I'll see you in two weeks a minute ago I
said I'll see you in a week correction
cross that out I'll be back in two weeks
I'm gonna go have a good time hey if you
see me at the fish concerts come up and
give me a hug give me a high five give
me a fist bump don't be the guy that
emails me on Tuesday and says hey bro I
saw you at the fish shows I did not come
say hi bro come say hi come shake my
hand you never know a lot of times I've
got seed packs in my pocket I might not
be able to get the mylar packs into the
concert but on the parking lot outside
wherever there's a good chance I've got
seeds in my pocket come say hi all right
the show is officially over at this
point ladies and gentlemen I'll see you
next week with fresh new content I want
to give a big shout out to my buddy
robot Dave and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
oh
[Music]
build yourself every time Rusty Jeff
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign