the girl from your heart podcast that's
now
[Music]
all right podcast World welcome to
episode 815 of the grow from your heart
podcast in this episode we're going to
talk about preparing for our outdoor
Harvest before we do that I want to give
a big shout out to my friends at
Attitude Seed Bank USA make sure you
check out the Attitude Seed Bank USA for
a fresh drop of irie genetics premium
seeds all right now let's talk about
preparing for our outdoor Harvest many
people have been working all summer long
most of the fall on their outdoor
Gardens and it is quickly approaching
Harvest Time this is a very critical
part of the growing process many people
Overlook the preparations and
expectations and needs of harvest time
so let's do a little quick talk here and
get everybody prepared to harvest their
outdoor Garden all right now when it
comes to harvesting our outdoor plants
the first thing I would think about is
where are we going to put this Harvest
we need a safe secure location to put
all of our plants when we chop them down
we can't just stack them up we can't
just pile them up in a corner they need
to hang they need airflow they need
space they need a controlled environment
do you have that area prepared do you
have something in mind start cleaning
that room out now because life gets
chaotic around Harvest time and you're
going to find yourself overwhelmed and
overloaded and the last thing you want
is to be scrambling for a dry and cure
space while you're chopping down the
plants let's get prepared we still have
a little bit of time before Harvest time
comes up let's start thinking about this
stuff now set yourself up for Success at
this point we've got time to start
looking for the tools and supplies in
space which is needed for Harvest maybe
even you need a few friends we'll talk
about that later on but let's start
preparing now before these plants come
down like I said a moment ago let's set
ourselves up for Success you have spent
weeks those plants have been outside
vegging for a couple a few weeks maybe
even vegged indoors for a couple of
weeks if you do big plants you vegged
them indoors you vegged them Outdoors
they flowered for eight to ten weeks
outside you took major care of them
every day you were out there watering
them defoliating keeping the bugs off of
them now at the Harvest Time this is
where we could really screw up all of
the love and care that we put into these
plants so let's be prepared the first
thing we need is that dry and cure space
do you have somewhere that when you cut
down the plants do you have somewhere
you can hang these plants safely you
need a room that I prefer a dark room if
there's a little bit of light in there
that is okay but I definitely prefer a
dark room for hanging the plants do you
have a room that is secure is this room
that you're thinking about secure is it
not accessible to Children is the main
important thing then the second thing is
is it accessible to thieves do people
know your ganja is in there is it locked
up safe and secure do you have cameras
do you have maybe a little alarm system
in case somebody gets in there but
definitely have a safe and secure place
for these plants we don't need the kids
getting in there we don't need thieves
getting in there we definitely don't
want animals to get in there if it's
your own domestic pets if it's wild
animals outside they're gonna love the
smell of that ganja and they may try to
get to it and they may try to eat it up
a lot of animals love the smell of
cannabis rats bunnies uh anything like
that they will get to your plants if
it's available and they will try to eat
it so you need plenty of space a secure
place with little white we also need
some airflow in this room are we getting
some airflow in there a room that uh let
me back up and this isn't even on my
notes this just came to my mind because
this is very important we want a room
that doesn't have a funky stanky musty
Aroma because if you hang these plants
in a funky stanky room instead of
getting good ganja smelling buds they
are going to absorb that funky musty
basement Aroma into the plants so think
about that when you are now that we're
preparing a dry and cure space maybe we
can clean out a room and open up some
windows and get some air in there and
get that old basement Funk smell out of
there or that old barn smell or that old
work shed smell whatever it is let's
freshen it up a little bit let's get
some airflow happening now so we can
freshen up the air in that room get rid
of some of that old nasty stale Aroma
whatever it may be because that will end
up into your buds instead of your buds
smelling like Grateful Dog or Morning
Dew or strawberry Starburst they're
going to smell like grandma's basement
and nobody wants to smoke that [ __ ] so
think about the uh the smell the aroma
that is already existing in your
anticipated dry space then the next
thing I wanted to talk about was airflow
we can start cleaning that funky air out
now if we get some airflow going you're
going to want air flow in the grow in
the dry space I would put a couple of
fans in there one up higher one down
lower maybe even one on the ground
stirring the uh the ground air around we
don't want the wind blowing directly on
the plants drying them out we want the
wind moving it around so that we don't
get any micro climates any Hot Pockets
any wet pockets in the room let's just
move and stir all of that air also if
you've got some sort of an exhaust fan
in that room to vent out that humidity I
out of the top Corner out of the top
middle of that room that would be ideal
also maybe consider a carbon filter in
that room if you've got neighbors
thieves something like that may smell
your ganja crop as you're drying it in
that room you're exhausting that nice
ganja scented air I would put a carbon
filter on there another thing to think
about is maybe a dehumidifier in your
dry and cure space when I've got plants
hanging in a commercial room I honestly
put a humidifier in one corner a
dehumidifier in the other corner I set
them both at 55 percent and I let them
fight all day so that room stays at 55
percent constantly unless we're opening
and closing the doors that does happen
but we with the moisture of the plants
in there the humidifier and the
dehumidifier battling we can get pretty
close to the parameters which we expect
in that room at all times also of course
I'm running a commercial facility when
I'm talking about this there's an air
conditioner in the commercial facility
we keep that at the desired temperature
about 60 65 degrees maybe between 60 and
70. I understand a lot of you are
drawing in a basement in your extra grow
room in your garage in the tool shed
we're going to try to meet certain
parameters it would be ideal to get
within five degrees or five percent
humidity but I understand that's not
always possible we may have to be
flexible and work with the 10 degree 10
threshold here that will work for you
let's try to stay right around 55 65 60
maybe the ideal temperature and humidity
a lot of people are going to have input
and different thoughts on that it's all
going to work just adjust as you find
necessary these are just guidelines for
you to start with 50 humidity sixty
percent humidity those will both work
you're just going to take a little bit
longer a little bit shorter time to dry
so think about the aroma in that room
think about the airflow in that room
like I said we don't want fans blowing
directly onto the plants all day would
you want fans blowing on you maybe some
of you weirdos do but you don't want it
blowing directly on you all day just
stir that air around don't dry the buds
out with the fan let them dry slowly but
have that fan moving the air around if
you need to rotate the plants so that
one isn't always getting beat up by the
fan at all times feel free to rotate
those plants so something I didn't even
talk about how are you going to hang
these plants in the room let's just say
that you've chosen a space in which to
hang your plants if you're using your
grow tent that's ideal also a lot of
people just cut down the plants and then
hang them right up in the grow tent but
how are you going to hang them what are
you going to use to suspend your plants
from the ceiling the rafters how is it
going to work one thing I recommend I
suggest that happens a lot and this is
great even if you're doing this and
you're grow tip this will work very well
buy a thing of clothes hangers just the
cheap plastic triangle clothes hangers
the little hook on the top you don't
need anything expensive anything fancy
if you're a broke ass get the wire ones
if you can even find the wire hangers
anymore but get some coat hangers and
then when you cut your plant pay
attention to the way that you're cutting
the plant if you watch the way the
cannabis plant grows it makes a stock
that comes up then it makes a branch
that comes off to the side than just
above that a branch that comes off to
the side if you cut the plant down
properly think about come from the top
of the plant work your way down a few
inches maybe I'm going to say about 10
12 inches I think that's probably about
10 or 12 inches then that's a good
section to cut if you find one of the
intersections where the main stock comes
off and there's a branch coming up this
way cut right below that you can use
that Branch as the hanger flip that
upside down put that on your coat hanger
and now you can hang that hanger
wherever you want depending on how big
your buds are how dense and fat and
beefy your branches and buds have gotten
you can probably fit several of those
branches per coat hanger don't waste too
much space and just do one bud per
hanger do at least three that's my
opinion so continue chopping your plants
start at the top take that main top off
cut it put it on the coat hanger have
the hanger hang it up on something so
you can access right then go down a
little further cut in sections that you
feel comfortable with and hang those up
and hang those up in that cool secure
place that dark place with plenty of
airflow and a controlled temperature and
humidity temperature humidity and
airflow are super important in the
drying and curing process
if you don't have enough airflow if you
get too much humidity you can definitely
ruin your buds by creating Bud rot it is
still potentially an issue to ruin the
inside of those buds with the wrong
environment so get that room dialed in
get the temperature down 60 or lower get
that temperature right let's get an
exhaust fan in there let's get some air
moving and let's try to get the water
out of those plants as slowly and
quickly as possible I know that sounds
redundant but as a grower that's what
you're trying to do you want it to dry
as slowly and quickly as possible you'll
figure this out when you get there the
longer the drying process takes the
better the weed will taste but the
longer it takes the longer it [ __ ]
takes which means there's more
opportunity for issues and problems to
arise once you pass a certain moisture
level don't even worry about it if
they're hanging you've got airflow you
will be fine if the first few days is
when you do really need to pay attention
and make sure that you've got plenty of
airflow and that your humidity is under
control now if we do have a drying and
curing space figured out a place where
we can hang the these plants let's
review what we need we need a dark room
that is secure with airflow and about 50
to 60 percent uh 55 to 65 percent uh
humidity and temperature in that room
like I said a moment ago in my
commercial environment I have a
dehumidifier set at 55 humidity I have a
humidifier set at 55 humidity I've got
an air conditioner set at 60 degrees at
the other end of the room I've got an
era a duck sucking air out so that all
of my stale warm air that Rose to the
top with all that humidity in there is
just being pulled right from the room in
a commercial environment I don't put
that carbon filter on there in a private
grow put that carbon filter on there so
everybody doesn't smell it but that is
the main setup we've got the
environmental controls happening in
there that also put a hygrometer in
there so that you can look and see what
is happening in that room at all times
uh something like you could just get the
little cheap one from the the local
hardware store that just sits on the
table and you can look at it manually or
you can get a pulse Pro and you can look
at it on your phone you've got so many
options for that but be aware of what's
happening in there so that you can
adjust it if you need to all right those
are the first things I would think about
that is the dry and cure space what
about some workspace how are you going
to manage chopping this down do you have
some space where you can cut these
plants down carry them to another table
then do some work with them or do you
need to do it all out in the field where
the plants are be prepared for that I
don't know your situation I know many
people so let's just hypothetically say
I've got a greenhouse out in the middle
of nowhere and that Greenhouse doesn't
have like a lot of work space for a
bunch of big plants once I cut them down
I've got one table that whole table is
covered by one plant maybe I can take
the plant carry it to that one table
break it down into smaller pieces then
put it on my coat hangers there and then
move it to my dry and cure space maybe
I'll take the whole plant to my dry and
cure space hang it all up at once and
then break it into smaller pieces it
just depends on your environment your
space what you've got the thing I'm
trying to get at is be prepared many
people Overlook the importance of the
workspace they think about I've got this
room where you going to do the work
another thing you want to think about is
supplies now is the time to get supplies
let's not wait until Harvest day to say
oh yeah I needed things what are we
going to need when it comes to harvest
time the main thing you're going to need
is gloves I go through lots of pairs of
gloves harvesting I put on thicker
gloves while I'm chopping down the
plants I wear thicker gloves when it
comes to shucking but when it actually
comes to the trimming the manicuring the
de-leafing part of the trim work I will
go through a lot of gloves another thing
I should add that I may have forgotten
to talk about that just came to my head
while I'm thinking about harvesting is a
few days before you harvest this could
happen uh seven five three days maybe
even the day before Harvest if you can
pull off a bunch of those big leaves
anything with a long pedial sticking off
if you and your trim crew can go and
just pull off all of those leaves that
will save you time when it comes to
harvesting all of those leaves just dry
up around the plant they become crusty
they become crispy it becomes a big mess
it's extra [ __ ] to manage when it does
come time to Manicure if you can pull
pull those off while the plant is alive
they come off much more easily it's just
quicker just go in and just pull all
those leaves off you don't even need
scissors for it just take off the leaves
you could pop off with your fingers that
will also speed up your drying time if
you're in a place where you are drying
too quickly maybe don't do that but if
you're in a place where you want to kind
of speed up the dry get those leaves out
of there that gets more moisture out of
the room immediately that's going to fix
the humidity and the drying cure space
and also that saves you less [ __ ] that
you have to clean up and Trim in the
future so get those leaves out of there
maybe a good start now let's see what
else are we going to need gloves I said
we need a lot of gloves if you're going
to trim by yourself get your size gloves
if you've got friends coming over be
considerate maybe buy an extra large a
large medium and a small box if most of
the time you won't use the small gloves
the small rubber gloves are super tiny
most people don't wear those check
around look and see what your crew wears
and just make sure to have gloves on
deck for everybody and the crew that is
super polite of you and then nobody's
gonna get their fingers all sticky and
then also you're not going to get their
skin in your weed and then if somebody
gets an eye itch or a booger itch they
could just take off their glove and
handle it they don't have to go wash
their hands just to itch their eye when
you're trimming this is not on my notes
this is just from experience don't rub
your eyes or do try it one time and then
you'll never do it again but my advice
is don't rub your eyes when you're
trimming not at all not a little bit not
with the corner of your finger not with
the back of your hand just don't do it
your whole hands are going to be sticky
you're covered in resin you got
trichomes and chlorophyll all over your
hands as soon as that finger hits your
eye your body's gonna go you [ __ ] up
about 20 seconds later you're just going
to be in the bathroom going oh man it
burns bro and you're just going to be
rubbing your eye and your hands are
sticky because you've been trimming and
your eye is sticky and then when you
move your hand away from your eye your
[ __ ] eyelashes are going to stick to
your fingers
just don't do it dude that's my advice
don't touch your eyes when you're
trimming uh use gloves if you're high or
nose itches take off the gloves take
care of your eye your nose do whatever
you got to do then apply a fresh glove
don't be a cheap ass and keeper using
gloves they're not that expensive put on
a new glove all right other things you
might need scissors have at least one
pair of scissors on deck for every
person that you plan to trim with you
everybody needs at least one pair but
after a few minutes of trimming those
scissors are going to get sticky as [ __ ]
A lot of times what we'll do we'll just
have a bucket of dirty scissors a bucket
of clean scissors when yours get dirty
throw them into that dirty pile grab a
clean pair of scissors somebody in your
crew will take it upon themselves maybe
it's you there's always a person in this
group somebody will say I'm sick of
looking at the dirty scissors they'll
grab the dirty scissors and they will
start cleaning all of those scissors
what is customary
as they take all that scissor hash that
comes off the scissors and they put it
in the middle of the table and that is
now smoke for the table if anybody in
the room wants to get stoned smoke that
scissor hash bro that [ __ ] is good stuff
that is Mike's favorite [ __ ] to smoke I
think Mike really loves scissor hash so
uh when you're trimming throw those
dirty scissors into a little pile then
somebody in the crew and maybe you who
knows there's always somebody that likes
to do that the one person with OCD will
grab all those scissors clean them up
take all that resin off there roll it up
into a ball maybe they'll even be polite
enough to pack it into a bowl and get
that going around for everybody but
rotate scissors out have enough scissors
for everybody and then have maybe a
backup pair for everybody also I know
that adds up quite quickly but then also
have something on Deck to clean those
other scissors I like to use a small
razor blade just to scrape all the [ __ ]
off of it and then I soak them in
rubbing alcohol like 91 ISO if you have
some of the Dark Crystal glass cleaner
that also works very well to clean
scissors also a little bit of coconut
oil will get that extra residue off of
your skin off your fingers if you got
some up here on your arms or whatever a
little bit of coconut oil will help that
rub off so have gloves have scissors for
everybody have a way to clean those
scissors have a backup pair of scissors
for everybody if possible another thing
if you can get them have the little
springs for your scissors have backups
of those because you have no idea until
you get down to it you have no idea how
many pairs of those scissors the spring
is going to fly out the spring is going
to get stuck if you can get the scissors
they come with the backup spring I
recommend purchasing those another thing
you will need is some sort of trash
receptacle a trash bag a trash can
something to put leaves and trim and
sticks and waste into another thing to
think about is where are all of your
sticks and stems and empty pots and all
that [ __ ] where's that going to go when
you're done are you going to recycle
upcycle your soil are you doing a living
soil where you can just keep going did
you do Cocoa did you do uh what else is
the other option uh maybe you did some
hydroton Maybe maybe you did rockwool
cubes what are you going to do with your
waste I don't know where your grow is
taking place are you in a legal state
are you in a Prohibition state if you're
in a legal State it's much easier to
dispose of your waste but still be
careful because if somebody Drives By
and sees a bunch of five gallon pots
outside in your bag of Fox Farms left
over soil and a bunch of sticks they
know you just harvested they know
there's a crop in the house if it's law
enforcement they want to check on your
crop and see how much you got if it's
thieves they want to come get your crop
if it's the homies they want to come
smoke your crop be discreet with your
trash whether it's illegal or illegal
place in most locations once your trash
goes to your curb that is now fair game
law enforcement does not need any sort
of Warrant to go through your trash
think about that when you're putting
your trash at the curb maybe just maybe
you need to find a safer more discreet
place to get rid of your trash hopefully
maybe you're living in a rural area and
you can just throw it all in the compost
bin that would be ideal but I do
understand that's not option for
everybody I want you guys all to be
successful and I want you all to be
careful so that trash can be used as
evidence just as much as your harvested
product so keep that in mind wherever
you are the other thing I mentioned is
some hangers or some wire of some sort
and some little screw hooks let me talk
about what I'm talking about we need to
hang these plants when we cut them down
the first thing I talked about was the
space how are you going to hang these if
you use your grow tent it's already got
those bars in the ceiling that are
holding it up and the bars that come to
hold up the uh the carbon filter and the
light you can just hang the coat hangers
from there if you don't have that what
you're gonna do something I can
recommend is get those eye hooks that
screw into the wall and of course don't
do this in like the living room do this
in the work shed do this in the garage
do this in the basement do this
somewhere like that use little eye hooks
screw them into the wall then walk
across the room and at the same height
put another eye hook in the wall over
there then use a piece of you can use a
lot of different things I've seen
fishing line used I've seen twine used
make sure it is very strong because
you're going to hang more than you
anticipate but just run some sort of a
line from one end of the room and string
up as many lines as you need and hang
those plants on there but let's start
thinking about it now before you're
cutting down plants and then you go oh
[ __ ] where am I going to hang these
because that's what a lot of people do
that's what a lot of Stoners do that's
what a lot of Growers do let's be ahead
of the curve let's set ourselves up for
success and be ready for this upcoming
Harvest now I've covered the main
supplies that we need for a successful
Harvest let's talk about a couple of
small details that will make this
Harvest better comfortable chairs are
very important you're going to be at
this for several hours I don't know how
many plants you've got I don't know how
well you did but hopefully you're going
to be trimming for several days I heard
somebody today say that they will be
trimming until Christmas they're going
to chop down around Halloween and they
will be trimming until Christmas imagine
how much ganja that is imagine how many
hours of sitting in a chair with
scissors in your hand looking down at
some buds imagine how much time that is
think about a comfortable chair I don't
know what you consider a comfy chair I'm
sitting up in a higher bar stool type
chair right now it makes me sit with a
straighter back and kind of gives me
forced better posture that would be a
good chart for me to trim in of course
then I'm going to get tired and want to
lean back but consider what you like as
a comfortable chair also be considerate
to your trim crew if you invite people
over don't give them a five gallon
bucket to sit on don't expect them to
trim your weed while they sit on a crate
give them a comfortable chair give them
a pillow to put on that chair if they
need to think about the people you've
got coming some of you young guys can
trim all [ __ ] night with no problems
my back gets sore right about here my
nickel gets sore right about here I've
got to think about how to keep that neck
and back in shape I recommend taking a
lot of breaks I know that sounds like
laziness but you got to get up you gotta
stretch that any other job you're
required to take a break every two hours
take a break for every two hours you
don't want a repetitive stress injury so
make sure you set a timer set on put on
a podcast or something at the end of
every podcast make sure you in the work
crew stand up stretch your wrists do a
couple of different wrists stretches
wiggle your arms put your hands above
your head get some some Wiggles going on
hold your hands low get some Wiggles get
some blood flow into places the blood
hasn't been in a little while uh maybe
go outside look at the sunshine go look
at a tree go see what outside looks like
if you've been inside go outside or if
you've been outside go inside change
environments get a different view for a
little while uh maybe go outside with
all your friends and smoke a joint get
away from the trim table take the crew
out there and smoke a joint for 10
minutes and don't talk about trimming
don't talk about the plants that will
buy you a lot of time I know it sounds
silly but when you're going to be
trimming for up until Christmas good
scheduled breaks and a good disciplined
break in a routine will definitely help
you out so make sure your trim crew is
comfortable make sure you guys take good
breaks and stay motivated stay fun how
can we do that if you are the guy the
gal the person in charge of hiring a
trim crew it is also good Customs to
provide drinks and snacks you also got
to pay the trim crew some way I don't
know how you're going to do that that's
up to you if they're friends they'll
come do it for free if you want to
compensate them you can give them weed
you can give them money give them
edibles but definitely feed them while
they're they're working for you keep in
mind a lot of us are vegan vegetarian
have some dietary restrictions maybe ask
people hey I'm trying to buy some snacks
what what's your favorite munchie food
for while you're trimming and that way
you can get people some good snacks some
good drinks make sure you have good
water around take care of your people
what else can we talk about podcasts and
or music have some sort of entertainment
going if it's just you trimming by
yourself put on whatever you like I you
can [ __ ] judge on your own decide for
yourself listen to what you enjoy but if
you've got a crew like if Mike was here
I wouldn't play Fish all night I may
play some fish but if Mike's here
trimming he's not going to listen to
seven hours of fish uh if Mike is here
we're not going to listen to Legion of
skanks podcast back to back like I would
if I was by myself be considerate of
your trim crew keep them motivated make
them like you if I brought my makeover
and we trimmed for six hours and I
played fish and Sublime all day he will
not come back tomorrow we got to
consider think about your trim crew they
do not have to come trim for you so make
sure you keep them happy fed and
comfortable make it a fun experience a
lot of people say the phrase trim jail
and maybe I'm a stickler but that
bothers me there are people in jail that
are dealing with some [ __ ] if you're
trimming you're not in jail bro you're
sitting at the table with your friends
listening to Sublime eating [ __ ]
snacks possibly on Discord chatting it
up with us so I don't really like it
when you guys call it trim jail because
there are people in jail that don't get
to do [ __ ] all day they're dealing with
some [ __ ] and we're sitting at the table
listening to Sublime drinking kombucha
and expensive bottled water and a nice
air-conditioned environment with all of
our friends and nothing to worry about
so trim jail does sound kind of weird
alright ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I think that wraps
up my outdoor Harvest preparations for
this year I hope I helped set you up for
success I hope you have a great Amazing
Outdoor Harvest this year I hope it is
everything that you asked for everything
that you hoped for I hope you supply
yourself as long as you need it if not I
hope you made a bunch of notes and you
know exactly what to improve next year I
did not do the free seed giveaway on
this episode I'm going to do a modified
giveaway here's how you can win free
seeds by listening to this episode join
my Discord server once you join my
Discord server send me a direct message
and tell me why you should win a free
pack of seeds and I'll pick somebody out
of those messages to send a free pack of
seeds if you need a link to the Discord
server make sure you check out the show
notes there will be a link in the show
notes and in the video description join
us on Discord I look forward to seeing
you there alright that is all I've got
for this episode I am going to take next
week off I'm going to take a little
vacation hopefully I'll talk about that
more on the episode when I come back but
I'm not going to record next week so
when the next episode does not come out
have no fear I am having a really good
time I'm off at a really fun event we'll
talk more about that on a future episode
but don't worry if I don't put out an
episode on Saturday I'll probably put
one out the Saturday after that unless
my voice is fried and I have way too
much fun but relax I'm just having a
good time big thanks to all the people
that check on me when I don't put out a
show that means a lot to me I am
rambling at this point if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns please do send me an email my
email address is growfromyourheart
hotmail.com if you have cultivation
questions I recommend you go to my
website
irygenetics.com at iregenetics.com there
is a grow help tab click on that help
tab we'll ask you a few questions send
me your grow question if I read your
grow question here on this podcast you
win a free pack of irie genetics premium
seeds also make sure you check out the
patreon campaign at patreon.com forward
slash grow from your heart guys that is
all I've got for this episode I'll be
back in two weeks with fresh new content
I want to give a giant shout out to my
buddy purple skunk and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
build yourself every time Rusty Jeff
hold up