if you keep refreshing the website to
see if I've updated I redirect go ahead
and click subscribe the grow from your
heart podcast Starts
Now Rustin Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode 86
of the grow from your heart podcast I've
got a fun show lined up for us in this
episode I'm going to talk a little bit
about a vacation I recently took then
we're going to talk a little bit about
adjusting our grow room for the upcoming
winter conditions if you live in the
United States we are now shifting from
that warm summer season to the cooler
fall season so it is time to make some
adjustments in the grow we'll talk more
about that in just a minute I I want to
start the show by talking about a little
vacation that I got to take last week I
got to go to Las Vegas and see a
festival called skankfest Let Me Explain
skankfest is not exactly what it sounds
like but it is close to what it sounds
like I am a big fan of a podcast called
the Legion of skanks Legion of skanks is
one of my favorite podcasts it is hosted
by LS J Gomez big J oakerson and Dave
Smith a lot of times they have a lot of
great comedians as guests on our podcast
most of the time it's uh East Coast
comic
those guys aren't as gentle and fluffy
as some of the other guys I like the
rude crass humor that these guys put out
so the Legion of skanks threw a festival
called skankfest this was their seventh
skankfest they've thrown this was the
second one that happened in Las Vegas
and when I saw the lineup I knew that I
had to go to this party skankfest was
amazing I could start listing comedians
that were there and I'm going to miss a
bunch but some of the comedians that
were there that you may have heard of
are LS J Gomez uh big J oakerson Dave
Smith
Mark Norman Joe D Roa Joe list and then
there were old school comedians like
somebody you may have heard of there was
a lady named Roseanne Bar that's right
Roseanne from TV Fame uh she was there
she did some stand-up comedy she was a
guest on the Legion of skanks live
podcast it was amazing to see Roseanne
there uh Dr Drew was there Dr Drew did
the Dr Drew after dark podcast also you
guys there was a wrestling match there
was a mixed martial arts match during
skankfest during the day during that
match the competitors were blindfolded
and wearing shock collars and the
controllers of these shock collars were
given to random members of the audience
and then the guys were put into a boxing
ring and they were fighting a sort of
Royal Rumble style about seven on seven
a bunch of dudes just fighting until
people gave up uh they were in the ring
blindfolded wearing shot collars doing a
mixed martial arts match it was every
bit as chaotic and entertaining as it
does sound but for that event Dr Drew
Pinsky did sing the national anthem we
all might not know that Dr Drew is an
amazing opera singer but Dr Drew the guy
from L line the guy that teaches us
about problems with our pecker and all
kinds of weird sexual talk that guy is
an amazing opera singer so he opened the
ellismania fights with the national
anthem and he did an amazing job so big
shout out to our buddy Dr Drew also Ron
White was there I'm not sure if you guys
know Ron White or tater salad uh he was
not on the schedule but I was in a room
watching comedy was waiting for another
comedian to come on and the host said
ladies and gentlemen
we have a special surprise for you Ron
White and Ron White came out and did
several minutes of Amazing comedy had me
laughing is at my ass off that was a
great time also Sam Talent was there Sam
Talent is an amazing upand cominging
comic um I think he's super popular in
the Colorado region he's becoming more
and more popular uh day by day he's been
on Joe Rogan so he's definitely
expanding but Sam Talent was there he
was amazing uh Tim Dylan was there you
guys I could list comedians all weekend
there were so many people there Jeremiah
Watkins um who who else was there that I
was just trying to think of Josh Potter
was there brenn and sha and Brian Ken
were there it was a great time everybody
would perform on these little theater
stages and then after they performed
they were just hanging out in the
hallways with us so I was rubbing elbows
and fist bumping and smoking joints
allegedly with a lot of the uh my
favorite comedians so skankfest was an
amazing time uh there were seven
different stages and there was comedy or
a podcast happening on every stage at
every time and then they built that
boxing ring outside they did some mixed
martial arts there were a couple other
things that happened out there there was
a booty cheek slapping contest you guys
know they do the uh the face slap
competitions on ESPN now they stand
there and they take turns slapping each
other in the face they had some pretty
girls do butt cheek slap competitions
skankfest was everything you can imagine
it would be so I think I rambled on
enough about skankfest I could go on all
weekend talking about the party about
the festival it was amazing uh make sure
you check out if you watch uh Legion of
skanks podcast make sure you check out
the recap episodes that they're posting
up on YouTube look for all the footage
it was an amazing time and if you're a
legion of skanks fan and you were not at
skankfest this year I look forward to
hanging out with you next year because I
will definitely be there also if we made
friends at skankfest this year bro
thanks for hanging out every person that
I met and hung out with if it was a f
minute interaction or all weekend long
thank you guys I had an amazing time at
skankfest with my new friends and old
friends that I found there speaking of
old friends you guys may have seen the
photo I did run into our friend d as
from night owl and his lovely partner in
crime Miss Maddie uh shout out to those
two beautiful folks for hanging out with
me I did post a picture of myself and
Dazz from night ow and it got a lot of
response and yes all of the assumptions
you made from that photo are completely
accurate look for Night Owl iy genetics
projects in the future but it will be a
while the most I can say right now is
that the f1s have been made and in the
future there will be some stuff from
night owl and iy genetics all right I
think that's all I've got to talk about
skankfest uh let me talk a little bit
more about comedy festivals because when
I came back from skankfest I had tickets
to see Bert kryer big J oakerson and Dan
Soder at Red Rocks that was an amazing
show uh it was weird to think about
comedians playing at a 10,000 seat venue
uh but man they got a party going they
bring DJ cipa sounds who's famous in New
York uh cipa sounds gets the party going
uh he plays a bunch of great music um he
played good music for the crowd it's a
bunch of white people music for a bunch
of white people but DJ cipa sounds got
us dancing it was a good time and then
Dan Soder came out did about 10 minutes
of Amazing comedy his set was awesome
big J oerson came out you could tell
that big J was still fried from
skankfest we both had skankfest voice
and energy it was like we both needed a
nap but it was well worth it then after
big J crushed the stage for a few
minutes Bert ker came out and did an
amazing Set uh he did a full comedy show
and then told the machine story and in
the machine story he interrupted himself
to tell other stories and other jokes uh
Bert was lighting joints and passing
them to the crowd it was a really good
time so um you guys if you can go see
Live Comedy I highly recommend it that's
some of my favorite [ __ ] to do I want to
see you at skankfest next year and if
you're going to any upcoming comedy
shows message me maybe we can smoke out
front if you're at any shows in Colorado
it's probably the Paramount Theater or
uh Comedy Works message me maybe we'll
get to catch up and smoke all right I
feel like I covered all of the stuff
about skankfest I want to look at my
notes saw crer oh it says here I got
sick Bro um I did not do any crazy drugs
I didn't do anything weird in Las Vegas
but I came back sick as [ __ ] I had a
major sinus infection I had a chest
congestion problem so if I do sound a
little shitty here on the podcast I
apologize I can hear it in my nose just
a little bit uh but I'm not going to let
that slow me down it took me uh several
days to get my [ __ ] back in Action here
so uh this is going to be a short
podcast not a lot of details and we're
not going to talk too much about highly
detailed growing because my voice may
not be well and I don't want to waste a
good show with a crappy voice all right
that's enough about
skankfest um yeah shouts out shout outs
to everybody that I hung out with if it
was a comedian if it was a civilian an
old friend a new friend uh Daz from
Mesto Maddie from misto all the crew
from Comedy Works when I showed up so I
got off the plane I went to my hotel
dropped off my bags put on some clean
clothes uh and then I thought I'm going
to go out to Fremont Street and see
what's going on and I was on Fremont
Street for 20 minutes walking and I
heard several dudes yell rosta Jeff and
I was like well this is weird because
I'm not in Denver in Denver that would
be normal I was in Las Vegas and people
are screaming my name and I looked back
and it's the crew from Comedy Works so
big shout out to my boys from Comedy
Works they were all there waiting to
hang out I just kind of buddied up with
them and partnered up with those guys
for Thursday evening and they made it a
really good time so shout out to all the
friends at skankfest new friends old
friends uh friends that remember me and
friends that have no idea they met me
you guys skankfest is great uh there are
people there that are sober and there
people there that are the exact opposite
and everything in between Good Times all
right that is enough talking about
skankfest there's one more thing I want
to cover before we talk about winter
adjustments in our grow space in this
podcast I been giving away free seeds
that's right I have a website iry
genetics.com if you go to my website on
the top there's a row of tabs one of
those says grow help or questions if you
click on that tab you were given the
opportunity to ask me a grow question
something about your garden something
about your plants maybe at some about
consumption or cannabis culture get
creative send me a question if I read
your question here on the podcast that
means that you will win a free pack of
iy genetics premium seeds at this time I
do feel like I have sent prizes to
everybody who has won seeds on the
podcast but I am not perfect I make
mistakes [ __ ] slips through the cracks
if you have sent me a message and I read
your grow question here on the podcast
and you feel like I owe you a pack of
seeds and you have not gotten them
please send me a reminder email put the
word prizes in the subject line send me
an email say hey rosta Jeff you owe me
seeds let me know what episode I read
your message in and then send me a real
name and a shipping address when you
send me a shipping address please send
me a real name I say this a lot I don't
want to send seeds to Bong smoker 5000 I
don't like sending seeds to uh Ganja
Farmer 420 Stoner Dave 56 I try to avoid
all of that stuff let's put a real name
on The Box the USPS is getting curious I
do not want any of those packages to get
opened because there's a weird name on
them so let's help each other out also
your mailman knows your real name
they're delivering mail to your real
name Bob Smith Bob Smith every day and
then you get one package it says ganab
Bob 5000 they know there's something
weird in that package so let's just put
a real name on there put a real safe
address on there and I do look forward
to getting your prizes out if you've
gotten prizes now is the time to start
posting those photos of the progress if
you're growing any I genetic strains I
would appreciate it if you join us on
the Discord server and in the Discord
server there's a tab for every strain
that I have put out most of the strains
are on there some of them are under the
new and unreleased tab but if you scroll
through the tabs there's a blueberry
butcher Big Mountain fudge cake uh it
goes alphabetically I'm trying to keep
up but if you go down and go
alphabetically almost every strain is
listed on the Discord you can click on
that strain you can look at the current
photos and grow reports that are up
there and I highly encourage you to post
your grow progress in those tabs that
does a lot of things for us then new
Growers that want to grow that strain
they can go there and have a
conversation with people growing that
plant they can say hey I'm growing Big
Mountain fudge cake let's go to the
Discord and look and they can see all
the previous grows that people are doing
they can talk about which phenotypes
they got how long they took uh what
anomalies they saw if the plant needed
any extra feeding or attention that
should all be right there in the Discord
so I invite you and encourage you to
come join us on the Discord server also
people who post impressive photos on the
Discord end up with free seeds because I
want more impressive photos so join us
on the Discord post those grow report
photos and maybe just maybe I will send
you more free seeds all right now let's
talk about the important part of this
podcast let's talk about adjusting our
grow room from the summer conditions to
the upcoming winter conditions I am in
Colorado for the past 3 months it has
been 90° in the next week it is going to
shift from 90° to about 65° days very
quickly here that means I'm need to make
adjustments in my grow space how am I
going to compensate for the drop in
temperatures the first thing I'm going
to do is I'm going to remove my air
conditioner I don't need the air
conditioner in that grow space right now
it is already cold enough so the air
conditioner is coming out to replace
that air conditioner I'm going to hang
up a 1,000 watt high-press sodium lamp
and that is going to keep my grow space
warm a lot of people say bro you're a
dinosaur that's old technology yes I
agree but here in Colorado last year we
got about negative 15 -7° and that is
freaking cold having that HPS lamp in my
room will help keep the room warm when
it gets that cold and also it's adding
more light I could put a heater in there
but all the heater is going to do is
make more heat I can put a light in
there use the light to generate heat use
the heat to heat the room and I'm
getting more light so that is my
strategy I took out the air conditioner
and I have added one big light to create
some heat in that grow room if it
doesn't get warm enough guess what I'll
add another light in there because a
heater in my opinion is a great idea but
that's just heat if I can get two things
out of making heat why not make light
increase the amount of light in the room
that's what the plants want anyway so
I'm going to use those grow lights to
keep the grow room warm the next thing I
did was I took out the dehumidifier I
don't need that dehumidifier right now
it's not super hot outside I'm not
getting super high uh humid conditions
in the room instead since it is cold and
dry outside I am now adding a humidifier
so I have swapped my cold source for a
heat source and now I have swapped my
dehue for a hue those are the big major
shifts that I have done in that room now
I don't know how you have your ducting
setup but if you are in the right
environment in the right place maybe you
can turn your ducting around and bring
in some of that cool air and cool that
hot room if you've got a hot room so
these are just a couple of basic ideas
that I think about when winter starts
coming let's turn off that air
conditioner let's hang up another light
let's get rid of the dehumidifier and
add hum a humidifier I don't know your
grow room and I don't know your
situation but let's think about ways we
can optimize that grow room for the
seasons another thing to think about is
are your plants on the floor in your
grow space think about it this way that
floor if you've got a grow room in a
basement if you've got a grow room in a
garage a room that's not insulated how
cold is that floor getting can you take
off your shoes and socks and stand on
that floor comfortably if you can't the
plants cannot either that is like having
their feet or their balls sitting on a
cold floor and then we're going to add
water to that pot now we got cold wet
feet eaten balls on a cold flooor those
plants are not going to be happy my
advice is to lift those plants up off
the ground some way either build a
little table build a tray or if you've
just got a few plants a very easy method
is to buy more pots of the same size and
flip them upside down if you got a three
gallon pot get another 3 gallon pot flip
it upside down and put your plant right
on top of that now your plant is up off
of the ground and actually a little bit
closer to the light which may be a good
thing for you so think about those plant
roots are they cold are they going to
get real cold when you water and another
thing to consider is how cold is the
water that you are feeding these plants
my water pipes run uh along the outside
of my house so when it's cold outside
the water coming out is naturally
freaking cold I like to run that water
fill up my containers whether it's a
trash can some buckets or a reservoir
whatever you're using fill that up and
then I put it in the grow room under the
grow lights for several hours to warm up
that way when I water it that water is
not super cold I would not recommend
feeding water colder than 69 or 70° to
our plants that will have detrimental
effects to the plants so let's think
about the ways that we can utilize and
optimize our grow room for this seasonal
change another thing we can think about
is what are you doing with the heat from
your grow space if the grow space is
warm enough and you need to get rid of
some of that heat are you ducting that
that heat into a living space within the
house don't send the heat right out the
house outside out the attic outside
through a window or something it's cold
we need that heat you can utilize that
heat you paid for it uh however if the
light generated the heat if the heater
generated the heat you're paying for it
via electricity so let's put that heat
into the house somewhere shoot it into a
bedroom shoot it into the bathroom if
that's what you got to do let's warm up
some part of the house uh maybe you're
growing mushrooms in another room shoot
that heat into the mushroom room or
maybe shoot that excess heat into your
veg area but let's not shoot heat out of
the house while it's [ __ ] cold in the
winter season another thing to keep in
mind is when are you running these
lights in the summer my flower room
comes on at night time because I don't
want to compete with the sunshine I know
it's easier to keep my grow room cool at
night because the sun's not up I don't
need the grow lights and the sun
creating heat so when the Sun goes down
that's when my grow room comes on in the
summer are you going to switch those
hours in the winter so that the lights
are on during the day and then you get
that cold at night so you can get it
extra cold in the grow space how are you
going to utilize the change in the
seasons to make your grow room ideal
also excuse me for clearing my throat
there not even going to edit we're going
to keep moving cuz I'm on a flow another
thing to think about is daylight savings
time is coming up I don't know if we're
even still going to do that in America
is that still a thing but I know that
it's coming you spring forward and you
fall back it is just about time to fall
back are you going to set your timers on
daylight savings time now or do you plan
to wait until daylight savings time
comes and then adjust your timers or are
you just going to forget about Daylight
Savings Time altogether in your grow and
let it ride and just be whatever time it
is in there and let that rock that is
something to think about now because all
of these things are approaching rapidly
the season are going to change quickly
especially here in Colorado the further
east you go the more quickly things are
changing I've Got Friends on the East
Coast that are already talking about
it's getting cold everybody's chopping
down their outdoor plants maybe that's
something else we should talk about
really quickly have you chopped down
your outdoor plants are you ready are
you prepared get out there and get those
going because it's going to get cold
it's going to get Frosty and your
outdoor plants are going to be screwed
very soon unless you've got some sort of
warmth or shelter for them all right you
guys I think that covers the uh season
switch that I wanted to talk about I got
to talk about skankfest we got to talk
about switching our rooms for the grow
season so friends and foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to a quick
and short episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast I'll get my voice and my
health back in Action we'll do a solid
show for next week I'll be back in about
a week with fresh new content thank you
for listening make sure you check out
the patreon campaign at
patreon.com fromy yourheart if you guys
have any grow questions make sure you
send those grow questions to the growel
tab on iry genetics.com make sure you
check out the patreon campaign at
patreon.com forg grow fromy your heart
and anything else if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from yourheart
at
hotmail.com that is all I've got for you
for this episode like I said a moment
ago I'll be back next week with fresh
new content I want to give a big shout
out to my friend never ever even and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ] big up yourself every time
R
Jeff
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah
tell to take another DB grab your pie
and and I go about the back Ro is in the
lab sit back par them up relax hold
up