if you have ever had to dump the entire
Reservoir because two drops of pH Down
was not enough but three drops was way
too many go ahead and click subscribe
the grow from your heart podcast Starts
Now R and Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode
817 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun show lined up for us in
this episode I'm going to give away free
seeds hang out we'll talk more about the
free seeds later in this episode I do
want to announce that iy direct will be
back November 1st that's right if you've
been looking for iy direct have no fear
the website will be back November first
there will be a lot of great items
available uh make sure you join the
mailing list at IR genetics.com when
edirect goes back online you will get a
notification and update also make sure
you check out patreon at
patreon.com fromy yourheart because
patreon members do get first dibs and
first notifications when there are
updates at iy direct.com a lot of people
have been asking what happened to iir
why did I have to take down the website
I will do a full podcast episode about
why I had to move the website about the
uh the situation that happened and how I
resolved that and where we are now I
will do a full podcast about that but I
will probably put that on patreon that
will be patreon only content when I put
that show out when I do complete that
episode I will let you know that that is
available but the saga continues the
thing is not completed yet once I have
the website going again sales Are Back
In Action things feel smooth then I will
talk about it I'll make the full podcast
about it I built a good uh chronological
timeline I'm keeping an outline of how
it happened happened the uh timeline of
events I will talk about it all very
soon but it will be a patreon episode
I'll let you know when that's coming so
that you can join the patreon and check
out that story if you are all at all
interested in the uh story of why iir
disappeared and the triumphant return of
iy direct all right that's enough
rambling here at the start of the show
let's jump into everybody's favorite
portion of the podcast that is the email
portion of the podcast if you need grow
help if you have grow questions please
go to my website iry genetics.com
there's a growel tab at the top of the
page or a tab that says questions we're
doing some work to the website on the
website so things will change uh it may
say grow help it may say questions uh
use whichever one pops up for you go to
the website go to the question tab uh
type in your name tell me your grow
question let me know what's going on in
your garden if I do read your grow
question here on the podcast you will
win a free pack of iy genetics premium
seeds that's right you'll get a free
pack of seeds so send me those questions
on IR genetics.com or of course I
direct.com I will read your question you
will win free seeds the first question
to be read on today's podcast came from
somebody who wants to call themselves
Stefan thank you for the great message
Stefan uh the question goes just like
this it says hey rosta Jeff what's up
bro good to meet you it says I hope that
you are well thanks a lot for the
interesting topics that help us
understand this plant better hey you are
very welcome thank you for the great
compliment thank you for noticing and
thank you for contributing it does say
I've got some general request general
questions regarding Fox tailing flowers
and I hope to get an explanation from a
pro other than the Bro Science you can
find online well uh to be completely
honest with you here my dude this is
going to be bro science uh what you're
asking about I don't have any scientific
knowledge I didn't do any real research
this is just what I've experienced uh
with playing with genetics playing with
a lot of plants and what I think a lot
of this is my opinion we'll jump into
that let me get to it uh the question
question is uh why does fox tailing
happen at all is there a way to avoid it
and is there even a need for it other
than avoiding the annoying extra labor
when it comes to trimming thanks a lot
and please keep up the great work dude
thank you for encouraging me to keep up
the great work I have skipped a couple
of weeks of episodes here uh I've been
doing shows every other week I've been
spending a lot of energy getting iy
direct going again uh that's been very
timec consuming very costly it's been a
little bit stressful to tell you the
truth and I've dedicated more time to
that than I should uh I should have been
here doing the podcast but I put more
energy into I redirect needed to get
that going I'm here now doing a podcast
but thank you to all of the people who
uh when an episode does not come out
people like immediately they're like hey
bro are you okay is are you all right is
your life okay is everything good people
check on me when episodes don't come out
thank you to those folks big fist bump
to everyone who checks on me uh but I
will not stop doing the podcast
sometimes I do need to skip a week take
a break uh life gets busy bro and I've
been enjoying life and doing those
things uh but have no fear the podcast
is not going away now let me answer this
question and quit rambling uh cuz I am
quite rambly today I've been smoking
some uh toay taii to uh it's actually
called my taii to [ __ ] cake from Green
Dot uh it's an amazing dab it got me
super rambly let's stay focused it says
um the fox tailing why does it happen in
all happen at all sometimes uh that is
just basically a phenotypical expression
sometimes that plant is going to fox
tail uh no matter where you put it no
matter what environment that plant goes
into uh let me talk about fox tailing in
general a lot of times when we grow a
plant it makes a little like a pine
cone-shaped Bud sometimes it'll make a
fingery looking bud with weird finger
shapes coming out coming out of it weird
stacked cxes sometimes that is less or
more exaggerated depending on the plant
and the environment so those are your
fox tails a lot of people don't like
those like this grower said because it
is extra work when you were trimming
those are a pain in the ass to work
around and they're not super pretty in
the bag uh what causes that I was saying
a moment ago most of the time that fox
tailing a lot of the time that is
genetics it is in the genetics many
genetics will do that a lot of the more
tropical sativa type stuff will do that
uh most of your Afghans and your indicia
stuff won't do it as much uh but I
believe that is so uh so that that plant
it is hot and tropical and humid where
that plant is being grown and if it got
tight and cluster that inside part would
get moldy so the plant knew that and it
went hey let's spread out a little bit
and it's got all this breathing room so
it doesn't get moldy in the inside of
the plant uh that is my theory that
that's what I think Fox tailing is about
it can be exaggerated by room
environment conditions like if it gets
too hot they will bring on more Fox
tailing if it gets too dry that could
encourage Fox tailing also if it gets
too humid that could encourage Fox
tailing it's all about uh what happens
in the environment and how that plant is
uh genetically programmed to respond to
that environmental trigger so is
foxtailing a good or bad thing is the
next part of this question um that is a
very relative question if you're growing
for flower if you want a nice uh bag
appe peel if you want the sack like Dr
Dre taught us a long time ago you want a
sack of rocks you want a bag of tight
dense buds that just lines the bottom of
the baggie would be your quarter of
nuggets and that's all that should be in
there some dense tight rocks uh that is
a good mindset if you're rolling blunts
if you're taking bong loads but if you
are a concentrate maker some of these
finger uh fingery foxa buds are more
desirable I've said this before a long
time ago imagine if I were to take my
Fist and I were to roll it around in
powdered sugar we're going to moisten up
my fist and roll it in powdered sugar
I'm going to get this much surface area
worth of powdered sugar uh imagine if
that is tricomes on a plant you got this
much Tricom all over here I don't know
the surface area I don't know how to
measure that but this much surface area
covered in tricomes now imagine if we
grew a more open structured Bud a more
foxtail Bud that was like this and had
weird shapes coming out of it look at
all that extra surface area I just
opened up for more troms that if we're
making concentrates that would be much
easier to extract from the plant that
more fingery areer more spacious open
type of a bud is more desirable for a
concentrate maker I do see a trend
starting that the concentrate makers are
realizing that the flower smokers want
that tighter Bud that tighter bud
structure which we all enjoy Which is
popular which we're all accustomed to
there's nothing wrong with it but the
people that are making concentrates that
are leaning more toward the phenotypes
that are more open that are more Airy
because like I just talked about there's
more uh more uh surface area to get
tricomes on and also if you got this bud
with just this much Tricom in it all
this inside it's hard to wash that it's
hard to extract that this bud is much
easier too however you're pressing it
extracting it washing it blasting it
processing it whatever you do this bud
is easier to knock tricomes off of so
that is a pro and a con of that foxa but
if you're looking for bag appeal if you
want to put it on the Shelf at the
dispensary if you want the crew to buy
it and pay top dollar for it maybe that
fox hilly shit's not for you but if
you're making concentrates that just may
be the perfect strain for you and in the
future I do see a trend in those foxtail
strains getting more popular for the
concentrate makers imagine if you're
running Bubble Bags you got all those
fingers that's so much easier to wash
than a tight bunch of rocks in my
opinion in my experience all right let
me make sure I've covered this question
I did ramble quite a long time about
that one um Fox sailing does it happen
yeah it's a thing it really does happen
is there way to avoid it sometimes that
fox tailing is genetic sometimes it is
brought on by too much heat uh if you're
getting a lot of excessive Fox tailing
maybe raise your lights get that butt
away from the light that may help you
out maybe cool off the room is there a
need for it yeah the concentrate makers
like it uh extra labor when it comes to
trimming yeah if you're making
concentrates you don't have to trim it
so that makes it so much easier uh this
is all about phenotypical selection
maybe pick the one that is not so
fingery oh excuse me my voice is burning
out right there I apologize for that
that one but my friend Stefan uh thank
you for the great question since I read
your message here on the podcast guess
what you my dude win a free pack of IE
genetics premium seeds please send me an
email with your real name and a good
safe shipping address and in the subject
of that email please put prizes uh so
that I know to look for you so that I
know to send you prizes anybody else out
there if you're expecting prizes send me
a reminder put the word prizes in the
subject line of the email address and I
will get or in the yeah the subject line
of the email and I will get your prizes
out to you as soon as possible all right
let's keep the podcast moving I do have
another great question here in front of
me this one came from our friend Blue
Grass ganja what's up Bluegrass ganja I
do like that name it says hey rosta Jeff
I have recently popped several tester
packs from another breeder I have been
noticing on one of the seedlings that it
is showing variegation and that is when
you see um just different like it'll
probably be dark green and you'll see
some light green color ing uh maybe
tiger stripes maybe Stripes going up the
length or the width of the plant of the
leaves there uh that is basic
variegation uh maybe an albino looking
leaf or something on there or a half
albino leaf that is basic variegation it
says would you be concerned and what are
the possible outcomes from finishing
this plant thanks always I do appreciate
the knowledge this is a great question
it is not uncommon to see some weird
things in little tiny plants in
seedlings that are brand new a lot of
the time the plant will simply grow out
of that the variegation it may grow out
of it uh weird mutations when the plants
are little it may grow out of it it may
not it may continue um if it doesn't
then you've got a really unique plant
that I would flower out I would keep a
clone of it and I would see what it does
if it's super fire and it grows good and
smokes good uh gets you good and Buzz
has a nice flavor to it and it makes
some cool variegation that may be
something fun to play with I would keep
an eye on it make sure it doesn't do
anything super weird but I would just
keep growing it treat it like normal but
keep an eye on it if it starts doing
weird [ __ ] then make some decisions uh
message me back but your options right
now are that it's going to grow out of
that by the time it's a foot tall you'll
never even remember that it had a
variegation or it's going to stay just
like it was or it will uh exaggerate the
variegation at which point I would make
some decisions uh look at the plant send
me a picture at that point then we can
make some decisions but at this Little
Seedling stage uh it's very likely that
it will grow out of that but some of my
plants some of my favorite plants are
the weirdos That Grew From a pack of
seeds uh the weird The Misfits the runs
that most of you would have thrown away
those might be some of the best plants
in the pack sometimes if you think about
it they're doing weird [ __ ] uh maybe
they're just going to bang out a whole
bunch of THC as another weird trait you
never know what those weirdos could do
sometimes give them a chance so that was
a quick answer uh my friend Blue Grass
ganja since I did read your question
here on the show that means you my
friend win a free pack of iy genetics
premium seeds once again please do send
me your shipping address you guys when
you send me those shipping addresses you
guys gals and everything in between
please send me a real shipping address
with a real name I've said this before
the post office knows your name you live
there they know who gets mail there
these are seeds they're fully legal and
legit to send uh give me your real name
and real address I will get you seeds
safely but once again my dude Bluegrass
ganja thank you for the great question I
do appreciate it I do look forward to
the followup let me know what happens
with this plant uh if it gets crazier if
it grows right on out of it uh if you
decide to call it if you decide to keep
it going if you decide to breed with it
let me know because I'm very curious
about your variegated plan all right
let's keep this party moving I do have
another great question here in front of
me this one came from our friend tokom
MAAC shout out to our friend tokomak hey
bro send me your shipping address
because you want a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds tokomak has a
question and it goes just like this my
question is a breeding question about
s1's all right let's talk about S1
before we get too far what is an S1
let's just say that you've got a Golden
Goat female plant you take that Golden
Goat you cut two clones of the same
plant that Golden Goat and Golden Goat
we're going to treat one plant with a
solution it is called Silver tho sulfate
that solution will cause this plant to
create pollen that pollen will be put on
the other clone now we have just made
Golden Goat S1 seeds those seeds will be
all female all Golden Goat seeds because
we used a Golden Goat female and a
Golden Goat female we bred them together
that is all Golden Goat S1 it is self s
stands for self one is the first
generation this is the first generation
of selfed Golden Goat seeds we're just
using the Golden Goat as an example here
because that makes it easy we're going
to move forward with the question it
says when Crossing an S1 with a male of
a different cultivar and hunting the
results to find a keeper female what
would be the purpose of back crossing
the keeper to the original S1 that is a
very good question let's talk more about
that so to explain this I'm I'm going to
stick with the Golden Goat Theory
because I've kind of done this with
Golden Goat and I can explain how and
why and what my purpose was and what the
uh the purpose could be of this so you
want to take a Golden Goat S1 and you
want to pollinate that with a different
cavar now I didn't do exactly this with
the Golden Goat let me make a disclaimer
when I did this I used the original
Golden Goat clone because I have that
most people don't have that original
Golden Goat clone they've got the S1
seed and this example he's asking about
the S1 seed so for the story we're going
to change my Golden Goat to the S1 but
for history sake I've got the original
Golden Goat clone don't get it twisted
don't change history don't think I'm
saying something different than ever
before uh we're just changing the story
to for this podcast uh we're going to
start with the Golden Goat S1 seed and
then when uh we going to cross the
Golden Goat S1 with a maale of a
different cultivar we're going to use uh
the daybreaker because hypothetically
realistically that's kind of what I did
I took Golden Goat daybreaker I
pollinated so then I took that male of a
different cultivar like in this question
and I pollinated that S1 in the real
world I did the Clone only like I keep
saying I want to make that disclaimer
but for this story took the daybreaker
mail pollinated that S1 Golden Goat that
would have made arise for this story now
also out of that arise did come a very
good a couple of male plants the one
male known as King Solomon but also
there's the Lesser known male that is
the Golden Goat dominant male of the
arise batch that is the one that I used
to make the Golden Goat backcross seeds
so now let's talk about uh what would be
the purpose of back crossing the keeper
to the original S1 now what I'm talking
about here is going to be a little bit
different then we'll touch on what the
actual question is um the thing that I
did was I found a male this uh question
is asking about finding a female I found
a male um because we took a male plant
and pollinated a fem seed that made male
and female plants out of that so I found
a male that really spoke to me that
looked just like the Golden Goat and my
purpose for back Crossing that was
because I wanted to stabilize those
Golden Goat traits uh and make Golden
Goat seeds there are no pure Golden Goat
regular seeds and a lot of purists do
not want to buy the feminized version uh
some people are just not into feminized
seeds there's an array of reasons why uh
we're not going to talk about that now
but some people don't want to buy fem a
lot of people want original Golden Goat
bat cross seeds so I took the Golden
Goat I pollinated it with daybreaker I
have now got seeds that are half golden
goat half daybreaker because parents
were 50/50 one of one uh one of one on
one side one on the other it came out
50/50 I searched for a phenotype a male
that looked a lot like the Golden Goat
if any of the phenotypes look like the
daybreaker I eliminated those for this
project because I don't want daybreaker
traits in this cross my next step if I
want Golden Goat uh if I want Golden
Goat backat cross seeds I need to
essentially wash out all of the
daybreaker traits so I'm looking for a
male that does not look like daybreaker
at all I need a boy that looks exactly
like Golden Goat so I found that dude
then I took that dude and I pollinated
the original uh mine was like I said the
original Golden Goat clone but for this
story I would pollinate that original S1
the purpose for that is now I'm washing
out some of those daybreaker trads
because now it's more of a two to one
mix of that Golden Goat Golden Goat
daybreaker combination cuz I kind of
washed out some of that daybreaker by
breeding it back to the Golden Goat I
got really lucky or maybe I did really
good uh thinking and planning I was very
meticulous in my selection uh I was
taking leaves off of my Golden Goat
female and leaves off of my potential
Golden Goat male candidates and matching
them up to see if Le Leaf shape and size
and serration were even I was rubbing
one with one hand and one with the other
and making sure the smells were the same
throughout the flowering phase I was
very meticulous with selecting my Golden
Goat uh my uh it's an arise Golden Goat
dominant uh looking phenotype of arise
male I was very specific in selecting
that one so most of my phenotypes in my
Golden Goat backat cross come out very
very Golden Goat dominant the batross 2
so if I did it again if I grew those
batross one seeds and found a mail plant
out of that and put that back on the
Golden Goat again it would really lock
in those Golden Goat traits most of
those seeds would be Golden Goat uh just
straight Golden Goat coming out when
they grew so the purpose for my reason
for going backwards was to wash out the
daybreaker traits and lock in the Golden
Goat traits I was removing the plant
that I used to adulterate it to initiate
the backat cross process because at the
time there was no Golden Goat mail there
still is no Golden Goat male but people
want those pure Golden Goat non- femin
seeds the closest I can get is a backat
cross or a backat cross 2 version so
that is one reason I talked about why I
chose the male that's for the backat
cross to lock in traits you are saying
uh what if I were to back cross the
keeper to the original S1 so you're
going to find a female keeper out of
here and cross it to the original S1 it
would essentially do the same thing it
would lock in whatever traits you have
found it would really lock in those
traits to where probably 70 to 80% of
the seeds you grew would look just like
the original plant that you've started
with if you did your selections properly
so if I read that correctly you want to
take your S1 you want to pollinate it
you want to make seeds that all makes
sense so far you still got the S1 over
here that's our marker uh then you want
to find good a good female out of that
then which one are we going to reverse
are we going to reverse the new female
let's see what would be the purpose of
back crossing the original to the
original or the new one to the original
uh which one do we want to reverse you
could do either one but either way you
do it I would reverse uh the original
and put it on the new one I would do
both honestly I'd [ __ ] around and do
both over time but at that point you're
just walking in uh if you find that
keeper and then you find that golden go
you're just putting in the or that
original S1 you're just locking in those
traits uh hopefully you selected the one
you really love and then you can lock in
those traits in the next breeding
project uh that would be the purpose is
to lock in traits you're not going to
open anything up you're not going to
create anything new uh you may see some
um transgressive segregation or some
weird recessive traits but the main
purpose would be to lock in dominant
traits which you have identified and now
that we're talking about it this is sort
of uh kind of what I did with the
Grateful do and number 77 kind of on
accident without even realizing what I
was doing but that is another story for
another time uh somebody remind me cuz
I'm not going to write it down to do an
episode about number 77 and the Grateful
Dog and we'll talk more in depth about
that in the future that's a whole other
podcast all right my dude uh tacomac I
think I've answered your question here I
did a lot of rambling about this and I'm
not even sure that I got you a solid
answer I think it makes sense uh breeder
to breeder I think you'll understand all
the stuff that I was saying all right my
dude make sure you do send me your
shipping address because I owe you a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
and I look forward to seeing what you do
with those since you are a breeder
somebody's starting thinking about
breeding I do encourage you and give you
my blessings and permission to breed
with any seeds that you receive from me
if you get I gentics premium seeds
regular feminized seeds uh any seeds
that come from me you do have my
permission and blessings to breed with
them if you got them in a uh a positive
way if you stole them or scam someone or
rip them off uh throw them away you
don't deserve them but if you got them
in a positive uh what is it an ethical
way grow the [ __ ] out of those breed
them produce some quality seeds as long
as you give me credit on the breeding
package or when you put them out or when
you share them I don't mind breed with
my stuff I encourage it I did not invent
cannabis I'm not a stickler about that
breed breed free love grow the ganja all
right that is all I think I've got for
you for this episode ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers indoor Growers
outdoor Growers cannabis enthusiasts
worldwide thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast I'm truly
grateful that you guys support the show
thank you thank you for listening uh if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know that I
would love to hear from you the email
address is grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy reach out also
make sure you support the support that's
I'm not even going to edit that make
sure you support the patreon campaign at
patreon.com fromy yourheart of course
everyone on patreon will receive a
coupon code as soon as iy direct is
launched make sure you support us on
patreon what else do I have for you um I
think that is it oh I do want to give a
giant shout out to our friend Emma
Marley and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
big up yourself every time R the
[Music]
Jeff
time to take another DB grab your pie in
nle about the back Ro is in the lab sit
back H mom and relax hold
up