the grow from your heart podcast Starts
Now Rustin Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ] welcome to the show
everybody I'm your host rosta Jeff this
is episode
8177 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun show lined up for us in
this episode we're going to give away
free seeds that's right hang out we'll
talk more later about the free seeds
before we get to that part I do want to
announce that iir is back that's right
after a short break or a short Hiatus
iir is back online make sure you check
out
redirect.sh great stuff on iy Direct
there will be more stock coming very
soon make sure you check out that Black
Friday sale that is coming up on iy
Direct I will talk more about that in
the upcoming episodes also patreon
members do get free packs from I direct
if you're a member of the patreon at $25
or $50 on the patreon you will receive
one or two free packs of seeds and a
coupon for a discount at edirect decom
so make sure you check out edirect decom
and also check out patreon.com for SL
grow from your heart I did mention that
we're giving away free packs to patreon
supporters this month we have two
different tiers of free packs available
one tier is a gorilla goat freebie and
the other tier is a blueberry butcher
freebie there will be two different
packs available next month so if you're
a member of patreon at $25 a month or
higher this month you will receive a
free pack of seeds of course if you do
contribute 50 bucks to patreon this
month you will get two free packs of I
genetic seeds and a coupon code for
redirect.sh questions or contact if you
contact me and send me a grow question
if I read your question here on the
podcast I will send you a free pack of
iy genetics premium seeds so send me
those grow questions also many people
are asking about where is IR
genetics.com the site is under
construction that one will be back very
soon uh we did update iir now that iir
is live we are working on IR
genetics.com both sites will be up and
running very soon for now make sure you
check out iire direct.com you can send
those growel questions to the questions
tab the contact tab there on iir anyway
if I read your question on the podcast
you will win a free pack of seeds the
free pack of seeds from today's episode
goes to our friend who wants to be
called x-ray toker big shout out to my
new friend x-ray toker thank you for
listening to the podcast and thank you
for a great question we've got a few
details here about the garden that are
not necessary we're going to throw that
first page over there we're going to
jump into the second page because this
is where the question Pops in it says
please describe your problem and
everything you've done to fix it the
question goes a lot like this it says
Hey Rasta Jeff the problem is simple it
is spidermites yes the dreaded
spidermite every grower at some point in
time is going to experience spidermites
if you have not experienced spidermites
yet uh you were bragging you're going
not me never had it well guess what
they're coming just because you just
said that that is how they work they
know you're bragging they are on their
way they will be in your grow soon start
taking care of [ __ ] have no fear we're
going to talk about how to take care of
that here but spidermites everybody's
going to get them once everybody's
either had them or will have them very
common we can talk about ways to prevent
them but it is a very easy pest to bring
home a very easy pest to get also with a
little bit of strategy a little bit of
preparation a little bit of watchful eye
and eye for detail the spidermites are
not too problematic to get rid of if we
notice them early once they start moving
around infesting all of the plants
getting in all of the rooms it's more of
a pain in the ass but it is never
impossible to get rid of spidermites I
can get rid of I think I can get rid of
any pest given enough time uh given
enough budget and enough manpower and a
proper strategy I can eradicate any pest
in any cultivation facility how big or
small it is let's stay focused here
we're going to talk about integrated
Pest Management today and we're going to
focus mostly on spidermites this
question says how do I get rid of the
spiderm mites without losing all of my
strains that is a very good question
says some of these strains I've had for
years uh bro as a seed breeder as
somebody who relies on my uh strains my
genetics my mother plants I definitely
understand how important it is to not
lose those strains it goes on it says I
have sprayed with soapy water followed
by a cold rinsing now I have an exhaust
fan cranked up with some serious wind
trauma the wind is a good idea that's a
good place to start the message goes on
it says I do need to clear this out
before my new seed order arrives don't
make me cry I will be 70 this year well
happy birthday my friend and this is
almost my only medicine well I'm proud
of you for being uh that far into life
and not falling for all of the doctor
prescriptions at that age they really do
try to push a lot of pills and a lot of
medicines on folks your age so good job
for keeping cannabis mostly your only
medicine that is great all right they
wrapped message up with thanks and love
for the show and great info love you bro
sincerely and then he signed it with his
real name I will not say that on the air
thank you bro great message let's talk a
little bit about spidermites I'm going
to do my best to not break your heart
here but some of this may be challenging
some of it may be a little bit of work
but together we will get rid of those
spidermites I do have a lot of stuff
written down here uh you said that you
started with um soapy water followed by
a cold rinsing that is a good start but
I bet you those spidermites just laugh
at you uh spider mites have been
evolving I got some spidermites a while
back from California this was several
years ago they're gone they've been
defeated but it was a challenge I got
some new mites from California these
meno mites these super mites uh the
mites are evolving these were like the
Ninja Turtles of spider mites I could
not get rid of them they took anything I
threw at them uh it took a year and it
took a really solid winter to get rid of
them I needed that Colorado winter to
come in and I blasted that cold air in
the grow room uh crippled some plants a
little bit but that is what got rid of
them uh so the mites are evolving I bet
that that soapy cold water uh they just
laughed at you they're like oh yeah we
needed a bath and so they just cleaned
themselves up in it so let's talk more
in depth about getting rid of these
mites something that I wrote down is
when trying to eradicate a pest let's
focus on the pest we are facing I see
people just uh on the internet on social
media in general just saying hey I've
got spider mites what should I spray and
then people will recommend crazy random
[ __ ] like spray safer soap or spray
oregano oil or spray this or there's
many terrible examples I could give why
not focus on the pest you're trying to
eradicate research that Pest and apply
the product that will get rid of that
pest if I told you right now that you're
going to the Olympics tomorrow would you
say what what event am I in or would you
just prepare for every single event if I
told you you're going to be in the
Olympics tomorrow and you're a figure
skater would you go preparing for the
bob sled team or would you prepare for
the next few months to be a figure
skater what I'm saying is prepare for
the thing that we need to attack if
you're facing spider mites let's attack
spidermites if you've got thrips let's
attack thrips if you've got fungus snats
let's go right for the fungus snats
let's not just use random generic hippie
ideas that might work for everything
let's focus in and attack the insects we
are trying to attack so like I said just
a moment ago let's attack the pest we
are trying to attack no matter which
insect pest Predator whatever it is we
are trying to get rid of in our garden
it has a life cycle it's going to live a
certain amount of time if it's if it's a
bigger pest something like a rabbit or a
deer that is a pest that gets in our
Garden we're not going to talk as much
about that but those could live four
years if it's an insect its whole life
cycle could be a few days then we got to
learn also not only the life cycle of
our pest but we need to understand the
breeding cycle of those pests as well
some of the bugs we're battling are born
pregnant what yeah they came out
pregnant already what kind of hood bugs
do we have but that's how they are so
understand the life cycle of the pest
you're dealing with understand the
breeding cycle of the pest you're
dealing with then let's disrupt both of
those processes with within these bugs
then we have a better chance of beating
these insects so do a little research
understand how do they live where do
they live do they live under the foliage
they do they live on the stems do they
live in the dirt where do these bugs
live understand where they live how they
live and how they breed and now we're
getting into their heads we've got a
much better opportunity to eradicate
these Intruders now once we've
identified the insect which we are
choosing to do battle with today's
victim is going to be spidermites they
tried to come into our room we're going
to show them we don't play that game
we're going to get rid of these
spidermites once you've identified the
pest then you need to make some personal
ethical decisions how do you want to
attack these spider mites or whichever
bug you may be facing one good option is
predator bugs do you want to start with
predator mites or Predator insects in
your grow and use those as a way to
eradicate your current bug situation
that is a very useful very cost-
effective way to go about it but you've
got to release bugs into your grow that
can take a little bit of time for those
bugs to uh establish a colony get in
there and find where they need to go to
go find the the bug that they need to
eat then there's a battle that needs to
happen and then eventually uh your
Predators will out eat all of the other
bugs and then they will die off as well
or they'll move along if you've got a
Perpetual environment maybe those bugs
will stick around you can make that work
but uh if you run out of bugs they may
disappear so Predator bugs is a very
effective way of eradicating bugs in
your grow but it does take a little bit
of time for them to get to work how
about sprayed pesticide applications
that is always a very reliable way to
get rid of almost almost any pest is a
sprayed application now here's where you
have to make more ethical decisions what
types of sprays do you want to apply to
your garden a lot of people are going to
say I use all organic products but then
I'm going to remind you that cyanide is
organic and if you get any of that in
your body you're going to get sick and
die so uh don't Focus too much on the
word organic don't be sold by the word
organic let's focus more on the active
ingredients and inactive ingredients in
that bottle do some research on what is
in the bottle then think about how
gentle or non- gentle you want to be how
aggressive you want to go how much
chemical blast you want to use um some
people are going to say it's a scale of
organic to nuclear that's a good range
organic like we just said is kind of a
buzzword but do you want to go gentle
hippie soap or do you want to go [ __ ]
aoid how far in between do you want to
go that is up to you as a farmer what is
going to happen to the product that you
are going to grow and sell are you going
to smoke it are you going to consume it
yourself are you making concentrates out
of it if you're making concentrates your
con concentrating the pesticide if it's
still in that plant are you going to
make edibles and then are you going to
eat those pesticides yourself are you
going to sell that product are you
selling it to uh the street or are you
selling it to Medical uh medical
cannabis consumers there's a lot of
things to think about here if you're
going to smoke it yourself do whatever
you want with it do whatever you feel
comfortable with it if somebody else is
going to get this product be very
careful and very uh very thoughtful
about what you spray or apply to your
plants it could be uh nutrients
pesticides anything in this realm think
about what you're putting in there uh
think about it if it's for you that's
important but if it's going to someone
else it's your responsibility to pass a
safe clean ethical product along to your
consumers they're giving you money
they're giving you trust they're
expecting cannabis that is safe to be
consumed make sure you give them that so
whatever you're going to spray on there
make sure that it is something that is
consumable that you would consume
understand the halflife and the duration
of Life uh that these chemicals will
last in your plant if you're spraying
something sustain mic it could stick
around in that plant for quite a long
time research halflife start
understanding how long it takes for that
uh pesticide to break down within that
plant and be gone hopefully it's gone by
the time you harvest but pay attention
to those sort of things uh also there
are a lot of things to understand when
it comes to applying pesticides that
people completely Overlook but
understand what you're giving your
customers please let's think a lot about
that I do have a few more things I want
to touch on before we go too deep into
pesticides um the key to a clean grow
room and the key to not getting spider
mites or the key to getting rid of
spider mites is really don't get them I
know for this person it's too late but
maybe some of you are saying I've never
had mites the key is prevention in a
commercial facility we start at day one
with preventing spider mites or any
other pest from entering the room it's
your responsibility as the farmer to
make sure no pests get in that room and
if they do it's your job to react
quickly and understand how to mitigate
the problem before it becomes a tragedy
in that grow space a lot of people like
to blame soil bags for bringing in bugs
guess what you brought the bag into the
grow you should have understood what was
coming along with that keep that sort of
stuff in mind so prevention is key how
do we prevent bugs from entering the
grow space clean up basic cleanliness is
one of the main ingredients to a
successful grow clean everything if
you've got a leaf on the floor get that
leaf out of there that leaf went into a
trash bag or a trash can get that trash
can Andor trash bag dumped and out of
the grow facility to a dumpster outside
as far away as you can get it move that
set yourself up for Success if you've
got a bunch of debris just random [ __ ]
in the grow space that doesn't need to
be there if it's your grow tools your
T-shirt your drink uh whatever doesn't
need to be in there get it out of there
those are more places for bugs to hide
things for them to hide under places for
them to hide on clean up create a basic
standard operating procedure for your
cultivation facility for a sanitary grow
environment whatever that means to you
how are you going to I don't know where
your grow is I don't know if it's in
your house house I don't know if it's in
your basement your garage I don't know
if it's in a big commercial facility I
don't know if it's in a barn in a field
whatever you need to do to create a
standard operating procedure to create a
sanitary growing environment that is
what you need to figure out as the Ganja
Farmer on duty so if you need to build a
clean room where you walk in and change
your shoes your clothes uh spray your
hair down with something wrap your hair
up put it in a hat however you want to
do it uh put on some gloves then go into
the grow space that may be a step that
you need to take if you're coming from
one grow to the other definitely have a
space where you can stop and change a
lab coat or do something to just make
another layer so that when you're in
here in this grow space all the
spidermites are sticking onto that uh
lab coat take it off go in another room
with a different lab coat that may help
mitigate spreading the problem but
create an sop so that you don't bring
bugs in and you do not move bugs around
get the trash gone the trash doesn't
need to just go so if your grow is in
your basement don't just bring the trash
up to the kitchen or the garage it needs
to go out it needs to get to the curve
as quickly as possible get rid of that
[ __ ] uh clean you clean yourself clean
your clothing I've got dreadlocks when I
go into the grow I tie up my dreadlocks
and put a hat over them so that if
anything does try to climb on me
hopefully it stays on the hat uh people
always ask yes I do wash the dreadlocks
but um they could get in there I could
move some bugs around in the dreadlocks
so that's why we got to be very careful
uh what about your equipment do you have
a separate set what about shoes I see a
lot of people wear the same shoes
outside and then you go into a grow
space wherever you walk through outside
were there spider mites was there
powdery mildew perhaps on a plant was
there a fungus now was there a thrip
what did you bring in from outside on
your shoes into your grow space cuz your
grow space is a beautiful environment as
soon as you got in there that spidermite
that thrip that fungus net whatever it
was I went oh this is [ __ ] nice and
it went and found a hotel in one of your
plants so change your clothes change
your shoes what about your gear do you
have and we should be doing this anyway
because hopl and vroid is running ramp
now are you changing scissors between
different grows are you using gear for
outside that you're using inside don't
do that don't cross-contaminate think
about the equipment now let's kind of
segue into things that we can actually
do within the grow uh to the plants to
help mitigate pest problems one thing I
really think is beneficial is
defoliation defoliate all the leaves
with the big purple pedal or the
gigantic leaves that are blocking the
Sun from getting to the buds pull those
leaves off of there you don't need those
leaves anyway those leaves are where the
bud are going to hang out where do you
get spidermites the bottom of the leaves
where do you get powdery mildew on top
of the leaves no leaves no problems get
them out of there make his few leaves as
possible in that room but keep the
plants healthy and you will mitigate
pest problems another thing that I like
and this listener mentioned is wind if
you can get some fans going in that room
spidermites and bugs do not like wind
they like a nice calm place they could
chill out they can eat some food they
can get some ass and they can make some
webs that's what they want disrupt that
make it uncomfortable for them
then another thing I talked about a
moment ago is don't cross-contaminate
your grows if you've got home grows in
multiple rooms don't go from room a to
room B without taking care of yourself
especially if you see a problem clean up
change your lab coat change your shoes
change whatever you need to do if you've
got grows in two different houses
perhaps change clothes from house to
house if you're working in multiple
cultivation facilities as a consultant
definitely change your shoes and your
clothes between facilities if possible a
lot of facilities now have a foot wash
you step into this little tray and it
puts [ __ ] all over your shoes it's
cleaner stuff it's fine I'm a sneaker
head it's cool it'll spray this Splash
this [ __ ] on your shoes and then you
step onto another tray and it puts a
little booty right over your shoe now
you're walking around with fresh clean
feet in there those are really great for
a commercial facility um are there any
bushes or flowers or shrubs or plants
outside of your house or your commercial
facility that are housing insects uh it
is not uncommon to see somebody just go
to Lowe's and get some uh spray product
again use do some I said Lowe's also go
to your local home hardware store uh
local hardware store if you have one but
go get some pesticide spray and spray
that on the plants outside so that you
can get rid of the bugs out there as
well but when you do that they're going
to try to move in so make sure you're
prepared for that but treat the outdoor
once or twice a year so there's no bugs
in the shrubs and bushes outside if you
can remove those go get rid of those
shrubs and bushes but I understand
nature is happening out there we can't
chop down all the trees please don't do
that all right another thing I really
want to make sure to mention is I do see
a lot of yellow sticky traps in use one
thing to think about is those are not uh
to eradicate bugs those are to indicate
the presence of a pest uh you should
have those all over the grow every six
or 12 feet apart there should be a
yellow sticky card so that when you walk
by it you can take a look you should
look at it as you walk by in the morning
walk by as you look at lunch walk by at
the end of the day just take a peek if
there's one bug on there at one point in
time make a mental note I saw a bug if
there's three bugs on there later make a
note three bugs should it's increasing
pay attention if there's one or two bugs
that's going to happen just they fly
around they see light [ __ ] happens but
if you start getting increasing numbers
of bugs that's a sign [ __ ] is happening
in your grow you need to start taking
care of those so hang yellow sticky
traps or even the blue sticky traps in
the grow to indicate the presence of
some pests now let's talk more about
preventative um preventative do you want
to release Predator bugs I've talked
about the Predator bugs there are many
options for predator bugs like I said
before choose your bug wisely make sure
you're getting the predators that you
think you will have pest so you can
fight what is coming or do you want to
apply sprays if you're going to apply
sprays I recommend sprays on a rotation
have multiple products on hand spray
them on a rotation on a schedule in M gr
environments I try to spray on Monday if
I see any sort of a problem I step it up
and I spray on Monday and Thursday at
the change of seasons I spray on Monday
and Thursday it just got cold I
anticipate bugs trying to come in they
got an extra spray this week on Thursday
just just to make sure nothing sneaks in
now when you are spraying products one
thing I highly recommend is research
every product which you are going to
apply understand the product you were
going to apply understand the active
ingredients understand the inactive
ingredients understand what those active
ingredients can do to you if you are
exposed to them if you spray that and
get some on your skin what is going to
happen to you understand those sorts of
risks open up the label on those bottles
every pesticide bottle has a label and
it unfolds there's a little booklet in
there that will tell you a lot about
that pesticide
when you read that see if it says
warning danger Hazard see if it's got a
skull and crossbones look at the level
of danger level of Hazard which that
pesticide presents then read about the
personal protective equipment required
to apply that pesticide many of them are
going to tell you wear long sleeves wear
gloves uh cover up your feet for sure
when you're applying a pesticide don't
go doing it Barefoot like a hippie I
recommend a respirator if you're
spraying with a paint sprayer or
anything that makes bubbles wear a
respirator because because you don't
want to breathe in those micro bubbles
with pesticide in it also eye protection
is a must and if you got long hair
dreadlocks or even not cover up your
head and be safe but make sure you
research the personal protective
equipment needed for the pesticide you
are applying now since I am certified by
the Colorado Department of Agriculture
as a pesticide applicator and Handler I
am also train the trainer certified by
the Colorado State University and the
Colorado Department of Agriculture I was
trained by Theo walker uh just give it
some credentials here but with all that
being said I should remind you about
something that is called the reentry
interval whenever we apply a pesticide
we should apply that pesticide uh with
the lights off and then safely exit that
room and then we should hang a sign on
the door if you're working with anybody
else there's a sign that is required on
the door that says hey guess what we
sprayed a pesticide we sprayed this at
this time you're not allowed to enter
for this many hours from that time so
that nobody goes in that room and gets
wet pesticide product on their skin
breathes in that Vapor we're trying to
be safe there's what is called a
re-entry interval don't go in the room
until that re-entry interval is up and
many people may not know this but if we
are applying a pesticide indoors you
should double the recommended re-entry
interval printed on that bottle most of
those products are not designed to be
sprayed and applied indoors most of them
are for outdoor commercial use or
outdoor agricultural use when we apply
these products indoors we are not
getting sunshine on them we are not
getting wind like we would normally get
we don't have the natural environment to
break down that pesticide and dry it up
and make the plant process it or break
down the way that it should uh naturally
outdoors so it is highly recommended to
double the re-entry interval when
applying a pesticide spray application
indoors I just want to say that because
I'm certified by the department of a and
it would feel very irresponsible to not
give you that disclaimer for
preventative measures I recommend
spraying once a week like I said before
if you see any problems popping up
double that spray spray Monday and spray
Thursday if the problem gets bad
consider spraying three times a week but
that will get brutal on the plants
you'll see them respond they may tell
you hey that is too much you may have to
settle it down especially depending on
the products you're going to apply I
have said before that you can apply what
I call a tank mix that is multiple
pesticides mixed together at one time uh
in one tank and spray it you can do that
if you research each pesticide which you
are applying and don't be redundant have
uh if you're going to apply one that is
a Pym base don't put two pyrum based
products in there together but don't get
redundant if you're going to put one
pyin product in there don't mix in just
another pyrin product put something else
a different mode of attack inside of
that mix that way we can hit the bugs
with two different attacks you could
throw a left and when they try to block
the left you could throw that right and
knock them right the [ __ ] out two
products maybe three products at a time
is not a bad idea if you understand what
and why you are mixing maybe mix a
little batch maybe don't mix a whole
bunch at one time so you don't get a
chem IAL reaction but a tank mix is
highly acceptable now that is my
preventative strategy I spray once a
week with a rotated pesticide schedule
on a schedule every Monday I spray if I
see a problem I step it up to every
Thursday on a schedule I've got a
pesticide rotation there are a few
products I really enjoy I think they
work really well together uh just to
give you a kind of an idea I like to use
uh we'll say botanigard Max on Monday
and then uh Evergreen on Thursday and
then we would probably do something like
um and also make sure you're checking
with your local state guidelines if
you're using this in a commercial
facility I don't know what is regulated
in your state I'm making recommendations
for what I do uh in a personal grow if
you're growing in a commercial grow
things are regulated by the me and the
department of a so make sure you pay
attention to that but I would do like
the botanigard Max and then Evergreen
and then probably like venerate on the
next one and then just start the
rotation over and if I have a pest
problem I see a couple things I would
possibly do like the Evergreen and
venerate together and then do botanigard
Max and maybe the Evergreen again the
next time just to double up and throw
some super punches but don't be afraid
to do a tank mix and get creative and
knock those bad [ __ ] out all
right I do have notes and I feel like I
fell off my notes where am I attack
we're at the attack phase now let's say
that we do see some bugs in our grow
room now it's time to step it up instead
of just Monday we're spraying Monday and
Thursday um this all depends on where
you are in the grow cycle if you're in
veg uh go ahead and spray the [ __ ] out
of them with whatever you want that is
up to your ethical standards if you're
in flower you really need to consider
what you are spraying on these plants uh
if you're in the first 21 days of flower
you've got a lot more opportunity for
sprays the first 10 to 14 days go ahead
and spray away unless you're breeding uh
you don't want to mess up those pistols
but it's all about the phase and how far
into flour you are there are some
products we could spray later uh I don't
really want to spray too late if we
don't have to but sometimes it's
necessary if you're going into flour and
you do spot a a bunch of bugs and you
want to get rid of them that is the time
to overload the garden with those living
Predator bugs uh sworsky hypoaspis miles
Pim pmus Cal fornicus Green Lace Wings
Ro beetles get in there and attack with
everything you can find but if you are
still in the veg phase go ahead and
spray whatever you feel comfortable
start hitting them on Monday with one or
two products hit them again on Thursday
with one or two products keep that going
until you see there are no pests present
maybe even continue one or two
applications even after you think the
bugs are gone it is important to me to
spray every room I've got a mom room a
veg room a clone area a flower area this
is all commercial buildings with a lot
of [ __ ] make sure that everything is
treated equally those mother plants are
where it all starts those veg plants are
the building blocks for flow that flower
room is the bread and butter they're all
equally important make sure that those
bugs are all getting treated in every
room or you're just going to move them
around if you can get those mother
plants super clean and get the veg plant
super clean and then keep them clean
through flow that is the goal so maybe
release a whole [ __ ] ton of Predator
bugs in your mom room and then those
bugs will keep moving around with you
once you establish colonies keep those
bugs coming in the mom room every couple
of weeks add more add more uh however
you cut clones keep that schedule going
maybe order more bugs every week you cut
clones cut some clones add more bugs cut
some clones add more bugs and it all
moves down the chain from the mom room
to the bedroom to the flower room keep
the bugs alive in there that's just a
good strategy that may work for for you
all right where were we attack multiple
modes of attack on an aggressive routine
twice a week but like I said a moment
ago be specific don't bring a knife to a
might fight right I'll said that again
don't bring a knife to a might fight if
you're fighting spidermites uh don't
bring something designed to fight thrips
if you're fighting thrips don't bring
some [ __ ] to Des designed to spite to
fight spidermites that's easier than it
sounds I know that was hard to say but
you know what I'm trying to talk about
if you're fighting spidermites get a
pesticide designed at eradicating
spidermites don't go get some hippie
soap don't try some witchcraft don't do
Voodoo go get a pesticide that says
designed to eradicate spider mites do
the right thing set yourself up for
Success you're going to spend the money
you're going to spend the time you're
going to spend the energy go at it hard
right at the very beginning let's win
the battle now keeping in mind the fact
that we are understanding which pest we
are battling where are those bugs are
they on the underside of the leaves are
they living in the soil where do those
pests reside where are they hanging out
where's the party let's treat that
appropriate area let's spray the bottoms
of the leaves start at the bottom of the
plant spray the undersides of the leaves
and work your way up to the top then
also possibly maybe a suggestion if
these bugs go into the soil if you got
thrips or fungus Nets we need to treat
the soil we need to do what is called a
soil dredge one of my favorite soil
dredges is Evergreen I'll mix up my
water just like a a bunch of five gallon
buckets just like I'm going to water the
plants and then I will put an amount of
Evergreen in those buckets and stir it
really really well then I will water
that into the plants until it runs off a
little bit now I'm sure that I've got
Evergreen in all of that soil all of
that Medium if you're using cocoa soil
whatever you're working with saturate
that uh repeat again in about 3 or 4
days and now you've probably gotten rid
of all of your soil born pests all the
bugs that were in the dirt are dead
they're going to fly up and try to get
to the leaves we have sprayed those
leaves with something maybe a couple of
things are not going to want to be up
there create a non-desirable environment
for those bugs whether it's a poison or
just something uncomfort able put
something on the leaves and they won't
want to go there so think about what bug
you're working with do you need to treat
the leaves do you need to treat the dirt
do you need to treat both let's do that
let's also clean up the room and
ourselves and Go full heavy Attack Mode
again do you want to go bugs do you want
to go sprays do you want to go organic
or do you want to go nuclear this is all
up to you there are many suggestions for
getting rid of spidermites on the
internet they're all going to work but
you just have to decide how ethical that
product is for you and if you want to
consume that or pass that to your
customers now sometimes an infestation
can just get way too far ahead of us
sometimes we don't notice uh sometimes
you go away on vacation you come back
[ __ ] happened uh sometimes you've got a
helper they didn't know what they were
looking for sometimes [ __ ] does get out
of control I try not to let that happen
I try to pay attention maybe you slipped
up maybe you [ __ ] up and you got
spider mes maybe they're real bad and
you're thinking I cannot beat these
plants here is the last ditch effort if
you've tried every pesticide can think
of If youve released all the the bugs
you can think of here is one more idea
that we can do to get rid of these bugs
this is the last ditch effort I would
get a reservoir of water I would put a
pesticide in there you've got a million
[ __ ] options you can use uh you can
use anything from hydrogen peroxide to
Smite to banish to Evergreen to Tria 70
to venerate to uh much more powerful uh
products I'm not going to mention here
if you got a real problem I'll help you
but I don't want to share these product
names with anybody who doesn't really
have a struggle problem you shouldn't be
using these unless it's a last Stitch
effort to save some [ __ ] anyway makes up
a a reservoir a dunk dish of a pesticide
solution then we're going to cut some
clones we're going to go to your plant
that's got spidermites on it we're going
to cut a clone off of it then we're
going to dunk it in that dunk mix dunk
it in there and swish the [ __ ] out of it
get the spidermites off of it get the
webbing off of it uh whatever product
you need to use get that [ __ ] off of
there then uh you've got an option some
people people will tell you depending on
the pesticide that you just used uh if
you use Smite or banish you do need to
dunk them and rinse them in clean water
and get that pesticide off um the
pesticide is now within the plant it is
moving within the cells of the plant if
you use some things and that will
continue to keep the bugs away but give
them a good dunking and make sure to at
least get all these spidermites the webs
the bugs off of the plant then dunk it
into the wet uh the clean dish to get
rid of the pesticide then pot that clone
as usual dip it in your clone solution
uh pop it into the Clone Dome or the
easy clone or however you normally would
now pay very close attention to those
clones as soon as they are rooted and
able to get put into pots we need to
start treating them right away with an
integrated Pest Management routine I
would get the Evergreen out evergreen's
not too uh too brutal on small plants
and give it a light application of
Evergreen I would probably do that uh
Monday and Thursday then next week I'd
probably switch to the venerate then
next week I'd go botanigard Max uh and
then just make sure that we got rid of
the bugs it's going to be easier to to
treat the bugs on these little tiny
plants than it would on these big
gigantic plants so we're going to take
some clones we're going to dunk them
we're going to rinse them uh clip them
dip them and stick them get them in the
cloner however you do your clones that's
a whole other podcast change to that
episode now watch that one but do your
clones then here's the fun part we're
going to put a trash bag over those big
mommy plants and we're going to cut
those down and get the [ __ ] rid of them
they're going in the trash or the burn
pile they need to go ASAP far away also
let's get rid of the dirt that they were
in also maybe even throw away the whole
[ __ ] pot depends on how bad and how
mad you are at these plants but let's
get rid of it chop them down get rid of
this [ __ ] get rid of the dirt get rid of
the plants not just out in the garage
not just out by the house but far far
away get rid of that [ __ ] take it to the
dump go burn it make sure it is gone
then uh you got to get rid of these
clothes that you're wearing you got to
clean the clothes up you got to clean
your dreadlocks you got to get rid of
the spider mites that may have come home
with you go straight to the shower clean
yourself up put your clothes in the
washer rub the washer put on some clean
clothes and now let's start treating
those plants like they're lightly
infested we need to keep the infestation
down hopefully we got rid of the most of
the bugs but they could still be there
so the big plants are gone the babies
are growing much easier to treat
hopefully we can preserve our genetics
that way all right let me make sure I've
gotten all of the notes cuz I was going
quite fast because there's a lot that I
wanted to cover I feel like I did a
pretty decent job of good job here of
talking about how to eradicate pests the
most important thing here is don't bring
a knife to a gunfight if you're fighting
spidermites attack spidermites if you're
attacking thrips attack thrips don't
just buy whatever pesticide was on the
shelf that is not setting yourself up
for Success that is not how we win
that's not how we do it in the IE Army
get the right [ __ ] let's win this battle
all right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of this podcast like I said
before if I read your message here on
this podcast you do win a free pack of
iy genetics premium seeds so my friend
x-ray toker please do send me your
address so I can get you a free pack of
Premium seeds if I did not read your
message on this episode please don't be
discouraged I've got a giant pile of
emails here in front of me and I do plan
on continuing reading them on future
episodes all right my voice is running
out I think that's all I've got make
sure you check out the patreon campaign
at
patreon.com fromy yourheart if you have
any questions that are not grow
questions you can send me your questions
Corrections comments and concerns to
grow fromy yourheart hotmail.com
anything else you could possibly need is
on iy genetics or
iirc. guys my voice is done I'm getting
out of here I want to give a big shout
out to my buddy Dave's black eye and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
big up yourself every time R the
[Music]
[Applause]
Jeff
[Music]
time to take another Dam grab your pie
in and I go find the B
is in the lab sit back
relax