[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] yeah welcome to the podcast
everybody I'm your host rosta Jeff this
is episode 820 of the from your heart
podcast I've got a great show lined up
for us in this episode I'm going to give
away free seeds that's right I'm going
to give away free iy genetics premium
seeds hang out we'll talk more about the
free seeds later in this episode before
we get too far I do want to let you know
that iir is back online that's right I
direct.com is back online if you're
looking for fresh iy genetics iir is the
place also the Black Friday sale has
started early on IR
redirect.sh that the Black Friday sale
has begun if you're part of the
MailChimp newsletter you've gotten a
notice if you're not part of the
newsletter or the patreon now is the
time to sign up to do that go to my
website IR genetics.com there will be a
spot at the bottom of the page to sign
up to the newsletter also a link to the
patreon if you're a member of the
patreon this month and you contributed
$25 or more this month you did get a
coupon code for one free pack of seeds
if you contributed $50 or more on
patreon this month you got two coupon
codes for two free packs of iy genetics
premium seeds make sure you guys check
out the mailing list and
patreon.com SLG fromy yourheart to get
signed up that was a lot of information
right there real quick uh this month the
free you getting two free packs of seeds
this month and iir the two free packs of
seeds this month our gorilla goat and
blueberry butcher next month it will be
two different packs so make sure you do
join the patreon campaign wow that was a
lot of stuff to say all right now that
we made it through that mouthful I want
to give a big shout out to my friends at
the dude grow show that's right I was on
the dude grow show uh the show is
recorded Monday uh big shout out to
Scotty reel and the dude and of course
to my buddy Gro uh and also to the
entire panel we did a dude grows panel
show it was myself Michigan Matt and hot
rod big shout out to my new friend
Michigan Matt and my buddy hot rod for
being on the show with us uh we talked a
lot about cannabis cultivation I feel
like it was a very informative show so
if you're not already watching the dude
grow show most of you already are if
you're not already watching go give my
friends a follow at the dude grow show
make sure you watch the episode where I
was on the show and leave some comments
let them know how much you enjoy me on
the show so that they will invite me
back big fist bump big shout out to the
entire dgc big shout out to dude big
shout out to Scotty big love to Gro much
love to all of you also I hope to see
you guys at the dude grows cup that's
right June 4 June 1st in leaport
Colorado that's easier to say than it
looks June 1st in Lort Colorado it is
the dgc Growers Cup come hang out I will
be there it will be a good time we're
just talking about it this is an early
heads up we will do a lot more
advertising in the future all right
where do we want to go from there I
think I've covered all of the business
iir is back Black Friday sale also if
you are looking for a gift certificate
for I redirect that's right ladies I was
talking to your man he said he wanted iy
genetic seeds for Christmas he said you
might not know what to get him the easy
way to do it is to send me an email and
let me know that you would like to
purchase a gift certificate for I
redirect it is really easy there are
many any ways to email me send me an
email I recommend rosted Jeff IR
genetics.com put in the subject line put
in gift certificate that way I'll know
exactly what you need uh then I can
respond to you and let you know how we
can get you a gift certificate for your
significant other for the holidays or if
you just want one for yourself uh
whatever you need we can now do a gift
certificate send me an email we will get
that taken care of I think I covered all
the important notes we have let's jump
into the email portion of today's
podcast I've got a lot of great emails
here in front of me now with the the
start of the show I did say I was going
to give away free seeds here is how you
can win free seeds from listening to the
podcast if you go to my website iy
genetics.com there's a tab that says
growel if you click on that grow help
tab we will ask you a few questions at
the bottom you're able to type in a
little paragraph about your grow problem
let us know what's going on in your
garden if I read your question here on
the podcast I will send you a coupon for
a free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
on iir so go to IR iy genetics or IR
direct.com there's a growel tab on both
of those websites click on that tab send
me your grow question if I do read your
grow question here on the show you win
free seeds it's that easy today's first
question came from my new friend Matt
and it goes a lot like this it says hey
rosta Jeff hey Matt good to meet you bro
the question says I hope you and yours
are well everything is excellent thank
you for the well wishes I hope
everything is well for your family and
yourself and your garden the message
says you've already answered one of my
questions before unfortunately I have
not been able to to pop the free seeds
you sent me oh so I guess I will send
you a coupon for another free pack but I
should probably say that from now on
only one pack per person or some [ __ ]
like that but I never said that so you
get another pack bro uh and rules are
made to be broken so sneak them in if I
read your [ __ ] twice and I don't realize
it then you'll win free seeds again uh
thanks for being honest it goes on it
says my question is as follows if a
longer flowering time plant is
pollinated do those seeds also take
longer to reach maturity in your
experience take care from Matt hey Matt
this is a really great question the
short answer is no most of the time
seeds take around 6 to 8 weeks to be
done from the time they're pollinated
till the time you can Harvest them there
are a few things uh that can speed or
slow that down or speed it up or slow
that down but in most cases you're
looking about 6 to 8 weeks for seeds the
thing is that some of those longer
flowering plants will take longer to be
ready for pollen that is the caveat with
those plants not all plants want pollen
at the same time so a plant that takes
longer to finish quite often we'll want
that pollen later in its flowering cycle
so the seeds uh themselves are not going
to take longer to finish but it may be
longer before that plant is ready for
the pollen itself two good examples in
my garden that I've have used quite
often are the Platinum Tangi female and
the Strawberry Fields female I breed
with both of those the Platinum Tangi
makes of course the orange gasm and
makes sunkiss uh it's making some other
stuff in the near future here it also
made the Michelangelo on the other hand
we've got the strawberry the strawberry
fields which makes the strawberry
Starburst that makes the Raphael that
one also makes the red pill it makes a
bunch of great stuff so both of those
plants I use in the breeding project um
I've done a bunch of great things with
both of those but what I have learned is
that the Platinum Tangi plant wants
pollen uh so one thing where I should
start I guess the Platinum Tangi plant
finishes much sooner than the Strawberry
Fields plant does in a normal flower
room by about 7 to 10 days depending on
the conditions the environment the feed
I've seen it as much as 7 to 10 days
difference in flowering in time
something I've definitely noticed as
well is a 7 to 14 day difference in Peak
pollination times of those plants those
are just two plants in my room that are
very common that I breed with a lot now
imagine the variance within all the
plants that I work with and have worked
with uh what I've noticed is so your
question is do the seeds take longer if
the cultivar takes longer the answer to
that is no but the part I'm talking
about now is sometimes certain plants
will take much longer to be ready for
the pollen most plants it's about like
day 23 to 32 you got about a 10-day real
Prime window but with some of them the
longer finishing plants it could be day
27 to day 37 I guess would be that nice
10day window some of them actually they
give you like a 3 week flowering window
where you can pollinate them and the
pistols are super ripe if it's a longer
flowering phenotype or a cultivar so uh
the question was do the seeds take
longer no but sometimes it takes longer
for the female plant to be ready to
accept that pollen now my friend Matt
that is a really great question I do
appreciate that it looks like I have got
your email address here as long as
that's an underscore I've got all the
info I need to send you a coupon code
for a gift certificate for iy direct.com
so you can grab that free pack of seeds
my friend by the time this episode comes
out if you have not found that coupon
code please do check your spam email
because many of those coupon codes do go
to the spam all right Matt thank you for
the great question let's keep this show
moving we've got some good momentum all
right this next question came from my
new friend Q congratulations Q you have
won a gift certificate for a free pack
of seeds on
edirect make sure you check your email
for that gift certificate also make sure
you check the Spam if you have not found
it also if you don't get that send me an
email cuz I want to make sure there's no
glitches in my Matrix the question goes
a lot like this it says hello roster
Jeff hello Q good to meet you dude it
says my question is more related to iy
genetics website than my grow at the
moment you know I've been expecting this
question I've been waiting for this I am
prepared let's talk about this right now
it says I was looking on the iy website
for the descriptions histories and
lineages of the seeds and I have found
that those are no longer there was this
something that had to change to keep iir
online um kind of yes honestly I'm doing
a more updating so you may have noticed
that a little while back iir disappeared
uh I'll talk more about why I redirect
disappeared and how I rectified that
situation on a patreon episode in the
near future stay tuned I'll let you know
when I record that I'll let you know
when that's coming out but yes I
redirect did have to shut down for a
brief moment as I was working on getting
iy direct repaired and rebuilt and back
online I realized there were a lot of
other things that needed to be done to I
genetics.com I focused at that point on
getting iy direct back online we got
that one back it is up and running now I
genetics is under construction but I've
gotten most of the website back up in a
satisfying form but I do have to work on
the genetics page the genetics page is
currently under construction there are
approximately or were approximately
somewhere between 100 and 120 strains on
that website I am updating every
description by myself by hand one at a
time it is taking a little bit longer
than I had anticipated to do that I'm
doing it myself I don't have a helper
helping me with that I have to type in
Aroma flavor flowering time morphology
uh grow tips um what else smoke reports
a bunch of things like that I'm going
through my notes and finding all those
things compiling those and making a nice
new updated genetics website for you so
the strain page will be back also there
will be a patreon podcast I mentioned
this I'll do a patreon podcast about
what happened with iir why it had to
disappear how it came back why iy
genetics is set up the way that it is
now I will talk about that some of you
are going to ask about some of the new
stickers you're getting on your packages
all of that will be covered on the
patreon episode so if you're not already
on the patreon make sure you check out
patreon.com fromy yourheart of course
I'll let you know when it comes out so
you don't sign up for patreon for a
bunch of months and don't see the
episode I'm honestly still catching up
trying to do the website work get
getting my uh feet back under me after I
redirect got closed down and honestly
updating those website descriptions
takes much longer than I had anticipated
uh I try to do so many at one time once
I've got them all up there we'll go
ahead and relaunch that page it's under
construction let me continue uh also I
was ready for that question so thank you
for asking I've been wanting to explain
a little bit it does go on it says I
love the show and the seeds you make I'm
running lemon Jeffrey and New Town
currently while getting Jack the Ripper
number five started for the dgc cup bro
bring the lemon Jeffrey uh bring the
nuke town bring the Jack the Ripper
bring it all to the dgc cup cannot wait
to see you there cannot wait to smoke
some of your product cannot wait to
shake your hand bro cannot wait to high
five you when we are on the podium
winning the dgc cup together he wraps it
up with I hope to hear from you but if
not I understand you're a busy man keep
it real and spread the love dude I'm
glad I was able to answer your question
thank you for getting me hyped up about
the dgc cup also make sure you check
that email once again for that free
coupon for that free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com all right I've got one more
quick message here in front of me we're
going to burn through this one this one
came from the growel tab on iry
genetics.com that means that my friend
Minnesota Joe is going to get a coupon
code for a free pack of iy genetics
premium seeds off of iy direct.com where
we are currently hosting a Black Friday
sale make sure you check it out Black
Friday pricing on the entire website uh
there's a lot of good stuff up there
grab your orange gasm get the lemon Jeff
free uh there are packs of Inspector
Royale up there for 10 bucks go check it
out it's a three pack to be honest with
you but three seeds for 10 bucks go grab
them I
redirect.sh out to everybody in M
Minnesota for working on the Cannabis
legalization movement been sending a lot
of seeds that way the question says I
have been a listener for several years
now and I love all of the knowledge and
positive vibes that you give to the
community bro there's so many key words
in there love knowledge Positive Vibes
and Community thank you for noticing all
of that brother I appreciate that it
says I'm currently running both your
orange gasm and lemon Jeffy strains and
they are looking like absolute fire bro
if you've got a good lineup right there
the LJ and the OG are great together two
of my favorites I put my name on one of
them and the other one is my best seller
good work Crush those together it says I
had a question about finishing a plant
in flow that's a good question it goes
on it says I know there are several
products in the market to help finish a
plant and I have several different
products but I'm not sure which one I
should use and if I can combine products
then he goes on to list the products so
what they're asking about is which
products to use for finishing the plants
there a lot of so there are some
products that are sold as just plant
finishers there are products that are
sold as flushing agents and pl products
that are supposed that's harder to say
than it looks you guys put all those
peas those Peter Piper sold a product
for flushing purple plants uh try to say
that in a row bro but um there are
products that they sell to help you
flush your plants there are products
that they sell to help the plants finish
there are many products available uh
many of them are unnecessary there is
one that I do recommend that is actually
on this list so we are going to talk
about some of the products that my
friend has they were kind enough to
include a list with the message and it
goes like this it says I have unsulfured
molasses you don't need that toward the
finishing stage of the plants uh that is
more to feed the microbes at this point
you've got a good microb colony in that
rizosphere you can probably cut out the
unsulfured molasses the end of the grow
it says I've got can ofme I would assume
that's an enzyme product um I would use
that sparingly toward the end of flour
you don't need a whole bunch of enzymes
but keep a little bit of in that in
there just to keep cleaning up that root
Zone and if you're running Hydro
definitely continue to use that then it
also says I have a flushing agent called
florac clean uh I don't think you need
floral clean I don't think a flushing
agent like that is necessary at all uh
most of the time that is just an agent
that will get in there and break up the
salts that are bound into your plant
help those uh loosen up from the
rizosphere and help you clean out the
rizosphere if you were watering properly
getting runoff not overfeeding I don't
think that's necessary so you could
probably skip the floral clean unless
you really want to use it if you do use
that uh use as directed for your last
two maybe three waterings at the most uh
then it says I've got New Millennium
winter frost uh I strongly recommend
using winter frost as recommended on the
bottle do it just like it says uh the
folks at winter frost are freaking
genius are the folks at New Millennium
winter frost is a great bottle I
recommend using that exactly as
recommended so use your nutrients up
until the day uh that you decide to use
the winter frost use the winter frost
and then follow those instructions so if
you're finishing with your products that
you've got that's what I would recommend
then it says here's the part where I
really wanted to talk I just wanted to
answer the question so I could talk
about this part it says I currently grow
Sanic and then [ __ ] buzzers went off
my head when in my head when you said
Sanic using the ban Botanicare nutrients
and a promix ocean Forest 50/50 soil mix
that's a nice mix bro Botanicare
nutrients uh promix ocean Forest that
sounds nice nice and fluffy you got some
irration in there uh should I be using
one of these products over the other
yeah we talked about that what order uh
thanks for all you do one love from
Minnesota big shout out to my boys in
Minnesota and gals in Minnesota big
shout out to my new friend Minnesota Joe
but here's what I want to uh what I want
to Ramble On to wrap up the show here
you said the word Sanic um I think I
know who that comes from and I got
nothing but love and respect for all of
my cultivation Community uh you're my
friend even I'm going to even though I'm
going to say Sanic is not a thing we've
got to stop saying Sanic Sanic is like
saying I'm vegan but I eat steak on
Thursday that means you're not vegan
organic means it is made up of organic
elements there is no nonorganic thing in
your mixture right but when you add
something that's not organic guess what
you just did you wiped out you erased
the word organic you can't say it
anymore so Sanic dude that's driving me
crazy just say I used a mixture of
bottled nutrients or just don't say
Sanic just don't say that that's the
best way I could put it is to say uh I'm
sober but I do heroin on Friday that's
what Sanic sounds like to me like it's
not it's just not that's my rant that's
my [ __ ] that's my complaint for this
week some of us have pet peeves some of
us have a podcast where we get to
[ __ ] talk about it shout out you guys
send me your grow room or grow Community
Pet Peeves maybe I'll read those on the
podcast I'll try to keep it positive but
I will do it in a funny light if you've
got some funny grow peeves send those to
me uh you can do those on the growel tab
that way you've got a chance to win free
seeds as well uh go to the growel tab
let me know what your grow room or grow
Community Pet Peeves are what drives you
crazy what is your version of Sanic and
once again if you do send me your pet
peeve at the growel tab and I read it
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds on
idirect decom and when you get those
coupon codes uh they basically work like
a gift certificate and you can still use
all the uh the coupon codes codes the
discount codes that come along with that
if you've got a discount code if you're
a patreon member and you get a a gift
certificate coupon code all the other
codes will still work with that so
you're going to get the fat hookups send
me those pet peeves if I read it here
free seeds once again I'm going to try
to keep it funny and keep it
light-hearted if I do it but send me
those I think it will be fun all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends and foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns make
sure you reach out my email is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com once again
if you have those growel questions go to
my website iry genetics.com click on
that growel tab that way you qualify for
the free seeds that is the only way to
get the free seeds is using the growel
tab send those growroom pet peeves I
look forward to it anything else you
could possibly need is on the website IR
genetics.com there's a link to I
redirect you can get the seeds there's a
link to the patreon there's a link to
the Discord server there come hang out
on the Discord once again everything you
could possibly imagine except the
genetics I apologize those are coming I
read genetics.com all right that's all
I've got for you for this week I'll be
back in another week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my friend blue kiss and until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
big up yourself every time R the
[Music]
[Applause]
Jeff
[Music]
[Applause]
time to take another Dam grab your p in
and I go about the B
is in the lab sit back
relax