if you have been freaking out for a
couple of days because you can't figure
out why your grow lights are on a
different schedule after daylight
savings time go ahead and click
subscribe Rost and Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode 821
of the grow fromy heart podcast I've got
a great episode lined up for us in this
episode I'm going to give away free
seeds that's right hang out we'll talk
more about the free seeds later in this
episode I do want to remind you that
idirect decom is back online I want to
thank everybody for the great success
with the Black Friday sale at edirect
decom also Christmas is coming up I want
to remind you that gift certificates are
available for edirect decom if you need
a gift certificate please send me an
email with the word gift certificate in
the subject line I will tell you all
about how to get a gift certificate at
iy direct.com also don't forget that
patreon contributors do get free seeds
if you contribute $25 in the month of
December to the patreon campaign you
will receive a coupon code for one free
pack of seeds from iy direct if you
contribute $50 or more in the month of
December to patreon you will receive two
coupon codes for free packs of seeds and
a coupon code for discounted pricing on
the entire website at edirect
docomo make sure you check out
patreon.com from yourart I try to switch
up the seeds that I offer every month so
I don't do any repeats in the month of
December the free seeds will be a free
five pack of fist bump for the $25 level
and the $30 level will receive a free
10pack of Redline seeds from edirect
decom all right I think that covers up
most of to the business also I want to
send a big shout out to my friends at
the dude grow show that's right I want
to send a big thank you shout out to the
dude big shout out to Scotty re of
course a big shout out to Gro uh big
shout out to everybody behind the scenes
at the dude grow show I've been on the
dude grow show Monday hangout show I
think for the past four weeks in a row
and it has been a great time a great
hangout I get a lot of room to talk I
get a lot of time to advertise and it's
fun just hanging out with the boys uh
they build a really nice panel show the
dude and Scotty are on there but they
also invite a couple of cool guests uh
recently we had jiren as a guest we also
had uh Michigan Matt was a guest on One
show our friend hot rod was a guest I'm
sure I'm leaving out some people but
there have been a lot of great guests on
the dude grow show uh so shout out to
the dude grow show for having me on also
make sure you mark your calendar for the
dude grows Growers cup June 1st in Fort
Collins Colorado that's right the dude
grows cup returns to Fort Collins
Colorado on June 1st team iy genetics
will be there all of the dude grow crew
will be there make sure sure you are
there as well make sure you check out
dgc cup.com for all the links and
details that you may need to attend and
participate in the event I look forward
to seeing you you there last year was a
great time all right we made it through
that part what do we need to do next
recently I told you guys about an app on
my iPhone called the photon app I use it
as a light meter a par meter for my grow
space I'm able to measure how much light
I am actually giving the plants instead
of going it looks bright dude I actually
have some sort of a meter a measuring
device to show me a quantifiable number
on a screen that says they're getting
this much light and it feels pretty
accurate a lot of people have given this
app this device a lot of good Praise on
the App Store so recently the app has
offered a new product called a diffuser
previously we've been using a piece of
paper folded into a loop with a piece of
paper on it and we're putting that over
the camera of our phone to use that as a
light diffuser it does not give you 100%
accurate readings it is close it is good
enough it gives you a range to kind of
try to be in if you repeat this the test
every time the same way then you will
get repeatable results you can kind of
say it works good here it works good
here it works at 13 or 23 real well you
can make notes that way but they've put
out their own diffuser it is now
available through the app they do not
pay me to say this this is not
advertising this is just to let you know
I mentioned this app to you and now
there is a product that goes along with
the app called the diffuser that goes
over your camera phone that properly
diffuses the light so that you can get
an accurate reading it was actually made
for your phone for this app uh it gets
really good reviews uh the app gets even
better reviews now that we are using the
diffuser from the company that makes the
app so if you're using the photon app
there is now a new product you can add
to it uh I think if you open up the
photon app there's a thing on the right
top right or top left a little bar thing
you can click on there it will open up
the store you can buy the new diffuser
up your game set yourself up for Success
once again they don't pay me to say this
I just know that light meters are very
expensive and they are very useful uh we
found basically a free version you got
to pay about four to six bucks for the
upgrade and then I think the new piece
is about 20 $25 30 bucks for a really
accurate light meter is unbeatable go
look for one at a store they are quite
expensive all right I think I have
covered all of the uh business part of
the podcast let's work our way into the
fun part of the grow from your heart
podcast in a previous episode I did
mention some of my grower pet peeves I
did mention that the word s it kind of
drives me nuts I did write down another
pet peeve for today's podcast um I'm
trying to be light-hearted about this
but this is stuff that sometimes when I
walk into a grow it just drives me
freaking nuts uh something I don't like
to see anymore I think we have evolved
past and I am still guilty of this up
until recently I don't like bamboo
sticks in the grow especially bamboo
sticks that are uncovered if you just
got that Pokey stick popping up out of
the end of a pot it's probably perfect
height for me to either bend over and
poke it in my eye or kneel down to look
at the pl plant and as I'm looking it
goes right in the eyeball I don't like
Pokey sticks in the grow room I know it
seems simple it seems like a a small
thing to be bothered by but they're
dangerous and also those bamboo sticks
are uh beautiful vectors for a place for
a bug to hide it's a perfect spot for uh
pathogen just to chill down inside of
there's nooks and crannies and crevices
uh bug eggs little pieces of mold all
kinds of weird [ __ ] could be down in
there and they're hard to sanitize and
hard to clean so I don't like the sticks
if you're going to do the sticks if you
insist to get uh some of the new sticks
that are coated in the green [ __ ] so
that you can clean them uh you can
sanitize those more regularly and if you
insist on using the sticks please let's
put something on top of it I know a
tennis ball looks really wonky in your
grow room but so does Noah's Arc worth
of sticks popping up out of that place
as well so let's shy away from using too
many sticks in there uh and if we're
going to use so many sticks let's put
something at the top so that we don't
poke our precious eyes be more careful
please I don't want to poke my eye while
I'm working in yor grow while I'm there
doing a consultation while I'm there
doing a visit an inspection a photo
shoot just trolling and looking around I
don't want to get poked you don't want
me to get poked either you don't want to
poke yourself let's clean up get some of
those sticks out of there let's use
tomato cages let's use trellis let's use
something different like I said if you
insist on using a stick get some of
those Green Garden steaks they're much
better much more reliable you can
sanitize them and then put a flag or
some tape or some [ __ ] on the top of it
so that I don't poke my precious eyes so
those sticks are going to be my pet
peeve for the week ladies and gentlemen
I don't want to be the only one bitching
and complaining please send me your grow
room or even cannabis culture pet peeves
what drives you crazy what makes you
cringe when it comes to somebody's grow
room it could be your grow room it could
be somebody else's it could be a
commercial facility let it out vent let
me know your pet peeve maybe I'll read
it here on the show like I said before
if I read your pet peeve here on this
podcast you yeah you you could win a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
that's right if I read your pet peeve
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of Premium
seeds from iy direct.com all right we
have made it through all of the
advertising we've made it through the
peeves now let's get to everybody's
favorite portion of the grow from your
heart podcast of course that is the
question and answer part of the show I
like to answer people's questions that
come in through the growel tab on my
website that's right at iry genetics.com
there's a tab on the top that says
questions if you click on that tab we
give you the opportunity to type in your
grow question send me your grow
questions if I read your grow question
from the growel tab here on this podcast
guess what that means once again you win
a free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
our first question for today's podcast
came from my friend to the roach what's
up bro I haven't heard from you in a
minute hope you are well hope everything
is iy you my friend have won a free pack
of iy genetics premium seeds I will send
you a gift certificate for iy direct you
can pick out whatever you want it will
come via your email it looks like I
should have your email here I will find
it if I don't There It Is I've got your
email bro so I will be able to send you
that gift card make sure you check your
spam uh if you don't have a gift card
from me by the time this episode comes
out check your spam or reach out let me
know that you did not get it anyway I'm
rambling to the roach sent a message and
it goes a lot like this that says hello
rasted Jeff what's up my buddy roach
good to hear from you bro it says I hope
you are doing well and enjoying your
holiday season watching the dude grow
show your panel that you were featured
on and you brought up Leaf to kellex
ratio I believe this isn't really talked
about enough for beginner Growers out
there could you go more in depth and
breaking down what this is what to look
for and the pros and cons of such ratio
show examples okay you're asking for
examples I'm not going to show stuff but
I'll talk about it uh shout out to my
state of Ohio for finally taking it into
our hands and passing recreational
cannabis for the people I'm going to
talk about that part first yes big shout
out to the state of Ohio for finally
legalizing cannabis uh and the part that
he said was taking it into our own hands
uh yes um you have got to do it the
powers that be the politicians the city
council they're not on your side when it
comes to legalizing cannabis most of
those types of people don't agree
support or condone the legalization of
recreational or medical cannabis so
you've got to sway your Council people
whoever they are whatever level of it is
of Congress of city council wherever it
is whatever level you can AFF it is up
to you to make those changes nobody else
is going to make those changes for you
so shout out to the people of Ohio for
like my friend said taking it into their
own hands and passing recreational
Cannabis recently A friend of mine was
like y Ross to Jeff I want to open up a
weed business in my state it recently
legalized uh but I've got to wait to see
what they do with the rules and I
politely said brother don't wait to see
what they do with the rules make the
rules go to the City Council meetings go
to the zoning meetings be as involved as
you can in the legalization movement in
your area when it comes time to make the
rules be involved in that rule making
process be involved that way you can
make good rules we need people on our
team on our side in that room setting
the rules if not they're going to say
you're allowed to have one gram of
marijuana because one gram you can smoke
that for five days and it's worth $7,000
you shouldn't have any more in your
possession they should say you can have
one plant you can only grow one plant
for 5 years because one plant produces
32 pounds and costs 100 gallons of water
to produce they're going to say a bunch
of wonky [ __ ] they need Growers they
need consumers they need medical
patients they need recreational
consumers all in that room to make the
proper decisions and rules regarding the
recreational Andor uh medical cannabis
in your area when it comes to
legalization also when it comes time
don't forget to put in somewhere to
smoke that's the part we kind of [ __ ]
ourselves on here in Colorado you can
grow as much as you can possibly produce
you can buy plenty of cannabis on every
corner in Colorado but the thing you
cannot do is safely consume that
cannabis anywhere except the safety of
your home hotels won't let you smoke a
lot of airbnbs won't let you smoke you
definitely are not allowed to smoke in
your car I'm not saying it doesn't
happen but it is illegal you're not
supposed to smoke at the park it is
definitely illegal to smoke at the State
Park not the skate park both probably
but any state park any federal land any
federal area that is illegal to possess
and or consume your cannabis on Federal
Land which is all of the state parks
which includes Red Rocks which I know
that sounds crazy but that is federal
land it is illegal to consume there well
we did not do is give oursel a safe
place and a safe way to consume that
cannabis a lot of the states that came
after us New York if you can smoke a
cigarette there you can smoke cannabis
there is the rule in New York and that's
all kinds of places in New York make
sure you include some sort of safe
consumption area in your legislation
when you were writing new cannabis rules
all right I give a big shout out to Ohio
let's answer the actual question here
that came from my friend we got super
rambling on this one um the question
here is let's talk about Leaf to Cal
ratio what does that mean I mentioned
that on a podcast uh what are leaves we
all know what leaves are right leaves
are the leafy part hanging off of your
plants what are cxes that's basically
the bud formation the part that builds
the bud when you break the bud apart
those little popcorns little circles
those are your cxes your bra um you want
a lot of those that's what builds the
flowers it's just a bunch of little cxes
stacking on topping of each other making
a big giant flower cluster is basically
what the buds are we want a lot of cxes
a lot of BRS
um so when you look at some weed you'll
see we're just going to say that the bud
is uh what's that that's about 16 in
tall right you got a 16inch tall Bud a
lot of times you're going to see buds
with a leaf here a leaf here a leaf here
a leaf here a leaf here a leaf here
that's a high Leaf to calx ratio if it's
if it looks furry like a Shaggy Dog if
it's a pain in the ass to trim that's
probably considered a high Cal or no I'm
saying that backwards that is a high
Leaf to calx ratio there's a lot of leaf
on there compared to how much consumable
bud is going to be on that plant by the
time you're done so basically what this
says is how hard or easy is that plant
to trim that's the uh the easy way of
saying that uh Leaf to calx ratio is
just the fancy way of saying how many
leaves are on that plant and how hard
will that plant be to trim you'll notice
some of the Girl Scout cookies crosses
uh the old school GSC the Girl Scout
cookies The Thin Mint The Forum cut all
that stuff it made plants with giant
pedals real long pedals on the leaves
and then a lot of leaf up and down the
bud not a lot of Sugar Leaf on there if
you were a hom grower if you were kind
of a lazy grower if you were on your own
and you didn't want to trim all that
[ __ ] off you didn't really have to
because all those leaves on there were
super Frosty and they're just real
little so it was real easy with the Girl
Scout cookies to go and break off all
those bigger leaves and then just give
it a medium trim and you're ready to go
because it had a low Leaf High Kix ratio
there was less Leaf more calx very easy
for it to trim in that situation some
stuff that comes from the iy genetic
line that has got the low leaf and a
high calx ratio would be a lot of the
stuff from the Jack the Ripper crosses I
made uh Jack Tripper will do it for you
uh the blueberry butcher will do it for
you uh the Jack Tripper stands out in
that category quite well though you'll
see some photos I've posted or just big
old long buds with like six leaves
coming out of it at the end of harvest
that's really easy to trim you don't
have to pay the trim crew for as many
hours uh it's not as much work not as
much processing time and the product is
still top shelf so that's a good way to
save yourself a half of a step and
possibly a few bucks if you're paying a
trim crew or trim people that is money
you can keep in your pocket uh that's a
profit already that you've already made
before you even spent it so my friend I
hope I covered that for you that is
basically how much Leaf is on that plant
based on the size of the bud that
dictates kind of how hard or how long it
is going to take to trim that plant uh
let you kind of prepare set yourself up
for success in your grow if you're
somebody that totally hates trimming you
probably want plants with with a lot
more calic and very little leaf ratio
all right my buddy to the roach I think
I answered that question quite well you
my dude are going to get a gift
certificate for a free pack of seeds for
redirect.sh all right podcast world
let's keep this party moving I do have
another great question here this one
came from my new friend Pacific Josh
Josh I'm pretty sure I met you on
Discord briefly recently thanks for
coming and hanging out you are
definitely invited back come back around
also everybody out there you guys are
all welcome and invited to the I Army
Discord server uh there should be a link
in the show notes or the video
description if it is not there please
reach out I will get you an updated link
to the Discord server a lot of great
things happen in the Discord server
there's a general chat where people just
have a general chat we talk about life
we hang out there's also a lot of grow
talk happening there are tabs for every
strain that I have well I can't say
every strain but most of the strains
that are available and current that
people know about from IR genetics
they're all listed on the side of the
Discord server if you want to see
pictures if you want some info if you
want some details on a specific strain
you can go there and click on that you
can learn a lot if you're going to grow
a strain you want info if you're
thinking about growing it a lot of
details can be found on the Discord
server also uh you can post a question
in the general chat or in any category
that you feel is appropriate and a lot
of my friends and myself there will
answer those questions for you then my
favorite part is the smoker Lounge the
smoker Lounge is a live interactive chat
uh it's just like any other chat it's
kind of like a zoom chat or a what's the
other one I was on streamyard it's a lot
like a FaceTime except there's a lot of
people there sometimes there's 10 or 12
people hanging out sometimes there's
only two or three of us uh you can turn
on your camera and hang out with us if
you want or you can leave the camera off
just go on voice chat you're able to
hang out and have a conversation with
myself uh quite often my buddy Billy
bong is there uh my buddy Dave is there
quite often blue kiss is hanging out
there's a great crew that's always
hanging out there uh there's a morning
crew and afternoon crew a nighttime crew
and a late night crew uh just rotates
different people throughout the day
throughout the night uh shout out to
lollipop John big up to my buddy TPS a
lot of great people in there all day
long so if you want someone to come hang
out with and talk about growing ganja or
maybe play video games with us or or a
lot of times the boys go and play VR
games there's a lot of fun stuff
happening on the iy Army Discord pop in
hang out with us also a lot of exclusive
deals and a lot of heads up happen on
the IE Army Discord anyway my friend I
am rambling let me get focused and
answer your actual question we haven't
even gotten to that part by the way my
buddy Pacific Josh you my dude went a
free pack of iy genetic seeds uh from iy
direct.com you will receive a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds make sure
you check your email like I've said
before by the time this episode comes
out if you have not received your gift
certificate please do check your spam
and then reach out if you have not found
that message the question does go a
little bit like this it says yo rosted
Jeff my humidity and my drying area
suddenly spiked downward while I was
away for Thanksgiving so we had a Fresh
Harvest it sounds like that outdoor
Harvest was hanging up my dude went away
for Thanksgiving to go get some turkey
and mashed potatoes and while he was
away the humidity has plummeted in the
dry and cure area now it says my buds
are pretty crumbly at this point now my
advice uh may work for you I don't know
what you mean by crumbly are they
[ __ ] Dusty are they falling apart or
are they dry and you're exaggerating I
hope they're real dry and you are
exaggerating being a drama queen about
this it says is there anything I can do
to save this dry and cure um I've got a
couple of answers my best bet for you is
I don't know how much weed you've got I
don't know how much product there is if
you can put it in big sterlite bins um I
think they're 30 qu sterlite bins
they're about this wide uh can you see
that on camera I'll try not to edit that
out uh they're about uh 2 and a half
maybe 3 feet wide uh they're about 20 in
tall maybe 20 in deepish I think that's
the right dimensions but I would put as
much of the flow as you can into those
bins I don't know how much you've got
but put in the appropriate size bin and
then I would find if you've hopefully
got more plants growing use some fresh
wet leaves from a current crop just grab
some of those leaves chop them off the
plant and throw them right in that bin
less than you think you need I've done
this before you don't need as many fresh
leaves as you may assume to reconstitute
rehydrate some dried up plants so fresh
leaves would be my first bet if that is
not an option maybe some of those BEDA
packs or something similar after that
you're going to have to try something
extreme and I don't want to make any
recommendations to help you ruin the
crop at that point possibly if it's real
dry maybe you can just make some
concentrates or something out of it I
know everybody prefers that fresh frozen
but it's way too late for that what
you're going to do right maybe at this
point you can make some uh some sort of
concentrate a a lot of times back in the
day dry crumbly product would become uh
some sort of B I'm not going to tell you
to break the law or do anything crazy
but a lot of people back in the day
would make BHO show out of this product
I don't know if you know how to do that
I'm not going to recommend you do that
be safe don't hurt yourself legal legal
disclaimer insert here all right so uh
the humidity dropped your plants are
real crispy I would say seal them up
into a container uh put some fresh ganja
leaves in there hopefully you have some
fresh leaves I don't know what the
chances of that are I don't know if
you're a Perpetual grower I don't know
if this was an outdoor crop and it's all
gone uh but leaves would be my first bet
then a BEDA pack or something similar
like that and then after that you're
going to have to find another way
someone probably at this point is going
to tell you to put like a wet paper
towel or something in there that sounds
[ __ ] terrible but it probably will
work also do you have a humidifier maybe
you can hang them in a room with a
humidifier I really don't want to do
that that just sounds like you're going
to cause more problems so uh I would try
the leaves I would try the Bova packs
and then after that I would think about
making concentrates I hope you're able
to save the Harvest I hope you learned
your lesson I know you are not the only
one facing uh these uh trials and
tribulations a lot of people had
struggles out out there with that
outdoor Harvest you guys um this goes
back to something I say a lot set
yourself up for Success we know Harvest
is coming um you knew Harvest was coming
you knew you knew Thanksgiving was
coming uh you could have prepped for
this you probably could have prepared
for this uh you said the humidity
dropped guess what would have fixed this
a humid of fire and you had nine weeks
of flow 3 weeks of [ __ ] veg at least
all to think about that humidifier so
next year you guys set yourself up for
success you're chopping down those big
outdoor harvests so many of my friends
lost like 25 to 50% of their outdoor
because of small human error next year
let's look at those errors and try to
win set yourself up for Success so my
dude Pacific Josh thank you for the
great question I hope I was able to help
you out I do feel for you for having a
dry crispy crop that is never a fun
thing to come home to hopefully we're
able to help you out a little bit in
some way shape or form also I hope the
Thanksgiving dinner and Company was
worth it my bro also you do win a free
pack of iy genetics premium seeds you
will get that coupon code in your email
like I keep saying make sure to check
for your spam if you do not find it
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast if you have made
it this far I do have a reward a
surprise for you if you are shopping on
IR
redirect.sh highir.com that coupon code
is valid through the month of December I
want to say thank you for all the love
and support and thank you for making it
this far into this episode of this
podcast also make sure you guys check
out IR genetics.com everything you could
possibly need is at IR genetics.com
there's a link to the patreon server uh
there's a link to iir there's a there
should be an updated uh link to the
Discord server if that does not work
somebody do please email me because that
link uh Discord changes that link quite
frequently anyway my voice is burning
out it's time for me to get out of here
I'll be back next week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy brewing for turps and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
me Rost the Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
big up yourself every time R the
[Music]
[Applause]
Jeff
[Music]
time to take another D grab your pie in
and I go about the
B is in the lab sit back
relax