[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] yeah welcome back podcast
world I'm your host rosta Jeff this is
episode
822 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a great episode lined up for us
in this episode I'm going to give away
free seeds that's right hang out we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
in the episode I do want to remind you
once again that
redirect.sh details on a gift
certificate send me an email at grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com put the word
gift certificate in the subject line
I'll get back to you and let you know
how to get that gift certificate for IID
direct.com I also want to invite you to
the dude grows Growers cup that's right
the dude grow crew is throwing a party
June 1st just outside of Fort Collins
Colorado join us once again for the dude
grow Growers Cup team iy genetics will
be there the dude grow crew will be
there and I look forward to seeing you
at the dude grows Growers cup make sure
you check out dgc cup.com for all the
information all right I feel like we've
covered all of the business part of
today's podcast let's segue into
something a little bit more fun if
you've been watching the last couple of
episodes I've definitely noticed it
while I've been editing and a few people
have nosed it enough to send in a
message and say hey rosta Jeff what has
happened to the bridge of your nose
that's right uh you may notice I've got
a little Dinger here on the bridge of my
nose it's been there for a couple of
shows uh nothing exciting nothing crazy
happen happened to my nose I was invited
to a virtual starw walk a non-vr
interactive experience and I went to
that experience and they promised us
through all the advertising through the
ticket purchase that it was not VR when
we got there the first thing they did
was put the VR helmet on me and told me
it's not VR they say it wasn't VR cuz it
was a screen and I could see the rest of
the room but it was basically putting on
VR anyway I'm bitching about the wrong
thing uh the person that placed the VR
helmet on my head was an average sized
person and I
6'5 and she reached up and tried to
gently place this VR helmet on my head
but when she let go of it it smacked me
right Square in the [ __ ] nose made my
eyes water a little bit gave me a little
bit of a Dinger so wasn't anything real
exciting that happened to my nose I went
to a non-vr interactive starw walk and
when they put on the VR goggles or the
VR helmet they busted me right in the
bridge of the nose that's really what
happened to my nose so thank you to all
of the people who said hey rosta Jeff
what's going on with your face I do
appreciate your concern my nose will be
just fun fine uh it did hurt for a
little bit but I am over it now thank
you for your care and concern now that
we've got my nose out of the way let's
move into a new section that we've been
doing here on the podcast this is a
section that I call growroom Pet Peeves
a few weeks ago I mentioned something
that really bugged me in a grow room and
I've invited you the listeners the
viewers to rant and vent a little bit
and let me know what drives you nuts in
the grow room what is your grower pet
peeve is there something in your grow
that drives you crazy is there something
you seeing another grow that drives you
crazy perhaps you work in a commercial
cultivation facility and something just
pisses you off there every day and it's
the same thing I encourage you to send
me a message you can do it on YouTube
you can do it through an email you can
even use that grow help tab on iy
genetics.com but send me your growroom
pet peeves let me know what grinds your
gears about cannabis cultivation it
could be about the Cannabis Community
anything cannabis related that just
frustrates you or like I said grinds
your gears or is your grow room or grow
culture pet peeve let me know if I do
share your grow pet peeve here on the
podcast guess what you will win a free
coupon for a free pack of iry genetics
premium seeds at iy direct.com right
here in front of me I do have a growroom
pet peeve this one was sent in by my
friend newbie nugs big shout out to my
dude newbie nugs my friend newbie nugs
please send me your email address so I
can send you a coupon code for a free
pack of iy genetics premium seeds at iy
direct.com because I'm about to read
your pet peeve here on the podcast and
that pet peeve goes just like this it
says yes my pet peeve is pictures of
dirty grow room floors yes if you're
going to grow clean up the floor if
you're going to take a picture clean up
the floor if you're going to post that
picture clean up the floor or at least
edit out that dirty floor what are you
doing bro one of the main things to
think about in growing is cleanliness
cleanliness is how you prevent probably
70% of most of your major problems in
the grow so clean that [ __ ] sh up off
the floor my dude newbie does have more
though he says uh pots on the floor with
no drain pans and runoff stains and
build up yes that is so gross bro if
you're going to put pots on the floor
and water them have something to catch
that run off unless you got a floor
drain and you're doing a bunch and you
got the commercial thing going then
that's a different story hose that down
when you're done but if you're growing
in a hom grow and you're pouring water
into a pot have something to catch that
water after it goes through the pot not
just the floor then don't let those big
new nutrient those big salt Rings build
up on the floor that's just ugly you can
do that if you want but I understand
that that is a pet peeve I'd recommend
not doing that clean that up let's just
be a little more uh have a little more
Pride for the grow room my buddy does
have more to say though he says add a
little soil and leaf for garnish I love
that bro that is why I read your message
cuz I like that tone we're just going to
read it all it says my pet peeve is uh
pictures of dirty floors pots on the
floor no drain pans runoff stains and
buildup and add a little soil and leaf
for garnish it sounds like You' just
made a a recipe for disaster there my
bro uh those are all pet peeves yes
clean that [ __ ] up especially if you're
going to post a photo then it does go on
it says just lighting up the neon sign
for pests and pathogens and problems
even worse is carpet in closet grows oh
man uh yeah carpet in a grow room does I
didn't even know but that's like nails
on a chalkboard just reading that carpet
in the grow room I wouldn't recommend it
I understand some of you guys have to do
what you got to do you got to grow where
you can grow but carpet uh that's such a
great place for so many bugs to hide and
then you're going to spill [ __ ] on that
carpet and ruin it and it's going to get
moldy and funky it's going to get gross
I'm feeling you newbie nugs my dude
please reach out because I owe you a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
all right podcast world let's segue into
the question and answer part of this
podcast I do have a website that website
is iry genetics.com on the top of that
website there is a list of tabs one of
those tabs does say grow help or grow
questions I forgot what it says I didn't
go there today and remember myself but
go to the website if you have a grow
question go to the grow help tab we'll
ask you a couple of preliminary
questions then we give you space to type
in your grow question send me a question
if I read your grow question here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com I've got a great question
here in front of me this one came from
my friend who wants to be called all
mixed up what's up bro it's good to hear
from you it's good to answer your
question on the podcast did not look at
the name before I pulled this uh
question out of the pile I simply read
the question and thought this is
something I could answer now I do see
the name on there my friend I will be
sending you a coupon code for a free
pack of iy genetics premium seeds the
grow question goes just like this it
says yo rosted Jeff what's up all mixed
up good to see you bro it says I was
wondering if potency would go up if I
let my cultivars go longer that's a very
good question it says I pulled lemon
Jeffrey at day 65 and had my flower
tested it tested at
20.1% THC and 2% CBG so that is a sign
that it could have gone longer that CBG
uh may have converted into more THC if
you let that go longer you may be on to
something it goes on though it says I
was wondering if potency would go up
with more days in flour or is it that if
I'm in organic soil and not using pgrs
to push the cultivars to their full
potential thanks as always rosta Jeff
from your friend all mixed up so this is
a great question now a couple of things
come to mind to answer this question but
the first thing I want to talk about is
the Tricom ripeness the main thing that
matters is the ripeness of the tricomes
of these plants did you use
magnification to see how many Amber
tricomes you had on this plant before
harvest my next question would be what
percentage of those tricomes were Amber
did you have 10% 20% 30% amber tricomes
how many of those tricomes were Amber at
Harvest time then we could experiment
from there we could cut some down
earlier we could cut some at the same
time cut some a little bit later dry and
cure them exactly the same then have
them lab tested again it may be cultivar
specific it may be uh it may be
phenotype specific but it all depends on
the ripeness of that plant so going
longer it may have been more potent in
different cannabinoids the THC in there
may have converted to something
different the CBG Also may have had the
opportunity the potential to
convert into THC there are many things
that can happen in just a few more days
of growing that plant so it's all about
those troms were the tricomes ripe at
Harvest Time were they at their Peak
ripeness could they have gone a little
bit longer were they a little bit early
that's what's going to make the main
difference the second thing I would
think about is the dry and cure process
all of your photography on social media
is impressive so I know you're a skilled
grower I know you're a qualified
photographer but after the grow I don't
know what happens after you take those
photos I don't know if you're able to
dry and cure properly and I'm not
doubting you I'm just saying that also
could be a factor in increasing potency
of those plants so keep in mind that the
dry and cure process can uh dramatically
increase or decrease the potency of the
overall finished product uh if you dry
it too quickly it may lose a lot of the
potency it may lose a lot of the turps
if you dry it nice and slowly you should
retain most of the turps and most of the
potency but many variables can mess that
up very quickly so the two things to
think about our harvesting at Peak
ripeness and the only way to really
master that is by cutting down at
different times really and then testing
but are you really concerned what the
lab report says I'm more curious what
does it do when you smoke it did you cut
it down at the right time according to
your Buzz to your desires uh if you want
more of a racy buzz cut it down a little
bit earlier if you want that middle buzz
cut it down when you got about 20% Amber
tricomes if you want more of a sedative
couch lock relaxed sort of a buzz then
wait till so you got 30% amber tricomes
that's where you need to dial in your
desires so what I would do is I would
grow three or four plants and then I
would cut one down at where did you cut
yours down 65 so I would cut one down at
day 60 then one at day 65 and one at Day
70 and then I would dry and cure them
all the same oid the best that you can
then I would send them to a lab then
while you're waiting for the lab to run
their test and send you results do your
own independent testing uh take the
plant that you cut down at day 60 and
make it your first smoke of the day if
you normally smoke a joint if you
normally smoke a bong load if you
normally smoke out of the hookah however
you normally do it take your first smoke
of the day of that plant that you cut
down at day 60 and then take notes of
what happened did you get caught in
mouth did you get a nice Buzz did you
enjoy it is it what you're looking for
then the next day then you could smoke
whatever weed you want after that
throughout the day then the next day uh
take that plant you cut down at day 65
and smoke that one the same exact way as
you did yesterday for your first smoke
of the day then let's take notes did you
get cotton mouth did you like the flavor
like the aroma did you get the buzz
you're looking for then compare it to
the one you smoked yesterday then you
can smoke whatever weed you want for the
rest of the day I give you permission
then the third day guess what we're
going to do we're going to smoke the
sample that went for 70 days and we're
going to compare it on the same criteria
as the first two then we're going to
think about which one did you really
enjoy the most write it down pick one
write the things that you notice the
pros the cons the pluses the minuses the
similarities and the differences Mark
all that [ __ ] down then uh when the
tests come compare the lab tests to your
personal paper notes uh did you agree is
that your favorite the one of that is
the most potent is that the one that you
chose the one that's the trippiest is
that the one that you chose and then see
if those test results line up is your
favorite plant the one that got you the
highest the one that gave you the
favorite Buzz is that the one that had
the highest lab test was the one that
you said tasted the best the one that
tested with the highest TPS just play a
game and see if you can get the lab test
if you can predict the lab test or if
the lab tests agree with you I just
think that that would be fun what
matters the most is which finished
product do you prefer do you like the
early cut the middle cut that late cut
that is the most important part or maybe
you're growing for a medical need for
somebody else uh maybe you're growing
for a for a profit uh does your medical
client or does your uh your clientele do
they prefer a certain one that's what's
going to matter the most uh use that lab
test for funsies it sounds like you're
testing anyway and I'm always curious to
see lab results please do send me those
but the most important part is which one
do you like the most now he does wrap it
up with or is it that I'm growing in
organic soil and not using pgrs no I
don't think that that is a factor here I
think you're a great grower I think
you're going to get similar results in
pgrs or in your organic soil or whatever
you chose to grow in I'm sure that you
would kill it and get similar results uh
don't feel bad that 20% THC was your
test result that's not a low number
that's not a bad number uh that's very
common that's very uh that's acceptable
in the Cannabis industry and you got
that 2.0% CBG which tells me there could
have been possibly more THC if you did
let it go longer so uh the only way to
answer that is honestly to let one go a
little bit longer and then test it again
and see what type of results you do get
but to make that official you have to do
everything the exact same all over again
or it's not official uh science so I
would run like I said before run a few
plants and then cut some down at some
time some at another some at another and
then run those maybe you could cut uh
one branch off one branch one branch
that sounds kind of silly I don't like
that idea but it it would be good
science it would work but uh I would do
three more tests if you can uh from a 60
a 65 and a 70 and if you want to go
crazy go for a day 75 test just for fun
most importantly though smoke them see
what you like my dude 311 I do thank
thank you once again for the great
question that one got me rambling quite
well I'm going to send you a coupon code
for a free pack of iy genetics premium
seeds and I can't wait to see what you
do with them my friend all right we do
have another great message here in front
of me this one came from our friend who
wants to be called stacks and the
question from Stacks goes a little bit
like this it says yo this podcast rocks
a lot of good info and has helped me in
my breeding Journey well you're are very
welcome I'm glad to help you out in the
breeding Journey uh it says I'm I'm sure
you've spoke on this before but thoughts
on selfing so selfing that is when you
take a female plant and you treat it
with a solution and that female plant
will make pollen that pollen is
feminized pollen I will take that pollen
and put it on a clone of the exact same
plant that will make feminized seeds
that are we'll just say Golden Goat is a
Golden Goat to Golden Goat since that is
the same plant it pollinated itself that
is now selfing that is an S1 that is a
selfed feminized plant that is what
selfing means just to catch you guys up
then he goes on and he says what about
the next Generations the S2 the S3 and
so on that is a very good question it
says I read on the internet that it's
the quickest way to
uniformity um sometimes those S2s and
S3s well let's talk about how we do that
and what that is uh the S1 is when you
take that original plant and pollinate
itself right that first seed that comes
off that is S1 if I were to grow out
those seeds and find a plant that look
just like the mommy that I'm looking for
just like the original plant that I
reversed that I'm working with if I find
that one again then I cut two clones of
that and reverse one and pollinate the
other one again and do the process again
now I'm making S2s if I repeat that I
making S3 every time I do it I make
another generation with another
number sometimes in those further s
Generations things can be great or they
can be really really wonky sometimes
you'll bre just weak slow growing
growing plants sometimes you'll grow
some mutated plants sometimes you'll
bring out some weird recessive traits
but sometimes you do have really good
luck and you're able to lock in the
exact traits that you were looking for I
have played with S2 and S3 generations
and a couple of back crosses and
different variations of that and from my
experience it's less risky to just leave
that S1 alone and be happy with the
phenotypes that are coming from that
than it is to go S2 and risk the
mutation and the weird uh of vigor and
the weirdness that does come from that
now there is more to this question let
me jump to it it says uh my thought is
if I find the perfect cross in an F1
generation could I self that to get
uniformity or are there problems this
way now the F1 generation is not
feminized I'm not sure if you meant F1
generation in there but we'll talk about
a couple of different things here let's
start with Golden Goat uh you said find
the perfect cross Golden Goat is a
nearly perfect cross I love that plant
it's fun to grow it's fun to smoke and
it breeds beautifully so I'm going to
use Golden Goat here uh you said my
thought is if I find the perfect cross
which will say Golden Goat um Golden
Goat is an F1 so that fits perfectly
into your criteria it says could I self
that to get uniformity or are there
problems this way no there are
absolutely no problems in selfing that
F1 that is a great idea that is exactly
what I do I do that with the Golden Goat
I do that with a couple of other things
when you self an F1 a lot of the times
what I do find is that I find
approximately 50 to 70% of the progyny
look just like the original mother plant
so if I take that Golden Goat I selfit I
make Golden Goat S1 seeds at least 50%
of those seeds are going to look just
like the Golden Goat that I started with
now here's a way that I like to break it
down when I'm talking about fem seeds
and phenotypes to expect most of the
time in my experience and believe me
there are many variables this is just
from my experience and what I have seen
most of the time I'm going to find 50%
of the phenotypes look just like the
plant that I reversed so if I'm working
with Golden Goat 50 to 70% we're going
to sa 50 for this just to give myself a
buffer zone and just for mathematical
purposes uh usually 50 to 70 but we're
going to say 50% of those seeds are
going to look just like the Golden Goat
now what we're also going to find is 20%
of those seeds are going to look like
the mother of Golden Goat and 20% of
those seeds will look like the dad of
the gold Golden Goat now we're also
going to find about 10% of those seeds
just to be complete weirdos who knows
what those are going to look like that
is just what the genetics do they could
look like Grandma they could look like
Grandpa they could be all over the place
but usually about 50 to 70% of them are
going to look just like the mom that we
started with we're going to see some of
the dad and some of the mom on The the
parents the mom and the dad and then
sometimes we're going to see some weird
phenotypes in there so that is generally
the ratio that I find when I'm working
with the uh the s1's which is a
feminized version of the F1 now I
understand that the question was asking
about going further generations to lock
in that uniformity or the word stability
that's when stable comes in here but I
think by doing the S1 that you're going
to lock in as much as you need to you're
going to find enough phenotypes that
look just like the original mother plant
if you're doing this for yourself for
preservation uh that S1 is perfectly
fine you will find a lot of great phen
types in there they look just like the
mom if you want to do this for
commercial production if you want to put
these seeds out then you may want to
work it further but honestly the Golden
Goat s1's that I put out people are
finding phenotypes that look just like
the original Golden Goat they get a
six-pack of seeds and they'll find one
that looks just like the original Golden
Goat in that pack so my dude I hope that
was a sufficient answer to your question
I always do love talking about breeding
and since I read your question here on
the podcast that means that you win a
gift card for a free pack of iy genetics
premium seeds on iy direct.com check
your email by the time this episode
comes out if you don't find the gift
card in your email please do check your
spam sometimes those gift cards do go to
the spam folder I do not want that to
expire before you get the opportunity to
use that gift card all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast make sure you
check out the website at IR genetics.com
there's a link to the Discord server
where somebody is hanging out in the
smoker Lounge chat right now taking dabs
talking about Life Sharing grow
knowledge with you everything you could
possibly imagine is at IR genetics.com
there's a link to iy direct.com where
you can get those seeds anything you
could need iy genetics.com I know that
was a big mouthful here right at the end
of the podcast if youve listened this
far I've got a gift for you make sure
you use coupon code love and I
direct.com you'll get 10% off all right
that is all I've got for you for this
episode ladies and gentlemen I do want
to give a big shout out to my buddy J
mro and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ]
big up yourself every time R the
[Music]
[Applause]
Jeff
[Music]
tell to take another Dam grab your p in
about the
back in the back
relax all right here holy [ __ ] that is
loud [ __ ] a