[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] happy holidays podcast
world I'm your host rosta Jeff this is
episode
823 of the grow from heart podcast I've
got a great episode lined up for us in
this episode I'm going to give away free
seeds that's right hang out we'll talk
more about the free seeds later on in
the show I do want to remind you that I
direct.com is back online that's right
make sure you check out edirect decom
for a restock and fresh drops I recently
added chemical cocktail and Mac one to
arise to IR
redirect.sh 4K you can get chemical
cocktail and more freebies available at
iy direct.com all right I think that
covers all of the advertising and news
here at the start of the show let's jump
into one of my favorite parts of the
podcast this is the section I call Pet
Peeves when I go to grows when I'm in my
own grow when I'm at a commercial grow
sometimes when I'm in a social situation
smoking or talking about cannabis a lot
of things will trigger a pet peeve in me
and I've been sharing those pet peeves
on the show I encourage you to send me
your pet peeves tell me what what drives
you crazy in your grow somebody else's
grow if you go to a grow and you see
something what just makes you cringe
what is your garden pet peeve send those
pet peeves to me I do have a website
that website is iry genetics.com on that
website there is a list of tabs one says
grow help if you go to that growel tab
you can send me grow questions or there
you can also send me your grow pet peeve
if I discuss your pet peeve here on the
podcast I will give you a gift
certificate for a free pack of seeds at
edirect tocom today's pet peeve came
from me no one's getting free prizes no
one's getting seeds today if you saw
that spit I do apologize I'm human not
even going to edit that out but uh
today's pet peeve comes from me my pet
peeve is unlabeled pots bro don't plant
a bunch of seeds plant a bunch of clones
and think you're going to remember what
is in each and every pot uh most likely
you were stoned as [ __ ] when you were
popping those seeds most likely you were
stoned as [ __ ] when you were cutting
those clones you were probably most
likely highest giraffe [ __ ] when you
were putting those clones into soil
putting those seeds into dirt whatever
you did and you did not label them bro
we're not going to remember we're
cannabis Growers and cannabis consumers
cannabis makes you kind of forget some
details so if you're going to put some
pots some plants in some pots have some
plants anywhere label them so we know
what they are don't come back and have
to guess is this one bubble goat is this
one nuk town is this one strawberry
Starburst let's put some labels on the
plants label each one carefully and
maybe possibly label each plant more
than once something I heard somebody say
they did did recently they labeled their
plants and then all of the labels got
washed off of the tags when they watered
they used a non-waterproof marker so
make sure you use the appropriate marker
maybe if you need to get some duct tape
write the strain name on the duct tape
stick that duct tape on the pot spin the
pot around 180° and do it again write
the strain name on that duct tape stick
the duct tape on the pot do it again
that way you can double down in case one
gets washed off one gets [ __ ] up you
got two labels on there set yourself up
for success is what I'm saying nothing
drives me more crazy than not knowing
what strain we just grew not when if I
send you multiple packs of seeds and you
say this could be this one or this one
I'm not sure as the breeder as the
person that's going to post those
pictures none of those photos are valid
I can't use it if it's an I think sort
of situation I need to know this is the
strain that I took the photo of I want
to know what's in that pot so my pet
peeve of the day ladies and gentlemen is
label your pots label your clones your
cloner especially I see a lot of cloners
that you'll take a piece of paper and
you'll write like a legend like clone
number one excuse me clone number one is
a rise clone number two is blueberry
butcher clone number three is strawberry
Starburst so you've got your Legend
right excuse me for clearing the throat
there on the podcast not going to edit
that out keep going uh you got your
Legend one two and three but what
happens if you turn the paper or turn
the cloner do you still remember which
one was where I know that sounds silly
but I've seen it happen I've seen people
make mistakes please ladies and
Gentlemen let's label our plants much
more carefully that is my pet peeve
please I encourage you to send me your
pet peeves let me know what drives you
crazy in the garden if I do read your
pet peeve here on the show you win free
seeds all right now let's move into the
more popular portion of today's podcast
which is the question and answer section
of the show I have that website I spoke
about a moment ago IR genetics.com on
that website there's that grow help tab
right at the top click on there it will
send you to a section where you can send
me a grow question it may ask you about
your garden what is the temperature
what's the humidity what's the vpt then
at the Bott bot we basically ask what's
going on bro that's where we give you
the opportunity to tell me what's going
on in your grow and I will try to help
you if you use that growel Tab and I
read your question here on the podcast
guess what you want a coupon code for a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
today's first winner came from my friend
hunter gatherer bro I did not even
realize this was you this is a huge
supporter on cannabuzz a huge social
media follower bro thank you for all of
the continued uh support uh words of
encouragement the Great comments All the
following and stalking on social media
does count so thank you bro I just
realized who this one came from this is
a great question shout out to my buddy
Hunter gather my friend you have won a
coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds by the time this
episode comes out you will have that
coupon code if you don't have it yet
make sure you check your spam a lot of
people do miss those please do find
those coupon codes so this message goes
just like this it says Hey Rost Jeff
thanks for all of the Growers love over
the years oh bro you are very welcome
much reciprocated love thanks for the
support and the love back it says by
offering I solid genetics at affordable
prices and the knowledge you've passed
to this community over the years I have
upped my medical grow immeasurably bro
that's a huge compliment uh just by
knowing that I'm offering seeds at an
affordable price and giving free
information and that's improving your
grow that makes it worth my time and
energy to do it so thank you for that
feedback that's a huge compliment it
goes on it says why are the descriptions
for your strains no longer found on your
websites your descriptions were
excellent and informed my purchases can
you please bring them back Grower's love
from hunter gatherer yes I do understand
that for a while all of the descriptions
on IR genetics.com were gone most of the
descriptions on iir are very vague uh
there are a couple of reasons for that
we'll touch iy direct first um on iy
Direct if you want to take a credit card
and process money the credit card
processors do not want a lot of
information and details about your seeds
on that website so what you can
basically put is a photo you can put a
strain name you can put a cross you
cannot put a flowering time you cannot
put any details about growing it you
can't put flavors and Aromas just the
name and the cross how many seeds are in
the package is basically what you can
put up there that's what wave allows me
to do uh wave the uh the credit card
processing company that I use they have
a very strict compliance guideline and
every product I put up on my website on
iir is scanned by their comp clients
team and it has to meet a certain
criteria if I say the wrong words put
the wrong details they will not even
allow the product to appear on the
website uh they may take wave off for a
certain time if I mess up so I'm very
careful about what I put on edirect
decom uh that is because the credit card
processors do not want a lot of details
up there now let's talk about I
genetics.com there's no sales being done
there there's no credit card processor
there why did I remove those
descriptions for a short time at this
time I can announce that the description
the genetics page The Strain
descriptions are back they have been
edited uh they're a little more vague
than they were but they are back now
let's talk a little bit about that I had
to change some of the descriptions and
some of the wording uh mainly for legal
and Technical reasons um I'm learning
that you can't say I can't say things
like uh Golden Goat is good for
headaches technically that is a false
medical claim so I had to reward many of
the things on the website a lot of
things were geared at potency and false
medical claims and I don't want to brag
about potency at this time on the
website and I also cannot make uh
medical claims of any sort what I can
tell you is how it makes me feel when I
consume it but I can't tell you how it
will make you or other people feel I can
give you a testimony but I can't give
you I can't like again I can't make a
medical claim or any sort of claims that
I can't validate uh in a scientific
Manner and I don't want to I probably
could validate a lot of those claims I
can get 50 people in a room we could
smoke a joint and say yeah I do feel
like I'm stoned we could all agree on
that but I don't want to go through all
that uh it's easier just to not say [ __ ]
than it is to explain why you said some
[ __ ] so I had to remove some stuff off
the website um I am going to talk much
more about this on a patreon episode I
have to be careful about what I say I'm
sure you understand that but I'm going
to do a patreon episode that will be
available to patrons in the month of
December I'll probably uh record that
right when I wrap up here so look for a
more detailed episode uh in the month of
December on patreon I will keep it
affordable there will be a slight pay
wall but it will be available check
patreon.com fromy yourheart in the month
of December uh it will be available
there so the descriptions were gone I
can announce now that those descriptions
are back many of the descriptions are
back I it SP it took me a lot of time I
edited each and every one of those
descriptions by myself individually one
at a time uh that's all my thought
process my experiences with those plants
uh that's all in those descriptions
right now it is minimal and slightly
vague we need to do that for a few
reasons that I won't discuss here I may
talk more about that on the p patreon
episode over time those descriptions May
evolve again the older descriptions are
saved I didn't just delete it and forget
about them uh the highly detailed
descriptions are saved uh there are do
they are documented somewhere else so
they can be replicated in the future
many of those are all over the internet
if you go to seedfinder.eu you can find
a lot of those old descriptions um a lot
of the other websites that document
cannabis have those descriptions luckily
uh we got a little bit of notice and
those things got uh posted in other
places also many of those live on the
Discord if you need strain details that
we cannot put on the website on iir or I
genetics.com check out my Discord
there's a link to the Discord server in
the show notes and in the video
description uh Discord can be it's a lot
to navigate if you're new but just come
hang out we will guide you through it uh
somebody in there will help you all the
stuff on the left that's all of the
different uh tabs you can open each tab
has different stuff in there the tabs on
the bottom will have strain names on
them you can find blueberry butcher uh
uh every strain I was just trying to
think of random strains Golden Goat or
rise they're all on there you can click
on it and you can uh we share our grow
experiences so other people that have
grown it have posted photos all the way
from seedling all the way up to harvest
and their experience with each plant and
if you have questions I'm on Discord uh
much more than I should admit so come to
Discord there's a Smokers Lounge chat
I'm probably in there I'm probably
logged into the Smokers Lounge chat on
my phone right now even though I'm not
in there I'm just muted and uh they're
in there chatting right now somebody in
there will be more than happy to help
you with your plants if I'm not there I
probably am I'll be more than happy to
talk about it come to the Growers Lounge
come to the Discord you are invited but
a lot of the info that we cannot put on
the main website on the other websites
on the main internet is hidden is on the
Discord it lives there freely come hang
out you guys it's a great Community all
right so let me get back to the main
part of the question here uh where and
why uh they're gone they were gone they
are back but they are vague uh they will
improve and grow over time also if
there's there's a strain that is not
listed and you discover that something
you have experienced is not on the
website send me an email uh you can send
it to uh grow fromy yourheart at
hotmail.com and I will add that strain
that I have forgotten I put about 120
130 strains up there I may have easily
overlooked or forgotten something I'm
going to include all of the males all of
the females uh it just takes a little
bit of time but this was a good question
I've been asked this question several
times I was just not ready to address it
I like to address things when I have
good news when I have a resolution and
now I publicly addressed them anyway and
I've publicly addressed it because I
have fixed the problem iir is back the
descriptions on iy genetics is back it
is all back and happening I did send out
a newsletter uh letting everybody know
that the descriptions were back many of
you probably got that newsletter if you
did not get that newsletter go to my
website IR genetics.com on the bottom
there's a little envelope looking thing
with the blank space to type in your
email address it says stay up to date if
you type in your email address click the
enter Mark or hit send or whatever it is
on there that will add you to my mailing
list uh when I put out new drops on
Direct when I make updates to the
website I try not to spam you too much
it's been holiday season I've been going
a little bit hard but I promise I'll
settle down on all the emails once the
new year begins but join the newsletter
you can stay up to date to all the fresh
drops uh all the updates on the website
there may be some events coming up there
may be some secret passwords you may
need things like that at IR genetics.com
on the Stay Up to-date tab down on the
bottom all right my dude hunter gatherer
thank you for the great question uh go
check out the website because everything
you're looking for is back also check
your email because you've got a gift
certificate for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds all right let's
move into the next message here this one
came from somebody that wants to be
called is that
LS G that's their name so shout out to
lsti uh dude I've got your email address
so make sure you check your email and
your spam for a gift certificate for a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
the question from LS goes like this it
says what up rosta Jeff shout out to you
and the rest of the iy army yes big up
to the entire iy Army thank you for all
the support excuse me for the throat
clearing I will admit it I was taking
dabs anyway the message goes like this
it says I hope you had an amazing
Thanksgiving yes Thanksgiving was great
everything has been beautiful it says my
question is one about water for your
crops that's a really good question it
says is it okay to use spring water from
local natural spring to water my girls I
know not to buy store-bought spring
water yes that is true then it says what
would the shelf life be like I'm not
sure the shelf life but I've got a good
answer for the rest uh best way to store
it I'm not an expert there any other
Pros or cons you could send my way
thanks for all you do uh take care and
best uh catch you in the Discord yes
shout out to my friend for hanging out
in the Discord I'll probably be there
after I record this and a patreon
episode I'll go hang out on Discord take
some dabs I hope to see you there there
now let's answer the question the
question is can this listener use spring
water in their Garden natural spring
water my first instinct uh without any
education uh without any research
without being the water guy I would say
uh yes you should probably use that
spring water in your garden uh this
water does not have any added chemicals
in it nobody's put any chlorine no
chloramine uh they're not putting
fluoride in this water uh I would
probably recommend this water for
drinking for watering plants this is
probably a highly valuable water also
it's going to have natural minerals and
probably Trace elements of natural
microbes in there as well uh it's
probably really high quality water yes I
would probably recommend Watering your
plants with this spring water one thing
I would think about is maybe get it
tested um you can have water tested it's
very affordable uh it's easy to do you
can contact your local water company you
can uh probably contact the local
Department of a one of them can steer
you in the right direction to get your
water tested they'll tell you what's in
there they'll tell you if it's safe to
drink if it's safe for plants uh and
then just give it a little Quick Test
it's probably affordable depending on
where you are get it tested just for
peace of mind but um if if the
vegetation and everything around that uh
that spring is healthy and happy that
water is probably super great it could
have sulfur in it it could have other
things in it smell it taste it see what
you think um but I would bet that that
water is great for the plants now here
comes the uh the hippie and me the
person that has to uh speak up uh you
said natural spring where is it where is
it natural spring local natural spring
um I don't know how much water is coming
out of that I don't know if it's a
heavily flowing natural spring I don't
know if it's a light flow I don't know
what you got but don't take more than
what you deserve don't ruin the spring
by drying it up uh be uh be mindful of
how much water you're taking from that
natural resource there don't destroy it
uh leave no trace and then other than
that bro do your thing with the water uh
get those plants super healthy maybe
take a sip of it uh there are several
Springs around me in a place called
manitu Springs some of them you can
drink from some of them they suggest
they suggest you're allowed to but they
suggest you don't drink from it because
of specific mineral content so I may
check on that with these plants or with
this water but check the vegetation all
around uh maybe give it a test water or
maybe actually pay for a water test but
most of the time that spring water is
going to be highly valuable water for
your plants all right my dude LST IG
thank you for the great question once
again check your email because you have
a coupon for a free pack of iy genetics
premium seeds on I direct.com all right
we're going to keep this momentum
rolling I've got another great question
here in front of me this one also came
from the growel tab on iy genetics.com
so you do get a coupon code for a free
pack of iy seeds this one came from my
new friend Dallas Dallas said I'm a huge
fan here well thank you for being a fan
bro thank you for all the support thank
you for the great question it says I
love the show and I've watched tons of
older episodes it's almost embarrassing
but I do appreciate it it says I know
you've talked about this before but I
cannot find the episode that's okay
there's like 820 something now says I've
been hunting through some seeds and I've
grown this cultivar four times and it is
stretched each time every time I've
grown it I've upgraded to a taller tent
from four to six and now an eight-footer
i top it and send it into flower at 3
weeks it seems like the better I grow
the harder it is to grow small plants
all right that kind of make sense cuz
you're feeding them better taking better
care they're getting bigger faster but
we should also learn how to control
these plants with each grow it says I've
upgraded to a great AC infinity light
but the stretch never stops uh a lot of
my stuff is stretchy I don't know what
you're growing but a lot of my stuff I
will admit uh I am guilty of producing
stretchy plants early in flower but we
could talk about how to mitigate this
just a little bit the question is how
can I slow it slow the bolt or just keep
it in check sorry that was long winded
but I would love to hear back bro nobody
ever should apologize for being
longwinded when speaking to me I say
more words than one one sentence uh more
words and more one breath than most
people uh I'm talking fast over here I
got a lot of [ __ ] to say I got my own
show don't feel bad about being long-
winded thank you for the good question
um there are things we can do to
mitigate the stretch of these plants uh
the main thing I think you're doing it
right is flip early many people are
afraid to grow my plants because they
take 70 maybe 77 days to flower but then
I tell them you can cut 2 weeks off your
veg time cuz my plants grow so quickly
and so vigorously that it doesn't matter
you're still growing a 9we plant even if
it takes 11 just flip it a little bit
early because they are so vigorous uh
but my plants do grow tall they do grow
fast things that I do suggest to help uh
mitigate that stretchy phase is uh top
it you said top it that is a very good
way to do it uh top it early then you're
going to get a bunch of tops that are
going to grow out of control right so
top it flip early those are the first
things to do other things to think about
popping and twisting do you guys pop and
twist your plants I've talked about this
on previous episodes it's time to do a
refresher I'm going to use a pen as an
example so this is a branch on a plant
right this pen right here uh the branch
is coming up I do this on every Branch
so the soil is here right the plant
comes up here I'll grab about here with
this hand and about here with this hand
and twist opposite directions until it
does a little bit of a pop depending on
the thickness of your uh stock the
branch it'll be a louder or more quiet
pop some are twisty some are Woody some
are rubbery some plants will react
differently but a lot of times you'll
hear a little let me see if my knuckle
will do it you'll hear a little just
like that crunch pop that was just a
little knuckle pop in there that's what
I call it pop its Knuckles so the plant
is coming out of the dirt right here uh
we got the stick coming up I'll grab
with my right hand here just cuz I'm
right-handed that's how I prefer to to
grab it it's easiest for me grab it
right above with the left hand give it a
Twist you're going to hear that
cellulose structure of the plant pop
what's going to happen is you're going
to create a little a little little
knuckle there a little Burr it's going
to be a little stronger spot in that
plant I'm going to go up a couple of
inches and I'm going to do it again then
I'm going to go up a few inches and do
it again and then go up again and do it
again and I'm going to do that to the
entire plant I'm going to start at the
bottom and work my way up the main stock
all the way to the top then I'm going to
go to the bottom branches and work my
way up all those then the lowers and
work my way up every branch is going to
get popped and twisted popped it and
twisted popped and twisted that's what I
said every branch is going to get a nice
pop and twist a nice knuckle crack ing
then wherever I pop those Knuckles it's
going to get a little bit thicker just
like in your finger you can see my
fingers are swollen at my knuckle and
they're going to get a little bur there
a little bit thicker they're going to
get more support they're going to be
stronger those branches will become more
robust and tougher they'll be able to
support the big fat buds that are coming
up in the future now also this is going
to slow down the stretch of that plant
because it's going to spend a lot of its
energy healing up that broken cellulose
structure the fibers of the plant we
just broke we didn't really ruin
anything we didn't damage anything we
just broke broke it enough to slow down
that growth we do that in the first 2
and 1/2 weeks of flow the plan is just
adjusting its hormones into the
flowering phase at that time by the time
we're done popping and twisting
everything and that stretch phase is
over it's not even going really into
flower yet the flowers aren't going to
happen till about day 21 24 is when
you're going to get buds developing so
go ahead and pop them twist them crack
them manipulate them all the way up
until you start seeing Bud set you can
even go a little further if you want but
that will slow down that growth and it
will make the plants a little they'll
stay squater and more bushy and more
robust they'll stay a little lower and
you're not even messing up the buds
it'll slow down that stretch phase so
pop them twist them top them put them
under a trellis is something else you
can also do if you put them under a net
they can't go much higher because
they're under that net it's a it's a
skill it's an art form to learn how to
Trellis plants properly but do it the
only way to learn it is to do it but the
main idea is to get them to grow out
instead of up so you're not dealing with
one big giant uh Victory Bud one Glory
Cola that's touching the light and
messing everything up you've got
everything bent down it's all growing
evenly and everything gets that nice
even Light canopy so um flower early top
them pop and twist them trellis them uh
also feeding them properly can also help
mitigate that stretch in some strains
understand this is only going to be
strain dependent and this will only do
so much but if you give them if you
reduce that nitrogen give them
phosphorus and pottassium early in flour
that may help mitigate that stretchiness
in the start of the flowering phase
everything is going to take off for
about the first uh you'll see it take
off about day 10 and it won't stop until
about day 21 24 things are going to go
crazy in the stretch phase once you get
past that it's slow gradual growth until
the end if it really explodes at the end
of week n9ine or 10 but if you can
manage that super turbo growth for the
first 3 weeks you should be able to
manage the next six weeks of growth uh
they won't grow as quickly and rapidly
once you get past that I call it puberty
that puberty stretchy phase there
they're going from young girls to ladies
they just want to stretch and be seen
all right what they're really doing is
they're stretching to get up top so they
can receive pollen I'm sure you notice
if you grow a male plant he grows taller
more quickly than everybody so he can
get up high and when he pollinates that
pollen can fall the girls are trying to
get up above the other girls so that
they can get that pollen they want to be
the one to get that pollen cannabis's
whole purpose the whole purpose of that
plant we think it's to get us High
that's that's our favorite part but that
plant's whole purpose is to breed it
wants to make seeds for next year so
that it can make seeds for next year and
so on so keep that in mind when you're
working with cannabis plants its whole
goal is to breed we think it's to get us
High that's like a bonus all right my
friend Dallas thank you for the great
question I do have your email address so
make sure that you check your spam and
your email for a gift certificate for a
free pack of seeds at iry direct.com all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone cutters Paul and
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast if you did not hear your
question on today's show please do not
feel discouraged I've got a mountain of
emails over here and they keep on coming
so if I did not read your question on
this episode do not feel discouraged it
may come up in a future episode also if
you have questions send them to that
growel tab on iy genetics.com also make
sure to check out that updated strain
section on iy genetics
anything else you could possibly need is
on iry genetics.com there's a link to
iir there's a link to the Discord server
there's a link to the YouTube videos
check it out at IR genetics.com also
make sure you check out the patreon
campaign at
patreon.com grow from your heart I know
that's a lot of info here at the show
but if you made it this far I've got a
coupon code for you make sure to use
coupon code love at edirect decom to
save 10% off your purchase at
edirect that coupon code has been
extended and updated so coupon code love
at iy direct all right that's all I've
got for you for this week I may be back
next week with fresh new content if I
don't pop up next week I'm just enjoying
the holidays with the friends and family
you go hang out with some friends and
sign out of the internet for a minute I
want to give a big shout out to my
friend Indica B and until next time take
a fat dab and give your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]
[Music]
big up yourself every time R the
[Applause]
[Music]
Jeff
[Applause]
[Music]
time to take another dance
grab your p in about the
b in the lab sit back par them moment
relax hold up