[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go happy
New Year podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 82 four of
the grow from your heart podcast I've
got a fun show lined up for us in this
episode I want to talk about starting
the new year strong in our grow space
before I get to that part of the show I
do want to send a big thank you to
everybody who supported the grow from
your heart podcast iy genetics rosta
Jeff or the iy Army in any way in 2023
big thank you I do appreciate all of the
support all right I feel like I covered
the cheesy part of the show now let's
jump into the main topic of today's
podcast this episode will come out right
at the start of the new year happy New
Year everybody I want to talk about
setting ourselves up for success in 2024
one of the first things I want to do to
start the new year is I'm going to clean
my grow space 100% I'm going to clean
every nook and cranny every inch of the
grow space from top to bottom then I'm
going to clean my nutrient storage and
mixing area then it will clean my
pesticide storage and mixing area then
it will clean all of the gear everything
will be shiny and brand new to start the
new year it will take me a little bit of
time to do this but I feel like the time
that I spend doing this will probably
speed me up over the next few weeks
because then I will know where all of my
gear is all the nutrients will be lined
up in the right spot all the mixing
stuff will be clean and ready to go uh
sometimes most of the time I do try to
put my stuff away and clean up after
myself and be an organized good little
grow guy but we all know that sometimes
we get in a rush uh things get
overlooked things get set in the wrong
place some messes get overlooked for a
little bit here at the start of the year
I'm going to clean all of that stuff up
reorganize and I do believe that it will
save me time just by reorganizing and
cleaning up my mess putting in a few
minutes now will save me time over the
next couple of weeks so the first thing
I'm going to do is clean up my grow
space now the second thing I did in my
grow space I've already done this part I
may recommend you do it too if you are
using the same type of equipment it is
winter time here in Colorado which means
I am now using HPS Lighting in my grow
space I know those lights are old those
are dinosaurs but sometimes they work in
the right conditions I've got a basement
grow in Colorado lately it has been
super cold and guess what those HPS
lights are keeping it just right in that
grow space so I just recently hung two
HPS lights to keep it warm for the
winter conditions when I hung those HPS
lights I put two brand new bulbs in the
fixtures when I did that I got a piece
of duct tape and I wrote down the date
when I put those new bulbs in those uh
fixtures and now I know exactly when
those bulbs were placed in those
fixtures if you are using HPS bulbs and
you cannot remember when the last time
you replaced them was I strongly
recommend you do it here at the start of
the year and make a note of when you put
those bulbs in there I do try to replace
those bulbs every two maybe three crops
but it's a good idea to write down the
date when you put those bulbs in there
so you know exactly how long they've
been in there then occasionally bust out
your light meter I don't know if you've
got a real light meter I don't know if
you're using the photon app bust out
whatever you use find a distance from
that light that is consistent maybe go
12 18 in just do it consistently every
time and take a reading see how much
light that bulb is putting out if you've
lost more than 20 or 30% of the output
of that bulb it's time to swap that bulb
because you're paying for 100% of the
electricity if you're not getting light
out of that bulb it is time to switch it
out for efficiency so I would recommend
adding new bulbs and writing down the
date of when those bulbs were added also
if you're running LEDs keep in mind
those lights do degrade over time the
manufacturers don't want you to believe
and know that that they do degrade but
they definitely do degrade over time it
takes much longer than a HPS bulb but
those LEDs do lose efficiency over time
so maybe think about testing those as
well start testing those here at the
start of the year now I did start the
podcast off by saying we were going to
clean up the grow space but let's focus
on cleaning everything I just said that
I hung those HPS lights those HPS lights
have a glass Shield between the bulb and
the grow space and the heat is kept in
there and it's moved out by a duck so
that heat can never make it into the
Grove now is a good time to clean that
glass on those hoods if you've got
hooded uh lights with glass on there get
in turn the lights off let it cool and
then clean that glass it is also a good
time to clean your air conditioner
filter if your air conditioner has
filters get in there and clean those
filters Also let's deep clean the
dehumidifier that dehumidifier has
probably got some gunk in it let's take
it all apart and clean it thoroughly I'm
sure you've been doing the mini clean
the quick clean but let's give it the
long clean let's take it out of the room
take every component and part out that
you can figure out how to take out and
clean it very clean and put it in there
brand new so that we've got a fresh
clean dehumidifier Also let's clean up
the humidifier if you're not using RO
water your humidifier and dehumidifier
are going to have calcium and other
minerals built up in them now is a good
time to clean those and make them brand
new now since we're cleaning all of the
equipment it is also a good time to
clean out our reservoirs and all of our
watering equipment I don't know if
you've got a giant res I don't know if
you're using a trash can I don't know if
you've got a couple of 5 gallon buckets
I don't know if you're using a pitcher
or a water wand but however you do it
let's clean up all of our watering and
irrigation equipment I would recommend a
product called fizan 20 use fizan 20 as
recommended on the bottle mix that up
and use it to clean your Reservoir your
buckets uh also use it to clean your
watering pitcher if you use a watering
wand and a pump you can run the fisen 20
right through there just make make sure
to rinse and clean everything thoroughly
with clean water after using the fizan
let's not feed any fizan 20 to our
plants they will not enjoy that but it's
a great product it'll make everything
smell Hospital clean and it will remove
all of the pathogens in your watering
equipment so let's clean that up like I
said if you got a big Reservoir clean
that up if you got a big trash can on
Wheels clean that up if you're just
using buckets let's clean those up and
let's clean up the watering pitcher if
you just got a pitcher if you're using a
water wand if you're using a pitcher
whatever you're using let's just clean
that up make it look fresh and clean for
the new year that will also help you
mitigate problems in the future all
right we're talking about cleaning
everything also um I've got perhaps
maybe there are cameras in my grow space
when I worked in a commercial
environment we would have to take a day
just to go around and clean all of the
lenses on all of the cameras so if
you've got cameras in your grow space
get a ladder get out that cleaning rag
that little microfiber Rag and let's
clean the lenses on our cameras so that
we can see everything nice and clearly
in our grow space when we're trying to
creep on our grow when we're far from
home and making sure everything is okay
now that I'm talking about creeping on
the grow far from home let's also make
sure that all of our monitoring
equipment is calibrated and hung in the
right place sometimes I'll go into a
grow room and I'll notice that the uh
the sensors for your AC Infinity are not
in any useful positions the plants are
growing here they're about this high and
that AC Infinity the little uh the
sensor piece is way up here get that
sort of near the plant so that we kind
of know what's going on with the plants
right make sure that all of your gear is
in the right spot and that all of that
gear is calibrated let's check all the
Cycles on all of our stuff too I don't
know what kind of uh programmable
controllers you've got but let's check
and make sure that everything is working
the way we think it is run through your
programs run through your time make sure
everything is set the way you expect it
to be something might be happening in
there that you don't even know about
let's just check and verify all of our
settings now since we're checking and
verifying settings you know I'm going to
talk about it soon in this episode let's
calibrate all of our testing equipment
that's right if you've got a pH pen a
big pH meter a combo meter let's clean
it and calibrate that I definitely
recommend calibrating your pH meter at
least once a week a lot of people will
go two weeks some people will go longer
if you're working with a lot of plants
and mixing up a lot of nutrients you
definitely want that meter accurate so
clean and calibrate your PH meters as
often as you have time for the solution
is not expensive it doesn't take much
time uh if you do it every other morning
every third morning at least once a week
in your grow those pins will stay
calibrated and it will make a big
difference in the way your plants uptake
the nutrients if the pH is proper in
your feed solution so right here at the
start of the Year let's make it a habit
let's calibrate our pH pins let's clean
and calibrate our pH pins then let's get
a little notebook get a log and write
down today January 1st I cleaned and
calibrated my pH pins I also added new
bulbs in this one room we're going to
add a lot more stuff to this little
notebook this journal that we talk about
here later in the episode let's keep it
moving let's calibrate our gear the pH
pins uh let's clean them and calibrate
them also let's clean our EC meters if
you're using an EC meter let's clean it
because those things will get gunky over
time and they work better if they're
clean all right where do we go from
there now is a good time to do inventory
inventory you might say yes we're going
to go through a lot of nutrients over
the next year if everything goes our way
we're going to run a few crops with a
lot of plants we're going to need
nutrients we also going to need
pesticides let's go in the grow and see
which bottles have been around for too
long it may need to be tossed out these
things do expire I would not keep
nutrients around for more than a year so
if you got some old [ __ ] write that down
I need to replace this bottle toss that
old bottle order a new bottle pick up
all the bottles and give them a shake
what's low do you have anything that you
need to replace check on your nutrients
check on your pesticides and let's make
an order and replace all of the things
that we're going to need for the next
couple of weeks maybe the the next grow
that way we've got everything on hand
that way there are no surprises we don't
run out of anything through the grow
cycle set yourself up for Success today
let's plan the whole grow ahead right
now while we're thinking about it now I
did say Let's do an inventory of the
pesticides and our nutrients Also let's
think about personal protective
equipment I'm not sure how big your grow
is I don't know your pesticide routine
if you're going to spray frequently you
may need a lot of tyac Suits if you only
spray every so often you don't need as
many tyac suits
maybe you're not even a tiac guy maybe
you are I like the suits it just makes
it nice and easy I can tuck my dreads
behind myself and zip it right up into
the suit put on some gloves some booties
and a mask I'm ready to rock also
speaking of the Mask if you're using
ventilation it may be time to order
those new cartridges if you've got a a
respirator mask let's replace the 3M
cartridges on our mask and on our little
log let's make a note I swapped out the
cartridges here read the package let's
see how long those cartridges are good
for I don't remember I don't want to
give you poor advice but write down when
you should change those and then maybe
order the extras now so then when it
comes time to change the cartridges on
your 3M respirator you've got backup
cards ready to go let's order a bunch of
rubber gloves while we're at it we're
always going to run out of gloves I go
through at least one or two pairs of
gloves every day in my grow space uh if
I've got a helper that's another pair of
gloves when you're trimming harvesting
you go through excessive gloves order a
box of gloves right now while you're
thinking about it and then see how long
it takes I said see how long we'll stay
focused see how long it takes you to run
through that box of gloves and then
order more as necessary and then you can
start to see what it costs and when to
anticipate ordering things I'm trying to
get you on top of staying on top of this
so that you can get comfortable ordering
things before we run out of them now
another good thing to think about is
have you tested your fire extinguisher
you should have a fire extinguisher near
or around the grow space you should have
one in your home anyway uh you never
know you can catch them [ __ ] on fire
while you're cooking uh you could be
taking a dab and cause a problem there
should be a fire extinguisher handy
especially if you're growing uh have you
checked on it look at that fire
extinguisher it's got a gauge on it it's
got a little red a yellow and a green if
it's not in the green you need to get
that thing charged or replaced right
away uh recently there was a great sale
on fire extinguishers I'm not
advertising I was at Costco and I picked
up two new fire extinguishers because
they were on a really good sale price I
got one that is designed for electrical
fires and one that was design designed
uh I think it's just household or all
around I forget the other one one is
specifically for electrical fires I set
that next to the grow space because
anticipate any problem would be caused
by electricity in there right so I got
the one for electrical fires you get
what you feel will best suit your needs
but I recommend a fire extinguisher I
really hope you never need it I pray a
jaw that I never need mine but I would
rather have it and not need it then need
it and not have it that's just the way I
roll set yourself up for success is what
I'm talking about
now that fire extinguisher what else
could go well with that fire
extinguisher you say that quickly while
you're thinking about nine other things
what else do we need with the fire
extinguisher possibly a smoke detector a
smoke alarm may be a good idea the thing
about a smoke detector is uh when that
goes off are you going to be the one
that responds to that or is it going to
be somebody else in your area uh do you
have nosy neighbors are you in apart in
an apartment building in a condo think
about that sort of stuff we do want to
be notified of a fire but who's going to
notify maybe you want to be the only one
notified so think about that stay safe
but think about those sorts of things
now since we're talking about smoke
alarms that makes me think about a few
more security things we can think about
like I mentioned a moment ago I do have
cameras in my grow space um now is a
good time to go reset the passwords on
those cameras if you've got any sort of
security system uh cameras or maybe
anything that is accessible online
through a password maybe just routin L
go and change those passwords there's a
reason why a lot of services do request
you to update your password every so
often if it's your security for your
grow space if it's your camera for your
grow space if it's your AC Infiniti that
you're accessing maybe go change that
password just for Peace of Mind do it
often uh make sure you document that
password when you change it but go
change that password here at the start
of the year just to shake off anything
that may have followed you another thing
you can work on implementing or updating
here at the start of the year is your
integrated Pest management system what
have you been doing to keep bugs out of
your grow and what are you going to do
to continue keeping those bugs out of
your grow here in the future now is a
very good time to start a spray or a
predator bug rotation how do you want to
handle the bugs today is a great day to
start decide which products you want to
use order them and start applying them
uh together Andor in a rotation on your
plant on a schedule start marking that
down on that log or that journal that
we're going to talk about in just a
little bit then start spraying on a
rotation in my personal grows and
Commercial grows that I'm responsible
for I like to spray on Monday no matter
what if there's no problems we're going
to spray a preventative a pesticide
application on Mondays if there's any
hint of a problem that pest may be
present we're also going to spray on
Thursday we're going to apply a
different product possibly different
products in conjunction on Monday and
Thursday then we're going to spray again
on Monday and Thursday until that
problem is knocked down then we we will
resume just Monday sprays but work on
your Rhythm and routine for your
pesticide application make it regular so
that that way those bugs have no chance
of getting in there and colonizing make
sure you're always looking and make sure
you're applying pesticides or releasing
Predators on a regular schedule now
speaking of regular schedule here is
something new that I have not talked
about a lot uh that I probably never
mentioned in one of the these yearly
episodes where we set ourselves up for
success but I have recently become very
paranoid of hop latent vroid um I've
done an episode about it I am not
qualified to teach you uh in depth about
it so hopl and vroid is a virus that
came from the Hops family that's why
it's called hop Len vroid but cannabis
is Hop's very close cousin so it is
transferred over to the cannabis plants
uh this virus is um you won't even know
it's in your plants unless you use lab
testing but what will happen is you'll
grow your plant it'll look totally happy
totally healthy and then in midflower it
will just dud out and start to look weak
and bored uh it will start to look like
it's losing energy and it will slowly
die in front of you uh plants that used
to give you 3 lbs per light will now
give you A4 pound per light and you'll
be disappointed and angry that is
probably hop Laten vroid it is
non-detectable by the human eye youve
got to get a lab test on these plants to
detect the virus so I have become super
paranoid of incoming clones incoming
plants anything that comes into my grow
before it makes it a general population
it actually stops right here on this
table and I take a testing sample from
it and send that to a lab and they test
for the presence of hop and vroid before
that plant ever makes it into one of my
grow spaces one of my new habits that
I'm putting into practice here in this
year is I'm lab testing every plant
before it makes it to the grow and I am
also regularly that means every 6 to 8
weeks I am testing plants in my grow to
make sure nobody is snuck in any hopl
and vroid along the way I did start
testing my plants recently for hlv but
here at the start of the year I will be
much more scheduled and much more
methodical in keeping all of my plants
tested for the presence of hopl and
vroid maybe that is something you want
to implement maybe you want to test your
plants randomly something I definitely
recommend is testing any incoming clones
and if you've seen any plants in your
grow they look like they're like if
you've got 10 plants and two of them are
just kind of growing like [ __ ] now is
the time to get those tested and see if
they have the virus because that virus
will spread through your grow rapidly we
can talk a lot more about that on a
future episode but it may be a good time
to implement hop lat and vroid testing
in your protocol all right now so far in
this podcast I feel like I've been
talking about physical changes we can
make to our Grow rooms to set ourselves
up for success in 2024 let's shift gears
and talk more about planning and
strategy that we can put into place to
set our ourselves up for success in our
grow rooms everything successful starts
off with a good plan and a solid goal so
let's start by making plans and goals
for our grow room one of the first plans
and goals I would put into place is how
many harvests do you want to pull from
your grow this year I don't know how
many flowering rooms or flowering tents
you've got I don't know how much veg
space you've got but think about how
many harvests do you realistically want
to pull from your grow space this year
we've got 365 days to work with if
you've got a dedicated flowering room
and you put plants in there for 63 days
which is 9 weeks which most plants are
finished in about 9 weeks you can
probably pull 5.7 Harvest from that
dedicated flowering room now that means
there's no downtime there's not a day of
downtime there are no breaks can you
make that happen can you get that 5.7
harvests from that room most people
would be happy with five complete
harvests from one flowering room in a
year I would be happy with that if you
could get that 7 out of there and be
halfway through a harvest at the end of
the year that is a big win but let's
think about it now how many harvests do
you want to pull from that room do you
have a dedicated veg space if you want
5.7 Harvest from that flower room you
will need a dedicated veg space to where
you can pull down a crop move plants in
the same day and keep going and then get
that veg space active again to where
when we pull down that flower room the
veg space goes right back in there let's
think about how many Harvest we want to
pull realistically you don't have to do
5.7 per year this is up to you and now
is the time to think about it if you've
only got one flowering room do you want
to do a Perpetual cycle to where you're
taking down so many plants uh every two
weeks every 3 weeks every 30 days now is
the time to start thinking about those
plants and put them into place at the
start of the new year also I would think
about how many plants are going to go
into that room or into each tent how
often then start thinking about how many
mother plants do I need to supply clones
for this many flowering rooms this often
then there's the other thing to think
about are you going to run clones are
you going to run seeds now is a good
time to really start thinking about
strategy realistically think it takes me
this long to veg the plants as big as I
want them the plants I like to run take
this long in flower how do I prepare to
always have plants in my flower room and
always have plants in my vegro ready to
fill those spaces without overloading
myself and possibly without going over
your legal numbers now is a good time to
think about that and the new year is a
great time to start a new Perpetual
project also it may sound wild but now
is a good time to start thinking about
your outdoor crop I know we've got five
six maybe seven months before we can put
Plants outdoors in many areas but it is
never too early to start thinking about
that outdoor crop are you going to run
seeds and put those Outdoors this year
you could start seeds now in January you
could veg them you can take a clone from
them you can either flower the Clone or
the vegged plant you can sex the plants
this way find out if they're boys or
girls you can run these plants one time
and see what is the keeper phenotype
what would do best outside you can make
that selection and by March or April
you'll have your decisions made of what
should go outside then when May or June
comes around you've already got clones
prepared then you can veg those uh if
you start now you may be able to veg
some plants 5 6 or 7 ft tall if you've
got the ability indoors and put them out
as monsters when they go out side and
that's how you achieve those big
California monster plants that we see on
the internet all right so now is a good
time to start thinking about that
outdoor crop that is coming up in 6 or 7
months another huge way we can set
ourselves up for success in this year's
grow is by reflecting on what we did
last year did you take notes on last
year's growth if it was indoors if it
was Outdoors if you've been growing for
many years or just one year or maybe
even just one grow did you take notes
what were you happy with what were you
unsatisfied with what did you do very
well what do you not do very well are
you taking notes do you know where you
can improve do you know where you're
killing it do you know what you can do
better do you know where you're wasting
money are you taking notes let's take a
minute to reflect on last year's grow
and see how we can improve this year's
crop I think if we take a minute to
identify what our weak point is in the
growth space then we can really improve
upon that and then we can really step up
our entire game in the grow everybody's
got one thing they're not not good at in
the grow don't be ashamed don't feel
embarrassed by it the thing to do is
study that one thing a lot of people are
not good at taking clones uh I have got
a very good clone sop on my Discord if
you join the Discord I'll show you how
to find that clone cutting sop many
people find great success using that
clone sop so if cloning isn't your game
reach out we can help you learn to
become a better cloner if drying and
curing isn't your thing study drying and
curing if you don't think you're good at
identifying a deficiency in a plant
maybe that's the area you need to do
some research in then by the end of the
year you'll be the deficiency
identification expert you'll walk into a
grow and you'll go that plant needs CAG
that plant's had too much phosphorus
you're way giving that plant too much
nitrogen why is it so cold in here
you'll become that guy just do a little
bit of studying and pick up the
knowledge that you need in the area that
you are lacking I will admit that the
area I could use the most Improvement
and is probably understanding lighting
when it comes to yumul PO Jewel and all
those colors and all those graphs
something in my brain doesn't give a
[ __ ] to learn about that I care a lot
about photosynthesis I understand
nutrients I understand the the breeding
techniques I understand a lot of the
cycles and processes of the plant but
when it comes to understanding the
lighting my brain doesn't care to learn
all of that so that's probably where I
need to do the most Improvement is
learning about lighting what's your weak
area I admitted mine don't be
embarrassed let's work on it and get
better at it together in 2024 I know
everybody's got that one thing that they
need to work on but what else can you
improve in the grow I'm sure there are a
few small details uh maybe you're not
taking time to clean up after yourself
like me maybe you're not phing properly
maybe uh you're in a rush on one thing
maybe you're not paying attention to one
detail let's take a minute and look at
the grow and look at our processes and
see what we can improve on what are you
doing in that grow that is just habit
what are you doing that is just ritual
are the things you're doing in your grow
space in your uh in your standard
operating procedure every day day when
you go in there you check the room you
look at the plants you do your thing I
don't know what you're doing in there we
all have our own uh method to our
Madness in there but in your standard
operating procedure does everything make
sense is there a move in there that
you're doing like I said that is just a
ritual that is just because do you know
why you're doing everything that you're
doing you might be able to eliminate
certain processes certain steps maybe
even certain products in your grow if
you just take a step back and analyze
what you're doing in there dayby day in
your standard operating procedure maybe
you're doing something weird because you
learned it from your hippie Uncle who
learned it from his hippie uncle and
nobody has any idea why you're doing it
you just heard that it works pay
attention check on that stuff see if
it's some actual stuff or if it's just
habit or Voodoo or a ritual that is
making you feel good is it really doing
something let's also think about the
money we're spending in there are we
being cost effective in the grow are all
the products you're buying providing
some sort of value to the grow are they
adding some sort of value to the outcome
also think about your time in there um I
don't think about the time that I'm in
my grow as being uh hours on the clock
or uh part of the cost of growing that
product because I love being in there
that's my zen space also it's been
really cold and it's nice and warm in
the grow so if it's middle of the day
and I've been out running errands and I
come home and I'm [ __ ] freezing
sometimes I just go in the grow and
defoliate just to warm up I'll be in
there just doing it but if you're a
working person who is using this grow as
part of an come document your time in
there see where you can streamline your
time if you can't be in there all day
I've got the freedom the ability the
lifestyle to spend as much time as I
really want to in my grow with limits
you know but many people don't have that
luxury uh we've got families jobs uh
careers Hobbies relationships uh all of
the above that keep us busy so think
about the time that you're in there and
see if you are making the most of your
time in that growth space like I said
before if you've got weird rituals or
whatever maybe we can eliminate those
and focus and get in that grow and do
what needs to be done and get out and
even make the grow more efficient by
doing so now I did touch on this part
several times here in this episode one
thing I definitely recommend if if you
were comfortable with this if you were
in a legal state if you're in a
proabition area do this part very
carefully possibly if you choose to do
this but I like to keep a grow Journal
um I keep a simple notepad in my phone I
use the notes app in my iPhone and I've
got little notes that are headline with
each grow space my grow rooms all have
names uh and each grow room with each
name I've got a different list of notes
that I've done in that room I just keep
track of what I've done um
hypothetically we'll say today that I
fed that room uh 10 gallons of water
then I'd write down each nutrient that I
put in that water I'd write down the pH
of the solution then I would write down
the EC then I would water I'd probably
write down the temperature and humidity
of the room too as I documented it as I
was watering just making random notes
all of that [ __ ] is kept in my AC
Infinity little monitor there but I
wrote it down too so if I want to go
look it's there in my notes what I fed
it the AC Infinity didn't write down
what I fed it I knew the temp and
humidity at a certain time I wrote down
what I fed it uh I know wrote down what
time I fed it what date so if I see a
problem in a few days I can go well what
did I feed it and I can look back and I
go oh I [ __ ] up and gave it too much
calag I gave it calag two feedings in a
row didn't need to do that I see the
issue if I defoliate I'll write down I
defoliated the room really heavily or
really lightly if I notice something a
small presence of fungus snats I'll
write that sort of [ __ ] down um don't
forget to buy this I also make myself
notes like that but start a grow Journal
write down definitely write down the day
a clone was cut write down the day a
seed was germinated write down the day
that that clone or seed went into dirt
write down the next day you transplanted
that write down the day that it went
into flow uh write down the day that you
change the timer if you make changes
write that down if I adjust my air
conditioner up or down one or two
degrees I write that down if I change
the humidifier the dehumidifier I write
that down everything gets documented so
that when I'm looking at the plants and
I go what the [ __ ] happened I don't
wonder what the [ __ ] happened it's
somewhere in the notes I just got to
read and say oh on this day I turned up
the [ __ ] air conditioner or I turned
down the dehumidifier and everything
went to [ __ ] three days later maybe this
has something to do with it just save
some sort of notes give yourself some
sort of Journal set yourself up for
success that way if you have problems
you can look back and see what you did
wrong but also if you grow the best weed
you've ever grown you've already got the
blueprint you can do it all over again
repeat everything you did in the last
cycle so one thing I definitely
recommend is keeping a grow Journal you
can get many beautiful great journals on
Amazon if you're the kind of person that
writes stuff down you can get a plain uh
notebook paper notebook if you want you
can get one of those mol skin journals
you can just use the iPhone you can use
Google Docs however you want to do it
how ever you feel comfortable with in
your environment like I said if you're
in a Prohibition State those notes may
be used against you in a court of law so
be careful with that but it's safe and
legal here in Colorado we're actually
required in a commercial grow we're
required to document all the pesticides
we apply we're required to document
defoliation weight uh we even have to
document how much trash we take out of
the grow space so just get in the habit
of documenting things it will be good
for you if if that is something you're
comfortable with in your area all right
I feel like if giv you a lot of tips and
tricks and planners to set yourself up
for Success here in the New Year in your
grow space the most important part
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls is
to have fun and enjoy growing don't make
it stressful don't make it burdensome
don't make it a chore uh make sure you
have fun grow from your heart breed with
love and have a good time in that growth
space I think your final product will uh
reflect the uh the input that you did in
that grow if you're not there enough if
you're just growing it just to grow it
those PL are going to show you if you're
in there every day giving them love
giving them attention taking care of
them the way that they need it those
plants are going to show you so give
those plants the love that they deserve
give them the care that they deserve if
you're anxious nervous having a bad day
uh maybe you got some road rage from
traffic maybe you're having a a fight
with your big brother maybe your cousin
uh stole your shoes I'm just making [ __ ]
up if something went wrong and you're
not uh physically mentally spiritually
right maybe don't go in there and spread
that stress to the plants unless going
in there does give you that feeling of
relief my grow space is my zen space uh
the air conditioner and the blower is so
loud in there that I can't hear you if
you're talking anyway I don't pay
attention to the phone very much when
I'm in there so I can't hear [ __ ] I'm
just zoned out listening to the blowers
listening to the fans watching the
leaves Russell that is my zen space so
don't think about stressful negative
[ __ ] when you're in the grow space don't
think about your wallet don't think
about how much money this crop is going
to be worth when it's harvested don't
think like that think about how good
people are going going to feel when they
consume this product that you put your
time your energy your love and your care
into that is the rewarding part of
growing good ganja so like I said before
grow from your heart and breed with love
and put love and care into your garden
and it will reflect back at you you'll
have a beautiful Harvest if you put that
love and care into it ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers old school listeners new
followers new supporters I want to give
a big thank you to each and every one of
you for listening to another episode of
The Grow from your heart podcast I look
forward to putting out more quality
content in 2024 can't stop won't stop
thank you for all the listens and
support I'm going to wrap up this
podcast make sure you check out my
website IR genetics.com there's a link
to uh the Discord you can join the
Discord server there's a link to the
patreon campaign where you can support
the show there's a link to iir where you
can buy seeds and soon the link to the
merchandise store where you can buy
shirts hats and more merch will be
updated very soon make sure you check
out I genetics.com if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns please do send me an email the
email address is grow fromy yourheart at
hotmail.com that's all I've got for you
ladies and gentlemen have a great safe
New Year kickass in 2024 uh I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Chad
Westport and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for
me the Jeff you bad
[Music]
[ __ ] big up yourself every time
R the
[Music]
[Applause]
Jeff
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah
tell to take another DB grab your p in
and I about the
b in the lab back
relax