[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode 82
six of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got a fun episode lined up
for us in this episode I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about the free seeds later in the
episode I do want to take this moment to
invite you to the dude grov cup that is
happening June 1st in Fort Collins
Colorado that's right the dude Groves
cup is coming back I will be there white
Mike will be there the iy Army will be
there we cordially invite you to join us
at the dude grows cup make sure you
check out dgc cup.com for all the links
deets and info you may need tickets are
on sale now so get those tickets because
the event does sell out every year all
right now we're going to Segway into one
of my new favorite sections of this
podcast this is of course the pet peeve
section of the show this is the part of
the podcast where we talk about
something that just may drive you crazy
in a grow room maybe you see it in other
people's grows maybe you see it in
pictures on the internet maybe you work
at a commercial grow where some weird
[ __ ] happens this is the section of the
show where we can air those grievances I
call this the pet PE section today I'm
going to share with you one of my major
pet peeves about growing about the
Cannabis industry it is something very
simple it is when a breeder gives
somebody seeds and those seeds go into a
collection box and never make it into
any dirt or into any Grow rooms you guys
you gals you Growers you smokers uh we
put a lot of work we as breeders put a
lot of work into producing those seeds
when we give you seeds we're like hey
bro you want some new [ __ ] it's cool
that you want to keep it you want to
cherish it you want to keep it like a
Keepsake or something put it in that
treasure box and keep it forever but as
a breeder it would be really cool if you
grew at least a couple of those seeds
that I gave you anyway that's my pet
peeve I understand you they're like
Pokemon cards you want to catch them all
you want to collect them all you want to
have them in that Vault but as the
breeder grow that [ __ ] man grow it we
want to see what it does we want to see
what you do with it that's why we gave
it to you so one of my pet peeves is
seeds sitting in a box I wish I could
start giving my friends seeds that are
already folded in paper towels you guys
did order tester seeds on the internet I
wish I could send those to you already
folded up in a wet paper towel so it's
like hey they're started for you now
you're on a timeline you've got to get
them going now that way we know you're
going to grow them I wish I could do
that with the testers it's not realistic
I understand not everybody's able to
grow them right away I understand you do
have other things lined up I do
understand that you've got a grow room
plan a grow room strategy but still it
would be cool if you grew that [ __ ] that
we sent you for free all right that is
my pet peeve for today's episode I would
like to hear your grow room or your
cannabis Community pet peeve kees maybe
you've seen something in a grow room uh
maybe you've seen it on the internet
maybe you've seen it at a commercial
grow maybe somebody says or does
something that just drives you crazy in
our community this is a good spot to air
that grievance you can reach out to me I
have a website it is IR genetics.com on
that website there is a top row of tabs
one says grow help or grow questions if
you click on that tab that tab is
designed for you to be able to send me
grow room questions and I can help you
with your growth if you need help send
them there but this is also the
opportunity for you to send me your grow
room pet peeves use that growel tab send
me your pet peeves if I read your pet
peeve here on the podcast I will send
you a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds on iy direct.com also if I read
those growroom questions from the growel
tab I will also send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds so please do
send me those grow room pet peeves uh
use that grow help tab also if you need
help in the grow room send me those grow
questions on that growel tab once again
if I read those questions or pet peeves
here on the air you will get that coupon
code for a free pack of IE genetics
premium seeds all right I've got one
more piece of business to cover before
we jump into the email portion of
today's podcast you may have noticed
that for a short while I was posting
shorts on YouTube maybe you didn't
notice if you didn't go check them out
I've posted a few shorts on YouTube
basically they are short clips taken
from long episodes I watched some of the
shows I found a few uh key moments that
I thought would be notable I cut them
out then I post them I edit them up a
little bit and then I post them to
YouTube as shorts it's great it does a
lot of advertising for the show I've
noticed I do get more subscribers and
more viewers because I post those shorts
I honestly don't have the time to make
those shorts so here's where I'm going
to ask for help ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls cannabis Community my
video editing friends out there if
you're watching these podcasts and you
see key moments that you think could be
turned into useful shorts or useful
clips for social media I would
appreciate it if you clip those moments
edit them down to they need to be
between 30 and 55 seconds long if I want
to use them as shorts so if you're
watching the show you see a notable
moment uh clip that out it could be a
longer segment that you chop down into
30 to 55 seconds so that I can post it
but find that clip that you think is
good that may stand out chop it out uh
turn it into a 30 to 55 second clip if
you want to put a cool intro a cool
outro on it or don't I can add that if
necessary on my own or I can use it as
it is if you want to put a filter or a
texture on it uh that is up to to you do
your artistic creative thing on it but
if you can send me one or two shorts as
an audition I would truly appreciate
those then if I like your style maybe we
can work something out what I would like
to do honestly is trade you a few packs
of seeds for a few shorts maybe you
could send me a few now a few in the
future and then I'll send you a few
seeds now a few seeds in the future
we'll keep it like a continuous trade
going that way you're always stacked up
with new seeds and then I've always got
new shorts to post I love the shorts
they do a great job but honestly I
simply don't have time to rewatch the
podcast pull the shorts out edit them
back down and then post them that takes
a lot of time so if anybody out there
would like to make those short clips for
me I would love to trade you seeds or we
could work out some sort of other
compensation for your time once again
what I need is a short clip somewhere
between 30 and 55 seconds long you can
do your artistic creativity to it uh you
could take a long clip that's a 3 minute
ramble and you can cut it out uh and
make it 30 to 55 5 Seconds what we need
is things that will uh draw people into
the podcast to get people watching get
people's attention in that quick short
time all right I wanted that ramble to
be much shorter I went way too long on
it so I'm going to wrap that up and say
I look forward to your response the best
way to reach out to me is use my email
address grow from yourheart
hotmail.com all right I feel like we
covered all of the business at the start
of the show now it is time to work into
the email section of today's podcast I
do get a bunch of great emails once
again I mentioned that growel tab on IR
genetics.com if you go to my website iry
genetics.com on the top there's a row of
tabs one says grow questions or grow
help click on that tab if you have a
grow question please do send me your
grow question through that tab if I read
your question here on the show you will
win a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds on idirect decom this first
question did not come from the growel
tab uh this one came from YouTube we
also talked about this a little bit on
my Instagram live I was intrigued by
this question I thought I would address
this here on the show this is a great
one this one came from my friend who
wants to be known as Brian 420 p.m.
thank you for the great message Brian
this one showed up on YouTube it said
it's so great for us consumers to hear
from a breeder from a breeder directly
like this I love your transparency well
thank you very much that means a lot to
me uh I do realize that that does help
me out a lot in this community in this
industry many of the Breeders will sell
you a pack of seeds and once you've got
their money that's the end of the story
they won't respond to your emails your
messages uh there's no contact there's
no show where you can find them no
Discord where you can conversate with
them uh they take your money and they
salute you if you get that much they
mail you a package and it's all over at
that point uh I believe in customer
service I believe in being a part of the
community I believe that the product I
sell you should be of quality you should
be satisfied with what you get and I
feel no need to hide I feel like I'm
sending you a good product so many of my
people tell me uh what a good product
they get from me and if anybody does
have problem I'm quick to correct it so
the transparency thank you for noticing
you said I love the transparency thank
you I've got nothing to hide and I feel
like uh it it means a lot to uh the
community the iy Army you guys know that
I'm here uh if you got a problem with
the package of seeds or even just a grow
question you can message me I do get a
lot of messages so sometimes everybody's
message does not get answered promptly
but I try to answer most of the messages
I receive and I'm on Discord way more
than I should admit so if you really
have a question a problem a concern you
can find me on the Discord server pop in
uh if I'm not there I'll be there soon
and we can talk about whatever is going
on uh if we need to we could break off
into a private chat and talk about it
there but uh thank you for noticing the
transparency and it does make a big
difference I notice it makes a big
difference in the community when I go to
events I notice uh the few breeders
there are other breeders that put their
faces out there and shout out to them
the folks the guys the gals that put
their faces out there and they're on the
internet they're the ones at the events
that have large booths that have more
people at their table that have more
traffic uh the people that keep their
head down and they don't put their faces
out there and they don't answer messages
you can see at the events because
there's no traffic at their Booth so
thanks for noticing that now it does go
on it says based on only customer
feedback in the last year which of your
strains collected the most positive
sentiment now that was a really good
question I did also talk about this on
my Instagram live show if you're not
following me on Instagram I'm _ gentics
on Instagram be careful there are a
couple of fake accounts I'm the one with
35 Point something thousand followers
the others have like hundreds of
followers so don't be duped uh but this
did come through on my Instagram live
every Monday night I do a live show at
7:10 p.m. mountain time on every Monday
uh on Instagram so find my Instagram I
genetics Monday 7:10 Mountain Time watch
for me to go live I'll be up there on
the top click me you can watch me do a
live show you can ask me questions
interact and hang out and then after
that I go play on Discord as well so
Mondays are busy but uh this came up on
the Instagram I don't recall the answer
that I gave on Instagram I may have said
blueberry butcher but after the
Instagram live show I took a moment and
I went and looked and kind of read some
messages and scrolled through some
things and looked at some uh customer
service emails and some reviews and I
don't remember the answer I for sure
gave on Instagram but after thinking
about it and looking into it a little
bit uh The Strain that got the most uh
positive sentiment the most accolades
the most not Mo most notable strain from
my lineup this year that's harder to say
than it looks uh I'm going to say it was
a tie uh between the orange gasm and the
blueberry butcher Orange gasm has been
my most popular strain for two or three
years uh it sells very well it grows
very well it's got great results I get a
lot of great customer feedback from the
orange GM but recently I've noticed the
blueberry butcher may be passing that
one up in popularity it's also newer so
it's got more hype behind it um people
are really having great success with
that blueberry butcher it makes gigantic
buds it's got tremendous potency it
tastes really good it makes all kinds of
amazing extracts if you're doing it with
BHO if you're doing it with water if
you're pressing it the concentrates come
out really well from that blueberry
butcher so it's going to be a tie uh
between that orange gasm and the
blueberry butcher then in third place I
know you only asked for one but uh it's
my podcast I can ramble if I want to the
third place winner in that competition
would be the lemon Jeffrey so my number
three most notable strains it's going to
be a tie between orange gasm and
blueberry butcher currently uh number
three or maybe that's number two is the
Lemon Jeffrey uh maybe number three so
top three orange gasm blueberry Butcher
and lemon Jeffrey are the three that are
getting the most notoriety now now that
will shift because I've put out a lot of
new stuff recently uh people just simply
have not had time to grow all of it and
send back a bunch of great feedback
there's new stuff coming out there's new
stuff in testing there's new stuff
that's recently been released so people
are growing that and there will be new
feedback on that within the next uh 3 6
9 12 months especially over the next 18
months all those reports will start
coming in we will see a big shift now
I'm going to add on to this subject you
mentioned uh the strains that got the
most positive sentiment I mentioned
those three now I want to talk about the
strain of the year for 2003 that I feel
like got overlooked the most I make a
lot of great strains uh I grow them I
send them out to friends to grow them
and then we put them online for other
people to grow them I see what you guys
are growing because you post your
pictures on social media you send me
pictures you share the photos on Discord
please join the Discord server and post
your pictures of my lines over there but
uh from all the results that I've seen I
think people are really sleeping on the
red line red line is an amazing plant it
produces gigantic flowers uh they're
super potent they've got amazing Aromas
and flavors if you're a concentrate
maker Redline is made from Red Lebanese
hash plant so it is a hash plant
derivative uh the red line is very
overlooked I feel like it would have
sold more I feel like it would have been
more sought-after and more hyped up but
people kind of seem to be sleeping on
the red line so those are my top three
best sellers and the red line is the one
that got overlooked this year I think
previously in the previous years uh
Scarlett Bonas was the one that got
snubbed and overlooked uh both of those
strains the red line and the Scarlett
Bonas or hot fire and they just didn't
get a notice uh sometimes I wonder if it
was my marketing if it was timing if it
was the strain name a lot of times it's
the strain name that does that people
weren't into the strain Scarlet Bonas
for some reason but I wonder what what
does it sometimes I know what's going to
make a strain stand out it's because
it's hot fire uh the name is great the
flavor is great the photos are great but
then I put up Red Line right next to it
I think it's a cool name uh Redline
because when you smoke it your eyes get
stupid red and also that's as high as
you're going to get you're red lining
and then also I used to ride bikes when
I was a kid and it's a tribute to the
red line bicycles I rode GTS but red
lines were around um but the red line uh
one of the most overlooked plants in my
opinion what really was funny that
happened though is Scarlett Bonas I do
still have some Scarlet Bonia seeds very
few I need to package them up get them
on the website but those are almost gone
what I thought was funny is when I was
almost out of scarlet Bonia seeds The
Strain got real popular and people
wanted it now that it's gone I don't
make it anymore I'm not interested in it
now it's hyped up that's probably what
will happen to the red line all right my
dude Brian 4:20 p.m um I do owe you a
pack of seeds this did not come through
the proper Avenue but it was a great
question it gave me a lot of good
Rambles so uh Brian 4:20 p.m. please do
reach out to me uh please don't fake it
don't tell me you're Brian if you're not
uh Brian reach out to me do it on
YouTube send me a message or a comment
on YouTube with your email address or
with a way to get in touch with you
because I would like to send you a c a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iy direct.com all right let's keep this
party moving I have another great
question here this one did come from the
growel tab this one came from somebody
who wants to be called soda what's up
soda is this soda from Discord good to
see you bro even if it's not soda from
Discord you should join the Discord and
then you will be the other soda on
Discord I'm super rambly today I don't
remember what I smoked I wish I did so
that I could tell you anyway this
question is a general grow question it
says I'm just wondering about Federal
rescheduling or descheduling yes there's
a lot of talk lately about the DEA uh
rescheduling or uh rescheduling or
descheduling cannabis uh lots of talk
there's no true info out yet at the time
of this recording it does go on though
it says do you think breeders will be
able or even want to send out flower
tester packs before folks decide which
seeds to buy that is a pretty cool idea
he clears it up he says what I mean by
that is maybe a couple of nugs or
pre-rolls of each flowered product so
you know which seeds to buy based off
the effects you get when you try a test
sampler think of it like a sampler at a
micro Brewery I like that idea yeah I
was just seeing myself walking around
Costco getting little samples as you
said that uh it says this would be just
an additional product people purchase if
they fixed the laws yeah that is a
really cool idea I do like that um I see
some pros and cons to that um it may set
a really weird expectation if I grew a
bunch of uh let's just say pick a strain
what's coming out real soon we're going
to say light Ripper uh light Ripper is
coming soon you guys p91 to Jack the
Ripper light Ripper is coming it will be
released very soon stay tuned check out
iir sign up for the newsletter all that
good stuff um but light Ripper is coming
let's just say I wanted to advertise
light Ripper so I grew whatever a whole
bunch of light Ripper and I rolled up um
or just divided up a bunch of grams
let's say I took a pound and I gave you
a whole bunch of grams you got it all in
grams and then people that were tempted
to buy the seeds could order a sample
for whatever a gram would cost and then
we could hypothetically send it in the
mail um maybe I would have light Ripper
maybe I would also have uh what else is
something that's going to come out soon
I don't want to give you guys too many
uh tinf foil hat maybe I got some
tinfoil hat packs maybe I got some parad
packs uh but maybe I got the weed also
and then I could send you a parad Graham
A tinfoil hat gram a light Ripper Graham
and you can get all those and you can
smoke those and then you can decide
which strain you want to buy those seeds
from that is a really cool idea but
here's the catch I've been growing weed
for a really long time I've grown weed
I've grown cannabis in basements I've
grown cannabis in attics I've grown
cannabis in uh rooms that have been
built under stairs I've also uh grown
cannabis in Giant commercial production
facilities I've grown in all different
types of ways I also bred this product
that we were sampling I should be able
to grow this like a pro I should be able
to grow the [ __ ] out of this this should
be award-winning so I may be setting uh
an unrealistic expectation if I grow it
and I send it to you and you choose from
those three um maybe I chose a different
phenotype than you maybe I had better
lighting than you maybe I had better
nutrients than you maybe I've just
simply got more experience and you're
going to make your selection based off
of my grow which that's cool but y grow
won't be the same so maybe it won't come
out the same for you but I see what
you're saying it's a really cool idea
I'm just saying as the breeder I like
the idea but I'm also sketched out by
the idea for a few reasons most of the
time I think the descriptions and the
genetics give people a pretty good idea
of why they want a strain and why they
want to grow it so um uh it's a really
cool hypothetical idea it's a really
cool fantasy it's a really cool what if
um but there's a lot of things to think
about that come with it now what I wrote
down is bro that's what the events are
for things like the dude grow cup The
Groovy gravy event uh the emerald cup
any of the other big consumption events
or the big uh uh community events where
you go and you're allowed to consume
that's what that is for um the Breeders
The Growers we try to bring samples
sometimes the venues tell us we can't we
try to sneak them in anyway sometimes we
do what we can sometimes we simply don't
have samples ready we between crops or
whatever but uh what we like to do is
bring a sample so if we're going to the
dude grows cup I want to sell you a
bunch of orange gasm or lemon Jeffree
seeds why wouldn't I grow a whole bunch
of orange gasm or lemon Jeffrey jar it
up and bring it with me to the event
have it sitting on the table that way
when you're like hey I'm thinking about
buying orange gas I'm be like there it
is smell it and you go holy [ __ ] I have
to buy two packs of that so uh the
events is where that is all about also
what's beautiful about the events you
can find uh five six 10 or 20 people
that are growing itic strains and you
can sample from different people who
have grown it uh in different
environments different conditions with
different lights uh different nutrients
uh different completely different
methods all together soilless mix cocoa
Hydro um however you can grow cannabis I
was trying to come up with some smartass
way but we'll stay focused but people
are growing it from California to Maine
uh people we got people in Maine where
it's snowing right now we got people in
Arizona where it's hot right now
everybody's growing it in different eni
environments and conditions and we all
meet up at the dude grows cup and you
can say hey this guy grew Raphael in
Arizona this grew Raphael in Missouri
and you can see both of their samples
and this guy grew Orange gasm in
Colorado and this guy grew Orange gasm
in Maine and you can look at both of our
samples and you can see kind of a
variety of what IE genetics has to offer
by coming to the events with the
community so not only do you get to come
see the product smoke the product you
get to meet a bunch of people you get to
meet uh the iy Army all the people
you've been talking to on the Discord
and then you'll also get an opportunity
to meet Mike and myself we're not shy uh
we are stuck behind the booth most of
the time because we've got work to do
but come up to the booth you don't have
to buy seeds you don't have to buy
anything to come to my booth and say hi
if I'm not busy if there's not a long
line there there's points in the day
where the booth gets really dead and
really slow it comes in waves when
there's not a wave if you just want to
come [ __ ] come [ __ ] dude that's
what we are there for come shake my hand
give me a fist bump give me a hug if
that's what you're into say hi uh meet
us come say hi um smoke some of the weed
meet the community and say hi to us is
what it's all about so I'm rambling once
again I'm remember what I smoked bro but
it was [ __ ] good it's working but um
this would be a cool idea it' be cool if
I could send you out some samples like
every few months just be like hey here's
five different samples let me know what
seed pack you're into and we can get you
that that would be cool but that is
really what the community events are for
so get out there join the community move
around and go to as many of the events
as you can there are a bunch of events
coming up I'm not sponsored by any of
the events I'm not sponsoring any of the
events but there's the dude grow cup
there is rumored to be a groovy gravy
secret stash coming up there are two
different Boo Crew meetups coming up um
uh lemon hoko does his Meetup every year
there's the emerald cup there are plenty
of other random cups all throughout the
country go to those be a part of that
Community meet more people and then find
out where the next event is going to be
in your community then start branching
Out start traveling around go to more of
the events meet more of the family all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen Chu
ERS All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
short episode of The Grow fromy heart
podcast I've been trying to keep them
short I notice you guys watch all the
way to the end if they are shorter if
you want longer episodes argue in the
comments I'll see what I can do for you
thank you once again for listening if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
send me your questions Corrections
comments or concerns of course if you do
have a pet peeve or a grow room question
use that growel tab on IR genetics.com
everything you could possibly need is on
that website IR genetics.com there's a
link to the patreon server there's a
link to the Discord server uh there's a
link to the website to get the seeds
everything you can imagine is at IR
genetics.com also if you've listened
this far make sure you use coupon code
love for 10% off at irir that's right if
you're shopping at iir use coupon code
love to save 10% um right now I'm doing
a sale while I'm recording this episode
I'm doing a sale on edirect we are doing
an inventory reduction blowout sale
that's right I need to count all the
inventory on I redirect but you know
what it's easier if there's no inventory
to count so I'm just going to blow it
out at Crazy Prices this will come out
uh probably during the weekend uh there
may still be some stuff left that coupon
code love will still apply all the other
coupon codes you have will still apply
so go hit I redirect and grab the packs
you've been thinking about getting while
they are still there there uh once these
seeds all do blowout we will do an
inventory we will do a fresh restock and
some new drops but if you want some
packs at a blowout price now is the time
all right that's all I've got for you
I'll be back in one week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my little brother Hawaiian Jay and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]
[Music]
big up yourself every time Ry
[Applause]
[Music]
Jeff
[Applause]
[Music]
tell the take another DB grab your pie
in and I go find the B Ro is in the lab
sit back on relax hold