[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 828 of the
grow from your heart podcast in this
episode we're going to talk about
breeding I'm also going to give away
free seeds that's right hang out we'll
talk more about the free seeds later on
in this episode I also want to let you
know that there will be a Valentine's
Day sale at idirect decom that's right
idirect decom will get a fresh restock a
fresh drop of new products and prices
will be reduced for Valentine's Day make
sure you check out idirect decom for the
Valentine's Day Sale all right all right
I don't want to waste too much time here
at the start of the show let's jump
right into most people's favorite
portion of the podcast that is the
growel portion of today's show all of
today's questions are going to be
focused on breeding all of the questions
also came from the growel tab on my
website that's right my website is iry
genetics.com make sure you go to iry
genetics.com there's a row of tabs on
the top one of them says questions or
growel click on that tab there will be a
few preliminary questions we will ask
what type of question do you have is it
a garden question is it a general
question if it's a grow question we will
then ask about the the temperature the
humidity indoors Outdoors basic
questions to give me an idea of how to
help this grow question then most
importantly we give you a space to ask
your grow question send me those grow
questions by using that growel tab if I
read your question here on the show you
will win a free coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at IR direct.com the first
question on today's breeding podcast
came from our friend who wants wants to
be called Brian ja big shout out to
Brian ja thank you for the good breeding
question this question goes a lot like
this it says yo Rasta Jeff I appreciate
the knowledge the help and amazing
products that you provide that is a
great way to start a question thank you
very much bro for the love and support
thank you for noticing it says I have
grown out the Golden Goat batross and
the Scarlet Bonas and even though I made
some really big mistakes the plants were
some of the best I have ever grown that
is a huge compliment to my genetics uh
you would aded that you made a few
mistakes and they were still some of the
best that you've ever grown uh good job
for having a great successful grow and
also good job for admitting that you've
made some mistakes in there that's a
hard part for a lot of people to do so
great job admitting it and also good job
on that great crop it goes on it says I
am currently in week six with the
machine and the plants are exactly what
I am looking for the aroma is awesome
yes the machine is hot fire I hope it
works out beautifully for you take care
of it but let it finish all right there
is more to this message let's get get to
the breeding question we all know
there's a question here it says I am
planning on making my first batch of
seeds that is always a fun project it
says I'm going to use your Jack the
Ripper F2 number five that is going to
be an awesome project as well it says
you and subcool have taught me so much
there are no better seeds to start with
my friend that is a huge honor um I am
doing my best to uh pass the torch that
subcool passed to me subcool was about a
generation ahead of me uh in the
Cannabis world he taught me a lot about
cannabis you guys I often say that
subcool taught me a lot of what to do
and a lot of what not to do uh in the
Cannabis world in the Cannabis industry
in the Cannabis community so big shout
out big rest in peace to my buddy
subcool but it is an honor to think that
subcool and myself are the two guys
teaching you and inspiring you to breed
and that you want to use my uh Jack the
Ripper f2s which maybe some people don't
know that Jack the Ripper was originally
made by subol I was given uh honor and
Blessing by his uh former partner and uh
what's the word there his X wife Miss
Jill um I was given the blessing to use
that Jack the Ripper in a breeding
project I've made f2s of it I've also
made a lot of outcrosses with it but our
friend Brian ja here has chosen the Jack
the Ripper F2 number five phenotype to
make his very first breeding project
with because he learned a lot of what he
knows from sub cool and I that's a huge
honor uh to sub and myself so thank you
now let let me get myself back on track
it says my goal is to grow plants with
the strongest smell and taste possible
that is a very good goal um and I'm not
going to critique you here this is your
very first breeding project you're
inspired you're looking for uh the
strongest smell which of course is what
everybody wants and taste possible we
all want that smell and taste but what
about uh things like potency what about
plant Vigor what about structure uh what
about resistance to problems like
pathogens and maybe bugs what about
resistance to Drought what about the
ability to tolerate light stress or cold
stress press those are just other things
I would recommend you also add to the
requirement list here if you don't know
about all the positive traits that you
should be looking for in a plant you
might not look for them so I just want
to remind you that it is awesome to
breed for that Aroma and flavor but what
about Vigor what about plant structure
uh what about potency those are also
things to consider this is your breeding
project you can do whatever you want I
just want to throw some ideas at you
because you're new I'm not discouraging
um focus on that smell and taste if
that's what you'd like to do but also
keep in mind those other things I
mentioned structure growth flowering
time what if these plants take 140 days
to flower but they taste exactly how you
like is that tolerable most people
wouldn't accept that so just things to
think about there other than just taste
and aroma so it says knowing that is
there a male I should look for that will
fit these characteristics that you that
you can talk about in the description
now um unfortunately the hard part about
seeking a male is that the only way to
truly tell what flavor and Aroma that
male plant is going to pass to the
progyny is by breeding with him um so
you've got to find a male we'll talk
about that a little bit more in here I
do have some criteria for helping you
find a male but you've got to find a
male then what you also got to do is
you've got to find the female is there a
female plant that tastes very close or
exactly like what you're looking for is
that female plant available the first
part of this is to find that girl that
tastes very much like that uh the flavor
that you're seeking so find that female
plant then find a male now a moment ago
I talked about structure and vigor and
all that let me refer to my notes here
because I did make a couple of notes
that are very important in my opinion in
my experience in my reading from what I
understand to the best of my knowledge
but I am not an expert um generally in
most instances that male plant the male
part of the uh the the program here the
mail plant of the equation is the word
I'm looking for contributes to the
structure the Vigor and the flowering
time heavily and the pest and pathogen
resistance a lot of that stuff comes
from the male side of the equation so
select a male and my what I would
recommend is find a female that's got
the flavor if you're just breeding for
flavor find a female plant with the
exact flavor you're looking for then
find a male from the Jack the Jack the
Ripper line that has structure that has
Vigor that's got all of the physical or
all of the visual things that you can
see find that from the male plant
because what I think what I believe is
the male contributes heavily heavily
heavily to the structure the Vigor the
flowering time um and the pest and
pathogen and stress resistance a lot of
that will come from the male so if you
insist on going mostly for flavor find a
girl that tastes real good CU we can
already verify that she's got that
Flavor now look for that male that has
the structure you like then like I keep
saying also look for that female with
the flavor and Aroma then breed them
together together and then you're going
to find a phenotype out of there that
will carry that structure that Vigor
that plant growth traits that you're
looking for and it will also have that
flavor and Aroma because it's already in
there it's an ingredient we've mixed
that in we've stirred it up some of the
phenotypes that come from this will have
that flavor guaranteed now if you really
want to lock that in if you want to do
this um you said knowing that uh you
asked about a male I'm going to totally
throw you off track you could do
feminized seeds if you find a girl a
female plant that's got the traits that
you're in love with you could easily
reverse that plant uh take two clones of
it reverse one put that pollen on the
other and make feminized seeds of that
plant if that is what you wanted to do
if you're going strictly for flavor but
I like your idea uh you're going to it
sounds like you plan to start with a
male and a female which would be awesome
so like I've said multiple times now
find the female that tastes just like
what you're looking for find a male with
the structure the Vigor um a good
growing male you'll know it when you see
it um subcool taught me this and I'm
going to pass this knowledge on to you
at the same time um most of the let's
just hypothetically say you've got a 10
pack of seeds usually there's 10 seeds
in my 10 packs there's usually 12 so you
got probably 10 of them worked for you
just because you might be a new grower
I'm just making assumptions here we're
just doing math out of the air you got
10 seeds most of the time five of them
will be female five will be male um the
females are easy to select from because
we can um we get to experience them we
get to grow them smell them touch them
smoke them consume them get high from
them and enjoy them the females will be
obvious which one you want the males we
don't necessarily get to smoke we don't
get to consume but the females are
easier to feno hunt here's how I kind of
do the boys we got five boys generally
there will be one or two that take off
flowering very early uh they're just
like hey look at me I'm a boy I want a
flower I'm going to get ahead of
everybody I'm going to grow bigger I'm
going to start making pollen those two
boys in that pack usually do not get to
be my breeding candidates and I'll
explain why from what subcool taught me
and from what I understand from my own
experience from using Subs guidance I
have learned an experience that those
males that flower too quickly that are
too eager to flower they pass too much
of themselves to my breeding project now
what I mean by that is if I take a male
I'm just going to pick something random
here I'm going to say chocolate if I
took a meil that is chocolate and I
pollinated strawberry banana lemons and
gas I want chocolate strawberry
chocolate lemons chocolate banana and
chocolate gas is what I hope to get out
of that if I use that first dude he will
make everything taste like chocolate I
just remake this dude all over again
because his genetics are so dominant are
so strong in this mix that all of his
kids look just like him mommy has no
chance of getting a daughter that looks
just like her it's all going to be a
bunch of [ __ ] Beefcake looking dudes
look just like this uh over testosteron
male that's the way that I can explain
it to you so those first two are usually
not the candidates the fifth one he's
taking too long to flower usually not
the candidate so it's usually the third
and fourth male in the mix to show me
that they're male usually one of them's
a little taller one of them's a little
different shaped that's what you're
going to usually that's what I choose
from is males number three and four out
of those five so the first two that take
off I don't like those the last one to
take off he's usually too slow it's
usually number three or number four
you'll have to decide do you want that
tall lanky one do you want the short
squatty one do you want the one with the
big wide leaves what I what I would
recommend is flower all five of them out
as far as you can if you can take them
to like week six week seven week eight
you'll get to see what type of flower
structure they develop you'll get to see
that big old flower cluster on the top
it is really fun and interesting
watching flowers on male plants develop
they're going to make a [ __ ] ton of
pollen so be careful if you've got other
rooms in flower try not to contaminate
those rooms with pollen but doing a male
phenol Hunt is very fun and very
rewarding if you've got the space and
time so flower out those boys look for
like I said remove one and two you'll
know they'll go into flower early one's
going to get way tall uh call those guys
three four and five keep an eye on those
numbers three and four those are going
to be your candidates out of a 10 pack
that is my experience so I've been
rambling for a couple of minutes about
that part find that good male that
provides that structure then we've got
to pollinate with him and like I said
before my goal in selecting a male is to
find a male that's going to put
chocolate or whatever selected flavor
into the mix so that I can make
chocolate strawberry chocolate but an I
don't want that dude that's just going
to dominate and those later flowering
guys they're not so dominant in their
genetics that when you breed to them
they're going to allow their qualities
their traits to pass into the progyny
but also Mommy gets a chance to show her
beauty and her expression in the
breeding as well let me get back to my
notes because I've gotten way off track
although I'm right where I need to be um
pollinate your favorite female and then
I put in parenthesis females something I
like to do I keep saying this when I'm
breeding with the male plant I just said
to take that chocolate and put it to
Strawberry bananas [ __ ] pineapples
watermelons breed it to everything the
reason I want to do that the reason I
recommended breeding your male plant to
multiple female plants different females
if you can um is because here's here's a
reason I want to see what he presents
and delivers and across across multiple
plants if I breed uh chocolate to
bananas and it comes out chocolate
bananas I know that these two plants
make chocolate bananas it doesn't give
me any evidence it doesn't give me any
it just gives me what these two plants
do if I breed that to strawberry and
lemon and one comes out chocolate
strawberry now I know that it delivers
that chocolate trait if the chocolate
and the banana plant both or the
strawberry and banana plant that I Brad
it to make progyny that are both uh
really really tall then I know that that
trait came from the mail plant if the
progyny uh come out with like a really
weird color across three different
progyny then I know that the male is
delivering that cuz that's the common it
in the mix so that's why I like to breed
to multiple different females from one
male plant now here's another option and
I'm going to [ __ ] with your head here uh
I'm assuming you've got a 10 pack of the
Jack the Ripper uh number five plants
one thing you could do which would be a
lot of fun and you will find the
phenotype that's got the flavor that
you're looking for you could put all 10
of those plants in a room all five boys
all five girls and you could just let a
wild crazy plant orgy happen in that
room and what that is called is an open
pollination
um if you were going to list that on
paper to describe it you would just say
uh five Jack the Ripper females cross to
five Jack the Ripper males and an open
pollination uh there are several good
reasons to do that uh it just makes a
lot more seeds if you want to preserve
this line and make a bunch more seeds
this will show you so many of uh the
genetic options this will show the
genetic potential in so many different
ways because you've got every male and
every female phenotype available for the
mix they're all going to pollinate each
other I don't know the mathematical
equation but uh it's 5 million something
or 250 million something is the way that
I think it would work if you took uh
plant number one and pollinated all five
of these that's five plants right and
then plant number two and pollinated all
five of these and you can do that that's
how it will work all five plants will
pollinate all five other plants you'll
have lines going to be String Theory all
crazy going from one plant to the other
but that is a possibility that open
pollination or you can remove anything
you don't like and still perform the
open pollin I'm just giving you
different ideas the first thing I would
do is find the female that tastes like
what you like find a male with the
structure the Vigor uh the leaf shape
the flowering time that you're into then
I would breed them then I would grow out
those seeds then I would try to find the
phenotype that tastes just like you're
looking for if you're satisfied with
that guess what Tada that is your first
breeding project and it is successful if
you find the phenotype your goal is to
find the fenal with your flavor desired
if you find that you have hit your goal
I would try to go for further
Generations uh this is a really fun idea
but if you were breeding strictly for
flavor um that's fun but what about
potency don't you want to get really
really high from it also so what I would
do is it's going to get you really high
it's Jack the Ripper it's going to have
the potency but if you're breeding
strictly for flavor think about it like
when we were building uh characters on a
video game they gave you a 100 points to
build your character we're just going to
say it was a basketball video game uh
you got some speed was one of the
attributes you got uh shooting accuracy
uh you got awareness uh you got stamina
and then there's probably something else
um who cares what it is right ability to
sell sneakers so you got all five of
these things you got to fill them up
with as much uh as much as you want but
you've only got a 100 points to put into
there so think about that the same thing
happens when we are breeding plants
you've got 100 points worth of
attributes to assign if you focus 90% of
that on Flavor the potency the Vigor all
that other stuff is going to fall to the
waist side so keep flavor and Aroma up
there real high as your importance but
also keep in mind that we need some
potency so um if you do insist on
breeding one plant strictly for flavor
what I would also do now this is where
it's going to get really interesting now
we're going to talk about line breeding
what the heck is line breeding you've
got your we're going to breed two
different lines of the same plants I'm
going to breed a Jack the Ripper uh F2
from you've got F2 so you're going to
breed F3
you're going to make the Jack the Ripper
F3 you're going to select for flavor
only just select for flavor then from
those f3s we're going to find those
seeds and select for flavor and make F4
from that batch of seeds we're then
going to make F5 Now by this time every
time we grow these seeds we should find
that exact same flavor every time almost
every plant 89 95% of these plants
should taste exactly the same just like
we we talked about just like you're
searching for because this is the fifth
generation that we have bred well you
got them at f2 this is the third or
fourth generation you've bred
specifically for that one specific
flavor if it didn't have that Aroma and
flavor you did not breed to it it got
knocked out it got pushed away out of
the breeding project we've gone five
generations locking down this Flavor now
what I would also do at the same exact
time I would run a parallel breeding
project of Jack the Ripper I would start
with the same exact seeds but on this
side I would breed for potency and uh
Vigor cuz I want a vigorous plant I want
a potent plant and a plant that tastes
good so we're going to focus line one is
Jack the Ripper flavor Town that's all
we're working on then on this other side
in this other breeding room I'm going to
breed a Jack the Ripper that is nothing
but potency and vigor I don't care what
it tastes like I don't care it could
taste like cardboard it could tastes
like dog puke as long it as long as it
is the most potent plant in the room and
it is vigorous when it grows that is
what I'm breeding for so I'm going to do
that F3 F4 F5 I may go to F6 on both
sides it just kind of depends on what
the phenotypes are showing me at this
point now on both sides when I germinate
these seeds I'm getting 89 to 95%
homozygous plants which means they all
look exactly the same on this side
they're all going to smell exactly like
that one Aroma that I'm going for that
Jack the Ripper lime turp that I found
that I'm in love with I've got it locked
in every phenotype makes it on this
other side every phenotype is
ridiculously potent and it's got an
amazing structure now guess what we're
going to do we're going to breed those
two together and that's going to be our
true F1 breeding project that could take
you 15 years to accomplish that to be
realistic with you don't rush that
project don't be in a hurry to do it but
to get to F5 F6 that's five or six years
worth of work right there if you do it
properly and then you got to do it on
two different sides on two different
lines you got to carefully
select at some point in that breeding
project there will be a misstep and you
will have to go backwards one generation
it happens don't be afraid that happens
when you're breeding you think this is
the male I need to use you do it and you
grow them out and you go well [ __ ] I
didn't find what I'm looking for in
there you just chose the wrong male not
a big deal just time space money you
still get to smoke all the weed and have
a good time but the breeding didn't make
any forward progress got to go back and
do it again so what I'm talking about
here is line breeding your first idea is
to create a strain that is completely
flavored town now I want to add to that
I want Vigor and potency so I'm going to
use the same genetics and just keep
going in filial generations and breeding
again a different project um either line
a or line b line one line two flavor
town and [ __ ] Tricom Town whatever
you want to call them just keep breeding
and then make this one only focused on
potency and structure and vigor and this
other one is just focused on Flavor then
when I get to the F5 or F6 I'll get the
female that has the flavor and the male
I'll find a male uh phenotype from from
that Pro from that uh population of
seeds that looks just like what I need
that structure I'm sure it's going to
pass on that potency pollinate that
flavor toown female and The Offspring
from that will be the Super vigorous the
super flavorful and the super potent
brand new F1 version of your line and
guess what also comes with that brand
new hybrid Vigor so that is a huge fun
project that is something that you could
definitely do um I may have taken this
simple answer way too far but this is a
really fun ramble um the easy way to do
it is to find that male that fits an
easy criteria find a female that tastes
good let them [ __ ] if you want to go
further I definitely give you a lot of
different Avenues to have fun with that
on my friend Brian I hope I thoroughly
answered your question this was a fun
breeding question for me I got to talk
about a lot of fun stuff we got to pay
tribute to our buddy subcool uh shout
out and rest in peace to subcool and
also my friend the best part maybe you
want a coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds that's right by
the time this episode comes out you will
have a coupon code in your email for
free seeds I've got your email right
here make sure you check the Spam if you
don't find it because sometimes they
think the codes are spammy all right
let's keep this party going I've got
another great question for you this one
came also from the growel tab at IR
genetics.com go to the website IR
genetics.com use that growel tab if I
read your question you do win a free
pack of iy genetics premium seeds this
one came from our friend Pegasus shout
out to p yo Pegasus check your email
check your spam folder because you my
friend have a coupon code for a free
pack of iy genetics premium seeds at
idirect tocom pegasus's question goes
just like this it says yo what's up
rosta Jeff yo what's up Pegasus it says
I have a question about breeding that is
very good this is the breeding episode
it says let's just say if I were to
breed a male arise plant with a female
Afterglow would The Offspring be in
different if I had used the opposite
plants the female arise and the male
Afterglow much thanks and keep on
growing yes this is a very good question
and ironically um I made Afterglow which
is uh Clementine to aise which is a huge
hit it kills it but then also uh I put
that Afterglow plant in a greenhouse and
pollinated that with the arise again so
the first half of this has happened
which is really weird that you brought
that up uh my idea there was to uh put a
little more power into the Afterglow
just a little more turbocharge but also
try to keep that orange turp uh it seems
to have worked I'm rambling at this
point let's answer the question at hand
here like I talked about just a moment
ago it is my belief my experience my
theory that much of that flavor and
Aroma is coming from the female side
many of the other traits do come from
the female side but is real what is
really noticeable is the flavor and the
aroma then what I think happens from the
male side like I said is that vigor the
structure the plant uh the flowering
time is heavily contributed by the male
I think the resistance to problems comes
from the male side so yes if you did
switch them you're just automatically
going to get different traits just and
the main thing that came to my mind is
knowing about breeding they're different
phenotypes um even if so the male the
male version of a rise and the female
version of a rise you may select
different phenotypes they're going to
have different traits within themselves
uh so that already starts us doing uh
different uh opportunities in the
progeny so um yes I do believe if you
reverse them um you're going to change
something definitely uh it's like I
believe kind of when you're breeding you
taking traits from chromosomes the
traits from Mom traits chromosomes from
Dad and you're putting them into a
whatever a primordial blender and you
shake it up and however those
chromosomes and traits all land that's
what you get I feel like it's going to
land differently uh you're more uh
predisposition to get certain outcomes
if the male and female are are certain
variants I have no scientific evidence
to back that up that is just it's got to
be different how it would not be science
would science in nature together would
not make that come out the same and I
believe that without any real I don't
have any science to back up that claim
but that just makes sense to me um let
me get myself back on track here the
different phenotypes yeah you've got
different phenotypes um if you took the
Afterglow female um and a aise male and
then you did that work then you tried to
switch that around are you going to find
phenotypes that looked just like the
Opposites like the male that looks just
like the I think you understand what I'm
saying that would be the challenge there
just that phenotypical variation is
going to be enough to cause variation in
the different breeding projects so
basically you're just reshuffling the
deck and just putting all the black
cards in one spot and all the red cards
in another spot and we're just
reshuffling and we're going to get
different outcomes in my opinion so I
think I covered that question quite
thoroughly I got to Branch off of the
last question for that so Pegasus thank
you for the great content once once
again make sure you check your email
check that spam folder cuz you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds all right ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps and
hoes friends and foes smokers Growers
clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
experienced breeders I really do want to
thank each and every one of you for
listening to another episode of The Grow
fromy heart podcast if you enjoyed this
breeding episode make sure you check out
the next episode because I do have more
breeding questions prepared for you uh
I'm sure you could tell by now my voice
is burning out my throat is so it is
time for me to wrap up this podcast
thank you for listening if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy let me know
what you think of the show if you've got
a correction please do correct me humble
me I love that sort of stuff reach out
let me know what you think of the show
also check out the website I have
mentioned it before IR genetics.com
there's a link to the patreon
patreon.com fromy yourheart there's a
link to the Discord server and there's a
link to iir to get those seeds where
there will be a Valentine's Day Sale
make sure you check that out I
direct.com you guys you gals you Growers
you smokers my voice is done for this
episode I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
shout out to my buddy diver Dave and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]