[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode
829 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got a great episode lined
up for us in today's show I'm going to
give away free seeds hang out we'll talk
more about the free seeds later in the
episode I do want to remind you that the
dude Groves cup is happening in Fort
Collins Colorado that's right the dude
Groves Cup in Fort Collins Colorado June
1st the dude will be there Scotty re
will be there I will be there Mike will
be there the iy Army will be there I
invite you to join us at the dude Groves
cup June 1st in Fort Collins Colorado
make sure you check dgc cup.com for all
of the information I also want to remind
you that the Valentine's Day Sale is
still happening at I direct.com that's
right make sure you check out ect.com
you can get a package of two seeds for
$14 there are several varieties still
available make sure you check the
website idirect decom for current
pricing and current availability all
right I think we covered all the news
and advertising here at the start of the
show let's work our way into the pet
peeve section of today's podcast
sometimes when I go to a grow space when
I go to a grow room when I'm scrolling
on social media I will see something
happening in a grow room in a grow
environment in a commercial grow that
simply drives me crazy I want to know
what are your grow room pet peeves if
there is something that drives you crazy
about a grow send that to me go to my
website iry genetics.com there's a tab
that says grow questions or grow help
click on that tab use that tab to send
me your grow room pet peeve if I read
your pet peeve here on the podcast you
will get a coupon code for a free pack
of iy genetics premium seeds at iy
direct.com today's pet peeve came from a
longtime listener a longtime supporter
they call themselves chivo Del Norte
their comment says Aloha rosta Jeff
thank you for your dedication to the
craft much respect bro thank you for
noticing and once again thank you for
the longtime support I do notice and
appreciate that it goes on it says my
pet peeve is when I go into my friends
grows and I see extension cords
everywhere it looks like a bird's nest I
just can't I just can't when I see that
it drives me crazy and when I ask where
the fire extinguisher and the smoke
detector are they say it is in the other
room uh yeah that that is a
nerve-wracking when you go to a grow
space and it looks like spaghetti all
over the floor it just looks like a
jungle of extension cords it looks like
a big knot it looks like a big fire
hazard uh first of all it just looks
like [ __ ] have some pride in your grow
space don't make it look like trash then
second of all uh you're going to trip
over that that's a tripping Hazard
you're going to be carrying a bucket of
water you're going to be thinking about
something else you're going to be
looking at the plants staring at the
plants like we do you're going to trip
over that cord you're going to fall on
your face uh when you fall when you trip
you're going to pull the fan pull that
whatever it is it's going to fall on
some other [ __ ] you're going to fall
you're going to break some [ __ ] uh
you're going to spill whatever you got
in your hands that's a trip Hazard
that's a problem don't do that also all
of those extension cords are fire
hazards that is a fire risk let's not OV
extension cord our grow space let's be
very conscious uh of and aware of the
electricity consumption and how it's
being distributed and dispersed through
the grow space especially if you are in
an old house uh old houses are not
designed to run thousand watt two three
th000 watt grow lights in a in a room
that's not what they should be doing
modern homes they should be able to
handle probably 1,000 watt light per
bedroom maybe more uh depending on your
Breakers go check your breaker box
anyway I'm not qualified to give you
electrical advice but I am qualified to
say clean up after yourself get those
cords off the floor they look like [ __ ]
you're going to trip over them and they
are a fire hazard so that is a great
grow room pet peeve I absolutely agree
with you it looks like a bird's nest it
looks like a bag of spaghetti dumped on
the floor let's clean that up let's get
that organized try to get all of your
cords up off the ground away from where
water could be in a commercial grow
environment when you build the grow
you're required to put all of your light
sockets and receptacles uh 3T or higher
off the ground I believe it is I think
it's got to be 3T so in your house if
you're going to plug PL in the vacuum
plug in a fan plug in a light most of
the time you bend over the sockets are
down there in a commercial facility
they're up way higher in the event that
you do get a bunch of water and that
grow the water and the electricity do
not meet set yourself up for Success my
friend chivo Del Norte that is a great
comment that is a great contribution to
the show uh check your email check your
spam because you my friend did get a
coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds from iy
direct.com all right all right that was
the pet peeve section of the podcast now
it is time to work our way into the
email question and answer portion of the
show once again I'm going to mention my
website iy genetics.com on that website
there is a row of tabs up top one of
them says store one of them says merch
there's a bunch of tabs up there one of
them does say growel if you click on
that growel tab there's a short
questionnaire it will ask uh what is the
VPD of your grow room what is the
temperature what's the humidity are you
growing indoors or Outdoors just a few
questions to give an idea of how to
better answer your question go to that
growel tab send me your growel question
if I read your question here on the
podcast guess what you will win a coupon
code for a free pack of iy genetics
premium seeds at iy
direct.com the first question on today's
podcast of course came from the growel
tab it came from our friend who wants to
be called inner city Buzz shout out to
Inner City buds I apologize shout out to
my new friend inner city buds the
question is a general grow question and
it says says yo Gro bro what's up dude
it says what if and that's a good what
if I like this one it will get me
rambling very well it says what if a
feminized plant went inter sex and
pollinated another female plant would
these seeds be all feminized because
there is technically no male involved in
this breeding and one more thing How
likely would these seeds be How likely
would these seeds to be intersects
themselves if the intersect was caused
by stress and if so is there a way to
breed out the interex gene um okay
there's a lot of stuff going on in this
message to where I just want to back up
and I want to really uh take this one
from the beginning so it says and this
is a great question but there's a lot to
talk about here it says what if a
feminized plant went interx okay so
we've got a plant that came from a
feminized seed and then at some point in
the flower it shows interex which means
it is a hermaphroditic plant it's got
both male and female uh parts so it's
going to throw pollen and it can also
receive pollen that's not mainly what we
want in the grow that is not ideal but
it is what is hypothetically happening
what if uh we've got a Fen plant and it
went intersects okay so it showed
intersects and it made pollen and that
pollen uh pollinated another female
plant okay that makes good sense so far
the question is would these seeds be all
fem because there is technically no male
involved well now technically there is
no male involved but we have to go back
because you do have a hermaphrodite
involved somewhere in the breeding there
is an intersex plant somewhere in the
breeding this plant just didn't turn
intersect this plant is intersect this
plant has always been an [ __ ] you
just had to give it the right
environment to express that [ __ ]
trait that's the best way I can describe
it so uh there may have not been any
male involved in the breeding which uh
very possibly very possibly true there
was no male but at some point in this
breeding there is an interex plant that
interex plant could have came from
either side of that equation the pollen
donor or the pollen receiver and again
I'm start I'm talking about the starting
female plant the plant that came from a
feminized seed one of its parents was
interex or one of its parents was
interex either way that intersex trait
is in the lineup and when you bred to it
you put that seed in the appropriate
environment and that ENT sex trait
expressed itself that is a phenotypical
expression that is a trait interex is a
trait just like Aroma just like Flavor
just like Vigor just like potency just
like pest resistance intersects is a
trait and it is in your breeding mix
there's more of the question here let me
keep reading it um we took a Fen plant
it went intersex pollinated another
female plant so you've got an intersex
plant pollinating a female plant we
can't say a female plant anymore because
that plant is now intersec SE we crossed
out that female it's not a female this
plant is a hermaphrodite that is now
pollinated a female plant would these
seeds be all fem no these seeds will not
be all fem because they were not made
with two female plants they were made
with one hermaphrodite we crossed out
that one it's not a female anymore it
doesn't get to play female it's a
hermaphrodite we've seen both parts it
doesn't get to decide its gender we've
seen it science [ __ ] uh it is a
hermaphrodite so that's a hermaphroditic
plant that pollinated a female plant not
a female to female so we've got to
correct the whole project here has got
to be updated and corrected the data is
no longer accurate so um we are now
taking a hermaphrodite plant and
pollinating a female plant the question
says uh because technically there's no
males no there's a hermaphrodite in here
How likely would these seeds be to be
interex themselves if the interex was
caused by stress the interex wasn't
caused by stress uh it presented itself
because of the stress the propensity the
opportunity for those seeds to be
intersect um is 50/50 in my opinion you
would have to grow them and find out I
definitely wouldn't give any of these
seeds to anybody that you like I would
grow them myself grow a hundred of them
before I share any of them but what
you're so what we've got to correct in
this is it was not a female plant this
was not a female Toof female interaction
this was an interex plant to a female
plant so your whole idea of the female
to female not making any uh male seeds
uh that is washed out because you're not
using the ingredients which you started
that you thought you started with so
somewhere along the line what needs to
happen I'm I'm thinking too many
thoughts at once I'm going to say this
one right now when you're making
feminized seeds what needs to happen is
every plant you are breeding with needs
to be stress tested and thoroughly
vigorously tested for interex traits
every plant in the room that you're
going to breed with the pollen donor the
pollen receivers all of them I do a lot
of stress testing I do a lot of uh
selection or a lot of very special
selection uh through when I do breeding
I won't use anything that shows me
intersect traits if it shows intersects
for any reason in my room I avoid
breeding with those plants and if I do
breed with those plants I keep them for
myself I really don't find a reason to
even breed to that uh there's no need
for that you said something in here is
there a way to breed out the interex
gene um why just skip it don't even do
it uh just skip that trait altogether
but what needs to happen is better
testing before these plants are bred
with you did not have two female plants
you did not have a solid female on both
sides because the breeding somewhere
introduced a hermaphroditic plant and
that is showing up again so the only way
I can explain this I've been trying to
find a good way to explain the Herm
trait and breeding the best way that I
can explain this is if you use any
interex plants in your breeding imagine
I'm going to take this a weird Direction
imagine we are making um a giant cake
there's a party coming up it's almost my
birthday just bringing that up as the
the reason why're we're making a cake my
birthday is coming up we're going to
make a gigantic cake right but for some
reason we're going to put we're going to
call the hermaphroditic trait poison we
know it's in there just going to
sprinkle some poison in my birthday cake
then we're going to stir it all up and
we're going to put it in the oven we
don't know where that poison went in the
cake all the poison could be all at this
end of the cake all the poison could be
at this end of the cake the poison could
be sprinkled out a little bit here and
there or it could be evenly uh spread
out homogeneous through the entire cake
I don't know where that poison went
that's exactly how I feel when you're
breeding with inter sex traits in your
breeding program there's poison in there
we don't know where it's going to show
up we don't know how long it's going to
take to show up we don't know how much
of it got spread around we don't know if
it's all at this end we don't know all
of the poison went to this end but we do
know that it's in there so why do you
even want to mess with it I don't want
any of the cake because I know there's
poison in that cake I'm going to go
somewhere else and get poison free cake
which would be a nonin seex plant which
would be a better bread line from a
breeder that paid more attention this
line uh wasn't tested uh intersect
traits are going to happen I can't say
that this wasn't tested um interex is
going to happen science nature they get
together they find a way I call it the
Jurassic Park Theory James Bean also
calls it the Jurassic Park Theory uh
life will find a way uh life will
continue the Cannabis plant's number one
goal we like to think we like to act
like we like to be egotistical and
arrogant and believe that this plant is
here to get us high and heal all of our
ailments but guess what the is not
thinking about that at all the plant's
number one purpose in life is to
reproduce just like you and me it just
wants to reproduce all day long it's all
it's thinking about it's why the male
plants get taller uh the female plants
stay lower so you can drop that pollen
onto them uh it's why he takes off a
little bit sooner but the number one
purpose of that plant is to reproduce so
you're going to find hermaphroditic
traits uh that's just going to happen
occasionally um it will happen it's not
it's not 100% preventable but uh in my
breeding what what I'm saying is I
thoroughly test my plants my every plant
that goes into my breeding program is
stress tested it's abused we do some
damage to it we do some light testing
some feed testing uh hot cold climate
changes we we run it through the ringer
I used to have a bunch of commercial
facilities where we could really abuse
these plants now you got to do it on
smaller areas but I abuse the [ __ ] out
of them if they show me interex traits
they don't get bred with that's why my
feminized seeds are reliable and we
don't see uh you don't hear any reports
you don't see it on the internet people
are not saying I has Herms because I'm
doing my due diligence and my work and
it sounds like I don't know who these
seeds came from I don't know where you
got these seeds or what this
hypothetical question derived from but
this breeder it sounds like that you're
hypothetically creating may not have
done the work may not have done the due
diligence to make sure that those plants
were not intersex plants before they
went into the breeding room let me read
the question again because I got rambly
I got way off topic on the in my head
here if a feminized plant went inter sex
so it's a female plant that came from a
fem seed when intersect pollinated
another girl those seeds will not be fem
because it was a a Herm plant that
pollinated them so um and that's another
I'm going to say that's another one of
my freaking pet peeves it drives me
crazy when people say that a Herm plant
will make F I want to know how does that
work it's like just like I explained
there's poison in there poison is going
to come out if you breed if if the one
plant tastes like strawberries and one
tastes like chocolate and you breed it
you're going to get chocolate and
strawberry if one of is a Herm why
wouldn't the Herm pass right along how
is a Herm going to make fem that's what
I want to know it's one of my major pet
peeves drives me crazy all right my dude
inner city Buzz that was a great
question please check your email check
your spam folder because you do have a
coupon code for a free pack of IE
genetics premium seeds all right ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps and
hoes friends and foes smokers Growers
clone Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you for listening to
a short quick episode of The Grow from
your heart podcast I want to leave this
episode with just this topic all by
itself I realized that this one is going
to make a good show by itself we'll make
it a quick episode I'll be back in a
week with fresh new content make sure
you check out the website IR
genetics.com there's a link to the
Discord server come join the Discord
hang out with us um there are probably
people in the smoker Lounge video chat
right now talking about growing ganja
talking about life having a good time uh
probably taking d ABS smoking a fatty
come hang out with us you my friend are
invited to the Discord server there's
also a link to iy direct where you can
get the seeds that's right check out the
Valentine's Day sale at irir get
yourself some discount priced seeds
there's also a link to the patreon
server uh where you can support the show
and possibly get free seeds I have not
set up the March patreon settings yet uh
my birthday will be in March I might not
give out freebies uh that might be a
birthday month I might take that one off
on patreon just to uh to catch up and
enjoy the birthday month I am rambling
at this point ladies and gentlemen boys
and girls thank you once again for
listening um I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
shout out to my buddy hot rod and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]