[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis Community
it's time for episode number 83 of the
grow from your heart podcast your source
for Cannabis News education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran Dabber if you're a cannabis
activist or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you I'm your host I'm your host my
name is rosta Jeff I can't even get
through this intro today I'm super
dabbed out I want to thank everybody for
joining me I need to give a huge shout
out to the Mystic Roots band Big shout
out to cat cot and the entire Mystic
Roots crew thanks a lot for letting me
use your music on the show make sure you
guys support the Mystic Roots crew and
stay positive sound all right I think I
got through that intro finally that was
a rough one uh before we get too far
this podcast is brought to you by my
good friends at H gr indoor growing
supplies H gr indoor growing supplies
has two locations to serve Colorado
visit the Denver store at 6271 Beach
Street or check out the beautiful peblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in peblo
Colorado check out H gr for competitive
pricing and a great selection of indoor
growing supplies and check it out guys
when you're at H gr indoor growing
supplies make sure you let them know
that you listen to the growth from your
heart podcast and they will give you
commercial pricing on your entire
purchase that's right you'll pay what
rosta Jeff pays uh you'll pay actually
you get a better discount than what
Jesse gets and he works at the shop so
go ahead and let them know that you are
listening to the podcast and they will
hook you up fat at hyro indoor growing
supplies at 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful peblo Colorado I was talking
to burn yesterday and if you're
listening to this on Monday uh they just
got a fresh stock of worm castings from
the Rocky Mountain worm company so make
sure you go grab some worm castings
today all right I think that's all the
advertising I'm going to do today if
you're interested in sponsoring the show
just send me an email it's grow from
yourheart hotmail.com I'll get you all
of the information that you do need you
guys I got a pretty solid show lined up
for you I hope everybody had a great 710
this is the Monday after the weekend of
710 I hope everybody had a great time at
the Chalice Festival I hope whatever you
did for 710 you had a great time I hope
you coughed your lungs out I hope you
got dabbed the [ __ ] out hope everything
went your
way before we go any further I do want
to give a huge huge shout out to kind
pain management in Denver Colorado uh
they do not sponsor the show they are uh
not supporters of the show but what they
are doing is they are growing lemon
Jeffrey which is a strin ey bread I put
that together and I got some seeds in
their hands and they are killing it they
have posted some lab tests up on their
Instagram feed they're hitting over 26%
THC on the lemon Jeffrey and the best
part is it is on shelves now you can
head to kind pain management there are a
medical and a recreational facility so
anybody can grab some lemon Jeffrey
check out what I bred check out what
kind caign management did with it big
huge shout out to them one thing I want
to do on this podcast is check out a
video that somebody sent to me of three
x cops smoking weed and the video is 6
minutes long I'm going to watch the
whole thing I may edit parts of this out
of the podcast so that you guys don't
have to sit through six whole minutes I
may skip through parts of it we'll see
how my ADD kicks in as we do this but I
think this is a great video we're going
to watch parts of it and then we will
talk about it so let me kill the theme
song and we are going to play this cops
smoking weed video so it starts off with
some dub Steppy music I don't know what
that's called but some really uh some
music and it shows three older dudes old
enough to be our fathers uh taking bong
rips and then here's what they have to
say the last time I smoked was in
probably
1968 when I was in college first time I
smoked I was 14 years old uh I got
caught the first time I smoked
so and for some reason Kos on that for a
while tried it once and tell you I was
on a water bed with a very agreeable
woman and listening to RAB cidan blue
which I know lasts for about 18 minutes
and 40
seconds and it lasted for oh hell two or
three hours okay re-extend now the left
so all three of these xcops have just
admitted to having used cannabis
illegally in their life and now what
they're doing is taking a uh field
sobriety test before they smoke any
cannabis so there are three retire cops
they all know how to [ __ ] with each
other and give each other a sobriety
test this one old guy has got such
shitty old knees that he can barely pass
the heel to tow walk but this says also
that it was recorded in Washington where
cannabis is legalized so they're keeping
these cops out of trouble uh cop number
one now they're in plain clothes they
don't look like cops their facial hair
looks like cops you guys PL clothes guy
number one is now hitting the bong he
had the presenter of the video light it
for him and now we'll let I graduated
from WSU in 1970 and went to work right
in the same year and U didn't retire
until
97 there there you
go now this old dude sticking you can
stop pretty fat bong
rip that was a good rip my name is David
I was a reserved police officer from
1997 through
2004 second dude took a pretty nice B my
name is Robert went to the police
academy in the fall of 1970 and worked
until the fall of
1986 and then after that I taught as a
freelance trainer mostly for the
criminal justice training commission
taught at the police academy for N9 or
10 years all right so none of these guys
knew how to carb uh they've all taken a
couple of fat bong hits and now it's
starting to kick in the one guy just
said so now what we wait and this is
where the fun starts the clock shows you
five minutes have gone by and we'll let
you hear what theying right at first
because I think I had stuck on my
mustache or
something Have you ever arrested someone
from you know I thought about that a lot
and as far as I can remember I never
arrested anyone for it but I took a lot
of pot away from people and threw it
away in front of them and I thought that
was a bigger deterrent than actually
writing a criminal citation I think it
should be legal I think it should be
more widely available for medical
reasons it's like the last piece of
prohibition so do you believe marijuana
is a Gateway Drive I think it certainly
can be a Gateway this is my favorite
part like to respond to that too because
I'm going to pause it cuz uh the um the
host is a little a little bit hard to
hear on this show he's his audio is
terrible so what the guy just asked
these cops is do you think marijuana is
a gateway drug and I'm going to back up
about just a couple of seconds here
because this is honestly my favorite
part of the video is this guy's answer
okay so they just asked him do you think
marijuana is a gateway drug and I'll hit
play Do You Believe marijuana is a
gateway drug I think it certainly can be
a gateway drug yes I'd like to respond
to that too because if you look at it
everyone who's a heroin addict started
out drinking milk
so you're saying game apparently I mean
that's the argument about marijuana and
I'm not sure that's true so that guy
just said that milk is the gateway drug
you guys because everybody that started
that does heroin started off drinking
milk I don't know if he really feels
that way or if he's just too high and
hasn't been high in years and that's
what just came out of his head but that
was my favorite statement from this
whole video I was hearing that cop say
that everybody that is on heroin started
off using milk so milk is the gateway
drug also the one cop said he's never
arrested people but he's taken a lot of
weed away from people uh that's
respectable his job was to arrest people
for weed and he didn't do it so he's
kind of on our team a little bit the
other cop said it should be legal and it
should be more readily available for
medical purposes so I applaud these cops
so far let's keep watching this video uh
now this is 15 minutes later I don't
know if this is 15 minutes from the time
they took the bong hit or if this is 15
minutes from the clip that we just saw
which would put them about 20 minutes
into this stoned Adventure so I'm going
to hit play turn the volume up again and
we will see what these old guys are up
to and that's the
clock so now they're smoking a joint
they're hitting the bong showing a
montage now 25 minutes later starting at
93 count backwards by seven and now
they're going to try to do sobriety
tests 9 uh
86 and the question he just asked him is
[ __ ] up he said starting at 93 count
backwards by sevens your right fo I
can't do that so okay hold it for 20
seconds count oh count to 10 okay how
about
five so now they're doing the uh hold
your leg up test and the guy couldn't do
5 Seconds this one guy he did pretty
good doing the Heel To Toe test better
than before yeah he said better than
before uh this dude was doing a heel to
toe test a minute ago and I said that he
was [ __ ] it up cuz his knees were so
bad now that he smoked a little bit of
reefer this dude just nailed the Heel To
Toe test cuz his pain doesn't hurt in
his knees anymore so they accidentally
found a good reason to use marijuana all
right I'm going to hit play on the video
again we'll keep going I feel a little
floaty it's not unpleasant but it's
shadowed by
The Faint discomfort of not being
fully whatever that's kind of what
police officers do they're very staunch
they're very in control all the time
this doesn't necessarily allow you to do
that is actually pretty comfortable
though I mean it's it's relaxed and I
don't feel like I have to be in control
it's it's pretty cool so this guy's
enjoying it and this is 45 minutes lat
legalizing marijuana is that it it takes
I mean some of the stuff you can buy in
the street now you never know what it's
cut with I don't agree with that he's
claiming that marijuana is cut with
stuff which is weird but that's his own
uneducated you know he doesn't know
where it came from and what it's going
to do to you well yeah and it also costs
you know more to put somebody in in
prison not jail but prison uh then it
cost to send them to Harvard you hear
that it costs more to put somebody in
prison than to send them to Harvard now
they're playing the game where you put a
card on your name and try to guess who's
what not we're going to skip part of
this it's unnecessary but you guys I
don't know given in the right
circumstances they just asked I'm going
to back up two seconds they just asked
would you do it again is the question
and here's their respones I'm letting
the YouTube video load well I told my
son on the way over here I was I had a
pretty good headache coming on and I
think my headache starting to clear
clear up I mean it's going away would
you do it
again I don't know given in the right
circumstances I suppose yeah I'll smoke
again probably given the opportunity so
all three of these guys said they will
smoke again the video with you guys
taking one and since that was their
answer he wants them to hit the bong one
more time so they're all going to take
now this is great they're doing a
montage of these three older dudes
taking bong hits and smoking a joint and
it looks like uh like they're trying to
make it a scene from uh The Hangover or
something it's pretty good all right so
I'm gonna wrap up this video because I
honestly don't know how much I was
allowed to play of that video without
some sort of usage rights let me give a
shout out to the person that posted it I
found it on YouTube it's by cut video
make sure you subscribe to them they've
got 587 139 followers be 140 for them uh
they would appreciate that I'm going to
go ahead and click like on this video so
they can get some credit there but make
sure you check it out guys it's a funny
video you're going to want to watch it
yourself all right now that we've gotten
through watching that video let me talk
about it a little bit uh one thing I
really liked is that these dudes seemed
open-minded they didn't remind me of a
lot of the cops that I've dealt with
that are real standoffish and think they
have to be in control of everything the
One Cop actually said that that's a
cop's job is to be in control and once
he smoked a little bit of reefer he
wanted to relax and lighten up and not
be such a prick of a cop so I liked that
he was open-minded and wanted to
participate I like that the one guy said
it should be legal and then what I
really liked was that they all wanted to
smoke again they said yes we would do
this again so maybe the those cops are
going to go talk to one of their friends
who is still a cop and be like you know
what dude we got Stoned on this video
and it's not as bad as you think maybe
one of their friends is going to watch
this video maybe this video is going to
help people change their opinions of
cannabis and even if it even if you're
already a fan of cannabis I recommend
watching it because it was highly
entertaining big shout out to whoever
sent that video to me I do not remember
who it was but I appreciate it all right
that's enough of the video I've got a
few news articles that I'd like to share
with you guys um this article we'll just
jump right to it this article comes from
the PUO then and it is written by uh Dan
cinta no it's actually written by
Kristen M white so the headlin says
extra marijuana tax money set to hit the
roads and I've talked a little bit about
this in previous shows and it is finally
happening this was my recommendation and
now here you go here's the article you
guys it says the pbla West Metropolitan
District will spend an additional
$200,000 on roads in the community for
the remainder of the year in a
three-fold approach that Public Works
director Dan cinta outlined for the
board recently the extra money comes
after directors agreed to allocate the
$200,000 it received from PLO County for
marijuana tax money toward chip sealing
already planned this County will pay the
$200,000 directly to its Emulsion
supplier freeing up 200,000 PLO $200,000
PLO West would have spent of its
$350,000 budget for chip sealing this
year the highest need we have in the
district right now has to do with gravel
roads CA told directors we have 6.2
miles of gravel roads that when we have
the storms we've had this spring the
clay underneath fails and some stretches
are impassable it would be our intent to
start attacking the repair of those
roads as soon as possible we propose to
bring in additional staff equipment and
additional gravel so I have recommended
this several times you guys I've said
that we should take all this tax money
that we're making here in Pueblo
Colorado and fix some of the goddamn pot
holes all over the roads well guess what
they have heard us the people have
spoken the people listened and now they
going to fix the roads with all of that
tax money so big shout out to the city
of peblo for actually doing something
about the roads of course they're
starting with dirt roads that are
impassible but once those are done
they're going to fix the potholes in my
city so that my car will not sound like
[ __ ] when I
drive thank you it's about time all
right here's another news article this
one comes from Denver I actually found
this news article in the PLO Chief then
and big shout out to Mike uh make sure
you guys follow Nemo punk I think it's
Nemo Punk 15 on Twitter Mike sends me a
lot of news articles I appreciate it
thanks a lot dude uh we'll get right to
this article uh the headline is raising
the bars for pot and this is something
else that we've been talking about and
hinting at on the podcast and things are
finally coming around so the sub
headline says Denver campaign promoting
promoting use in 21 in over 21
establishments uh this article is by
Kristen Wyatt of the Associated Press
and then it says Denver beer wine or
weed campaign is underway to ask Denver
voters about owing marijuana consumption
in bars and other places that only allow
people over 21 activists who campaign
for recreational pot legalization in
Colorado have launched a petition to
drive what they call limited social
marijuana consumption at bars the
activists need about 5,000 signatures to
get the question on November ballots it
would allow bars or clubs to allow
marijuana use as long as patrons bring
their own weed and comply with clean air
laws that means the pot they consume
would have to be edible or if smoked
consumed on an outside patio the way
cigarette smoking is regulated now
outdoor smoking sites would have to be
shielded from public view so if you guys
don't know about the Clean Air Act in
Colorado you are not allowed to smoke in
a restaurant or anywhere that serves
food or basically where the public is
you have to get a um [ __ ] I don't know
the word uh tobacco shops have them but
you have to get like a a smoking license
like a tobacco shop or a cigarette shop
if you want to smoke in there they apply
for a permit and you're able to smoke in
there um so with the clean act we are
not able to smoke cannabis inside of a
building even if they do allow it we're
going to have to step outside to an
outdoor area that is shielded from
public view so I'll jump into the
article a little bit more here it says
marijuana is now I don't how they I
don't like how they worded that I'm
going to read it the way it should have
been written it says marijuana is now a
legal product for adults in Denver and
it's really time that we give adults a
place to use it legally and socially
said Mason tvert who ran Colorado's 2012
campaign to legalize recreational pot we
shouldn't be requiring that you sit at
home if you choose to use marijuana as
an adult and I completely agree with
that you guys there are so many places
to buy dank buds in Colorado but there
is nowhere to legally go smoke it so
this would change a lot of things and I
think it would promote business people I
wouldn't go to a bar I have no reason to
go to a bar I don't drink alcohol I
don't want anything to do with bar girls
I don't want to do with bar dudes I
don't like drunk people but if I could
go to that club and hang out and take a
couple of dabs and hang out with my
friends that are drinking I would be way
more inclined to go to the bar and then
I'd spend a few bucks there because I'd
have to buy a soda or some sort of juice
or [ __ ] to keep my mouth hydrated while
I'm dabbing but anyway we'll keep going
with the article Colorado law prohibits
recreational pot consumption openly and
publicly or in a matter that endangers
others it does not however bar against
consumption in private over 21 clubs the
Denver measure would clarify what counts
as a private club and that's something
we've been struggling with here a lot in
Colorado is getting a private club uh
marijuana dispensaries are banned from
allowing onuse uh on-site use of
products they sell and from selling
alcohol or food that doesn't contain pot
the Denver proposal would only allow
bring your own consumption uh Denver
wouldn't be the first city to allow
Marana in bars Netherland has a state
statute allowing limited on-site
consumption at over 21 clubs so in Ned
you can go smoke I didn't know about
that uh in Colorado Springs the state's
second largest city has several
marijuana marijuana clubs that are
tolerated if not specifically Allowed by
Statue Colorado Springs Mayor John
suthers has told the city council that
he plans to see regulations on the clubs
The Gazette newspaper recently reported
uh I've been to three uh marijuana
cannabis smoking Social Clubs in uh
Colorado Springs and you know it's kind
of cool to be able to go and hang out
and just smoke there is the 420 speak
easyy there's the Lazy Lion and then
there's the original speak easyy and you
as a an adult 21 or over can go into
these places and you can have a dab of
your own out of their rig you can bring
your rig or a lot of them have a dab bar
that will sell you dabs some of them you
have to pay a little fee to get in a
little cover charge but if you're an out
of towerer and you want to come hang out
and take some dabs with some Colorado
kids you know there's nothing wrong with
going to one of those places it's
actually pretty damn fun I ended up at a
kind of a secretive place in Denver
taking dabs all night at a Speak Easy up
there and it's just fun hanging out
taking dabs in the club we just replaced
alcohol with dabs and it's way fun I
really enjoy it for some reason all
right I need to continue with this
article uh where are we uh the Denver
petition comes after that City rejected
pot friendly bars uh Denver has several
underground clubs where patrons use
marijuana for a joining fee but the city
has intermittently arrested people for
public consumption at those
clubs arresting for smoking weed again
wait I thought we were past that anyway
the raids and arrests leave tourists
with nowhere to legally consume pot
they've bought argued supporters of the
ballot measure among the supporters is
Jane West an events promoter who last
year arranged classically cannabis
concert with the Colorado Symphony
Orchestra the city threatened to block
the concert citing public consumption
laws the symphony rebranded the concerts
as a private bring your own cannabis
fundraiser and the city dropped its
objections uh West was convicted of a
misdemeanor for organizing a separate
cannabis friendly event last year a
brunch at a bakery an eight-person SWAT
team descended on the event and shut
down the brunch West said Wes became one
of the first to sign the Denver petition
the petitions are due by early August so
uh where's this petition because
everybody here in Colorado needs to sign
this if you listen to this podcast you
agree with me that we need to allow
recreational consumption in 21 and over
establishments for adults out of public
view out of indoor smoking areas so that
we're able to medicate if we're a
medical patient or we're able to
recreate if we're a recreational smoker
we should be able to Puff the people are
at the bars getting wasted doing shots
[ __ ] getting drunk getting into
fights raping each other being heathens
but the people that want to smoke a
little bit of weed and relax are being
singled out and I think it's sucks and
it's time for a revolution it's time for
us to be able to smoke in these clubs
where we want to go I think it' be a
good idea I think it's kind of dumb that
they don't allow it all right big shout
out to the PUO Chieftain big shout out
to Kristen Wyatt you guys if you're in
Colorado if you're a Colorado resident
find this petition I'm looking to see if
there's a link to it but there is not so
we need to find this petition somewhere
and we need to sign it each and every
one of
us so that's enough of that article
let's go to the next article this
article is a little bit long let me see
how much time I have got left here in
this show so um we've talked recently
about the discussion between the natives
and the government to allow natives to
grow cannabis on native land or Indian
reservations recently federal agents
have raided two major marijuana grows on
tribal County or on tribal land in modok
County so this article comes from where
is this this is actually from KCTV decom
which is a TV station in Southern
California and there is no let's see
Megan Hunt is the author so let's read
this article it says federal agents raed
what appeared to be a large- scale
commercial marijuana grow on the pit
River XL reservation and the alterus
reservation in modok County on Wednesday
morning photos from the scene show
dozens of law enforcement vehicles at a
large Greenhouse site there's also one
photo of a bulldozer with what appears
to be a load of marijuana plants in its
bucket according to Lauren horwood of
the USA uh the US attorney 's office
special agents with the Bureau of Indian
Affairs and The Drug Enforcement
Administration and other federal states
and local agencies conducted a search of
two large-scale marijuana cultivation
facilities located on federally
recognized tribal lands at the alterus
Indian Rancheria and the XL
Ranch at both sites law enforcement
seized a total of at least 12,000
marijuana plants and over 100 pounds of
processed marijuana other than the
Contraband marijuana and items of
evidentiary value no tribal property was
seized and no federal charges are
printing horwood said she explained that
the search warrants are part of an
ongoing investigation relating to the
financing and management of a commercial
marijuana cultivation project the
project warrant affidavits were unsealed
until today horwood also said that while
the US attorney's office doesn't
normally comment on ongoing
investigations because of the public
nature of this raid they are releasing
information she explained that marijuana
grows have received substantial
attention in modok County as well as the
US Department of Justice's guidance
relating to marijuana cultivation on
tribal lands the cultivation facility at
alterus Indian Ranch area was located
within the trib's former Event Center
with within approximately 100 yards of
the trib's publicly operated gaming
facility the Desert Rose Casino so these
guys were growing a major grow 100 yards
from the Desert Rose Casino where people
go all day and gamble all day that's
kind of kind of funny to me uh the
facility on the XL Ranch was next to
Highway 395 on the banks of the pit
River horwood explained that the pit
River facility consisted of 40 newly
constructed Greenhouse structures each
capable of accommodating appr
approximately 1,000 marijuana plants and
additional gable roof structures that
boosted the square footage of roof
covered structures by another
50% that is a lot of plants you guys
this dude had 40 green this operation
had 40 green houses with a thousand
plants each that's the potential of
40,000 plants in those green houses plus
stuff that was covered that increases
their Square footage by 50% which is
another 20,000 plants if you do it
mathematically I think all right I'll
keep going uh both of the grow
operations which appear to have been
operating in conjunction with each other
and were in excess of the locally
enacted marijuana cultivation limits
applicable to County Land horwood said I
feel like I read something of that uh
they were they were both in excess of
the locally enacted marijuana
cultivation limits so that's something
that's kind of if you're allowed to grow
cannabis if you're able to do that
legally without being [ __ ] with by the
government stay within your damn limits
why don't you just stay in the limits
these guys were over their limits
they're growing too much and that's what
got them in trouble which is a sign of
greed and selfishness and not growing
from your heart and growing from your
wallet all right we're going to keep
going on the article it says the volume
of marijuana that the XL facility alone
was capable of producing estimated
approximately 40 to 60,000 plants far
exceeds any prior known commercial
marijuana grow operation anywhere within
the 34 County eastern district she added
according to tribal Representatives all
of the marijuana cultivated at both both
facilities was intended to be
distributed off of tribal lands at
various unidentified locations according
to the search warrant affidavits the
investigation to date indicates both
operations may have been financed by a
third-party foreign National and you
guys I actually uh found these search
warrants on Facebook for some reason I
was scrolling through Facebook and
somebody happened to post the search
warrants and for some reason I was
completely enthralled with with reading
these search warrants and it was
completely entertaining for some reason
I could not get my head out of it but
they said that this thirdparty foreign
National was a guy from Canada who owns
Canadian cigarette companies who has got
a history of drug convictions so they
got a Canadian guy come to an Indian
Reservation who financed a major grow he
paid for everything they were supposed
to grow the Cannabis distribute this and
allegedly get him his portion and keep
the operation going um I was amazed that
I found the uh search warrants and all
of the stuff written up if you guys ever
get a chance to read a technical
document like that do it just for fun if
you're one of those kind of people some
people are into that [ __ ] uh you'll get
a kick out of it it was really neat uh
they will not give the snitches names
they call them confidential informants
and give a long excuse why they keep
them confidential uh they talk about how
the raid happened they talk about so
many small details uh you guys will
start tripping out and wonder if you're
being watched when you listen if you
read a search warrant cuz there are so
many small details that these guys
[ __ ] up on they were getting their
pictures taken they were talking to
people and all of that [ __ ] is in the
police reports and in the search
warrants and you would never assume that
that shit's being told to police but so
much of it was yeah all right I'm going
to continue with the article if I can
find out where the hell I was all right
here we go according to horwood the
investigation of the cultivation
facility search today indicates that
both our commercial marijuana
cultivation projects operated with the
intent to transport large quantities of
marijuana off tribal lands for
distribution at various locations yet to
be identified by the tribes which is a
concern to the Department Department of
Justice because it goes against their
guidelines uh you know why it goes
against their guidelines because they
don't make any [ __ ] tax money off of
it that's part of the problem uh horwood
said that the US attorney's office
consulted with members and
representatives of both tribes which are
federally recognized on multiple
occasions before today's raid and
reminded the tribes that cultivation of
marijuana is illegal under federal law
and that anyone engaging in such
activity did so at the risk of
enforcement action she added they were
also concerned because the large
quantities violates federal law is it is
not consistent with California's
compassionate use act and undermines
locally enacted marijuana regulations so
basically you guys these guys got [ __ ]
because the the tribal laws and the
locals said you guys are growing too
much weed you're going to get in trouble
and guess what they went ahead and did
it and guess what they got dealt with by
the police it's a little bit ridiculous
don't [ __ ] around you guys if you're
allowed to grow cannabis if you're a
native if you're not a native whoever
you are if you're allowed to grow
cannabis don't throw it in their face
and grow too much just follow the rules
grow you're allowed to grow and be
thankful if you're in a non-legal state
do what you got to do I can't encourage
you either way but if you're in a
non-legal State and you need medicine
grow what you can do what you can be
careful don't get caught all right in
the search warrant that I read you guys
they listed all of the strains that
these guys were working with because
they P the way that a lot of this
started they pulled over one of their
transportation vehicles that was uh
transporting plants from one grow
facility to the other and this guy had
a, oneg pots uh with babies in his uh
rider truck truck or his Pinsky truck
and they listed off what he had and dude
they had blueberry cookies in there they
had platinum OG in there they had Girl
Scout cookies these guys had some Great
Cuts and I started thinking about it
natives the natives people we used to
call Indians when we were kids those
guys are an agricultural commu uh uh
culture all of their culture is based on
the earth and agriculture if these
natives that were growing these cannabis
plants were the natives that we think of
when we daydream about Indians uh those
guys in my mind would grow amazing
cannabis and I would love to have gotten
a sample of the [ __ ] that they grew I'd
love to see what the natives are growing
I bet it's [ __ ] dank just because
that's what they do they're outdoor
people they're connected with the Earth
they're connected with plants uh I could
assume that they grow some dank dank
weed sounds like they're putting out a
lot of it too all right what else do we
have um I think that's all the news
we're going to do because we are at 29
minutes and 50 seconds and my next news
articles are going to be a little
lengthy so they might go on the next uh
podcast they may get skipped you never
know how we're going to do it around
here so it's time to start wrapping up
the show but before I do that I got to
give a couple of shout outs oh and also
um big shout out to everybody that's
watching on Periscope right now I'm
doing most of this podcast live on
Periscope there will be some editing
done but if you're watching on Periscope
big shout out big shout out to Roxy hola
big shout out to El Diablo El Diablo
just jumped in big shout out to corn dog
big shout out to everybody that's
watching me on Periscope I really
appreciate that um let's see who else do
I need to give a shout out oh dude big
huge shout out to Judy what up Judy also
big shout out to green and healthy
wellness a big shout out to hunt damsel
and the entire turpex crew and of course
John randles Jr big shout out bro uh
green and healthy wellness took very
good care of me this weekend I got
myself a brand new turpex t-shirt so I'm
excited big shout out to all those guys
let's see yeah it's time to wrap up the
show I don't have anything else left for
you guys so uh I will be back I've got
another podcast it'll probably drop on
Wednesday so no it'll come out Thursday
I do Monday and Thursday I don't know
why I say Wednesday but I always do that
on accident um it'll be back I'll be
back Thursday make sure you check that
out uh thanks for listening to this
episode make sure you check out the
sponsor High gr indoor growing supplies
make sure that you let them know you
listen to The Grow from your heart
podcast they will give you commercial
pricing on your entire purchase uh if
you were interested in sponsoring the
show uh if you've got a product You'
like me to review send me an email it's
from your heart at hotmail.com I will
get you all of the information that you
need uh let's see yeah don't forget the
show is available on iTunes Stitcher and
every single episode is always and
forever archived on iry gentics
color.com don't forget about the
donation button you guys if you go to
iry genetics.com click on the podcast
tab at the top right there's a PayPal
logo if you click on that it does go
directly to my Paypal account I'm not
begging you for money but if you feel
like the podcast was worth a little
something and you're in a position to
contribute I would definitely appreciate
it if you're not not in a position to
contribute that's just fine dedicate
your money to your grow do what you got
to do there are people that are able to
help and they're the ones who I'm
talking to thank you guys very much um
we're on all the social media sites you
guys make sure you follow me everywhere
you can I'm on Twitter it's gfyh podcast
make sure you follow iy genetics on
Instagram make sure you follow me on
Facebook do all that good stuff we love
the social media we love the interaction
I've been posting a lot of stuff to
Periscope lately I'm actually recording
this podcast live while I'm on Periscope
so what Up Periscope if you guys are
watching I appreciate that sorry I
haven't been interacting with you I've
been focused on the podcast so um make
sure you follow me on Periscope make
sure you support all my sponsors make
sure you love one another make sure you
be good to yourself uh thank you guys
for listening I promise I have a bunch
of great episodes coming up we got my
buddy Joe coming on to teach us about
cannabis photography my buddy sloppy is
going to come on and talk about how
moving to Colorado changed his life I'm
trying to get the garden of Weeden back
onto the show but they're busy what up
guys if you're listening this is my call
to action Garden of Weeden please come
on the show sometime soon because my
listeners miss you uh also we're going
to get Mike on the show again pretty
soon we got a lot of things planned out
you guys episode 100 is going to be
coming out in October we're just working
toward that and I'm super excited we're
going to try to do some celebration or
something on episode 100 I hope you join
me for that you guys I'm just rambling
so thanks again for listening until next
time take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me
it's WR right here it's absolutely clear
that gja theing of the nation don't
St always be
here be here for enough
generation yeah they want you to feel
Tipsy Derby
Tipsy puppy doll comeing your
[Music]
face they don't want to smoke the Sweet
Lemon the smile up the
children you pick him up you lick him
down you off try to run him down
the coming
right PL coming right
back using your s laboratary
resource so many illness they call Herb
[Music]
cure so why don't you give I and I the
per
rain come falling make the G grow and
the Sun come shining Thee the fall pick
him up lick him down to
down come
right using your
s resource