[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go take
four welcome to the podcast everybody
I'm your host rosta Jeff this is episode
82 9 of the grow fromy heart podcast let
me start by apologizing for being a day
late with the podcast I've been a little
bit overwhelmed with a trim job with a
small Harvest I'm caught up now we'll
talk more about trimming and harvesting
later in the podcast I do want to
cordially invite you to the dude grow
Growers cup that's right the dude grow
Growers cup is happening June 1st in
Fort Collins Colorado uh the dude grows
crew will be there the iy Army will be
there I will be there white Mike will be
there we do invite you to come join us
for the party at the D dgc Growers cup
June 1st in Fort Collins Colorado make
sure you check out dgc cup.com for all
of that information also big thanks to
everybody who participated in the
Valentine's Day sale on iy direct.com
that Valentine's Day Sale is now going
to segue right on into a rosta Jeff
birthday sale that's right my birthday
is March 1st why not do a roster Jeff
birthday sale on edirect decom so by the
time this episode comes out there will
be a live sale happening on red
direct.com go check out the new
inventory and the new pricing it is my
birthday let's celebrate all right I
feel like I covered all of the business
here at the top of the show now let's
segue into the pet peeve section of
today's podcast a lot of times if you're
scrolling the internet if you go to your
friends grow space maybe you work in a
commercial grow but a lot of times we
will see something in a grow environment
that will simply drive you crazy drive
me crazy I call that our growroom pet
peeve I want to know about your growroom
pet peeves you can send them to me at
grow fromy yourheart hotmail.com if I
read your growroom pet peeve here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at edirect dcom
today we're going to discuss one of my
grow room one of my grow Community Pet
Peeves when you buy a package of seeds
it says recommended flowering time uh
we're going to say 60 to 70 days that's
really common for some seeds that I
would sell so suggested flowering time
60 to 70 days I'm the breeder I'm the
one that bred those seeds I've probably
grown a bunch of those seeds I've had
testers grow those seeds got a lot a lot
of experience with the seeds that are in
that package I have a pretty good
general idea of what to expect from
those especially how long to let them
flower now let me get to the point here
my pet peeve is when I see people online
talking about day one of flowering time
and what is considered day one there are
a lot of people out there who try to say
that day one is the first day you see
pistols forming or the first day you see
Bud set happening or the first day your
plant shows you sex all of those are
nonsense day one of flowering is the day
you turn your timer to 1212 most of us
are running 18 hours on 6 hours off or
something similar maybe you're doing 24
and zero but that first day you turn
that timer to 12 hours on and 12 hours
off is day one of the flowering cycle
there's no negotiations no changes uh
and I get to choose that because I cre
created the seeds that you're working
with I put the label on there and I know
that day one starts for my count when I
change that light that's why I put 70
days on there it would have been a
different math equation I didn't put day
one is uh the day that you change the
lights plus the day that you see pistols
minus the angle of the Moon it doesn't
say any of that it says day one is the
day you change the light into flower and
then from 70 days from then your plants
should be ready so my growroom pet peeve
is people not understanding what day one
means means how hard is it why are you
making things so difficult chill out bro
now we're going to work into another pet
peeve that does drive me crazy I also
see this on social media way too often
people will post pictures of male plants
it's a boy plant the plant is 10 12 17
days into flower it's showing male parts
and people will say why did my plant
show hermaphrodite why is my plant a
Herm bro it's just a male why do you
want it to be a Herm so bad I know that
sounds like a very small complaint but
what sucks about that is if you run some
iy genetic seeds and you grow a good
male and you complain that you got a
hermaphrodite and you tell a bunch of
people that my seeds are in sex that
looks bad on me because you're
uneducated and you didn't know what a
male plant looked like so that's another
one of my big pet peeves people that
identify a male plant as an interex
plant the plant was clearly male you
don't get to pick that bro the plants do
not let you determine their gender they
will tell you on their own all right
that is my pet peeve section of today's
podcast now I did say earlier that I've
been over overwhelmed because I've been
trimming some plants there is a very
long episode about harvesting and drying
and curing your plants here on this
podcast I don't remember the number
today we are going to do the quick
version of drying and curing your
harvested cannabis now the first thing I
want to talk about when it comes to
harvesting our plants is preparation
I've done a full episode recently about
preparing for Harvest uh mainly get your
gloves get your scissors get your area
also where are these plants going to go
once you chop them down let's think
think about that before we even cut
these plants down so we know Harvest is
coming right it's coming up let's just
say it's in a few days now is the time
to order two or three pair of scissors
if you can get some good Fisker scissors
or whatever you prefer get some good
quality scissors I got some free
scissors in the mail that came with
another product they just happened to
send me scissors I used those to trim a
plant the other night they lasted one
and a half plants before they were so
dull that they were just mushing the
plant I couldn't even trim with them uh
tried to clean them up tried to get them
back in action they're so dull they're
useless need to give them to a friend
who is a a sheer sharpener professional
shout out dude you know who you are uh
but get yourself some good quality
scissors cuz these things did not last
one and a half plants they were free
it's what you expect but I just grabbed
that pair I thought brand new I'll give
them a try they felt good in the hand
but they didn't trim with the [ __ ] after
a couple of hours they were toasted so
now is the time to order some good
scissors we know we're going to need
good trim scissors if you've already got
some clean them up get them prepared
also you're going to need or I suggest
rubber gloves if you're going to have
helpers get gloves in their sizes as
well uh be cordial also one thing I
would recommend is some snacks you're
going to want some snacks when you're
trimming not while but between trimming
uh I'm a snack monster it's a nice
reward to say when I finish this plant I
get to eat those snacks it's always just
a good mind game so if you're trimming
if you've got helpers oh excuse me for
the burping you guys not even going to
edit that out if you're trimming if
you've got helpers try to provide snacks
for yourself and since I'm burping it up
try to find some good drinks that your
trimmers enjoy do they drink kombuchas
do they drink have some water for sure
but do they want something tasty do they
want a lime horitos uh do they want one
of those weird tasting Tamarind hitos
get something tasty for your trim crw so
there's something good for folks to
snack on and drink on keep them
comfortable also uh this always does
help in my opinion if you're working in
a an environment where this is allowed
if you're in a commercial environment
you're screwed but if you come over here
and you trim with me you're going to get
stoned all day bro I put some weed on
the table some dabs on the table and
that shit's R game you can smoke all of
that [ __ ] as long as you can still trim
you will get paid don't worry about it
so have some snacks some drinks and some
smokables
available uh and some good entertainment
maybe pick out a couple of good podcasts
if you're by yourself uh maybe listen to
a couple of comedy specials but be ready
uh and a good chair I'm going to mention
a good chair is crucial I've got a
really nice chair in my office I can
move around I moved that to my trim area
it's nice and cozy it's got nice lumbar
support uh that chair extends my trim
period also good good lighting many
people Overlook the good lighting until
they cut down the plant they bring it to
the area and they go damn I can't see
this [ __ ] of course I've got studio
lights I've got lighting for days in
here but consider some lighting in your
trimming area that is going to be very
crucial it will uh trimming sucks you
may be at trimming at the trim table for
several hours you don't want to be stuck
there uncomfortable uh with your neck in
a position you don't want and your arms
in a weird way really try to get
yourself in a comfortable relaxed
position where you can get as much done
and extend your time trimming if your
arms are up here your arms are going to
get numb if your neck's crooked like
this your neck is going to get sore try
to get yourself set up in a comfortable
way where you can trim with your arms in
front of your face over a tray also
think about some sort of trim tray what
are you going to trim over do you have a
strategy all right there's a lot of
things to think about before trimming
even happens let's get some supplies
let's get some friends let's get a
schedule when is it going to happen
don't keep putting it off uh don't uh
just tell your Bros whenever at this
time have a time Friday at noon I'm
cutting these plants down you be here at
1 we'll start cooking like that's the
way it should go have a plan how about
some space do you know do you have room
if I cut down one of my big plants it
would barely fit on this table uh so I'd
have to break it down into smaller
pieces hang that up and then process
that small pieces at a time do you have
room for that how is the temperature the
environment in that room is it suitable
for yourself is it suitable for your
trim crew is it suitable for the plants
then after the trim area what about
where is that bud going to hang however
you're going to do it are you going to
run lines are you going to hang it from
hooks are you going to hang it from coat
hangers how are you going excuse me how
are you going to hang this plant one
thing I like to do I like to start by
hanging so we'll talk about this in a
moment but have some space how are you
going to hang the plant then how are you
going to control the environment in the
room in which your plants are hanging uh
ideally we would have and this is Up For
Debate people are going to argue this
and I'm going to give parameters because
it's much easier and um it is slightly
critical to hit these parameters but
certain exact temps aren't as critical
in my mind I've been growing weed uh
very good weed before we had all these
super crazy monitors and all this Tech
you can get by but what I'm trying to
say is we need a room where we can
control the temperature and the humidity
uh somewhere between 50 and 60% humidity
and also somewhere between 50 and 60°
fahren in that room uh for as long as
possible where you're drying and curing
is ideal I understand we don't all have
that try not to get too hot try not to
get too cold try not to get too dry try
not to get too moist it will work but if
you want really good the best weed 50 to
60% on both of those is ideal for you so
what about the area where the weed is
going to go so the way I normally do it
is I'm going to cut the weed down it'll
hang for a few days in that 50/50 room
that 50/50 environment that dark room
also it's 50° 50% humidity and it's dark
uh eventually it'll be time to cut it
we'll talk more about that in just a
minute I'm not going to skip steps
trying to stay focused but I am high as
[ __ ] if you can't tell today um then
eventually that weed's going to get
ready to trim once we trim it where is
it going to go do you have jars do you
have containers do you have buckets do
you have something available that is
airtight preferably opaque and food
grade would be ideal for these buds so
there's a lot of things to think about a
lot of steps let's get prepared now so
we don't destroy this Harvest we've
already gone however many days in veg 30
40 days in veg 9 10 weeks in flour let's
not ruin this stuff right here at the
very end so think about your environment
what about your equipment do you have a
humidifier a dehumidifier a small fan do
you have those types of things available
to you to put in your dry and cure area
uh what else do we talk about I said
time and space uh once you've got all of
your equipment I wrote down uh
humidifier dehumidifier FL fans scissors
gloves jars bins snacks music now what
about time and space you've got to
organize this I talked about that
briefly the thing that uh you may need
to be concerned about is once you cut
those plants down they are beginning to
dry at some point they will be dry
enough to where they need to be either
put into a container or ready to be
trimmed uh the reason I got overwhelmed
this week is cuz I cut down several
plants all at one time and then they
were all dry all at once it was a race
for me to get them into a container into
the jars before they got too dry so I
just once I started trimming it was
[ __ ] go time I had to keep on keeping
on so give yourself time and space to do
this uh also think about that hang area
I wrote temperature and humidity in the
Hang area make sure that is dialed in
now let's talk about my actual process
of how uh I did this Harvest I felt like
I did this Harvest pretty efficiently it
was just me I took down my legal number
of plants here in Colorado I feel like I
had a pretty good successful Harvest by
the way most of this uh is going to be
taken to the dude grow cup so we can
consume this at the dude grow cup it's
going to be rolled up into a bunch of
fatties are just available in jars uh
it's just going to be smoke ready at the
cup that's why I grew it uh this is just
party time bud there was a bunch of
lemon Jeffrey uh a little bit of orange
gasm a very small amount small small
amount of Grateful Dog there was a
double dragon in there and then
allegedly um there might be a Golden
Goat plant but we're just talking at
this point let's talk about the actual
Harvest so um you've done your grow it's
time to cut we're not going to talk too
much about uh what you feed it if you do
or do not flush by the way there's an
episode all about flushing is Flushing
real is Flushing a myth is Flushing bro
science uh go check the flushing episode
see how you feel about that uh do that
or don't uh then um I would say the day
before Harvest here is where my Harvest
procedure actually Begins the actual
Harvest because days before that I hit
up Amazon and got all the [ __ ] that I
need now here we go um I'm going to go
in and defoliate the plants as much as I
possibly can the day before Harvest as
many leaves as I can pull off big and
small if I can just get in there and
yank them off with my fingers the entire
room just going to strip it naked we
don't need any leaves at this point uh
it can be completely completely naked at
this time then uh when I'm done there's
a good chance I'll just unplug that
light unplug the room uh not the entire
room just the lights uh the room is done
I'm going to cut it down tomorrow a lot
of people like to leave that room in
extended Darkness um I'm just doing it
because the plants are basically
finished I'm just going to let them
sleep for an extra amount of time
because I'm not spinning that
electricity uh and they're done and then
if that extra extended Darkness does do
anything I also happen to add that I
just know I'm cutting them down tomorrow
they're done I just defoliated them just
need to let them finish for that extra
day tomorrow is Cho day that's the only
real method for the extended darknesses
just unplug the light there's no need
for it at this point just let them Rock
have a real long night then you wake
them up and kill them so uh the first
thing I do defoliate heavily every leaf
get it off of there get rid of it uh
most of the leaves you're pulling now
are not the sugary leaves uh this is all
trash get rid of that so then the next
day when it's time I will go in and I
chopped the plants um some of these
plants got lollip popped fairly high
they had real long legs I didn't chop at
the base I chopped up real high just
before where the first nodes came out so
I just chopped just below that then I
flipped the plant upside down these
plants honestly went onto a coat hanger
The Hanger that my t-shirt was on my
jacket my hoodie uh just like that uh so
I take one of the branch so your plant
goes up it looks like a p sign right the
main branch and the two coming off flip
it upside down use one side of the PE
sign hang it right on that coat hanger
that went into my dry and cure area that
was as close to 50/50 as I could get it
uh 50 degrees 50% humidity and 100%
darkness in that room that plant went
right into there repeat until everything
is harvested uh then closely monitor
those plants uh pay attention to your
equipment in that room pay attention to
the humidifier the dehumidifier make
sure you're dumping those or filling
those as needed because if one of those
goes to [ __ ] uh so here's something
crazy that I do I didn't mention this in
the dry and cure room I will have a
humidifier and a dehumidifier both set
at 50% uh or both set at 55% that way
you get honestly these devices have a
little leeway so you get somewhere
between 50 and 60% humidity and
temperature that way they're both
fighting the reason you got to make sure
they're both up to date is because if
one goes wrong you really [ __ ] up the
room because now you're just uh
dehumidifying the room extremely instead
of adding the humidity they don't they
don't it doesn't work that way so make
sure equipment's working hang everything
upside down let it hang go in there and
check on it so here's where the art and
the skill comes into drawing and curing
the plants while the plants are hanging
grab a branch and just give it a bend
the plant's either going to bend like
it's wet and rubbery and supple or it's
going to pop a little bit or it's going
to explode those are three different
points of the dry and cure phase if it
bends a little bit and is rubbery way
too early if it goes crack you're just
at the right point I would start
trimming up those buds and get those
buds into an airtight container or at
least Buck the buds off of the sticks
and into an airtight container I did
half and half this time um I bucked the
buds into a bin I trimmed up a bunch of
them those went into a jar so I can dry
and cure them at some point I ran I
realized I was running out of time I was
getting exhausted I had to go to bed I
just started bucking the buds off of the
sticks and I put those untrimmed buds
into a jar they will get dried and cured
with leaves on them we can trim those
whenever the time comes not a big deal
so uh when they start snapping when they
start popping a little bit that's when
it's time to start getting those those
buds those flowers even the whole plant
if you need to into some sort of a
container to now start slowing down that
drying process for some people this line
is hard to determine when to put them in
that jar is really hard to determine for
some people you don't want to go when
it's too wet uh cuz then you can cause
problems if it's already exploding and
real dry then you've already caused
yourself problems so you want to go
right when those not the thin thin wispy
sticks not the big stick in the middle
but those side sticks when those start
popping good that's when you want to get
those buds off of there and get them
into a container so now we've taken the
the B so what I did was I like I said I
cut all the buds off the sticks into
containers so I knew that this plant was
B A this plant was b b then I trimmed a
bunch of those buds and put them into
the jars those are basically trimmed and
in the trimmed cure process uh we'll
talk more about the curing in a second
that's all set aside like I said before
I ran out of freaking time I got tired
bro I did more than I thought I was
going to do and so those are still hairy
but they got put into the jar they're
trimmed off the stick they're fuzzy but
they're in the jar uh they're just
drying and curing like normal we can cut
those leaves off later like I mentioned
before so that's where we are at this
point in the dry and cure phase if we
get those buds into those jars before
they're too dry we are in good shape we
are on the right path here's where we
have to be very careful we are sealing
wet spongy squishy fluffy buds into an
airtight container now inside of that
container is all of the great [ __ ] to
cause the curing reaction but also
what's in that container is all of the
wrong [ __ ] to cause a moldy reaction so
we've got to find a balance here what
we've got to do is pop these jars open
and let out all that stale air so what's
happening is quick version uh check me
if I'm wrong we are sealing that jar up
the moisture inside of that jar is
working with the oxygen inside of that
jar to start breaking down the
chlorophyll inside of that jar so the
moisture is necessary to break down the
chlorophyll it will break down that
chlorophyll into to a gas at some point
we must open the jar and let that gas
out and let fresh oxygen into that jar
the trick is we cannot let out all of
the moisture rapidly as we do this
because the only way to remove the
chlorophyll from these buds is with a
little bit of moisture in them still so
we want to slowly remove that
chlorophyll by uh sealing that product
in the jar letting that curing uh
there's a word for it that my brain
won't say right now I know the word
we've got to let that curing action
happen uh we've got to let that
chlorophyll that oxygen that water
battle it out we got to let that
chlorophyll become a gas then we open it
we let that gas back out then we seal it
back up we've got to let that happen
multiple times slowly so basically what
I would like to do ideally and this is
going to be hard for some people but
I've got access to my crop most of the
time if you're a commercial grower you
may need a special employee or a team to
do this this was Mike's job back in the
day shout out to Mike but here's what
I'm going to do I'm going to seal all of
my jars up or maybe you're using much
larger containers seal those then set a
timer I generally set my first timer for
two hours in two hours I'm going to go
open up those jars now is the time to
make a huge assessment now we will know
if we put those buds into those jars way
too early way too late or right on time
a lot of things are going to happen in
that first two hours moisture is going
to move around uh if some of the buds
were damp and some of the buds were dry
now they will be even if the buds were
real wet but the sticks had a lot of
moisture in them all that moisture is
going to move around and kind of even
itself out if the buds were dry and the
sticks had moisture that moisture is
going to move around now we will see how
wet those buds truly are at this point
we need to make a decision do we want to
leave those jars open for a few minutes
and like I said we just don't want to
let them dry out too dry to where we
can't get the Anor robic action is that
the word I was looking for earlier so
that we can't get the antiobese uh the
breakdown to eat up that chlorophyll in
there so you want to leave it open just
to get some air out of there let some
moisture out then at the amount of time
which you desire I would say somewhere
between three and maybe 15 to 30 minutes
if they're real wet if they're real
soppy dump them out of the jar and leave
that out on the table for a few minutes
but if it's just sticky and wet leave
the jar open 15 to 30 minutes or 3
minutes it's up to you you got to learn
this this is a skill and an art to
develop based on the amount of moisture
in that jar so leave it open for a few
minutes uh seal it back up set another
timer for 4 hours at this time and 4
hours repeat the process pop it open
look at it see what you think how wet is
that weed if you don't think it's going
to cause any mold in there seal it up
seal it up for another 4 hours and then
go check on it if you think it's too
moist too damp too sticky too gooey at
this point leave it open a little bit
longer we don't want the buds in there
to be spongy and gross but we want them
damp and sticky so that we can slowly
dry them the object here is slow dry
it's to stretch out this dry process so
you want to put them in the jar and
leave them in that jar until that gas is
eating up the chlorophyll but then we've
got to let that chlorophyll out and
replace it with fresh fresh oxygen to
keep repeating that process so I
continue with the timer process I'm a
little bit OCD I'll go 2 hours then I'll
go 4 hours a couple of times and then 6
hours and then 8 hours and then
eventually 12 hours and then eventually
you only have to open them every day
once at once a time and for a couple of
minutes by then I've seen a lot of guys
put hygrometers in their jar once you
get to a certain point of moisture which
you desire once you you get to that 63%
you can leave those jars sealed if
you're comfortable with that and that
herb should smoke fairly well uh here in
Colorado it's a real struggle to get the
herb perfect because we've got that dry
climate everyone talks about that
Colorado crunch I'm sure if you're down
in the South it's going to take a little
more time to get your stuff dry because
you've got all that humidity uh some
folks have to set their weed out on the
table for a minute before they can even
smoke it if you set it out too long here
it turns to dust if you set it out too
long in Mississippi it gets too wet to
smoke so keep in mind everything I'm
talking about you've got to adapt and
adjust this to your environment not
everybody's got that perfect climate
controlled room not everybody's got that
perfect uh state of in their house and
their their commercial facility I
understand that so you're going to have
to adjust everything and the the plants
are the boss still so pay attention to
the moisture level when you're popping
those sticks if they're gooey wait a
little bit longer if it's a commercial
facility and you're going to have to
leave overnight you may need to stay
late tonight and put those plants in new
container as late as possible I've done
that plenty of times but try to wait
till the perfect moment until they're
not exploding you don't want it to
explode then you went way too long uh
you don't want it to be gummy and
rubbery that's too early you want it to
just crack just right that's the perfect
time to put those buds into a jar I'm
checking my notes um one thing I did
write down if your buds in your jars do
get a little bit too dry here is a way
to reconstitute and remoisten them I
don't recommend letting them get too dry
but this is a backup plan grab one fresh
Leaf off of a plant and put one fresh
Leaf inside of your jar and seal it up
for about two hours just two hours will
be enough for a mason jar then take that
leaf out of there and check the moisture
that bud you may need to leave that jar
open for a little bit um close it up let
that moisture constitute move around
what's it called equalize then check on
your product out after about an hour
again and see what you need to do with
it from there but that one leaf will
moisturize your plants way way more than
you're anticipating so I said two hours
maybe I should have just said one
because a lot of people on the internet
really uh have a hard time with details
and instructions so let's say 1 hour
after 1 hour with that leaf in there go
check on it because then people will
[ __ ] up and extend their time and
they'll still be okay all right so real
quickly um here is my rundown I know I
know I went really quickly but it
doesn't have to be as difficult as a lot
of people want to make it prepare
yourself get your room prepared uh 50%
humidity to 60% humidity 50 to 60° fah
in the room is ideal it can be a little
bit off those are parameters we
understand that not every grower has got
the perfect environment but understand
that way too warm is going to dry that
weed way too fast it will get harsh it
will taste funky and that will also be
detrimental to your turps so get your
environment get your gear uh defoliate
everything um then chop the plants hang
them up in your dark room then
eventually they will snap then you Buck
all the buds off then jar them you can
trim them before or after the jar The
Cure process is now started open and
close those jars on a schedule something
I should mention a lot of people talk
about how stanky wheed is around week
seven 8 n as soon as you put scissors to
it it's going to be exponentially stanky
yes I did say stanky um the neighborhood
might know the neighbors are going to
smell it if the mailman comes up to the
porch he might smell your weed if you
order food they're going to smell it be
prepared for all of that I don't want
you to get this far and then get in
trouble because the Harvest was too
stinky if you've got a carbon filter I
would set that up right by where you're
trimming if necessary uh something that
I like to do I go to the grow store and
they sell something um what's a product
called it's um should I know the name of
it and I just can't say the name of the
product it is a smell it's an ozone
product I may have to press pause and
research the name of this [ __ ]
product real quick if you go to the grow
store and you ask them for smell
products to eliminate smell what is it
called dude it just won't come to me
it's a jar and a lot of people tear the
lid off and open the jar and tear that
paper lid off and leave it sitting open
that's not how you're supposed to do it
uh open it up and poke holes in that
paper uh that's on top of there and then
just poke a few holes in the plastic lid
and screw the plastic lid on top of
there it will last a lot longer boys and
girls I'm going to pause and research
the name of this product because it is
driving me crazy I didn't even have to
pause and research it because it came to
my head as soon as I started typing
smell product in the internet it is
called Ona gel OA Ona gels so what I
would do I would get that jar of Ona gel
and poke hole straight through the top
of it just a few holes you don't need a
lot and it will last much longer and set
that by the doorway like I've got a
little table by my doorway for my keys
and all that good [ __ ] to set it right
there so that when the door opens If
somebody walks in the very first thing
they smell is Ona gel the Ona is
designed to suck up bad Aromas and odors
it takes all the molecules I don't
understand the [ __ ] science I'm lying
to you it's designed to kill the odors
but also it makes off its own uh like
Hospital uh it smells like a urinal cake
hospital kind of a smell so the Ona gel
would be beneficial put those at your
front door your back door um if you've
got any sort of air conditioning blowing
air out set the Ona gel next to that
it'll shoot that Ona smell right out
through your air conditioner that is my
advice because if you grew good weed I
ordered a pizza and the pizza guy looked
at me like holy [ __ ] bro as soon as I
opened the door he knew I was trimming
luckily I went to high school with that
pizza dude so I've known that dude for a
long time was not an issue shout out
pizza guy not going to say your name all
right boys and girls I have been
rambling here for a very very long time
thank you for listening once again I do
apologize for being a day late on this
podcast I feel like I made up for it if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
also make sure you check out my website
on my website IR genetics.com there's a
link to my Discord server come join us
on Discord there's a link to IR
direct.com where you can get the seeds
make sure you check out the birthday
sale like we talked about a moment ago
and also there is a link to my patreon
campaign
patreon.com fromy yourheart make sure
you follow those links if you're
interested in supporting the podcast I
think that's all I've got for you for
this week I'll be back next week with
more free seed giveaways and more grow
questions I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy Lefty and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]