[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] welcome back podcast world
I'm your host rosta Jeff this is episode
831 of the grow fromy heart podcast C in
this episode we're going to give away
free seeds that's right hang out we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in the show I do want to invite you
to the dude grow Growers cup that's
right the dude grows crew is throwing
the dgc Growers cup once again this year
uh June 1st in laort Colorado the dude
grow crew will be there the iy Army will
be there I will be there white Mike will
be there we do invite you to join us at
the dude grow Growers cup June 1st in
laort Colorado make sure you check out
dgc cup.com for all of the information
before I get too far into the show I do
want to send a big thank you shout out
to everybody who sent me some birthday
love if you supported the birthday sale
on IR
[Music]
redirect.sh sale is still going at ir
redirect.sh and the IR skunk will be
restocked we're going to talk more about
those later in the show but those are
restocked if you miss them so have no
fear go ahead I redirect the birthday
sale is still going and things have been
restocked all right I think that's
enough advertising I want to talk about
one more thing recently I did ask for
some help with short clips from the
podcast I want to send a big thank you
to everybody who has sent me shorts uh I
got overloaded with emails from the
birthday sale uh I got overloaded with a
lot of great shorts I haven't posted all
of them I've posted a few of them if you
have been sending me short videos thank
you I got a lot of them I'm filtering
through them I'm working out deals and
relationships with some of the people
that have sent them to me so thank you
for all of those short clips I'm sure
you guys have seen some of them on
YouTube uh people are doing a great job
sending those so once again big thank
you for all of the short clips I sent
out that call of action and you did
respond so thank you I do appreciate
that uh what's the next order of
business oh yeah I had to update my
mailing list service many of you are a
part of the IE genetics mailing list if
I do a new drop a new sale uh something
cool happens I do try to send you an
email try not to spam you too much
lately I've been sending a lot I do know
but I did have to change my mailing
service something went wrong with the
service I was using honestly they said I
violated terms of service I'm in
communication with them trying to get
that account back but you guys don't
care about that the point is I had to
update my mailing list service so if
you're getting an email uh that does not
look like the old emails I sent it's
because they changed my format I had to
change formats I'm not used to it yet
I'm learning it but I'm trying to get
the old account back my point is if
you're getting emails from IE genetics
that don't look the same those are from
me uh it's a new service it's a new
format I had to switch it up I'm trying
to go back to MailChimp we are in talks
we'll see if she'll take me back anyway
if you're getting those emails that is
me somebody said hey is this really you
it doesn't look like your messages
thanks for checking on us thanks for
making sure that really is me uh also
check your spam because I've been
sending a couple of new emails by the
time this comes out you'll probably get
an update that those skunk testers have
restocked let me make sure I've covered
the business we got one more thing you
guys you gals I have ordered new
t-shirts that's right there's new
merchandise coming to iy genetics those
t-shirts will not be on IAD direct they
will be on a different website I do have
an Etsy store I know it does sound odd
to have two different websites and sell
products on two different spots but
there's a business um purpose and a
business method for all of that the
t-shirts will be on the Etsy website if
you go to my website IR genetics.com
there's a tab that says merch if you
click on that merch tab that will take
you right to the Etsy store there will
be new t-shirts some of the older
t-shirts will be back up there there are
dab mats there will be hats up there
there will be new merch here is a deal
if you show up to the dude grows
Grower's cup wearing an iy genetics or
an iy army t-shirt or a hoodie if you've
got the T-shirt or the hoodie on and
it's visible and you're wearing it it's
not covered up with a jacket or
something if it's rainy I'll give you an
excuse but if it's a if we can see that
you're wearing iy army gear a hat would
even count if you show up wearing iy
army gear I will give you a free prize I
cannot promise you what the prize will
be right now but anybody who shows up to
the dude grow cup wearing iy army or iy
gen itic gear will receive a free gift
walk up to the booth and say hey bro I
was told if I was wearing this I would
get a free gift I will give you
something cool or I will authorize Mike
to give you something cool it will be
worth your time so grab some new iy gear
or rock that old iy gear honestly I want
everybody at the dude grow cup to be
wearing iy genetic skar I think that
would be a lot of fun come represent
come show the iy Army is strong come
show that iy genetics is strong show up
represent at the dude grow cup I'll give
you a free gift come hang out all right
I think that is all of the business part
let me go over my list really quickly uh
we got the clips we got the new mail
service I ordered shirts they will be on
the website and if you wear a shirt at
the cup you'll get a free gift all right
I feel like we've covered all of the
business here at the start of the show
let's work our way into the email
portion of today's podcast this email
did come from the growel tab on my
website that's right my website is IR
genetics.com i i genetics.com i
genetics.com that is my website that is
my my company uh go to IR genetics.com
on the top of that website there's a row
of tabs one of them says questions or
grow help I don't remember what it says
right now it's either questions or grow
help you'll find it it's pretty obvious
what it is if you click on that tab you
are given the opportunity to send me a
grow question or just a basic question
this is a good question that came from
that tab if you use that grow help Tab
and I read your question here on the
podcast that means you will win a free
coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from edirect decom that's right edirect
is the vending website IR genetics.com
is the Hub where everything else is I
know it sounds difficult but it does
make sense once you get there anyhow if
I read your grow question off of that
growel tab you will win a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds the person that
won a free pack of seeds today goes by
Trent Gil big shout out to my new friend
Trent Gil Trent's question goes a little
bit just like this it says yo roster
Jeff sorry to be a pest no pesting at
all I get a lot of emails I try to
answer most of them or reply somehow
I apologize if I don't get to all of
them you are not bugging me uh keep
sending those emails it says I'm still
curious what's the difference between
the 9s and the iy skunk I've already
ordered a pack of the '90s skunk but I'm
thinking about adding on a pack of the
iie if that is possible uh then here's a
part that is kind of a conversation but
I'm going to address this here just
because I've got the opportunity on the
podcast it says I don't know if I can
venmo the cash or cash app or send the
money I just don't want to pay shipping
twice um that is a really good idea I
wish that I could do that but um it's
not just a Onan kind of a me and you
doing a deal operation sort of a thing
anymore uh there's a shipping app
there's a website it's all got to go
through that website it's all got to be
official uh once the order is in I can't
really amend the orders sometimes people
will send me an email saying hey you're
going to send me a pack of 4K freebies
can you swap that out with this and
unfortunately I can't do it the the
amount of orders that I'm getting uh are
overwhelming and I can't keep tabs of
all the switches all the substitutions
it's just not possible
the way that the system is set up there
will be mistakes if I do that and I
finally got the system figured out to
where there are minimal mistakes I'm not
going to say we don't make mistakes uh
but everybody's trained well everybody
knows their role in the packaging and
sending part of the deal now and so
we're not making as many mistakes if I
were to uh take a cash app or a venmo
from you I would have to figure out
where that order goes it's just a I know
it sounds stupid but it's just another
it's all on the website it's all done
that way for a reason the orders all go
to ship station uh all the packaging
have help shipping them honestly and the
people helping me ship have to see it in
ship station it's got to go that way uh
I know it sounds stubborn but it's a
business that's the way we're running in
that's the way it's working uh there
aren't mistakes right now and that's
what matters the most uh shout out to
the people that help me also um where
were we can I send you venmo cash app
unfortunately that's not an option I
just don't want to pay shipping twice I
understand that but uh I'm going to give
you a free pack of seeds here so you
won't have to pay shipping twice and
you're going to get some free seeds it
says um is one of and then we're going
to get he goes back to talking about the
skunk testers here so we're just going
to say is one of the skunk testers more
indical leaning or more sativa does the
I skunk involve your Lemon Skunk is
there something different bread to it
and then it says I love some good skunk
um then he wraps it up with the stink is
just a bonus and then he says Uh there's
some more stuff here but I don't need to
read all this it says thanks man hope
you have an awesome day from Trent hey
Trent thank you for the great question I
do have some answers but honestly I'm
going to be quite vague when it comes to
talking about testers I try not to give
you too many details because that will
bias or sway your testing right now
you've got some seeds and you don't know
what to expect other than the hopes of
skunk and that I've told you guys it
takes about 9 to 10 weeks for these to
flower CU I want you to finish them out
on time and let them do the right
flowering time but that's about all the
details I really want to give so I try
not to give you guys too much
information about the testers because I
don't want to bias or sway your testing
I know what I've seen uh from these
plants and I'm not too far ahead of you
guys and the testing honestly um I'm
having fun with them just like you guys
but uh I know what I'm seeing from the
phenotypes I know what I'm looking for I
know what I want to see if you guys
discover in those phenotypes and what
you pull out I want to see if you're
seeing the same things as me if you're
discovering the same things I do or if
you're getting different things in
different rooms and I don't want to give
you too many ideas because if I say one
does this or one does this you'll be
looking for that and it puts a fixation
on things and it creates bias within the
testing this is like a blind study uh I
know the seeds are good I know they're
not intersects I know they germ well I
know they're quality but I'm looking for
certain specific traits to see what you
guys get uh just for documentation and
then for advertising a lot also but uh
you guys are going to discover a lot of
that so when it comes to the testers I
don't give out a lot of information I've
got notes here to keep me on track cuz
I'm highest draft [ __ ] to be honest to
you guys odd said I can't tell you too
much because it will bias your testing I
used uh skunk so these came from how
much information do I want to give you
these came from two different batches of
skunk number one seeds so there's seeds
of skunk number one from two different
batches uh there's also the skunk number
one clone and there is another batch of
seeds that we played with and grew some
skunks out of but that didn't make it to
this round of breeding so what I can
tell you is one is uh they're both skunk
number ones but when we did the feno
hunting my myself and another friend of
mine went through these plants and grew
them and smoked them and uh scrutinized
these plants and any of the skunk number
one seeds that we started with if it had
that sweet or that cinnamon some had
cinnamon if it had sweet or like
seasoning sort of smells it went away
the only things that passed through uh
our rigorous um the casting couch the
fenal hunts were the ridiculous rotten
skunk I don't want to share too much
because like I said it's going to sway
your testing but they are both from
skunk number one seed stock and they are
skunky that's none of the sweet [ __ ]
it's none of the candy [ __ ] I focused on
straight skunk I want to elaborate so I
need to get away from this topic before
I tell you way too much because I feel
like I've already told you enough
honestly um we use skunks I tossed
anything sweet there are two different
skunk number one phenotypes it came from
seed plus the skunk number one clone the
original OG clone is in the breeding but
you guys aren't getting that yet that's
not in this batch which means that there
are more skunk crosses coming what so
once you guys test these there will be
more skunk there's a skunk uh number one
uh S1 from that there are um there's
possibly Mel Frank sturban poison to
skunk number one I've already said too
much but um that's as much as I could
tell you right now I know I just rambled
a long time about that skunk and I can't
give you too much info because I don't
want to sway your testing um you're
talking about buying another pack I
highly recommend that I would love to
see what happens if you ran both packs
under the same environment right next to
each other that's really what I'm
looking for um that would tell me a lot
of stuff that would help me continue my
breeding that's kind of what we're doing
here so yeah run them both if you can
and um here's a good update those skunks
are restocked I may have said this by
now but by the time this episode comes
out there will be more of those skunks
the 90s and the iy skunk both will be
available at iy
direct.com all right my friend Trent Gil
by the time this episode comes out make
sure you check your email uh check your
spam because oftentimes those gift codes
do go to the spam folder but you should
have a coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds from iy
direct.com once again if you have any
trouble with that please do reach out a
couple of people said that Tech
difficulties using the gift cards I'll
guide you right through it it's not that
hard we'll do it together cheers my
friend thanks for the great message
we're going to keep this show moving
I've got another great question here
this one has been coming up quite a bit
so I figured it was time to answer this
this question came from my good friend
Dylan I've been talking to Dylan on
Facebook for a long time what's up dude
Dylan sent this question on the growel
tab on the iy genetics website so that
means that Dylan you want a free pack of
seeds from
redirect.sh Yo Rasta Jeff what's up dude
says I have a question about the
structural terms of the cannabis plant
on your descriptions of your awesome
strains it mentions the term more open
structured plants I was hoping you could
elaborate a bit on what that means and
what to expect from that I'm currently
waiting for scarlet Bonas Redline
Morning Dew and candylicious and I can't
wait for that run to get started BR
that's going to be a good run you got
some Classics in there uh the Scarlet
Bonas is a classic the morning dew is a
classic uh Redline is going to be a
classic in my lineup eventually that is
a hitter that is a winner don't sleep on
that one and then cand delicious that's
one of the most current newest uh F and
that is hot fire so you got a good
lineup in there dude that's like the
Dream Team uh I can't wait to see the
pictures also make sure you send me
photos my dude then it goes on it says
I've previously grown your feminized
Golden Goat and I loved it thank you for
sharing all of your knowledge and all
all of your excellent Creations I love I
genetics well Dylan we love you back bro
uh thank you for the great message now
this is a really good question uh Dylan
is asking about the terms I am using
when I talk about the structure of the
plants and since he listed four plants
here before I get into my notes that I
made my little chart that I wrote about
structure I'm going to address the four
plants he's talking about Scarlet Bonas
um so if I was talking about structures
of plants it's just like talking about
like if you looked at people or if you
looked at trees like I'm tall and skinny
and lanky that's a way to describe me uh
if somebody was built different than me
you could say that they were short and
Pudgy or thick might be the word or just
different that's what I'm doing with the
cannabis plants I'm finding words that
apply to the shape and structure of the
plant that I think would translate to
most people so if we're going to talk
about Scarlet Bonas Scarlett Bonas is
built mostly a lot of the phenotypes are
built like me tall lanky kind of
stretchy kind of skinny uh they're going
to stretch out a lot in flowers so I
would call that a tall stretchy branchy
kind of plan I'm tall lanky and stretchy
and branchy myself so I can say that
Redline uh red line is a little bit more
bushy which bushy right you can now that
I'm giving you some descriptors to
compare it to Bushy it bushes out just a
little bit more the Scarlet Bonas goes
up up up and out a little bit the red
line goes out quite a bit and not up as
vigorously so now we're starting to
figure out the different the ways I'm
applying these words Morning Dew Morning
Dew uh she will grow kind of wide kind
of bushy but also she'll get a nice IAL
dominant top uh she has that open
structure I'm talking about um if you
look at the the red line she's bushy and
messy on the inside all the branches
that come up are making a bunch of
leaves it's all tight together in there
it's just messy on the inside you got to
get in there and clean that [ __ ] up the
morning do is a little bit more open to
where when you get in there to work with
it the branches aren't so claustrophobic
on the inside it's more open it's kind
of widened up it's self uh open is the
word for it more air flow less uh
nonsensical branching down at the bottom
less unnecessary leafing so that's the
open uh more branchy bushy structure
from The Morning Dew now candylicious uh
cand delicious has some phenotypes to
get pretty tall but also it's got a lot
of branching vit so now here's another
descriptor I talk about sometimes the
branches of the plants will um they'll
come out and they'll curve up and those
branches usually you'll notice reach the
top of the plant they try to make an
even canopy a lot of plants will shoot
branches that just go at an angle like a
45° I think it is about 45 yeah and just
go shoot shoot shoot and they'll just
come straight off and those will get
kind of messy sometimes you'll notice
that all that [ __ ] gets confused in
there that's a tighter more narrow more
closed up plant you may see that from
the uh the
candylicious so and that part comes from
the the Afterglow the Afterglow makes it
grow messy so those are just quick ways
to describe the four plants that you've
got now I do have a little flowchart
that I made here for myself I guess I
could call it um to talk about structure
um the first thing that we usually talk
about is frame and shape that's what
I've been focused on mostly here to
start um frame and shape things that I
would use to describe the frame and
shape are words like a tight structure a
tight frame an open frame but so let me
talk about a tight frame so some plants
will grow uh you get here I'm going to
use my arm is the main stock so some
plants you'll have a branch coming a
pair of branches coming here and then a
pair of branches coming here that's
about three or four inches apart and
then sometimes they'll be 8 to 10 in
apart if I say tight that means they're
closer together all the structure is
just tighter more compact um I would say
orange gasm compared to a rise orange
gasm is a tighter Golden Goat is a much
tighter plant compared to a rise a rise
just spreads itself out mansplains or
man spreads takes up all the room on the
bus where [ __ ] Golden Goat stays a
little bit tighter keeps into its own
space a little bit better so that's a
tight structure that open structure is
the next word on my list um those are
the plants where they're more open on
the bottom and they just spread out on
their own a little bit the branches
aren't touching and everything's growing
together it's just more open if you drew
a silhouette of it you could kind of see
some space of the background through it
it's not just a big bushy messy plant
the next word I've got is stretchy um
I've mentioned aise arise can be a tall
stretchy plant Jack Tripper can be a
tall stretchy plant it makes that
fishing pole in the middle that Long
Tall fishing pole Branch with all those
Long Tall stretchy branches that is
stretchy you guys have dealt with
stretchy before some of my stuff
unfortunately can be a bit stretchy then
the opposite of that is squatty plants
if you guys grow those plantss that they
don't go up a lot nuke town will do this
new town grows outward a lot uh but it
stays low that's a low squatty plant so
it's just down there if you've got a low
grow space I may recommend the nuke town
it may shoot up one appical dominant top
chop that [ __ ] out you got a nice Bush
bushy uh squatty plant there you go
that's and it's that one's kind of a
mess in the middle that's got a uh the
branches are open but on the inside it's
real branchy and leafy on the inside so
those are some structural terms uh some
visual descriptors we could talk about
that would identify the structure uh
branchy I just said branchy so nuke town
has train wreck in the lineage in the
background somewhere and that train
wreck represents itself in New Town as
just massive branches going every
direction uh you get the main branch
going up then you get a lot of [ __ ]
going out but then off of those you also
get little sub branches that most of the
time we would cut off cuz they're just
little suckers and we lollipop that if
you leave those on the nuk town they
will make more Buds and more free
branches so that is a branchy [ __ ]
plant in my opinion uh a word I've used
frequently also is bushy uh the red line
Red Line will go up and then it'll start
to go out especially if you top red line
take out that main top it'll get bushy
uh it'll look like a shrub or a hedge
you could just put two of them in front
of the front door it'll look like bushes
out there like you're greeting people
with nice bushes in front of the house
so that's bushy you guys understand
bushy the shrubs all the [ __ ] that you
see the decorative [ __ ] out there those
are bushes um tall plants a lot of my
stuff unfortunately I said now tall and
stretchy could be similar and different
at the same time you can have a tall
plant with tight node spacing have I
talked about tight node spacing yeah
we're going to talk more about that
stuff too I got that going on uh tall
plants and stretchy plants can be
different um Jack Jack Tripper will get
stretchy but uh the John Lemon will get
tall and that's a different thing
because it stays compact it stays
together it all gets tall where Jack
Tripper just [ __ ] that top takes off
the branches get out of control um so
that's tall and stretchy are different
things and then some plants grow very
wide um I used the the red line as an
example that one you might want to give
it a little bit of extra space because
it wants to reach out sometimes the
machine uh Saka sule those like to reach
out just a little bit and take up a
little bit more space if you ever grew
my Prana that was a plant that liked
more wide space more than it did the
vertical space so that is basically the
frame and structure that I'm talking
about when it comes to cannabis now
there are more things to cover on this
list now the next thing on my list is
node spacing I touched on this a little
bit ago when I was talking about tight
plants what do I mean by node spacing so
we've got our main stock of our plant
and we've got branches coming off of
that main stock by node spacing I mean
how far apart are those nodes and also
how far apart are those nodes on the
branches so you got your main branch
coming off and you've got more branches
and then you got more branch and more
branches how far apart is that there are
pros and cons to far and close
structures like that if your nodes are
too close together then that that plant
may not work in a high humidity
environment that plant may have a lot of
problems because there's going to be
branches close together leaves close
together high humidity may cause you
problems so you may want something a
little more open structured a little
less tight node spacing may be
appropriate a lot of the OG cush type
stuff has that far apart node spacing
but the Golden Goat has got really nice
kind of tight node spacing so if I breed
that Golden Goat to something kind of OG
G cushy it comes out with a really nice
frame and structure and really nice
appropriate node spacing it's not too
far apart to make the plant stretchy uh
and it's not too close together to give
it problems so I really think the Golden
Goat to older stuff really makes uh good
structured and shaped plants that's why
I use the Golden Goat so much it fixes
up a lot of that stretchy structure so
that's a lot of what I mean by node
spacing how far apart are the branches
uh from the main stock and also how far
apart are the shoots and Bud s sites on
those branches so that's what I mean by
node spacing another thing to think
about that tells us a lot about the
plant is leaf shape and size how big are
those leaves and what shape are they are
they real skinny long leaves are they
big fat leaves that you can make a shade
underneath that leaf structure and size
and shape will tell you a lot about that
cannabis plant it tell you a lot about
how long it's going to take to flower if
those leaves are real huge you may have
like an eight or nine week flowering
plant the longer and skinnier those
leaves get the longer flowering plant
you're generally going to have that
usually does apply so that's not a hard
and fast rule of thumb but most of the
time if you look at all your plants in
the room you go well holy [ __ ] that
Golden Goat that Jack trier's got them
long skinny leaves it's the longest
flowering plant in the room if you've
got Isabella those going to be long
skinny gigantic leaves it's going to be
one of the longest flowering plants in
the room uh if you've got some of the
old daybreaker crosses I made those make
giant leaves they finish up quite
quickly so you'll notice that leaf shape
will give you a huge indication of how
long that plant is going to need to
flower um then I talk about sturdy or
wispy branches that's a huge indicator
that definitely lies into structure uh
sturdy are the plants sturdy or are they
wispy and shitty um you'll notice a lot
of those OG kushes they can be kind of
wispy and shitty and need a lot of
supports but things that have been bred
with the Golden Goat the Golden Goat
itself a lot of the Jack Jack the Ripper
crosses those are very sturdy the
Platinum Tangi all the Tangi crosses uh
orange gasm it'll just hold itself right
up it's ready to go it will salute so
you got sturdy branching versus wispy
branching uh you got some plants that
make that a real Woody sort of a
structure some are just genetically will
make that Woody structure some will make
a real soft green plush structure uh
those both have their pros and cons so
those do fall into structure when I'm
talking about structure what else do I
have nug formation flower cluster um
some plants those OG kushes I've been
talking about are going to make golf
ball buds up that stock you're just
going to have a golf ball then 6 in 3 in
up there' be a golf ball and then a golf
ball they'll get bigger as they get to
the top of the plant and those golf
balls hopefully will'll turn into a nice
Cola at the top but those OG cushion are
going to make your golf ball type
structure then some of the other stuff
I'm just going to use Golden Goat you're
going to get that big donkey dick
baseball bat type of structure then I've
got plants like Grateful Dog that make
Acorn style buds they're silver and
purple they look like big acorns they
just triangles all over the plant you're
going to have different bud structure
sometimes you're going to have real
dense real tight buds
sometimes you're going to have open
fingery possibly foxtail type of buds
that's just all about the structure the
phenotype the genetics of that plant
what else do we have colors and Aromas
those are obvious we've talked about
that before colors that's what colors
the damn plants are Aromas uh that's
what you think it smells like sometimes
I'll tell people this smells like bubble
gum and they'll tell me I'm crazy or
whatever no it's subjective bro to me it
smells like bubble gum uh where are we I
wanted to give a couple of examples like
I did earlier um a tall plant let me
Jeffrey would qualify as a tall plant
all of the uh Jack the Ripper crosses
will qualify as tall plants branchy
plants uh nuk Town qualifies as a very
branchy plant the Double Dragon as a
branchy plant the bubble goat some of
those bubble goat phenotypes have that
open structure that I've talked about
and that's a real classic uh Christmas
tree looking sort of a shape real easy
to grow sort of a plant uh the orange
gasm that is a tall plant with a tight
structure so those are some examples of
some of my plants and the structures
that that I would identify so those are
just a few examples from strains in my
lineup that I can tell you about the
structure of course you're going to get
phenotypical variation uh different
lighting is going to give you different
amounts of stretch and different amounts
of height the way you feed uh your
environment will play into this but this
is generally what you can expect and
this guideline is just basically what I
call uh the basic structures of plants
that open structure that tight structure
uh you got some plants you can see it if
you drive through Cali you'll be able to
tell these differences uh out there in
the fields real easily there's those
super tall tall sativa plants uh they're
going to be out there for a long time
those are what I call the tall
stretchier plants those tight plants
that look like a big shrub and a bush
those are tight bushy plants uh once you
start understanding uh how I'm
describing it start just looking at the
plants more it will all become obvious
to you so my dude Dylan this was a
really good question you got me rambling
for quite a long time my friend make
sure you check your email because I do
owe you a coupon code for a free pack of
iy genetics premium seeds I'm excited to
get those to you we've been buddies for
a long time uh it's great to read your
message on here I didn't know this came
from you until I printed it and then
went to read it so big up fist bump to
my buddy Dylan all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast if I did not read your
question on this episode please do not
feel discouraged I've got a mountain of
emails over here that I want to read on
this podcast if your message did not
come up don't be discouraged there are
plenty more episodes coming I have no
reason to stop doing the show no reason
to stop reading your questions keep
tuning in maybe I'll read your question
on a future episode keep the questions
coming once again you can use my website
IR genetics.com i i i genetics.com that
will get you to the website that's where
you'll find the growel tab also you will
find a link to my Discord server dude
come hang out on Discord we've been
getting a lot of new people on Discord
it is a good time uh you can post
pictures of your grow you can post
pictures of your test grow if you're
test growing iy genetic seeds I highly
recommend that you come post pictures on
the Discord server on the Discord server
you'll find pictures of most of the I
genetic strains there's pictures of
almost everything uh there's pictures of
the testers that are happening in
progress now and there's also a smoker
Lounge where I'm probably hanging out
taking dabs if I'm not on the podcast if
I'm not out having fun I'm usually
signed into the smoker Lounge just
hanging out you can come chat with us
there's a lot of cool people people in
there that know a lot about growing
cannabis uh they're just also a lot of
fun to hang out with big shout out to
the Discord crew come hang out you guys
also I'm talking about the website there
is a link to the merchandise by the time
this episode comes out I hope to have
new merchandise on the website and like
I said if you do wear that iy genetics
or iy Army t-shirt hoodie or a hat that
is visible not covered up by a jacket or
something if you probably wear that gear
to the dgc cup I will give you a free
prize come say hi make sure you come say
hi at the dgc cup anyway you guys uh I
want to meet everybody I want a fist
bump from the whole crew especially if
you listen to the podcast come say hello
all right I am rambling but one more
important very important detail if
you've made it this far in this episode
of this podcast when you go to I
redirect use coupon code love and you
will save 10% that is my thanks to you
for listening all the way through to the
end of the podcast all right this is
truly the end of the show all right I'll
be back next week with fresh new content
I want to give a giant shout out to the
entire crew at Denver Comedy Works and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]