[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 832 of the
grow from your heart podcast you know
I've got a great episode lined up for us
in today's show I'm going to give away
free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about the free seeds later on in the
episode I do want to invite you to the
dude grow Growers cup that's right June
1st in leaport Colorado the dude grow
crew is throwing the dude grow Growers
cup make sure you check out dgc cup.com
for all the info on the dude grow
Growers cup while we're talking about
the dude grows Grower's cup I want to
remind you that I did restock the iy
genetics Army GI Joe logo t-shirt trying
to get these on the camera here got to
move my dreadlocks got to move the mic
out of the way but these t-shirts the
shirt I am wearing these have been
restocked if you go to my website IR
genetics.com there's a tab up at the top
it says merch click on that tab that
will take you to a store where you can
get all kinds of shirts there are hats
there are uh rolling trays there are dab
mats lots of great merch up there go
grab one of the new iy army shirts uh
the cool part is if you wear IE genetics
or IE Army merchandise to the dude grow
cup I will give you a free prize make
sure you stop by the booth and say hello
show me your iy army gear I'll hook you
up with the free prize come say hi even
if you don't have I gear or I merch come
pick it up at the cup come say hello I
look forward to seeing you there all
right I think I covered all of the
business here at the start of the show
the next thing I want to talk about is
daylight savings time how did you manage
daylight savings time in your grow most
of us here in North America just had to
move our clock 1 hour forward so that
means your grow room came on 1 hour
later that means it stayed on 1 hour
later than it did the day before did
that mess up your schedule did that
freak you out a little bit I want to
know in the comments section how did you
adjust to Daylight Savings time there
was a few options of how you could
adjust to this you could simply let it
ride let that plant schedule do its
thing and then you adjust your life
around it just move things around one
hour that's kind of what I did a lot of
people they will adjust that light in
the flowering room and the light in the
vedro Just Adjust that timer 1 hour to
make it fit their schedule to make it
actually work with the real clock that
the time that it was on I find that a
bit uh abrupt to a flower room but many
people will do that then the other
option of course is to uh unplug that
light and leave it unplugged for would
it be 25 hours or 23 hours that would
have been 25 hours and then plug it in
at the next round of normal time those
are the three main options that I think
of to get you back on schedule for
Daylight Savings Time I Want to Know
What You Did let me know what you did in
the comments section here if you're
watching on YouTube YouTube Type A
comment let me know how you adjusted uh
your grow room and your life to Daylight
Savings time if you're here in the North
America region where we just switched
our clocks all right that was the first
thing I wanted to talk about the next
thing I want to talk about is a question
that I have been receiving quite a bit
lately I'm not sure what made this
strain real popular why people wanted to
talk about it but of course I'm talking
about a strain that I bred a while back
called double Paula we're going to talk
very briefly about double Paula I'm
already getting a smile on my face
because double paa is very elusive we're
going to talk briefly about double paa
what is double paa double paa is a very
beautiful plant um it was bred I bred
double paa in approximately I want to
say uh Circa 2017 it could have been
2018 um could have been that time frame
when I bred that one so I made that one
around 2017 2018 is about when I think I
made that one uh double paa is known for
making gigantic yields big old fatty
buds buds the size of my arms I got
skinny arms but they're long so it makes
big long arms I should have said my legs
my legs are better um so it makes big
giant buds big giant yields it will make
a a large variety of candy and fruity
turps there's like watermelon in there
uh there's some bananas there's like
apricot flavors do you say apricot or
apricot argue about that in the comments
as well but that turp is hidden in there
a little bit uh it's got candy flavors
in there it's got all kinds of fruity
candy deliciousness flavor that I really
enjoy um those big giant buds that I
talked about at making are bright
fluorescent green uh makes most of the
time makes really bright fluorescent
green flowers sometimes there are some
phenotypes that will be the complete
opposite they make a really dark color
with the golden leaf curl at the end uh
that's double paa most of the phenotypes
take about 65 to 72 days to finish on
you so uh let that one finish but you're
going to have big gigantic buds uh the
cix to Leaf ratio is very very nice on
the double paa uh not a whole bunch of
leaf on there uh it's really easy to
trim makes big giant buds really easy
for bag appeal really nice for the trim
crew uh big heavy colas is the next note
that I wrote down and then I wrote down
also heavy feeding um also it's going to
get tall I want to exaggerate that these
plants do get tall and they eat a lot so
um yeah like I said before double Paula
is shrouded in mystery still kind of is
that's the most I'm going to tell you
today but a lot of people are asking
about double paa honestly that's all the
info I'm going to give you double Paula
is kind of a secret um I don't know why
I just stuttered when I talked about it
but double Paula is kind of a secret in
my Arsenal I tell you everything I tell
you so much I tell you so many details
uh double Pao will be a secret uh as
long as I can keep it a secret there may
be one other person out there that knows
the truth uh I don't know if they have
ever told anybody what double Paula
really is so that's my story with double
Paula and I'm sticking to it now let's
segue into another section of today's
podcast this is the pet peeve section of
the show you guys know what a pet peeve
is something that just drives you
freaking crazy uh something that grinds
your gears something that is
cringeworthy there's a lot of different
words for it sometimes I'll be looking
on the internet and I'll see something
in somebody's grow photos and I'll go ew
or sometimes I'll walk into a grow space
a commercial grow a private grow and
I'll go oh man just something that
simply drives me crazy in a grow room I
encourage you to send me your pet peeves
if something just drives you freaking
crazy in a grow if you work at a
commercial grow if you see it in a
private grow if you see it online it
could be also in the grow or the
Cannabis Community it could be something
that happens in a smoke Circle does
somebody do something that drives you
crazy is there a weird rule or something
a weird Community or cultural thing that
just pisses you off let me know send me
an email at grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com if I read your pet peeve
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds on
edirect decom our first pet peeve comes
from somebody named redyed Rick I
actually found this one on
YouTube excuse me for the groly throat
of course I've been taking dabs today
red-eyed Rick said the number one cause
of house fires is the extension cord and
that was told to me by my residential
electrical teacher and fire chief in
trade school so yes uh they did not send
me this as a pet peeve but that is one
of my pet peeves is going into a grow
and seeing that spiderweb of electrical
cords of power cords of power strips
everywhere you guys that [ __ ] just like
our friend just said is the number one
cause of house fires is the extension
cord so if you're the grower that's got
all the extension cords all over the
place one of my friends yeah I'm talking
to you bro uh be careful because that is
a cause for fire go check on I don't
want you to use them I'd rather you not
use them uh get the electricity figured
out do it properly I understand some of
you guys are going to do what you're
going to do I don't promote it I don't
support it but if you're going to do it
use the best highest grade power uh
electric cords power cords what are they
called the extension cords you can get
the highest grade best quality you can
get and go feel them make sure they're
not getting too hot and pay attention to
how many amps you're pulling from that
wall socket because uh if you've got an
older house uh that wiring in there will
heat up that will catch on fire um I
don't want you to harm your family I'm
talking to everybody at this point not
just my one friend that I know has got a
[ __ ] maze in a zoo of extension cords
but I don't want anybody out there
anybody to get hurt by a fire I don't
want your house to get burnt down I
don't want the house to have a small
fire
I don't want the fire department to come
I don't want the adrenaline in your
heart um I definitely don't want the uh
the Cannabis industry the Cannabis
Community to be blamed for that fire
down the street imagine how shitty that
sounds uh Hey Bild you hear the House
burn down down the street yeah I heard
they were growing a bunch of weed in
there and one of the grow lights caught
on fire like that' just be the worst
[ __ ] for the community at this point
we're finally almost starting to be
taken seriously and people don't look at
us like a bunch of lazy Stoners Like a
bunch of criminals
we're past the BHO explosion phase of
this culture so let's move forward and
keep putting a positive impact on the
community and not move backwards by uh
burning the [ __ ] down with too many
extension cords so that is my pet PE for
the show um my friend red-eyed Rick you
did not send this to me as a pet peeve
but if you contact me uh on YouTube let
me know how I can send you a coupon code
for a pack of seeds I will hook you up
with a free pack of seeds because I used
your YouTube comment for Content here on
the show all right let's keep this
awkward momentum moving I've got a bunch
of great emails here in front of me I've
got a website that website is IR
genetics.com if you go to that website
on the top there's a bunch of tabs one
of those tabs it either says grow help
or grow questions if you click on that
Tab and you send me a grow question or
ask for grow help if I read your
question here on the podcast I will send
you a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds on air.com the first email
question on today's podcast came from my
new friend Lawrence big shout out to my
buddy Lawrence Lawrence make sure you do
check your email because you have got a
coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds Lawrence's
question uh this question came in kind
of oddly written but I was able to
translate it and break it down into uh
I'll just make it make sense for you
basically Lawrence said uh I bought a
pack of feminized seeds so they've got
feminized seeds and they're asking can I
use one of these female seeds out of
this feminized pack to breed with if I
put male pollen on this feminized seed
so basically they're asking is there a
difference in breeding between feminized
female plants and just using a regular
uh non- feminized regular male female
breed female plant is the basic of this
question here then it says much love
from our friend Lawrence Lawrence bro
thank you for the great content because
this will be fun to talk about for just
a moment here uh the main answer is uh
that is a great idea there is no problem
at all with breeding a male plant to a
Fe female plant that came from a
feminized pack of seeds there is no
problem with that at all I encourage
that that is something that I would
definitely do also what you can also do
is you can pollinate that female plant
that came from that female pack of seeds
with any other reverse female of your
choosing if you've tested it and done
the proper background research but um
yes that plant is a very viable plant
for breeding if you find a keeper that
you enjoy whether it came from a femin
seed or a regular seed yes you can breed
to that there is no difference in that
feminized plant and a regular male
female bred female plant there's no
difference the only difference is the
way that it was bred in my opinion in my
experience the difference is the pollen
um I've repeated this on this show a
couple of times we're going to say it
one more time here uh just to get the
message out here and I did learn this
analogy came from Mr Soul big shout out
to my friend Mr Soul uh Rick thank you
for the great info uh Mr Soul kind of
put it this way one time this is not the
way that it works this is an analogy
this is just a way to paint the picture
so that you can understand how feminized
seas and female uh breed feminized
plants work now imagine um just imagine
this is what we're going to build in our
brain right here on this side uh we have
got a plant and it is dumping pollen
just pollen is coming out of this plant
over here we've got a row of female
plants uh they're ripe for pollination
they've got their pistols are up in the
air they're horny their legs are up
they're looking to party they're like
dude let's get it uh let me move this
one dreadlock out of the way it's
driving me nuts there we go that was
starting to hurt pressed against my ear
anyway so we got a bunch of ladies over
here they're ready to party this dude's
over here he's ready to ski what we've
done basically essentially this is not
really what we did again this is an
analogy uh what we have learned to do is
put up a screen in the middle and put a
vacuum up top and suck out all of the
pollen that is male pollen we are only
putting female pollen on this side of
the room so what we're able to do is all
the plants on this side of the room will
be females now that's the only
difference after that pollination after
that female pollination happens there's
no difference they are just like every
other plant many people like to uh talk
like there's a a weakness to these
plants they have less Vigor they have
less potency something will be wrong
with them they're more prone to
intersect if the proper work was done
before the breeding project was started
those feminized plants have the
potential to be everything and possibly
more than those regular Plants could be
now what I wanted to get to is I want to
talk about breeding with these plants
I've been rambling for a minute the
point is yes you absolutely can breed
with those plants there's no difference
other than that pollination was SE the
male pollen was basically sucked out
again that's not how it works and again
uh thanks Mr soul for the great analogy
but the only difference was that pollen
after that everything is the same we
have got plants uh if you grew a
population so I breed male and female I
breed male female breeding plants and
feminized plants if you bought or I gave
you a bunch of packs of both of them and
we put all the fem seeds on one side and
all the reg seeds on the other and grew
them uh Once you pull out all the male
plants and put the plants in a
population together you're not going to
notice any difference other than the
strains you're going to be able to tell
phenotypes apart but there won't be any
difference in Vigor there won't be any
difference in pest pest or pathogen
resistance these plants are going to be
just as good as the regular plants if
not better so uh there's no big
difference I want to talk about now
about strains that I have bred from
feminized plants and I'm trying to think
of other things that I've done while I'm
talking about this but I know that
morning dew let's talk about Morning Dew
U morning de is a Grateful Dog female
which came from feminized seeds and then
I pollinated that with the arise that
makes morning de you guys love morning
dew plants Morning Dew makes amazing
plants I love it you guys love it um
highle breeders Growers and smokers
enjoyed the morning de I think it's
mostly sold out now but morning do was
made from a feminized female and a
regular male plant so that that's
something that this viewer this listener
was exactly asking about I took that
pollen put it on what was a feminized
female and that made amazing seeds now a
lot of people ask Will that give me uh
more a ratio of male to female seeds
after I do that no they come out about
50/50 still uh that's been a question
that a lot of people have asked it does
not make a difference another cross we
could talk about is the Lemon Sunrise
the lemon Sunrise was the lemon Jeffrey
female that's a lemon Jeffrey that's a
lemon skunk and a Golden Goat two female
plants bred together to make a feminized
lemon Jeffrey I took my selection out of
there my favorite lemon Jeffrey cut
pollinated that one with the arise and
that one made the lemon Sunrise which
were amazing freaking plants uh very
similar to the um the Cascade and the
Firefly and if you grew them all side by
side you could see the differences and
the commonalities but you would never
know that some of those were feminized
and some were not from femini seeds so
the overall answer here is uh absolutely
breed with those yes that is possible uh
the short answer is there's no big
difference uh in that female plant than
there was with a female selected from a
male female breeding population my
friend Lawrence thank you for the great
question I'm not sure where you are I
could tell that uh this was translated
I'm not uh being disrespectful in any
way but if we can ship seeds to where
you are I look forward to getting you a
pack of IE genetics premium seeds my
friend Lawrence thank you for the great
message all right this next message came
from the iy genetics website also this
one came from our friend grumpy toad
shout out to grumpy toad don't be so
grumpy bro it can't be that hard being a
toad maybe it can I don't know the
question goes like this it says yo Rasta
Jeff yo what up grumpy toad it says
thank you for being a legitimate source
of grow knowledge I think I speak for
all of the community when I say that bro
thank you uh I appreciate that to be
called legitimate I've been legitimized
now that's like getting a little blue
stamp on Twitter so thank you bro I am
legitimate I appreciate it uh I try not
to say nonsense I try not to talk
[ __ ] on the show I understand that
what I say is going into a microphone
and out to the internet and people are
going to um apply the techniques I
recommend and buy the products I suggest
so I try to be mindful of those things
when I'm talking on here so thank you I
appreciate it that's what I'm trying to
say let me learn how to take a damn
compliment uh my friend has a question
it says I have a question here related
to breeding those are my favorite uh
also the audience really loves the
breeding questions it says when I see a
strain called a and it is a cross
between B and C so we've got strain a
which is a cross of plant B and plant C
that makes sense to me is there any
convention that says which of the
parents are the male what I mean is does
the male come first and the female
second peace from your friend grumpy
Toad and then there's a little note here
to myself that I'm going to keep private
but yes grumpy toad I'm glad that you
were asking this question because I see
a lot of um new breeders and I see
breeders on social media messing this up
and uh a lot of consumers know the basic
rule of this and I feel like if a
breeder got this wrong on a package it
would deter me from purchasing those
seeds so let's uh talk about the
standard here and let me touch back on
what you were asking so that I can make
this super clear for everybody when you
buy a pack of seeds let's just say
you're going to buy a pack of seeds from
me we're going to say that you're going
to get a rise just we're going to pick a
rise as a random pack of seeds a rise is
a Golden Goat female pollinated by a
daybreaker male so I would put Golden
Goat X daybreaker the reason I list it
that way and this will be easy to follow
once you figure it out ladies first I
always list ladies first when I'm
listing the cross the female plant will
be so maybe now that we're talking about
feminized seeds in this episode I will
say the plant that received the pollen
will be the lady plant females first the
pollen donor will be listed second so if
you've got the two parentheses you see
Golden Goat X daybreaker that would
indicate to me right away daybreaker was
the pollen donor Golden Goat was the
girl that received the pollen so in
general Horticultural practices uh let's
try to teach everybody this in the
Cannabis cultivation world but ladies
first when listing genetics now there's
another step we can go with this um I've
got acoss that um it is three different
plants together but it was basically
these two plants over here in
parenthesis that was one really good
plant that just never got a name and
then there's another plant that got bred
to that so when I list the genetics it
is plant a cross to plant B and C in
parentheses now what that indicates to
me we're always going to do female first
so that plant a on this side is the
female in that equation and these two in
parentheses were bred together to make
one plant and then that one plant is the
pollen donor that pollinated that female
I hope that makes sense I'm going to try
to do it again the mathematical equation
that we would be looking at would be um
plant a times and then in parentheses b
x c So it's b cross 2 C just to be clear
on that one so plant a would be the
female because it's the first one in the
equation and then it was cross to these
two plants which made one plant I just
don't have a name for it it is B and C
in that equation B would be the female
pollinated by C that made a new plant
and they we're going to pollinate a with
that I hope that makes sense ladies
first even if you're having multiple
sets of brackets the lady will always
come first in that equation if you have
questions if I didn't make that clear uh
let me know in the comments or send me a
message we'll talk about it I'll do a
follow-up episode because without
drawing that out like a mathematical
equation on a chalkboard it kind of
doesn't make sense so um my buddy grumpy
toad I hope I answered this for you
because I really got rambling on that
one ladies first um lady times male and
then sometimes you'll see so if I had
two plants that didn't have a name um
just plant so we'll say Golden Goat to
daybreaker didn't get a name uh that was
not a rise we'll just say Golden Goat to
daybreaker in parenthesis and then we'll
say uh Platinum Tangi to Golden Goat
over here on the other side um we know
which is the male and female in both of
these and then if I cross those together
I just put an X in the middle and show
you the bunch of [ __ ] on the left side
is going to be the the female part the
bunch of [ __ ] on the right side is going
to be the male part all right I've got
to rambling on this uh my buddy grumpy
toad I owe you a pack of free seeds so
make sure you check your email because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from iy direct.com all right
ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
pimps and hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I want to thank
you once again for listening to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast if you have made it this far I
have got a gift for you when you go to
IR
redirect.sh use coupon code love and you
will save 10% off your entire order uh
there will be fresh stuff on there very
soon stay tuned um I'm a little bit
behind on orders I got a lot of orders
on the birthday sale as soon as I get
every order caught up and sent out then
I will restock the lemon Jeffrey Golden
Goat and orange
gasm make sure you join the newsletter
on IR genetics.com scroll to the bottom
put your email address in there when I
restock the orange GM the lemon Jeffrey
the Golden Goat and also the big
mountain fudge cake femin seeds and
there will also be new testers coming up
when I restock all of that if you sign
up to the newsletter you will get a
notification you will know when all of
that stuff is coming so and also that
coupon code love will be valid when the
new stuff drops so stay tuned IR
redirect.sh sletter then you get all of
the notifications the restock is coming
also I gave away free seeds on this
episode if I did not read your question
on today's episode please do not feel
discouraged keep sending me the
questions if I read your I've got a
stack of questions here if I read your
message on a future episode I will still
send you the free seeds all right let me
make sure I've covered everything that
is it that's all I've got for you for
this episode you know I'll be back in a
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big huge shout out to my friend
at the Chicken Shack and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]