[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 833 of the
grow from your heart podcast you know
I've got another fun episode lined up
for us in today's show I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in the
episode speaking of free seeds I do want
to remind you that anybody who shows up
to the dude grows cup wearing an iy
genetics or iy Army t-shirt will receive
a free gift so make sure you stop by the
booth show me that iy Army merch that iy
army gear and I will hook you up with a
free gift even if you're not wearing
merch if you're not wearing the gear I
invite you to stop by the booth and say
hello give me a high five give me a fist
bump give me a hug if that's what you're
into come introduce yourself say hello
at the dude grow cup that's right the
dude grow cup is happening again this
year in leaport Colorado on June 1st uh
the dude grow crew will be there team iy
genetics will be there the iy Army will
be there and I invite you to join us at
the dude Groves Cup in leaport Colorado
on June 1st for all of that information
check out dgc cup.com that will get you
all the links and details you need for
the dude grow cup if you want to show up
to the dude grow cup wearing iy genetics
merch and get that free gift all you
have to do is go to my website iry
genetics.com on the top there's a row of
tabs one of those tabs says merch click
on that merch tab grab some merch if you
order it now it will be delivered on
time for the dude grow cup and you can
rock that gear at the dude grow cup and
get yourself a free prize all right I
feel like we're making a lot of great
progress in this episode I do also want
to remind you that I have restocked iy
Direct that's right my other website IR
redirect.sh at the time of this
recording I also restocked the big
mountain fudge cake fem seeds but they
are moving very quickly so make sure you
hit I direct.com for orange GM lemon
Jeffrey and Golden Goat feminized seeds
all right we've gotten all the business
covered here at the start of the show
now let's work our way into the pet
peeve section of today's podcast that's
right sometimes when I go to a
commercial grow maybe sometimes I'll go
to a friend's grow or perhaps I'll just
be scrolling online sometimes I see
something in a grow room or in a grow
environment that simply drives me crazy
sometimes it even almost hurts my
feelings and makes me sad for the plants
I can see just by looking just by taking
a quick visual look that there are
simple things that we could do to
improve this grow in many ways small
details could give you better potency
better Harvest weight and just make the
grow overall more enjoyable for the
grower sometimes that stuff drives me
crazy I do encourage you the listeners
and the viewers to send me your growroom
pet peeves you can reach out and send
them to me at grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com if I read your growroom pet
peeve here on the podcast I will send
you a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds on idirect tocom today's first pet
peeve came from somebody who calls
themselves local C and it says my pet
peeve is when a grower thinks plant
problems like deficiencies will be fixed
the day that they are addressed and
watered uh it can take a few days or
more to see a repair and calmag is not
always the answer that is absolutely
correct sometimes I'll see people post
hey I've got a problem this is what is
wrong with my plants help me now let's
say hypothetically that somebody posts a
photo of a plant with an obvious
nitrogen deficiency I would identify
that nitrogen deficiency I would explain
to them why I think it's nitrogen I
would say that plant is way yellow it's
not as green as it could be that's
usually a sign of nitrogen deficiency
then I would recommend a couple of ways
to correct that nitrogen problem most of
the time my first recommendation to
correct a nitrogen deficiency would be a
fol your feed I would say grab your
bottle of Base nutrients that's a
nitrogen based nutrient bottle right
there Shake It Up mix up a full of your
feed apply that to the plants nitrogen
is a mobile element so the plants are
going to receive that and they will move
it around as it needs to be that
nitrogen nitrogen will get distributed
throughout that plant as needed that
will solve your nitrogen deficiency the
other thing I would recommend is to mix
up a feed solution with that base
nutrient which is heavily nitrogen based
then water that into the plants as
normal now most people are probably
going to do one maybe two of those
things though a lot of people are going
to overdo both of those things but
that's not the point here the thing is
they're going to do that and then
they're going to look at the plants and
they're going to say they're still
yellow yes those plants are still yellow
they're not going to Green up right away
it's going to take a little bit of time
for the plants to metabolize the
nutrients you just gave them for them to
move that around to make that nutrient
mobile I can't remember the word of
moving mobile nutrients there's a
specific word for that they've got to
move those nutrients around where they
need to be and then over a course of
time you will see Improvement on those
plants but yes this viewer this listener
is absolutely correct that many times
when I make recommendations to people I
go say go spray that plant go fure feed
that plant with a nitrogen product
they'll go spray it and they'll say
still green dude and I go well yeah the
nutrients take a little bit of time to
work you're going to need a day cycle
for that metabolism to happen a night
cycle for corrections to be made maybe
another day or two for things to balance
themselves out it may take a day two
three maybe four or 5 days to see any
results when you were doing any sort of
correction that goes to any kind of feed
uh when you feed a plant uh unless
you're in cocoa or Hydro cocoa and hydro
do show you quite quickly but if you're
in a soilless mix or a soilless
situation you mix up a bottle of
nutrient you feed that plant most of the
time it's going to take two three maybe
four or five days to actually see
results of that feed a lot of processes
have to happen unless you went extreme
if you weigh overfed if you put
something in there that's way too hot
you might notice notice it the next day
if your nutrient if your pH is way off
you might notice that quite quickly but
most of the time it's going to take you
2 3 4 maybe even 5 days to identify
what's going on with that plant so be
patient when you're making Corrections
on if it's a deficiency or an over feed
be very patient waiting for changes to
happen you could just cause more
problems by being impatient trying to do
too much so identify that problem uh
find a solution create the solution uh
execute that solution then sit back and
let it work uh go smoke a joint go walk
the dog leave those plants alone for a
day or two pay attention but don't do
more [ __ ] to them just let them heal I
see a lot of people cause more harm than
good by doing too much so yes that is a
good uh a good pet peeve thinking that
those problems are going to uh be solved
just by one quick foler application it
will work but it may take a little bit
of time for those nutrients to move
around or whatever the case may be be
patient there was more to this it says
it can take a few days or more oh and
cowm mag is not always the answer
absolutely anytime I'm on social media
on somebody's got a plant problem the
first answer is always calmag bro that's
not always the answer unfortunately a
lot of times it is the answer but it is
not always the answer all right my buddy
local C thank you for the great pet
peeve thank you for the great content
you really got me rambling with this one
this message was sent to me via YouTube
was as a YouTube comment so I do not
have your email address most of the time
I just cut and paste the email addresses
uh from the messages to send you your
free uh coupon code for free seeds my
friend local cook please do reach out so
that I can get you a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds off of iy direct.com
all right let's keep the momentum going
and segue into the growel portion of
today's podcast I've been talking about
my website iy genetics.com on that
website there is a list of tabs up on
the top one of those tabs does say grow
help click on that tab we will ask you a
few preliminary questions and then we
give you the opportunity to send a grow
question if you send me a good grow
question and I read that question here
on the podcast I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds off of
idirect decom today's question came from
our friend Ty what up Ty thank you for
the great content the question goes like
this it says yo Rasta Jeff wagan I hope
all is well big up Bren I hope
everything iy in your part of the world
uh things are good over here I'm doing a
podcast and I'm stoned as [ __ ] so I have
nothing to complain about big fist bump
the question says been watching and
listening to the podcast for a little
over 3 years now you have a good Soul
bro thank you for noticing that I do
appreciate it it says you drop knowledge
for free and you put TLC into it uh both
of those are true so thank you it said
thank you I appreciate what you do boss
now for the question I was fortunate
enough to purchase some of the '90s
skunk testers congratulations bro those
were quite limited then it says I was
wondering if it was cool to sell or give
a clone away being that those are
testers now most of the time when it
comes to my plants my seeds my Creations
genetics in general I have no problem
with people cutting clones and sharing
those clones however what you have got
are tester seeds it would be and this
goes for almost any seed that you're
going to grow let me kind of back up if
you're going to give a clone away the
person receiving that clone expects you
to have ran that plant and tested it and
verified that is worth their time and
energy growing in that Garden that's why
people want clones because they want
something that they know is tried and
true uh they know it's female they know
it's not interx they know it doesn't
have any issues then they know it's
going to grow well in the garden it's
going to flower in a reasonable time
it's going to have a desirable Aroma and
flavor and then it's going to be
desirable in the end it's going to be
desirable to smoke and consume or make
concentrates or edibles however you're
going to use this um the person giving
out the Clone is kind of responsible the
person receiving the Clone is trusting
that Giver to be responsible for vetting
clone you've got if you've got the fem
you've got six seeds don't give them a
clone until you've ran all of six of
those seeds and you've identified the
winner out of that pack that is your as
a grower as a grow Community member as a
a Ganja Farmer that is your
responsibility that's your due diligence
to run those seeds uh if and I this
stands for testers uh any seeds that
you're working with it is your
responsibility to run those before you
give out a clone because the person
getting that clone like I said is
trusting you and relying on you that
that clone is like I said going to
flower in a reasonable time it's going
to have a good aroma and flavor and it's
going to be potent and it's not going to
have any problems but keep an eye on
these plants and don't pass along any
problematic plants to your friends and
that goes for any seed the any seed
could be problematic any seed could also
be a gem but any seed that you are
running make sure you run that before
you pass out a clone to your friends and
I don't just say this with tester seeds
I don't just say this because this is my
new creation I don't I'm not trying to
hoard this or do any gatekeeping I don't
want you to give your friend a
problematic plant before you've even ran
it run it grow it grow it a couple of
times uh maybe you don't want to give it
to him because it's not worth giving to
them maybe it'll give them problems or
just maybe just maybe it's so freaking
amazing that you want it all for
yourself and you don't even want to
share it and if you give it to them now
and you haven't even finished it maybe
you're giving out something that's going
to set you apart from the market that
may have helped you out in the future I
try not to uh what is it called
encourage gatekeeping here but that is a
thing that may happen sometimes I don't
give away my favorite plants cuz they're
my favorite plants that's what separates
me as a grower as a breeder I've got
this plant that's what makes us stand
out so run all those seeds find what you
enjoy find what you like and then once
you know that those plants are good
there's no problems then consider giving
a clone and yes I know uh when people
see that word skunk they're going to
want a clone already but uh do them the
favor and run it first do the feno hunt
for them um maybe just maybe involve
them in your selection when it comes
time so you're going to grow the six
seeds right uh probably one of them will
get cold early on you'll run five of
them uh one of them is not going to be
the top one that you want you got four
to choose from bring your friend over
when you do the pheno uh selection when
you're smoking these when you're doing
the smoke test and the sampling bring
your buddy over maybe you like clone
number one and your buddy likes clone
number two the best you can easily give
him that clone or that mother plant and
then you both have the skunk that you
desire and you can both grow that uh you
can have your differences and your
similarities but I'm rambling and the
point here is um not just with test
seeds but with any seeds don't give out
clones until you fully ran that plant
and vetted it like I said a moment ago
as the Clone Giver people are trusting
you that is a lot of trust they're
trusting that you have ran this plant
you verified that it's a female there
are no interx traits uh it flowers in a
reasonable time it's going to give you a
desirable Aroma and flavor and a nice
buzz and anything that is required for
your needs I don't know if you're
growing for concentrates Edibles
topicals whatever but does it fit the
bill they're trusting you and also so
they're trusting you to give them a
clone that does not have problems no
bugs uh no pathogens definitely no hop
late and vroid definitely no russet
mites they're relying on you to give
them that clean clone so make sure you
provide all of those Services hit all of
those markers as somebody giving out a
clone and the person receiving the Clone
also it is also your responsibility to
treat that clone as if it has got every
problem on the planet when you get that
clone treat it treat it multiple times
times try to give it some isolation some
quarantine away from population that way
if it does have spider mites russet
mites thrips fungus snats whatever put
it put that clone in another area and
then keep an eye on it daily and treat
it and see if you see any bugs on it
once you know that it's clean then you
can put it in the general population
with the rest of your plants but that is
your responsibility as the Clone
receiver um I trust all my Bros I want
to believe in all my friends but if
anybody gives me a clone if my Mama gave
me a clone I would still treat that
clone like it's got thrips pites fungus
snats hlate and vroid and powdery mildew
all over it I would leave it in honestly
it would sit right here on this table
for a couple of days is where the new
clones come uh I mix up a spray solution
I spray the [ __ ] out of them and they
sit right here they don't go into the
grow space for several days and I look
at them I pay a lot of attention to them
uh just quarantine isolate uh that way
if there is a problem I can identify it
and get rid of that clone or I can treat
it until that problem's gone then put it
in with the rest but any clone that
comes in like I said if it's my mom if
it's Mike if it's my best friend if it's
from uh any dispensary every clone that
comes in I am very suspect of that clone
I don't care who you are it's my
responsibility and my fault if something
goes wrong so uh my buddy Ty that was a
long ramble my dude uh make sure you
check your inbox I've got your email
address here so that means that you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of iy
genetics premium seeds at iy direct.com
let me wrap this up and make sure that
we got everything here um I'm wondering
if it's cool to give away a clone um no
it's not cool to give away a clone yet
uh I did reply to my friend Ty I said
dude at least wait until I release that
strain before you start giving out
clones that would be polite but like
I've said in the past those are yours
and you can honestly do whatever you
want with them you paid for them I can't
sell you a car until you not to drive
fast that doesn't seem right but run
them grow them be a good friend be a
good grower a good cannabis community
community member then share those cuts
all right let's keep the party going I
do have another great question here
right in front of me this one also came
from the growel tab on edirect decom
this one came from a friend who wants to
be called 420 Lane big shout out to 420
Lane it's a general grow question that
says yo Rasta Jeff so I've been popping
beans now for a while but for some
reason I did not get a cut of this
particular phenotype I'm going to stop
myself right there I always preach to
cut a clone any time you're grown from
seed or you get a clone from your buddy
or you're growing something new when you
run it take a clone from it because you
never know that could be the most
amazing plant that you have ever grown
and like our friend here they're
realizing 7 and 1/2 weeks in this plant
is going to be a boss and now they don't
have a clone of it and they're already
starting to get heartbroken it's only
seven and a half weeks in we'll read
more uh but they don't have a clone they
already are regretting not getting a
clone so I always say take a clone if
you didn't there's another option we
will talk about it right now it says
she's now seven and a half weeks into
flower if I take a cut from this plant
will it root yes the answer is
absolutely yes it will root uh I would
take a clone somewhere near the bottom
just take a nice clone like you normally
would uh clip it dip it stick it clean
it up quite a bit at the top so there's
not a whole bunch of extra foliage up
there and that clone will root my
recommendation is to put that clone in a
turbo cloner an easy cloner an autoc
cloner some sort of aeroponic cloner um
I've noticed they root much more quickly
in that style and also they seem to
reveg more quickly in the easy cloner
recently I was experimenting with some
plants I had a plant I did something
similar but I did um enough plants to
where I didn't have room to take as many
clones as I was running plants my theory
was just that I was going to reveg so
what I did was um I grew a plant I
flowered it um I finished it I harvested
it I left two buds on the bottom or two
branches on the bottom right um I wanted
to rev this plant I cut one of those
branches off and put it in the easy
cloner and I left that other Branch just
sticking off the pot just like it was
guess which one of those plants reved
way more quickly the plant in the easy
cloner was Stronger Faster more robust
and it reved way more quickly so I would
recommend taking a cut and putting it in
an easy cloner if that is possible and
that plant will root and rev very
quickly in that easy cloner if you give
it 24 hours of light I understand that
may not be possible 186 will work 24
hours of light would really speed up
your uh reveg process so take that clone
put it in that easy cloner if possible
put that under 24 hours of light in that
easy cloner it will will rev quite
quickly for you now I keep saying the
word rev if you're not able to get that
clone you can always rev that flowering
plant that you're working with the way
that I recommend doing it is when you're
going to harvest there'll be um a couple
of buds at the bottom just cut off most
of the plant leave three maybe five
thumb siiz buds at the bottom I got big
thumbs they don't even have to be this
big big but leave some thumbs with
foliage on them you want some leaves and
stuff on those plants cuz that is what's
going to receive the Sun or the light
and that's what's going to tell that
plant to begin the Rev process so chop
the plant down leave three to five
little tiny bottom buds at the bottom of
the plant and rev those those should rev
quite quickly for you another tip that
you can do and I get a lot of
controversy when I talk about this
before you harvest about 7 to 10 days
before Harvest you can put your lights
back on an 18 hours on and 6 hours off
light cycle I know that sounds wild to
some people but what that's going to do
is going to give your plants more Photon
energy photons are the number one source
of energy for our plant if you do that
the last 7 to 10 days of the flowering
period you will bulk up your plants they
will get beefier they will get more
dense and they may even finish a day or
two sooner now also what that is going
to do that is going to speed up your
reveg process people are going to say
Rasta Jeff if I put my plants on 186 in
flower they will rev yes eventually they
will rev you're going to cut them down
before that but you're going to leave a
couple buds on the bottom that have now
gotten a huge head start on the reveg
process they will begin revegging much
sooner than a plant that did not have
186 at the end of flower that reveg
process um the buds are going to look
like [ __ ] for a little while uh nothing
will happen for a few days you'll put it
into the 186 you'll feed it give it some
nitrogen it's not going to do anything
after about 2 weeks you'll see coming
out of the top of the buds just little
shoots coming out little leaves coming
out of the top of the buds then those
will start growing longer then they'll
make Leaves they'll make curly Twisted
World leaves then eventually they'll
start making perfect little clones that
look just like little plants coming out
of there I recommend cloning those
little shoots and using those clones as
your new mother plant don't use that
revegged one it's been through a little
bit of stress get those clones start
fresh with those clones that is your new
mother plant so the quick answer the
question was can I take a clone at week
7.5 yes you absolutely can uh the
quickest way to do that it will reveg
more quickly in the easy cloner and then
uh if that does not work for you just
simply reveg the entire plant this is
why I do recommend taking clones from
everything because you never know you
may have the next uh chem 91 you could
have the next Gorilla Glue you could
have the next arise uh you could have
the next Girl Scout cookies you never
know what you might be growing so always
take those clones all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I'm sure you can hear my voice is
burning out and getting dry it is time
to wrap up this episode of The Grow from
your heart podcast I do want to thank
you once again for hanging out for
another episode make sure you hit the
website I genetics.com there's a link to
the Discord server you can join us on
Discord there's a link to the iir where
you can grab the beans there's a link to
the merch store where you can get the
new merchandise and there is a link to
the patreon where you can support the
podcast everything you could possibly
need is at I genetics.com if you have
made it this far in today's episode make
sure you use coupon code love at iir to
save yourself 10% that is all I've got
for this episode I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to my buddy 804 Green
Ranger and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad [ __ ]