[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 834 of the
grow from your heart podcast I've got a
great episode lined up for us in today's
show I'm going to give away free seeds
hang out we'll talk more about those
free seeds later on in the episode I do
want to remind you once again about the
dude grows Growers cup that's right June
1st in leaport Colorado the dude grow
crew is throwing the dude grow Growers
Cup come hang out the dude grow crew
will be there the iy Army will be there
team iy genetics will be there I invite
you to join us at the dude grows Growers
cup make sure you check dgc cup.com for
all of the information and another
reminder anybody that shows up at the
dude grows Growers Cup on June 1st
wearing any iy genetics or iy Army
merchandise will receive a free gift
that's right if you've got iy gear on
show up to my booth come say hi come
introduce yourself show me your gear and
I will give you a free gift also even if
you're not wearing merch or gear show up
come say hi uh introduce yourself give
me a high five a fist bump a handshake a
hug whatever you're into stop by the
booth and introduce yourself I'm all
about meeting new friends saying hi to
Old Friends uh show up at the dude grow
cup and do not be shy you don't have to
buy anything you don't have to be
wearing gear you can come simply for a
fist bump a high five you can come smell
the weed we've got on the table that
doesn't cost anything show up to the
dude grows Growers cup and say hello
introduce yourself I don't want to get
on social media later and hear people
talk about I saw you with the booth it
looked like you were busy bro I was busy
but I'm never too busy to make new
friends at the dude grows cup so stop by
the booth also you may be asking how can
I get those t-shirts so that I can get
that free gift at the dude grow cup at
the iy genetics Booth those t-shirts
they are very easy to acquire go to my
website iy genetics.com I it's a
Jamaican word it means to feel super
blessed powerful and positive feeling IE
so it's IR genetics.com that is the
website there's a tab on that website
that says merch if you click on that
merch guess what you'll find merch broh
there'll be t-shirt there will be uh
hats there will be uh rolling trays if
there's still any left there's a lot of
good merch there at the iy genetics
merch uh tab go check out the merch get
a shirt wear to the dude grows Growers
cup and guess what free seats bro all
right I feel like I've covered most of
the business now I do have one brand new
important announcement to make that's
right we are approaching the month of
April uh this episode will come out just
before the start of April that means
that it is time for the April sale on iy
direct.com
that's right there's also a link to iir
on IR genetics.com they'll both get you
to the seeds if you're looking just
click around poke around you will get
there but edirect decom is the website
for the beans we are going to start I am
going to start that 420 sale on April
1st so make sure you hit edirect decom
go see the new sale pricing I'm going to
add a few new things as well there will
be a few new five packs on there some
things will only be available in five
packs I've seen that some of the five
packs are more desirable for some of you
so some things will be available in five
packs and there will be brand new items
what will there be rosta Jeff what there
will be some new stuff something called
April O'Neal what what is April O'Neal
that is Indiana bubblegum to blueberry
cookies oh yeah then what is the other
brand new one that is the Baxter
Stockman Baxter Stockman is the grape
candy to the blueberry cookies uh two
amazing new strains those are a
continuation of a series that I did a
while back so the collectors will be
after those will be a limited number of
those available on the website I will
reserve a few packs a very limited
number of packs for the dude grow cup
but these will drop uh April 1st on the
website pay attention uh patreon members
will get a newsletter about it uh the
folks on the newsletter we'll get
another newsletter about it I will
advertise on social media these seeds
will go quickly so pay attention for
April O'Neal and Baxter Stockman to drop
April 1st on I direct.com as part of the
420 sale all right I've been rambling
for a long time I feel like we've
covered a lot of business here at the
top of today's podcast we are going to
skip the pet peeve section because I
want to make sure to cover a few grow
questions in today's episode earlier I
mentioned my website IR genetics.com at
the top of that website there is a tab
that says grow help if you click on that
grow help tab that gives you the
opportunity to tell us a few things
about your grow we ask questions like
what strain are you growing are you
growing indoors or Outdoors are you
using HPS or metal highlight light we
ask a few basic questions to give me an
idea of how to answer the question that
you're going to ask then at the bottom
we give you plenty of opportunity to
type in great detail about the issue
that is happening in your grow room if
you send a question to that growel Tab
and I do read your question here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds off of edirect
decom today's first question came from a
person who wants to be called D Rod guy
I think that's how you say that that's
how I'm going to say it uh we're just
going to call you D for now so I don't
so I don't have to keep saying your name
wrong big shout out to my new friend D
D's question goes a little bit like this
it says yo Rasta Jeff I love your
content well that's a great way to start
off and email my dude thank you for the
compliment I love the support so it goes
both ways thank you bro it says I am
living here in prohibition land and I
have to grow covertly yes you be very
careful out there in prohibition Landon
the person that wrote this is a
hypothetical character does not really
exist I don't even exist my name is not
rosta Jeff so this is all fictional uh
this is just hypothetical it goes on it
says uh maybe possibly hypothetically I
currently am growing in a small portion
of a closet so I have used one and two
gallon pots that makes sense you got the
small space so you'd run smaller pots
that's a good logical decision there
then here is where we come to a great
question it says by limiting the size of
the plant am I also limiting the potency
I must say that the flower I've gotten
so far has been pretty good but not
great do I have to let her grow to her
full potential uh that's a really good
question so if you're running in a small
space you've got small pots you're going
to grow smaller plants are those plants
going to reach their full potential um
or are you limiting yourself on potency
was the main part of the question here I
really don't think so I think that as
long as you let that plant finish its
full flowering cycle uh those hormones
and that triome development is what you
are going for so I really don't think
you are uh limiting yourself by running
small plants honestly I don't think so
my first question though is are you
running from seed or are you going from
clones uh that may make a difference
those clones are technically the age of
whichever plant they were cut from so I
know that that blows some people's minds
when I say that let's think about that
for a minute you've got a mother plant
that is we'll say 3 months old right
it's this tall it's three months old
it's got some Bush to it you cut clones
from it those clones are the age of that
plant they're 3 months old when you cut
them so when 3 months that clone is
technically a six-month old plant in all
technicality I know that sounds wild so
uh perhaps those smaller plants even if
the hormones and the uh and everything
wasn't developed properly in your
smaller plants if you're running from a
clone it technically already is all
there it's the age of that original
plant like I've been talking about so if
you're running clones it definitely
shouldn't be an issue at all seeds as
long as you veg them up for a couple
weeks two or three weeks and then flip
it sounds like you got plenty of time to
do that uh they should uh be fully
developed and give you a great outcome
um as long as you let them flower long
enough that may be something that you're
missing and it sounds like you're also
kind of if you're running in a small
tight space like this you might be a new
grower don't expect that first crop to
be amazing and impressive that's that's
the one you learned on uh figure out
what you don't like about it figure out
how to improve on that and then work
from there and make it better next time
what's going on in the room how is the
VPD how's the circulation uh how is the
light quality the light quality is going
to have a lot to do with it you can't
put a really power light in that small
space but put as much light as you
possibly can in there the most efficient
the proper Spectrum get a good light in
there uh how's the air that's the VPD
basically uh how's your feeding what are
you feeding how often did you feed how
was the ph and the EC of each feeding
did you make every feeding and every
watering to that plant count was it all
strategery or was it just done kind of
willy-nilly that'll make a difference in
your next grow did you take a lot of
notes uh do you know what you did last
time so that you can look back and say
this seems to have worked this right
here was an experiment might have thrown
me off we can do that better maybe take
notes on uh future grows um my next
notes to myself are I run small plants a
lot when I'm doing new projects when I
so let's just say I just bred a bunch of
new seeds and I want to see what those
seeds have created I'll run a bunch of
tiny plants just so I could see what
they look like instead of growing them
big and tall and wasting time I'll run
them real small and I've come out with
really satisfactory uh results from just
little tiny plants uh there may have
only been just a couple of blunts or a
few fat joints or something to smoke out
of that excuse me for the throat
clearing by the way I'm just trying to
keep moving uh keep my train of thought
here uh there may have been little
plants to gave me just a few bong rips
or a couple of fat joints to smoke but
we definitely enjoyed uh every rip and
every puff of that and it was quality it
was potent it tasted good and I feel
like it did come to its uh full
potential even though it was a little
tiny plant um and those smaller plants
the advantage of those smaller plants of
course you've got to do small plants
you're in a small space but smaller
plants is less time for potential
problems uh just think about anything if
you're doing anything for less time
you've got less potential for things to
go long or to go wrong so if you're just
running vegging for three weeks a little
tiny plant while I'm over here vegging
for eight weeks I got five more weeks or
for spidermites to sneak in for powdery
mildew to pop up something like that to
happen you're you're harvested five
weeks ahead of me before I've even
thought of harvesting because I'm still
vegging so um yeah you're going to get
more crops per year with that short veg
time with small plants and you may run
into smaller problems the only thing it
sounds like you need to work on is
diagnose the problems which are not uh
which are making your cannabis not meet
your expectations and then improve from
there uh my friend D thank you for the
great question I do appreciate this make
sure you check your email because you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds on IR direct.com all right this
next question that popped up is a
breeding question this one came from
somebody that we are going to call NBC
you know who you are NBC uh make sure
you check your email because you've got
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from iir
the message goes hey rosta Jeff I love
your podcast specifically the ones that
feature breeding information well here
you here you go because you've got a
good breeding question and thank you for
listening to the show I do love your
support as well it says I have a
question about breeding specifically
since I know that you do this for a
living I figure you would be the best
person to ask uh bro I do do it for a
living but before that I do it for
sanity I do it out of passion I do it
because I am uh strongly compelled to do
so even if you's stopped buying the
seeds if nobody followed me on social
media if the world went blackout and
everybody disappeared and all I had was
a grow light and some seeds I would
still grow and breed this would all
still happen so I do do it for a living
but I also do it uh just out of
necessity uh or I might blow up if I
didn't breed and smoke a bunch of good
ganja and uh produce and create good
seeds I have something I might just
spontaneously combust anyway but thank
you for noticing and here we go it says
I'll start I will be starting a breeding
project very soon soon and I want to
know if it is better to have the male
grow directly next to the female and
create seeds the oldfashioned way or is
it just as viable to gather the pollen
store it and then pollinate the females
later on down the line have you noticed
to reduce seed numbers or lack of
viability from storing then pollinating
or is it same same all right this is a
very good question and I understand this
very strongly uh perfect timing equals
more seeds uh that's the first thing
that I wrote so the more uh the better
you time it the more seeds you will
produce and um I would recommend just
getting the pollen straight from the
plant onto the females because uh
Gathering it storing it that reduces
viability Maybe by a small percent but
why would you can just get it straight
from the plant onto the other plants
without storing it if that is possible
that's what I would recommend but it is
all about the timing as the main
ingredient here um let me get more in
detail about the timing um if you put
the boy and the girl in the room at the
same time just a mail plant and if
female plant and don't do anything they
will make seeds just the timing of
nature the timing of these plants uh one
may be a longer flower plant one may be
shorter but it will work out there will
be viable pistols when pollen is
available that will happen but sometimes
if you put certain plants in ahead of
time uh then put the male in or put the
male in and put the females in at
certain times then you will achieve much
higher seed production now the examples
that I always use in this situation uh
two plants that I breed with quite often
are the Platinum Tangi plant the
Platinum Tangi plant is the mom to the
sunkiss the mom to the orange gasm uh
the mom to uh the uh Tangi Ripper and
then on the other side we've got the
Strawberry Fields plant that is the mom
to Strawberry Starburst uh the red pill
uh what else have we done with that
there's a bunch of stuff that came from
that one anyway let's stay focused so
that sunkiss plant prefers to receive
pollen between days 21 and
26ish like I'm saying is I've done it
indoors Outdoors there's a window there
but that's about a week that 21 to 26
day window there is when that orange
gasm or the uh sunkiss plant the
Platinum Tangi wants that pollen the
most I know I said a bunch of different
strains and my brain skips when we think
about strains Platinum Tangi is a strain
so that Platinum Tangi wants the pollen
around day 21 to 26 but the Strawberry
Fields plant that one wants its pollen
around day 28 to day 35ish so if I put
the mail in the room and let everybody
go at the same time I will get a minimal
amount of seeds from both of them
however if I put that Strawberry Fields
plant in the room a week ahead get it
pollinating put that Platinum Tangi
plant in the room a week later get or
not pollinating get it growing get it
flowering get a bunch of pistols on it
then if I bring in that male when he's
already got a bunch of pollen on him and
Shake him that's what I'm going to get
the maximum amount of seeds the other
option of course is to collect that
pollen bring it and then shake that bag
of pollen but like I said a moment ago I
do I have I will store pollen but I get
better results from not storing it
because coming straight from the plant
you don't lose anything uh there's no uh
static electricity doesn't kill anything
the cold the change the environment
stresses uh nothing kills any of that
pollen it's still 100% viable as it
comes off of the plant so that's the way
I would recommend doing it another thing
I'm going to touch on I don't know if
this is even yeah it is I wrote this on
my notes I just thought of this while I
was rambling one thing I've noticed and
this may just be no I've noticed this
I've seen this this is not this may Bro
Science cuz I don't have a lab coat but
I've seen this when I've got a male
plant and a female plant in the same
area maybe not even in the same room but
a room apart from each other I feel like
the girl plants get a little bit
stickier they get a little bit more
pistols I don't know if that mail plant
is putting off some sort of pheromone or
if he's saying hey ladies I'm over here
and I'm going to get in that room and
just a few days and I'mma Let It Go but
I feel like all the ladies in the room
they're they're getting hornier they're
expressing that they want pollination
more they get more pistols the pistols
just get more robust they do it a bit
little bit more quickly and they seem
like they want that pollen it's like
they know and that may sound crazy to
some people but if I've got a male plant
on this side of the door and a female
plant on this side of the door those
girls get more pistols it's like they're
they're just smelling each other I don't
know if the male makes more pollen
that's a good I just thought of that one
I was like well does the opposite happen
I don't know I've never paid attention
to that I'm going to have to do that
experiment you guys I want feedback back
in the comments we are on YouTube We're
on Spotify we're all over the place go
to YouTube would be your best bet go to
YouTube leave me some comments right
down below let me know if you agree or
disagree that having plants of the
opposite sex in separate rooms but not
able to contact each other does that
make them hornier do the females get
stickier do the guys get more pollen do
they build bigger loads uh let me know
what you think in the comments argue
right down there my favorite comment
will win a prize so that should help out
a little bit um so the main question is
is it better to store the pollen and
then pollinate them later or to have the
male just dust them I prefer to do the
mail just dusting them uh that but
that's if you want the whole freaking
room pollinated also because that's
going to go crazy that pollen will fly
everywhere it will be a Dusty mess and
every uh every pistol in the room every
Brack in the room will be seated so be
careful if that's what you're doing if
you want to just dust a few branches uh
Dustin area then of course get that bag
of pollen get that vial get out your
Q-tip your paintbrush however you want
to do it then paint up a few branches
that way but uh the way that I do it um
I put that dude in another room I get
him flowering uh I flower out the girls
at their specific times in their room
then I drag the boy into the room give
him a good shake at the right time then
here's a free tip excuse me for clearing
the throat so much not even going to
edit this episode uh live to drive is
what we're calling it but after I do
that pollination I wait uh five seven
maybe 10 more days just keep an eye on
that dude uh and then you'll see that
there's more pollen it's building up
it's starting to to fall again at that
point give them a good shake or cut the
top off even and go smack the lights and
let that pollen rain down onto your
plants or even take tops that have male
flowers on it with pollen and just rub
them all over the girl plants maximum
pollination all right I feel like I have
answered this question and then some uh
NBC I've got your email address right
here in front of me yes I do so please
make sure you check your email address
uh By the time this episode comes out
you will have a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at iy
direct.com while I'm talking about those
coupon codes for those free seeds let me
throw out a little reminder a little
update something that I was thinking
about here that uh probably should have
gone at the start of the show but I
didn't write it down I just thought
about it these coupon codes they do come
with expiration dates somebody asked if
they have to use that uh that coupon
code by that expiration date yes um
unfortunately I can't make those coupon
codes last forever uh because they do
they're in my computer system it's it's
technical issues technically and uh
budgeting and finances and things like
that but anyway I cannot extend or
change the expiration dates of those
coupon codes once they are issued so yes
please do use those uh quickly before
they do expire and if you uh missed it
send me a message I will help you out
this is the last disclaimer for that the
last chance for that but there is an
expiration date and that is real I can't
change that can't fix it um I just can't
have free seeds floating forever I just
can't that's hard to do um
accountability accounting wise so
they've got to have a uh expiration date
all right that's enough rambling let's
move on I've got one more great question
here this one also came from the growel
tab at I genetics.com this one came from
our new friend Tom nice to meet you Tom
Tom is quick and to the point it says
when picking a breeding project should
you top your male plants uh it's an
early shower I'm just pollinating her
sisters uh it's an F2 now so by doing
this would it become an
F3 um so there's a couple things here to
talk about should you top your m plants
I don't top my males uh I like him just
to make that big giant donkey dick
pollen sack up there just all that
pollen on that one giant top that's what
I prefer I don't top the males um it's
an early shower you're pollinating its
sister so you're saying by saying sister
did that come from the same batch of
seeds like there was a boy it pollinated
a girl that girl made seeds you grew
those seeds one's a boy one's a girl uh
that would equal boy brother and sister
to me and you said those are f2s by
doing this does it become an F3 abs
absolutely yes it does you've been
listening you've been following along so
you my friend you win a free pack of
seeds off of I
redirect.sh part of the question is do I
top the male plants no I do not Top Male
plants that's not something I do um and
then uh pollinating sisters to make F3
you are absolutely correct all right
that was a quick one Tom thank you for
the great question my dude that gives us
time to move on to one more question
this one came from somebody that wants
to be called razy J Rie make make sure
you check that email for your free seeds
air.com
looks like Rousy is also an Aussie says
hey Jeff J here from Australia uh love
the podcast and have listened for a long
time anyhow I hope you are well big
shout out to all of our Australian uh
listeners and viewers I just happen to
be wearing a Natalie rise shirt uh
Natalie happens to also be from
Australia big shout out to miss rise uh
rise nation in full effect uh but big
shout out to the whole Australian Nation
all the Cannabis farmers and out there
um you guys you got to get that stuff
legalized get some medical or
recreational Cannabis going for the
Australian people out there uh there is
a white mic in Australia what I mean by
that is I'm the ganja grower I'm the the
spokesperson uh that comes and talks
about growing and smoking and I'll smoke
on camera and I'll do this part of it
White Mike is my U my partner in crime
my the other side of this uh industry
where he's the guy that will help with
city council and help write the rules
and address the politicians and he will
go speak in front of those people I'll
talk to The Growers he'll speak to
Babylon we need somebody in Australia
that wants to stand up and do the white
mic position um I love and respect all
you Growers out there they want to be
the grower guy somebody has got to stand
up and be um possibly the Martyr maybe
that's what you're going to make
yourself but somebody's got to stand up
and say hey Australia or wherever
something smaller and then work bigger
but say hey we need medical cannabis
here on our our nation we need that it
would help out a lot and speak up for it
um tell them how and why and show them
what it would look like uh teach them
that it's not a crime teach them that
we're not criminals teach them that we
smoke and we're peaceful and it actually
helps a lot of us in a medical way uh
teach them the business aspect of how
cannabis can be uh beneficial to the
entire nation to the entire Island um
anyway I I wish people in Australia
could have some legal cannabis and
anyway there's a person out there that's
listening that just needed that little
kick go do it bro go do it um what if
you were the person that could spark
legal cannabis in the whole nation of
Australia and get everybody smoking
wouldn't that be awesome all right
that's enough of a pep talk there is a
question it says story leading to a
question I like that that gives me some
clarity it says I had four plants in my
grow one of those intersects I already
know what you're going to say and
produced a small amount of flowers on
the lowers when I noticed I pulled it
out of the tent but the others got
pollinated and they are seated now here
comes the question my question is will
the seeds from the other plants have
interex issue or will there be some
feminized or regular seeds all right
this is a good common question this is
also one of my pet peeves so let's touch
on this one our friend is growing plants
one of those plants went intersects and
I love that you use the word intersects
on here that is the correct word um
thank you because the word her me is a
pet peeve Herm is cool her me bothers me
don't even know why bro so interx was
absolutely the correct word here this
plant through male and female parts
those male parts have now pollinated
other females in the room and the
question is what about these seeds are
they regular are they feminized are they
more Herms the answer is they are not
feminized seeds this is not how fem
seeds are made they will not be fem I
think about it this way we know that 50%
of that breeding project has intersex
traits in it we' have now bred it to
another plant that means that at least
50% of the breeding has got intersect
potential in that plant in that line of
seeds so they could be intersects they
could be good seeds they could grow some
amazing magic they could be awesome but
also they could be straight up
intersects or they could be weird
mutants but they are not feminized seeds
to be completely clear they are not
considered feminized what was done to
make them feminized to ensure that they
are female nothing and that's what we
call a feminize seed is a seed that has
been uh produced in a proper way that we
know and can guarantee that it's female
it's a long process there's work to it
that was not done so these are interex
bag seed that could be anything you can
grow these I recommend you grow them you
may find uh you may find the next hot
fire you could have the next chem dog
the next Girl Scout cookies in there or
you could have a bunch of interex trash
in there uh grow them see what you've
got don't give them away don't sell them
don't share them uh just grow them
yourself in your space and see what
you've done so um yeah that's the short
answer and that is also uh the long
answer my buddy Razzy J make sure you
check your email cuz you've got a coupon
code for a free pack pack of seeds at
air.com all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls if I did not read your
question here on today's episode please
do not feel discouraged I've got a
mountain of emails uh it is 3 feet tall
over here no I'm just exaggerating
that's the paper rack but there's a
bunch of email over here to be gone
through to get answered on the podcast
so if I didn't get to your message today
please do not feel discouraged you may
win free seeds on the next episode also
keep those grow questions coming go to
the website IR genetics.com there's that
growel tab send me your questions if I
read your question here on the show you
will win a coupon code for free seeds
everything else you could possibly need
is also on that website there's a link
to I redirect to get seeds there's a
link to the patreon so you can support
the podcast uh patreon contributors do
get free seeds make sure you check on
patreon for all of that information
there's also a link to the merge tab you
can get a t-shirt you can get a hat uh
you can get a rolling tray if you wear
your hat or your T-shirt to the dude
grows cup guess what free gift come by
and say hi make sure you tune in next
week for fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Kurt Z
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]