[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] yeah welcome back podcast
world I'm your host rosta Jeff this is
episode
835 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got another fun episode lined up
for us in today's episode we're going to
give away free seeds hang out we'll talk
more about those free seeds later on in
the show I do want to invite you once
again to the dude grows grower cup
that's right June 1st in Fort Collins
Colorado the dude grows crew is throwing
the dude grow grow cup of course the
dude grows crew will be there I will be
there the iy Army will be there we all
invite you to come join us at the dude
grows Growers cup make sure you check
dgc cup.com for all of the information
all right I also want to remind you that
the 420 sale has started at I direct.com
that's right make sure you check I
direct.com for current inventory and
pricing I did stock the April O'Neal
which is the blueberry it's the Indiana
bubblegum to blueberry cookies we also
stocked the Baxter Stockman which is
grape candy to the same uh blueberry
cookies we also added a new freebie
that's right the $100 level freebie is
now Cherry goat which is Cherry jelly
across to the Golden Goat so make sure
you check idirect decom for the new
drops and of course the 420 special
pricing all right I think that covers
all of the business part here at the
start of the show that we need to get
through let's jump into what is known as
the pet peeve section of today's podcast
sometimes when I walk into a grow space
it could be a friends grow it could be a
commercial grow sometimes it's just
something I see at the grow store maybe
it's something online something will
just drive me crazy and a grow that
becomes a pet peeve what are your
growroom pet peeves share them with me
send me an email at grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com with the word pet peeve in
the subject line if I read your pet
peeve here on the podcast that means
that you do win a prize that's a lot of
peas in a row uh but if I read that pet
peeve here on the podcast you do win a
free prize you will win a free pack of
seeds off of ir
redirect.sh seeing people run a
humidifier and a dehumidifier at the
same damn time it's funny that that's a
pet peeve of yours because honestly bro
I do that [ __ ] all the time I'm here in
Colorado where the temperature uh the
humidity level uh it changes drastically
over the next couple of days uh like two
days ago I was wearing a jacket it was
snowing I had my snowshoes on I was
wearing a beanie had a scarf I was out
in the cold uh super super cold now
today it was 75° out there I was out
there in joggers in a t-shirt just
loving the sunshine so here in Colorado
we get drastic drastic changes I can't
risk having those changes Outdoors
affect my indoor grow environment my dry
and cure spaces the way to do that is
put enough equipment in there to keep
those parameters the way you need them
to keep that environment how you need it
I often talk about running the
humidifier and dehumidifier at the same
time I'll set them both in a dry and
cure environment especially I will set
them both at 55% 55% humidity
55° um 55 degrees in the room 55%
humidity on the humidifier 55 on the
dehumidifier let all three of those
pieces just work it out together all day
long so we've got a humidifier a
dehumidifier and an air conditioner just
banging it out all day making sure the
environment stays the way that we need
it so um I understand it's a pet peeve
to some people but uh in Colorado man
I've got to do what I have got to do I
can't risk I getting too hot or too cold
I can't let it get too dry or too wet
and I do have that opportunity like I
said because of the major swings in my
environment here uh we had snow a couple
of days ago we have heat today I'm sure
that in just a couple of days because of
these changes we're going to get some
rain or some sort of moisture just how
the environment reacts here so then when
that moisture comes that rain comes my
humidity will spike in my dry and cure
room that dehumidifier will help me out
there um so yeah I do get it it drives
you crazy but that's what I've got to do
so sometimes uh those weird things that
you see there's actually a huge purpose
for that so my friend frog Slayer thank
you for the uh the great ramble you got
me going here on a good start on this
podcast I do appreciate that um big up
and give it a try bro maybe that
humidifier dehumidifier combo will give
you some Advantage especially in that
dry and cure area all right I want to
keep moving because this next message
has me excited and puts a smile on my
face this one came from the growel tab
on IR genetics.com if you go to my
website I genetics.com it is i i e just
in case I say it too Qui quickly or if I
mumbled through that or something iy i i
e that again is a Jamaican word uh it
means to feel it's a pwa word means to
feel uh the Most Blessed you could feel
the most powerful you could feel uh I
describe it is like um the first time I
ever remember feeling iy I was sitting
on a little Hill uh there was a dog next
to me the sun was setting there's a
little bit of wind coming from behind me
uh there was a tree next to me and for a
minute there everything just felt
[ __ ] beautiful just fine ah just it
was great the grass was kind of you know
when you sit in the grass it feel like
it's comfortable but the grass is uh
slightly cold and cool and it cools your
butt and it cools your feet so on a hot
day you sit in that cool grass in the
shade you got the sun on you just
watching the city everything everything
was iy bro I felt just blessed and at
peace and perfect that's what IE means
that's why my company is IE genetics uh
powerful and pleasing uh it just makes
you feel real good so anyway so I'm
rambling that's what iy means the
website is iy genetics.com i i e and
then of course the word genetics I hope
you can spell that one by now IR
genetics.com is the website at the top
of I genetics.com there's a list of tabs
one of those tabs does say grow help if
you click on that growel tab we give you
the opportunity to send me your grow
question once again if I read your grow
question here on this podcast you do
want a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds off of idirect decom so that is
where the seeds are handled so this one
came from my new friend Eric what's up
Eric it's good to meet you it starts off
with hey man hey man good meet you it
says much respect big respect back at
you as well then the message gets fun it
says I was listening to a podcast and
March 28th is your anniversary so it's
been 10 years now if my math is correct
you guys we just had the 10-year
anniversary of the grow from your heart
podcast and I did not even uh notice or
acknowledge that I had to have a
listener send me an email letting me
know that this podcast has been going
for 10 years years that is wild to me to
think that I've been doing the show for
10 years uh there were uh I think the
first 500 and something episodes were
Audio Only and then around 600 or 650 I
started putting out the video because of
the uh we were locked down and had that
crazy virus thingy that happened to all
of us uh but 10 years is wild to think
about I've been doing this podcast I can
remember the first episode I know who
was here uh I can um Invision that time
frame this uh area wasn't even set up
that way the table was a different
direction everything was different back
then uh my how we have grown a lot of
people will message me they'll say hey
bro I just found the show I'm listening
to old episodes I'm going back to the
archives sometimes that is so
embarrassing but at the same time uh
it's great to hear how far the show has
grown uh I left that overcompressed
microphone sound I used to have a big
old crazy podcast setup the gear has
evolved so much just my podcasting gear
uh but and video the video has come a
long way I quit using two cameras cuz
camera 2 kept given me [ __ ] and I would
have to cuss it out in the middle of the
podcast but things have come a long way
uh in 10 years in podcasting we've gone
a long way let me keep a focused on the
rest of the email it does go on though
uh thank you for all of your hard work
bro thank you for the support thank you
for paying attention and noticing that
the show is 10 years old now 10 years of
podcasting you guys that is wild to me
we're 835 episodes in I've only missed a
couple of Mondays I did take a couple of
breaks cuz I was traveling of course I
uh had the vid a couple of times but um
I've been banging it out you guys this
has been a lot of fun it's gotten really
fun to do the podcast I'm comfortable I
can just turn on the mic and start
rambling so that's super cool and the
community shows uh it shows that I've
been doing this for a long time when I
pop up on another podcast any other
podcast you guys come and watch and you
show the love and I appreciate that it
says I recently purchased some seeds
from you and I'm looking forward to
popping them soon yes brother please do
and send picks when you do then it says
have a great day and another 10 years
times 10 peace and love from Eric Eric
thank you for the great message my dude
10 years um he said 10 more years times
10 um I would like to promise you 10
more years who knows where um who knows
where I will be in 10 years at the way
life is changing who knows where
podcasting will be uh at the rate the
internet the world entertainment content
the way things are being delivered who
knows where this service this idea will
be in 10 years you might just have a
chip in your neck that you just think
about roster Jeff or growing weed and my
show will play in your sub conscious who
knows where we're going with this but
with the Apple Vision Pro and all the VR
and [ __ ] who knows where all this
entertainment is going uh who knows what
podcasting and YouTube will be 5 10
years from now uh then also who knows
where uh ganja and cannabis and growing
will be in 10 years will it be legalized
will it be re criminalized will it be
forgotten about will people just be over
it by then like yeah weed whatever we
all smoke weed and grow weed now shut up
about it will it just be like a common
thing will it be the Walmart product
will it be a Monsanto product um where
will the equipment be about growing like
what kind of gear are we going to have
what kind of genetics are we going to
have in 10 years like are we going to
pot pot seeds and there all completely
like exact clones of each other are we
going to have brand new genetics is it
going to be the same or are we going to
dial it in uh will my idea of the slurry
ever come to fruition but who knows what
the future holds of cannabis also who
knows what the future of cannabis holds
for uh State legalization national
federal legalization then what about
worldwide legalization of cannabis then
that opens us up to Commerce what if uh
the Americans and the Canadians uh can
freely move their cannabis back and
forth what if we could take cannabis
down south what if I can mail cannabis
to my buddies in Jamaica what if my
Jamaican friends could send me cannabis
what if what if like I'm I'm curious
where will we be in 510 and then my
buddy said uh 10 years times 10 that's a
100 years um I hope I'm not podcasting
in a 100 years I will that will be a
very boring old man podcast you probably
don't want to hear that one but I hope
by then somebody has has grabbed the
torch that I have lit uh that I have
received from previous Growers previous
breeders shout out to subcool I hope by
then somebody grabs this torch and runs
with it uh and does a lot of things I
want to know where uh where cannabis
will be in 10 years like the
legalization the science uh where will
it be as a community uh as a commodity
I'm very curious so um I'll do my best
to keep going for as long as podcasting
exists as long as I've got a voice and a
camera and an internet connection I'm
going to keep it going um I got super
rambly on that one my dude Eric thank
you for pointing out that the podcast
has been going for 10 years that is
incredible please do check your email
inbox and check your spam because you my
friend have got a coupon code for a gift
card for a free pack of seeds at
air.com and once again while I'm talking
about these free seeds at edirect decom
I've received this message from a couple
of people these gift certificates these
coupon codes do come with an expiration
date a couple of people have messaged me
and said hey is that expiration date
real uh yes that is real real for
Logistics bookkeeping purposes uh
website purposes inventory purposes for
accounting purposes those gift cards
have to have an expiration date uh so
please when you do get those emails get
in there and get those seeds I
understand you may be waiting for
something to restock but most of the
time uh they do have about a 30-day
expiration date on there and that's I'm
trying to be generous but also I've got
to keep the business in line and um
having a bunch of gift cards out there
that have not been redeemed as daunting
as a business own it's like I feel like
I owe it makes you feel like you owe
something and you always want to be able
to cover what you owe so they do have to
have an expiration date and that that
encourages you to shop more quickly
anyway I am rambling the gift cards do
expire that expiration date is real and
that's just the way that it's got to be
so please uh shop quickly all right that
covers that disclaimer let's keep it
moving because I have got some momentum
happening and it feels good to be on the
microphone uh this next message once
again came from the growel tab on iry
genetics.com this one came from my new
friend where is the name my friend we're
going to call them Jeff shout out to
Jeff for the great message it says I saw
that you had skunk testers yes a couple
of weeks ago maybe a month ago by now I
did release two different versions of
skunk testers there's the 90s and the IR
skunk two different uh different crosses
I'm not going to tell you too much they
have a common parent uh but then the uh
the other parent is different so that's
more information than you've had I don't
like to give you too many details on
testers because it will uh it will bias
and sway your testing I want you to test
it and see what you see not what my
words influenced you to see is why I
don't talk about it but it says uh I am
not in the position to be a tester I
appreciate that you didn't buy testers
and put them in a drawer uh you know
that you're not in the position to do
that so you held off you're waiting
you're being polite that is very cordial
I respect and appreciate that of you and
I'm going to do an episode very soon all
about tester seeds uh that will be a
very fun one for everybody so stay tuned
but this message does say uh but I have
been looking for the old stinky three
bagger skunkweed from my youth yes my
friend we all have it says um I Heard
because of the illegal nature of
cannabis they have managed to take the
smell away I want that smell yes me too
dude um so there was a time period when
uh there was a cannabis boom uh ganja
growing got real popular in a large
cultivation setting in a commercial
environment but it was an illegal
environment still uh those operations
got busted I believe that that's why a
lot of our favorite strains kind of
disappeared for a little bit is because
those large grows with that stank got
busted so I believe that you're on to
something when you say that uh cannabis
kind of got away from that super stank
smell because we were trying to hide the
aroma and be a little bit more discreet
if you came to the front door and were
delivering a pizza or looking for your
lost cat or trying to sell me Bibles or
whatever they do uh and I open the door
and it smells like skunks you know I'm
growing weed that's going to raise some
suspicions if you open the door and it
smells like oranges or strawberries
there's a chance you may think I'm
eating oranges or strawberries or
something different is happening in
there you're not just going to go he's
growing a bunch of weed in there I just
gave us an opportunity for a little bit
more camouflage a less a little bit less
obvious bit of aroma so I do agree with
you I believe that that is part of why
uh we swayed away from that skunky
stanky smell but now but now uh ganja is
getting legalized almost everywhere and
people that remember that old stank
smell we you they uh we all want it back
and I was missing that skunk smell I
remember my uncles I talk about my
uncles a lot I had three uncles two of
them heavily influenced my cannabis
career intake consumption um
appreciation they're both gone now rest
in peace boys I love you and miss you
every day but um these two uncles uh
they smoked the skunk weed back in the
day and they got excited about skunk
weed my one Uncle would be like hey uh
I'll say their names cuz they're gone
Eric would be like Hey Ron I got some
skunk weed and Ron was kind of a heavy
set dude and that [ __ ] would run
up to the smoking area when there was
some skunk weed to smoke the ants the
[ __ ] my ants that were around they
would come and not ants like little ants
my aunts my uncles's sisters they would
show up and want to smoke too oh brother
you got some good skunk weed and they
would [ __ ] get extra lit and then uh
the whole house would smell like a
[ __ ] skunk so I remember skunk from
when I was little and my uncles were
hyped on skunk so I understand that we
all want that skunk back um my dude said
you had skunk testers but I wasn't in
the position to test test them that's
[ __ ] respectable thank you uh but you
do want that skunk any
recommendations my recommendation that I
can recommend right now is stay tuned um
those testers that I put out were
basically a preview a very uh tip of the
iceberg of my skunk
experimentation uh I have fallen in love
with a couple of skunk phenotypes that I
played with I don't want to talk too
much about it in the future once some of
the skunk testing that has gone out has
been completed I will tell you uh where
the skunk seeds and clones I played with
came from there were two different
batches of seeds three different batches
of seeds two that got selected from that
were that had the keepers I wanted uh
one clone that is really popular got put
into the mix so there were three
different skunk parents that are kind of
getting gangbanged and different
manipulations around those I'll tell you
more about that but stay tuned because
there's more skunk coming that skunk
pollination uh didn't happen to just a
couple of plants there were many many
plants in the room I can tease that
there was a BC Lemon Skunk female in the
room that got pollinated by the skunk
number one what that's going to be wild
uh there's a Durban Poison that got
pollinated by that skunk um a lot of
stuff got pollinated so those will be
trickling out slowly over time and then
there will be more of these all remade
and then rebred together and other
things I'm in love with this skunk
project so uh my recommendation is stay
tuned and keep an eye on the website uh
because eventually there will be some
skunk stuff that is tested that will be
released and it's coming um I don't want
to say soon because breeder talks soon
is way different than consumer talk when
I say soon to you guys you're like is it
ready yet and I'm like it's it's growing
I'm sorry I shouldn't have said soon but
breeder talk grower talk and consumer
talk different time levels there when
you say soon my recommendation my Bros
stay tuned there will be more skunk
coming I'm in love with the skunk can't
get enough of it that smell that Aroma
that flavor what if I put the the skunk
number one to chem 4 and chm91 and stuff
like that what if all that happened what
it's coming stay tuned we just want to
grow it before you guys get to it uh my
hope is that you trying to recreate it
yes trying to recreate it and also add
it to other things uh put skunk to
everything that's kind of one of the new
ideas here and also narrow down some
skunk turps that we like I want to say
so much dude but I can't reveal too much
with uh the testing that's happening I
don't want to sway you but stay tuned
because it's all in my head and
obviously I'm excited about it so I will
talk about it once we get uh a lot of
test reports back from you guys he wraps
it up with PS Rost to Jeff oh thanks uh
PS I'm a subscriber to your show and I
love when you're on the dude grow show
uh that's a huge compliment it's always
encouraging to know that the other
listeners of other podcasts appreciate
my presence on their show it lets me
know that I'm not intruding uh I'm not
just uh being annoying on the show so
it's great to know that I'm wanted on
the dude grow show I have a good time
over there uh big shout out to Scotty
reel of course shout out to the dude big
shout out to Gro big shout out the
banner I can't shout out the entire crew
you guys you got too many over there if
you're part of the entire dgc crew in
any way big shout out to you thanks for
the support uh and I will be back on the
show I definitely do have a good time
being on that Monday panel show all
right let's keep this good momentum
going I've got another question here in
front of me this one also did come from
that growel tab at iy genetics.com this
one came from lunchbox boys Tai big
shout out to Tai keep that lunchbox
strong I don't even know what that means
the question says yo roster Jeff I hope
all is well with you and your family I
have a smoker's question this is a great
question
it says I have been dabbing for about a
year now uh welcome to the party my bro
then it says I need something to travel
with any suggestions I always hear you
say you've been on dabs and I was just
curious how you dab when on the road all
right that's a good question now let me
uh let me preface all of this with the
disclaimer uh rosta Jeff is a fictional
character and I do not dab in the car uh
on the road while I'm driving I would
never do anything like that because I
don't believe that that is legal here in
the beautiful state of Colorado and I am
a law-abiding citizen and I encourage
you to do the same thing however if
cannabis were completely illegal and we
were allowed to smoke while we drive I
would definitely take big fat Dabs out
of a puffco peak Guardian that's what I
use on the road allegedly uh it's a good
device it is a little bit spendy it is
not the cheapest uh portable smoking
apparatus but what I like is the puffco
guardian or very similar as the the
puffco peak Pro that's probably the one
that is more available uh the puffco
peak Pro uh it comes with a basic
chamber I like the upgraded chamber the
uh extra-large 3D chamber is the way to
go it gives you some more settings it
gives you bigger rips that is what I use
it fits in the cup holder it holds a
charge well it gives big fat rips it's
easy to maintain um it's easy to clean
out you just need a Q-tip and you can
Q-tip it up it holds a charge for a good
time it gives me plenty of dabs for
while I'm gone you can charge it with a
car charger if you need that um so what
I suggest my personal device would be a
puffco peak Pro get the good one get the
pro uh don't get the entry level model
if you've got the opportunity I like the
guardian it's a little bit better but
you don't need that if uh you're just
going to be using it in the car or
whatever um I recommend the puffco peak
Pro with the upgraded extra- llarge
chamber it's another 130 or 140 bucks
but it makes a huge free difference it
definitely does I am not a show per for
puffco nobody has paid me to say this
puffco has never given me a free
anything um I paid full price I just got
my daughter full disclosure she got a
for Christmas she got a puff Co I
[ __ ] paid full price for it no
discounts or nothing nobody pays me for
this I like the puffco that's what I'm
saying um sometimes you might want to
put a different topper on it um the the
smoking piece I don't do that because I
just uh I don't want to break an
expensive part that I travel around with
allegedly that might be in the car now
me uh having said that I prefer the
puffco my buddy hot rod is going to
argue with me and say the ca V2 is where
it's at there's another brand called
Carta c a r ta they make a very fine
portable vaporizer unit uh that is very
comparable to the puffco a lot of people
will argue which one is better uh I have
the puffco it works for me my daughter
had a CA for quite a while it hit very
good but it died we sent it back for a
warranty they returned it it died again
both of our puff CES have been going
strong so that is where I stand on that
the ca seems like a good product for
most of my friends that have it they
enjoy it it rips well it's affordable I
prefer the puff Co those are the top two
there are several other portable smoking
devices that are available on the market
that are more affordable in my opinion
you kind of get what you pay for with
the these devices they do charge you too
much they are overpriced but the good
[ __ ] is expensive when it comes to
uh portable smoking devices uh a lot of
people I see online I've got a lot of
friends with the Dr Dabber and the do
Dabber mini and then there's another Dr
Dabber I think it's Debbie Dabber or
something like that there's one with the
ball attachment on it that seems like a
quality device a quality product however
I have not hit it I've got a couple of
friends that I dab with on Discord and
it seems to be reliable and effective
for them but like I said I did not buy
one I don't know uh there's a another
product out there you know what I don't
like it so I'm not even going to tell
you there's one I don't like and I'm not
going to recommend it because I'm just
going to talk [ __ ] about it and Bash it
so uh I'm not even going to mention it
on the show we're just going to stay
classy uh I recommend the puffco either
the peak Pro or the guardian uh there's
another thing out there called the proxy
it works but it's not my favorite either
the puffco proxy if you're going to buy
a puffco uh get I like a when I take a
dab I need water I want water in my I
want bubbles it makes it so much cooler
more enjoyable so get the uh the
guardian or the Peak and skip the proxy
is my opinion I've got a friend with the
proxy I hit it it worked I didn't get
nearly what I would have gotten out of a
puff C Peak Pro so I think you get what
you pay for um they're quality products
if you get a good one and if I missed
something if there's a product you
recommend there's a comment section go
ahead and argue about it in the comments
I encourage it all right my buddy
lunchbox boys tie thank you for the
great question that question did qualify
you guys don't be shy the questions do
not have to be grow related the
questions don't have to be about growing
ganjo or about the Cannabis Community it
can be about a product it could be some
sort of weird advice uh I know some
things don't be afraid to ask uh my dude
make sure you do check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds from iy
direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers all of you amazing
cannabis enthusiasts out there I want to
thank you once again for 10 years of the
grow from your heart podcast without you
guys um this podcast would not have made
it 10 years without you uh this would be
a mental issue I'd be a guy with too
many toys and too many pieces of
equipment talking to myself and they
would probably put me in a padded room
by now so thank you thank you for making
this podcast a huge success uh thank you
for making IE genetics a huge success I
understand that you are what makes it
successful I am part of it you are part
of it without us both doing our part it
would not be what it is so I appreciate
it it does does not go left unseen
unappreciated unnoticed thank you um I
do appreciate the love the support the
kindness the encouragement the
acceptance uh all of that stuff the
community that uh is I want to say that
I built but I didn't build it you guys
are building that Community I'm just
here with the voice thank you for that
the community that follows me the iy
Army uh the dude grow crew that hangs
out all the other podcasts that have uh
followed because they saw me on another
show thank you guys you're all iy Army
you're all family as far as I'm
concerned thank you all right we're
getting mushy here at the end of the
show let's wrap it up and say goodbye
while we're still doing well thank you
guys I do appreciate you all for
listening uh make sure you check out the
website IR genetics.com I talked about
IR gentics earlier there is a tab for
everything you could imagine you could
get the merch you can get the seeds you
can find the patreon you can find the
Discord uh you can find a link to the
podcast you probably already know where
that is everything you need is at IR
genetics.com make sure you check IR
genetics.com
for anything you could possibly need I
think that's all I've got for you all
right I'll be back in a week with fresh
new content I want to give a big shout
out to my friend Val and until next time
take a fat dab and give your mom a hug
for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ]