[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
[ __ ] all right here we go
welcome to the podcast everybody I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode 839
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's episode I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in the show I do once again
want to cordially invite you to join us
at the dude grows Growers cup that's
right June 1st in leaport Colorado the
dude grows crew is hosting the dude
grows Growers cup the entire dgc crew
will be there the iy Army will be there
and we all look forward to meeting you
at the dude grows Growers cup make sure
you check dgc cup.com for all of the
information as this episode comes out
that event is only 2 weeks away so it is
very close to being sold out make sure
you get those tickets today if you show
up to the dude grow cup wearing an iy
genetics or iy Army t-shirt hoodie or
hat I will give you a free gift make
sure you stop by the booth and say hello
and pick up that free gift also if
you're not wearing any iy gear I merch
don't be shy please come to the booth
and say hello if you'd like to meet me
shake my hand say hello uh share
pictures of your grow share some flowers
that you grew I would love to meet all
of my friends at the dude grows Growers
cup stop by the booth I will have a big
Booth it will be very easy to find I
will be there Mike will be there stop by
and say hello I look forward to meeting
everybody sometimes my booth will be
very busy I will have a line I'll have a
lot of people in front of me please do
not be shy stand in that line for a
couple of minutes or simply come back
when there's not a crowd and introduce
yourself I'm never too busy to shake
hands to meet the iy Army to meet the
crew that's what I'm there for don't
message me the day after or the week
after saying hey bro I saw you at the
dgc cup wanted to say hi uh but you
looked busy I am never too busy to shake
your hand uh give you a fist bump give
you a hug take a picture smell your weed
um stop by introduce yourself uh like I
said a moment ago there may be a line it
may be busy but if I see somebody
standing there and they're starting to
look anxious like they want to meet me
like they want to talk to me I do pay
attention to that I do try to speed up
the line and try to get people coming
and going so I can meet everybody uh
don't be shy uh don't feel like you're
bothering me you're not uh I will be
more upset if you do not introduce
yourself and tell me later that you
chickened out that you were too shy than
I would be if you just walk up interrupt
people be awkward come say hello that's
what I want meet me shake my hand that's
what I'm there for dude I want to meet
everybody in the crew also we will have
a bunch of great merchandise at the
booth stop by the booth see what we've
got check out the menu you may be
surprised there will be new things there
will be a lot of the classic things and
there will be some surprises all right
that is the dude gross crew we look
forward to seeing you there uh the next
piece of advertising I've got before we
jump into the question answer portion of
the show is there is currently a sale
happening on edirect decom that's right
for the entire month of May I will be
blowing out regular seed packs on
edirect decom for ridiculous pricing you
can get a 10 pack of light Ripper
regular seeds for 10 $1 right now at
edirect
docomomo all right that is all of the
advertising for the start of the show
here let's work our way into the pet
peeve portion of the podcast I'm sure
you most of you understand what a pet
peeve is a pet peeve is something that
just simply drives you crazy I like to
focus on growroom pet peeves something
that I see in a grow room whether it's a
commercial grow whether it's a private
grow maybe saw I saw it online or
perhaps it could be a cannabis Community
pet peeve something that just simply
simply drives me crazy I've been
encouraging you the listeners and
viewers to send in your pet peeves you
can email me at grow fromy yourheart at
hotmail.com simply put the word pet
peeve in the subject line so I can find
it if I do read your pet peeve here on
the podcast I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds off of
idirect decom today's pet peeve came
from my friend patio toker big shout out
to my buddy patio toker I've seen you on
the Discord you've been around for quite
a while so it's great to get an
opportunity to send you a coupon code
for free seeds patio tokers pet peeve
says my pet peeve is undefoliated plants
we're talking plants that have never
been touched okay that is a very valid
pet peeve and what he means is uh
defoliation is when you go in and take
off some of the larger leaves I
recommend it I suggest it I almost
demand it be done in commercial grow
environment when there's a lot of
foliage a lot of uh Leaf happening in
the room I find that that that taking
off those leaves can mitigate a lot of
problems but patio toker's big pet peeve
is that he does not like plants that
have not been
defoliated that big 70s Bush of a plant
with all those leaves growing in there
simply drives you crazy I can understand
that however let me tell you a little
bit of a story I recently ran a grow
room and in that grow I was struggling
to keep the humidity up I was not going
to buy a humidifier for one grow it was
a short grow process at a weird part of
the year I had switched equipment I had
switched the way that I was running my
ducting I was struggling to keep the
humidity right in this grow space my
smart idea was to defoliate less than I
usually do I left the leaves on those
plants to allow them to transpire and
put uh moisture into the air the all of
those leaves were releasing more
moisture into my environment and
contributing to the humidity because I
actually needed that in that grow space
so most of the time you are correct All
of That 70s Bush all that extra foliage
all those leaves are good opportunities
for powdery mildew it's a good place for
bugs to hide it blocks uh light from
your bud s sites there is great reason
to defoliate but in this situation my
room is getting so dry that I just chose
to leave a bunch of leaves on the plant
and honestly it brought it up just a few
percent just to keep that room where I
needed it I could water heavily the
water in the plants would raise the
humidity just a little bit then all of
that evaporation from the plants helped
but then also all those leaves letting
out all that water from the stoma that
definitely helped me uh increase the
humidity in the grow space so I do
understand that a lot of times that
could be um not visually appealing it's
probably not best for the growth of the
room in most environments in most
occasions however this one time in my
grow space I tried a trick and it did
exactly what I needed done so sometimes
these pet peeves are going to be
subjective sometimes we got to think
about um and this this goes for the
internet and advice on the internet as a
whole if you see advice if you see some
guidance that may work in a certain
situation in a certain environment in a
certain room but we don't always know
what all the situations in somebody's
grow space may be I was struggling to
keep my humidity up because I had
readjusted my ducting I'd made some
changes and I was not going to buy a
humidifier simply for it was about 40
days worth of growth that I would have
needed that humidifier wasn't going to
spend the money on it maybe I'm a cheap
ass Maybe I'm efficient maybe I'm e
economical but my idea did work what I'm
getting at is uh there's more than one
way to skin a cat and sometimes the
things that we see in a grow that look
like a problem are actually a solution
so we've got to be open-minded uh you've
got to be kind of a mcgyver and a grow
space you've got to be able to adjust
and adapt and you've got to be very
open-minded I think I said that but if I
would have been super stubborn and said
no I have to defoliate cuz that's the
way I operate that's my sop I actually
would have [ __ ] up that crop I think
it did much better because I left a
bunch of leaf on those plants so my dude
patio toker uh 75 or 85% of the time I
do agree with you defoliate those damn
plants but occasionally like in my
instance those leaves contributed to a
little extra humidity and allowed me to
increase the humidity the overall VPD in
the room was improved because of that
extra 70s Bush my dude I'm still going
to send you a free pack of seeds even
though I don't 100% agree with you this
was a great peeve um I like that it's
subjective and I like being able to talk
about things that we slightly disagree
on although we do agree 85% of the time
all right my dude check your email
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds
all right let's keep this show moving
now we are going to work our way into
the question and answer portion of
today's podcast I have a website that
website is called iy genetics.com it is
i i e genetics.com iy it's a Patwa or a
Jamaican word uh iie means to feel the
best you can feel to to feel blessed to
feel at ease um there are many ways I
could use to describe it you ever been
sitting um maybe on the beach um
probably at the beach just a little bit
of sun coming down on you you're looking
out at the ocean you're watching the
waves crash there's a little bit of
Breeze moving your hair but it's not
uncomfortable it's just nice a nice
breeze just moving the hair maybe you
got your lady with you your dude with
you maybe you've got your dog with you
maybe it's your best and perhaps it's
your child with you maybe you're all by
your damn self but maybe you're out
there smoking a little bit of a joint
and you just got this feeling everything
just feels good nothing is wrong nothing
could bother you just feel good that's
feeling iy I feel blessed I feel
powerful I feel at ease I feel peaceful
um watching the ocean do its waves I'm
feeling the breeze in my hair I feel the
sun sunshine on my skin smoking a little
spliff I got some love next to me no
matter who it is uh that is the feeling
of being iy or when there's music and
you're at a concert and you got your
hands up and everybody's vibing together
that is the feeling of feeling iy that's
why I choose the word iy to represent my
genetics there's not much better than
feeling iy that is a good feeling so iry
genetics.com I got off on a good ramble
there thank you for that go to that
website IR genetics.com there's a list
of tabs on the top of that website one
of those tabs says grow help that's
pretty obvious if you need grow help
click on that tab we give you the
opportunity to ask us a grow question
simp send me your grow question if I
read your question from that growel tab
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
air.com today's first question came from
a person who wants to be called ganjaman
Welcome to the party ganjaman thank you
for the question uh by your real name I
know who you are you've been around for
a while so thank you for the support the
question says hey rosta Jeff I hope you
are having a wonderful time bro just
like I said everything IE it says I am
messaging here to ask about your
breeding setup it would be nice for a
tour one day on YouTube if possible you
know I really enjoy showing you guys my
garden and my plants and my setups and
things but I'm sure you've noticed or
maybe you haven't I have definitely
noticed and YouTube notices every time I
show a ganja plant in one of my videos
YouTube takes down my video so I'm
allowed to show you my face um my shirt
and this [ __ ] curtain behind me but
that's about all you get because if I
put Plants up on the screen YouTube
takes my video down immediately and then
they send me a community guidelines
strike and if I get too many of those
they take away the channel so
unfortunately I am not comfortable
showing uh my grow spaces or plants on
this channel I did a very good topping
video about topping our plants I put a
plant on the table and showed you where
to top it and YouTube took that down it
got a couple thousand views and then
YouTube took it down also I took that
top and showed you how to make a clone
out of it in another video YouTube took
that one down also those are the two
videos I've attempted to bring plants
into the studio and do Hands-On work
with them and then YouTube took it down
so unfortunately I'm not comfortable
doing a tour um that'd be super cool it'
be really fun maybe a patreon only bonus
or something but right now it's not
anything that I've got lined up but it's
a good idea now that I just said it hey
Rost to Jeff when you're editing this
write down the idea of doing a patreon
only growroom Tour episode don't edit
that part out so that people can hear
about it all right it's says uh that
would be uh a tour would be cool one day
if possible um I doubt it but maybe on
patreon it goes on though it says I'm
looking to start a breed I'm looking to
start breeding my own genetics so that I
can keep strains that are no longer
being produced and sold and make my
crosses of my own all right that's a
really good idea preservation is key
especially with the possibility of the
DEA changing scheduling on our favorite
plan it may be much harder to acquire
seeds in the future we will talk about
that as time goes on as things change
I've promised to keep you updated on
that it says I've got a few questions on
the subject you have come to the right
place my friend I do enjoy breeding
questions it says do you keep your male
plants in of different strains in the
same tent and all of your female plants
in one tent in a separate room or can
you keep them in one bedroom all
together with no worries of pollen since
they are in veg so I keep my I call them
Father plants all the boys that I have
selected are fathers all the female
plants I've selected are mother plants
so uh mothers and fathers are all kept
in the same uh space during their mother
and father cycle this is just where I
keep the plants just to have the
genetics on storage it's my stable my
preserve if you will I'm able to keep
all of those plants in the same room in
the same space because like you said
they are in veg you will not have any
pollen present until several days end of
flower unless you make a mistake
sometimes your male plants if they get
root bound if they don't get enough
light if they get underfed uh if they
just start getting pissy in general for
any reason sometimes those plants will
begin to go into flower and start
dumping pollen for no reason but you
should see that way ahead of time so you
can keep your father and mother plants
and your veg plants and your clones and
your seedlings for that matter basically
all in the mother room and the father
room and the stable if you will uh keep
them all in that environment I recommend
18 at least 18 hours of light I honestly
do 19 on and five off why do I do that
because some of the more like I said a
moment ago some of the more sativa
dominant plants uh the more tropical
varietals the haze varietals some of
those will try to flower if you give
them too much dark time if they're a
little bit root bound if they're getting
underfed if they get overwatered
sometimes those plants just a few things
will trigger those boys to try to go
into flower I cannot have that happen
because once they start going into
flower it's really hard to turn a male
back around once he gets started that he
really wants to go so I will keep those
on 19 hours on and 5 hours off in my
mother area to keep Healthy Growth and
prevent those plants from going into
flower so um you can keep all those
plants in the same room I would adjust
that timer to 19 on five off and then
feed these plants they're going to need
a uh a heavy vegetative diet they
basically need uh just the grow bottle
uh for the most part if you've got that
base nutrient the grow a grow B that's
probably what they're going to need they
may need would feed them microbes of
course they may need a few other things
based on how big and how old they are
but keep an eye on them it's real easy
to feed mother plants very easy give
them a basic vegetative nutrient mix um
I've been talking about that light
spectrum I try to go 19 hours on and
five off sometimes I will reduce the
intensity of the light in my mother area
I don't need these plants growing super
quickly I don't need them uh getting
really big very quickly I just need them
to simply be healthy and exist so that
when I do need Cuts they are there and
available so I kind of turn the lights
down a little bit on these plants to
slow the growth I've noticed uh if I've
got the plant the lights boosted up all
the way they grow too quickly for me I
have to top them I have to defoliate
them too much I just simply reduce the
lights and they grow beautifully they
grow just fine for the way that I need
them now there is another part to this
question it says do you keep males okay
do you keep males of the same strains
and the same tint yes because there is
no pollen at this time as soon as you
start making pollen everything must be
separated which is the next question so
let's move on to that it says can you
still grow a seedless crop in the same
house when breeding I definitely don't
want to pollinate and Seed my medicine
and okay so we're going to talk about
that first um breeding in a location
where you're also growing and hoping to
have cilia buds this is an art I've uh
figured this art out it took me a while
um full disclosure we could talk about
it now because it's not happening but um
I used to have a grow in my office is
right over there where I edit this show
is just a room over on the other side of
that wall um that used to be a grow
space on the other in that office where
you guys all see me hang out on Discord
and [ __ ] that used to be a grow space
with two 5x5 tents and a 3X3 tent in
there I'd put the boy plants in the 3X3
and then use both 5x FES on opposite
schedules one ran 9:00 a.m. to 900 p.m.
and the other one ran 9:00 p.m. to 9
a.m. that way I could maximize the
electricity in that room but not have to
do any upgrades to the electrical had
1,000 watt light running at all times
and then I had a little uh 400 light
running for my boy plants and then that
boy he only had to be on certain hour so
he would take a break but every 12 hours
tent a would be on and then every 12
hours tent B would be on so I was always
running a thousand watt light in there
but only one at a time running two
flowering Cycles very very efficient in
that room I was breeding a lot of your
favorite strains that I made came from
that room in there when it used to be a
grow space it's not a grow space anymore
I had to uh I had to make some
adjustments you guys I I was trying to
the numbers got changed here in Colorado
we used to be allowed to grow so many
more plants now we cannot that was a
wasted grow space turned it into an
office but that was a grow space up
there that room had pollen in it all the
freaking time I have another grow space
is was in the basement it was directly
below that room there's another room
basically a mirror of that office in the
basement of the house that were in and
that was where my main grow space was I
was able to breed plants upstairs in the
two tents and not contaminate and Seed
the grow that I had downstairs and it
was it took a few tricks to figure it
out but the main thing that I learned
and here's a golden piece of advice if
you're a breeder if you're thinking
about breeding uh this is going to be
one of those episodes and this is going
to be one of the things you want to
write uh write down or record or take a
note of one thing that I really found
important that really helped me out
breeding seeds and growing centy crops
in the same house is timing all it's
about is timing if you've got a plant
upstairs dumping pollen don't have other
plants downstairs in flour have those in
veg as soon as you chop down that male
plant and clean up the pollen put that
other room downstairs and flour you've
only got pollen around for about 21 days
if you do it properly maybe maybe up to
25 28 days you really don't need pollen
around for that long most of your plants
are going to get hit by pollen by day 30
so what I would recommend have your
breeding room get your breeding room
going put those plants don't have
another room in flower so let me back up
a step
um Harvest your cilia room the room you
don't want seeds in Harvest it uh right
before you harvest that you need to have
another room in flower that you want to
breed or in veg that you want to breed
in so Harvest your seedless crop while
you've got another room vegging that you
plan to breed in as soon as you harvest
flip that other crop to flour um in
about 14 days you'll start seeing the
boys uh about 21 days you'll Chuck
pollen by day 25 28 pollen has been
chucked cut down that male plant you
should have another room in veg
downstairs already that is ready to
Flower by the time that crop gets about
30 45 days in then flip the other room
as long as these plants downstairs are
not in flower if they're in veg they
cannot receive pollen so you have no
stress no worries no fear uh no risk of
pollinating that crop as long as it
stays in veg so you can't have both of
them in flour at the same time but it's
just a very short uh juggle there so I
would do a flower crop with no seeds in
one room and then a seed crop in one
room right after that and then back to
back we do flower seed flower seed and
as long as you clean up properly between
runs you won't have any contamination so
it's all about setting the Rhythm have
this room in the one you want a seed
have it in veg while your flower room is
growing Harvest your flowers put your
breeding crop into flow immediately cut
more clones for your other flowering
room and get that filled up and have it
in veg pollinate the breeding room clean
up by clean up I mean cut down down that
boy plant sweep up all the pollen then
spray everything with water water
deactivates pollen so get a I use a pump
sprayer it's a deck spray it holds two
gallons of water um I'll just fill that
bad [ __ ] up with water I actually may
put push in there uh from uh hydroponic
research it's a veg Bloom product it's
called push it's a foler application
it's a great product put that push in
there shake that up spray every single
plant also spray the walls spray
everything down just to kill any pollen
that may be in that room I'll do that a
couple of times I'll go in there and
spray water a couple of times just to
make sure I've deactivated all of that
pollen now once I'm confident that all
of the pollen is cleaned up put that
other room into flour now those seeds
will finish while your other room is
starting to flow you can Harvest your
seeds and then your other centy crop
will finish and it will be seedless if
you do it properly and time it properly
it's all about timing that is how I make
it happen that's how I made this house
produced a lot of flowers and a lot of
seeds at the same time unfortunately
since the new stupid rules in Colorado I
can't do that I've got to either make
seeds at one time or run a regular crop
at one time or use other houses and
Facilities which seems to be the trick
but um very limited here so we're not
doing all that multiple room [ __ ]
anymore it's all about that Rhythm just
don't have your centi crop in flour
while you've got pollen in the air and
everything should work beautifully now
if you do insist on having that male
plant in flower while you've got a crop
in another room like I said before water
deactivates try to keep everything as
far apart as possible try to have so one
thing I recommend is if you can set it
up with your ducting wherever the maale
plants are kept have that or where your
pollination room is have that
ventilation go out of your grow facility
If You Can duct that outside uh you may
end up pollinating the outdoor people's
grow if you're not careful but try to I
use a carbon filter so I'm thinking most
of my shit's getting caught in the
filter but try to duck that pollen out
so that you don't accidentally
contaminate the other rooms inside your
growth facility
um water deactivates everything uh if
you leave that pollen room try to I've
got dreadlocks dude so there's pollen in
my dreads I'm sure of it but try to wrap
your dreads up in a hat try to wear a
hat if you can change clothes if you can
take a shower I recommend that before
going from room to room but water will
deactivate that pollen if you need to go
from room to room I would say go spray
the centy room with water then go do
your stuff in the pollen room then carry
that water with you and when you go back
into the other room spray it again spray
yourself uh water will be your best
friend in that situation so I think
that's the best I can answer you for
that one I told you how I did it it's
all about that Rhythm don't have uh the
seedless cro in flow when there's pollen
and only have the pollen plants or the
pollinated plants in flour when you're
ready to pollinate them it seems to be
the easiest way to do it um there's more
though it says um can you use multiple
males at once in the same house I would
not do that um do not use multiple males
just separ separate your breeding
projects just time them out properly it
doesn't take as much time as you're
thinking it does to breed seeds um you
can Chuck pollen and get that mail out
of there in 30 days then you just need
to let those seeds finish up um get the
next mail and the next crop going in
another room and move them up there as
soon as you harvest and that would work
beautifully but I do not recommend two
males at the same time you're going to
have a Mori poage situation that pollen
is going to cross and get on different
plants it's not going to work the way
that you want it to who knows who the
baby daddy is at that point it turns
into a spring break situation what
precautions would you take to make sure
you don't transfer pollen between tents
water water water water and proper
ventilation is the answer is a different
bedroom needed entirely um I would do it
in a completely different bedroom I
honestly did it in completely different
sections of the house upstairs and
downstairs put a nice barrier between
there um they were actually the like I
said before the rooms were directly on
top of and Below each other and the
stairs are at the opposite end of the
house so I had to go all the way from
one end to the other then all the way
back down to the other so for Polland to
travel with me there it was possible but
it was much more unlikely because it was
such a distance um is a different
bedroom needed yes I would say so and
showering and changing clothes that is
obvious I think you should definitely do
that to not move that pollen around but
like I'm saying like the main thing to
make this work here is just don't have
plants you don't want seeded in flour
when there's pollen because the pistols
are what receive pollen um also Al too
late into flower the plants won't
receive pollen either once the pistols
are all withered up and dry and brown
those plants are past their estris past
their sexual reproductive stage uh they
cannot receive pollen at that point so
uh you could throw pollen at that point
also and not have to worry about those
plants let me make sure I got it the end
of it says also what happened to Jack
the Ripper uh nothing happened to Jack
the Ripper I've still got a good Jack
the Ripper male I've got two Jack the
Ripper females uh they're just taking a
little break I've been honestly regular
seeds do not sell making reg seeds right
now doesn't seem to be a very wise move
for the market for the business because
um 90% of my seed sales are feminized
seeds so making the Jack the Ripper
seeds again or more crosses of that
they'll probably most likely sit there
on the Shelf which is why uh reg seeds
are on sale on iir right now for1 or $20
a pack you can get a 10 pack of seeds
for $10 at iir go take advantage of that
sale I'm trying to breathe life into the
regular Seed Market Market let people
know that Reg seeds are awesome are
popular are viable they should not be
afraid which is really funny because 10
years ago we had to do the same thing
with fem seeds everybody thought fem
were problematic they were afraid of
them we educated the masses and now
that's all that sells people forgot
about the regs but Jack the Ripper is
still around uh ripping jacking uh
chilling it's in the grow space I've got
a mom I've Got Two Moms I got a dude in
there uh they may do work in the future
but right now they're taking a break and
I'm focused on the feminized seeds I've
got a couple of great fem projects
coming up um I'm going to make more
Golden Goat crosses there will be
grateful dog crosses but I've got a new
plant that is gorgeous I haven't talked
too much about it it needs to be bred
with so that is going to be a project in
the near future I'm saying too much
already let's move on this one says I
really appreciate the advice this will
be super helpful I wish you the best my
dude gaman uh thank you for a good
question I love talking about breeding I
love talking about pollen so this was a
great question for both of us my dude
make sure you check your inbox cuz
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at iy direct.com all right I'm
not sure how long we've been going but
we're going to jump into one more
message anyway this one is going to be a
fun one this one also came from the
growel tab on iry genetics.com this one
came from somebody who wants to be
called Tilly the question is do you
think it's worth it to try popping bag
seeds and hope to cross each other and
make new genetics all right that's a
really good question that's a multi-part
question there you were kind of putting
the cart before the horse with this
breeding part but um bag seed what is a
bag seed let's talk about that briefly
what is a bag seed bag seed is any seed
that came from your bag of weed let's
say you got a bag of purple Skittle
dicks right because purple Skittle dicks
is going to be the new popular strain
you got this big bag of purple Skittle
dicks right you find seeds in there
those are bag seed many people are going
to say I've got purple SK Skittle dick
seed but guess what you don't because
who knows what that seed came from we
know that the female portion of that
plant was purple Skittle dicks who was
the pollen donor who the baby daddy this
is a Mory Povich situation um we don't
know if that plant was self-pollinated
we don't know if that plant was
pollinated by an intersex plant we don't
know if it was pollinated by a regular
plant we don't know who the baby daddy
was so that is simply labeled bag seed
it came from a bag now are those is
worth growing the answer to that is [ __ ]
yeah dude grow that bag seed um that
could be the most amazing plant on the
planet or also it could be pure garbage
some of the most popular strains on the
planet came from bag seed um maybe
you've heard of a little cross called
chem dog there's chm91 chem D um there's
chem OG there's uh there's more that I
can't [ __ ] think of off the top of my
head but the chem dog lineage all of the
dog lines came from bag seed a guy
bought a bag of weed there were 13 seeds
in it he grew some of those from there
came that chem 91 the chem sister the
chem D all of the major famous chem
varietals came from bag seed so you may
have the next amazing line also Girl
Scout cookies is believed to have come
from a cherry pie bag seed it was a bag
of cherry pie with the seed in there um
I'm going to throw out my theory I think
it was a men py citral Kush that
pollinated that cherry pie just from
some stories that I've heard and that is
what made the Girl Scout cookies we will
never know but technically Girl Scout
cookies from what we know was bag seed
also Gorilla Glue and Golden Goat were
accidents which are technically bag seed
they weren't meant to happen it was an
accidental breeding project somebody's
pollen Got Away in their grow room they
found seeds in their weed those two
strains are two of the most popular
strains on the market so I would
definitely grow out those bag seed do
not sell them trade them or give them
away and if you do give them to anybody
make sure that grower knows that what
they've got is not a reputable tested
seed they have got bag seeds um you
could produce interex plants you could
produce crazy [ __ ] mutants we don't
know what's going to come from that so
be very open if you give that to anybody
I recommend you grow it you may have
like I keep saying you may have the next
Girl Scout cookies you could have the
next Mac one on your hands who knows
what you've got in there now until
you've grown this plant several times
you've beat the [ __ ] out of it you've
stress tested it maybe you've let a
couple of friends grow it in different
environments I would not breed with this
plant until you have fully investigated
this plant's potential is it interex um
if it shows any interex traits do not
breed with it if it shows you mutations
or problems do not breed with it the
entire point of breeding is to improve
this plant the entire point of breeding
is to make plant a and plant B and put
them together and make a plant that is
better than both of those plants if that
is not possible if that is not the
outcome come abandon that project don't
put a a crappy hermaphroditic plant into
a breeding project that is not setting
yourself up for Success that is setting
yourself up for failure and not doing a
service to the community or our plants
so let me get back to the notes and get
myself back on track um is it worth
trying to pop bag seeds the answer is
[ __ ] yeah dude pop those grow them get a
clone who knows what you've got but in
hopes to cross each other and make new
genetics um I wouldn't breed to anything
unless I have thoroughly stressed tested
it grown it several times identified its
weaknesses its pros its cons find out
what pisses it off find out what makes
it happy most importantly find out if
there are any interex traits and then
most importantly is there a reason to
breed with these plants are you just
breeding them because you've got them I
got a boy I got a girl they going to
[ __ ] or do you see traits in this plant
is there a reason is there structure
Vigor flavor Aroma color Leaf shape
flowering time um triome density
internodal spacing potency uh pathogen
resistance pest resistance drought
resistance um are there prosen cons to
these plants are there reasons to make
this plant worth breeding or are you
just making them [ __ ] because you got
them that's what I want to know all
right I think I've answered this
question pretty thoroughly my friend
Tilly make sure you check your email
because you have a coupon code for a
free pack of iy genetics premium seeds I
want to hear from you guys out there how
do you feel about growing and breeding
bag seed leave your comments Ms in the
comment section down below maybe just
maybe I'll pick my favorite comment and
you will get a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to episode
839 of the grow from your heart podcast
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know I would
love to hear from you the email address
is grow from your heart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your feedback your
hate mail your constructive criticism
your positive feedback I can handle it
let me know what you're thinking also
make sure you check the website iry
genetics.com everything you could
possibly need is at IR genetics.com
there's a link to the seeds at iir
there's a link to the merchandise
there's a link to the Discord server and
there's a link to the patreon campaign
come support the podcast on patreon
check out the free seed giveaways on
patreon all right my voice is running
out I feel like I'm rambling I'm going
to wrap up this podcast I'll be back in
a week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy random
hero and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another Dam
grab your pie in I about the
B is in the lab sit back PO on relax
hold up