yeah what's up cannabis community it's
time for episode number 84 of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
let's write up your new grower and if
you're a professional grower recruit a
new smoker or a veteran dabber if you're
a cannabis activists or even someone
who's just curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host Rasta Jeff thanks again
for joining me as always I want to send
a huge thank you shout out to the mystic
roots band they let me use their music
on the show and I really appreciate it
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew hope everyone's having
a great day sitting across the table for
me today is our good buddy white Mike
how you doing brother doing good man how
you doing I am doing great had a quick
day at work had some time to record I
thought I'd have you come over and throw
out a podcast before you go do your
activism stuff you do all right we've
got just enough time to get an episode
quickly but we'll get it going we'll
kind of get to the point here so Mike's
here we're gonna do some news doing some
news doing some news stuff before we get
too far I do have to do one quick add
this podcast is brought to you by hydro
indoor growing supplies hi Gro indoor
growing supplies has two locations in
Colorado they have a Denver location it
is 60 to 71 Beach Street or you can go
to my favorite store it's the Pueblo
location on 618 East 4th Street in
beautiful Pueblo Colorado check out
high-growth they do have great pricing
they've got a great selection of indoor
growing supplies you can get your
favorite nutrients at high grow and also
when you are checking out make sure you
let them know that you listen to the
girl from your heart podcast and they
will give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that'll save you a lot
of money love that commercial pricing oh
it's such a fat hookup it's actually a
better hookup than what the employees
pay or what the employees yeah what they
pay on products so they have been trying
to use my coupon code so Big Shot it's a
high grill for making the show possible
they really help me out every month also
before I go too far and it leaves my
mind I want to give a huge shout out to
a guy by the name of Brian Meyer I'm not
sure if it's Meyer or Mayer
Brian big shout out much appreciation
Brian hit that PayPal donation button
and threw a few bucks at the podcast so
that will help us with some upgrades I'm
working on getting a portable recording
device
I want the Zune h6 so that I could take
the show on the road a little bit more
my recording gear that I have now is
kind of bulky a little cumbersome yes
but the device I'm looking at will be
able to go to any event will be able to
go anywhere on the fly I'll keep it in
my backpack
we'll have podcasts coming from all
kinds of crazy places to those donations
helped a lot that will work out in the
very near future hopefully if anybody
out there wants to sponsor the podcast
just send me an email let's go from your
heart at hotmail.com I'll get you all
the information you need we can get your
product advertised to a target audience
of about 5,000 people per week plus all
the people that go back and listen to
the catalogued episodes so it's really
good idea to advertise with a
cannabis-related podcast because I think
that's all the advertising I've got I've
got some news articles hear the current
news Mike informed me of today was the
day that the Colorado Department of
Public Health and Environment actually
decided to deny PTSD as a qualifying
condition for medically recommended
cannabis in the state of Colorado
so in Colorado there are eight
qualifying conditions and all eight of
them were passed by the law back in 2000
so the CDP aichi hasn't added a single
qualifying condition and all that time
and this is the third time they've
denied PTSD you know I think PTSD is
definitely a qualifying condition it's
[ __ ] that they're not allowing that
it definitely should be and how many and
hour days work in the counter how many
people came in specifically saying I've
got PTSD marijuana out so much I love
that you guys are here absolutely so are
we is the Colorado Department of Public
Health and Environment basically giving
their finger to veterans and telling
veterans to go drink alcohol instead of
consuming cannabis to help themselves
that's basically been the effect of
their policy for the last decade or so
so guys what they were trying to do is
people that have PTSD they were trying
to get that as a qualifying condition to
get your medical marijuana
recommendation
from the doctor here in the state of
Colorado and it has been denied three
times now we cannot get post-traumatic
stress disorder as a condition that is
qualified that could be treated with
medical marijuana and it's not just vets
there's a lot of people out in the
community that have pts or PTSD and
marijuana helps a lot of them and now
they can't can sit down and talk to
their doctor about using cannabis
directly for that they'd have to if they
wanted to join the medical program have
to have one of the other eight
qualifying conditions or at least here
they can still visit the REC market and
just pay a lot more than they would in
our medical right which doesn't allow
them to grow the product that they need
you know that's that's a big part of
having your medical marijuana card is
being able to grow or being able to
assign a caregiver to grow for you
that's a big part of it right trying to
do three plants in your backyard or if
that's allowed in your area and whatnots
just brutal difficult already if you're
already suffering PTSD like now you've
got to protect yourself from you know
all the paranoia that comes with growing
my right for the first time you know I
think a large portion of the population
has some form of post-traumatic stress
disorder
whether it be childhood trauma anything
you can see something very little when
you're a child and that you're a
psychology kid a psychology student
something really little when you're a
kid can really [ __ ] you up permanently
if you don't take it right there was a
study looking at kids and some of the
rougher parts of Chicago and it was like
80% of the kids exhibited some symptoms
of PTSD and a lot of people started
calling it just they've dropped the D
and so it's no longer disorder it's just
post-traumatic stress it's what the
human body and brain does after a
seriously traumatic incident sometimes
in a lot of people coming home from war
or that have witnessed domestic violence
or been victim domestic violence or have
seen car crashes somebody I've seen
somebody die in a car crash and it's in
the back of my mind every time we're on
the highway I always get a little
flashback of that and I don't like
u-turns for the same reason yeah you've
told me that amazing story there yep
yeah so what I was headed for is I was
gonna imply that I don't know what event
it is but I know there's some sort of
post traumatic
stress in my mind from my life and
that's why I said everybody's probably
got it so I don't have a significant
event that I can recall but I have seen
some [ __ ] and I know that when I feel
even if you've got stress of the day
when you smoke it distracts you and it
calms that part of your brain down and
it allows you to not obsess on that
thought and lets you kind of break free
of that a little bit the big thing a lot
of the people that I know that we're
treating their PTSD with cannabis would
talk about is the dreamless sleep that
was the big benefit that they talked
about at least when they were in the
shop so it would stop their dreams yep
it's uh I mean I haven't
I barely dream and I attribute that to
cannabis use because when I don't smoke
I have very vivid dreams just regularly
that's odd because people have asked me
what I like to smoke and I say I like to
smoke a heavy heavy sativa right before
bed because it makes my mind do that
laundry thing and so I close my eyes and
I feel like I just dream instantly
because I'm already right there at that
thing you know what I mean could you
smoke that really high head high sativa
and I just close my eyes and then my
dreams or claymation and they just
happen as soon as my eyes closed and
then I sleep really well on a heavy
sativa and I have huge dreams from it so
that's kind of strange that it stops
other people's dreams which I'm not
gonna argue that if it's working for
them that's amazing do the right well I
asked you one day like you still dream
bro and you looked at me like offended
like of course why would no I have an
amazing dream isn't yeah I I just
assumed that that the effect was
something you got to cuz you consume way
more than me sometimes I can control my
dreams a little bit but if I get too
carried away I wake myself up but so I
know I'm like don't influence this dream
too much but also kind of guided a
little like but if I if I push too hard
I wake myself up out of the dream no I
haven't had a dream like eight years
that's beautiful oh man I dream
constantly I wake up talking oh [ __ ] or
something like that out of a dream right
yeah it's funny alright so if you guys
are working on getting medical marijuana
in your area in your state please while
you're writing the bills while you're
writing the rules please put in some
sort of a clause that includes
post-traumatic stress disorder it's not
something that you can see but it is
something that definitely exists we need
it for our veterans more than anything
but it's also for everybody let's
be fair out there you guys yeah not all
medical conditions are visible that's
something you got to keep in mind right
the bill well we uh we here in Colorado
all assume that the CD Phe would be
willing to add other conditions to the
lists of currently accepted conditions
over time but there's been countless
applications at this point I can't
remember how many but it's like 15 or 20
Wow
PTSD has been up three times and they've
denied everything just flat-out nope not
at this time there's not enough research
showing that there is you know a general
effect and there isn't research done
because it's not allowed yet not enough
research unless you're to a veteran harm
you can't do your research until very
very like within the last few months
recently so these studies are being
drawn up now they will be conducted in
the next year or seven the you know
findings will be out and become public
knowledge ten years from then okay and
we're just gonna keep letting people
suffer or I mean at least in Colorado
they can use the rec market or right I
mean it's not like the black-market ever
wonder what way here it has had to step
up its game considerably to continue to
compete but it will never decent options
and then once the vet has the bud here
in Colorado it's legal again so all
right so it's no good here but we didn't
take a step forward today and that sucks
that's yeah we stayed we stumbled over
our own dicks once again so make sure
you guys include the PTSD when you write
your new medical marijuana bill that's
my main point here and the next time it
comes up that we're trying to vote on
this make sure you support it because I
fully think that PTSD is a qualifying
condition get registered to vote
marijuana will be on your ballot in the
next two years yes it will yes it will
if it's not on the ballot in 2015 vote
anyway and just practice that [ __ ] there
you go be ready for 2016 because it will
then so we talked a little bit in the
last episode about the desire for Denver
voters to want consumption in some
establishments where people are over 21
and they're not smoking inside on where
is the date okay it was July 9th the
cannabis posted an update to that
article and
says Denver voters favor limited pot use
in bars
it says Denver marijuana poll a majority
of voters in the city support an
initiative that would allow limited pot
use no indoor smoking at businesses over
21 businesses such as bars so it's been
voted on this article was written by
Ricardo Baca from the cannabis staff I'm
a skip part of it because we just need
to get to the point here but it says a
majority of Denver voters support an
initiative that would allow limited
social marijuana consumption in
businesses such as bars according to a
poll commissioned by the group behind
the proposal the cannabis has learned
exclusively I kind of read that weird
but I think you got it yeah the people
that wrote up the bill paid for a poll
and the poll says voters are gonna
support it so fingers crossed it I mean
they're there poll doesn't if you're
really into politics their poll it says
that voters supported by 56% if they add
in the people that are totally not gonna
[ __ ] vote is that really give a [ __ ]
they're just like sure whatever would
support that but I'm gonna go support
that I would but there's television on
that night so net but I don't I hope it
passes in 2015 the need for this is huge
it's huge but the poll data does not
look favorable right now if more of us
don't get politically active true well
they actually says the poll results say
only 56 percent of likely Denver voters
either strongly support or somewhat
support the initiative according to the
democratic firm Public Policy Polling so
56% isn't a bold number that's nope
that's six percent away from losing yeah
and when you really look at the polling
data it's something like thirty percent
are like gung-ho about it in twenty six
percent don't give a [ __ ]
it says here for those against the
initiative 31% strongly oppose and nine
percent somewhat opposed it while five
percent said they weren't sure right it
was an automated telephone poll and it's
got a margin of error of three point
nine percentage points so this is just a
telephone poll people on the telephone
will say that they will do anything cuz
all you got to do is sit there and press
one for yes and two for no and three for
English right that's all they had to
worry about so yeah a lot of these
people probably won't come
and vote so the pollsters asked whether
voters would support allowing the
consumption of marijuana at private
venues in Denver provided that the owner
of the venue permits the consumption
access to the venue is limited to
individuals 21 years of age of older and
smoking marijuana indoors is prohibited
and any outdoor uses hidden from public
view that's all fair that makes sense
it's really not that but it's that of a
bill and it's fairly sorry guys dabs and
soda yeah um it's a pretty fair bill you
got to be outside and it's got to be 25
feet from wherever public gather so what
I'm envisioning is a shitload of roof
deck type establishments in Denver where
they just there's a couple of bars that
we're already doing this and if you felt
like being outside you couldn't smoke up
there tobacco or usually the last time I
was up there but now they're gonna allow
marijuana up there or at least 25 feet
away from the public so like in a model
back courtyard that's all fenced off
yeah there are several like servantes
servantes other side in Denver has got
the perfect little area for smoking that
would be sweet what's that other place
where we go to that there are a lot of
clubs up there that have nice little
outdoor areas that would be beautiful to
smoke in which to smoke yeah so just let
us do it they said that they're
gathering 5,000 signatures to get the
question on Denver's November ballot
another one of the poll findings that
Denver residents by a 4 to 1 ratio
believe that alcohol causes more
problems in the city than marijuana and
also favors their side of the
contentious issue Denver voters have
made it quite clear that they support
treating marijuana like alcohol said
Mason divert a national pot activist and
one of the primary authors behind
Colorado's original cannabis legalizing
amendment 64 Isis voters approved
measures to I measures to the effect in
2000 what measures to the effect in 2005
2006 2007 and 2012 and so it's not
surprising that we're still seeing such
strong support even among a more
conservative voting population in an
off-year election so people are
supporting it more surprisingly than we
had anticipated even a poll this goods a
little surprising the people who follow
this
so I I mean I wish them the best of luck
if I lived in Denver they'd have my vote
it says in the question that asked
respondents if alcohol or marijuana
cause more problems in Denver 55% said
alcohol 13% said marijuana 26% said both
and 6% were not sure so we're making it
obvious here that alcohol is the problem
in cannabis is the peaceful way to
gather and celebrate and have a good
time and relax the last paragraph of the
article says by more than four to one
margin in Denver voters cite alcohol
over marijuana as a bigger source of
problems in the city said divert anyone
who has spent time in the loto on a
weekend evening or walk down Colfax
Avenue on any given day knows that
alcohol contributes to far more problems
and far more severe problems than
marijuana he said which if you go out on
almost any major city any big city on
the weekends you if you go to the bar
where is that every downtown's got that
one area where there's a nice
congregation of bars and everybody goes
there and about 1 o'clock on Friday
night out of one of the bars erupts a
big ass fight and then after the bar
spills out and they all push this [ __ ]
out of each other and then the cops come
and a few people get arrested and then
you hear about it's Saturday um that
doesn't happen in weed events and if it
does we we shun those people from the
community and they don't come back right
cannabis is a peaceful drug like alcohol
is the problem for sure so I think if
they should if they let us smoke at
clubs and stuff I would go I don't go to
places because I don't drink alcohol
there's no reason for me to be there but
if I can go take a few dad's I'd be more
likely to go to the shows at the local
venues because even though it's not my
kind of music I would go be social if I
could go dab out and have fun there
right we're not antisocial we're just
sick of explaining that we don't drink
yeah I don't I do not want a beer but
thank you and no it's not because I'm
better than you it's because I don't
want to be an [ __ ] I'm a drunken
[ __ ] when I drink I wasn't an [ __ ]
I just don't want the hangover anymore
oh yeah I do the hangover is terrible
yeah I haven't had a hangover in 10
years that's so great alright so when it
comes time to vote you guys I want
everybody that listens to this show that
lives in the 303 and the 72 oh I want
you guys all to go was that right yeah
you got those right
I want you guys to go all of you have to
go vote do legalize consumption in adult
places please do that you start at the
dabs bro I just noticed the Tirpitz
well since you're looking at the Turf x
container I've got a star that says dab
review the other day I went up to
Colorado Springs and I visited my
friends I visited the lovely damsel
hello damsel I hope you're listening I
am so I also visited my good buddy huh
and I saw Jordan and I saw the turkey
boys and I also saw John Randall's jr.
and we all had a good time and I took
Danielle with me and we went up to the
shop and I picked up some tur pecks sour
Durbin sativa and I got a say bro
it is sativa as a mofo I get super
dabbed out when I smoke this [ __ ] you're
looking at me like well let's get a dab
of it the container but herein lies the
problem this [ __ ] was so good done damn
it only lasted a day it lasted one day
that [ __ ] was awesome I really approved
of it so if you guys can get your hands
on these Sauer Durban at Green and
healthy can of green and healthy
wellness in Colorado Springs from turf
bags I would definitely recommend her
pecs is doing some amazing things down
here to the turf ex crew they gave me
they hooked me up with a white and a
black extra extra large turf ex t-shirt
so I am now styled out inter pecs I'm
smoking it I'm wearing it I'm repping it
hard I like it
let me get a dab for myself and then I
get a DAB for you I know you like these
little tiny dabs tiny dab so I've got
stuffs to do tonight it'll be alright
here's a Deb for Mike and wall Mike
takes that dab I'm gonna move ourselves
into the next article here and we will
read some news come on Mike watch was
your buddy all right I got you mic is
muted oh you hear all that echo that
cuts out it's beautiful alright so we
are reaching how much time are we in
alright we're 20 minutes in we're gonna
make this a little bit of a longer
episode the article says this is also
from the cannabis stand it was written
by Gene Johnson of The Associated Press
the headline is one year in seventy
million dollars in pot taxes and other
lessons from Washington on the
sub-headline we get a headline and a sub
headline now in articles it's great the
Internet is [ __ ] up our heads with
250 million
in marijuana sales Washington still has
room to grow as its ninth largest grower
says it's amazing we could be so
successful and unsuccessful at the same
time the article goes on to say
Washington launched its second in the
nation legal marijuana market with just
a handful of stores selling high-priced
pot to long lines of customers a year
later the state has about a hundred and
sixty shops open pot tax revenues have
soared past expectations and sales top
1.4 million dollars per day they're
making 1.4 million dollars per day on
cannabis in Washington right now it also
goes on to San who knows the industry
might even start making some money
Washington pot farmers processors and
retailers have complained all years of
heavy state and federal tax burdens
along with competition from an
unregulated medical marijuana market
have made it difficult for them to do
business but at least some relief is
there as here this month two new laws
take effect one to regulate and tax
medical marijuana and one to cut
Washington's three-level excise pot tax
to a single 37 percent tax that's higher
than Colorado tax yeah that's the big
lesson between Washington and Colorado
is that the free market applies we see
it in Colorado there are a lot of people
that are that have been smoking
marijuana here for 4050 years and the
only time they visit the stores is for
novelty write the occasional selection
for the most part they're still buying
marijuana where they used to because
it's half the price yes yes in
Washington the taxes are so bad that
almost none of the locals are interested
because they're taxing it look 75% it's
like 25 percent three different times
and so by the time it gets to the
consumer at grams like 60 bucks in what
the [ __ ] yeah who's gonna pay that when
you can just go to the dude on the
corner and get it for 12 or 15 right
yeah
okay so article goes on to say despite
some industry gripes and those tweaks to
Washington's legal pot law marijuana
which marijuana law which voters passed
in 2012 to legalize marijuana for adults
over 21 officials and legalization
backers say the state's slow and
deliberate effort to regulate
marijuana has been a success a year
after stores opened on July 8th 2014
here's a look at the state of legal weed
here it says the taxes Washington racked
up more than 250 million dollars in
marijuana sales in the past year roughly
62 million dollars of which constitute
marijuana excise taxes that's beyond the
state's original forecast of 36 million
and when the state and local sales and
other shops other taxes are included the
total payday for the state and local
government tops seventy million dollars
okay so the interesting number there is
the 62 million excise tax in Colorado
the excise tax is what's supposed to pay
that forty million dollars for schools
and we've already crushed in the first
five months of this year last year's
whole year total nice because the
standalone production markets only just
now coming online yeah all the shops had
to produce their own for the longest
time here and so that was the
infrastructure we started with and
because of that that excise tax was real
small here in Colorado and that's the
huge difference between our taxes in
their taxes is by the time it gets to
the Shelf that excise taxes nuts yes
only 10 million of theirs was in sales
tax we collected like 60 or 40 or
something like that in just sales tax I
hope when the nationwide legalization
happens I hope all these crazy taxes are
done away with or adjusted somehow right
it's gimmick it's gonna have to come
back down to reality or they won't
matter so much because they're charging
you thirty six percent tax on a $2 gram
which is entirely feasible which from
there may they're growing a lot of
cannabis right now and in Washington
they may grow more than they're able to
sell is something that I see possibly
happening so that really could happen it
could go really dirty cheap pretty soon
here I don't see how long we've been
recording and we might yeah we're gonna
read the rest of this article and we're
gonna save the yeah I got one more
article we'll get into so the next sub
headline and this article says isn't
legal weed expensive in Washington and
it goes on to say a few growers
harvesting by the first time sorry let
me read it again
cuz it's moving there we go with a few
growers harvesting by the time the first
store just opened the average price of a
gram of legal marijuana sparked
spikes to nearly 30 dollars last summer
about three times the cost in medical
marijuana shops but prices have been
dropping as more weed gets harvested in
fact Washington has harvested 13.5 tons
of marijuana flower intended to be sold
as bud but stores have only sold about
10 tons some of the excess can be turned
into marijuana extracts such as oil but
the harvest has helped drive down the
prices to an average of about 1150 per
gram so I was a little bit right about
that they grew too much and it's getting
cheaper nevertheless that in addition to
tourists eager to visit the city's
historic first legal pot shop his
clientele primarily consists of
customers in the 25 and older range it's
more of an adult demographic but that's
okay says they have jobs and they can
afford to buy the product
the next headline says so what's next
Rick Garza director of the Washington's
liquor board Liquor Control Board soon
to be renamed the liquor and cannabis
board says he's proud of Washington's
efforts at a meeting at the top rep at
meeting the top priorities the Justice
Department laid out when it announced it
would allow Washington Colorado and
other states to regulate marijuana
keeping criminal organizations out of
the industry keeping the marijuana
in-state and keeping pot away from the
kids it goes on to say the state adopted
background checks and financial
investigations of pot license applicants
and capped the total amount of
production to try to keep it in line
with in-state demand while public health
advocates say they wish the state had
done more to stress the potential harms
of pot to teens the state required
strict packaging and labeling
requirements to keep children from
getting into the weed they did the same
thing here we kind of set a little
standard here I think the products that
appeal to kids also remain banned no
marijuana cotton candy or gummy bears
also clawed you can't get the sweets no
bears up there that's terrible I'm sorry
bro
yeah everything here sold them the
childproof packaging so even the candy
bars come in a pill bottle right
essentially so it's not like they look
like what your kids eat or it can be
confused easily yeah so the article
wraps up to say this isn't the first
time people have gone to Oregon to buy
something either because it's cheaper or
because they don't apply sales tax he
said we
for liquor and we see it for tobacco so
they're making a ton of money in
Washington and they may have grown too
much cannabis which is fine because
they're pushing down the prices all
right all right I'm gonna do this one
more article this is also from
Washington I know guys I'm in Colorado
but I like to share the news from all
over the place
this one says Washington cracking down
on unlicensed medical marijuana stores
we don't even have to read the whole
article here because that headline says
it all this articles by Martha Belial
from The Associated Press and I hope I
said your last name bruh he said 15
unlicensed medical marijuana shops in
unincorporated King County are on notice
that they are violating the law gene
County prosecutor Dan Centerburg and
Sheriff John something said Wednesday
that they were cracking down on these
stores after Washington lawmakers
amended initiative 502 to require
licenses for all pot shops the change in
the law brought medical marijuana into
the state licensing and tax scheme satur
Berg said the stores were notified by
mail this week and if they continue to
operate as unlicensed retail outlets for
the black-market they'll face civil and
criminal ramifications so these shops
are not registered and they are
operating like medical marijuana
dispensaries it says the 15 stores that
received a notice include seven in the
white sinner neighborhood two in Skyway
and six in the eastern part of the
county messages left at Northwest
cannabis mark in Seattle and Military
Road holistic and Auburn were not
immediately returned there was no answer
at Pacific coast natural medicine in
Seattle or the solution Renton so these
people are not answering the phones
because they're scared shitless they're
gonna get raided probably they're taking
tax money from the state and operating
in locations that would never be
approved by the LCB he said they are
blight on the neighborhoods they inhibit
that's that's a matter of opinion he
said the federal government is washing
watching how Washington regulates the
marijuana industry and the success of
the law depends on how well local
jurisdictions deal with unlicensed
retail stores in addition to sending
notifications to the 15 stores County
officials have notified landlords that
there's an illegal business operating on
the property he said this means that if
the stores continue to operate illegally
the liquor and cannabis board can go in
and seize all of the product if the
civil options don't work they'll
consider criminal remedies he said we're
not going in heavy-handed on this he
said we're telling them
new scheme has to be followed the days
of the wild wild west are over so we saw
this kind of happen in Colorado this
it's totally still it just happened in
our city like three weeks ago there was
just some dude who was like I could do
this it just opened up a dispensary
essentially out of his house oh that
guy's been going on for a while that guy
also was accused of blasting buds making
BHO out of the buds and selling those
buds that he blasted back on the black
market right and got turned in by people
in the neighborhood or whatever so these
guys have storefronts with advertising
and they're advertising just like a
normal store and now they're gonna
either have to get raided I hope they
don't bring it to that because this is
what sucks you have a state that allows
you to do this and then people like this
don't follow the rules and they [ __ ] it
up for have to go in there and tell them
to shut this down and if they don't
they're gonna get raided bro right the
feds will come in and take all of their
[ __ ] like at this point in Colorado you
just google the rules and then follow
the path laid out and you can have your
marijuana store you just you just follow
the rules and do it or you can just put
a sign in your front yard and get
yourself a whiteboard and a couple of
jars and a cash register and go to town
on your living room away for the cops to
show up and they will show up and you'll
be charged with unlawful distribution of
marijuana you'll be all kinds of stuff
yo all right guys we've been going 30
minutes um that's enough news for the
day hey Mike thanks for coming over bro
yeah man we got to wrap it up pretty
quickly because Mike's got somewhere to
be
let's see what else do we have on the
list here I've got a couple of questions
from periscope I'm gonna save those for
another episode I do need to remind you
guys nature's drain remedies dot-com has
changed their name nature's green
remedies com has a new website make sure
you check out the dank team calm the
dank team dot-com make sure you check
them out I don't have a coupon code for
you yet they're still rebuilding the
website getting everything going so make
sure you check out the dank team com
give them a shout out much love much
respect what's up Yankee I hope you're
listening to this one bro hope
everything is going well for you so make
sure you guys follow me on
periscope dude I have been on periscope
quite a bit my account is just Rasta
Jeff on there all the news you guys have
been hearing not all of it but a good
portion of the news that I've been
bringing to you guys has been getting
tweeted to me from Mike so Mike thanks
for sending me all the news giving us
content happy to bro I've been doing two
shows a week because you've got so much
news content forgot to keep people
informed that's the truth it's so
awesome right like prohibition was it
was just everything like no one
questioned it when we were kids and now
that dam is breaking and if more people
start getting active and more people are
informed we're gonna win we are winning
yeah we're almost the 50/50 line is
almost crossed there are almost more
legal States than unlegal states now yep
which is when that crosses I think
that's when something I listen we broke
the population 50/50 line already nice
it's just the numerical state number now
okay all those there's like a hundred
East Coast states with a gay people in
them yeah because they're the size of
right Enver okay before we get too far I
want to not forget to give shoutouts to
mark dank reveille and Arnie also happy
birthday to my cousin brandy I don't
know if you listen to this show but
brandy I love you I miss you I hope
you're having a great birthday this
comes out on July 16th that is her
birthday so if you guys are smoking a
bowl if you're taking a DAB blowing up
in the air for my cousin brandy right
now she was one of my best friends
growing up she was like my little sister
I love you a bunch so happy birthday
girl
also I'm gonna talk about one more thing
and they were gonna wrap it up dude
there's a guy on Instagram who calls
himself Bobo blaster Co he's got a
website it is furniture dot Big Cartel
dot-com that dude sent me this table
I've only had it set up for a day now I
haven't had a lot of time to play with
it but the time I have had to play with
it I really [ __ ] enjoy it this dude
makes custom coffee tables end tables
he makes bookcases he makes shelves but
he installs an email in your table for
you so I have now got a coffee table
with to email coils coming out of the
end of it I've got two rigs sitting on
the table both of those nails are hot we
can walk over there and Mike and I can
take a DAB side-by-side and choke
together yesterday I took a picture I
had a couple tea
friends adore a couple they already
they're together and they come over and
I told them go take a DAB together you
guys and so you got to go do a couple
dab I thought that was kind of sweet so
he painted the IRA genetics Colorado
logo on the tabletop it's a three foot
long by I think that's about two feet
wide coffee table it's got a little
shelf on the bottom
dude it's super sturdy the e nails work
bro I cannot complain he just smiled big
and yeah it's incredible we're gonna
have to demo it a little bit and really
really give it a try and then we'll do a
real review but it looks at this point I
can say it looks just beautiful and so
far it has worked I've taken several
dabs out of it I've been dabbing out of
it since yesterday he watched me unbox
it on periscope he actually was on I did
a periscope video when I got here I set
it up so Bobo got to watch me so you
guys big shout out to Bobo a blaster
coat check him out on Instagram he's
making furniture with an email built
into it if you don't know what that is
you just got to go check out either his
Instagram or his website it's furniture
like the word furniture with Abbey
furniture dot Big Cartel dot-com and Big
Cartel is just like a website it's like
an Etsy or eBay or something it's just a
retail sales site where anybody can set
up their own store so make sure you
check out burn ature dot Big Cartel com
support my buddy I endorsed this product
I'm gonna put it to good use I'm gonna
beat the [ __ ] out of it I'm gonna play
hard with it and see if I can't break it
we'll do everything we'd normally do
with it and then we'll give them a full
review here in a couple episodes but
make sure you check them out because so
far I think it's a badass but just looks
gorgeous man and that logo across the
top is really really did a really good
job thank you bro I appreciate it I
really do appreciate it it's a great
gift I don't deserve that I looked on
the website to see what he sells these
tables for and I am completely grateful
and appreciative of the gift you have
sent me thank you brother I really
appreciate it all right guys it's time
to start wrapping up the show I've got
some notes here that I like to read
toward the end of the show this should
come out on July 16th that means I will
be back on Monday with a new episode for
you I have a couple of plans to record
with a couple of people tonight so
hopefully they are able to make it big
shout out to
big shot at the slop big shout it to the
garden of Weeden um you guys don't
forget to check out the sponsor hydro
indoor growing supplies also don't
forget to check out the dank team
dot-com
and if you're interested in sponsoring
the podcast but if you have a product
you'd like me to review send me an email
it's girl from the heart at hotmail.com
I will get you all of the information
that you need because the show is over
so now please go to iTunes go to the
iTunes store search for the girl from
your heart podcast find the review
section give me a five star rating and
type in a comment let me know what you
think of the show and I will read your
comment on a future episode I will I
really will read it um if you want to
follow me on all the social media that
would be really awesome it's @gf wih
podcast on twitter it's girl from your
heart on facebook if you want to search
me on Instagram it's Irene genetics I
posted a whole bunch of great cannabis
photography don't forget that every
episode of the podcast the show is
available on iTunes and stitcher and
every single episode is archived on I
read genetics Colorado com if you're on
the website I read genetics Colorado
calm don't forget there's a girl from
your heart podcast tab on the top right
there's that Pay Pal button if you want
to click on there and throw a few
dollars at us we would definitely
appreciate it
I'll never charge you for the podcast
but if you want to make a contribution
to say thank you or to contribute to me
buying the zoom h6 so that we can get
the podcast on the road that would be
definitely appreciated
somebody threw me a few bucks the other
day so we've got a down payment on the
device it's not a huge downpayment but
it's more than we had every little bit
helps it's only it's only four hundred
bucks plus like probably a hundred bucks
worth of accessories so we can pull that
off here before too long yeah we'll make
that happen and then we'll take this
podcast out on the road
um like I said find us on all the social
media sites um dude Mike thanks again
for coming we got to get you out of here
so we can go get to your your event
thanks for getting for listening
everybody until next time take a phat
dab give your mom a hug for me thanks
for listening y'all
[Music]
not a soul mr disturb for the nomination
it is only
[Music]
it's glad the company is only a facial
do all the neighbors who live around the
farmer make your please don't become an
informer even if I survive it by my
count
[Music]
his only occupation
not a soul
[Music]
you