[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the show podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 841 of the
from your heart podcast thanks again for
joining me in today's episode I'm going
to review the dude grov cup that's right
I'm sure you've heard me talking about
it the dude grow cup just happened this
past weekend I'm going to jump into that
right after we talk about the new sale
at idirect decom that's right make sure
you check IR redirect.sh
the same strain they're both Durban
Poison it is Durban Poison number one
and Durban Poison number three those are
the females they've both been pollinated
by the same male that is the BC Lemon
Skunk male I cannot decide which
phenotype I like best the number one or
the number three so I put them both out
as testers you guys can run them see
what comes from your Gardens then that
will help me make my decision but there
is new stuff in stock at I direct.com
make sure you hit I direct.com for that
new stuff all right that's enough
advertising at the start of of the show
I said we're going to talk about the
dude grow cup ladies and gentlemen big
shout out to the dude grow crew uh the
dude Scotty reel Banner Guru uh Maestro
there's going to be a bunch of people
that I don't remember behind the scenes
but you guys all get credit to uh you
guys want to remain in the shadows I
will allow that big fist bump to the
backup crew and the spotlight crew the
entire dude grows the staff the crew and
of course the dude grows crew itself the
army that comes out and of course a big
shout out to the iy Army but let me stay
focused here because I am I've been
sampling all the goodies that people
sent me home with from the dgc cup and I
am well medicated it was a great time uh
big shout out to the crew that threw the
party it was bigger and better than last
year uh the tent was bigger uh there
were more people there were a lot of
great booths a lot of great interaction
going on a lot of great displays there
were full grow tents set up in the
middle so um yeah there were full grow
tents set up under this tent we'll talk
more about that in just a few seconds
but the cup was awesome briefly I'll
tell you about my experience uh it was
Friday afternoon Mike showed up in my
house a little after noon we drove up to
Fort Collins I I expected usually 3 and
1 half hour drive it took us closer to 4
hours and 20 minutes ironically to get
up to our hotel in Fort Collins uh the
interstate was against us I25 wanted
everybody to have a bad day that day we
did not let it stop us uh we kept our
spirits bright uh we kept our heads High
the puffco may have helped with that
operation but we made it to Fort Collins
checked into the hotel honest we walked
in we checked into the hotel we used the
restroom in the lobby and we did not
even go to our rooms we said hey we got
[ __ ] to do uh we went and grabbed a
quick meal I don't even remember where
we went for dinner we went and got quick
food and then after that we headed to
the dude grows pre party that's right
there was a party happening at the uh
dude grows Festival site I don't want to
give away the name of the farm or tell
you exactly where it was cuz some of
that needs to be a secret I think but we
headed to the party site um all I took
in with me that night was a ab and
smoking accessories went in there and we
smoked out we hung out with a bunch of
great people the pre- party was a great
time uh there was a bunch of cool people
there um I don't even want to start
saying names because if I miss people
then I feel bad but Mike and I claimed a
table we found a nice spot kind of right
in the middle a nice level table because
I had my dab rig with me of course it
was on a farm and some of the ground
wasn't completely level I'm not
complaining but I found a table that I
felt comfortable putting my rig on there
uh we got the rig set up we took a bunch
of dabs we hung out with a bunch of
great people Mike and I sat at one side
of the table and mainly uh there was a
couple that sat at the other side of the
table shout out for hanging out you guys
uh but then other people rotated in and
out all night it was a good time uh
people came and smoked people came and
said hello people had some food people
had some drinks people had some snacks
uh people showed me a bunch of great
weed and a bunch of great concentrates
people came and said hi uh that party
went very quickly we wrapped that up and
then we went and got uh some more food
because we were hungry again and then by
that that point Mike and I were both
pretty beat so we headed to our separate
hotel rooms uh where we finished the
night solo and then met each other I was
like I'll meet you right out here again
at 9:30 in the morning bro so we met up
at 9:30 right outside of our hotel rooms
uh we got some coffee cuz Mike needs
coffee I needed a muffin got some quick
snacks and that's when we headed to the
dude grov cup the official day was
Saturday the real party was Saturday you
guys Saturday was a blur we pulled up to
the dgc cup there were a lot of empty
parking spaces we got a nice Prime spot
we loaded in really quickly um I got set
up by 10:30 11:00 um I wanted to start
doing business at noon when the event
started but honestly um come bombard the
table get get early get there early get
the best seeds I'm not shy about it but
here's what Mike and I noticed about
11:15 I pulled out my rig I put water in
that rig about 11:45 I found my Banger
and attached that to the rig about 12:30
I finally found my carb cap around 1:00
I found the dab right I think it was
approximately 2:30 p.m. before my booth
slowed down before it was finally time
for me to be able to take a big fat dab
so I'm not complaining but we got into
the dgc cup around 10: uh we got set up
around 10:30 or 11: I scooped up a dab
and people started showing up at the
booth by 11:15 11:30 we were swamped and
I did not get to take a breath until
approximately 2:30 p.m. so for 3 or 4
hours there we were completely busting
completely busy uh I loved it it was a
good time time so many people came to
the booth and said hello a lot of people
of course bought seeds a lot of people
grabbed that new Golden Girls bundle
that was probably one of the hottest
sellers of the weekend um there were so
many people there wearing iy genetics
and iy army gear big shout out to all
the folks that came out and supported
the IE Army supporting IE genetics I'm
sure many people are wondering I said
there was a free prize or a free gift
for the people wearing the gear I gave
everybody wearing iy Army merchandise a
two pack of cherry skunk feminized SE s
what Cherry skunk fims let me tell you
briefly about that that is Jr's cut of
cherry Paloma of course Cherry Paloma is
from raw genetics Jr found a winning cut
that's been going around a lot of people
love it of course I ended up with the
cut of that and then I hit it with that
skunk number one when I did that skunk
reversal pollinated that cherry Paloma
so we made some cherry skunk seeds I
gave two of those to everybody wearing
iy gear so I'm sure that there are some
grows some households that ended up with
four or six of those seeds cuz if you
came together with your girl or your
best friend all three of you got the
seeds if you're all wearing gear and
then people got six beans I'm sure
people are running those already um I've
Got Friends running them already from
that but I'm sure people from the cup
have already got them sprouted so that's
what the people uh rocking the iy gear
got was a two pack of cherry skunk fem
seeds it smells exactly like you would
think it would smell it's got that
robust cherry citrusy turp and then it's
got that skunk back end on top of it
real nice plants but that's what
everybody got for wearing the gear so
the day went by super super quickly
eventually uh they were like hey guys we
are going to announce the winners of the
event and I was like how is it 5:00
already so they announce the winners uh
big shout out to hot rod hot rod took
fifth place uh I did not recognize any
of the top five winners never heard of
any of them before the uh number one
winning strain was the uh black maple 22
but I do not remember the name of the
grower uh I apologize for not
remembering that I should have had some
notes here but shout out to our boy hot
rod he got either fifth or sixth place
with his biscotti OG good work hot rod
also bro random note our friend hot rod
just moved and relocated you guys don't
get a lot of details cuz that's none of
your business but I want to send a big
shout out to my buddy hot rod hot rod
good luck out there in the new spot I
really do hope everything goes well for
you buddy uh you're still a part of the
army even though you left Colorado I
totally understand where am I I am
rambling so the award ceremony happened
and then after that uh everybody went
the [ __ ] home there was not a lot of
time from here's first place and the
place was empty it emptied out super
quickly a lot of the guys a lot of the
boys a lot of the gang made some plans
to go eat some dinner and do some things
after the event unfortunately it took
Mike and I way longer than anticipated
to pack up the booth of course we were
stoned and rambling and chatting and
having a good time uh I wasn't packing
up at any High rate of speed but we
packed up the booth got it all in the
car and then got out of there uh then we
realized we needed some more food we had
to go get some food so we went hit a a
semi-quick restaurant got some food uh
cleaned ourselves up a wee bit then we
boogied out to Scotty reel's house we
went to the bakery shout out to Scotty
reel for throwing two separate banging
parties in a row possibly three parties
there was a party uh previously that I
did not attend but shout out to Scotty
bro you threw some super good parties
that weekend uh we left the dgc cup went
got food then went to Scotty reels at
the bakery where there were a lot of
super cool people hanging out hot rod
was there blue kiss was there soda was
there um uh Gro was there the dude was
there uh untrained astronaut was there
Rua was there see I'm saying names now
and I know I'm going to forget people
but there were so many people there that
conversation uh Trek dgc was there uh
ballan for life was there um so many
people everybody was there big word was
there Ry even came to the party a bunch
of people were at uh at Scotty re's
house uh even Ricky Bobby was there big
shout out to Ricky Bobby the life of the
party but it was a super chill party at
uh at Scotty re's house we hung out
outside for a little bit on the back
patio uh smoked a little bit then headed
into the bakery where untrained
astronaut turned on the uh leaf blower
filled with weed and smoked us out so
much that my eyes burned a little bit no
offense bro but you toasted me I was lit
after that uh but that was a super good
party eventually Mike and I decided we
were toasted so Mike and I headed back
to our respective hotel rooms uh where I
said I'll meet you back out here in the
morning bro and we woke up the next
morning where uh we traveled to Denver
we just headed down to Denver we got
some food uh we just had a slow start in
morning morning we didn't do anything
real crazy for the start of the day got
moving kind of slow but eventually we
did meet up with a bunch of great people
at meow wolf we went separately they
were already there we were running a
little bit it wasn't late or nothing
we're just we'll see you there kind of
folks uh but a bunch of great people
were at meow wolf we met up with a lot
of the dgc crew the IE Army there um
just kept running into different people
that we did not even know was there uh
crazy hands was there uh blue kiss
Gardens was there Rua was there uh Becca
even showed up uh there's a lot of great
people that roamed around meow wolf I
saw more people in and out as people
came in uh that was pretty cool bumping
into iy Army uh people were noticing
that there was a big group there that uh
wasn't just because we all knew each
other and the other patrons of the place
were starting to look at us like who are
these guys uh we ended up hanging out in
uh there's a lounge in meow wolf called
sips we ended up hanging out in there
they have some mocktails I had a
mocktail no stress here I don't drink
alcohol but the mocktail was delightful
uh Mike had a limit we hung out and then
we called it a day you guys eventually
uh Mike and I were beat it had been a
long weekend my throat was starting to
hurt my voice was getting dead my social
battery was running out and I said hey
Mike we got a two-hour drive home buddy
and he looked at me he said let's Boogie
so we hopped in the car and we headed
south and I got home and the stubborn
guy and me took two fat dabs and went to
a drum circle that night what I know
crazy right I ended up at the poblo drum
circle at pillars Park come hang out one
time you guys it's a party um I was
useless at the Circle usually I'm high
energy have a lot of input a lot of
creativity I was slow bro I was not
killing it that night but that ladies
and gentlemen is the quick version of
how Mike and I did the dude grows cup no
grow information in there that was all
just ramble and chatter but the cup was
awesome it was a great experience in my
opinion the whole time was a good time I
wish I could uh do more I feel like I'm
behind my booth the whole time I did get
out from behind the booth and go explore
for a brief moment I did not even pee at
the dgc cup you guys that's how busy I
was but it was an amazing event next
time I'll make more an effort of an
effort to get out and do more go say hi
to more people a lot of people come and
say hi to me I saw so many friends but
there's people I need to go say hi too
shout out to durbs what's up buddy it
was good seeing you big shout out to
Duke Diamond he stopped by the booth and
said hello as well ah good to see you
brother um let's follow up on the plans
that we've made that's right Duke and I
have spoken about some plans you never
know what could happen there um I smoked
so many joints that uh I'm recording
later in the weekend my voice is still
raspy if I talk into the mic real slow
you could hear it it's in there I got
some Berry White going on ah that is all
dgc cup raspiness there I'm not sick I
don't have a cold sinuses feel good
usually I get the sinus Funk when I go
into a big group like that sinuses are
good this is just all dab throat so
that's a good thing I can fix that um
big shout out to everybody that brought
me a gift I came home with a ton of
great gifts so thank you guys for all of
the gifts um I got weed I got
concentrates I got some toys and prizes
I got some homemade things uh shout out
to Delila for the homemade gifts that
she sent me I really do appreciate both
of those uh but um one of my favorite
gifts and I'm not going to choose
favorites here and talk about it on the
show but my favorite gift bro I totally
going to do it was the lemon Jeffrey
concentrate from my buddy Frosty
McNuggets hey bro I'm drooling I'm
shaking I need a little bit more you got
some more of that lemon Jeffrey dabs I
need some more of that bro you hit me up
let's work out something let's make a
deal is what I think they say but the uh
Frosty McNuggets is lemon Jeffree
concentrate that [ __ ] was hot fire I do
need some more um one of my favorite
parts of the dgc cup you guys everybody
took a bunch of weed and everybody was
trying to be friendly and everybody was
trying to be generous like want some of
the weed that I grew would you like some
of my weed and everyone's like but I
have a quarter pound of weed too So
eventually at one point I decided I'd
grab a handful of small nuggets and just
throw one nugget at a time at my friends
there the whole iy Army was set up on
either side of me there's a picnic table
that we moved over and codered to make
part of our little smoke sash I just
started pegging people with nuggets and
then guess what they started pegging me
back and we had a weed War was pretty
fun uh you know it's a good Festival
when you can just throw weed at your
friends and just toss weed around and
leave a bunch of weed in the field when
you're done and not be stressed about it
Growers love that was a good time the
weed tossing party was a real good time
um I got to meet a lot of people from
the iy army that I had never met in
person before and people that I had met
that my brain doesn't remember because I
smoke too much and have a traumatic
brain injury so good seeing a bunch of
people shout out to the guy with the
cool dunks uh shout out to the guy who
started a breeding company to honor his
Fallen friends friend I truly uh loved
and appreciated and respected your story
um so many cool ass people um I'm trying
to follow my notes but I'm so way off
track here big shout out to everybody
for all the love and the fist bumps I
met a lot of fellow podcasters I got to
meet Chad Westport uh Chad's even cooler
in person he's just as tall as me in
person um shout out to Chad Westport
it's cool to meet that dude uh I met I
can Matt from I Canabis I cannabis Matt
uh not as tall as me but a super cool
dude bring good brings Good Vibes uh and
a dresser I definitely noticed a a dude
with some some dressing skills also I
got to meet Michigan Matt Michigan Matt
came to his booth and introduced himself
stuck his hand out like a gentleman and
said Jeff I wanted to come by and
introduce myself that was good to see
that dude uh so cool meeting fellow
podcasters also fellow podcaster I got
to hang out with blue kiss Gardens of
course I've met her before I know blue
kiss but she did get to come to the
event hang out a little bit uh harass us
a little bit if you will everybody loves
blue kiss's energy at the event also
shout out to a couple of my friends who
drove from New York I don't know if you
guys want your name said but I'm going
to call you R and W uh I'm going to call
one of you bubble lungs Because by the
end of the event bro your lungs sounded
like the bong when you spoke but shout
out for driving all that way you guys
it's great to uh one of those guys
doesn't know a lot about the Army he
just kind of got introduced into the
crew he's my friend for a while we know
each other from fish shows he drove all
the way from New York to come out to the
dgc cup that was super cool shout out to
those boys uh shout out to Bri and
Quinton people that I always look
forward to seeing at the dgc cup to they
went by so quickly you guys the booth
was hopping I got to see a lot of great
people lots of fist bump lots of
handshakes lots of hugs lots of selfies
if we took a selfie if we took a photo
together please send it to me or post it
and tag me uh I want to see those I want
to repost those I love those moments I
save those I'm a Cheesy guy like that
but please do send me that I want to
send a big thanks to my buddy Mike for
helping me at the booth Mike well I
could not have done all that [ __ ]
without you um stop by let's take some
dabs I owe you dabs and some more than
dabs share some of these gifts I got
with you holy [ __ ] some great gifts uh
big thanks to Ry dog Ry wasn't even
supposed to help at the booth but he saw
that we were busy and he helped in uh he
knows my seeds he knows me real well so
he jumped in and helped out thank you
bro uh big thanks to all the dgc the
[ __ ] dgc makes it awesome without the
dgc I would just be a guy standing there
uh with the booth you guys make it all
worth setting up all that stuff taking
all the gear carrying all those shirts
loading up all the stuff takes a long
time to prepare for the event I package
a bunch of seeds I had special packs
made just for you guys so big thanks to
the dgc for inviting me for having me
for treating me uh like family and
thanks to the iry Army for showing up
strong and bringing all the support then
of course once again uh big shout out to
the dude uh it's got your name on the
festival bro big shout out bro really
thank you for the party thanks for the
invite thanks for the love and respect
the podcast camaraderie the Grower's
love and just the Bros ship man I
appreciate it uh also same to Scotty
reel uh real quick I want to send a big
shout out to my buddy Scotty reel also
shout out to Gro Gro uh keep the show
going my bro and stay funny my dude uh
also big shout out to Banner for trying
to keep [ __ ] organized and then also big
shout out to J Maestro for spelling
everything correctly all right I think
that's what I've got next year you guys
I vote for a 2day event I want a two-day
dude grows cup next year that's right
two days maybe even three days let's do
a Friday night pre- party uh just like
we've been doing do a pre-party Friday
night drop off all the samples uh then
sat Saturday and Sunday we've got more
time to focus on sampling all the
samples and also I know you've heard
about it but I would agree and
appreciate and endorse a concentrate
event involved in the dude grows Growers
cup all right that is my review that is
my update that is my opinion of the dude
grows Growers cup once again thanks to
everybody who came out stopped by the
booth said hello bought a pack of seeds
grabbed a t-shirt even if you just came
and set high and didn't buy anything big
shout out big thank you I appreciate it
it was a great weekend for everybody I
look forward to seeing you next year if
you did not make it to the dude grows
Growers cup have no fear because next is
the secret stash let me grab my phone
and verify the date of the event cuz I
said the wrong date in my head recently
and I don't want to do that to you
because I like you kind folks the secret
stash is happening in Denver Colorado
June 22nd that's right it's a much
different event than the dgc cup very
very different um this is a much shorter
event a much smaller event um you were
given a shopping window when you buy
your ticket you were given a 1H hour
time slot you were LED in the building
for that 1 hour you can visit all the
booths you'd like then you were politely
uh what is it called escorted out the
back door uh and then that is where you
are welcome to the party there's a bunch
of boots outside where you can get um I
hope that the cheesecake guys is out
there big shout out to Bubba cheesecakes
uh and various food trucks and vendors
outside but the inside seed breeder area
is a very quick uh very quick shopping
experience you get a 1hour window which
is enough time you guys but it speeds
you up it gets it going and it makes
things much easier for the vendors uh
then we can re meet capacity without
keeping that building too crowded a lot
of advantages to these sort of events in
my opinion it gives me a minute to rest
between phases also uh the first hour
goes through at like 11: or noon after
that hour I get a five or 10 minute
break to clean up the booth take a drink
take a dab take a piss if I need to uh
all of that stuff makes for a better
event so uh the secret stash uh June
22nd in Denver Colorado uh if you want
information there should be a link in
the show description or the video
description or show notes I'll put a
link in there uh big shout out to the
secret stash we look forward to seeing
you in Denver how long have we been
going all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls I'm going to make this
just a dgc uh cup Experience episode all
I'm going to talk about is the dgc cup
in this show I'm going to wrap this up I
want to thank everybody for listening
thanks for hanging out uh make sure you
check out the patreon campaign at
patreon.com fromy yourheart you can grab
iy genetic seeds at idirect
docomo fromy yourheart hotmail.com I'm
going to make it a quick episode thanks
for hanging out I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to my buddy Braden
leatherberry and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad mother
time to take another Dam grab your pie
in about the
B is in the lab sit back relax hold up