[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother yeah welcome to the podcast
everybody I'm your host rosta Jeff this
is episode 842 of the grow from your
heart podcast you know I've got another
fun episode lined up for us in today's
show I'm going to give away free seeds
hang out we'll talk about those free
seeds later on in today's episode if you
were listening to this episode the day
it comes out that would be Saturday June
22nd today is the day of the secret
stash that's right big shout out to our
friends groovy gravy for throwing the
secret stash event in Denver Colorado
that event will be happening in the
Rhino district there are a lot of great
events happening in the Rhino District
today stop by the secret stash say hello
if you come by the booth and let me know
that you heard this message on the
podcast I will give you a free prize I
do look forward to seeing you at the
secret stash if you would like to stay
updated when there are more events like
the secret stash or the dude Groves Cup
coming up all you have to do is go to my
website and join the mailing list if you
scroll down to the bottom of the website
there's a tab that says stay up to date
type in your email address hit send you
will then join the mailing list when
there are events coming up I will send
out a newsletter and let you know what
where IR genetics will be you can come
out you can grab some seeds in person
you can give me a fist bump and possibly
get a free prize for knowing the secret
password for listening to the podcast to
join that mailing list go to my website
it is IR genetics.com that mailing list
tab will be down at the bottom scroll
down type in your email address hit send
and you will get updates you will also
get updates when I do fresh drops when I
put out new releases when I do a sale I
like to keep you updated when I have
things going on with ir genetics.com or
I direct so join that newsletter on IR
genetics.com the most recent newsletter
that I sent out was about a blowout sale
on redirect.sh
so what I have done is I've put all
those packs on sale on blowout pricing
on
redirect.sh while they are on blowout
pricing uh they will never be this cheap
again so make sure you go hit I redirect
and support that inventory reduction
sale that will go either until the end
of the month or until packs are sold out
then at the start of the month I will
restock uh there will be new pricing and
new products so if things are running
low uh things you're not looking for in
stock come back in the first of the
month and there will be a lot of new
things and a lot of restocks and new
pricing so hit edirect dcom also join
that newsletter on IR genetics.com to
stay up todate for that fresh drop all
right I think that covers all of the
business to be done here at the start of
the podcast let's work our way into the
question and answer portion of today's
show I do have a bunch of great emails
here in front of me these emails do come
from the growel tab on my website that's
right iry genetics.com is my main
website on the top of that website there
is a row of tabs one of those tabs does
say grow help or grow questions if you
click on that tab we do give you the
opportunity to send me your grow
question if you send me a question and I
read that question here on the podcast
you will receive a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at idirect decom
today's first question came from
somebody who wants to be called Vista
Del Loco big shout out to my buddy Vista
Del Loco thank you for the great
question make sure you check your inbox
because you do have a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at
iirc the question from my new friend
goes just like this it says yo roster
Jeff I've got a breeder and etiquette
question this is a great question and a
great way to kick off a podcast I do
appreciate this it says I want to grow
my own strain for myself and I want to
give it to my friends and family I would
like to say this is a strain that I made
I understand that that's kind of how I
got started there was a lot of pride in
making my first strain and um I made the
seeds I selected a male I selected a
female I put them together they made
seeds I had to wait a long time for
those seeds to be ready it felt like
forever then they were ready then the
best part was growing those and then
when my friends were smoking it they're
like bro what is this and I was like bro
I bred that I made that nobody else ever
will have that because that is my [ __ ] I
completely understand the pride the
enthusiasm and the excitement behind
this idea and I fully support it and I
want you to do it so let me give you
some guidance here it says do I just
take a male from raw genetics and a
female from iry genetics and voila I
made my own strain um kind of yes and I
actually I recommend those two breeders
those are uh raw and myself that our
stuff works well together I have bread R
strains together other people in the
group in the community have bread R
strains and it does work very well um
and I like the idea that you want to
start with two different breeders that
is a great way to get started you're
putting two totally different flavor
Petes two uh wide openen projects
together putting that together to make
your own stuff that is a great start but
uh voila did I make my own strain then
he follows up he says is it piggybacking
off of others how do I start without
ripping someone off for lack of better
term thanks for your time so I
understand what you're heading for and I
appreciate the forethought the sight the
courtesy the etiquette involved in this
question so if you just want to make
these seeds for yourself if you don't
ever plan to uh sell these seeds if you
don't want to go to market if you don't
want to be a seed producer a retail
seller um you can just take plant a and
plant B throw them together make seeds
and enjoy that is fine that is how it
all starts a lot of breeders um are kind
of picky they get a little pissy a
little whiny uh they act like little
[ __ ] to be honest with you when you
breed with their work I don't find that
to be reasonable uh they bred with other
people's work they did not invent I did
not we did not invent cannabis none of
us breeders on the market today and the
past or in the future invented this
plant We Are all uh stewards of this
plant we are all here to represent this
plant in the best way that we can uh
none of us invented it so uh you're
welcome to breed with my seeds raw
genetic seeds any other breeder out
there you are welcome and allowed to
breed with their seeds especially if you
just want to make something for yourself
for the basement for your grow uh to
smoke with the homies to say I did this
I'm proud now if you want to go a little
bit further if you ever plan on selling
these seeds there is a little more
etiquette involved in here um at that
point I would take a male and a female
and this is just um this is also this
used to be and I'm not sure if James
Bean still is if this is his requirement
but James Bean is the uh founder of
seeds here now and if a breeder
approaches him and he did what you said
just took raw and iy and threw him
together and made a seed uh James Bean
would probably tell you I don't want to
vend those seeds do a little bit more
work because here is what probably
possibly kind of should be done uh just
with a little bit of etiquette this is
in my opinion a step that you should
possibly do just to give yourself some
credit some validity in this breeding
project take your plant a and plant B
like you plan to do grow them out find a
male or a female that you really love
but I recommend find a male to start
with and use that male to pollinate
other plants that you really enjoy so
create your own maale and then use that
maale to do some work with and then
you've made you've done some work with
my gear and with Brad from raw you've
taken our stuff and made something which
is cool that's our work put together you
did that but then find a mail out of
that and put that to some other [ __ ]
maybe one of my other strains one of
Brad's other strains and then even do
one of somebody else's other strains I
don't know Mr Soul pick a a a Brother's
Grim strain and pick a Jinx Proof strain
and breed your creation to four or five
other breeder stuff just to Branch it
out a little bit and put some work
behind it don't just take the the blue
paint from Sherwin Williams and smear on
canvas and say I painted take that blue
paint mix it with some green paint and
then smear that [ __ ] on canvas then you
kind of did something if you take that
blue and green and mix it together and
then you paint a stripe and put a red
stripe next to it now you're making some
art of your own that's the best way that
I think I can kind of explain that now
there are a lot of breeders out there um
that are going to throw a fit a lot of
breeders will get upset if you breed
with their gear and put their seeds to
Market some of those breeders I may
reach out to them if you want to I'm not
going to even list who they are um
let's talk about the the Jack the Ripper
that I bred with I breed with a Jack the
Ripper male that Jack the Ripper is uh
subcools male that is not I did not make
that but I use that male in my breeding
project how do I feel ethical about that
how do I feel okay selling those seeds
first of all uh rest in peace subcool
subcool passed away he's not using it
anymore he's not going to sell those
seeds um he's not losing anything off of
me uh recreating or keeping that plant
alive subol and I had a lot of great
conversations he taught me a lot of
great things about the plant about the
industry uh about life he taught me a
lot of what to do also you guys know
very well subcool taught me a lot of
what not to do he was a good example for
this industry there was no map or no
road map of how to do these businesses
and subcool kind of showed me how to do
it in his own way he didn't teach me the
business I learned it by watching uh but
subcool was a big influence to me let me
get myself back on track but subcool was
my friend subcool was my mentor subcool
taught me a lot of things uh subcool
taught me what to do and what not to do
in this industry so when subcool passed
I wanted to honor subcool and I felt
that Jack the Ripper should be continued
it's something that it's an amazing
strain it need to keep it need to be out
in the world still it didn't need to
disappear just because sub was gone and
it was a way for me to honor my friend
subcool take his Jack the Ripper plant
use the mail make another uh generation
of Jack the Rippers and put that to my
stuff so that subcool and I could uh
collab so I used that Jack the Ripper I
used that male to make further Jack the
Ripper generations and then I also used
that Jack the Ripper mail to outcross to
my stuff to do some collabs with subcool
after he passed to show love to subcool
now something I did out of respect out
of etiquette um that I just felt was
right uh to the industry to the business
to my relationship to the plant uh to my
relationship to subcool I reached out to
subcools um they were divorced when he
passed away so I'm not sure the
technical word there I'm going to say
widow um I reached out to subcool's
Widow and business partner Miss Jill and
I said hey uh Jill Subs gone I want to
breed with Jack the Ripper may I have
your blessing to do so so I reached out
to uh the person that was closest to
this plant and said hey I know this is
part of your company can I breed with
this and Jill politely said hey Subs
gone I don't want Jack the Ripper that's
fair game do what you would like to do
thank you for reaching out so big shout
out to Jill for giving me the blessing
to breed with Jack the Ripper now where
I'm headed with this is there are a few
breeders out there that are are publicly
pissy about people breeding with their
work they talk about it on the internet
they talk about it online if you choose
to breed with some of their work maybe
reach out and say hey whoever breeder uh
I plan on breeding your plant to this
plant uh what is your protocol what is
your etiquette they could be a total
dick about it they could be cool about
it if you're going to sell those seeds
they may have a problem with it but like
I said before they don't own cannabis
bro they did not invent cannabis ask
them where they got the plants and seeds
that they started their breeding company
with they used some we all every one of
us I don't care how far back we go every
one of us breeders that is selling seeds
is using somebody else's plants
somewhere in the line none of us
invented cannabis plants we didn't fart
a plant out of the sky we didn't
manifest one we didn't AI generate one
we didn't 3D print one we used a plant
that's somebody else bread somewhere
along the line so to say that you can't
work with somebody else's gear and sell
seats is uh hypocritical in my mind and
also uh I love the healing aspect the
community the uh the cannabis plant more
than I care about uh intellectual
property rights there are some things I
do care about don't steal my strain
names uh don't steal my artwork don't be
a dick like that but cannabis seeds get
them out there grow them uh get those
everywhere breed them make more get
everybody growing get everybody growing
the best ganja that they possibly can
that's the whole point of this podcast
overgrow the government grow the best we
can get everybody on top of the cannabis
plants all right I'm [ __ ] super
rambly I wish I remembered what I smoked
before this podcast cuz I would tell you
and you could get some too and you could
feel as good as I do uh my dude Vista
this was a great question but like I
said um if you take plant a plant B
breed them together you've made your own
project if you're satisfied with that
also uh make a a predictive goal before
you do this write down a goal and say I
want these plants I hope these plants do
this then you know if you hit your goal
if you hit your goal you got something
to brag about that is your first cross
you you can claim it I would then find a
male out of that uh maybe even find a
female and F2 it but the first thing I
would do find a boy and then hit some
other girls and that is your breeding
project right there that you can talk
about that is your true work so um yes
the first run counts the second one is
when you can actually do something with
those seeds if you choose to my dude
thank you for the great question you got
me rambling quite well make sure you
check your inbox because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iy direct.com all right let's keep this
moment I'm going I've got another great
question here in front of me this one
also came from that growel tab on
edirect decom this one came from my
buddy mik D shout out to Mike D make
sure you check your inbox because once
again you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at idirect tocom the
question from my buddy Mike D goes a
little bit like this it says yo roster
Jeff I am in week seven of flower and I
would like to try to change my light
cycle back to the 186 schedule which you
promote it's a very good idea I endorse
that I recommend it I think you'll be
happy with it it says when I switch this
up what DLI should I shoot for
everything I read about says a shorter
light cycle in flower is better and I
don't want to damage my plants or waste
extra electricity if it's not necessary
thanks for all you've taught me and I
appreciate you uh this is a great
question let me recap really quickly
what I'm talking about then I'll explain
my reply my response my answer here now
let me recap a little bit about this
question in case you're new to the the
podcast for a while now I've been
recommending a new light schedule toward
the end of the flowering cycle when most
people would begin to flush I don't know
if you flush or not that's a whole
another topic a whole another podcast
but when most people would begin to
flush that last 10 to 14-day period of
your flowering period I recommend
changing the light cycle we should be on
probably a 1212 cycle for flowering what
I recommend is changing that light cycle
to 18 hours on and 6 hours off now most
people when they hear this the first
time they think I am completely crazy
I've been called a lot of prime words
because of this idea but the only people
that think this is a bad idea are the
people who have not tried it the people
who have done this have all reported
great results with the 18 hours on and 6
hours off at the end of the flowering
cycle my theory here my theory is that
light is the number one source of energy
for our plants at the end of the
flowering cycle why wouldn't we give our
plants as much light as we possibly can
to beef them up when they get more light
they can photosynthesize more they're
going to get bigger they're going to get
beefier and they're going to finish a
little bit more quickly because there's
just more process happening so a lot of
people are going to say won't that cause
your plants to rev no because we're
going to cut them down way before
they've even got that opportunity rev
takes closer to 3 weeks to even start
we're going to cut these down 10 to 14
days in this process you have no fear no
concern of a reveg process so quick
recap at the end of flower the last 10
to 14 days I recommend putting your
light cycle back on to 18 hours on and 6
hours off and then pay attention to
those tricomes because they're going to
ripen up more quickly than you were
familiar with and then you can Harvest a
little bit earlier and you will have
beefier more dense buds possibly even
more weight at the end of harvest so
this listener wants to try the 186 cycle
but they' got a question about the DLI
they said what DLI should I shoot for
because everything else I read was about
a shorter light cycle yes there are
other Educators out there other breeders
other Growers that do talk about a
shorter light cycle that will work you
will see results but I believe if you
try what I am preaching one time compare
that to those other light cycles I think
you will be happy with this 186 now the
question is what DLI should I shoot for
honestly here's a really simple answer I
don't have a DLI number for you in any
way shape or form uh whatever the DLI is
in your room now with those lights on at
1212 just simply change the timer that's
all you got to do a lot of people ask me
questions about this adjustment they
want to know do I increase the lights do
I turn down the lights uh do I change
the Spectrum do I move the lights no the
only thing I can recommend the only
thing I do I change the timer I don't
move the lights I don't change the
Spectrum I don't even check the DLI if
I'm on 12 12 I had 6 hours that's all I
do and that's what I would recommend for
you as well I understand that we all
like a metric uh I understand that we
like some sort of reading some sort of
data some sort of info we could write
down but in this scenario I've never
bothered to do that because that wasn't
uh part of my experiment part of my idea
it didn't matter to me because I knew
that whatever I was getting I want 6
hours more that was just the thought
process in there I understand that you
want data metrics analytical points that
we can write down but that's not I was
headed with this I've been growing
cannabis uh really good cannabis way
before we had all this technology way
before I had access to uh before I even
knew what DLI and VPD and all that [ __ ]
was uh I was doing it intuitively I was
watching the plants and seeing how the
plants respond to uh light stress abuse
whatever and that's how I know how to
manipulate the plant is by seeing what
has happened my pH pin is one of my
favorite tools but beyond that I don't
need a lot of oh and probably my uh my
hygrometer I need to know how hot and
cold it is in the room and what the the
uh the humidity is in there uh so I've
got a VPD monitor now that tells me all
of that but back in the day I didn't
need any of that stuff I look at the
plants the plants tell me almost
everything I need to know about that
grow room I look at the timer make sure
the timer is set right make sure the VPD
is in line and then look at the plants
if the plants are doing one thing it
means this if the plants are doing the
other thing it means this have you ever
just reached out and touched your plants
to see if they're hot or cold remember
when you're little your mom would touch
your cheek and say you're cold you need
a jacket you do the same thing to your
plants if you think they're getting cold
Reach Out And Touch them if they feel
cold they're probably cold crank up the
heat in the room add more light do
something like that my point is um I
don't have a perfect DLI number for you
because I never uh that wasn't part of
my experiment part of my project here I
noticed when I gave them more light they
performed better and finished earlier
and the way I gave them more is whatever
I was giving them 6 hours more so I know
wish that I had a data point I wish I
did too but plus 6 hours is my algebra
for you here uh my dude Mike D you got
me rambling pretty good whatever I've
been smoking has me rambling pretty good
so thanks for the rambling Point once
again make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at iy direct.com
before we jump into this next question
please remember to hit like And
subscribe that's right like the video
and please hit subscribe that way every
time I put out a new video you will get
a notification you will not miss any of
this fine high quality cannabis content
we do have another question here in
front of me this one came from my friend
Vermont red ey big shout out to my buddy
Vermont red ey make sure you check your
inbox because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at I
redirect.sh yo Rasta Jeff if a plant you
are making seeds with getss powdery
mildew are those seeds guaranteed to
have powdery mildew inside of them I
can't wait till the next drop thanks for
your breeding this is a very good
question I like this there are two
different uh thought processes that my
brain head down when we talk about this
question so let me try to unwrap both of
them slowly and we'll figure this out
together um so what this person is
asking if you've got a plant and you
pollinated it and there are seeds inside
of that plant if this plant gets
attacked by powder mildew will those
seeds have powdery mildew inside of them
the answer to that is quickly no uh
powdery mildew does not work like that
uh the babies will not be born with
powdery mildew that does not work that
way there could however be powdery
mildew on the outside of the seed which
is a completely different story it is
not in the seed it is on the outside
which means it can be removed and
sanitized it's two totally different
things so it may be on the outside the
powdery mildew may be on the outside of
that seed but it is not within that seed
so if you clean the outside it can be
sanitized it can be removed that is very
easy to do now what we're talking about
here um is kind of a question about
epigenetics this may be the first time I
brought up epigenetics here on this
podcast um let me explain it very simply
I don't understand epigenetics on a
scientific level um I understand it on a
very rudimentary level the way that I
can explain it in a way that I think we
will all understand is if a living
organism faces um a problem adversary
the same sort of we're going to we'll
use we'll jump right to the point if a
cannabis plant um over several
Generations if a cannabis plant is
attacked with powdery mildew eventually
epigenetics will create an evolutionary
cure for that problem and now this is
where I've got two different schools of
thought because part of me would say
well find plants that aren't susceptible
to powdery mildew and breed with those
but also this is how you generate plants
that are not susceptible to powdery Milo
so breed with those two different
schools of thought here follow along
this may be an environmental issue and
any plant we put in this region is going
to get powdery mildew so if we had the
if you had a grow room that every time
you put plants in there they get powdery
Milo something I may think of doing this
is just a wild idea but let's breed in
that room and let's breed in that room
for 10 generations and maybe the 10th
Generation that plant will realize
powdery Milo is not going away I've got
to do something about it eventually
those seeds will start to build a
defense and an immunity um a resistance
to powdery Milo and that is how you can
breed that in there is by doing it
multiple times putting a plant so we
take a plant put it in the room it' get
powdery mildew you take seeds out uh
grow those plants put plants in that
room again the one that got the least
amount of powdery Milo in that same
condition select that one breed to that
plant pollinate that plant pull the
progyny from those the plant out of that
generation that gets the least amount of
powdery mildew breed to that again but
keep that room [ __ ] up so we get
powdery mildew in there every time and
keep pulling out the one with the least
amount of powdery Milo generation after
generation and I think that epigenetics
evolutionary time over time over
Generations will teach this plant
powdery Milo is going to [ __ ] happen
you got to be ready for it and
eventually we will breed plants that
don't get powdery mildew that is one
school of thought my other school of
thought is why don't we breed plants why
are you putting [ __ ] in the room that
gets powdery mildew but that is how you
do it so I would also say if a plant
gets powdery mildew in your room don't
breed to it but we've got this uh this
chamber of death here that we've set up
so that is one way to kind of breed out
powdery mildew or breed in powdery Milo
resistance to plants over Generations uh
keep getting them powdery Milo and
select the best one put it in there
select the best one put it in there but
also while you're doing this my my side
B thought over here says take that same
plant and put it in a normal environment
and see if it gets powdery milw in there
see if it's just if it's going to get it
in normal environments or if it only
gets it from this heavy room test it in
normal conditions and stressful
conditions would be my thought process
to that that's my breeder brain wanting
to be um what is it called redundant on
seeing how healthy these plants are how
resistant they are so um no the answer
is no there will not be powdery mildew
inside of your seed but there could be
on the outside of the seed which is why
many people use um a light dilution a
light solution of diluted hydrogen
peroxide when they're germinating seeds
I don't do that I don't recommend that
um I feel that that wipes off all of the
living uh microbes we want right off of
that plant I do something a little bit
different I choose to put microbes I
introduce my own microbes into that soil
into that Seed Life uh before it's got a
chance to get attacked of course I do
use recharge is what I use add a little
bit of recharge to that germination
water or that soil and with that
recharge will do it's already colonizing
beneficial bacteria so there's no room
for the negative bacteria to get in no
problems get in there can get in there
my security guards if you will uh big
shout out to Scotty reel I Scotty reel a
shout out for the recharge um uh yeah
use some recharge to prevent that sort
of that powdery mildew problem but they
will not be on the inside of the seed
the zygote will not contain powdery
mildew but quite the opposite if you
breed several Generations like I was
talking about you can breed powdery Milo
resistance into that plant so my dude
Vermont rede thank you for the great
question very unique idea very unique
question we haven't heard something like
this and I got to sound smart by talking
a little bit about epigenetics all right
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers skateboarders
and fruit booters I want to thank each
and every one of you for listening to
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast if you enjoyed this
episode make sure you support the show
on patreon check out patreon . comgrow
fromy yourheart all the information you
need to support the show will be right
there if I did not read your question on
today's podcast please do not feel
discouraged I have got a mountain of
emails here in front of me this is the
stack that I have picked that I'm going
through for the next couple of shows
this is just a small portion of what
I've got lined up so have no fear if I
didn't read your question on today's
show uh I'm not done with the podcast
there are more episodes coming still
have plenty of opportunities to win more
free seeds so keep those good questions
coming once again that growel tab is on
my website IR genetics.com click that
growel tab send me your questions if I
read the question here free seeds for
you my dude everything else you could
possibly need is on that website IR
genetics.com there's a link to my
Discord server a link to the patreon a
link to get the seeds at iir there's a
link to get merchandise you can grab the
hats Grinders rolling trays a lot of
good stuff still available in the merch
store once again everything is available
at I genetics.com all right I'm sure you
can hear my voice getting dry and
burning out that is my cue to wrap up
the show and get out of here it's time
to go get some hydration and some dabs
um I'll be back in a week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy your mailman grow and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
mother time to take another DB grab your
pie in I go find the
back is in the lab sit back them up
relax hold up