[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome back podc world I'm your
host rosta Jeff this is episode
843 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another great show
lined up for us in today's episode I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
and we'll talk more about those free
seeds later on in the show before we get
too far in today's episode I do want to
remind you that the 4th of July is
approaching as the 4th of July
approaches in my neighborhood we play a
fun game known as gunshots or fireworks
so if you hear weird noises in the
background place your bets it could be
gunshots could be fireworks now I want
to take a moment to thank everybody for
the support on the iy direct inventory
blowout sale that's right on the last
half of last month I put all of the
seeds on sale on iir and you guys helped
me clean out that inventory so I did not
have to count so many packs for the
inventory it made it a lot easier to do
the work at this time as you're watching
this podcast there is a full restock on
edirect decom that's right early this
morning I put up a whole bunch of stuff
uh there is the brand new tinfoil hat
there is some Congo Ripper allegedly
there may be a restock of some of the
the old Ninja Turtles lines that's right
what there is Raphael back in stock
there is Donatello back in stock see
what else is in stock at idirect decom
go take a look right now a lot of things
will sell out very quickly so don't miss
the restock at I direct.com also there
are new freebies if you're tired of
those same old freebies I did update the
freebies list while supplies last there
will be new freebies at I redirect.sh
about when it comes to freebies at iir
that's right when you shop at edirect
decom if you spend over $30 you will get
a free two pack of feminized seeds if
you spend over $100 you get another two
pack of fem seeds it goes on at 200 300
and $400 those freebies do stack so if
you spend $100 you get the $30 level and
the $100 if you spend 200 bucks you will
get the 30 the 100 and the 200 and so
forth if you're going to spend more than
$500 on the website and you want more
freebies please do reach out I will set
you up with a good freebie package deal
all right make sure you do check idirect
decom because that restock is live now
this episode does come out on June 29th
make sure you go check iy direct if you
missed the restock make sure you join my
newsletter that's right on my website
iry genetics.com if you scroll down to
the bottom there is a spot where you can
put in your email address it says stay
up to dat if you put in your email
address it will add you to the
newsletter when I do these restocks I do
send out a newsletter to let everybody
know the restock happened and patreon
does get the first heads up so make sure
you join patreon at
patreon.com fromyou heart I think that
covers all of the news now let's jump
into everybody's favorite new part of
this podcast this is the pet peeve
portion of today's show all right I'm
sure most of you out there know what a
pet peeve is a pet peeve is something
that just drives you crazy that just
grinds your gears often times when I am
in a grow room situation or looking at a
grow space online I will see major pet
peeves something that just drives me
crazy I do encourage you to send me your
growroom pet peeves uh you can email
them to me at grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com if I do read your growroom
pet peeve here on the podcast I will
send you a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at idirect decom today's pet
peeve came from our friend who wants to
be called sweet what's up my dude sweet
it is great to meet you the pet peeve
goes a little bit like this it says my
pet peeve my brother uh taste Trends
fruity is the trend gas is the trend and
sour is all the trend and then he says
all I want is great flour and great
genetics I hate all of these flavor
Trends I understand what you're talking
about however I may disagree we will
delve more into that as this message
unfolds it says I hate the trends I
don't give a fruit no he says a
different word but I'm going to say
fruit because we're early in the episode
we don't want to get censored that says
I don't give a fruit if it's fruity piny
pissy gassy spicy or Woody as long as
it's killer product I I want specific
buzzes that's what I hunt for now that's
where we're going to kind of delve into
this in a minute if the buzz I'm looking
for comes in Pine well then it's going
to be Pine I love the great flavors like
the rest but if I can find no ceiling
shoot you to the Moon weed I don't give
a crap if it's trendy strain if it's a
trendy strain or not back in the day you
didn't know what you were going to get
and that was another part of the
excitement yes that was a I remember
those days when you didn't know what you
were going to get you just went to the
dude's house you got what the dude had
he paid him money you were excited just
to have something to smoke but this is a
whole new era of cannabis a lot of this
is uh medical cannabis people are SPO
smoking and consuming cannabis for uh
medical needs and they they need
specific things so a lot of that does
matter we're going to talk about that uh
as this like I said as this does unfold
um and I do agree just getting what you
used to get was part of the excitement
but now part of the excit for me is
going to uh sometimes it's my friend's
house sometimes it's the dgc cup I don't
really buy flowers from dispensaries but
I will stop in for concentrates CU I
can't make the concentrates that I buy
uh I can't keep up with Green Dot to be
quite honest with you uh but that
variety that's on the Shelf at the
dispensary that Green Dot when I go see
all those different jars and I've got
that variety and I know they're all very
good and very consumable that puts a
smile on my face when I go to the dgc
cup and I see that Hot Rod's got his
flower on the table Hobbit's got his
flower on the table turps has fiz flour
on the table soda's got his amazing
lemon Jeffrey on the table and I can
look at all of those all that variety
puts a smile on my face I love it we're
in a whole new era of cannabis I don't
have to just take what the dude's got if
it tastes like uh cat piss and I'm not
in a catpiss I can smoke the other one
that tastes like strawberries which
we're going to talk more about all this
let me finish your message it says
enough of my rant brother Jeff oh no
don't worry bro cuz I'm going to rant on
my own I appreciate your rant in fact
you've won a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at edirect
docomo smoke and that is what I crave
thanks bro from your friend sweet bro
thank you uh I'm glad that my hard work
is leading to your hard work and our
hard work is paying off so you've got
some killer smoke which is what we crave
brondo bro it's what plants crave now
there are a lot of things to unpack in
here as I've mentioned a couple of times
in this um you start by saying you want
specific buzzes and that's what you hunt
for you don't care if it comes in Pine
uh then you didn't list other flavors
but I understand what you're saying but
what I have found through my research
through my experience I think uh through
Reading and through science as well they
could probably back me up a lot of those
buzzes come along with a very specific
flavor those are the turpins that are
providing the flavor and also
contributing to your Buzz so here is the
analogy that I'm going to use to explain
this keep in mind I have no degree I do
not have any um education on this this
is what I have figured out through
reading through studying through my own
experience this is what I come up with
the THC or the chosen cannabinoid in the
product which you are smoking is what
makes you go high let's compare that to
a firework let's just say if you pack
this firework with THC the more THC you
put in there the higher into the sky
that firework is going to go right that
is your rocket fuel your your gunpowder
we'll say you're going to stuff that
into this firework we're going to light
it it's going to take off if you got 50%
THC we're getting 50% up there if you
got 89% THC we're going 89% way up in
the sky that's the THC now I really
think strongly the tpin are and there
are other con other parts other
components to this that do can play into
this uh equation here but we're going to
start with the tpin there are Esters
pades flavonoids other things in this
same category but we're going to focus
on turps just to keep it specific um the
T tpin when this firework goes up in the
sky that's you getting high but the tpin
in my experience in my opinion in my
theory those are what give you uh the
color to the firework those are the
different colors in that firework what
do we pack in there what and those are
different chemicals and fireworks that
do it but they're going to be different
TPS in cannabis those tping are what
affect my high in different ways I'm
going to get high from the THC but now
am I going to get paranoid am I going to
get the giggles am I going to get the
munchies am I going to get confused am I
going to get tunnel vision am I going to
I get horny am I going to get a headache
is my headache going to go away is my
blood pressure blood pressure going to
raise or is my blood pressure going to
drop there are several different things
I can get from different cannabis plants
I think most of that is from the turpins
a lot of it is from the turps so you
said I don't care about specific flavors
but I bet if you started paying
attention from this point forward you'll
notice that certain flavors and Aromas
give you different buzzes So when you
say that I don't give a I understand you
don't care what the trend is but it does
really matter what the flavors and
Aromas are uh I did an episode long long
ago that is called follow your nose it
may be before I was even doing video
podcast but it was called follow your
nose because I believe that your nose
knows when you go uh wherever you're
going to buy your cannabis if it's to
your own uh plethora of jars or to a
dispensary or to your buddy um if you go
to that dispensary and you open 10 jars
five of them you're going to go nah not
it not it if you're an experienced if
you're not just excited about it they do
all smell good but out of those 10 jars
maybe there's two of them that really
jump out to you and maybe there's
something to do with the way those tpin
are talking to your body now this is
another analogy I'll compare all of this
too this is why poop is brown and stinks
and why oranges are bright orange and
taste good and are good for you the poop
stinks uh because we're not supposed to
eat it that's Nature's little hint of
saying hey bro don't eat that like don't
do it bro unless you're a gross dog or
something most people aren't going to
want want to eat a poop unless there's
something deeply wrong with you on the
other hand oranges are bright orange
they get your eye you look if you're in
nature and you're walking around you see
an orange go oh that looks good just
something inside of your brain can taste
it you start getting the juicy flavor in
your mouth you want to climb over there
and get that orange and eat it and the
orange tastes good and looks appealing
visually for a reason nature gave us
those signals on purpose I really think
that the turpins and our flowers and our
ganja and our cannabis and our
concentrates uh they're that way for a
reason it draws us um maybe you don't
even know there was a reason why you
needed uh that lemon Jeffrey today maybe
that's the one you smoked and it fixed
so many things you weren't even aware of
uh internally or biologically that you
weren't even thinking about or maybe it
has put you in the mood that you needed
to be in uh cuz it's the turpine for you
maybe it works perfectly for you so I do
bet that if you did some studying some
paying attention you would notice that
certain buzzes come from certain turps I
notice uh most of the time lemony stuff
puts a good smile on my face lemon
Jeffrey Lemon Diesel lemon skunk it's
all got a good Smiley uplifting like hey
what's up bro kind of a buzz um all of
the GMO Han Solo Burger uh that stuff
the uh what's it called The Garlic
Banger from Green Dot that puts me like
heavy that's like narcotic it makes me
want to chill it just pushes me down all
of that stuff has a um a garlicky nasty
uh trash can fermented sort of a turp to
it uh sort of a heavier uh the opposite
end of the lemons and they have opposite
completely opposite buzzes so I I can
notice that in the buzz when I smoke
those different products let me pay more
attention to my notes cuz I've got a a
lot of notes Here I was actually on a
podcast with other breeders shout out to
my friends at the dude grow show I was
on the dude grow show I was on a
breeders panel and we had several
breeders talking about uh what we like
and what the market likes and to be
honest with you flavors and Aroma were
always in breeders top three any breeder
we went through the panel and like what
matters most to you and flavor and aroma
uh and the smokable product is
definitely in the top three for every
breeder on the panel that made a big
difference uh what else do I have oh I
wrote down that these Trends this is
where I do agree with this pet peeve
here I completely agree with this part
it drives me crazy this is one of my old
man pet peeves I'll jump in with you now
I'll get on your lawn with you um this
one when people say I got that gas if
you tell me you got gas right and I show
up and your weed smells like blueberries
I don't want it I want it gas if you say
I got that gas that's because your weed
smells like gas that's why you call it
gas that's why people have just taken
the word gas and applied it to any weed
now and that ain't real that's false
advertising that's like walking around
with uh Whoppers in your pocket talking
about you got Big Macs no you don't you
got some good cheeseburgers but you
definitely don't have Big Macs my dude
that wasn't your way right away all
right so that's my part of this pet
peeve if you call it gas that [ __ ]
better be gassy if you say I got the
fruit and it smells fruity I'm happy
with that but if you call it gas and it
smells like [ __ ] blueberries or
cookies or that's not gas my dude stop
doing that you guys all right let me
regroup make sure I answered your
question um the turps will predict the
buzz I think you'll find that I do agree
that the trends are silly but I bet you
that if you pay attention some of those
Trends will lead you in a direction um
the nose always knows follow your nose
because I think your nose knows what TPS
your body needs uh all turps matter and
if you're going to call it the gas show
up with that gas all right my dude that
is the pet peeve section of today's
podcast make sure once again that you do
check your inbox check that spam because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at I direct.com now since this
episode does come out right before the
start of the month it does give me a
good opportunity to make a public
service announcement if you do receive a
coupon code a gift code for free seeds
on I direct.com from the show uh those
do come with expiration dates those
expir ation dates are clearly printed on
the email that you do receive uh those
expiration dates are real it will expire
on that day so I do encourage you to
redeem those gift certificates those
coupon codes as quickly as possible I do
have to have an expiration date on those
coupon codes because I can't just have
free seeds floating out there forever
just have money on the books forever uh
it is a business I do have to close
those tabs at some point just for
Logistics and bookkeeping and business
reasons so help me help you uh when you
do get those coupon codes codes please
redeem those as quickly as possible
because if they expire I cannot help you
out I cannot reactivate that coupon code
I try to give you guys about 30 days uh
since it's here at the start of the
month uh everybody getting these uh your
coupon code will expire at the end of
July if you're getting them in this
episode so it gives you about a month
but I do encourage you to please use
them uh don't let them expire and use
them as quickly as possible all right
now that I got that public service
announcement over let's work our way
into the question and answer portion of
today's podcast of course I do have a
website that website is iry genetics.com
on the top of that website there is a
row of tabs one of those tabs does say
grow help or grow questions if you click
on that tab you can send me a grow
question if I read your grow question
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
idirect tocom the first question on
today's episode came from our new friend
Stefan and it goes just like this it
says dear rosta
I hope you're doing well and thanks for
sharing your knowledge bro I doing great
I hope you are great wherever you are
whenever you hear this uh and you are
very welcome for sharing the knowledge I
enjoy this question so let's jump into
it it says I've got some general
questions regarding land races when it
comes to breeding this is a great
question I'm going to enjoy this but
before I answer it let me give a little
bit of a disclaimer I am not much of a
land race grower or breeder uh the land
race Growers and breeders are kind of a
special Niche group when it comes to the
Cannabis World there are Growers uh
there are smokers there are Growers
there are breeders and then somewhere in
that little in between area uh I'm not
saying they're are less or anything
they're just their own little uh they've
got their own little sect their own
little niche uh they are the land race
Growers and breeders also off to the
side uh same little category different
category same kind of sect is the
Autoflower group so just smaller
branches of a big group just smaller
branch that have branched off they're
still part of our team but they're doing
a very specific thing I am not in uh
that land race group I'm also not in the
Autoflower group but I can talk enough
about it to sound like I know what I'm
talking about and I can definitely
answer your questions now let's start
this off by talking about what a land
race is many people out there may not
understand what land race genetics are
this question may not make much sense to
a lot of people so let's lay the ground
and talk about what land race genetics
means what is a land race um in my
experience in my research a land race is
basically a strain that is developed
naturally regionally and not interrupted
by humans um so let me give an example
of that let's just say there's a
mountain somewhere in Nepal that nobody
has visited for a very long time
hundreds of years probably nobody's been
to this mountain side in Nepal but the
people in Nepal that live there they
have been breeding and growing the same
cultivar for that hundred of years that
nobody has been there there's a hundred
years worth of breeding but no other
genetics have been introduced 100 years
ago there was a crop right it all
pollinated they didn't pull the boys
they didn't pull the girls then they
don't pull the seeds those seeds fall
into the ground so we'll say 100 years
ago that was an F1 we're just going to
start there who knows how long ago it
was uh somebody was walking on a trail
at some point they dropped two seeds
those seeds happened they grew there's a
boy and a girl that made more so that
was the F1 then there was F2 then it did
it again now there's F3 it's done it for
a hundred years
uninterrupted growing pollinating itself
falling to the ground and starting over
now the people in these regions may be
collecting these flowers these buds they
may be making hash or doing something
with it but the breeding is being
uninterrupted unadulterated now there
are two things that could be happening
here and I think both of these would
fall into a land race here um there's a
lot of open pollination happening for
sure uh males and females are grown
amongst each other they all the males
pollinate all the females so you've got
all kinds of different genetic
opportunities in there all of the Gen
genetics will be in that breeding if you
get enough seeds you'll find everything
possible within every mom and every
female that's happening naturally the
males pollinate the females they grow
they drop the seeds those seeds grow
keeps happening year after year after
year now my other school of thought is
that some of these Farmers may be
selectively calling males and females
from the crops that don't meet their
standards maybe they can visually see
that one doesn't put out the hash that I
need or the fiber that I need or that
male doesn't make the females that I
need maybe he can visually see that so
he may be removing candidates from the
breeding pool and for the land race
genetics folks out there I don't know
how they feel about that I don't know if
that's within the rules I don't know uh
how that counts like I gave the
disclaimer before I'm not a land race
breeding uh person that is not my area
of expertise but those are the things
that are most likely to happen in those
uh those unpopulated regions those
beautiful regions on the planet that we
haven't destroyed and built concrete all
over everything and put the internet
everywhere uh there are mountain sides
of just endless cannabis plants that are
Untouched by people or maybe slightly
touched by people but they are not
adulterated by other genetics those are
land race genetics that is the long
description that I said was going to be
short now let me jump into the next part
of this question it says how important
are land race genetics for you in your
breeding work now the quick answer uh
for that one is for me they are not uh
at the point where I am in my breeding
I've made enough things where um I don't
have to acquire any more plants or seeds
I'm not saying I don't want to but I
could stop uh any incoming plants and
seeds and I could breed for hundred
years I could breed for the rest of my
life with the seed and breeding stock
I've already created so at this point uh
those land races don't excite me don't
interest me I care about them I
definitely understand where they come
from what they are how they are working
in my current crosses and where um what
I can see the traits from around the
world and we can identify different
things from those land races and how
they are uh playing with my current
breeding but right now at this time um
that's those plants don't interest me
they're not on my radar maybe if there
were an apocalypse and we had to start
over or maybe if I had to start over if
I bred all my stuff into some bottleneck
where it all started coming out to be
lemon chem dog or it was all [ __ ]
golden Tangi or something it all turned
out if I messed it all up uh then maybe
I would go to land race genetics and
start fresh there uh get some Afghan and
maybe some Brazilian and some Thai and
then just start and I got three
different things I can start
triangulating uh within the next 5 or 10
years I can have a lot of stuff
generated to play with at that point uh
we could be doing a lot of fun feno
hunts but um to me not very important
but to a very certain niche of people
out there those land races mean
everything and it sounds like this may
be um some direction you might want to
go just by the question let me keep
myself focused CU whatever I smoked once
again it has got me going today it was
the Cherry pot pie concentrates from our
friends at Green DOL they do not pay me
to say that but if you want to shout out
to Green do laabs you know how to get in
touch with me where is we now it says
with people constantly traveling around
and the ongoing search for shorter
flowering periods in commercial growing
How likely is it to find real or even
new land races
anymore um the answer I wrote down is
you got to go where Arian hasn't been um
Arian rosam is the founder and breeder
for Greenhouse seed company and I've got
respect for his breeding I love what
he's done with the industry the world he
runs coffee shops in Amsterdam uh the
dude's got one of the most successful
seed companies in the planet probably
more cannabis Cups than uh most people
that I can think of the dude's got a lot
of awards um but he does something that
is um it's it gets my attention here and
it fits into this this conversation
Arian and his crew fly around to those
locations I was talking about where
cannabis has been unadulterated for
hundreds of years um I'm going to I'm
guessing hundreds of years I really
don't know like I said not the land race
guy but these land race plants have been
growing unadulterated for years and
years um our buddy Arion goes there um
meets with the right people they take
him to these Farms he meets the farmers
they give him permission to go into the
fields and he collects the seeds they
say do what you want to do bro taking a
couple of handfuls of seeds from us
isn't going to hurt have a good time out
there in the field enjoy yourself take
pictures uh they're they're very
gracious hosts so Arian and his friends
they go and they gather seeds and then
they take the seeds back to their
Greenhouse uh back to Amsterdam to their
business Greenhouse they grow them they
find things they breed with it um cool
that's how breeding should work that's
that's not a problem what they do that
kind of uh puts some alarms up puts up
some red flags and makes me uh concerned
with what they're doing a little bit
while they are there while they are on
these uh sacred land if you want want to
call it on these little plots of
cannabis on uh unadulterated cannabis
plots they are leaving the farmers with
seeds that they have made in Amsterdam
uh that
um they are a lot of their popular and
famous feminized seeds I could tell
because when they passed them the seeds
they were colorcoded a greenhouse Seed
Company dips their seeds in a color code
so you could tell which seeds are which
if you lose the package you can have a
whole bag of Skittles and you know that
all the yellow ones are Super Lemon
Hayes and I don't remember the color
code but they are colorcoded and so I
saw Arian give this guy handfuls of
color-coded seeds and now that guy's
going to go perhaps possibly maybe grow
those outdoors in that sacred
unadulterated land race cannabis plot
and now they've been adulterated now
there's new [ __ ] happening out there
there's new uh new jeans in the breeding
pool um new [ __ ] has come to light man
and I don't know how I feel about that
so um traveling around and doing
research uh How likely is it to find
real land races you've got to go where
Arian hasn't been um you've got to go
find go where the people don't go go
where uh find what region interests you
like there are several regions where
these land races are research them of
course think about where all of our
favorite cannabis comes there's
Brazilian there's Thai there's Afghan um
there's Pakistani weed that's really
[ __ ] good um there's weed from all
over the world but think about what weed
gets your attention and [ __ ] maybe
it's napali weed maybe it's somewhere
maybe it's somewhere real fun maybe it's
somewhere real sketchy but think about
where that weed comes from and go there
and start meeting people and build
relationships and let them know hey I'm
a Weed Farmer I'm a seed Hunter I'm
looking for the seeds from this region
so I can preserve them and start my own
project and do something uh for the
plant for the good of this plant and
people uh Farmers find each other ganja
heads find each other mushroom people
find each other uh I think the land race
folk uh if this is what you're meant to
do the world will put this into your uh
your lap it will happen for you you're
going to have to do some work but go to
those places go get those seeds or start
doing some networking on the internet
and trust people build relationships
with someone you trust get some land R
seeds from them but uh they're still
around the the land races are still
around there are plenty of places on the
earth that are untouched um there are a
lot of great places to go get these
seeds you just have to decide what you
want where to go get them and then
develop a relationship and go there and
acquire those seeds then you got to get
them back to the States sometimes that's
the fun part but that's on you my dude I
can't encourage you to do anything weird
all right now the next part of the
question says if they are still around
how do professional breeders separate an
original land race from the mini hybrids
and strain crosses out there um so if
it's a land race it doesn't have um like
so you know most strains so it's like
we'll say let me pick a strain out of
the top of my head I'm just searching
for something right now lemon Jeffrey uh
lemon Jeffrey says Lemon Skunk X which
means bread to or crossed or times a lot
of people say Golden Goat you got your
lemon Jeffrey X Golden Goat in
parenthesis that is or your Lemon Skunk
Golden Goat that's lemon Jeffrey if it's
a land race it's just going to say
Pakistani
that's all it is it's not going to have
other stuff that's why it's a land race
it's that Pakistani land race or that
Nepali land race or that congales hand
land race um it could be from a lot of
different places but the land races uh
they're not going to be crossed to
anything and you could tell by the way
that they grow uh they grow wildly a lot
of the times they don't have the
uniformity of any of the modern strains
because they haven't been bred they
haven't been selected for that uh Nature
has been selecting them it's the battle
of the fittest for the last 100 years uh
what grew the best is what grew the best
out there so if it's a land race you
probably got it from another land race
seed seller or Enthusiast or you went
and got it or it came from somebody from
that region um how do professional
breeders separate uh it's just because
it's not adulterated it's from that
region and you know where your seeds
came from and a lot of times you could
tell when you grow it out the modern
modern bread stuff uh is breed for
social media it's bred for photography
to sell seeds in magazines that's what a
lot of the [ __ ] on social media is is um
some of my best strains are not the most
photogenic some of my most photogenic
strains are not the best um a lot of the
stuff that you see online uh is bread
they're picking the best phenotype for
the internet and taking a picture of it
and selling seeds based on the colors of
the leaves and the amount of frost on
there but you don't know if that plant's
got any resistance to bugs or pathogens
or the potency and a lot of times it
tastes like [ __ ] cardboard but at
this point I am rambling let me get back
on track here to the next bullet point
in this question anyway if you want
those real hybrids you got to go get
them or get them from a true land race
Enthusiast now the next part are F1
hybrids based on land races more
vigorous than crosses that are derived
from other crossed strains I think I
kind of mentioned this part I don't know
about more vigorous because you get that
F1 hybrid Vigor um almost in um most of
the crosses that you make even if it's
modern stuff to old stuff or modern to
Modern old to old if you got healthy
plants and you put those to new genes
together uh most often you're going to
get some hybrid Vigor what you're going
to see with these uh land races the
words I wrote down is more wild they're
much more wild since they're uh these
are like Untamed animals these have
never seen a cage they've never had a
leash they're just [ __ ] flailing
they're going crazy um maybe the leaves
are crazy the branching is crazy the
structure is undesirable but that's not
like I said that it happened in nature
you've got to find the good [ __ ] in
there with the traits you like and breed
that the direction you want so um are
the hybrids based on land races more
vigorous um I would not say more
vigorous I'm going to say more wild
you're going to get Vigor you're going
to get hybrid Vigor but they're going to
find some wild [ __ ] in there all right
uh my buddy Stephan says thanks for your
input dude thank you for a great
question for letting me ramble like I
said I'm not the land race guy so I
don't know all of the land race details
but I hope I was able to answer your
question thoroughly and don't forget to
check your inbox for that coupon code
for a free pack of seeds from
hrdirect.com all right let's keep this
momentum going I do have another great
question here in front of me let's go
with this one right now this one came
from a friend in Germany guten taga and
F Vates I hope everything is good over
there in Germany the question starts off
with guten to rasted Jeff first of all I
love your show and I learned a lot hey
thank you for listening in Germany it's
amazing to hear that I have got German
listeners uh that's amazing to know that
we are international it's say my
question is about fast flowering plants
yes these fast flowering plants have
been all the trend lately it says I have
read that they are bred with autof
flowers to lower the flowering time and
that low flowering time is what I need I
understand all of the new Growers uh one
of the first things that are after uh is
fast flowering plants and I'm sure that
uh a lot of people in Germany are
looking for fast flowering plants so I
hope I'm able to answer your questions
here it says I live in Germany and I
like to grow outdoors but Autumn is cold
and wet yes I'm sure it does get cold
and wet it says in addition here I get
1212 around the 1st of September um yeah
our seasons are different so I'm not
sure where that lines up it says it's a
gamble every year what do you think
about these fast flowering plants do you
have any experience or is it possible to
create a strain that starts flowering at
1410 thanks in advance and keep on
rolling maybe we are legal when you read
this on on YouTube I think you are legal
now uh with some stipulations and
regulations so let's start by saying
congratulations to our friends out there
in Germany for their progress with
legalization now let's uh let's answer
some of these questions here the first
one uh have I played with the fast
flowering plants no uh I have not myself
played with fast flowering plants I
prefer longer flowering plants I think
they give me better quality and more
yield but I understand that
situationally uh that is not always
ideal so I do not mess with the fast
flowering um then the next part is um
can we create strains that flower at
1410 honestly I bet there are strains
that flower at 1410 already but any hom
grower or home breeder that is growing
indoors has eliminated those from their
breeding project or their selection
because it did not work for their indoor
grow it just wasn't doing what they
wanted so it probably got uh cold and
eliminated um most people are doing 1212
indoors now real quickly I'm going to
touch back on previous episodes and talk
about something called far red lighting
uh you're asking about a plant that
flowers at 14 hours of light and 10
hours of darkness is what I think you're
talking about so um a lot of times you
may look outside and you may think that
you've got that 14 hours of light out
there but what actually happens is as
that sun sets that is putting off a red
light spectrum known as far red lighting
that far red lighting triggers a
phytochrome response in your plants that
tells the plants it is time to go to
sleep so I'm certain that there are some
plants out there that that 14-hour day
when you see the 14 hours that's
probably probably 13 or 12 hours of
actual usable sunlight uh because you've
got the rising spectrum and the setting
Spectrum are a little bit different I
bet you there are plenty of plants out
there that will flower with that 14
hours of daylight that is actually
called the critical period how many
hours of dark Ness it takes for a plant
to flower uh that is probably dependent
on uh the location on the globe or in
relation to the equator where that plant
came from so I would assume that there
are plants out there that would flower
with that 14-hour light cycle and that
leads me to another option have you
considered Autoflower plants I
understand you want fast flowering but
why not just give a try with Autoflower
plants that may be another very viable
option um I've got a good friend that
grows outdoors here in Colorado he does
two sometimes three crops with our
outdoor season when most people get one
outdoor crop so what my buddy does he
puts a round of regular photo period
plants outside so he's got his photo
period plants outside those are going to
go into flower uh he puts them outside
as soon as the weather permits I think
that's Mother's Day here in Colorado
also he will put a round of Autoflower
plants out on Mother's Day so he's got
one plant of photos one plant of Autos
now both of these plants begin to grow
but but eventually the autof flowers
will go into flower and they will flower
and by the time they finish now the
photo periods start going into flower so
he chops one down and then he reloads
that plot with more autof flowers and
then by the time the other crop finishes
he's got two more crops done at the same
time so he runs one photo period crop
outdoors and two Autoflower crops
Outdoors he get gets three crops in the
time that most people get one and one
big advantage to those autof flowers as
they are done way before the thieves and
the Rippers and the frost get out there
uh to destroy your plants cuz in
Colorado uh people know we're growing
weed they start looking out for it they
come steal it about a week before
Harvest people will come take it if you
ran Auto flowers you're done way before
that time period even approaches so the
root of the question was about fast
flowering plants I don't have any
experience with the autof flowers or the
fast flowers but I know there are very
good uses for both maybe if you've got
the opportunity plant a row of both do
some fast fly flowers do a row of
autoflow and if you want to get frisky
maybe even put out a row of photo period
plants out in the grow space um I love
these questions from New Markets as new
markets come on uh there will be new
questions new demands um something you
may want to think about you said you
have got the cold and wet weather in
Autumn maybe just maybe uh you may want
to do some breeding and develop a strain
that works very well in your climate if
you're one of the first Growers out
there to get a head start and start
breeding outdoor plants in your region
that are already adapted to your
environment and ready for your
conditions uh you will be far ahead of
the market and those seeds will sell
very well to every outdoor farmer in
your region uh every section and region
that it works you can sell those seeds
they probably work indoors as well all
right my new friend from Germany uh
thank you for the great question I hope
I was able to give you some solid advice
you do win a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from idirect decom however I'm
not not sure if we can ship those seeds
safely to Germany so send me an email uh
send me an email at grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com put Germany in the subject
line uh when I see that I will reach out
and we will figure out if we're going to
get you a shirt or a hoodie or if we're
going to attempt to send some seeds to
Germany Dona fry all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers skateboarders
and fruit booters I want to thank each
and every one of you for list listening
to another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast once again don't miss that
fresh drop and restock on IR
redirect.sh get you some I direct.com
uh make sure you check the website the
other website if you need strain info
strain details all of that stuff is kept
on a separate website for legistics
purposes uh that website is iry
genetics.com so iry genetics.com has got
all the details all the info on all the
strains also there's a link to the
Discord server there's a link to the
patreon so you can support the podcast
there's a link to the Discord server
everything is at IR genetics.com I think
that's all I've got for you for this
episode before I leave please do
remember to click like And subscribe and
please leave some comments on this video
I do love seeing your opinions in the
comment section that's all I've got for
you for this episode I'll be back in a
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big old shout out to my buddy
Green Ranger and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me Rost a Jeff you bad
mother time to take another Dam grab you
be in N about the
B is in the lab sit back them moment
relax hold up