[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother yeah welcome back podcast world
I'm your host rosta Jeff this is episode
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got a fun episode lined up for
us in today's show I'm going to give
away free seeds that's right hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in the show I do want to remind
you that there has been a fresh restock
at edirect decom that's right check
edirect decom for a restock when you
check out use coupon code podcast to
save 20% off of your entire order every
item at edirect decom is eligible for
the discount so hit edirect dcom and use
coupon code podcast to save
20% before I get too far I do want to
send a big thank you shout out to
everybody who checked on me for not
putting out a podcast episode last week
uh thank you for checking on me I do
apologize for not putting out a show I
try to post an episode once a week but
sometimes the summer happens and I am
going to skip a couple of shows and
enjoy myself I am safe everything is
well everything is iy uh I was uh
visiting a couple of friends uh I spent
a lot more time there than I had
anticipated but sometimes friends and
family are going to take precedent over
a podcast this was one of those times I
thought I would catch up later in the
week but I did not because I got the
honor and privilege to go see Miss
Natalie rise do three shows in Colorado
I got to see the show in Denver uh just
a short drive up the highway an
excellent amazing show lots of good
friends shout out to my buddy ree in my
head I got to see him there and hang out
saw lots of other friends but ree
deserves a big shout out and then the
next day Miss Natalie rise played here
in my town which is Colorado that was
just a short drive up the road so that
was great to see Natalie in my town and
then I was honored and privileged enough
to be invited to a private barbecue with
Natalie rise and some of the very close
rise Nation crew uh that was a great
weekend shout out to miss Natalie rise
shout out to everybody from Rise Nation
I cannot list everybody but you guys and
gals all know who you are uh extra big
shout out to the quarantina backyard
concert family uh you folks are amazing
anyway big shout out to the crew I had a
great time seeing Natalie rise but this
all started by saying thank you to
everybody who checked on me uh it feels
really good to have loyal uh followers
supporters listeners you guys are my
friends is what I want to call you it's
great to have people that say hey dude
your podcast didn't come out first of
all was it a tech issue you might want
to check on that second of all if it
wasn't a tech issue are you okay that's
really great to hear from the family the
friends the Army if you will thank you
guys for that um I appreciate it so
shout out to you and of course once
again shout out to miss Natalie rise and
the entire rise Nation crew where do we
go from there ladies and gentlemen I
think it is now time to segue into some
emails I do have a website that website
is I genetics.com let me clarify
something I have two websites one of
them is iry genetics.com that website
will also lead you to iy direct.com I've
got two websites for Logistics purposes
uh it makes sense if you understand the
background reasons we're not going to
talk too much about that but the seeds I
advertise are at air.com the rest of the
things are at iry genetics.com that's
where you can find a link to patreon a
link to my Discord server a link to get
merchandise where we sell Grinders
t-shirts rolling trays things of that
nature uh anyhow on that website iy
genetics.com there is a tab that says
grow help or grow questions if you click
on that Tab and send me a grow question
I may read that question here on the
show if I read that question here on the
show guess what you win a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom the first email from that growel
tab today came from our friend we're
just going to call them Matthew big
shout out to my new friend Matthew
Matthew make sure you check your inbox
and check your spam because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
idirect decom our message from our
friend Matthew goes a little bit like
this it says rosta Jeff I want to thank
you for being an absolute Gem of a soul
that is a great way to start a message
thank you I'm still uh working on being
a better person every day I'm trying to
do my best uh sometimes I make some
mistakes but if I appreciate uh you
noticing that I am a gem of a soul that
is a huge compliment so thank you it
goes on it says I wish more people had
the attitude and ability to spread the
love the way you do actually this per
this person wrote this message not real
realizing it was coming straight to me
so it says the way he does but it's
coming straight to me so thank you um I
wish more people had the attitude and
ability to spread love the way I do I
appreciate that that is cool thank you
um I try to have a positive attitude of
course I'm not going to come on the
podcast I'm in a bad mood and be like uh
the world sucks I'm having a bad day but
I'm never going to do that I'm not that
way anyway but i' would keep the bad
attitude the negative stuff off of
camera of course I do have bad days
sometimes I wake up just in a funk
sometimes [ __ ] doesn't go my way but I
try to keep a positive mental attitude
keep my head up uh give thanks for what
I do have and not be sad about what I
don't have because that's that's the
best way you can do it right be grateful
and not be uh yeah the other way would
suck anyhow um spreading love uh that's
just what I think I do naturally but a
friend of mine recently pointed out that
I'm just uh naturally kind and loving
and giving so thank you for also
pointing that out it's good to see a lot
of people sing that in me recently that
makes me uh shine a little brighter and
give you it's able to give you more of
that love and giving it's going in
circles is what I think I'm saying here
you guys got me rambling shout out to
our friends at Green do laabs for the
excellent concentrates we're going to
keep going though this message says I've
been looking for the lemon Jeffrey for
quite some time now is I tried a local
strain called lemon drop a while back
and it had the best lemon flavor and
effect on my mind that I've ever had
okay I love that you're after the lemon
Jeffrey because the lemon drop made you
happy uh I do agree that you may find
something with those lemon turps that
makes you happy makes you smiley that's
why I like the lemon Jeffrey it fixes my
my weird glitches and it makes me feel
like a normal person and it makes me uh
happy and smiley and chatty and rambly
which is a good spot for a podcaster to
be anyhow it says um I would like to ask
if there is a way I can be added to a
list for when these seeds restock thank
you in advance from your friend Matthew
um yes the elusive lemon Jeffrey packs
every time I put more lemon Jeffrey on
iir it sells out quite quickly no matter
how many I put on there um people just
buy them up I don't know if you guys are
waiting in line for it I don't know if
something uh happen somewhere where it's
super popular but I cannot keep them in
stock I cannot make them quickly enough
unfortunately I only have a couple of
packs left in my own private reserve
right now that I will not let go of
those are for me in case something were
to go wrong but but have no fear because
I will make more lemon Jeffree seeds in
the very near future not right now not
this run but in the next couple of runs
there will be more lemon Jeffree seeds
created now this person asked Matthew
asked is there a way they can be added
to a list for when these seeds drop yes
there absolutely is an amazing way to be
added to a list on the website where you
sent this message at I genetics.com
toward the bottom of that page there's a
spot that says uh stay up to date and
there's a picture of like a it's like a
letter like an envelope you can type in
your email address in there and if you
type in your email address and hit send
that will add you to the newsletter that
I use to send out to let everybody know
about restocks fresh drops brand new
stuff merchandise sales uh events that
are coming up places I may be I've been
trying not to spam you guys too much
because I was hitting you pretty hard
there for a few minutes with emails but
uh if you join that newsletter that is
where you will get all of those updates
and I try to send May one every other
week I try for one a month but sometimes
during holidays you may get bombarded if
I hit you with the 420 sale I'll give
you a hey there's a sale coming and then
hey the sale started and then a hey
don't forget about the sale I may
sandwich three emails in a row there but
I try not to overload you unless it's
really worth your time to go take a look
so the place to go get added to that
list is on my newsletter at IR
genetics.com scroll halfway down you'll
see the spot where it says stay up to
date that's where you stay up to date my
friend ALS Al patreon gets the heads up
first I promise all patreon members that
they get the first heads up of all the
newsletters basically when I compose a
newsletter I copy it and I paste it to
patreon and patreon gets it first um the
newsletter will go out sometime in the
morning early afternoon patreon will get
it at like 3 5:00 in the morning uh as
I'm composing it they will get that
message right away they'll get it super
early so patreon always gets the first
heads up so if you do join that patreon
uh you do get the opportunity to get the
heads up for when new stuff restocks
occasionally about once or twice a month
I do give away free seeds on patreon I
just post hey the first 10 people to go
to the website and use this coupon code
will get a free pack of seeds uh
sometimes people get free seeds that way
and then if you join at specific tiers
the $25 level does get a free pack of
seeds every month and the $50 level does
get two free packs of seeds every month
so join the patreon there's a lot of
perks there all right my friend Matthew
thank you for the great message once
again my dude check your inbox check
your spam cuz you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds from I
direct.com all right podcast world let's
keep this good energy going and work our
way into the next segment of today's
podcast if you've been watching for a
while you know I like to do a growroom
pet peeve section of the show most of
you know what a pet peeve is that is
something that just drives you crazy
sometimes I'll be in a commercial grow
sometimes I'll be at a friends grow
sometimes I'll see something online that
just drives me crazy and a grow that is
a pet peeve I encourage you as listeners
to send me your growroom pet peeve you
can send me those growroom pet peeves on
that growel tab at IR genetics.com
today's pet peeve came from our friend
who is going to be called Brody G big
shout out to my new friend Brody this
message goes a little bit like this it
says hey rosta Jeff hopefully you had a
good Fourth of July holiday uh it was
excellent it was a great holiday let me
jump to the question part it says my
biggest pet peeve was after all these
years of growing when some somebody
sells me a cut claiming it is something
popular and it turns out not to be the
real thing that is very frustrating uh
that is uh it's almost offensive I've
seen that breakup friendships I have
been sold uh somebody claimed they sold
me something it was not what they sold
me they took a lot of money from me and
now they act like I did something wrong
because I want some sort of
acknowledgement at [ __ ] least that
this guy gave me the wrong clones but he
doesn't care anymore I'm the [ __ ] for
pointing it out I understand how that
goes I kind of lost a friend possibly a
business partner because he sold me cuts
and he's like I got extras if you want
them and he knew that it wasn't what he
was giving me he knew that but anyhow it
goes on it says uh it's not only a waste
of money time and grow space it's a
massive disappointment yes I agree with
that uh not only a disappointment it can
kind of piss you off a little bit
because you've been hyping it up you
told all your friends like bro I got
this new cut I got this new [ __ ]
space monkey balls and you're [ __ ]
excited about it and you're telling all
your homies and you're sending pictures
and then you smoke it and you're like
this is [ __ ] blue dream like I've
been there before bro like yeah I've
been there not just massive
disappointment sometimes you're a little
bit flat out pissed off it depends on
how much you paid for that cut and how
many of them you bought and who you got
it from if it's just some random dude on
Craigslist that I met met in a parking
lot and gave him 25 bucks for a clone
that's on me that's my dumbass fault for
trusting that guy but if it's one of the
guys in the circle that I know that like
actually I know he has this cut he's got
the [ __ ] monkey Space Balls whatever
I called it and I'm like sell me a cut
of that and he's like sure bro and he
sells it to me and I know he gave me
[ __ ] blue dream and I grow it and I
can tell right away that is that's
[ __ ] wrong that's that definitely
will cause a rift in the force let me
keep reading there's more to this it
says I appreciate the fact that you give
back to the community in so many
different ways peace love and big dabs
from bro G bro thank you for the
acknowledgement that I'm giving back to
the community I feel like we've uh
cultivated a great Community with the iy
army with the gfyh podcast true with the
I genetics team which is growers in
general we've got a really good
Community happening right now it's all
in a good spot uh the Discord is popping
all of the comment sections have been
real positive so thank you for noticing
that I'm trying to to give back to the
community the community has been really
important to me lately that word uh the
whole word Community the idea of
community is becoming more important to
me um so thank you I appreciate that and
my dude uh bro g once again check your
email check your inbox check your spam
cuz you my dude have a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at iy direct.com all
right podcast world now is the part of
the show that you have all been waiting
for I'm sure you saw on the title that
we are going to talk about fist bump and
red line so let's get down to business
shall we this portion of the podcast was
inspired by a question that came from
that growel tab on IR genetics.com this
question came from my new friend Richard
Richard make sure you check your inbox
and check your spam CU you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from I
redirect.sh Richard's question goes a
little bit like this it says hey rosted
Jeff my spirit tells me that your
genetics are legit and I will be
purchasing exclusively from you that is
a great statement and a great way to
start an email I definitely appreciate
that it feels good to know that your
spirit thinks that my genetics are legit
that's a lot of uh lot of that's a huge
compliment there is what I'm trying to
say and the idea of purchasing
exclusively from me is great I do not
expect any loyalty but I definitely do
appreciate appreciate that loyalty now
let me keep going because it does say
recently I got fist bump and Redline
seeds I am now 62 years old and I have a
green thumb can you please describe the
flavor profile of these great cultivars
thanks for the iy Vibes Richard yes I
would be happy to describe the uh
flavors and I'll actually give you a
couple more details on these strains
while we are here we're going to start
with fist bump fist bump is one of my
favorite strains one of my best selling
strains one of my most popular strains
right now uh fist bump is only available
in regular seeds that means you will get
male and female seeds out of the pack I
did not and I probably will not make
fist bump in a feminized form I've just
got a lot of other things in mind but I
just want to start by saying fist bump
is available in regular seeds only so
there will be males and females in this
package now I do have a few notes that
I'm going to try to use to try and keep
myself on track but we all know how that
goes if you've been here before now now
let's start with the name fist bump why
did I call the strain fist bump where
did that come from uh you guys know I'm
a ree fan I like to go to a lot of Reay
shows uh anytime you're at a ree show
and you see a friend or if you meet a
ree artist we don't shake hands we give
a fist bump that's a sign of respect
that's like what's up bro I respect you
that is our version of a fist bump I'm
sure a lot of different cultures out
there do a fist bump uh anybody from
rostic culture to skateboarders to Bar
Bros to biker dudes to sports guys we
all give a fist bump a fist bump just
says what's up dude we're connecting
what better way to name a strain than
fist bump show we are connecting we got
some love for you we're on the same side
we're on the same team what's up bro
fist bump just a fist bump for all the
ganja Growers out there so that's where
fist bump came from now let's talk more
about the plants themselves fist bump
what are the genetics what is the cross
of fist bump that is a cross of Sour
Diesel and aise what uh that's a really
fast growing uh tall branchy plant uh
makes plants grow really tall really
quickly be ready for tall plants I want
to I want to say that a couple times
they're going to get tall they're also
going to get branchy all those branches
are also going to get very tall if you
do not top the fist bump you will get a
very big fat dominant top cola if you
grow a really big fat top Cola make sure
you keep your VPD in line if you've got
a room that is known to get too humid or
have VPD issues I recommend topping fist
bump and growing a bunch of they won't
be tiny but you won't get this big
donkey dick style Bud that you normally
would you won't get that big baseball
bat you'll get a bunch of smaller
baseball bats which then will prevent
that powdery mildew or that bud rot
issue from happening that I said prevent
it will help stop that um you do have to
correct the room but if you do have an
overh humid room I recommend topping to
prevent that giant Cola set yourself up
for Success where else should we go from
here uh they're very vigorous they grow
very quickly that 21-day stretch these
plants are going to take off on you be
prepared for that these plants will
double if not more in size by the end of
flowers so however tall if it's a foot
tall when you put it into flow it'll be
two maybe 2 and 1/2t tall by the time it
is done be prepared for that they are
stretchy they're also heavy feeders in
uh veg they like a lot of nitrogen when
you put them into flour don't cut that
nitrogen off immediately all of my arise
crosses everything that came from King
Solomon my arise man
is basically a pretty heavy feeder
you're going to want to give it a lot of
nitrogen when you flip to flour I don't
recommend cutting off that nitrogen like
a lot of Growers do I recommend tapering
it off slowly so slowly taper off that
nitrogen so they don't Fade Out too
quickly on you if you see yellowing
early with fist bump or most of my stuff
that is bred with King Solomon I
encourage a foler feed with some
nitrogen to help that plant along
nitrogen is a mobile nutrient it'll get
on the leaves it'll move itself where it
needs to be uh that's the the short
version of what happens but don't let
that nitrogen get away from you let's
stay focused uh taper off the nitrogen
slowly uh then um let these plants
finish these plants are going to take
about 10 weeks if not a little bit more
sometimes 72 77 days is appropriate
don't be afraid to let them go because
they will bulk up at the end and get
super fat on you that extra time will
pay off you will get extra weight in the
long run um I wrote down 10 plus weeks
as my note here um these plants they do
take well to trellising topping popping
scrogging you can abuse these plants
they will take it the the only
challenging part about the fist bump
plants well two challenging Parts
they're going to get big more quickly
than you're anticipating these plants
will get away from you they'll grow very
quickly if you're not paying attention
uh you'll think I've got time to put
some stakes in there or time to Trellis
that you don't do it now they're going
to get away from you the other struggle
you may face is feeding if you don't
feed them properly early on you'll never
catch up you'll be chasing the feeding
forever with these plants otherwise
they're fairly easy to grow I know that
sounds intimidating saying they get tall
and hungry but most Growers can handle
that most of you overfeed your plants
anyway so I think you're going to be
okay now the main question here was can
we talk about the Aromas and flavors yes
uh this is where it gets exciting um
fist bump since it's got that Sour
Diesel in there uh it comes out gassy
and fuy it's like a little it's got the
gassy top to it where gas like gasoline
has a a certain an alcohol smell to it
but it's also got diesel which is nasty
so it comes out with both of those TPS
then also from the Golden Goat it's got
some Citrus and some like tropical
sweetness so it's like a uh it's almost
like a Tropical Smoothie almost a not a
Orange Julius but a a tropical Julius if
that makes any sense to your turp flavor
mind it's like if you ate a tropical
Julius if you had a uh one of those uh
those Mexican ice cream fruit bars uh
from the gas station that are super
[ __ ] delicious you know what I'm
talking about you Southern California
people um one of those bars a pelletieri
bar is that how you say it I'm a Greeno
it's all good uh next to the gas pump
next to the diesel pump that's what it's
like bro it's like Fruity gasoline at
the same time and it's really desirable
I really love that sort of Buzz that
sort of turp now one thing I do notice
is that some of the structure will
indicate what the flavors are going to
be like I've noticed that some of the
phenotypes that display certain visual
characteristics also do come with
certain scents and Aromas the plant with
the chunkier or big thick top Cola that
one's going to be mostly Sour Diesel the
one with the fingerer sort of kind of
shaped buds that one is the Golden Goat
there is a phenotype in there that will
get really really tall and kind of
skinny it puts off one long tall skinny
Bud that I believe comes from the island
sweet skunk and Hawaiian sativa in the
Golden Goat it's got a a lot of the
Hawaiian sativa structure and the island
sweet skunk Aroma that's where I really
think that one comes from and you can
smell it and I can visually identify
those specific phenotypes uh there are a
lot of different phenotypes that come
from these they are not very uniform
you're going to see several different
phenotypes but you can see the Golden
Goat you can see the diesel and then you
can see a couple of the weirdos that pop
up as well but um I've been talking
about this when it comes to phenotype I
don't want to tell you too much about
phenotypes because I don't want to pick
for you um I brought you a variety pack
of amazing flavors and I want you to
choose if you want blueberry raspberry
strawberry lime Mandarin guava there's
one in there that's for you I want you
to choose that one I don't want to pick
that I think you'd be better at that so
choose the phenotype that works best for
you but the flavors and Aromas was the
main part of the question uh gassy
diesel Aromas with like a tropical fruit
sort of a thing on top of it so it's
like you ate some tropical sorbet or
took a bowl of mixed fruit and put that
in your mouth but then you had to sniff
gasoline or diesel fuel at the same time
that is my feedback my update my report
on fist bump now we are going to work
our way into another strain from here on
out I don't want any confusion I just
want it to be known from here right here
now we are now talking about another
strain we're going to work our way into
Red Line let's talk about Redline um I
think I started last time with why did I
name it red line uh red Line's got a
couple of different uh meanings to me
first of all it's red Lebanese hash
plant so you got the red in there uh red
Lebanese hash plant RL already Red Line
when I saw the red line I saw RL but red
red Lebanese hash plant to the same
arise that made the fist bump so that's
King Solomon to Red Lebanese hash plant
a red Lebanese hash plant always list
ladies first when you're talking about
the cross uh that's an important detail
red Lebanese hash plant to the arise why
did I name it Redline couple of
different reasons it's got read the name
already uh Redline Redline was a bicycle
company when it still could be a bicycle
company I have not kept up but I used to
be a bicycle Rider I was a BMX
Enthusiast I loved that movie rad uh I
loved Matt Hoffman uh I was into GT
Bicycles I like freestyle bikes uh BMX
biking uh any way that I could hurt
myself on a 20-in bicycle uh I was all
about it so the uh Redline was a popular
brand at the time I was a GT guy I rode
Gary Turner Bikes but uh Redline was
super popular a lot of people loved it
so that played into my culture uh my
childhood so that was part of my
memories Redline comes from that but
also but wait there's more um the first
time I smoked Red Line my eyes got
bloody bloody red they were blood red it
was like dangerously red it looked like
there was blood dripping down my eyeball
it was so red from smoking red line and
you guys have watched me take fat dabs
on Discord you see me come in here and
talk about I just took 72 dabs um my
eyes it takes a little bit to get my
eyes red they get a little pink
sometimes at the end of the day you can
notice I get a little I get the messed
up eyes from smoking too much but not
like most people would but the red line
my bro Red Line had my eyes bloody
dangerous Dragon red it looked like
there was something wrong with me and I
thought it was an an anomaly so I've
tried again and every time I smoke red
Lin something about it just my eyes just
get blasted red they're getting red
thinking about it right now I can feel
them subconsciously I can feel myself
getting red I just [ __ ] talk about
how much that makes my eyes red I don't
know what it is I don't know what uh
what turp or what uh cannabinoid is in
there but something in that red line
just makes my eyes red and it does it to
everybody that smokes it uh at least
everybody I've seen smoke it they all
get the super [ __ ] red eye so that's
part of why it got called Redline
because Redline Bicycles back in the day
and then just because uh Redline bro
your eyes are so red and also uh Red
Line because I got so high bro I was
like is it the red line there ain't no
there's no further to go that's his high
as I'm going to be after that you ever
smoked yourself sober or just like spent
yourself you're like I'm super high and
you take another dab and you're like
wait where'd it go hey you just you just
redlined you over the max you got to
start over now you got to start remoking
anyway I am rambly as [ __ ] Redline it
got called Redline because uh the
Redline Bicycles you get red eyed and
you are as high as you're going to be
you're hitting the red line and it's got
red Lebanese hash plant RL is already in
there let's keep moving uh red Lebanese
hash plant to arise I'll describe the
red Lebanese hash plant a little bit uh
the red Lebanese hash plant is a great
plant but in my opinion uh it's a little
bit wispy it could be more sturdy more
vigorous more structurally sound
everything else is awesome it Roots
quite quickly it tastes really good the
buzz is [ __ ] awesome um and real
quickly side note sidebar somebody
recently asked me if they're allowed to
smoke hash plants as flower or if it's
only for hash no bro enjoy the flow if
you grew that and it made good flour uh
smoke it that way it's just uh it would
also make an excellent hash plant is
kind of why it got got called hash plant
and yes uh red line is a great washer
presser all that good stuff by the way
so the red Lebanese hash plant it's a
great hash plant uh it's got that old
school skunky sort of a turp to it the
only problem with it is it's not as
vigorous and structurally sound as I
would prefer uh it's got that oldw world
uh just land race sort of wispy
funkiness to it but um I knew that King
Solomon would fix it and he definitely
did so I bred the King Solomon a rise
male to the red Lebanese hash plant we
made red line let's talk about the
phenotypes that come out of that most of
the phenotypes are going to be bushy and
wide but also tall but not as tall as a
lot of my stuff it's still going to make
a big epical dominant top because that's
what King Solomon does but this one's
going to Bush out a little bit more
because that's what the red Lebanese
hash plant does it's not going to
stretch as much uh it's going to the
other one I said is going to double in
height this one uh not quite double but
probably close more like like what's the
word uh it's going to 2/3 on you is
about what it's going to do it's not
going to be as aggressively stretchy
that 21-day stretch isn't going to come
on and go shebang like the uh like the
fist bump it's going to stretch and then
just continue to grow it's not going to
be [ __ ] boom I'm stretchy out of
control it's going to do it more slowly
more controlled so you're going to get
less of a stretch but it is going to get
tall um if you top it I recommend to top
the red line take that big epical
dominant top out of there and top it and
you will get a bush of amazing beautiful
buds as especially if you are trellising
scrogging doing that sort of work then I
definitely recommend topping it take
that big top out of there uh you'll get
a lot more reaction from the plant in my
opinion in my experience make it bushy
and spread it out it's a fast grower it
is also a heavy feeder um don't feed it
as don't feed it as long as you would
fist bump and I know you may not have
both to compare but the fist bump is
going to need more feeding than the red
line but again it is a moderately heavy
feeder it can handle uh one of the good
things about red line is it can handle
some temperature swings I don't
recommend getting your plants too hot or
too cold but if you do red line will
take it very well I've seen Red Line get
too cold in the winter I've also seen
Red Line get too hot in the summer it
seems to be able to handle both of those
without getting too angry without
slowing down it still tasted good at
Harvest time it was still super
productive uh everything was perfect
even though we've had too hot and too
cold and in fact I've done both in the
same grow because I'm in Colorado I can
really [ __ ] up some plants here with my
environment and sometimes I really get
that opportunity and I have done it so
I've tortured red line and it seems to
handle all abuse and temperature very
very well I can take droughts I haven't
overwatered it on purpose but I would
assume since it's got King Solomon in
there it can handle some [ __ ] it can
definitely take a drought because I've
drought tested it before all right now
let's talk about flowering time for Red
Line in most cases red line is going to
take around 9 or 10 weeks to flower
completely if you are flowering for
smokable flower now a lot of people that
are going to grow Redline May grow it
for concentrates because this is a great
concentrate plant one thing you may
notice about Redline is that in some
phenotypes the tricomes do start to
develop early and these plants get
Frosty very early in the flowering phase
now I know a lot of you concentrate
makers you guys that wash the buds and
then press it I know you guys like to
take the plants down early this may be
very advantageous for you to cut the
plants down early because the Tricom
start growing early which means they are
starting to develop early which means
you might even be able to cut down for
concentrates even earlier so that may be
advantageous for you concentrate makers
however if you're growing for flower I
do recommend letting it go that full
recommended 9 or 10 weeks all right now
once again let's wrap back around to the
main point of this question our friend
Richard was asking about the flavors and
Aromas of red Lon so let's focus on that
now uh the main thing I like about
Redline is what I call the oldw world
flavors and Aromas now I feel like
everything tastes like like some sort of
cake or some sort of dessert or some
sort of Little Debbie snack or something
at the gas station it all smells like
that sort of snacks and treats now back
in the day weed smelled like weed it
smelled like cannabis it smelled like
ganja it smelled skunky it smelled
earthy it had a hint of spiciness to it
it had a very warm distinct smell it
wasn't hey I smell blueberries with a
hint of Muffins with a little bit of
frosting with a touch of Honey at the
end and it smelled like you might have
used a little bit of too much worm cast
and then I can smell a little bit of
what is that in there there's that bacon
grease at the end we didn't do all that
[ __ ] back in the day we went damn that
one's skunky or damn that one smells bad
that's how it used to be back in the day
and the redline turps smell like old
weed did back in the day it's got hints
of gas it's got hints of skunk it's got
that warm spicy skunky smell to it that
we' had back in the day and that's
really one of the things I love about it
so my favorite descriptive words for
Redline are going to be skunky uh maybe
a little bit spicy and then warm weed
remember when weed hits when the smell
of cannabis hits my nose the first thing
I notice is warmth it smells warm it
smells Savory it doesn't smell like
candy most of the time and it's got that
not candy smell to it now weed does
smell like candy but back in the day it
was warm and savory and skunky and
earthy uh maybe a little bit of like
different spices from the from the
kitchen might have been in there but it
didn't smell like candy and Bubblegum
and [ __ ] back in the day that's what I
think Red Line smells like is old School
oldw World turps old weed from back in
the day not not in a bad way but in a
classic way that a lot of us might miss
um before everything was uh blue dream
and Girl Scout cookies and biscotti and
gelotti and [ __ ] Skittles and all
that it tasted like weed back in the day
and that's what red line tastes like in
my opinion so my friend Richard um man
thank you for the great questions you
got me uh talking real good and you got
me to highlight two strains that a lot
of listeners have really been waiting
for some details on so ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls that is my
report on fist bump and Redline that's
my story and I am sticking to it before
I wrap this up I do want to give a shout
out to my friend Kevin jodrey shout out
to Kevin jodrey a lot of you may know
Kevin from the ganier uh Kevin's a great
dude he's a great teacher he's an
amazing [ __ ] grower uh a great
breeder a great dude all around I owe
Kevin a big shout out and a fist bump
shout out to my dude Kevin jodrey Kevin
I look forward to smoking a joint with
you soon my dude uh but anyway Kevin
jodrey has developed his um I'm not sure
what he even calls it but he's got a way
of breaking down flavors in the Cannabis
industry and he has identified the main
flavors in cannabis as Earth fuel floral
and fruit and I definitely agree that
that is probably the base there maybe
some outliers in there I'm not sure uh
where everything would fall into that
but if you can name a flavor I bet it
would fit closely in that color wheel uh
so we'll talk about these a little bit
and this may in the future help you
understand my descriptions of cannabis
when I I say it tastes earthy it tastes
fuy it tastes like a mango um what is
what Kevin's trying to do is create a
language so when I say it tastes earthy
you understand what I mean instead of
just going Earth what the [ __ ] does that
taste like so I'm going to talk a little
bit about about that briefly then we're
going to wrap up this episode and go
take some dabs uh but the four things
Kevin talks about are Earth fuel floral
and fruit now I'm going to try to talk
about those flavors and maybe name a
strain to go with each one of those
earthy um Bubba Kush uh pre98 Bubba Cush
San Fernando Valley OG cush uh most of
your kushes are going to have that
earthy flavor it tastes a little bit
like dirt uh you may get a coffee flavor
sometimes it may translate to a
chocolate flavor Big Mountain fudge cake
has got earthy coffee dirt turps to it
so that is where the uh I think that is
where I think the Earth comes in as that
sort of a flavor that like uh the the
cushy stuff the stuff that tastes like
dirt that smells like coffee uh that is
Earth how I would translate it now the
next one on the list is fuel fuel we've
all gotten gasoline right we've all
smelled diesel gas that is fuel what
strains smell like gas and fuel Sour
Diesel dude of course that classic sour
diesel smell is called diesel because it
smells like diesel fuel so that's where
the fuel comes from now let's get
creative here what if we had Earth and
fuel together what is that that's the
chem family in my mind that is where
chem comes in the chem dogs uh chem 4
chem 91 chem sister those are they've
got a little bit of fuel and a little
bit of Earth mixed in together that's
where you're getting that that that's
where the the Chim family lies that's
chemicals so when you put Earth and fuel
together that's where the chemical feel
chemical smell and Aroma comes from in
my mind I'm sure you guys can see where
this is going next we've got floral uh
the floral flavors are things like
lavender and lilacs and uh the strain
that comes to my mind well I'll say
Lavender is the first strain that comes
to my mind when we talk about floral but
if you if you smell lavender or lilacs
in your brain that's the Aromas that I
think of or roses even are floral that
sort of Flowery smell Grandma's bathroom
that sort of smell that's a flowery sort
of smell most of the time hopefully um
also Scarlet Bonas has a lot of Flowery
floral sort of turs to it in my opinion
in my
experience now the next one on our list
here is uh fruit and I'm sure most of
the people in the room understand what
I'm talking about when I say a fruity
flavor what do I mean by fruit uh fruit
can be anything from lemons to
strawberries to mangoes to watermelons
uh guavas kiwis um whatever fruit you
can think of uh fruit that's a category
of cannabis of ganja flavors of tpin so
when we're talking about when I'm
talking about these different flavors
I'm just trying to give us all like a
collective uh starting point to
understand what I'm talking about and
once again I want to give a big shout
out to my buddy Kevin JRE for kind of
listing and establishing this Baseline
for naming these flavors this definitely
defitely helps us all communicate better
and together if we all know that when I
say fruit I'm talking about fruit and
then we can expand on that by saying
lemons or oranges or watermelons or
mangoes or guavas or cherries we can we
can make more categories from there but
I think most things are going to fit
into these four categories anyway I just
wanted to touch on the way that a lot of
us in the Cannabis industry think about
flavors and Aromas and how we describe
it and try to get everybody on the page
here so that when we talk about turps we
all kind of know what we're talking
about and I'm going to rant about one
more thing just to make it fun uh you
don't hear me talk about the word tpping
profile a lot you don't hear me talk
about TPS a lot you don't hear me say
this strain is high in humulene this
train this strain is high in uh
terpinolene because uh the average bear
the average cannabis consumer doesn't
know what the [ __ ] that means anyway if
I said yeah this one smells a lot like
trinoline with some humulene in it and
it's got some caropine in it people are
going to go what the [ __ ] is that dude
but if I say yo this one tastes like
Lemon Diesel with a bit of honey in it
you can go lemon I know what lemon
tastes like diesel I've smelled diesel
Fu before okay lemons and Diesel that's
good together with a little bit of honey
oh that sounds nice or you know this one
tastes like chocolate cake with a little
bit of vanilla frosting your brain knows
what chocolate cake and vanilla frosting
tastes like that's why I try to describe
the things the way I do and I don't say
h this one smells like humulene and
kopine cuz nobody knows what the [ __ ]
that is all right that's my ramble for
the day I am sticking to it ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers Clon Cutters Paul
and Chuckers All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another ramble filed episode of The Grow
fromy yourheart podcast if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns you know that I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
fromy yourheart at hotmail.com don't be
shy reach out let me know what you think
of the podcast also you are more than
welcome to argue in the comment section
that's right let me know how you feel in
the comments I do enjoy reading the
comment section fill it up keep the
party going uh where else do we go from
there oh yeah like And subscribe that's
right um like And subscribe click like
And subscribe it's that easy all you
cool kids know what you're doing that is
all I've got for this episode everybody
I am done rambling I'll be back in a
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy caddy
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad mother
tell to take another D grab your p in
about the back Ro is in the lab sit back
relax hold up