[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the podcast party people I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 846 six of
the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in today's show before I get
too far I want to send a big thank you
shout out to everybody who has watched
an episode of the podcast that's right
we recently hit 1 million views on
YouTube that's right 1 million organic
views on YouTube uh big thanks Big shout
out to all 1 million of you who have
watched the podcast I do appreciate that
uh make sure you click like click
subscribe and keep watching so we can
get that two million views all right I
don't want to waste too much time here
at the start of the show let's jump
right into the question and answer
portion of today's podcast of course I
do have a website that website is iy
genetics.com at the top of that website
there is a tab that says grow help or
grow questions if you click on that tab
you can send me your grow question if I
read your question here on the podcast I
will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds off of idirect tocom
today's first question came from our new
friend Brian I do like this question a
lot my buddy Brian make sure you check
your inbox because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from iy
direct.com the question says yo rosta
Jeff how do you come up with the names
of your strains that is a very good
question many of you may not know that
not only am I a podcaster but I am also
the head breeder and sole proprietor of
iy genetics premium seeds I make a lot
of regular and feminized seed seed so if
you're new here uh that just catches you
up I do make those seeds I am the
breeder I'm the one that makes the
decisions on what to breed how to breed
it when to breed it then the funnest
part of the whole job is deciding how to
name those New Creations our buddy Brian
wants to know how do you come up with
those names there are uh countless ways
that I I am inspired by strain names A
lot of them you may have noticed uh are
Grateful Dead songs I am very inspired I
love the Grateful Dead I've been a dead
head a dead fan uh since about 95 so a
lot of Grateful Dead culture in me I
name strains after the Grateful Dead uh
Dark Hollow Franklin's Tower Scarlet
Bonas those were all Grateful Dead songs
there are plenty more those are the
first three to pop off the top of my
head also I Nam stuff after Fish songs
um character Zero is a fish song uh
Maize was named after a fish song
rhombus is not a fish song but it is
named after some fish lore that's where
the the fish comes in rhombus is a fish
thing uh Sunday show is kind of a a nod
to the entire jamb band culture in the
jam band world we say never miss a
Sunday show if you go see your favorite
jam band on Sunday you will get a
special performance a special show it's
like church it's like a family gathering
it's always a good time so Sunday show
became a strain name then uh what else
do we have we I named stuff after the
Ninja Turtles um I've got Leonardo
Donatello uh Raphael Michelangelo bbop
Rocksteady Shredder April O'Neal Baxter
Stockman those of course were all
inspired by one of my childhood favorite
cartoons the Teenage Mutant Ninja
Turtles now currently another line that
I've recently put out uh is named after
another pop culture icon I've got Rose
Sophia Dorothy and I always skip one of
them but you know the four Golden Girls
Who who do we got Rose Sophia Dorothy
and there's blanch how did we forget
blanch that hussy uh we got the four
Golden Girls those are named after of
course the Golden Girls uh sitcom TV
show from when I was a kid um frequency
shift how is frequency shift named um
I'm very into a reg artist named Natalie
rise big shout out to Natalie rise uh
she's a beautiful person amazing artist
uh she makes great music she sings
[ __ ] amazingly well she also uh is
very spiritual person a very energetic
person a very positive person and when
she comes into the room there's a
frequency shift and I named The Strain
frequency shift in honor of my friend
Natalie rise uh jammie The Strain Jammy
was named after my friend jir Morgan his
nickname is Jamie I made a strain based
on the traits that he likes and I named
it Jamie cuz his family calls him jammie
his name is jir I'm thinking about other
strains off the top of my head fist bump
why did I call fist bump fist bump um uh
fist bump bro when you see when I see
some friends when uh other dreads see
each other uh just give each other a
quick fist bump and I thought fist bump
was a cool name fist bump it works real
well I can't think of other strain names
bubble goat okay so this is another
Redline I talked earlier about how
Redline got its name on a previous
episode I called Redline Redline because
when I smoke it my eyes get bloody red
and real heavy also I used to ride
bicycles when I was a teenager I rode GT
Bicycles but Redline bikes were real
popular red Lin's got red Lebanese
hashplant in there so a lot of it comes
from pop culture references a lot of it
uh the names just create themselves like
bubble goat bubble goat is Indiana
Bubblegum and Golden Goat bubble goat
that name made itself gorilla goat
Gorilla Glue and Golden Goat those kind
of names make themselves uh peggo was
another one named after a Grateful Dead
song uh sometimes it's just random stuff
but sometimes it's uh just things that
happen to uh that it just tells you what
they are bubble goat like I was saying
it's just bubble goat so it depends on
cultural references it depends on uh
maybe just telling you the names of the
two strains together we'll describe
we'll make a perfect name for it bubble
goat gorilla goat I'm sure there's more
of those uh sometimes it's just random
stuff sometimes a friend will say
something cool one day uh Mike was
talking and he said something about the
word Afterglow and I said bro quit
talking because that is a strain name
and I wrote down Afterglow now we got a
strain called Afterglow um Storm Shadow
the old strain Storm Shadow that was
named after a G.I Joe character Storm
Shadow the silent killer um what else do
we got I'm trying to think of strains
that are available now Congo Ripper how
did we come up with Congo Ripper that is
Congo to Jack the Ripper that should be
fairly obvious there how those came up
uh White Chapel White Chapel is Golden
Goat and Jack the Ripper uh Jack the
Ripper was famous murderer a famous
serial killer uh the White Chapel killer
is also what he was known as so uh it
got known as White Chapel as the cross
I'm inspired by a lot of different
random things sometimes I'll smoke a
strain and get a certain flavor out of
it and that's how I name it sometimes I
try to honor the crosses sometimes it's
just a pop culture reference or some
sort of energy thing that I thought of
uh that I thought of when I smoked that
strain or that the two names made me
think of sometimes it's just totally
completely random uh Sometimes some
sometimes I don't have a name in mind
until I smoke it sometimes I've already
got a strain name in mind when I create
the line uh orange gasm I knew that
orange gasm was going to be super
delightful it's going to make your toes
curl uh it was going to have that
beautiful orange flavor orange gasm was
that just happened naturally so it all
just kind of depends I've got a list of
strain names if something cool comes up
uh sometimes it's a video game name nuke
town uh The Strain nuk town that came
from I used to play Black Ops all the
time Call of Duty Black Ops shout out to
Mike for getting me addicted to video
games for a short time uh I miss playing
video games with you buddy but I used to
play Black Ops and new town was the map
if you're going to play any sort of
video game newe Town 247 around the
holidays was the way to go I'd love to
Camp up in that one bedroom and just
snipe little kids that are new to the
game all day if you guys don't like
campers you definitely don't want to
play a shooting game with me but that is
where nuk town came from is the video
game uh from Black Ops that is nuk Town
um I'm sure there's a billion more strin
names that I could give you names for
uh chemical cocktail why did I call it
chemical cocktail because it smells it's
got chem uh chem dog in there and it's
got the Chim dog Aroma comes through but
it also smells a little bit like if you
took a kiwi strawberry Snapple and put
some chemicals inside of it it tastes
good but it's also like some chemicals
it's like you work at a nuclear plant
and you're having lunch break and you're
drinking something fruity it's like it
tastes good but also I feel like I may
grow a third arm or something from
drinking this chemical cocktail bro uh
cand delicious what is cand delicious a
lot of people like what does that even
mean cand delicious uh that [ __ ] is
delicious and tastes like candy cand
delicious bro you got to get creative in
this day and age a lot of the names are
taken um I try to do my due diligence
and research a name and think about it
like uh has somebody else used this what
else does this mean is there another
weird reference I don't understand about
this I try to do my research and then um
you wouldn't believe how many times
other people come up and they say hey
bro uh that the this one's already taken
sometimes that happens and I apologize
and usually I just stop making it um big
mountain fudge cake what are the name
Big Mountain fudge cake come from I
don't know if I've ever revealed this
publicly Big Mountain fudge cake one of
my favorite cartoons TV shows back in
the day was of course King of the Hill
uh King of the Hill was an awesome
cartoon animated series I don't know
what you want to call it call it
whatever you want either way shout out
to Hank uh shout out to Bobby shout out
to Peggy uh the entire King Of The Hill
Family even the little dog ladybird um
we give a whole shout out to Luan even
if we want anyway let's get back to the
point Big Mountain fudge cake in the
show King of the Hill they started a
band um the name of the band was Big
Mountain fudge cake they referred to
themselves as the fudge um I thought
it'd be really fun to name a strain Big
Mountain fudge cake of course I took a
strain with some chocolate turps in
there big mountain fudge cake so the
names are random and sporadic uh
sometimes I have the names in mind
before I even make a strain sometimes I
don't even think of the name until after
I smoke the strain I do have a long list
of strain names and I go through it and
I'm super picky it's got the strain a
strain name can make or break your
creation people may buy 2500 packs of a
pack of seeds just because of the name
uh they may not buy any of it because of
the name I really think Scarlett Bonas
if it would have been named something
differently it would have sold uh better
I think that one was slept on simply
because of the name there are some
things um I had a lady tell me that she
did not like my strain name Bounty
Killer so that's another one we can
touch on uh Bounty Killer uh was named
after a reggae artist named Bounty
Killer that's simply where that name
came from the kangi Kush was named after
a reggae artist called szla kangi
Capleton was named after a reggae artist
called Capleton I'm sure you could see
where this is going but I named a lot of
stuff after Grateful Dead songs Fish
songs ree artists uh things are named
after people some of the Stray names are
kind of jokes uh Saka sule and the
Machine what the heck is that about uh
many of you have probably caught on now
that I'm a huge comedy fan I love comedy
I love going to comedy shows uh laughter
is medicine music is medicine I love
music and comedy but the machine is
named after Bert kryer he's got his F
his most famous bit is called the
machine he tears off his shirt he yells
I'm the machine that's [ __ ] where
that name came from Saka sule came from
an episode of your mom's house uh not
just an episode of your mom's house but
also the host of your mom's house
podcast Tom sigura one of the best
comedians on the planet he went on Larry
King you know the old guy that used to
wear the suspenders he might be gone now
rest in peace if he's gone uh but Larry
King wore the suspenders and Larry King
asked Tom Tom sigura what his um like a
weakness what's it called one of your
weaknesses your um anyway he asked him
what a weakness was like one of his his
personal weaknesses I forget the [ __ ]
name of the the thing that he asked him
it's like a trait he's like what's one
of your weaknesses and he said chocolate
Soule and Larry King's a [ __ ] 124
years old he didn't understand he said
Saka sule with a big question mark and a
dumbfounded voice and so to that Tom
sigura just smiled back and said
chocolate sule and then Larry King got
it at that point but Saka sufle was a
madeup word that Larry King said one
time and that is how Saka sufle became
that's just how uh that happened he said
it I liked it uh the first hundred packs
of that strain that I sold came in a
package with an image of Larry King with
his suspenders and his microphone in
front of him those were two of his
iconic things
the first 100 packs of the machine I
sold also came in a custom package with
a silhouette of Bert ker holding a
microphone I had to do the silhouette I
didn't want to do any copyright
copyright violations but those were two
strains that sometimes I had to explain
the name another strain that people ask
me about a lot this strain name is
double Paula what is double Paula um
double Paula is a strain that I made
around 2000 I don't remember exactly I
want to say Circa 2016 2018 somewhere in
that time frame uh that's when double
paa was made people ask me a lot of
questions about double paa um I made
that one around 2016 it grows kind of
tall kind of quickly um tastes real good
good strong TPS on it nice and potent
one of my favorite strains um yeah
that's double Paula I get a lot of
questions about that one and guess what
I'm going to continue to get questions
because I ain't going to tell you [ __ ]
about double Paula right now I love the
mystery I love the mystery around double
PA it's a beautiful amazing strain you
guys love it uh the regular seed sold
out quite quickly rumor has it there
might be feminized seeds of that double
paa coming up anyway this was a great
question you got me rambling for at
least 10 good minutes about this thank
you I do appreciate it I love talking
about strain names I feel like there
were a lot more that I wanted to cover I
could probably hit pause go to the
website we could talk about a billion
strain names but the strain names are
inspired by uh Just Like Music just like
art just the things in my life uh the
Ninja Turtles gii Joe video games uh
reggae artist great Dead songs Fish
songs uh just random references to
things tinfoil hat why did I call
tinfoil hat tinfoil hat two reasons uh
because it makes you paranoid when you
smoke too much tinfoil hat you're
peeking out the windows and [ __ ]
thinking shit's going on that's not
going on also there's a famous podcast
called tinfoil hat hosted by Sam tripol
um it may be a little nod a little shout
out to Sam triple so that's tinf foil
hat there are a bunch of them you guys
uh Bobby Knight oh let me talk about
Bobby Knight then we will wrap up this
part because I feel like I really want
to give a shout out to Bobby Knight
Bobby Knight uh who is Bobby Knight
Bobby Knight is a uh Bobby Knight is PED
Bobby Knight was a basketball coach for
Indiana uh my grandparents both came
from Indiana um they were what you call
hooers and they were into hooer
basketball so my grandparents both knew
Bobby Knight very well they followed him
I come from a big Basketball family my
grandparents my uncles loved basketball
I'm 6'5 and everyone's disappointed that
I don't give a [ __ ] about basketball I
can shoot but I don't care to play D at
all so I just stand there and watch
everybody score on you and then I go try
to shoot my own shot we're getting
sidetracked anyway Bobby Knight my
grandparents were Indiana basketball
fans Bobby Knight was a coach for
Indiana basketball I got a hold of the
Indiana bubble gum the classic bubble
gum strain that comes from Indiana I
crossed the Indiana bubblegum to
Afterglow so right as those seeds were
coming to fruition and almost ready to
harvest Bobby Knight passed away and it
was like something just told me name the
strain Bobby Knight that gave me a way
to honor my grandparents it gave me a
cool strain name and we got to honor
Bobby Knight and then all of the uh
basketball fans knew what it was right
away and all the Indiana basketball fans
definitely knew what it was right away
so Bobby Knight was named after a
basketball coach from Indiana and my
grandparents were from Indiana and they
were a couple of my favorite people of
course so they inspired me in a lot of
ways I wanted to pay some sort of
tribute to my grandparents by naming a
ganja strain sort of after them but it's
Bobby KN so it doesn't have their name
in it or anything they're not
implemented in my business here but it's
a nod it's a shout out to my
grandparents and also of course Bobby
Knight and of course to that Indiana
background that is in my blood all right
that is my answer and I'm sticking to it
uh my new friend Brian dude make sure
you check your inbox check your spam cuz
by the time this episode comes out you
have got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from iy
direct.com all right let's keep this
momentum moving I do have another great
question here in front of me of course
before we jump into the next one let me
remind you to like And subscribe that's
right if you like the podcast make sure
you click that like button and also if
you're not already subscribed please do
subscribe that way every time I put out
a new episode you'll get a notification
and you don't miss any of my amazing
cannabis content all right let's keep
going that's enough rambling this one
came from my friend poly figs what up
poly figs this also came from that
growel tab on iir which means poly figs
you win a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds off of idirect tocom make sure you
check your inbox check that spam a lot
of times the messages do go to the spam
folder I don't know why I do apologize
also one more quick disclaimer those
coupon codes do expire those gift
certificates do expire many people ask
me is that expiration date real yes that
expiration date is real as [ __ ] you got
to use that coupon code by then if you
don't use it by then it tells me a
couple of things you didn't check your
spam also it tells me you didn't listen
to the podcast because if you listen to
the show you would know that you got
your message read which would then tell
you to go check your inbox so if you
didn't get it you snooze you lose I
cannot resend it I do apologize for that
but paully figs go check your inbox get
that coupon code for your free seats at
iir the question says rosta Jeff what
are your thoughts on clone clone
degeneration from the mother plant is
there a way to revive or rejuvenate old
clones I think you mean like rejuvenate
an old plant so um let me first touch on
something um he said degeneration clone
degeneration is a thing sometimes mother
plants get tired they get old uh if you
abuse a plant if you don't give it the
best care if it's uh threatened with
bugs or problems or inadequate
environment sometimes these plants can
get old and tired and stuck performing
that the way the way that they used to
that is what this listener means by
degeneration there is another thing that
happens people call it genetic drift
that is a different thing completely
I've done a full podcast on genetic
drift uh in the Cannabis world we are
using the phrase the term genetic drift
inaccurately incorrectly as we do many
terms in this industry in this business
in this community however today I want
to make sure we are not talking about
genetic drift that is not what this
listener is referring to this is
degeneration when a plant starts getting
old and tired uh it happens with every
living organism eventually if you don't
give it the ideal diet environment if it
faces any threats any problems pests or
pathogens or it could be a lot of other
things at this time um overwatering
underwatering a lot of stress on this
plant can cause future generations to
not be as healthy as they were the
genetics will be exactly the same but
the overall health of the new cuting can
may not be as as optimal as previous
generations of this plant so this
listener is saying is there a way to
revive or rejuvenate these plants um yes
unfortunately I feel like we have
already surpassed this time of the year
unless you've got some supplemental
lighting that may help you out but what
many breeders and Growers are known to
do is when the right time of year comes
around you can put small copies of your
plants outdoors and put them out there
in the sunshine and that Sunshine will
rejuven revive and correct many of the
problems that your plants may be
experiencing I've probably said it on
the podcast a few times I'll say it
again the sun is Magic the sun works
wonders the sun is the fixer the Healer
the sun will cure a lot of things if you
can put a small plant outside uh if you
can veg a plant or get a small plant
even if you got a large Plant put it
outside veg it let it be outside for a
week maybe two weeks you will see great
Improvement if if you put that plant out
at the proper time of year that depends
on where you live your location
geographically geographically that word
was easy to say it depends on your
location on the globe uh if you're in
certain regions you could do this all
year long if you're in Colorado you've
got about a three or four week window
where this is an opportunity so it
depends on where you are it depends on
your light if you've got a greenhouse
where you can provide supplemental
lighting this would work beautifully put
it out there just about anytime that
it's not too cold get that sunshine on
it for a few hours a day that will help
you correct the plant add some
artificial light to go with that
sunshine and you will see improvements
in the health of that plant overall in
just a couple of weeks of course you do
need to feed the plant properly you also
make sure not to get any you need to
make sure not to acquire any bugs any
pests we don't want to take more pest
indoors uh that could just lead to a
whole another slew of problems in the
near future we are going to talk about
integrated Pest Management that's
something that came up today on the
Discord so that is on my mind to talk
about in the near future but a way to
rejuvenate clones uh that have gotten
old that have gotten Dusty that just
don't seem to be as healthy as they once
were put them outside give them plenty
of light uh get them going Outdoors get
that sunshine on them feed them well uh
let them feel that outdoor environment
and they will come back around they will
get healthy again this will work for
most plants uh that are just a little
bit beat up looking old if they're beat
to [ __ ] and they're if they're supposed
to die sometimes you just got to let it
go you should have been taken better
care of that plant overall if it was
that important to you all right my
friend Paulie figs it's good to see a
message from you it's great too I see
from the Discord where I recognize you
it's good to be able to send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds so
make sure you check that inbox because
you got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds at iy direct.com all right ladies
and gentlemen boys and girls pimps hoes
friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers BMX Racers fruit
booters all of you beautiful kids out
there I want to thank each and every one
of you for listening to to another
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast I know this was a quick episode
but short and sweet we'll keep it good
before I get too rambly thanks for
listening if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
the email address of course is grow from
your heart at hotmail.com if you want to
send those grow questions and get an
opportunity to win free seeds do that by
using the growel tab on iry genetics.com
that's right I genetics.com everything
you need is on the website there's a
link to the Discord server join us on
Discord where we talk about growing all
day long also there's a link to the
merch where you can get a grinder a
rolling tray a t-shirt an ashtray a
stash pot you can get a grow from your
heart podcast hat there's a bunch of
great stuff at the merch store also
there is a link to iir where you can get
what seeds that's right go get those
seeds at I
redirect.sh will be available go get the
individual dual packs or the bundles go
grab those now at idirect docomo if I
did not read your question on today's
podcast please do not feel discouraged
I've got a small mountain of emails to
work my way through so maybe I will read
your question on a future episode so
keep those questions coming and keep
watching because maybe your question
will pop up on a future podcast all
right ladies and gentlemen that is all
I've got for you for today's episode you
know I'll be back in a week with fresh
new content I want to give a big shout
out to my buddy Hawaiian Jay and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
mother time to take another DB grab your
p in and I go find the
back is in the lab sit back them up
relax hold up