[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome back
podcast world I'm your host rosta Jeff
this is episode
848 of to grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another fun episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
in just a moment before we jump into the
podcast I do want to talk about my
recent weekend vacation that's right if
you listen to the show I did mention I
was taking a break to go on a vacation
and I had a super good time that's right
I flew to Las Vegas and I got to see the
last two dead and Company shows at the
sphere the band was amazing the sphere
was amazing the visuals at the sphere
were awesome uh everybody at the sphere
was amazing all of the friends that I
saw there and made there were amazing uh
if we ran into each other at the dead Co
experience in Vegas this weekend uh if I
gave you a high five a fist bump or
maybe a hug maybe we shared a
conversation perhaps we hit each other's
pens uh I gave somebody a pen also if
that was you that I gave a pen to you
all of those folks if I met you for the
first time and gave you a fist bump we
got a handshake off if we've been
internet friends and finally got to meet
at the deaden company shows yo big thank
you big shout out for making my dead and
Company weekend an amazing experience
that's right uh the sphere does not pay
me to talk about this the sphere does
not pay me to advertise but I'll talk
briefly about it maybe maybe some of you
just don't know uh the sphere is a new
venue in Las Vegas it is a big sphere
it's a big ball the outside of the
sphere is all a big LED screen I don't
know how to explain the technology but
they are constantly displaying crazy
video displays on the outside of screen
it's amazing um you can just drive by or
walk by the sphere or even fly by the
sphere and see amazing visual displays
on the outside but once you get in it is
even more amazing uh before the show
starts it feels sort of like you're
stuck in an iPad or you're a screen
saver but once the music gets going it
is amazing there's a
270° screen inside the sphere that means
everywhere you look except behind you is
a video screen so dead end company who
are the uh there are two remaining
members of the Grateful Dead that still
play and they filled in the rest of the
band with some amazing players uh they
call themselves dead in company but two
remaining members of the Grateful Dead
tour with the rest of the band and the
dead and Company nailed it at the fear
they put on an amazing show the last two
shows were extra awesome uh the night
before the last show was actually the
29th anniversary of the passing of Jerry
Garcia who was the lead guitar player in
the band for several years uh then he
passed in '95 they've had several
incantations or incarnations of the band
since then uh currently they've got John
Mayer playing guitar which a lot of
people think is wild at first I didn't
want to like it either seeing John Mayer
with the Grateful Dead but after the
first time I saw him play uh I knew that
he was the guy for the job and he's been
doing it for several years and he
absolutely crushed it at the sphere uh
dead and Co was amazing the last two
shows were amazing the sphere was
amazing uh the sphere visuals were super
amazing I've gotten to see uh four fish
shows and two deaden company shows and
the visuals that dead end company put on
were amazing um also everybody at the
sphere is super helpful and amazing they
don't pay me to talk about it I think
I've said that uh The Spar and deaden
company definitely did not pay me for
this free advertising but if you get an
opportunity to go see a band that you
like at the sphere I highly recommend it
it is it is an amazing experience it's
easy to get in it's easy to get out uh
the drinks lines and snack lines are
easy there's never a real long line uh
they've got a bunch of helpful people
around there to help you out if you
happen to be uh in need of any sort of
assistance somebody will pop out of
nowhere and help you out so shout out to
the sphere shout out to dead and Co and
once again big shout out to all of the
Grateful Dead family that I got to see
uh meet and hang out with at the dead
and Company shows all right I feel like
that's enough rambling here at the start
of the show uh maybe some of you loved
that maybe some of you weren't into it I
do try to share some of my personal
experience with you guys a lot of you
have been listening for a long time and
I feel like we're afraid friend so thank
you for letting me share my experience
with you now let's work our way into the
question and answer portion of today's
podcast at the top of the show I said
there was an opportunity to win free
seeds how do you win those seeds here we
go I've got a website that website is IR
genetics.com on the top of that website
there is a row of tabs one of those tabs
does say grow help or grow questions if
you click on that Tab and you send me a
good grow question perhaps I will read
your question here on the show if I read
that question here on the show I will
send you a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from idirect decom that's right
you can get the seeds at idirect decom
the first question on today's show came
from my new friend Shaggy big shout out
to my buddy Shaggy grows the question
goes just like this it says Hey family I
hope all is good big thanks for so much
constantly dropping the knowledge bro
you are so welcome for dropping the
knowledge I feel like if I didn't share
the uh the gift of growing I would
explode there's something I've been
given a Gift of Gab I've been given the
gift to understand cannabis plants if I
didn't share that with you I would be
disrespectful to whatever you believe in
they gave me this gift so I am rambly
and I love talking about cannabis so
this is how it worked out you get a
podcast I'm glad you appreciate it it
goes on it says I have a breeding
question for you that's good I love
breeding questions and I have got a
breeding answer for you it says let's
just say I have a female that has some
desirable traits and it is valuable to
reverse it and use it as a donor plant
all right I understand where you're
going with that you've got a female
plant with the traits you want to take
two clones of it reverse one use one as
a donor one as a receiver you can make
S1 seeds and preserve this plant so far
this makes very beautiful sense now
here's where it get gets weird it says
uh can I do this while still using a
male plant as a donor as well so they
want to take that pollen from that
reversed female and they also want to
take pollen from a traditional male
plant and put both of those batches of
pollen on their single female pollen
receiver plant I understand that part so
far I don't recommend it however I do
understand it it goes on it says since
our favorite plant can take multiple
pollen at once how will this affect the
seeds since the Reversed pollen will
only have female chromosomes all right I
understand what you're asking um how
it's going to affect the seeds is you're
going to have seeds uh with different
baby daddies you're going to have a
whole bunch of Mori Povich uh sort of
stuff going on you're going to get that
feminized pollen is going to hit the
plant and make feminized seeds all of
those seeds will be female that will be
your S1 so if we took that one plant and
the same plant pollinated it that is an
S1 there will be also other seeds in
there that will be f1s from that male
that you pollinated that plant with now
those seeds what they're going to do
they're going to make male and female
seeds uh we can tell that the pollen is
what determines sex and my science in my
thinking pollen is what determines sex
why do I believe that feminized seeds
I'm using fem pollen to make fem seeds
is what I'm doing so I believe that the
uh the sex is determined by the pollen
just like when males and females breed
that male sperm does contain the it
determines the sex of the the the
progyny seeds in cannabis are just like
that the male pollen does hold that male
or female chromosome so if I take
feminized pollen and I put it on that
plant we're only going to get female
seeds if I take that male plant and put
it on there we're going to get male and
female seeds from that because the
pollen does come or the sex does come
from the pollen so what you're going to
find is you're going to find male plants
you're going to find female plants
you'll also find feminized plants but
you won't know if they're feminized
because they're going to come just like
the regular female plants you won't know
they'll be girls so you're going to get
a bunch of girl plants probably and
you're going to have male plants pop up
in here I don't like this idea because I
am a a commercial seed maker a
commercial seed seller I need to know
the pedigree of every single seed which
I sell I can't have something where I
say it could be this Dad or it could be
this Dad that doesn't work for me that
doesn't work for the market that doesn't
work for my breeding uh my goals my my
project if you want to do this you can
just know that you've got what I call a
Mori poic situation on your hand who is
the baby daddy who is not the father
when you grow these out you're going to
get a bunch bu of wild different
phenotypes because you've got an S1
making that phenotype or those
phenotypes and then you've got a full
new F1 hybrid showing those phenotypes
in there so you're going to see a bunch
of different variation and you may be
able to identify what's what but you may
not and as a breeder I like to know
where uh what my project is doing I like
to know what that male did to the female
and what the female did to the female
this is kind of just making a mess in my
opinion if you want to do this just to
make a bunch of seeds to have some seeds
to play with and some [ __ ] chaos in a
grow that's perfect but don't sell these
don't give them away don't trade them
these are for you these are your private
stash for you to play with you knew what
you did you're accepting the risk you're
accepting that outcome just you don't
don't Pawn these off on anybody else and
make them deal with your Mori your Mori
Povich situation I do have more notes
written down here um it says Mory poic
is what my note says and then it says
you will have some regs and some fem uh
you're going to see a lot of different
phenotypes and you basically got two
dads in there this plant just basically
got knocked up by two different dads and
you get to guess who the baby daddy is
on all the progyny when you grow them
out so let me reread this make sure we
covered everything make sure we got it
right um let's see I've got a female has
some desirable traits reverse it and
also use a male donor yes I see where
we're going uh multiple pollins yes it
will receive multiple pollin at once but
all the seeds are also going to come out
uh it's like random seeds it's like just
playing a guessing game you don't know
what did what so so like I said if you
do want to make these seeds and do it
for fun have a good time uh don't give
them away don't sell them don't trade
them this is your Frankenstein for you
to play with why not just do it twice
why not just pollinate this plant make
the fem seeds uh wait a little while do
another project make reg seeds that's
what I would recommend that would be
much more strategic and much more
beneficial for the future of cannabis
when we're breeding my theory my idea is
to uh improve upon the plant if you've
got plant a and plant be and they're
both eights or nines and you're breeding
with two eights or two nines or a nine
and a eight hopefully you got two t but
I understand that's really I don't even
have two t I'm super [ __ ] picky but
hopefully you take two eights or two
nins and you breed them and you come out
with a solid 9.5 or maybe even a 10 if
you breed two eights together and you
come out with a six or a seven you done
[ __ ] up you did not do us any service
all you did at that point was make seeds
and anybody can make seeds that's when
you're pollen chucking that is my uh
public service announcement for this
plant if you're going to be a breeder
the goal is to improve upon the genetics
of the plant and in my opinion in my
standards U Mory poit [ __ ] is not
considered improving uh what if you find
something Stellar you've got a cool
plant but then do you know what it came
from I that kind of some people care
about that some don't the breeder in me
really really does all right my dude
Shaggy grow thank you for the good
question you got me rambling pretty good
make sure you check your inbox and do
check your spam folder because you've
got a coupon code for a free free pack
of seedss from idirect decom I hate that
I've got to say this one more time but
there will be an expiration date on your
coupon code that will be a real
expiration date that coupon will expire
at that day it will no longer be valid
you'll try to use it and it will go
it'll be just like the Family Feud Steve
Harvey will be like can I see
coupon no coupon bro there will not be a
coupon this tells me two things if you
don't use your coupon by the time that
it it expires cuz I give you plenty of
time in my opinion tells me a couple
things first you didn't check your email
all you got to do is check your email
check your spam folder that coupon code
will be there second the second thing it
tells me when I read your question on
the show you didn't watch the episode
because if you saw the episode with your
question most people I'm sure that
shaggy right now before he even finished
he pressed pause or he's doing something
he just [ __ ] pulled out the computer
he's like bro I got free seeds he's
already pulling up the coupon code
that's how it works if you're driving
you get home you go buy the seeds right
away so if you haven't got the coupon
code before it expires it tells me
you're not checking your email which you
should probably be doing anyway and also
it tells me you didn't even listen to
the show so that's why you didn't get
the free seeds because you didn't even
listen to the episode where your
question was read I give you most of the
time four to six weeks on those coupon
codes so when it expires guess what it
expired I kind of
apologize kind of don't all right we're
going to keep this momentum going I've
got another great question here in front
of me this one came from Frank White
sounds like a movie character Frank
White what's up dude I hope everything's
going well for you Frank White the
question says what's up rosta Jeff
what's up Frank White thank you for the
great question my dude make sure you
check your inbox check that spam folder
because like I said you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds and I
would hate for it to expire now the
question says first and foremost I
appreciate what you do for the community
your show has been a great listen on the
drive to work and while working in the
garden uh man thank you I'm glad that I
can help you out I'm glad you app
appreciate it and I'm glad I can kill
time on the way to work and in the
garden I listen to a lot of podcasts so
I know exactly what you mean I'm glad I
can give that back to you it says I've
got two questions for you today well my
dude I'm only going to send you one
coupon code but I will read both of your
questions the first one says how do you
feel about collaborating with other
breeders I totally understand testing
quality control selection preferences
Etc can make things complicated but I
was hoping to get your opinion on the
topic that's a really good question
collabs with other
breeders um a lot of us breeders are
very picky a lot of us breeders are very
um I can't even think of the word I'm
trying to say meticulous um words in
that vein we like to do things our way
some of us don't play well with others I
like to play well with others I try but
we're very um we're breeders for a
reason a lot of us came from this
background before everything was legal
um some of us are criminals some of us
are uh we come come from Criminal back
background and we are uh more used to
and more familiar kind of hiding in the
shadows and doing this [ __ ] on our own
because back in the day you couldn't
tell anybody what you were doing if I
told people back in the day that I was
growing ganja uh they would either rob
me or snitch on me or some [ __ ] would go
wrong so we had to keep it on the down
low and also that is part of what uh
traumatized a lot of us we are a lot of
us old school Growers and breeders are a
little bit broken we're used to looking
over our shoulder uh we're used to
worrying about [ __ ] we're used to not
trusting anybody because that's how it
used to be I know it's unhealthy uh I go
to [ __ ] therapy now to try to fix
that [ __ ] to be honest with you but um a
lot of us are a little bit broken
because we've been doing illegal
activity it's hard to trust people it's
hard to have good friends it's hard to
build real relationships uh when you're
looking over your shoulder and worried
about your best friend maybe trying to
rob you steal from you so that a lot of
us come from that background a lot of us
know the risks a lot of us have made a
lot of the Breeders have made good
friends cuz we all come from the same
thing we understand uh that history of
our lives but a lot of us don't play
well with others so it's a little bit
easier to just do it by yourself now
there are several breeders out there
that I would love to collab with and I
know that we would work well shout out
to Jinx Proof I want to work with Jinx
uh big shout out to Brad from raw Jinx
and ra Brad are the first two I think of
when it comes to doing a collab but
we've talked about it um and it never
comes to fruition I'm not blaming them
they're not blaming me we're busy
[ __ ] people we're doing our own thing
and to get two breeders on the same
schedule with the same idea to make a
plan that's a whole another ball game
for us to line up and we're already kind
of doing our thing uh Jinx has a family
Jinx is doing things where for Autism
Awareness Rose and Jinx stay super busy
with jinxy JR I'd love to work with them
when the time is right I'm a busy dude
I'm doing a podcast I got my own I've
got a 21-year-old daughter I host drum
circles I do a whole bunch of I got the
seed company that keeps me super busy
doing my thing Brad's doing his thing
there's no uh I'm not blaming anybody
I'm just saying the the time just hasn't
happened for all of that I like to I
would enjoy it but a lot of us would
rather just stick to ourselves and uh
play on our own we don't play well with
others because of the history I'm
learning I'm growing I'm maturing I'm
much better at playing with others at
this point but um it just hasn't come to
fruition now what does happen is
somebody's out there yelling it already
it's probably Tardis uh yelling at the
screen going what about forced collabs
almost everything a breeder does is a
forced collab if I take a plant uh let's
talk about the
um the the Cherry Paloma Cherry Paloma
came from Brad at Raw so I guess I have
collab with Brad from raw even though he
doesn't know it um I got the Jr token
Cherry Paloma cut everybody had that cut
for a little while I've taken that cut
and I've bred it to a couple of things I
BR it to something that I originated and
I bred it to some stuff that other
breeders also have originated so in a
sense I am force collabing with Brad
from raw uh there is some of my stuff
bred to several of or several of my
things bred to to his Cherry Paloma I
reversed a couple things H the Cherry
Paloma the skunk number one mainly um
also there's a uh BC Lemon Skunk to
Cherry Paloma there's a bunch of great
stuff out there that I've made with the
Cherry so I am forced collabing with
Brad from raw and it it's not that Brad
and I don't have a thing going on we
didn't talk about it or anything I just
had that plant and I pollinated it it
just makes it easier there's no I'm
doing my thing my business my sales my
way and he can do his thing we don't
have to will always be friends because
there will never be a business argument
that's one thing that I like uh with the
way that I just did this Brad wasn't
involved I'm not involved in Brad's
stuff when I see Brad it's all
friendship it's hey bro taste how good
this weed smokes and tastes uh smell how
good this jar smells it's not like hey
do you have the money for those seeds
because that [ __ ] sucks there is
business that gets in the way of things
so that's part of why I don't like to
work with the other breeders cuz money
[ __ ] up friendships I'll always be
friends with Jinx if we don't ever
collab I'll always be friends uh so I
guess I put them in the friend zone is
what I'm technically saying we're all in
each other's friend zone that way we get
to stay friends I'd rather have friends
than money at this point uh business is
going friendships are blooming let's not
mix the two don't [ __ ] where you eat is
also another phrase that they say it's
not that I don't trust these guys to do
business with them it's just easier if
we don't and also the time has never
come up and I trust those two dudes the
three of us would never [ __ ] each other
we could all leave a pile of money on
the table nobody would rip each other
off I'm just using examples and being
hypothetical here but uh that's part of
why I don't collab with people problems
come up every time I've seen so many
friends lose relationships and friends
just over weird weed [ __ ] that was
unnecessary if this weird business idea
didn't happen this group of friends and
this group of friends would still be
friends and they'd be a [ __ ]
Powerhouse instead of two small groups
that'd be one [ __ ] super group all
right I rambled on enough about that
let's move on to part two there's a part
two of this question it says are there
any plans to restock Jack the Ripper on
iir hopefully I can grab a few packs if
so current at this time unfortunately I
do not have plans to restock any more of
the Jack the Ripper stuff I have the
Jack the Ripper mail but kind of going a
different direction I'm really focused
on feminized seeds right now fem are I
used to say 70% of the market fem are 85
or 90% of the market right now uh
regular seeds are not selling so if I
made more regs they would sit on the
shelf or they would be sold at a blowout
price it's really not worth it at this
time I love making reg seed I love
breeding regular plants but right now
the Jack the Ripper is not in the lineup
I'm currently working with some fem
stuff the next run is Golden Goat um I'm
making a bunch of Golden Goat reversal
stuff there might be a Gary Payton in
that run uh there might be a GMO root
beer in that run who knows what else
there might be getting crossed to the
Golden Goat then following that I'm not
sure how much I've talked about this but
excuse me for burping not even going to
edit this out recently I found and
discovered in a close friend's grow a
phenotype of the cream that has got all
of the traits uh it's a n out of 10 it's
got everything you can imagine for a
breeding plant it's a female but I'm
going to reverse that cream and
pollinate everything in my [ __ ]
lineup with that bad girl so uh there
will be some Golden Goat crosses some
new Golden Goat stuff coming then
shortly after that we will have some
cream crosses those plants are in veg
now they're getting big enough to get
the clones and get everybody going but
that is what's coming up so no Jack the
Ripper for a while going to focus on fem
Golden Goat then the cream then maybe
more blueberry cookie stuff just
depending on how uh my creative juices
are flowing at the time and what pops up
between now and then all right so my
buddy Frank Wyatt I feel like I rambled
a lot on this answer um I don't work
with other breeders uh just because of
time and planning uh if there's somebody
out there that does want to do a collab
let's work on it but also I like the
idea that if you don't work with your
friends you can never break up with your
friends we're all in the friend zone we
keep business business and friendship
friendship all right I'm going to keep
moving I've got time for one more good
question here on today's podcast if I've
read your question on the show make sure
you check your emails check your spam
don't get overlooked on those coupon
codes this next one came from my new
friend MO shout out to my buddy Mo
before I get into this question please
let me remind you to click like And
subscribe that's right if you've made it
this far you obviously like my rambling
Shenanigans please click like on the
video and make sure you subscribe to the
channel That way every time I put out a
new video you get a notification you
don't miss any of my amazing cannabis
knowledge content all right let's stay
focused I'm getting goofy today the
message from my new friend MO says hey
rosta Jeff I love your podcast and the
genetics you put out hey that's pretty
awesome and ironic because guess what
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from iir make sure you check
your inbox check that spam folder and
when you grow those seeds please send me
pictures and make me proud but wait
there's more it says thank you for
making me a better grower dude you are
very welcome that stuff means a lot to
me that is like pouring nutrients and
recharge on me you are very welcome now
it does go on it says I know you like to
finish your plants the last 10 days on
an 18 and6 light cycle what many people
may be new to the show so let me address
what this person just said when I am
finishing my plants the last 10 days of
the flowering cycle I will put my lights
back on 18 hours on and 6 hours off
you're on 1212 now I will put those
lights on 18 hours on and 6 hours off
that is right the last 10 days I
increase my lights by 6 hours many
people's heads just [ __ ] exploded
they're saying what are you doing you're
crazy I've been doing this for a while
there are a couple of caveats Let Me
Explain do not do this on the first run
of a plant do this when you know how
long a plant takes to flow when you know
how long that plant usually takes to
flow if it takes 70 days start this at
day 60 if the plant takes 80 days start
at Day 70 don't do this on the first run
figure out how long the plant takes then
the second and third runs that's when
we're going to mess with the light cycle
so what do I do the last 10 days it's
real easy I go from 1212 to 18 hours on
and 6 hours off people their heads are
just blown up why do you do this good
question because it is in my opinion my
experience that photons that light is
the number one source of energy for our
plants light is what makes the plants
grow if we put that light on for more
hours per day they will get more light
which means they will get more
photosynthesis which means they will be
more productive which means they will
get beefier more dense and they will
finish sooner you may be able to turn
that light off in day seven and cut down
your entire grow 3 days earlier than you
had anticipated because think about it
scientifically you're giving your plant
a half of day more light every single
day you may be able to cut off a quarter
of a day every day that that happens
just by the DLI that that plant is
receiving now many people think that I'm
crazy because I teach this method but
guess what everybody that has tried it
has messaged me and been like bro this
is awesome the only people that don't
like this idea are the people who have
not tried it so keep that in mind when
you're typing your hate mail right now
if you haven't tried it I don't care
what your opinion is try it then send me
some hate mail all right now let's
continue with this message because there
is more to this it says I know you like
to finish your plants on that last 10
days on an 186 cycle I am currently
Crossing some strains would you
recommend to switch from 1212 to 186 to
make the seeds finish more quickly my
quick answer off of the top of my head
without any hesitation is yes that's
exactly why and how I learned this
method I realize that the seeds like a
lot of light when I'm growing for seed I
don't care what the plants look like I
don't need pretty buds nobody's ever
going to see the flower nobody's ever
going to smoke the flow it's all going
to get ground up into dust and the seeds
are going to get pulled out you'll never
know what the herb looked like so I do
turn my lights back to 186 after
pollination I'll explain brief briefly
let me try that I'm not even going to
edit that I'm going to try that sentence
once again I will explain briefly how I
do this so uh the plants are ready for
pollination right we'll just
hypothetically say it's pollination time
ta pollinate them now I will wait 3 to
five maybe seven days depending on the
cultivars in the room I'll wait a few
days about a week then guess what
pollinate all over again take that male
plant dust everything or the Reversed
female whatever you want to do it my
pollen donor everybody just got
pollinated a second time now I will get
rid of that male or that pollen donor
plant that is gone we have just got
pollinated females in the room I will
wait until I see those pistols start to
turn brown and wither up that is when I
put that light back on 18 hours on and
six off usually two to three maybe 5
days after second pollination is when I
turn those lights back to 186 now people
are going what are you doing dude 186
they're going to rev yeah they will but
I don't give a [ __ ] because I'm not
growing for buds these plants are fully
seated they're going to make amazing
seeds big fat healthy seeds when you
guys buy seeds from me and you get those
big fat healthy seeds that are the size
of Pebbles those were grown under an 186
light cycle and I strongly believe that
it's because of all of that extra light
that light gives the plants extra energy
that extra energy gives them more
photosynthesis lets them get bigger
beefier stronger faster and earlier so
if you do this you may be able to
harvest your seeds a little bit early
one thing I will recommend is pay
attention because if you let them go too
long like this they will get too hard
and you will get germination issues if
you let them go too long if you're good
and I experienced it growing for seed
I'm sure you know how to pull a couple
of seeds out of a calx give it a squeeze
and see if it's ready just do not let
them go too long is my main bit of
advice but yes I definitely do recommend
switching back to 18 hours on and hours
off after the second successful
pollination you will notice that your
plants finish more quickly you'll notice
those seeds get big and beefy and also
here is an advantage if perhaps you
forgot to get a clone of one of those
plants have no fear because they are
going to rev before the seeds are done
you will have plants that look like
total dog [ __ ] with big reved shoot
sticking out of them you can clone that
red put that in the cloner and start
brand new all over again you're going to
get clones and seeds and reved Ed from
the same freaking plant it's magical all
right my dude Mo thank you for the great
question once again make sure you check
your email check your inbox check your
spam because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at I
direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis Growers out there I
do want to thank each and every one of
you once again for listening to another
episode of the podcast uh the episode
would not be the same without you so big
thanks to everybody out there watching
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know I would
love to hear from you my email address
is grow from yourheart at hotmail.com
don't be shy send me your constructive
criticism your positive feedback or if
you got to do it let that hate mail fly
I'm not shy I'm not gentle I can handle
some emails go ahead and reach out grow
fromy heart hotmail.com you know I'd
love to hear from you uh everything else
is on the website at iry genetics.com
iry genetics.com there's link to the
patreon campaign you can support the
show on patreon there's a link to the
Discord server you can come hang out
with us on Discord and of course there
is a link to the merchandise you can get
a rolling tray a grinder an ashtray or
maybe even a hat or a t-shirt check the
website it is all there I genetics.com
of course you can find the seeds at
edirect
and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me rer Jeff you bad
mother time to take another Dam grab
your p and I the
B is in the lab sit back relax hold