[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother podcast microphone check it check
check check how does this microphone
sound this sounds pretty damn good how
does that look over there you got to
press record over here that makes
everything function much better
recording here recording there we're
recording every [ __ ] where let's do
it like this welcome back podcast world
I'm your host rosta Jeff this is episode
849 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in today's episode speaking of
seeds I do want to let you know that
there is a restock at air.com that's
right I direct is the place for the
fresh seed drops check iir for new skunk
testers and of course the new strain
wing suit which is a cross of the Medusa
to Afterglow two great strains uh that
is a long flowering strain so I hope
you're ready for a 14we flowering cycle
but that is a new offering at IR
redirect.sh
all right that's all of the advertising
I want to do here for today let's jump
into some people's favorite portion of
the podcast that is the pet peeve
section of the show of course I do like
to feature grow room or cannabis
Community Pet Peeves on the podcast of
course maybe you know what a pet peeve
is a pet peeve is something that just
drives you crazy uh maybe you go to your
friends grow you see something that just
bothers you maybe you go to a commercial
facility you see something in the grow
room that just drives you crazy maybe
you see it on the internet I encourage
people to send me their grow Room Pet
Peeves you can email those to me at grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com if I read
your growroom pet peeve here on the
podcast you will receive a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at idirect
decom today's growroom pet peeve came
from my new friend who's going to be
called traven I think that's how I say
that traven or traven much respect bro
don't know how to say your name but I'm
glad you're a part of the army either
way the pet peeve goes a little bit like
this it says hey Ross to Jeff I for sure
have a pet peeve Eve that I think other
Growers can relate to and yes bro I
definitely connected on this one uh made
me chuckle I had a conversation recently
uh with a friend about this I had a
friend who bought a fat sack of good
herb and they were a victim of what
you're about to talk about anyway the
question says I hate seeing beautiful
dense nugs with dog or cat hair all over
them pet hair is our enemy as a grower
yes absolutely a friend of mine recently
bought some really good weed except uh
about 78 of that weed is coated in
kitten hair so yes that can definitely
ruin a good bag of good weed uh it's all
Frosty green it's got bright orange
hairs it's covered in tricomes and he
turn that nugget over and there's a big
sticky lump of cat hair on there I've
definitely taken great photos in my own
garden I've been in there super proud of
the nugs I'm in there taking nug shots I
take a picture I'm excited I bring it to
the computer I throw the disc into the
computer I load the image up on the
computer and it's a really nice nug shot
with one [ __ ] dog hair right down the
middle of it been there so many times
I've done that I do not have a pet at
this time but I do plan to acquire a new
dog in the near future there are some
steps in front of that but there will be
a new dog when the new dog does come
into the world I will have to make
adjustments I'll have to reconfigure the
grow so there's more filtration to make
sure the dog hair does not make it too
there also I will have to change clothes
more frequently when going in and out of
the grow space to avoid that dog hair uh
from being moved into the grow but yes
my dude uh I'm just going to call you
travin we're going to say that's how you
say it and if it's not that's how we say
it today my dude um thank you for the
great pet peeve I completely agree with
you uh when you're looking at a bud or a
photo or any kind of product and there's
a dog or a cat hair in it that is almost
a heartbreaker it almost makes you want
to cry it's so near Perfection and then
there's a cat hair right in the middle
of the bud who wants to smoke a bunch of
cat hair not me my dude thank you for
the great pet peeve uh make sure you
check your inbox and your spam because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at
air.com once again if anybody out there
has a cannabis cold culture or grow room
or cannabis Community pet peeve I
encourage you to send me that pet peeve
if I read your peeve here on the show
like I said before you WI a pack of
seeds from IID direct.com now we're
going to work our way into the question
and answer portion of today's podcast I
do have a website that website is iry
genetics.com on that website there are a
bunch of links on the top a bunch of
tabs that will get you to a bunch of
great places there's a tab that will get
you to the Discord server come hang out
on Discord there's a tab that will get
you to the vendors I recommend you check
iy direct that is the easiest spot to
get all of the good seeds at the best
prices uh also there's a tab there that
says uh patreon you can join the patreon
server and I will be updating the
patreon server very soon uh we will be
updating the tiers the gifts the prizes
whatever you want to call them those are
due for an overhaul now what I'm getting
to is there is a tab on that row that
does say grow help or grow questions if
you click on that Tab and you send me a
good grow question perhaps I will read
your grow question here on the show if I
read that question here on the podcast I
will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at idirect decom today's
question came from the growel tab and it
came from my new friend Doug the
question goes a little bit like this it
says what's up rosta Jeff I've got a
little question here I actually found
this to be a fun uh and intriguing and
entertaining question and kind of an
exciting question for me to ask that
always makes a big difference so uh not
a little question this was a big one and
I really like it says I just bought a
tester pack and I'm curious as to where
your original lineage comes from for
your selections like what beans or cuts
are your go-to when you are trying to
find a new strain uh as a breeder that
is a very fun question that's a very uh
opening question and gives me a lot of
stuff to talk about so basically this
person is asking how do I acquire new
seeds or new clones or new plants for my
breeding projects where do these plants
come from how do I make the decisions
where to get them what to use this is a
very great great question as a seed
breeder as a seed maker as a plant lover
uh this definitely opens me up to a lot
of conversation so where do my plants
come from that I choose to breed with my
clones my seeds my cuting uh where does
all of this come from they come from a
plethora of different places and sources
if you will um let's talk about I've got
a sort of a list here of things um let's
see the first one that I've got written
down is Cherry Paloma uh Cherry Paloma
was almost forced upon me uh when Cherry
Paloma became popular two different
people sent me the Cherry Paloma cut
they're like hey bro I really think you
should breed with this and you should
work with this and I was like ah it
seems okay I might work with that I put
one out in a greenhouse it didn't make
it that plant got destroyed that
Greenhouse got hit by a storm uh that
cherry Paloma plant was murdered out
there I thought it was gone and then
guess what somebody else was like hey do
you have the Cherry Paloma and I was
like No And they sent it to me and then
another friend of mine in my close
breeding circle in my group came to me
one day he's like hey bro I got my my
hands on this Jr's cut of cherry Paloma
so it felt like Cherry Paloma was almost
forced upon me it was like the universe
the weed world I listened also the world
was like take this plant do something
great with this and I did I've done a
couple of great things with the Cherry
Paloma we made the Cherry skunk I've
also crossed it to the BC Lemon Skunk uh
I will talk about those in the near
future maybe those will be on the
testing uh the testing table soon but
that is where the Cherry Paloma came
from um three different people mailed me
cuts of the Cherry Paloma and then
somebody else a different Source
actually mailed one of my very best
friends another cut of the Cherry Paloma
so over time I had four different cuts
of the same plant arrive at my growing
areas and it was like a sign it was a
sign from the weed gods or whatever God
you believe in it was a sign as said hey
rosta Jeff put this in the mix so Cherry
Paloma is a fun one to start with um I
get a lot of cuts from my friends uh
locally and not so locally and also I
work worked in commercial cultivation
facilities where I would see a lot of
Great Cuts one good thing about working
in a commercial grow no offense to you
guys working there but uh those guys are
overworked sometimes there's two or
three dudes running a giant Warehouse
they're overworked the plants get
overlooked sometimes if they're focused
on room a room B may not even get
touched all day some of the plants get
slightly abused they get beat up in
there and I get to go to that facility
and see which plants handled the stress
uh which plants are not getting the pest
maybe the whole room got spidermites
there's one section that didn't get it
I'm going to keep my eye on that plant
try to remember these don't get
spidermites those might go into my
breeding projects later but I pay
attention in the commercial facility
watching these young dudes [ __ ] these
plants up for nine weeks and then I get
to see at the end of that 9we abuse what
comes out real well and how things react
to that abuse sometimes they
accidentally get overwatered sometimes
they accidentally get underwatered
sometimes they get bugs sometimes it
gets too hot sometimes it gets too cold
sometimes everything goes freaking
perfectly I get to see how these plants
in large numbers react in that sort of
environment with those sort of
conditions and so in multiple cases and
multiple occasions I've acquired cuts
from those commercial facilities to add
to my breeding projects I've written
down a couple of those um the Platinum
Tangi and the Strawberry Fields cut that
I have both came from a commercial
cultivation facility in Pueblo West
Colorado um the Platinum Tangi was just
a great cut it was vigorous it was hyper
vigorous it grew very quickly it could
handle a lot of problems uh we had one
room with an air conditioner intake that
in the winter a lot of cool air would
come in there it would mess up a lot of
plants I knew if I put that Platinum
Tangi up against that section they'd be
just fine those plants were super
resilient they handled all of the stress
so when it was time I acquired a cut of
that Platinum Tangi uh also that
Strawberry Fields that I got came from
the same commercial facility I watched
that plant tolerate all types of abuse
and bang out gigantic strawberry candy
flavored buds with high potency all day
long I had to get a cut of that uh the
Platinum Tangi made um it made orange
gasm it also made sunkiss it's made
other things the strawberry Starburst
cut ended up or the Strawberry Fields
cut made strawberry Starburst Raphael um
probably other things that I can't think
of off the The Red Pill came from that
one so that's where that one came from
uh another popular cut that I work with
a lot is the gold goat where did I get
the Golden Goat I've had the Golden Goat
since probably 2008 or 9 2010 at the
latest I'm going to say it's in Circa
2009 I guess is kind of where I think it
fell in but uh there was a dispensary up
north that sold Golden Goat flowers all
the time and the flowers were always
fire uh super good wheat it was super
potent um it always tastes real nice and
I just love the flavor and the buzz of
the Golden Goat one day A friend of mine
came to me um we're going to call him uh
Pineapple Express he happened to be from
Hawaii he was a really cool dude really
good grower really good friend uh
pineapple I hope you're well my bro
anyway he came to me he said hey do you
know this one guy in our group and I
said yeah I know that guy I don't think
he likes me and he goes oh no he [ __ ]
hates you for some reason and that's a
totally different story it doesn't
matter why I don't even care why that
guy didn't like me I sold weed at the
time he sold weed at the time I had all
the good customers he didn't like me um
he gave my buddy Pineapple Express a cut
of Golden Goat and he's like I will give
you this Golden Goat as long as you
don't give it to Jeff you know how
things go in this community my buddy was
like sure thing we'll do that and he
took the cut guess what he did drove it
straight to me so that's how I acquired
the Golden Goat that was kind of a uh
there was multiple reasons there first
of all that dude was a dick and said
don't give it to me and my buddy was
like haha and he brought it to me that
was just kind of a spite move also my
buddy knew that I was a good grower one
of the uh the known growers in town
somebody that should have that good cut
I got it and I grew it a few times and I
realized that Golden Goat was special
and that's why it got into my breeding
project um a lot of people in other
places were like it's not fair that
you've got that Golden Goat I'm I've got
cancer I've got other problems also I'd
love to have that cut it maybe medicinal
for me so that inspired me to make it
into fem seeds and ship it everywhere so
that's how Golden Goat fem seeds got
made and put out um where are we now the
Medusa many of you don't even know about
Medusa what the heck is Medusa Medusa is
a 16w we flowering sativa that will
knock your socks off um it doesn't make
me high it doesn't make me stoned it
makes me feel bent or crooked or it
makes me feel like I did different drugs
it's I don't know it does weird [ __ ] to
my brain it's pleasant but it can be a
lot sometimes if you're a smoker that
really wants to go to another planet and
try something new uh Medusa will get you
there fortunately I have crossed the
Medusa to the Afterglow I made feminized
seeds and I call that Wings suit I call
a wing suit cuz when you smoke it it's
like you just jumped off the [ __ ]
roof of a building and you spread your
wings and you were hoping for the
[ __ ] best that's what it's like when
you smoke this [ __ ] you'll sit at the
chair and wonder about life and your
heart will just race and you'll be
sweaty uh you'll burn calories by
smoking this weed just chilling out so
the wing suit takes about 14 weeks to
flower Medusa is like 16 17 weeks um
that cut came from a friend of mine who
wants nothing to do with the weed world
he wants to grow and breed good cannabis
and that's what he wants to do that's
his contribution to the weed world is he
gives us good plants to play with he
doesn't want to be on social media he
doesn't want any Spotlight that's not
what he's about he's a businessman he's
a family man in other Realms he uh he
hides in the shadows he was he's like
bane of the weed World he's born in the
shadows but that dude breeds some
amazing stuff and he gave me a cut of
the Medusa he's a really good friend of
mine also shout out bro I hope you see
this podcast um you know who you are I
don't even need to say your name he gave
me the Medusa cut and I breed with that
because um it adds diversity to my
breeding mix most of my stuff is sativa
dominant candy flavored but the Medusa
got a really unique sort of a buzz to it
um it's a different sort of a buzz than
what comes with most of my lineup it's
more paranoia inducing it's I I can't
even explain it properly most of the
time I'm high or I'm stoned and this one
is I'm bent and crooked and I don't know
I'm trying to park my car in motorcycle
spaces and losing my sunglasses while
I'm wearing them and [ __ ] like that uh
that but that that my friends is the
wing suit and the Medusa I'm going to
keep going I'm going to try to stay
focused obviously I've been taking a lot
of dabs today another one to talk about
is the cream where does my cream breeder
cut come from that's crazy random right
I made the cream I bred the cream seeds
I've been making cream seeds for quite a
while that is the cookies and cream
number 13 to arise I named it the cream
because the cream Rises to the top
cookies and cream arise cream Rising the
cream bro so I got the name the cream is
an amazing plant I've seen uh so many
people send me amazing pictures of the
cream it's frosty it's chunky it grows
very well it's got amazing flavors and
Aromas the buzz is very desirable
recently I gave a friend some seeds of
the cream and many other seeds and he
ran them in his grow locally in my
neighborhood right down the street I
pointed right there like you guys knew
where his house was I hope you don't but
my dude grew a bunch of seeds for me
locally right down the street I got to
go over there every three or four days
he's my homie I just go over there and
smoke and hang out and look at his
plants and check on him and see how the
day was going just kill some time over
there and stare into the plants uh like
Hank Hill and [ __ ] Dale Gribble just
yep you got plants we just stare at him
but we found he found he grew a cut of
the cream he grew a seed of the cream
that was amazing luckily we got clones
of it I've got a clone he's got a clone
also it's backed up in two spots uh
that's his cut but he was nice enough to
give me a clone of the cream um I
promised him when I breed to it he'll
get some seeds back from it but I have
got a cut of the cream that came from a
local friend that is phenomenal it will
be in my breeding uh rotation very soon
you'll see it as a pollen donor you'll
see it as a pollen receiver the new
cream cut that we recently found is I
want to say hot fire but it's frosty
cool this one is Frosty cool it's
covered in tricomes the structure is
real nice the color is beautiful um the
turps are mostly there but the turps are
not overpowering to where I think so
what's real what it's all it's really
missing is powerful turps it tastes good
it smells good but it's not like shabow
I think when I breed that to some of my
more flavorful females that will leave
room for that structure that Vigor that
potency that triome content The Leaf
color um then we're going to get flavor
from everybody else is what I'm really
hoping for so we'll leave some room for
those ladies to do some work in the
breeding project but that's where the
Cream came from I do have more um on the
list also I've got AJ Sour Diesel I've
got AJ Sour Diesel AJ's cut I've got a
couple other Sour Diesel Cuts but right
now we're going to focus on the AJ sour
and Kosher Kush where did I get AJ sour
and Kosher Kush um I've been smoking
those strains for years I love those
cuts those are awesome I honestly got
them from reputable clone vendors in the
Colorado area I knew people back in the
day that sold clones they'd give you a
menu they'd say we got these the Clones
are somewhere between 10 and $10,000 a
cut depending on what you want to buy
pick what you want tell us what you want
we'll send you a total we'll bring you
the Clones on Monday that is where the
AJ sour and the Kosher Kush came from um
amazing Cuts I love those you will see
those in the breeding uh very soon so
there are a lot of avenues and ways that
I acquire clones also so um I buy seeds
and clones off of websites just like
normal civilians I'm not afraid to go to
a website and if I heard about something
that I want and it gets my attention
I'll go find it on the internet and buy
it just like a normal customer I'm a
customer I'm a a civilian I'm a shopper
just like you guys I like to go buy new
[ __ ] and add it to my repertoire but
also uh people love to send me random
seeds and clones I've got a box I can
see it it's a box that sits on my table
uh it is a small lunch box just filled
with seeds that people have given me
that I do want to grow eventually but
I've got so many seeds that it's not
possible within my lifetime to grow out
all these seeds but people love to send
me seeds and they love to send me clones
like I said that cherry Paloma just kept
popping up couldn't get rid of the
Cherry Paloma so I did take the hint
ladies and gentlemen I did uh listen to
the universe I did breed with it I made
some great [ __ ] with the Cherry Paloma
um if you bred with cherry Paloma are
you seeing a couple of mutants are you
seeing weird Offspring and anything that
came from the Cherry Paloma just curious
let's talk as breeder friends post your
pictures send them to me let me know
what you think so where was I I buy and
trade seeds and [ __ ] also um if you've
got some cool seeds and I may be
interested in them and I've got some
cool [ __ ] I'm open to Trad sometimes
don't be offended if I don't want your
stuff but there is some stuff that's
hard to find that I was looking for and
I also will trade clones if it's the
right clone my inbox is going to [ __ ]
blow up because of that and in the
future I do intend to sell a few clones
on IE Direct that's right we'll be
selling a few clones on um very minimal
clones at premium prices because it will
be just me handling everything I tried
to sell clones before with help I did
not like the way it went I want to do it
myself I will uh cut the Clone I will
package the Clone I will ship the Clone
it will all be me so that when there's a
complaint it's [ __ ] on me last time I
had a helper didn't go the way we hoped
for I apologize now I'm talking in the
weeds all right where are we um I buy
seeds off the internet I buy clones off
the internet I buy clones sometimes from
dispensaries if I'm somewhere sometimes
a friend of mine will just give me a
really Killer cut as a breeder something
I appreciate and enjoy if you grow a
pack of my seeds and you find a really
Killer cut um I would love it if you
contact me and maybe help me acquire
that cut from you and I would make it
worth it I would send you seeds I would
promise you seeds in the future um yeah
that that sort of stuff does happen and
then also I put your name on that cut if
you want your name on that cut you'll
notice there is the Afterglow Painted
Lady cut the way that that worked was I
sent Painted Lady some seeds uh she grew
the Afterglow she found a [ __ ]
Stellar cut one better than what I found
and she sent me a cut of that I named it
the Painted Lady cut it says painted
lady right on the package she gets a
shout out every time I talk about that
cut so shout out to the painted lady
hope you're well uh also if you need
some beans let me know because I've made
you promises I'll send you more beans I
made a lot of afterglow crosses with the
Painted Lady cut so if you want
something reach out I'll get them to you
I haven't seen you grow much lately but
I hope you're well all right ladies and
gentlemen I am freaking rambling how far
have we been going we're about 20
minutes in with some edits all right we
do have time for another question but
before we go that far I want to send my
buddy Doug a big thank you Doug um I
hope I rambled on and explained how I
got my cuts uh that is how I find seeds
and cuts I am just places where they are
people send them to me I buy them on the
Internet just like a shopper uh luckily
I'm in Colorado I know clone vendors
sometimes uh people send me a text
message with like just 10 things on
there like I got these you interested
and I'll say sure I want this one and
this one and then suddenly those clones
just appear how do I choose to breed
with them is a totally different story I
need to run those in my environment
before I'm going to choose to breed with
them 99% of the time uh sometimes like
the the strawberry and the Platinum
Tangi I grew that so many times that I
just brought it home and we we [ __ ]
with that right away but most of the
time it comes to the personal grow I
grow it out a couple of times see what
it does then I'll spread it around to
the homies and we'll put it in some
breeding tents but I think I answered
that one quite uh in depth so my buddy
Doug uh thank you for the great question
did I say your name at the start of the
show or the start of the message anyhow
but anyway my dude Doug thank you for
the great question once again do check
your inbox and your spam cuz you've got
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from iy direct.com all right we're going
to keep this great momentum going I do
have another question here in front of
me this one also came from that growel
tab on iy genetics.com this one came
from our friend zany in Michigan shout
out to my new friend zany in Michigan
also big shout out to all the Growers
out there in Michigan killing it holding
it down keeping it real I hope all of
your Gardens come out very well this
season the question says Hey Rasta Jeff
is it wise to do a few pheno hunts of
different crosses all in the same room
um so I'm assuming you've got uh
multiple packs of seeds and you want to
run multiple packs and see if you can
find a good pheno out of all of those
packs or maybe a population of each pack
maybe three of this one three of this
one three of this one I understand what
you're doing I think here uh Is it wise
do I advise this yes I absolutely do um
that way you get to see how all those
different plants react to that room not
only do you get to see how plant a
reacts to that room but you could see if
maybe plant B acts differently in the
room if plant C reacts differently in
the room that will help you find not
only the phenotype that you are hoping
to find to smoke and consume but the one
that works the best in your grow
environment perhaps one of these strains
we're just going to go very basic one's
an Indo one's a sativa one's a [ __ ]
hybrid maybe you'll find that one of
those works way better in that grow
environment so not only are you pheno
hunting for the plants that you wish to
consume and smoke but also you are pheno
hunting to see which plants work best in
that environment there are pros and cons
to running a monocrop which means just
putting one pack of seeds in the room
and doing a pheno hunt from that whole
pack there but I do like seeing the
diversity of the different packs of
seeds in this room that will show you a
lot of different things and like I said
before now you're not just picking that
one plant that works you're going to
find a a lot of different options you
may find that one gem that works the
best in that room uh don't fall in love
with any plants uh before you've smoked
everything don't fall in love with
anything too early uh give every plant
in there an equal chance because some of
those ugly plants some of those slower
plants uh those often times turn out to
be the Beauties so give everybody a fair
chance in this run see what grows the
best smokes the best and Suits the needs
are you growing for a um a personal
consumption reason is it medical or
recreational are you growing for
somebody else's medical needs or are you
growing simply uh for a profit um find
the one that fits your uh your needs
fits your Niche fills your demands
that's the phenotype which you are
looking for um so now briefly let me
jump into what I kind of just brought my
mind to there are pros and cons to
running multiple packs of seeds um if
you're just running that one pack of
seeds you get a larger population you
may find uh you're going to find
different phenotypes you're going to
find it's like opening up more baseball
cards you got that more of a chance of
finding that uh that rookie card of the
popular player for today I have no idea
who the [ __ ] plays baseball today you
guys but it's like finding that Mickey
manual baseball card there the more
cards you open the more chances you have
for that Mickey if you're running 10
seeds of something you got a one in 10
chance of finding that super gem you're
looking for if you run a 100 seeds you
got that one in 100 if you only run
three seeds of something you're
diminishing your chances of finding that
phenotype however then then my brain
does this also does this AR argument how
many seeds do you need to run out of a
pack of seeds to find a keeper and my
fem seeds there's six of them if you run
three to six I really think you'll find
a keeper so I think your numbers are
going to be okay if you do at least
three of each thing in this fenal hunt
all right I'm rambling at this point um
there are pros and cons to this um like
I said before if you run a whole pack of
something and fill the tent with one
thing you got a much more uh a much more
a broader view of what those genetics
have to offer you may find something uh
more special in there but if you want to
fenal hunt multiple things uh you will
see what your nutrients are doing your
environment is doing what your skills
and work are doing to multiple different
plants you may learn things that way
you'll see that some things do work like
we said before Indica sativa hybrid
you'll see that some things work well
for this plant that don't work on this
plant and this plant tolerates some [ __ ]
that these don't this one really likes
something you'll see the diversity in
that population and how they all respond
to different treatment all right my dude
you really got me rambling on this one
that is super good thank you uh my
friend zany from Michigan once again
make sure you check your inbox CU you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds from
air.com all right ladies and gentlemen
boys girls pimps and hoes friends and
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters Paul
and Chuckers All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for listening to
another episode of The Grow fromy heart
podcast I had a lot of fun recording
this episode if you had as much fun
watching this show as I did recording it
please smash that like button that's
right click like on the video also
subscribe to the channel That way you
never miss any of my glorious Canabis
content also keep the conversation going
in the comment section I've been trying
to be more available more present in
that comment section gets a little bit
overwhelming but I will check in and I
will reply to the comments so keep the
comments going in that comment section
i' love to see how you guys feel about
the show speaking about seeing how you
feel about the show if you have any
questions Corrections comments or
concerns I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com if you've got some
corrections comments concerns uh maybe
some hate mail don't be shy go ahead and
reach out grow fromyou heart at
hotmail.com also make sure you check
that website iry genetics.com everything
you need is at iy genetics.com there's a
link to the patreon there's a link to
iir where you can buy seeds which are on
sale right now go get some seeds also
there's a link to the Discord server
come hang out on Discord and there is
the growel tab so if you've got
questions you can send them right to me
also if I did not read your question
here on the show today don't feel
discouraged I've got a mountain of
emails here in front of me and then this
would be a uh a double mountain of
emails I don't know what I'm talking
about anymore got a lot of freaking
emails to work my way through don't be
discouraged I may read your question on
the next episode this one right here
could be your question so don't get
discouraged stay tuned keep watching
keep listening maybe your question will
come up on the next show all right
ladies and gentlemen I am ramble this
was a fun show I'm going to wrap up the
podcast I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
old shout out to my buddy splooch and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
mother tell take another Dam grab your p
in I go find the
B is in the
sit back moment relax hold up