[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome back podcast world I'm
your host roster Jeff this is episode
850 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds that's
right hang out we'll talk more about
those free seeds later on in the podcast
I do also want to remind you that there
is a fresh drop and a restock at edirect
decom that's right check IR
redirect.sh many of the soldout items
and speaking of free seeds if you spend
over $30 at IR
redirect.sh at iir also if you spend
over $100 you get another two pack of
free feminized seeds that does continue
at 30 100 200 300 and $500 so the more
you spend the more freebies you do get
of course those freebies do stack if you
spend $100 you get that $30 freebie and
the $100 freebie that does continue so
hit iir check that restock check that
replenish and grab your freebies at I
direct.com something you may notice
while you're checking my websites is
that there has been a change to a
popular strain name that's right the
strain that was named after the little
square chewy candy we can no longer use
that name that was being used I don't
think I can even say it right here right
now on the podcast without causing
myself some trouble because we got a
little letter more than a little letter
we got an important letter uh we got an
email that says we must cease and assist
from using um so I can say this in this
phrase I think without getting in any
trouble uh from now on we must cease and
assist from using anything with the word
star burst in it we can no longer use
the word Starburst in any branding or
advertising I've got a very official
letter here from the great Folks at Mars
Wrigley uh the part that I will share
with you says to protect Mars Wrigley's
valuable intellectual property and the
consuming public Mars Rigley must ensure
that its trademark are not misused by
Third parties well guess who I am I'm a
third party I was using the word
Starburst in branding they said no don't
do that they said if you do that more
it's going to cost you a lot of
money guess what I don't want to do I
don't want to give them a lot of
money so we're going to stop using that
that strain has been changed uh that
strain's actually been discontinued I
don't make it anymore it hasn't been for
sale for a while all of the seeds are
gone so it's gone now it's not part of
the production it's not part of the
catalog any further that problem has
been solved but they were very clear
about the names that we can and cannot
use uh anything with Skittles Starburst
Eminem Snickers Twix Lifesavers Hub
Bubba Milky Way Three Musketeers there
are a long list of names that cannot be
used and then they go on and another
page to make it clear that any form of
Skittles or Starburst cannot be used in
any association with any other brands
they've spelled it about 45 different
ways in this paper just to let us know
they're not around so if you do
go to any of my websites and you see
that that strain that was once named
after that little tiny pink delicious
chewy candy uh that strain name has
changed it's because I got the
oldfashioned ceas and desist letter so I
had to change that name I'm not up to
anything fishy I'm not trying to pull a
faster one on you guys uh it was a legal
matter and I had to take action quite
quickly um I had to respond to them uh
and let them know that I was going to
change it and how I was going to correct
this so I responded to them uh so far I
think we're in the clear all as well
this was just a hey stop before
we get you letter so at this point uh
has stopped hopefully they don't
come to get me now let's move on to
something more exciting um ladies and
gentlemen the past weekend I got to go
see my favorite band on the planet for
four nights in a row that's right I got
to go see the band
at Dicks Sporting Goods um I don't even
know the real name of the uh the soccer
field it's a Dicks Sporting Goods Event
Center sporting good soccer field I
don't even know what it's called it is a
gigantic soccer field in Denver Colorado
in Commerce City it is owned of course
by Dick Sporting Good so it's got the
dicks logo everywhere uh that's right we
go we are fish dicks for four days and
we love dicks it's a great time uh make
all the jokes you want it is worth it
but I got to see fish for four nights
some people are going to say you went
saw the same band four nights in a row
yeah bro fish will never do the same
concert two nights in a row they don't
do anything similar uh nothing was
similar for nights in a row they did
four completely different shows
completely different Vibes completely
different songs uh totally different
energy A lot of it was based on the vibe
of the day the vibe of the crowd um so
yeah it's a different show every single
time at a fish show I've seen over a
hundred fish shows they are all
different they are all unique I loved
every one of them for its own way what
I'm getting at is I got to go see fish
for 4 days it felt amazing I haven't
felt that free in a long time I haven't
felt that good that iy that blessed uh
in a very long time it was a very good
experience uh very good rewarding end of
the summer if you will it's kind of
starting the fall Now The Summer's
wrapping up uh I've got one more big
party for the end of the summer but that
was toward the wrap up here for me the
next one might be fall cuz it might be
hoodie season by the time that comes
around I'm rambling at this point what I
want to do now is give a big shout out
to all of the beautiful people who said
hello to me at the fish concerts if you
walked by and just stealed iy and put a
thumbs up or a fist bump up in the air
uh iy bro much love good seeing you if
you ran up and gave me a big old hug and
told me it was good to see me uh great
to see you as well if you're a fellow
breeder and we traded something uh good
to see if you're a fellow breeder we
didn't trade uh perhaps we just danced
for a song I think it was 2001 perhaps
we got down during that um if you're a
fellow breeder and you came to say hello
what's up dude if you're a little tiny
dude that looks like Boo Boo Bear and
you came and gave me a big old hug
there's two people that could qualify as
holy uh anyway if we saw each other
at the fish concerts uh and we bumped
into each other shared energy exchanged
Vibes in any way thank you it was an
honor a blessing a a pleasure a
privilege to see you with the shows I
had such a good time this weekend I feel
like I could ramble about the concerts
all weekend most of you guys are here to
hear about ganja learn about growing and
cultivating cannabis so I'm not going to
gush too much over the fish shows but I
feel refreshed I feel revived that was a
great time uh big shout out to everybody
that I saw there if you're an old friend
a new friend if you're a fish friend if
you're a can industry friend however we
met however we know each other if we sh
a moment at fish youo big up big fist
bump thank you and I say this a lot of
times if you know who I am if you know
what I look like I I am 6'5 my
dreadlocks touch my calves uh I usually
wear some pretty uh some pretty dope
Nike Dunks that's probably me uh walk up
say hello I don't want to hear about it
uh on Tuesday like hey bro I saw you at
a concert on Friday I should have said
hello but I didn't bro walk up say hello
I do want to meet you I do want to fist
bump I want to hear your story I want to
make friends I'm not a I'm not a shy guy
I want to I go to those shows to make
friends and it's a party I'm not there
to go hang out alone so come say what's
up so if I saw you there fist bump and
if you saw me and you didn't say hello
come say what's up next time I'm very
friendly uh I may have been not all in
my head during the fish shows but nobody
was bro come say hello it doesn't matter
I'll stare you right through you maybe
I'll still say hello it'll be a good
time catch me on shake down we'll take a
dab all right so I've said hello to all
my fish friends I talked about the ceas
and assist letter I reminded you about
the restock at iir now I think it is
time to introduce a new part of the
podcast that I'm not sure if I am
excited or nervous about but we're going
to learn together here um I get a lot of
emails I get a lot of questions on the
podcast and I do promise that if I read
your question here on the show that I
will give you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at I redirect that has
resulted in mountains of printed emails
I've got stacks of paper in different
categories they're all piled up all over
this table over here right off camera uh
it looks like a looks like a paper
portraits I'm exaggerating but I've got
an idea uh many people have told me that
I talk too damn much and guess what
you're right I talk too damn much but
that's why I've got a podcast what I'm
going to do is I'm going to try to
minimize the amount of rambling and
chatter uh on these answers and
questions and I'm going to read a
question and I'm going to try to just
bang out as many questions as I can in
the next few minutes and not give those
long ridiculous long winded repetitive
answers I like to give we're going to
try to do a rapid fire question and
answer podcast episode it's not going to
get rapid fire until we start shooting
so we're going to look at the time we're
at that time I know how much more time I
want to continue the show and from now
here we go Rapidfire podcast questions
these questions did come from my website
iry genetics.com that's right iy
genetics.com there's a row of tabs one
of those tabs says grow help or grow
questions if you click on that tab you
are given the opportunity to send me a
grow question if you send me a good grow
question and I do read that question
here on the podcast even if it's a rapid
fire quickie I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from
idirect decom today's first quickie came
from somebody who's going to be called
Candyland stash I like the name the
question quickly says hey rosta Jeff hey
Candyland says I've been growing about
three years now all right that's a good
amount of time I have six strains all
right uh three years six strains I don't
want to lose these strains but I'm also
getting kind of bored and I'm ready for
a reset all right that's understandable
a few are Elite clones and a few are
seeds I personally popped I'm debating
on breeding on a breeding project to
preserve the genetics and even make my
own strain I'm torn between attempting
to feminize one of my six and
pollinating the room and popping a pack
of RS to search for a male I'm just
looking for some experience and some
some experience guid guidance on this
one so you've already got plenty of
plants and you're thinking about popping
another pack to find a male I wouldn't
do that that's a whole new feno hunt
that's a whole new project that could
Inspire some some more inspiration and
give you more passion of growing but I
wouldn't add more to this what I would
do and you're asking for my experience
If This Were my room I were bored with
these plants but I had a couple that I
want to preserve what I would do is I
would clone my favorite plant I would
take two clones of the favorite plant
then I would take all the other plants
and put them in the room I would reverse
one clone of the favorite and then I
would pollinate everything with that
reversal now you've basically got that
your favorite you've got that in
preservation you've got the S1 of that
now you've made r1's of everything else
and you're going to find those plants in
their somewhere eventually you can bring
that out by searching through that
population so you've basically got
everything kind of preserved all the
others are adulterated but you've got
something close to it and it's cross to
your favorite plant so you've
potentially just made uh six batches of
feminized seeds if you take your F you
said you've got six right six strains so
what you've got is the opportunity to
make six different feminized crosses uh
you can take your favorite plant uh take
two cuts of that one's going to become
the pollen donor will one will become
the receiver then the other five
favorites of your plants pollinate them
make seeds out of them now you've got
plenty of preservation for the future
now what you're also going to do is
Inspire yourself you're going to want to
grow those seeds and now you've given
yourself some brand new inspiration uh
some new energy to go and then you're
not bored and that reset won't be as uh
won't be as long you'll be more
motivated to get over that all right I
feel like I'm already rambling this
question has gone on longer than I truly
intended I feel like I answered you bro
reverse your favorite and pollinate
everybody the quick answer all right
once again check your inbox because you
do have a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds from iy direct.com before I read
the next one I do have to remind you to
click like And subscribe that's right if
you like this episode click like if you
want to see more you know what to do
click subscribe all right the next
question came from somebody who wants to
be called John at dank Perfection what's
up John thank you for the question it
goes like this I've been enjoying
listening to your podcast thank you I've
been growing for just a few years and I
try try to be like a sponge and soak up
the knowledge thank you there's a lot
more I'm skipping to the question it
says my question is which of your
strains would be best for me to try let
me tell you what I'm looking for I would
love to find something that is osaman
dominant I can tell you right away I
don't do a lot of lab testing for tpin
so I can't tell you what's got osaman
but I can answer your question based on
the data that you have given me I worked
for a wck farm in Washington that had a
strain called WiFi OG which was Fire OG
to the White I was doing a lot of
testing and found that that had off the
charts osine uh so basically you're
looking for the plant with osine which
your acrosses do you think would be
similar or have similar effects okay the
quick answer there is uh my Dr mind
Bender cut has Fire OG in it so anything
with the Dr Mindbender may get you there
what's got Dr Mindbender or what's going
to be close to that what may get you
there would be the Sunday show or also
I've got a skunk tester crossed to the
Dr Mindbender that is available on the
website now Dr Mindbender to skunk
number one testers are available uh
they're at a very affordable price
they're on the website right now I would
grab some of those uh that's probably
going to get you close and then also the
4K has got the potential to get you
close to that but Sunday show and the
new skunk tester are what I would
recommend to find that osine and get you
as close to that Fire OG as you do
remember my dude John make sure you
check your inbox check that spam folder
cuz you've got a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at idirect decom I like
this you guys we burned through two
messages already two people have gotten
seeds we've answered a couple of good
questions let's keep this rapid fire
Pace going and see how long I can keep
this up all right this question
came from special KL special kill
special KL I'm not sure bro Special K
how about we're going to call you
Special K now that's your new
name I'm rambling already
this all up it says when getting
started breeding when do you use open
pollination versus selected individuals
now that's a really good question I
quickly have to talk about the
difference between open pollination and
selective breeding we're going to do it
super quickly don't worry open
pollination that is when I have multiple
males and females and I let them all
just have a big orgy so the pollen from
plant a b and c is going to hit female
plants one two and three in every
combination possible the pollen from
plant a went to 1 two and three the
pollen from plant B also hit those so
we're going to get every combination in
the room that is an open pollination why
would we do that um that is fun that
shows a lot of diversity uh you're going
to find all of the different phenotypes
that are possible in those genetics
that's that's the reason for that you're
going to find all the different
combinations they may come up in that
gene pool it's a lot of fun it's also a
very viable and useful way to increase
your inventory of seeds so that's a
great reason for open pollination um
it's going to make a diverse population
your population is going to be very
diverse you're going to see a bunch of
different traits a whole bunch of
different growth uh different alals if
you will are going to pop up but if you
want to increase uh traits and inventory
and see what that progyny has to offer
open pollination is the way to do it um
individual selective breeding that is
when you are dialing in traits that is
when I want to isolate or highlight
traits or even breed out specific traits
so if you want to open up the gene pool
and open up the breeding do that open
pollination if you want to do selection
and select for certain things that's
when the selective breeding comes into
play I feel like I answered that one
super quickly and just used a whole
bunch of weird Logic on that one
I hope I answered that one uh
sufficiently my dude Special K check
that inbox because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com this is kind of fun I like
burning through these messages it feels
like progress just throwing paper in the
burnt it pile I like that all right the
next one came from a friend we're going
to call Joey D what up Joey D it's not
Joey Diaz but it is damn close the
message says yo rosta Jeff thank you for
all the knowledge I appreciate all you
do and I've learned so much about
everything that has to do with cannabis
plus some life lessons bro that is a
great way to open a message to
me thank you I appreciate it it says
I've been growing three years I got my
hands into a little bit of pollen
chucking all right so after 3 years
you're into a little bit of pollen
chucking that makes sense it says I have
a blueberry spice SP cross I made that
sounds delightful and it's got a
hint of blueberry but more spice all
right do you think I can cross it to
another blueberry strain to add more of
the blueberry flavor or do I keep
hunting through the original cross for a
more blueberry is plant um you've got a
couple options here you can keep hunting
through the seeds if you've got a lot of
seeds find that plant that tastes just
like blueberries and then make f2s with
that if that's what you want to do or
breed that uh reverse it and breed that
one to uh the good phenotype that you've
got you could back across a phenotype to
the original blueberry parent if you've
got that original blueberry I don't know
if you have that I don't know which
parents you've got or you definitely
could find if you want to add blueberry
to it the easy way to do it we'll just
be finding something with super
blueberry TPS and breed it to that if
you want blueberry the answer is breed
it to the blueberry um but I would
backcross it to the original blueberry
parent if you've got that just try to
that way you're keeping you're still
working with your original genetics kind
of keeping it inhouse doing your thing
and keep that project alive try to not
fix it but update or polish the the
project you've already made try to put
that blueberry flavor into there with
what you've already got you know you've
got it you know you've got blueberry you
started with it let's see if you can get
it in there by using blueberry that
you've already got so I would say
backcross it um if you can backcross it
to the original blueberry do that I'm
not sure which was the male which was
the female I've got minimal info or the
option is like you said go find another
Super blueberry turp that's just focused
on that blueberry turp and breed it to
that maybe you'll get what you want out
of there uh that was a super quick
answer also Joey D once again my bro
check your inbox for a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at edirect decom
before I read the next message I do need
to remind you that those coupon codes do
expire those gift certificates do expire
they come with a clearly labeled
experation date yes I said experation
we're having fun today that expiration
date is real it's not a joke I'm not
taunting you that shit's going to expire
I've got to make them expire um because
for logistical bookkeeping reasons I
can't have free money floating around
forever and also uh if you don't use
that coupon code it tells me you didn't
even listen to the episode where I read
your question and you're supposed to be
listening all right where do we go we've
got another question in front of me once
again I'm just spitting these answers
out as quickly as I can off the top of
my head with very little review so I
hope I'm nailing these and giving you
guys good quick answers sometimes I
don't need to ramble so much which is
I've already what I've started doing now
let's get focused this one came from my
buddy Dave in Ontario shout out to my
Canadian friends out there sorry I can't
send you seeds anymore Health Canada
does not like me anyway this message
says Rost to Jeff it's Dave from Canada
what's up Dave out there in Canada says
I'm submitting another excellent
question for your show yes bro and I'm
sorry I can't send you the seeds but I
do send you a high five and a big fist
bump it says I asked this in the
Breeders chat on Discord if you want to
pop in there and chat about it but the
question is and this is a very good
question do you find that the PA and
donor of a feminized line will more
often than not be the dominant phenotype
so you got a feminized line the pollen
donor do I find that the pollen donor
will be the dominant phenotype not
regularly not always not commonly no
there's a reason for that we're going to
talk about in the next line of the
question um but no uh most often no
that's that's the bottom line on that no
uh then it says like out of 100 seeds 50
or more will be leaning to the pollen
donor or uh dead ringers of the pollen
donor um no what that means is that your
pollen donor is uh more dominant in the
breeding mix than the pollen receivers
that uh remember when I talked about the
Brock Lesnar Theory this is Brock Lesnar
Theory uh in practice showing itself
right here you've got a Brock Lesnar
Paul and donor and those genes are just
dominating the mix and everything that
you make looks like poor Brock Lesnar's
daughter so that's this is Brock Lesnar
Theory uh in action here in practice
showing itself if you haven't heard that
listen back a few episodes I don't
remember which one it is we talk about
selecting male plants I labeled
something the Brock Lesnar Theory go
listen to that episode somebody cut a
clip out of it for me and send me a
short please I'll send you a
gift card um we're going to get so many
of those the first one the best one is
going to get a gift card um but so that
I think that that leads me to believe
that your pollen donor has just got
dominant genes and dominant traits in
all aspects then it says do you find
that regular seeds perform differently
without reading the rest of the question
I'm going to say no but then it says uh
in that with regular seeds more than
50/50 fenos are likely sometimes a
phenotype is different and that's the
only thing I'm really going to uh
concede to that I will say is different
with fem seeds the amount of
phenotypical expression is a little bit
different let me read more of what
you're saying more 50/50 fenos are
likely and the dominant pheno could be
either male or the female that dominant
one like I said that's going to be Brock
Lesnar Theory whichever if you've got a
really dominant male or dominant female
breeding uh partner that will pop up
that dominant trait those traits will
pop up but let me get myself back on
track do you find regular seeds perform
differently in that with regular seeds
more than more 50/50 fenals are likely
and the dominant pheno could be either
male or female more phenotype variation
so something I may agree to is that I do
see less variation in the femin seeds
but that's mainly with the selfing of
femin seeds if I took a Golden Goat S1
I'm not adding any other genetics to
there so yes I'm going to see less
variation in that but that is kind of
the only way that I think I agree with
you on that what I really think is
happening is what I have identified as
the Brock Lesnar Theory one of your
plants is just simply dominant uh you've
got a big uh blond-haired blue-eyed dude
and you're breeding it to a bunch of
different uh ladies with different
traits all your babies are coming out
with blonde hair blue eyes uh that's
just the genetics of that
caveman the andreal jeans you reading
with there um I think let me read this
one more quick
time yeah you're and you even said it in
here where the the dominant feno could
be either male or or the female uh yeah
that's
um yeah that's all about the gene Combos
and which plant was dominant I think I
answered that I think I may have
confused myself I think I may have
confused you more but I feel like I got
it covered there all right I'm going to
take a quick pause take a quick drink
and then we are going to continue with
these rapid fire questions all right
podcast world I am hydrated I am liveed
I may have taken a quick dab while we
had the camera paused you will never
know what could have happened while I
was gone let's stay focused let's get
back into this podcast before we do it
let me remind you once again check out
the restock IR
redirect.sh many of the sold out items
that I redirect go check it out before
they sell out again a lot of people
complain that things sell out quite
quickly yes I apologize go check now
there is restocked let's get back
into this Rapid Fire episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast I'm having fun
with this we're going to bang out two
more quick questions of course this
question came from that growel tab on
iry genetics.com it came from my new
friend Smitty Smitty said hey I love the
podcast and all of the good information
thank you I do appreciate that it says I
have two 2x4 t0 both with living soil
beds and my last girl had an issue with
spidermites Bro spidermites I hate
spidermites but we can destroy them we
will win I said I was able to keep them
under control and finish both rounds
then I clean the tents as thoroughly as
I thought was needed but always the good
but when it comes to spider mites uh
this round the mites have come back so
my question is what can I do to
completely clean my tents between rounds
to ensure the mites are wiped out
without leaving strange chemicals in my
soil my tents are staggered by about 4
weeks they're spaced about 15 ft apart
I'm not sure if I'd be safe sanitizing
each tent individually oh excuse me for
burping it not even going to edit that
it's cuz I took a big fat drink right
before I recorded it says or if I should
let both tins finish and clean them at
the same time I'm growing The Golden
Girls pack along with cand delicious in
the coming rounds so all of your help is
appreciated my dude uh I think I have
got what maybe a very uh viable solution
for a person in your situation you will
not have to shut down you do not have to
worry about any weird chemicals which
could get me going on another complete
side rant but what I would
recommend are Predator insects I would
release a bunch of Predator bugs uh
specific predators in both grow spaces
um especially running Perpetual it
sounds like you're kind of running
Perpetual uh you got two tents and
they're staggered uh they're four weeks
apart if you release bugs in both tents
they will stay there and they will stay
as protective security guards forever
and you may have to replenish lightly
you can have them delivered on a
schedule if you even want to but you may
have to lightly replenish these bugs
bugs but if you get a good population of
Predator bugs colonized in these grow
spaces you'll never have to spray
anything and you'll barely ever have to
replenish these Predators if it is done
correctly so what I would recommend and
this is just a list of Predator bugs
that you can order from many different
vendors and Distributors I'm going to
recommend arbco organics.com it's a
rb- organics.com they do not pay me I'm
not sponsored by them I'm simply a
satisfied customer I have several
friends who have shopped with them there
are plenty of other companies and what
are they called insecti Aries they may
be closer to you but I can recommend I
can recommend arbo they've done great
work for me before but the bugs I would
recommend are sworsky pmus Cal fornicus
hypoaspis miles and Green Lace wings and
there's another one cucumeris is what I
think it's called that may have been the
name of another one they may have
swapped a name the cucumeris is one that
I forgot to write down that I'll add to
that but we've got the sworski pmus Cal
fornicus hypoaspis miles Green Lace
wings and cucumeris I would release as
many of them as you can afford into that
grow space and they will decimate your
spidermites they will destroy the
spidermites release it into both spaces
you can release that in your flower room
without any harm without any problem at
any time any stage of growth they will
be harmless to your flowers they will be
very beneficial uh you can use these at
all times you can use them on your
seedlings all the way up to your
flowering plant plants and they will eat
up all of the bugs for you and then
they'll start looking for other bugs and
they'll go further and looking for other
bugs and there aren't any they'll leave
and then they'll die and then you'll
have to replenish them so that you don't
get more spidermites in the future but
this is what I recommend it's very easy
it's very reliable and if you don't want
to spray if you don't want weird
chemicals which triggers me in its own
way we'll talk about that later in a
future episode but the Predator bugs are
the way to go they're a little bit
expensive but if you think about it
they're cost effective compared to a
bottled pesticide Ro ation you would
want two or three different bottles
you're going to have to apply those I
think the bugs will be more effective
and cost effective one thing I'm going
to say don't use ladybugs because them
are lazy all right I'm
going to read one more message in this
rapid fire podcast and then what I want
from you guys please if you would was
leave me some comments in the comment
section and let me know what you thought
of this rapid fire show do you prefer
the long drawn out answers when I ramble
my face off and give you repeated too
much info or do you like it when I bang
through a whole bunch of questions and
give you a bunch of info really quickly
I'm curious I want to know what you
think argue about it down there in the
comments section this next question came
from somebody called my plants talk back
uh everybody's plants talk back you just
got to be listening this question says
I'm getting ready to start my first
breeding project I like that says I
don't want my whole crop to be seated
that's going to be a struggle my dude uh
it says but I want a good amount of
seeds to play with and Hunt through on
average how many plants should I
pollinate from a reversed female to give
me a healthy yield of seeds also any
tips on reversing females would be uh
useful uh I've done a full podcast on
reversing plants so if you can find that
full podcast we don't have to ramble
about it here we could stay rapid fire
um I've purchased the chemicals needed
to make STS and I have a recipe are
there any additives no don't add
anything to it spray it just like it is
you want the silver nitrate sodium thy
sulfate distilled water that's all you
need um do you recommend collecting the
pollen by hand no smack that revers
plant right up against your uh pollen
receiver plants just give them a good
smack a good tap if you can that's the
way I would recommend to do it how long
can I store the pollen um no more than a
couple of months if you insist uh put
the reverse plan in the tent yeah do I
recommend you put the reverse plan in
the tent yes put it right next to them
let it pollinate and then shake it and
then rub it up against the girls when
it's time um thanks love your show would
love to try some of your beans keep on
growing well my friend I apologize for
rubbing my eye here on the podcast I got
something in the eyeball I think it was
my own dreadlocks uh my dude you do get
to try my seeds cuz you get a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom the main question here was um I
want a good amount of seeds on average
how many plants should I pollinate to be
honest with you you can make a lot of
seeds from very small plants when I'm
doing a brand new breeding project if I
just want to try something out and make
some seeds for myself that you don't get
I will pollinate plants that are in beer
cut cups what beer cups yes I will take
a male clone and a female clone and a
beer cup and I'll take several of those
clones of the females and I'll put them
in a little tiny room and I'll pollinate
them in the corner and I can hit five or
six seven or eight beer cups with one
beer cup male put them right in the
middle hit all those girls and I can
produce 30 to 50 maybe 70 seeds of each
one of those plants and that's plenty
for me to play with so a small beer cup
a one gon pot is a plenty big enough
siiz plant to make plenty of seeds for
you to play with beer cups are easy to
manage if you understand how to do it uh
you don't need to veg them very long veg
it till it's about 3 and 1/2 4 and 1
half Ines tall then flip it let them do
their magic they will pollen it you'll
make plenty of seeds uh one gallon pots
will make hundreds of seeds uh you could
produce plenty of seeds to play with and
just a small pot in a small amount of
time is what I think I'm trying to get
to I was going to ramble on a lot more
but um yeah just one plant will get you
plenty of seeds I recommend pollinating
several different females that way you
can see uh the representation of that
male amongst multiple different crosses
and see what he is contributing to the
breeding it'll give you more insight to
what he's doing I've rambled about this
a lot in other podcasts this is not the
time or place for me to get rambly
ladies and gentlemen boys girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers all of you rapid
fire podcast listeners I look forward to
your feedback on this episode let me
know what you thought of this rapid fire
show I tried to bang out as much info as
I could in as short a time as I could
get through some of these emails get you
guys some prizes everybody that got
their message read does get a free pack
of seeds so make sure you check your
spam check your inbox get those coupon
codes get those beans but most of all I
look forward to your comments in the
comment section let me know what you
think of this show maybe I'll do more
quickies maybe I'll do more at the
regular Pace maybe I'll mix and match
it's my party and I'll dab if I want to
all right it is time for me to wrap up
this show thank you for hanging out make
sure you check iy direct for that
restock make sure you check iry
genetics.com for all things iry gentics
you will find a link to the Discord
server you will find a link to the
patreon server you'll find a link to the
store where you can buy uh hats Grinders
rolling trays t-shirts and things like
that everything is at iry genetics.com
there's a link to iy direct where you
can get the beans make sure you check
iry genetics.com I think I said that
enough times I think that's all I've got
for this episode I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to my buddy GB and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
mother tell take another DB grab your p
in and I about the
back is in the lab sit back them up
relax hold up