[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome everybody to the grow
from your heart podcast I'm your host
rosta Jeff this of course is episode 851
in this episode I'm going to give away
free seeds hang out you know I talk more
about the free seeds later on in the
podcast before I get too far I do want
to send a big thank you shout out to
everybody who gave me feedback on the
previous episode that's right in the
previous episode I did what I called a
rapid fire podcast where I answered
questions in a rapid fire manner a lot
of people seem to like it some people
didn't love it I do appreciate all of
the feedback and all of the comments
thank you for that if you missed it go
check it out it is the previous episode
on the YouTube channel go leave some
comments let me know what you think
about that show where do we go from
there now I want to send some big thank
you shout outs to the top three patreon
supporters that's right a big shout out
to my buddy lemur priest big shout out
to Billy Podunk and also a big shout out
to my buddy Brian C thank all three of
you for the continued patreon support
you guys are amazing uh if you guys are
not already supporting patreon check out
patreon.com fromy yourheart and stay
tuned if you do support the show on
patreon you you just might hear your
name on a future podcast episode where
do we go from there one more piece of
information once again check I
direct.com that's right make sure you go
check idirect dcom you never know what
might be in stock what might randomly be
on sale go check it out go take a look I
direct.com now let's move into the
question and answer portion of today's
podcast the questions on today's podcast
did come from my website iry
genetics.com that's right I do have two
websites don't get confused but I
genetics.com doeses have a link to
everything you can imagine on that
website there is a tab that says grow
help or grow questions if you click on
that grow help question tab guess what
it gives you the opportunity to send me
a grow question type in a good question
if I read your question here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds from edirect
docomo question on today's podcast came
from somebody who's going to be called
weed vet shout out to my new friend weed
vet thank you for the great question the
question says hey rosta Jeff greetings
my new friend weed vet first of all
thank you for your service then it says
uh let me start out by thanking you for
the excellent podcast you are very
welcome sir thank you for listening it
says I discovered you on a road trip
from Minnesota to Phoenix and I've been
back into your archive quite far oh that
means you've been listening to those old
episodes uh that makes me proud and also
embarrassed thank you for listening and
also don't judge me Me by those old
shows bro I've grown a lot but uh they
exist and it happen so I don't delete
them that's a time capsule uh that's how
it was it's what I did it's what I said
it's what I thought then who knows watch
The Evolution see how I grow throughout
the years you guys don't be afraid to
change your thoughts and opinions as you
become more educated on things you're
not stuck on a belief just cuz uh that's
what you've always believed if you learn
new information that like like the dude
said new [ __ ] has come to light man if
some new [ __ ] comes to light uh learn
adjust your info is going to dictate
what you believe let that change if it
does change I'm preaching some weird
[ __ ] now let's stay focused shout out to
my friends at green. laabs it says I
would also like to thank you for sharing
your knowledge and your experience you
make me a better grower my dude weed vet
uh that right there is the the recharge
for me as a as a podcaster you just
fertilized me quite well um thank you um
that's what makes me a better podcaster
so it goes in a big circle these kind of
compliments uh make me recharged and
more inspired to do more podcast casting
and knowing that I'm helping people and
making someone a better grower that
makes all the lights the equipment the
time it's all worth it brother so thank
you uh keep growing keep listening we'll
get better together now we will I was
going to say we're going to quit
rambling but we're definitely not
because the dabs I took are making my
head spin today I enjoy it uh here we go
it says so here's my topic I would like
to hear you speak about it says in
breeding cannabis how far into the
female flower cycle do the plants uh to
take the plants to harvest seeds thank
you for all you do and for all of the
help you provide uh my dude you are very
welcome once again thank you for your
service and thank you for the great
question also my friend make sure you
check your inbox for a coupon code
because you have won a free pack of
seeds from idirect decom that's easier
to say than it does sound but thank you
for the question uh thank you for the
service now let me ramble a little bit
about uh so the question is uh it sounds
like you've got some plants they've been
pollinated and no you want to know how
far they need to go into that process
until those seeds are ready until you
can Harvest those seeds uh most of the
time after
pollination so this is after you know
the plants have been successfully
pollinated I pollinate twice I'll hit
them one time I'll let that boy uh
regenerate another batch of pollen then
I'll go in there and I'll hit them again
usually about 5 to seven days apart
maybe 10 days at the most I don't want
to go that far to be honest with you but
5 to seven days apart is ideal hit them
twice chop down the dude clean up the
pollen then let those plants start doing
their thing now uh the question the
answer to the question is generally from
that point about 6 to 8 weeks it depends
on several factors uh it could be 6 to n
weeks it just depends on how much light
is in the room what kind of light is in
the room how intense is the light how
many watts is it the appropriate
Spectrum how many hours is that light
running things like that definitely uh
contribute to the finishing time of your
seeds also uh humidity warmth cold swing
Wings overwater underwater all of those
things will contribute to the finishing
time of those seeds in what I would call
ideal conditions 6 to8 weeks and that is
going to be plant specific some of your
plants will spit them out in eight weeks
some are going to take nine weeks
because that is what that plant does you
won't be able to speed it up you can't
rush it there are tricks and tips you
can do like I said lighting and things
but that plant is just going to take
that long no matter what in some
phenotypes now I do have some tips here
uh you can get them to finish more quick
if you use a method that many people
that listen to my podcast or are at
least trolls on the Internet or have big
mouths on Twitter they think this idea
is crazy but anybody that's tried it has
sent me a message and said dude I tried
your uh the 186 method is what it's
called a lot of people know what I'm
leading to already people that are
afraid to try it think I'm a lunatic for
this they use a lot of creative words to
describe my idea here it's not my idea I
don't remember exactly where I learned
it it was a combination of things
falling into place now one practice I do
recommend heavily is after those plants
are pollinated what I like to do is I
turn my light timer back to 18 hours on
and 6 hours off I go to my regular
vegetative uh light cycle for those
plants after pollination has happened
many people's heads are blowing up
they're like why would you put your
flowering plants back into a veg cycle
because at this point I don't care about
buds I'm not growing for buds I don't
want flowers I don't care what they look
like at the end I am strictly growing
these plants for seed I focused on seed
production uh you're not going to get
any usable smokable flour out of this a
lot of people want to be able to grow a
plant that makes flowers to smoke and
seeds and when I'm doing it I focus on
one or the other I make a crop that is
going to be fully seeded because if I'm
making seeds I want every single every
single bat every single CX to be stuffed
with seeds in that entire plant I want
as many seeds as I can possibly get if
I'm going to smoke it I don't want any
seeds in there so it's one or the other
for me so if I'm doing this method I'm
doing it with a fully seated crop I'm
not con too concerned about the
appearance of this crop of the flowers
of the buds I don't care what it looks
like as long as those seeds are super
healthy that is all that matters to me
so when your head's blowing up saying
those plants are going to go back into
veg or weird stuff is going to happen
yes absolutely weird stuff is going to
happen uh after about 21 days the plants
will show signs of R about three weeks
into this uh you're going to be like
what is happening the plants are
spitting out little shoots starting to
put little plants coming off the top of
my regular plant what's going on it's
completely going into rev the leaves are
going to start twisting and doing weird
[ __ ] but guess what the seeds are going
to be very healthy very happy and very
viable and when you grow them you will
see that they're they are very
productive very happy seeds uh they will
make all of your grower friends very
happy if you sell them or share them
with them so what I do when I making
those seeds is I pollinate two times
then I turn that light back on to 186
and it speeds up that process this will
get those eight weers down to seven
weeks this will get the seven weers down
to six weeks the plants that take longer
to ripen the seeds will also take longer
in those expect that uh but uh not as
long as the plant will take to finish a
few weeks shorter but expect them to go
longer you can speed them up by doing
this 186 light manipulation method so
just a recap because we all know I like
to get rambly uh the quick answer to
this is most plants are going to take
you 6 to 8 weeks for those seeds to be
done maybe 9 we and some plants uh but
typically it's about 6 or eight weeks
until they're done after the pollination
of course and then uh the second part of
the question that I wanted to add to was
you can speed that process up by
changing that light cycle back to 18
hours on and 6 hours off again expect to
see Wild [ __ ] coming from those plants
but the seeds will be amazing all right
my dude weed vet I want to thank you
once again for the great question also
thanks again for your service I hope I
answered your question question
thoroughly uh big shout out to my
friends in Minnesota and once again dude
check your inbox because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from
air.com all right we're going to keep
this show moving of course this next
question is also about seeds and
breeding going to keep the theme moving
this one came from a friend who wants to
be called xtg grown xtg my dude make
sure you check your inbox because you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds from idirect decom
the question goes a little bit like this
it says hey there much love for all you
do for the community Big Love bro much
respect going back at you I appreciate
that it says I appreciate the wisdom you
just keep dropping bro thank you uh I've
been having a lot of fun putting out the
podcast lately thank you for listening I
appreciate that uh the question says I
was hoping you could share a little more
information I'm starting to flower out
some plants and I'm only worried about
producing seeds with them so that will
make this easy it said my question is
when growing for seed making what
changes in your nutrition and light
cycle would you make if any uh thank you
much man stay well all right this is a
great question I do have fun with this
one the thing we're mostly going to do
if we're producing seeds and we're not
focused on uh flower production is I'm
going to drop out those Bloom boosters I
don't need the big heavy PK boosters at
the end of flower those aren't necessary
because I'm not uh boosting blooms I'm
just making seeds so we're going to drop
those out is going to be our first major
change we're going to feed the basic NPK
uh basically if you're a bottle-fed
nutrient grower person I don't switch
out uh so when you regularly go from Veg
to bloom you're going to switch to your
Bloom nutrient if you're making seeds
keep that veg nutrient going uh give it
that little bit of an increased nitrogen
uh lower volumes of potassium and
phosphorus uh that's just basically what
I've seen work well for the uh seed
production you don't need that Big Bloom
booster going on uh then a little a
little bit of extra uh calcium maybe a
touch extra of magnesium they come in
the same bottle everyone's going to say
just use the Cal Mag that's that will
work for you a little touch extra um and
then some silica I like to add a little
bit of silica a tip if you're mixing all
these nutrients in make sure silica
first um that's just a rule of thumb
when you're mixing silica products into
your uh solution mix the silica first
get it thoroughly emulsify then add your
other products in I would go the silica
your base nutrient the CAG
and then after that I would add some
amino acids is another thing I would add
you can add carbs in there if you'd like
but amino acids is another thing that I
would definitely add to that micro
Hydroponics makes a great Amino booster
product it is cost effective you need
very minimal of that to make healthy
seeds I would add that to your mix amino
acids are the building blocks of life it
makes sense to me to add a little bit of
aminos to my feed for my seeds it makes
sense to me so that's mainly what I
would recommend and then um for light
once again I would talk about that 186
light light cycle some people will tell
you to leave in the uh if you do switch
out the HPS for the metalight if you're
old school uh some people may tell you
to leave that metal highight in there uh
throughout the veg process right into
flour but uh my main nutrition
difference is going to be I'm going to
cut out those Bloom boosters I recommend
usually um some boosters I'm not going
to say them because I don't want to
confuse your head cut those out we don't
need those uh we need so another thing I
also want to recommend is the entire
room needs to be in line you need a
solid VPD um if your plant does get
powdery mildew the powdery mildew will
attack the seeds the seeds will have
powdery mildew on them uh that doesn't
mean they will grow powdery mildew that
is not what that means at all but if an
educated consumer buys your seeds and
puts them under a microscope a
magnifying glass they can identify the
presence of pathogens that were on that
seed as it was shipped uh there can be
fungus on the seed when it arrives to
your customer if you got Bud rot if you
got powdery mildew uh make sure not to
do that let's get that room dialed in
get the whole room in line you need
everything beautiful not just uh not
just the nutrition you need uh subcool
used to call it the laws the lights the
air the water and the soil all of that
needs to be dialed in and when you're
making seeds it's very nice to get all
of that extra dialed in to get those
seeds extra perfect uh to get the plants
extra healthy that way you can get as
many uh as many pistols as possible on
each plant and then make as many seeds
as possible to start with and then just
keep those plants thoroughly healthy all
the way then you have healthy happy big
fat robust round seeds all right let me
make sure I've answered this question
because I'm super rambly today which is
not a problem for a podcaster uh what
changes to nutrition uh drop out the
bloom boosters keep that uh the base
nutrients coming all the way through uh
you don't have to flush because you are
feeding seeds uh no one's going to smoke
this and I think flushing is partly
mostly a myth anyway uh flushing is a
myth I'm standing to buy it um increase
your Cal Mag feed them some silica and
of course feed them those amino acids
and if you want to get frisky give them
some carbs and always nobody pays me to
say this but give them some microbes big
shout out to my buddy Scotty reel get
yourself a bag of recharge real Growers
use recharge they don't pay me to say
that they're just my friends and it's
good product all right where were we
also that 186 light cycle will help you
out to speed up this seed process my
dude xtg grown uh thank you for the
great question once again check your
inbox because you have a coupon code for
a free pack of seeds from
air.com all right before we jump into
this next question it is my duty and
responsibility as a podcaster to remind
you as a viewer to click like And
subscribe that's right if you like my
ramblings about ganja growing please do
click that like button if you want an
update every time I put out an episode
please do click that subscribe button
and just in case you cannot get enough
of my Shenanigans join me on Instagram
that's right every Monday night I do a
live show on Instagram on my Instagram
it is _ gentics I I eore gentics let me
give you a fair warning there a couple
of fake IE genetics accounts that's how
you know you've made it ladies and
gentlemen when there are fake accounts
that's how you know you are successful
but follow me on Instagram I am _
genetics I am the one with a lot of
followers 36,000 is followers follow the
other accounts only have a couple of
hundred don't be fooled but please give
me a follow on Instagram _ genetics
check out the iy genetics Instagram
Monday Night Live show where I do I just
answer questions on the fly on Instagram
all right where were we we are going to
jump into this next question here I've
got a question right in front of me this
one once again came from the I genetics
website from the growel tab this one
came from our friend who is called nine
toes um usually I answer the questions
today I want to ask a question bro where
is the 10th
toe curious my dude what happened to the
10th toe respond I want to know send me
an update please I look forward to it
all right where were we the question
says what's up roster Jeff first off
thank you for the podcast and thanks for
the inspiration to LEAP into making my
own seeds my dude uh thank you for
listening to the show and thank you for
considering me an inspiration I've been
called a lot of words a lot of names and
an inspiration is when I'd like to be
called again thank you my bro the
question said my question is this uh
when pollinating a receiver plant makes
sense so far is it possible to pollinate
two different branches with different
pollen and make multiple crosses from
one female plant it is possible but I
don't recommend it you can do it but I'm
a stickler I like Purity I like um I
like knowing a lot of where uh pedigree
is what I really like to know I want to
make sure that the seeds that came from
this Branch definitely are what I think
they are and I'm hypercritical about
that if you're not 1,000% stressed about
it if you don't care that maybe the
pollen from this pollination got over to
this one and and vice versa go for it
but I don't want that to happen I sell
seeds I need people to be able to rely
on this is what I said it is if you're
going to grow it yourself and have fun
with it uh get down to it bro do make
the [ __ ] happen have a good old time
but if those seeds are going any I don't
recommend it because you could you could
simply cross-pollinate which isn't a
thing that I normally say that's a silly
word to me but that's what you could
accidentally do cross-contaminate your
two pollinations and you could get
because pollen is microscopic pollen is
Tiny and it just takes one strong breath
and you can move that pollen
accidentally around so I wouldn't do it
the could you yes would I know that's
that's the quick version of that answer
but um could you is it possible yeah yes
it's possible to uh pollinate different
branches with different pollen to make
different crosses from one plant it
absolutely is but it's risky and I would
not do it but like I said if you're a
home breeder if you're a dude having fun
uh that sounds like fun to me I can't do
it in my position CU I really I want to
know the pedigree of everything in my
garden to a really um an OCD type of
level there is more to this I'm not
going to shoot you down completely and
in the question though it says also when
growing plants for seed is the drying
the same as for smoke or should it be
drier than normal thank you for the time
I took a dab and I gave my mom a hug bro
thank you for the dab and the hug I
appreciate that uh she mumbled something
about orange gasm oh I'm not going to
read the rest of that um that's that's
that that's cringey bro I like it um I'm
just not going to read the rest of it so
I only recommend one male is what I
wrote on as my notes Here pollen moves
easily you could breathe pollen into the
wrong part but like I said if you're
having fun get down to it bro Jungle
Boogie now let's talk about this other
part how dry should I let these plants
get what I do we're just going to talk
briefly about how I harvest seeded
plants because that's the only way to
get this right uh what I normally do is
I take the plant and I chop the plant
down I take the plant tag and make sure
it is now attached to that dried plant
in a or in that harvested plant in a way
that it will not come off that plant tag
is moving with that plant now for the
rest of its life it ends up in the bin
with the seeds that helps me verify it
just keeps it stays all the way through
so I chop down the Plant I take the
plant tag it goes with it it hangs over
a tupperware bin might be a sterlite bin
I don't remember the name it's sterlite
it's a short one it would normally go
under your bed for clothing is what I
think they sell it for but it's just the
right size for a harvested plant so I
hang the plant right above that I hang
it above that in case I leave it too
long and it starts to dry and the seeds
do fall out then it falls into my
Collective bin right underneath it it
most of the time they don't get that far
but I do let them get what I would
consider the unit of measurement for how
dry they are would be dry as [ __ ] that
is the unit of measurement which I let
them get to they'll be they will be dry
as [ __ ] then I will take a pair of
gloves and I will grab one the plant by
the stock and I will hang it over that
uh Bin and I will pull all of the buds
right off of that stock just like this
and it's so dry that it just sounds like
it's raining seeds right into my
collector bin and then with those same
gloves I will take my hands and just
mush that butt up into little tiny dust
basically and then now I've got dust of
green dust with a bunch of seeds in
there now the fun part after that is
sifting that green part the chaff is
what that is called from the seeds
that's what that is uh you want you got
to get all the chaff out of the seed or
the seed out of the chaff depends on
what you got more of is how I guess
you're going to refer to it but that is
the fun part I've got a machine that
helps me do it uh there are a lot of
different creative machines available
but uh you're asking about how dry I let
it get dry as [ __ ] my dude uh just let
it get crispy dry and the seeds will
probably start plopping out and that's
when you want to grab it and just chuck
all those buds shuck all the buds right
off the stick into a bin and then I just
give it the old dusty [ __ ] hand
treatment just grind it up all your
material is going to fall right into
that bin you could tip it one way and
most of the seeds will roll down but
there are a lot of different methods to
get the chaff separated from there many
of them involve using uh either a light
fan or a vacuum if you can put a vacuum
on low and learn how to feather it
brother just to get uh just get the the
weed out and not the seeds you'll figure
out how to do it you'll suck up a few
seeds in the beginning but uh if it's
yours it's okay just don't go ham and
[ __ ] suck that whole batch of seeds
up don't do it just skip this idea um
I've seen it done I know how to do it
I'm not going to teach you how to do it
and suck up a whole batch of seeds in
the vacuum because you'll be mad as [ __ ]
at me bro here comes the hate mail
roster Jeff I'm digging through my
vacuum for my f1s no thank you don't
want to hear it but if you learn how to
do it you could gently feather a vacuum
over your batch of seeds and suck up all
the chaff and not get the weed or the
seeds that you want all right where are
we what am I even talking about at this
point let's not make it a morovich
situation unless you really wanted to
get it dry as [ __ ] and find a process
that makes it easy to separate all of
the chaff from the
seeds all right ladies and gentlemen
boys and girls pimps and hoes friends
and foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers all of you amazing
podcast listeners out there for full uh
full disclosure I did notice a technical
glitch in this episode it's going to
take me a few minutes a lot of extra
minutes to edit and repair this episode
so I'm going to cut it short it's going
to be a little bit short of an episode
but hey it's a podcast episode I can cut
it short if I want to there's a
technical glitch that you don't even
want to know about that I've got to
repair it's going to take me quite some
time but the show must go on uh like
nadab says we never miss an upload shout
out to my dude in adav uh this is all
unconfirmed news ladies and gentlemen we
we're going to wrap up this rambly
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content uh make sure you check
out the website I genetics.com there's a
link to the Discord server you will find
a link to the merchandise store you will
find that growel tab where you can get
your question right here on the show
also there will be a link to I
redirect.sh
you think of the podcast um I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Citrus
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another DB
grab your p in about the
B is in the lab sit back
relax roots and wisd start to
s from the know seeds we grow tuning now
to hear the vibr that Jeff in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard healing
light to can go from your heart your BL
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a do educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof RF will guide you through in
this GED find the new rise up higher
Find Your Way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the song
[Music]
open minds to see the truth in the soil
lies the proof R the Jeff will guide you
through in this Garden find the new rise
up higher Find Your Way brow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong join the movement sing the
song o
[Music]
[Applause]