[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother yeah welcome back podcast world
I'm your host rosta Jeff this of course
is episode
853 of the grow from your heart podcast
in today's episode I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in
today's podcast I do want to send a
quick update a quick apology I did miss
two uploads that's right I don't usually
Miss uploads I did give you a warning I
was going to skip a week I had to skip
two weeks I went to a Comedy Festival in
Las Vegas every time I go to Fremont
Street I come back with the plague uh I
can still hear it in my headphones my
voice my nose do not sound right I
apologize if I sound a little funky on
this episode but I'm trying to get an
episode out uh thank you for all of the
people who sent me well wishes and asked
if I was okay uh no bro I was not okay I
was dying I had the Las Vegas plague it
was not a good time but I am recovering
I am much better I am back on the mic
and I'm excited to do a podcast episode
uh quickly just to talk about where I
was I don't like to talk too much about
what I was doing on the podcast here try
to stick to the topic but I went to a
festival called skankfest many people
many people may say what was skankfest
that's an interesting name yes I listen
to a podcast called the Legion of skanks
hosted by Big J oakerson Louis J Gomez
and Dave Smith it's a great podcast they
throw a Comedy Festival every year that
Festival is called skankfest it's an
amazing Comedy Festival it's getting
very popular it's getting very big I've
gone for the past couple of years I had
a really good time uh got to see a lot
of great comedians I got to see a lot of
great podcasts recorded live I got to
see a lot of great friends that I know
from SK Fest that I only see at
skankfest or comedy shows or festivals
so it's great to meet up with all of
them they're all there in one place
skankfest is cool because a comedian
will do a show on stage and you're in a
big room packed standing room only
shoulder-to-shoulder with uh comedy fans
uh skanks a bunch of skank nerds a bunch
of Comedy nerds a bunch of bunch of
crazy dudes having a good time uh and
then your favorite comic will tell his
last joke and be like all right guys
that was my set have a good time and
they'll walk off stage and come stand
next to you and watch the next guy on
stage cuz the comedy is so good that
they want to be part of the crowd they
want to be involved uh the comics and
the comedians just all blending together
that skankfest it's a good time said I
wasn't going to talk too much about it
guess what talked a lot about it all
right now I want to do a couple of shout
outs to a few people who support the
show on patreon quick shout out to my
friend Jessica k a big shout out to
shorty Y and a big old fist bump to my
buddy OG purple thumb all right now we
are going to work our way into the
question and answer portion of today's
podcast as I start this I want to give a
a big shout out to everybody out there
in Florida uh everybody on both coasts
who have suffered from hurricanes uh the
hurricanes have been tremendous there's
been a lot of damage a lot of uh
destruction uh there's also been some uh
that is never good I may have to bleep
that word out just for YouTube
censorship purposes but there's been a
lot of Destruction a lot of turmoil
because of these hurricanes uh big shout
out to all those people I do send a big
fist bump to you a lot of jaw love to
all those people lots of protection for
you hope you recover from all the
turmoil very quickly hope things get
back to normal as close as that can be
for you as quickly as possible now that
is part of why we are going to read a
question that involves a question about
lights and a power failure and a power
problem a lot of people are going to
experience power problems at this point
in time electricity failure if you're
near the hurricane areas your power is
going to go out uh this question kind of
got highlighted because of that is
happening now so let's work our way
right into this question this question
came from the growel tab on iry
genetics.com if you go to iry
genetics.com
there's a row of tabs one of those tabs
does say grow help or grow questions
click on that tab if you send me a good
grow question and I read that question
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
edirect tocom the question goes a lot
like this first of all it came from our
friend who wants to be called bad Papa
um okay that's an interesting name I
like that shout out to my new friend bad
Papa it says with winter coming up and
then I really big wrote over that the
word hurricanes because this is very
valid for hurricane season it says will
a power outage in the garden cause a lot
of problems how long can plants survive
without light when should you consider
using a power uh an alternative power
source and what problems could arise in
veg and or in flower how long could
plants survive in low temps if perhaps
problem perhaps a power outage could
occur this is a very good question now
what I'm going to say to the folks
experiencing these power shortages and
interruptions uh where the hurricanes
are if your power is going out and
coming on randomly and going out I would
just say unplug everything and just let
it stay unplugged until they get
figured out it's probably better for the
plants and it's definitely better for
your equipment your ballasts uh all of
your gear would rather just come on and
stay on or stay off then come off and on
off and on all intermittently uh with
power surges coming through the house
just unplug that let it rest the
plants should be fine if they're in
flower they're not going to get light
but they'll stay in flow they'll keep
flowering if they're in veg eventually
they may flip into a phase that's when I
would get in there with some light every
few hours and just wake them up it takes
them a little bit to fall asleep but if
you get in there every few hours and
give them light you can keep those
plants awake you can do it with very
small lights just keep them awake keep
them alive but you can keep them in veg
if you do give them a little bit of
light but what I'm saying is if you've
got a bunch of power interruptions just
unplug uh let that stuff rest let
all the gear rest don't let it keep
coming off and on that's more
destructive to your gear there's a lot
more stuff that I did WR down here now
the question did start with winter is
coming so let's focus a little bit on
this winter aspect of the question uh
there is one part that says how long
could the plant survive in low temps if
perhaps a long power outage occurred if
you are able to be in that house you
personally as a person are able to be in
that house and be safe and be
comfortable the plants are just fine
those plants can survive very very low
temperatures if they are healthy I don't
know about maybe some hydroponic plants
that may be a different story if you got
water in there those roots get super
cold that could be problematic for you
but these plants can't handle quite cold
temperatures um we always thought
certain temperatures were as low as they
can go but a few years ago it snowed
here in Colorado very early we got a
very early snowstorm and there were some
very healthy crops that survived that
snow so we've seen extreme we've seen
snow on the plants you had to go outside
and shake the ice and snow off of the
ganja plants and they were okay so they
can survive it's kind of up to the
plants it's up to a lot of other factors
but they can survive very cold
temperatures if you're in that house and
you're not dying those plants are
probably just fine uh so the winter is
coming something I would focus on if you
are in the South if you're near these
hurricanes I would be more concerned at
this point with humidity you're going to
want to maybe open a window I don't know
what you can even do but you're going to
get a lot of humidity if your grow is
trapped in the house and you don't have
power uh those plants even in the dark
will create humidity they're going to be
breathing they're going to be
transpiring and respiring and moisture
will be happening into the air in that
room uh the humidity from the pots the
leaves uh just the soil itself will be
letting off humidity so depending on the
temperature of the room and the
environment you may have a humidity
issue in there you may need to vent a
fan do something uh waft out that
humidity somehow may be the other thing
to deal with uh let me give a quick read
make sure I cover this whole question
and then we'll send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds from idirect
decom once again make sure you check
that spam because sometimes that's where
those coupon codes go winnner coming
power outage how long can they survive
without light they could survive uh a
very long time without light but they go
into flower so to prevent that uh go in
there every few hours with some light
and give them light even if it's an
intense flashlight Shine the Light on
them and wake those plants up they will
come awake when should when should you
consider an alternative power source um
if you're in flow it'd be cool to have
an alternative flower Source but most of
the time if it's two three maybe four
days which uh it usually doesn't go
longer than that in we're if you're in
the states uh most of the time except
for that one time in Texas it went
pretty long but most of the time you're
not going to need some sort of stuff
like that unless you're in a hurricane
area but then if you're in a hurricane
situation is the grow really the
priority anyway you're using that
generator just to run the basics of life
and keep the keep the family alive um if
you can afford a generator set it up why
not have fun get at it but not
everybody's got that kind of funding I
think you your plants will live three or
four days without power if they really
needed to um yeah I think I've covered
most of the question here uh the
Winter's coming they can get pretty damn
cold and then for the hurricane season I
recommend uh some some sort of humidity
control I don't know what you're going
to do in there open a window start
Fanning your arms I don't know but
that's what I would recommend maybe that
humidity already flew out with the
hurricane I don't know man I know the
humidity is high in Florida right now
all right my dude bad Papa thank you for
the great question I hope I helped you
out I hope I gave those hurricane people
some advice if your power is flickering
off and on just unplug it that way if
you get some water you're a little bit
safer anyway all right make sure you
check your inbox my dude because you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds at iir
.c all right I do have another question
here right in front of me this one also
came from the website this one came from
OG JZ shout out to my new friend OG JZ
that's hard for me to say for some
reason I really could mess that up this
is a general grow question that goes a
lot like this it says yo rosta Jeff I
love what you do for the Cannabis
Community yo thank you for noticing uh
and I really enjoy it when people use
the word community in it when they talk
about what I'm doing for ganja cuz I
really do try to build a community the
Discord Community is strong the IE Army
is strong uh so thank you I appreciate
it and thanks for letting me be a part
and a leader in the community that's
it's an honor to be welcomed into this
community because uh this community is
uh it's it's tight so thank you I'm just
making sure that my recording gear is
working right I got a weird flickering
light going on here everything is
popping up good up there all right I'm
getting paranoid now all right the
question goes when breeding and
collecting seeds what is the easiest way
to harvest the seeds from the plant
that's a very good question I like this
one so uh you've got a crop of plants
they are fully seeded is what I'm going
to assume breeding and collecting seeds
what's the easiest way to harvest the
seeds so uh when the plants are done I
chop down the entire plant I hang it
upside down I get the plant tag and I
attach it to that plant so that it will
not come away from that plant that tag
and that plant will continue together
for the rest of their lives when that's
a bag of seeds that plant tag ends up in
the bag of seeds it'll travel its whole
life with it I don't want any confusion
so chop down the Plant hang it up side
down put the plant tag on it now we know
what it is I use um it's from the brand
sterlite is what they are they're little
bins that are made to store clothing
under the bed little like a tupperware
or rubber made plastic bin uh you're
supposed to put clothes and shoes and
stuff like that under it put the lid on
it and slide it under the bed for
storage uh I put one of those underneath
the hanging plant so that if any seeds
do begin to fall out they land into that
little plastic bin it's not going to
happen for a while but it may happen so
I've got each plant hung up kind of
spaced apart with a plastic bin
underneath it and then we let it get to
a very uh specific dryness uh percentage
I need a very specific percentage of
dryness I've I've discovered a very
precise unit of measurement uh at which
I prefer the moisture level in my plants
when I'm going to start the next step so
um the next step is to uh get the plants
to that precise unit of measurement and
that precise unit of measurement is dry
as get these plants dry as you
want them crispy uh I want them so what
I'm going to do I'm going to put on
gloves uh and I'm going to put these
plants I'm going to just chop them into
smaller pieces and put them in the bin
I'm going to grab the stick and I'm just
going to pull the Nuggets right off the
stick just shuck that bud right into
that plastic bin I'm going to get all
the buds off the sticks into that bin
and then I'm going to take my gloved
hands and I'm just going to grind all
that bud into dust just grind it all up
gently I'm not going to crush the seeds
but I'm going to grind all that flour
material up and you'll hear the seeds
just fall out into your bin and all your
weed will just be all in your face it'll
be all piled up everywhere in your bin
and then you can kind of tip that bin to
one side and scoop the weed material up
to one end all the seeds Will Roll most
of the seeds will roll down to the
bottom and you can scoop a lot of that
we call it chaff the bud material that
doesn't have seed um I don't use that
for anything that goes in a compost bin
I know that's going to ruffle a lot of
feathers but I've beat the out of
it it's been so beat up that if I make
edibles with it they come out green and
they don't taste good cuz all the
chlorophyll if I make concentrat same
story all that material has been so
Disturbed that there's so much
chlorophyll just oozing out of it that
it makes bad product so it's all trash
it's all compost it makes it makes good
great compost and good bokashi starter
but uh so I take that buds I just pull
them off the sticks and then now I got a
bucket of buds or a tray of buds and I
take my glove take my gloved hands and
just crush up all those buds I just kind
of do this like it just crunch crunch
crunch and just crush it all up and
you'll hear the seeds fall out the
material will fall out and then there
are several ways from there to remove
the seed from the chaff I've got a
machine uh it's called the easy seed
seed sorder the grow it's easy seed seed
sorter it looks like a shoe box and it's
got a shoot on top you pour your
material in and it's got a couple of
trap doors in a fan and I am not a
physicist but the way that it works is
the fan blows the weed material this way
so all the light stuff goes this way
into a drawer and it falls and all the
seeds are heavier than that so if the
fan doesn't blow them and it blows those
into another drawer and I can open a
drawer and I got seeds in one and
material in another and I'll dump those
seeds into a little bin and then I'll
run that material one more time honestly
just to be careful and make sure I get
all the seeds uh cuz sometimes it'll
miss a few but I'll give it one or two
runs maybe a third run depending on how
much material you try and that that
machine pulls it apart very very quickly
there's also another machine that looks
like a um if it's a Plinko it looks like
a Plinko a Chinko Plinko machine I don't
remember what that shit's called back in
the day um
there's another machine it's made uh
it's constructed from wood and
plexiglass and it's much taller it's a
much bigger uh more cumbersome machine I
I wouldn't with that unless you've
got a lot of seeds to sort but this one
hooks up to a shop vac and you put two
five gallon buckets underneath it and
you pour your material in there and it
works on the same principle but the shop
vac will suck the weed material up and
your seeds will fall through the other
side you got two uh you got a bucket of
weed material and a bucket of seed
material and then your shop vac got all
the really light weed in it so that's
another thing that's available if you
just Google uh hemp seed sorder these
things will pop up both of these will
pop up the little white seed box that I
use is not available currently those are
all sold out but the uh the other
machine with the plexiglass on the front
where you can watch it operate that is
available uh both of them work very well
I like mine cuz it's much smaller
doesn't take up very much space however
it does make a mess uh that fan shoots a
bunch of material out I have to do it in
the garage and then there's a lot of
sweeping up to do don't do it with the
car in the garage cuz your car will be
tinted green but uh let me make sure I'm
staying on track uh when breeding uh
what is the easiest way to harvest the
seeds yeah get it dry as and then
just pull the stick right out of the
buds let the buds all gather into a bin
and then crush it all up and then there
are several ways to do it if you don't
have one of the machines I talked about
uh I've heard of people just lightly
using a vacuum you got to be real
careful if you do use the vacuum just
real gingerly suck the material off the
top and get the leave the seeds on the
bottom you can probably gingerly figure
out how to suck the material up and get
those seeds out of there you guys I
apologize for the running nose that just
started happening on the podcast I'm
telling you I'm recovering from that
lost Vegas skankfest plague and it's not
over yet it keeps kind of it's perking
back up all right where were we uh dry
as is the precise unit of
measurement and then get all that
material out of there before you uh seal
those seeds up in anything make sure
that all that green is out of there
and make sure everything's nice and dry
make sure there's no moisture left in
there because you don't want to get
moldy seeds and that is still a
possibility all right my dude OG JZ
thank you for the great question I love
talking about breeding I love talking
about seeds if you have any more
breeding or seeds questions please do
Reach Out ladies and gentlemen make sure
you send those questions to the website
go to the website IR genetics.com click
on that growel tab send me your grow
question if I read your grow question
here on the show I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
edirect if I owe you a pack of seeds and
you haven't gotten the coupon code
please do send me a reminder what
happened a couple of times um I'm not
going to show everybody's everybody this
page but where the email comes up for
some reason the email doesn't populate
in this form so I got to go digging uh
and I was waiting for you to email me
because I know you're going to to let me
know your address so email me if I
haven't gotten you your packs of seeds
and I will get you your coupon code as
soon as possible thank you for the
patience and for the help rede did I
send you a coupon code I think I did bro
I hope so if not remind me I'll get you
that coupon code all right where were we
this is the part of the show where I
remind you to click like And subscribe
that's right do you like the show click
like that shit's free click like for me
please do and also subscribe that way
every time I put out an episode you'll
get a notification and you never miss
any of my high quality educational
content all right let's keep this party
moving I do have one more good question
here in front of me this question also
came from that growel tab this one came
from somebody we're going to call James
shout out to my new friend James James
thank you for the great question I've
got a good answer for you the question
goes a little bit like this it says Hey
Rost Jeff how can I effectively deal
with fungus snats these things are out
of control my first piece of advice is
stop overwatering I bet a lot of your
plants are overwatered also I bet you've
got house plants and I bet those plants
are all overwatered as well uh those
fungus snats come in on house plants
those fungus snats come in in bags of
dirt they breed very rapidly a little
bit of overwatering will encourage more
fungus snats so uh stop overwatering a
little bit uh stop overwatering your
house plants also check your drains in
your house sometimes those drains get a
little bit funky uh you'll start getting
some fungus snats some little bugs
flying up from there check those maybe
those drains need a little bit of
treatment there's a lot of things you
can do for those as well that may be
another source of your fungus snats the
drains all the drains in your house the
showers the sinks check on that I know
it sounds funky but that's where they
will like to congregate so check all
your ganja plants your house plants all
those drains if you can cover those
drains that's a good idea that'll keep
the fungus knats from coming up there
squ some lemon juice put a cover on it
that'll help you out really quickly uh
but stop overwatering the plants uh the
house plants and the ganja plants is the
first piece of advice uh let that soil
dry out a little bit that will let them
die off they won't be able to breede in
there they won't be as happy in there
defoliate the lowers if you're if the
lower part of your ganja plants are
touching the dirt take that off of there
defoliate all that lower I like to
defoliate a lot of the bottoms of the
plants uh that'll help mitigate a lot of
the bug problems then if we need to do
some chemical treatments this is when I
would recommend a soil dredge this is
very easy to do if your plants are
healthy this will not cause any problems
at all if your plants are a little angry
and don't have healthy Roots this could
cause them to get a little bit pissed
off but what I would do is I would mix
up first of all I would try a soil
dredge with a very simple product called
mosquito bits or mosquito dunks uh it
comes in a mosquito dunks and bits are
really easy to find the uh dunks are
easier to find than the bits in my
opinion I order the bits on Amazon they
show up quite quickly mosquito dunks or
mosquito bits they're the same thing
just in a different form one's a big dut
one's the doughnut already crushed up
which is advantageous CU I'm going to
tell you to crush the doughnut up anyway
uh put some of that mosquito bit stuff
in your water uh you can't put too much
put a bunch of it in there mix it up I
want to see it floating around a little
bit in there then water the plants uh
this method will not bother your plants
at all that any plants can handle this
do this to all your plants your house
plants your ganja plants water it with
the mosquito bits uh water it uh just
like you normally would water water as
heavily as you normally would let it dry
once it dries water with this again uh
what we're trying to do is get this in
there a couple of times and really
saturate the plant with the beneficial
bacteria that is in these mosquito bits
uh that'll make those bugs get the
out of there they won't want to be there
they can't survive they will leave so my
first attempt is the mosquito dunks or
mosquito bits give them a nice water
with that they're very available uh
they're on Amazon you can find them at
Target Lowe's home Depot possibly your
local mom and popop hardware store but
they are very available uh get those in
the water water the plants also water
the house plants uh that will help any
standing water you've got around you can
throw some of that in there that will
help get rid of the mosquitoes and the
little fungus gnats if that does not
work then that's when I would step up to
either evergreen or Panic or maybe even
botanigard Max and I would do a soil
dredge with one of those three products
don't mix those but do a soil dredge I
would start start with Evergreen uh do a
small maybe 15 to 30 MLS uh per gallon
of Evergreen that's kind of heavy maybe
go a little bit lighter if your plants
aren't in good shape so go ahead and do
a soil dredge with the Evergreen get
that down in the soil that way the bugs
don't want to be in there uh then let
them dry up and then repeat that again
in about 2 to three days if the plants
look healthy enough to survive through
that it's going to do some damage to the
roots cuz it is oily it's going to
frustrate them but that's how we're
going to get rid of the bugs if you
really want to if they're bad uh also do
a foler spray you could do the uh banic
foler spray you could do the Evergreen
foler spray you could do botanic guard
Max there's several fol year sprays
you've already got the Evergreen because
that's what I recommend for the soil
dredge you could spray it with that but
I think uh two doses of the soil of the
mosquito dunks should get rid of them if
not step up your game do an evergreen
dredge do it again in two or three days
and if you really want to get frisky in
there go ahead and spray at the same
time you probably should spray anyway if
you've got fungus snack
uh there's also an opportunity you got
some other bugs go ahead and hit it with
a decent spray of the Evergreen or the
Panic all right my dude James make sure
you check your inbox and your spam
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at iy direct.com
ladies and gentlemen if you have
listened to this podcast this far into
this episode uh make sure you use coupon
code fire fi use coupon code fire to
save 20% off of everything at iirc
that's right this is my reminder to make
that coupon code when I edit this
podcast coupon code fire f i for 20% off
at I direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys girls pimps hoes friends
foes smokers Growers clone Cutters
pollen Chuckers uh All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I do want
to thank you once again for listening to
this episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast where my voice does not sound
amazing in my headphones I hope it
sounded good to you uh give me some
feedback in the comments let me know
what you think of the show let me know
if you could hear the
um I don't prefer questions in the
comment section it's easier for me to
get the questions emailed to me um it's
easier to print them and manage them but
let me know what you think of the show
uh give me feedback all that sort of
stuff in the comment section keep the
comments going you guys it's good for
the algorithm and I love seeing it
happen um I think that's all I've got
make sure you check my website that's
right IR genetics.com there's a link to
I direct there's a link to the Discord
server there's a link to the patreon
where you can support the podcast
financially I will update the patreon
prizes for this month I have not done
that yet I telling you I was sick from
being in Vegas all right enough excuses
enough chatter I'm going to get out of
here click like click subscribe leave
some comments I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to my buddy Jake from the
front metel Friday podcast and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
time to take another Dam grab your pie
in I the
B death is in the lab sit back moment
relax roots andom
to from the know seeds we grow tuning
now to hear the vibr that Jeff in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard healing
like the canis go from your H your this
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the
song notal medicine and love flows
within us like a do
educate and Elevate join the Journey
Don't Be Late open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof RF will
guide you through in this Garden find
the new rise up higher Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
light We Stand real strong join the
movement ining the
[Music]
song open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find a new rise up up high up Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
[Music]
[Applause]