[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome to the podcast everybody
I'm your host Roston Jeff this is
episode
855 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds hang out
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in today's episode before we
jump into the question and answer
portion of today's show I do want to
give a big shout out to my friends at
the dude grows show that's right they
were kind enough to invite me on to be
the co-host my friend Scotty had to step
out of town for a little vacation I was
invited to be the co-host of the dude
grow show big shout out to dude for
being a gracious host big shout out to
my buddy Gro for being an awesome
producer and a big shout out for to
Scotty reel for taking a day off to let
me co-host the show if you're not
already following them make sure you
check out the dude grow show on YouTube
go give them a follow type in dude grow
show rosta Jeff the newest episode with
myself will pop up uh give it a view
give it some clicks some likes leave
some comments let them know what you
think but most importantly subscribe to
the dude grow show big shout out dude
thanks for having me on the show all
right let's move into the question and
answer portion of today's podcast I do
have a website that website of course is
IR genetics.com on that website there's
a row of tabs one of those tabs does say
grow help or grow questions if you send
me your grow question and I read that
question here on the podcast I will send
you a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds off of iire direct.com the first
question came from our new friend
Sleepwalker that's a great name shout
out to Sleepwalker I feel like I've been
sleepwalking all week the question goes
a little bit like this it says hey rosta
Jeff I love you I love the podcast and I
love your genetics bro that is a lot of
love don't even know you but if you're
sending that much love I already know I
can love you back it says I have a
question about the new clone drop you've
been doing I'm curious what the
acclamation procedure is for your
shipped clones I'm betting a lot of the
lucky folks who are able to score would
appreciate this info U then he says
unfortunately I wasn't able to get one
um yes I do have a solution for that it
says I know other sellers have specific
programs for keeping them alive and
slowly adjusting them what is yours
thanks for everything all right so this
is referring to many people may be
confused what this uh listener viewer is
talking about I recently did a little
drop of lemon Jeffrey rooted clones on
IED direct.com that's right I was able
to sell a few clones on iir and I do
plan to do that again uh this listener
said they were not able to get the
Clones they did sell out quite quickly
uh the way to make sure you get updates
when those clones are available is to go
to the website the same website where
you send in those questions I
genetics.com go to about three quarters
of the way down at the bottom of the
page there's a tab that says stay up to
date a little picture of a mailbox if
you type in your email address when I do
clone drops I will send out a newsletter
and everybody will get a newsletter when
those clones are coming out you can stay
up to date and you can get those clones
also patreon does get the first heads up
on new drops restocks and sometimes
random coupon codes so check out
patreon.com fromyou heart that also is
on IR genetics.com that's like four
websites I've mentioned in 30 seconds I
should chill out and stay focused over
here so my point is if you want to know
when those clones come out make sure you
join the newsletter that way you'll get
an update or of course patreon does get
the first heads up now let's address the
main part of the question yes I am
shipping clones and you can buy them off
of I direct.com but then they arrive and
what do you do with them how do I take
care of them that is a very good
question they're all sent via Priority
Mail Express sometimes I change up the
boxes depending on what is available but
they are always sent Priority Mail
Express so they get to you very quickly
now when your package arrives I do
recommend that you bring it indoors and
let it adjust to room temperature if it
was on the truck and it's really hot
outside you don't want to open that
package when the the plant inside there
is really hot and open it into a cool
room and the opposite if it's really
cold don't open it into a warm dry room
let that box sit and adjust to the room
for a little while let it adjust and get
to room temperature then when you open
it you will find that there is a baggie
a one gallon baggie inside of that box
it's probably taped to the the box is
what I've begun doing uh it's the most
secure and costeffective way to ship
these clones just tape it right to the
box so there's a big baggie in it's
gently taped to the Box remove that tape
get that big baggie out unroll that it's
just wrapped up once or twice unfold it
open that up reach inside you will find
the plant right inside of there at the
bottom of that plant are very nice roots
that have grown out I took a paper towel
and I moistened it and I gently wrapped
it around those roots it's just wrapped
around just very gently wrapped it's not
folded up too technically uh it's just a
real nice gentle wrap you can probably
unwrap it and then unfold it and it
should come right off the roots will be
very robust and very healthy the plants
that I sent are very healthy plants so
uh carefully unwrap that paper towel
sometimes they're going to get stuck if
it gets stuck put a little water on
there you just pour a little bottled
water on there you could spray some
water on there if you prefer get it wet
that paper towel should come right off
if it doesn't it's not a big deal gently
plant that paper towel and those roots I
would recommend you remove the excess
paper towel as much as you can whatever
stuck you can leave it there if you're
afraid to to damage those roots but then
gently plant that paper towel the
remnants and The Roots right into your
medium if you're going to soilless mix
uh living soil uh cocoa you can just put
that paper towel right in there it's
very biodegradable it will biodegrade
quite quickly and it will not cause you
any problems so just put minimal paper
towel in there I'm not saying throw the
whole thing in there but if some of it
gets stuck you can trim around it you
can pick it off a little bit of paper
towel will not cause you any problems
when you plant that so the first step is
getting it out of the box carefully open
that box up get the the baggie out of
there open up the baggie get the plant
out carefully remove that bottom baggie
uh so I wrapped it in a paper towel and
then I put another baggie over that to
keep that secure to keep that moisture
in there so just gently remove that
second that second baggie take the paper
towel off uh then get your medium what I
recommend what I would do uh these
clones are ready for this I would get a
Solo Cup I buy a bunch of beer cups when
I do this I just go buy a stack of beer
cups from the store uh just get like 50
of them for a good price keep them on a
shelf I've always got them available I
cut holes in the bottom with my scissors
so that way I've got three drainage
holes in the bottom of my beer cup scoop
up some soil or soilless mix whatever
you're using pack it in there not tight
but not loose either you want it packed
in there kind of firm then it will make
a little cone shape on the top of the
soil so the the cup is round there's
just a little cone I can't figure out
how to describe that because just a cone
inside and here we go I'll grab a bottle
let me get a prop so uh I will make this
is a little more pointy than I would
prefer but we make a little cone shape
out of the soil then what I try to do is
take the roots those roots of that clone
are kind of shape imagine that my white
fingers are those roots I want to spread
them over the top of that cone so they
don't Bunch up inside of that new medium
I don't want them tightened up in there
I want to give them an opportunity to
spread and grow spread your roots that's
what you want them to do so I make that
little cone shape and I just lower those
roots onto there and hope that it
spreads out a little bit uh you'll get
good at it you'll get better at it the
more you do I know you've only got one
clone right now but over time you'll
practice this and you will get good at
it so I will take that oh one one thing
I forgot that soil is already moistened
once I filled that cup I have moistened
it what is in the water that I fed it I
definitely recommend we use some sort of
micos when you're potting these new
clones uh there are a couple advantages
of this uh the First Advantage is those
microbes will help speed up that plant
growth that root growth will go
explosive when the recharge or the
powdered micos or whatever other product
you do choose to use the the great white
the Orca whatever product you choose
when that hits those roots they will
explode when that comes in contact with
the roots and the water that will make
those roots start to grow very rapidly
so you'll get rapid root development
which will lead to big fat healthy plant
development and the other advantage to
using these microbes is once you build
up these colonies of beneficial bacteria
that are good for the plants the proper
microbes uh those microbes will fight
off uh the bad microbes the bad funguses
that try to come around anything that
will be detrimental to the plant any
pathogens will be prevented by those
beneficial microbes so build up some
colonies get those going start with that
very first watering a lot of the good
soils and soilless mixes we are buying
already come with that in there but add
a little recharge like I said add a
little uh what's it called Great White
uh a little bit of the cheap micos a
little bit of azos whatever micro
products you can add in there let's get
them in there and get these plants a
little bit of a head start or even a
little bit of a recharge if you will
shout out to Scotty reel all right so
we've got our so these plants are wet
with our micro product in there uh we've
got a little cone shape at the top of
the cup I'm going to spread those roots
right over that and I'm going to grab
another about a half a handful of dirt
and just set it set it right on top of
that and just tap it down a little bit
just give it a little tap just so that
the plant just enough to hold the plant
upright and then those roots can grow
down and we're not squishing any Roots
then I kind of spin that that cup uh
I've got a really smooth technique where
I just take two fingers and tap the dirt
down and spin the cup and it only takes
me a couple of seconds to pack all that
dirt perfectly tight we want it pressed
in firmly but we don't want to squish
the roots and we want to allow room for
that plant to grow uh we need those
roots to be able to work their way
through that soil uh we want it kind of
firm not too tight not loose it's really
hard to describe once you see that
perfect root growth you'll understand
once you water it all in and it starts
to dry and compact by that next watering
that's right about where you want it so
uh when you water it in Pay uh pay
attention it's going to start to dry
watch how it settles push that dirt in
and then maybe add more soil soil this
makes whatever you're using don't be
afraid to top it off after a day or two
after a watering or two uh so we've got
our plan it's potted now it's in this
little cup then I would put it under a
veg light I would introduce it slowly
honestly I recommend you do this with me
too um I always isolate and uh what's
the word I'm looking for there's a word
um quarantine a clone my brain could not
think of quarantine you guys I don't
have any notes I've got very minimal
notes this is all just coming out of
what I would do I would quarantine this
clone anytime I get a clone from a
friend a bro a homie a clone service a
clone shipper any clone that comes in it
honestly sits right here on this table
for several days so I can observe it the
day it comes in it gets treated with
nuclear uh pesticides I apply some crazy
[ __ ] to it I'm not going to smoke that
plant it's going to become a mom I need
to Nuke it and make sure there are no
bugs on that plant so as soon as it
comes in It Gets Zapped and then it sits
right here on this table for three to
five days where I can observe it I'll
spray it on that first day I'll spray it
on that third day then I'll give it a
good observation and make sure there are
no bugs on there before it even makes it
into general population uh as a breeder
as a person who uses my plants as a
business I cannot risk bringing a
pathogen a pest into my garden I have to
be very careful so that plant sits right
here I recommend to you guys even if
it's coming from me bro I'm a reputable
clone Source but still quarantine that
bad [ __ ] make sure there are no
problems just make that your standard
operating procedure no matter who sends
you the Clones bro pretty girls have
problems too uh make sure that the Clone
is clean so clean that clone up
quarantine it isolate it now at this
point I would recommend adding some
light even if it's just in this room I'm
going to add some light to it I've got a
pretty good light right up above me that
light puts off quite a bit of light
enough to keep a clone alive sometimes
I'll crank up the studio lights also
there's a window right behind me I can
put some sunshine on this clone if I
need to I just need enough light to keep
it going keep it growing keep it healthy
it's been in the dark for several days
uh you don't want to go blasting it
immediately with super intense veg light
uh just set it on the table give it a
little light let it adjust give it a few
days it will be fine if that plant
starts to look a little bit droopy a
little bit sad
sometimes they will it's just
environment and plants its nature
sometimes they're going to look a little
bit sad if it looks droopy if it looks
pissed off I recommend getting a baggie
like a sandwich baggie or the little bit
bigger than a sandwich baggie and just
make a little Dome and just slide it
right over it and that way you can kind
of control the amount of humidity that's
in there and the plant won't be
subjected to so much air flow it'll be
able to develop more humidity inside
that Dome while it's generating its
roots and getting its life started so if
it's starting to look a little bit sad a
little bit pissy uh just take a baggie
slide it right over the top of that
plant if you really want to secure it
use a rubber band at the bottom of that
usually not even necessary you could
just slide it right over uh that'll trap
enough moisture in there that will help
out your problems so we've gotten it out
of the box we've built our little
pyramid we've moistened the water built
our pyramid drop the plant on top of
there spread the roots uh filled up on
top of it so our plant's nice and sturdy
uh label that cup that's something that
we should definitely do you've got this
cup right your bright red cup right on
there the name of the strain right now
just write it real big on there so
there's no chance to forget maybe you
get another clone in a couple days you
don't want to mix them up maybe you
already have more label this bad [ __ ]
so that way you paid money for it you do
not want to lose it get it confused so
we got a labeled clone and a cup it's
back filled it looks good uh we have
treated it for bugs if you want to um if
you want to spray it I would recommend
spray it don't don't just think just
because it came from me I'm 99.9% sure
it's clean but guess what everybody
that's given me a clone that had bugs on
it said I'm 99% sure it's clean it's
that one [ __ ] percent that'll get you
bro so uh make sure that's it's clean
spray it quarantine it uh if it starts
to look sad put a little baggie over it
uh put uh I put the big quart bag it's
not a sandwich I think it's a quart size
bag slide that right over the top if you
need to generate more humidity in that
Dome more light and more heat is the way
to generate that humidity get a light
above it uh that will start to bring the
water up toward that light that will
help you get some humidity in there so
uh you've got your plant you got your
little humidity Dome on there I'm going
to check my notes and see what else I
wrote down that we need to cover here
I'm learning my uh shipping o sop I'm
getting pretty good at it the roots are
wrapped in a paper towel and then double
secured in two baggies oh I use an easy
cloner uh that's something that I'm
going to mention here these come out of
an easy cloner so the whole time once
the plant is cut as a clone it never
goes under a dome so these didn't
require any hardening off time or
whatever you call that when you have to
open the Dome and let those clones
adjust that's why I'm pretty sure that
they should be pretty Hardy when they
come out of that baggie when you get
them that's why I say only sometimes
they're going to need a baggie to help
themselves rejuvenate but also they're
coming out of an easy cloner so the
roots are just exposed and hanging uh
but they're super healthy and I keep
them secure I just want you to know what
to expect uh if you do think about
ordering uh a clone from me uh then it
says carefully pot um if the roots are
let's see if the if the roots are stuck
you can bury the paper towel uh light
feeding lots of microbes veg light and
then slowly increase that light I didn't
even write down quarantine on my notes
here so after 3 to 5 days once that
plant shows you that there's no bugs on
it then slowly introduce it to that veg
light if you've got a a little LED or a
T5 light that'll be perfect for this
little plant slowly introduce it I just
don't want you to burn shock confuse
this plant by putting it under a super
bright light and frying it uh I know
that you just paid some uh some funds
for it so I want it to be a success I
want you to succeed with the products
you buy from me uh if that's a clone if
it's a seed I want success for you uh I
sell you seeds and then I teach you how
to take clones so I want you to be
self-sufficient once you've got a clone
or some seeds to do that with uh let me
make sure I covered everything I'm 99.9%
sure but like I said it's always that 1%
dude um I think we covered it's only
0.1% at that point right I know
somebody's going to correct me and I
know who it will be um I think I covered
that one my dude Sleepwalker uh thank
you for the great question everybody out
there I hope you enjoyed that quick
little sop on how to take care of those
brand new clones when I do ship them to
you um Alo if you're trying to get on
that waiting list if you're trying to
get the updates on how to get the Clones
go to IR genetics.com there's a part at
the bottom it says join the mailing list
or stay up to date type in your email
address when I put out new clones I will
send out an email that says lemon
Jeffrey clones are available uh I
honestly cut some let's see today is uh
Saturday is when this episode comes out
so give me 12 days from Saturday that's
like a weird 80s movie title 12 days
from Saturday but that's about when
those clones should start start popping
Roots there will be some lemon Jeff and
there will be some other surprises that
I'll start talking about more as soon as
I see the little roots and my friend
Sleepwalker make sure you check your
inbox because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com all right we're going to keep
this rambly podcast moving I do have
another email here in front of me this
one also came from that growel tab at
edirect tocom before I read this I do
want to remind you if you like the
podcast click like and click subscribe
it's free and it just takes a second all
right this question came from our new
friend Leo and it says Hey Rasta Jeff
when making seeds do you look for the
same attributes in your reversal plant
as you would a stud male this is a very
good question people know that I love
making feminized seeds I'm also known
for making very high quality regular
seeds uh those require different type of
pollen donors so it is a different hunt
when I'm hunting for the femin stuff uh
I get to smoke those plants I get to see
what they taste like I get to see what
the buzz is like I get to experience
that plant uh in a different way than I
do those male plants so it's kind of uh
it's like I've already got the flavor I
keep doing this Chef kiss motion with my
hand I already know what that plant
should taste like and what that flavor
should uh contribute to the breeding so
it's a little bit of a head start it's a
little bit of a I don't know it's like I
already know what chocolate tastes like
so if I want to cook something or bake
something I know when and where and
where not to use chocolate so that's
also how breeding works with fem seeds
all right let me get to the part of the
qu let me get to the answer here um a
reversal if I'm selecting uh so if I'm
selecting a male plant for pollination
um I will accept a nine out of a 10 I
would prefer on a scale of 1 to 10 I
would prefer a 10 but a 10 to me is
really hard to attain that is uh that is
that's like the most perfect plant you
could ever find and I found nearly
perfect plants but there's always I'm
picky dude I'm picky so if I would say
that a male plant has to be a nine and
that is in plant growth shape structure
flowering time amount of pollen that it
makes uh the amount of time it takes to
make that pollen uh the flowering time
of that male because I let them go nine
or 10 weeks and let them I see what they
do I observe what those flower clusters
do do they make colors how much water
does it take does it is it an
overdrinker is it an under Drinker how
much feed does it like I pay attention
to a lot of things when it comes to
selecting a male plant uh let me make
sure I check my notes Here Yeah growth
traits um so uh uh what are we shape
structure flower time uh flower density
um that matters on the mail end the
female so all these things matter when
it comes to selecting a male plant now
that male plant can be a nine but when
it comes to selecting a reversal I need
a 10 and I know that sounds wild if I'm
that picky on my male plants uh how can
I be that extra picky on the females
that are reversed yes that's how picky I
am um if the male plants can be nines
these reversals must be 10 because we
get to smoke them we get to sample them
we get to experience them why wouldn't I
pick a perfect 10 so I need that shape
that structure that Vigor that
resistance to pathogens that resistance
to pests people really forget about that
one uh everyone's worried about what
does it look like on Instagram and how
much can I get for a pack of it um as a
grower as a breeder is it pest resistant
is it pathogen resistant a lot of people
are growing a lot of outdoor flowers now
I need to breed stuff that does not
catch the powdery mildew I need to breed
stuff that doesn't get the bud mold I
need to make plants that are bug
resistant so people are not getting
attacked by pest in their outdoor
Gardens that's something that I'm
thinking about so I look at that at the
females that I'm going to reverse uh
what kind of leaf shape do they have uh
what kind of uh basic structure and how
do they grow do they get real tall do
they get real stretchy or they stay real
tight can they support themselves what
about the flowers I mentioned the same
thing in the male plants how are the
flower clusters are they real dense are
they fluffy are they foxtail are they
fingery then also one of the main things
to think about one of the most important
things I guess that I should have
mentioned first is what is the goal of
the breeding project does this pollen
donor uh meet the criteria of what I'm
trying to create so I like to use really
weird analogies I started using baking
earlier so we're going to stay with that
like I said earlier if I want to make
chocolate muffins I'm not going to bust
out like uh pastrami that's not going to
go in my chocolate muffins so if I want
to breed chocolate this I know that's
[ __ ] wild right but it makes sense so
if I want to breed chocolate muffins I
need something muffiny and chocolatey
right it wouldn't reach for the pastrami
stuff so find plants that meet the
criteria for your breeding project are
you trying to make make fruity flavored
stuff skunky flavored stuff and of
course this plant's only 50% of the mix
but keep in mind it's going to be a big
50% it could be 60 maybe 70% depending
on how the breeding goes keep that in
mind what if I do want to make pastrami
then I'm going to find if I want to make
pastrami Rye mustard I need a plant that
smells like Pastrami and mustard a plant
that smells like R I got to breed those
bad [ __ ] so think about that when you
are starting to breed what do you want
your outcome to look smell taste how is
the buzz then as the grower the breeder
how does it grow is it problematic in
the [ __ ] grow room cuz I don't want
to grow problematic plants I have a
large clientele of homeg Growers a lot
of the people that purchase my seeds are
medical Growers that are growing for
their medical needs or they're providing
for somebody with the medical condition
the consuming cannabis will help with
their medical condition and improve the
quality of their life many of my
customers are home Growers many of my
clients are people growing for
themselves so I need and a lot of them
are new Growers because I have a podcast
I introduce a lot of new people to
cultivation so I need a product that is
very reliable very easy for the new
Growers of the community to be able to
have good success with so that's
something I think about when I'm growing
and breeding so if I can knock that
plant over and forget to water it for a
couple of days and then go pick it back
up and set it back up and prop it up and
it goes hey I'm ready to grow those are
the plants that I should think about
breeding with because I want people to
have good success in the garden so it's
a plant that can take abuse and one day
one way I find those is uh and I've
talked about this before I'm involved
with commercial cultivation facilities
and I'll go walk through the facilities
and I see plants that Just sh shine and
I know that those plants are getting
beat up cuz those workers the guys in
the facilities are overworked there's
too many plants they not getting paid
enough there's not enough people so I
know those plants are getting abused
when I see the plants that shine in
there so I watch how they get abused in
the grow and then I see the best plants
that come out and I select those as some
of my breeding plants so I like to pick
stuff that I know uh can take some abuse
that can tolerate some drought some uh
if you forget to water it for a day it
might be okay if you overwater it the
next day it should still be okay I like
plants I can teach you to pop and twist
and lollipop and do all the work to so
I'm keeping that in mind as I'm
selecting for my breeders also so um
let's see let me get back to my notes um
I need them to be better than a regular
male because I can smoke it I can see
all the traits that we're looking for
that's the main thing that I wanted to
stress on this um we got to cover all
the important details the smoke the buzz
the aroma the flavor and then all the
growth traits and of course I've
reviewed all those a bunch of times so
it says when making fem seeds do you
look for the same attributes and my
bottom line answer on the bottom of the
paper it says I look for the same
attributes and more uh like I started
this my my male my real male donor
plants my male pollen donor plants uh
those can be nines I'd prefer a nine a
9.5 I'll accept an 8.5 maybe it's got to
it's got to have some really super
traits but those mail plants can be
nines I need a really good solid mail
plant that meets my criteria and I've
gone through the criteria and it mean it
helps me reach the goal of my breeding
product project which we've talked about
uh so I need need that solid mail but
for a reversal it's got to be a tan cuz
I already know what it smokes like if
why would you reverse something that
isn't everything you want if it's not
you've already smoked it you know what
it's going to taste like you know what
how it's going to get you high you know
how much of it you have to smoke to get
you high also is there a ceiling is
there a limit to this plant the more I
smoke can I just keep getting higher or
do I max out at some point because a lot
of plants have a limit uh some of the
more uh the Congo Ripper uh the more
Congo Ripper you smoke the higher you
get the more wing suit you smoke the
higher you get but a lot of the other
strains it's common just for your
biology once you smoke to a certain
point you'll just max out you won't get
any higher I don't know if you guys just
saw me full Panic CU my computer screen
went bright blue it's not supposed to do
that I got it to come back so it might
be time for a new Macbook
patreon.com fromy yourheart um my dude
Leo I think I answered your question in
great detail I think I rambled on about
this more than once or twice so uh my
dude make sure you check your inbox for
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from I
direct.com all right I'm in a super
rambling mood so let's get one more
message one more question out for the
podcast this one also did come from that
growel tab on iry genetics.com you guys
go check out iry genetics.com there's a
lot of Great Links there there's a link
to my Discord server come join us on
Discord hang out join The Smokers Lounge
take some dabs with us I pop on camera
take a couple of dabs talk a little bit
of [ __ ] I hang out almost every day on
Discord you're invited you don't have to
come on camera but you can join the
smoker cange if you'd like to uh also
there's a link to iir where you can get
those seeds what get yourself some seeds
stay tuned for a Black Friday sale I
told you I'm nice and rambly all right
this question came from our friend aie
Wy 420 big shout out to Aussie Wy 420
thank you for the great question also
check your inbox because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
idirect tocom so the question goes a
little bit like this it is labeled a
problem in my garden and it says I was
wondering I've got a seated crop and it
became infected infested with spider mes
okay so he's uh he's got some plants
theyve been pollinated and since that
time happened the dreaded spider mights
have showed up of course this has
happened to me before this is solvable
this is fixable and it may not be as bad
as your thinking it may be it says uh
would this affect the way the seeds
finished will they still be vigorous or
am I wasting my time um then it says the
plants are currently drying to be dry as
[ __ ] uh you've been watching the show
good work bro and after this would you
recommend to clean what would you
recommend to clean my grow area I have
used a bleach solution is that enough
cheers and thanks so much for the
podcast from aywy 420 this is a very
good question so you bred some uh some
seeds and in the process those mother
plants the female plants were infested
with spidermites now you've got the
seeds those seeds should be viable you
should be able to produce uh viable
potent vigorous plants from those seeds
uh my true answer is there's only one
way to find out my dude grow some of
those seeds and see what you've got uh
there's uh no stress in doing a
germination test I don't know how many
seeds you have maybe you got 30 maybe
you got 30,000 but take 10% of them
however many you got if you got 30 take
three seeds so just pull 10% of your
seeds and fold them up in a wet paper
towel and germinate them and see how
many Sprout uh if they sprout then
you've got really good seeds grow those
why not just keep going with those see
what you come up with do the uh the 1212
from seed method that I talked about on
the dude grow show and just run these
plants really quickly and see what
you've created you may have some cool
[ __ ] if you did your research and did
your dude diligence before you made this
cross you may have made some real gold
here so run these seeds see what you've
created uh just do it for the fun of it
just see if they germinate that's a fun
test uh run them on the 1212 method that
I mentioned uh that's a fun game to play
just run them and see what they do take
a bunch of pictures and see what you
have created like I said you may have
new gold there you may have created the
new uh the new chem dog the new golden
go you may have the New Girl Scout
cookies you might have the new gelato on
your hands bro we don't know what you
have done in that Garden we got two more
things to talk about since these plants
were infested with spidermites during
the uh the development time the way my
brain thinks is that if you do that same
process multiple times if you uh take
the F so you got F1 seeds take those f1s
and make f2s but in the process let
those plants get hit with spidermites
again then take those f2s and breed F3
and when you're doing it keep the spider
mites going don't ever get rid of the
mites just keep them going because what
you're going to do eventually if you
breed properly if you do the proper
selection and this is a whole another
bracket of this conversation we're not
going to have today but people will
continue this part in the comments talk
about how to do this in the comments if
you're a a person that understands
breeding what you eventually will do is
you'll breed plants that are fully
resistant to spidermites if you select
the plants that get hit the so if you
fully infest the room with spidermites
and you find female plants that the
mites don't touch and then breed to
those and then infest that room of
spidermites again and find the the
female plants that the mites don't touch
and breed to those you'll breed out the
spidermites out of that plant they they
won't want it it'll take several
Generations but you could focus on that
you could definitely make that a thing
you're already the first step into like
a 23 step process Why not start now all
right so we've talked about the uh the
resistance to spidermites that you were
breeding that's pretty cool now we got
to talk about cleaning up this room I
think the bleach will do you just fine
you said that you have bleached used
bleach to clean up the room that should
do it if you've cleaned up everything
however bleach is not an integrated Pest
management system you've cleaned up the
room one time it's clean for now but uh
spidermites are microscopic and they're
going to find a crack in the whatever a
crack in the whatever I don't know where
the room is if it's in the basement if
it's in a gigantic facility if it's in a
real tight laboratory those spidermites
they've already found one crack they
know where it is they're going to keep
coming in and they're going to come back
if you're bringing them on your shoes on
your clothes if they found their own
entry way if you've got a pet that's
bringing them they will be back so it is
time to develop an integrated Pest
management system there are a lot of
different ways to do this uh in my
opinion as a commercial cultivator uh
the most effective uh cost effective
time effective way is to apply a spray
application of a pesticide once or twice
a week and when I say the word pesticide
people get scared but there are a lot of
great options of products you can use uh
this is where I leave it up to you this
is where you need to do the research and
find out um what strength of pesticide
you want to use how organic you want to
stay there are a lot of things to think
about I've got my own opinions I don't
want to spout most of those right now
we're running out of time on the show
but this is where you get to decide some
ethics and think about how you want to
do things how bad do you want to spray
these bugs uh how often do you want to
spray do you want to use some hippie
oils some preventative [ __ ] or do you
want to get in there with agricultural
pesticides and spray once and know
you're not going to have to mess with it
for one or two weeks there are a lot of
things to think about and also things to
understand uh understand these
pesticides understand what you're
putting on your plants understand uh if
it's good or acceptable uh so my rule of
thumb is I am in Colorado I understand
the Colorado Department of Agriculture
and the Colorado marijuana enforcement
division pesticide application rules I
am actually certified by the Department
of Agriculture as a train the trainer
certified uh p pesticide trainer uh
which means I can go to a commercial
cultivation facility and train people
there on how to safely handle and apply
pesticides uh but make sure you go read
all of that stuff is what I'm getting at
learn about those pesticides so what I
was getting at is I go by the Colorado
Department of Agriculture and Colorado
marijuana enforcement division pesticide
application rules if a product is banned
in the state of Colorado I do not use it
uh if a product that I use on a regular
basis becomes banned sometimes I'll
remove that product from the rot
honestly most of the time I use it until
I'm out of that product because I'm not
in that facility but I want to follow
that guideline so make sure that that
product or if you want to do the
research see if that product is approved
in your area for cannabis application if
you have commercial cultivation or the
Colorado approved pesticide list is not
hard to Google if you Google Colorado
marijuana enforcement division approved
pesticide list you can find it and you
can see what you can apply to the
products then you have to learn when to
and when not to apply those products and
how to apply them learn about re-entry
intervals learn about uh your pesticide
uh your safety gear learn about all that
stuff but please do learn about uh
integrated Pest Management the most
effective way in my opinion is sprayed
applications once or twice a week now if
you do choose to go with the sprayed
pesticide applications as your method of
integrated Pest Management I do
recommend a rotation Don't Spray the
same pesticide every time you spray
because these bugs will develop a
resistance to your pesticide that's
right if you go in there every day you
throw a right hook by the third or
fourth time they just throw up that left
block and they keep their day going you
need to rotate your pesticides I would
recommend two to three different
pesticides and spray one and then spray
the other and then spray one and then
spray the other so you can really
confuse these bugs just mix it up rotate
them also another thing you can do is
called a tank mix uh this is a little
bit Advanced but do some research do
some reading this is possible I do this
all the time in commercial facilities
you can mix more than one pesticide in
your tank at a time and apply them for
multiple modes of attack if you want to
apply something that isn't real sticky
add a little bit of Evergreen uh that'll
make it stickier and then now you've got
two different modes of attack for that
application in one time follow all the
rules write that stuff down when you do
that all right that is my pesticide
application rant now let's talk about
your other option the other option is of
course Predator bugs you can buy and
release bugs into your grow that will
eat the existing spider mites there are
bugs that love to eat spidermites um
depending on where you are the
environment in your grow space there are
several different options um I really
like the lace Wing eggs you can buy lace
green lacewing eggs and you can hang
these little placards on the plants and
they've got just little lacewing eggs
all over them and they will start to
hatch and they look like little
alligators and they'll start climbing
around and they will eat all of the
other bugs in your grow space um those
things are hungry they're vicious they
will go eat all the spidermites the
spidermite eggs the thrips uh the fungus
snats they will eat the [ __ ] out of
everything the Green Lace Wings will
develop it and then after that they turn
into real big Green Lace wings and
they'll eat everything else a few other
Predators I would recommend are the
sories the cucumeris the hypo aspis
miles and then why not throw some Ro
beetles in there and there was another
one on my mind that my brain won't say
sworsky cucumeris hypoaspis miles
californicus that's the same as somebody
else uh Ro beetles um I also recommend
the um uh we'll say the Green Lace wings
and there's another one that goes in the
soil that my brain will not think of but
I think five recommendations is enough
this is enough to give you a springboard
a jumping point to start thinking about
the Predator bugs also many people in a
home grow don't like the Predator bugs
they they think it's gross to have the
idea of bringing in bugs but you'd be
amazed at how many bugs are already
there we won't even think about that now
all right so uh your first option is uh
so you've cleaned up the room clean
everything real good then I would start
treating the plants uh introduce an
integrated pest management system rotate
three pesticides in uh once or twice a
week if you don't see any bugs spray
once a week at the first sign of bugs
step that [ __ ] up spray twice a week um
if you don't want to spray stuff because
of whatever and that's up to you I get
it people don't want to spray [ __ ] uh
they get worried about poisons or
whatever uh a lot of things to read
about and educate yourself on there then
you can try the uh Predator bugs which
again is a lot of things for people to
understand all right I think I covered
this one very well aie 420 my dude make
sure you check your inbox cuz you my
friend have a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds from I direct.com ladies
and gentlemen if I did not read your
email on this episode please do not feel
discouraged I have got a mountain of
emails here in front of me I've got a
lot of them broken down into different
shows uh questions I feel like will fit
together or time out for a good show so
I've got a pile here I got a pile here I
got a whole stack over here if I didn't
read your question on this episode
please don't feel discouraged there are
more episodes coming and there will be
more questions on every show so every
show is another option to win free seeds
that's right keep sending those
questions ladies and gentlemen go to my
website iry genetics.com use that growel
tab send me your question because if I
read your question here on the show I
will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at
air.com all right let me check my notes
make sure we've covered everything once
again while I'm checking these notes I
will remind you to please click like And
subscribe that's right also uh if you
agree with me if you disagree with me
the comment section is a wonderful place
to keep the com to keep the conversation
going just leave some comments down
there there are a lot of brilliant
people in the comments thank you I do
appreciate it I love all the the just
hey dude great show all those uh that
all matters to me but all those hey uh
here's a correction I love all that as
well and then here's that hey what he
said is all awesome but also and then
when somebody replies with oh yes and I
love those keep that going in the
comments you guys that means a lot to me
to see the community building in the
comment section I found my place on on
the computer I know where I was going um
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns that you'd like to
keep private my email address of course
is grow from yourheart hotmail.com don't
be shy if you've got questions
Corrections comments concerns uh maybe
you want to advertise on the podcast
maybe you just want to tell me something
that I shouldn't say on the show uh let
me know I would love to hear from you
grow from your heart at hotmail.com once
again I will mention the website iry
genetics.com I'll spell it across the
screen right here because if you're not
familiar with the word iy I understand
that could be uh hard to spell and hard
to guess iry genetics.com go click
around uh go poke around you never know
what you might find all right that's all
I've got for you for this episode I'll
be back in a week with fresh new content
I want to give a giant shout out to Phil
L and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me Rost Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another D grab
your p in a by the
back in the lab sit back relax
hold roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning out to hear the vi that Jeff in
our conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must loud be heard he like
to can ofis go from your heart your
bliss rise up higher Find Your Way grow
from your hearts every day in the light
We Stand real strong join the movement
sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
do educate and Elevate join the journey
don't be late open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof RF will
guide you through in this gard and find
the new rise up high up Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
[Music]
open minds to see the truth in the soil
lies the proof rer Jeff will guide you
through in this Garden find the new rise
up higher Find Your Way grow from your
heart words every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the song
[Music]
[Applause]