[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the podcast everybody I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 850 56 of the
grow from your heart podcast you know
I've got another great episode lined up
for us in today's show I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in
today's episode before we get too far I
do want to send a few shout outs to a
few of the great folks who support the
show on patreon let's send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy Ames High
let's send a fist bump and a thank you
shout out to Johnny posum and I also
want to send a big thank you shout out
to one of my favorite photographers ADHD
grower big thanks and big shout out for
all of the continued patreon support if
you want to support the show on patreon
make sure you check
patreon.com SLG from your heart all
right now let's move into the pet peeve
portion of today's podcast that's right
a lot of you may know what a pet peeve
is a pet peeve is something that just
drives you crazy maybe when you walk
into a grow space or maybe when you look
at a friend's grow space on pictures
maybe you see something that just drives
you crazy I like to give you folks the
opportunity to send me your growroom pet
peeves and of course if I read your pet
peeve here on the podcast I will send
you a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds at idirect decom today's pet peeve
goes a little bit like this it says yo
rosta Jeff what's up brother what's up
bro thanks for the the great message and
make sure you check your inbox because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds from edirect decom the pet
peeve says I hope all is well with you
and yours I have a massive pet peeve
that I think uh serious Growers know all
too well yes I have pre screen this pet
peeve and I completely agree with you
the pet peeve says one of my biggest pet
peeves is Growers who cannot keep track
of their clones and they mislabel their
clones with the wrong name or they just
make up new names because they can't
remember their plants lineage at all oh
man that is aggravating this person says
it drives me nuts and absolutely mad
when something is supposed to be sherbet
or cake and it smells like burnt rubber
anyway hope all is well in your world
and one love
from your friend Chooch Chooch my dude
thank you for the great pet peeve I
completely agree with you my dude uh a
plant if you can't keep yourself
organized I don't want to even get a
clone from you please label all of the
plants in your garden very carefully
it's one very important step and if you
do give me a clone uh please make sure
that that clone is what it is labeled uh
like I agree with this person it drives
me nuts when they're like I think this
one is this I think this one is this bro
just grow it smoke it get rid of it try
again later properly lab those plants
next time please label your [ __ ] and if
you're going to give me or another
person a clone please make sure that
clone is what it's supposed to be this
is absolutely correct if you a lot of
people are selling clones right now like
I've talked about before I sell clones
on iir when they are available uh join
the newsletter you can get updates uh
but anyway the lemon Jeffree will be
available soon in Clone form uh when
people get that they're going to expect
a lemony citrusy tall growing lemon
Jeffrey plant if I send them a stretchy
skinny OG Kush plant they're all going
to be pissed so if you do give somebody
sell somebody a clone please make sure
that that thing is what it is labeled
because people get very excited we grow
it we spend a lot of time and then 15
weeks later we find out that you lied to
us and gave us something and took money
for it and now we feel slighted we don't
like you anymore we think you're a dick
uh 20 something years ago somebody sold
me a clone and I paid a lot of money for
it and it was not what it was supposed
to be and to this day I don't [ __ ] with
that guy because he took a lot of money
from me blatantly lied to me uh saw how
excited I was offered me more cuts of
the same thing for more money and it
none of those cuts were what they were
supposed to be so not going to say his
name not going to say who he is I don't
[ __ ] with that guy anymore from a a
small clone transaction 20 years ago
that's how important it was to me so
that's a great pet peeve uh label your
[ __ ] especially if you're going to give
it out share it uh distribute it in any
way make sure that [ __ ] is properly
labeled it does matter a lot of people
like it shouldn't matter that much it
does uh it's like if you you went to a
restaurant and you were vegan and you
ordered a vegan meal and they brought
you a steak you'd be pissed just like if
you paid money for a clone that was
labeled diesel they brought you
strawberries you would be pissed just
like you should be I like to consider
myself sort of a cannabis historian I've
been around a long time in this industry
in this business and this community uh I
watched it go from the black market or
the free market whatever you want to
call it uh it evolved into the medical
marijuana market now we've got the full
recreational Market here I saw a lot of
Brands develop up here I saw a lot of
Brands come and go I saw a lot of
breeders come and go I saw a lot of
products happen uh since I was there in
that whole thing as it was happening I
kind of took it as part of my
responsibility to become the historian
and make sure that all of that [ __ ] is
proper and if I want the stories and the
history to be proper I need the genetics
and the plants to be proper as well as a
breeder as well uh the Cannabis
historian in me the breeder uh the
person that's been here for a while I
want all these stories and things to
line up there's a bunch of [ __ ] out
there uh it's one of my responsibilities
I'm taking the responsibility to make
sure that all of the Cannabis lore is
spread properly uh spread truthfully and
I want the genetics to do the same thing
so please help me preserve the uh the
story the history the legend the lore uh
and the reality and the truth of
cannabis so that we can keep it uh keep
all this lore uh keep it true keep it
positive is what I'm trying to do all
right I am rambly that was the pet peeve
portion of today's podcast uh thank you
once again to my dude chuch for for the
great pet peeve once again I've got your
email address here check your inbox for
that free pack of seeds from I
direct.com all right this is the portion
of the show where I do ask you to click
like And subscribe that's right if you
enjoy my cannabis ramblings please click
like make sure you click subscribe that
way every time I put out a new episode
you will get a notification you never
miss any of my amazing cannabis content
all right let's move into the email the
question and answer portion of today's
podcast of course I have a website that
website is I genetics.com if you go to
that website on the top there is a row
of tabs one of those tabs does say grow
help if you click on that growel tab
youve are given the opportunity to send
me a grow question if you send me a grow
question and I read that question here
on the podcast I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
decom today's first question came from
somebody who's going to be called Cool J
mans what up Cool J mans good to meet
you bro the question goes a lot like
this it says hey rosted Jeff I love the
show you put out a bunch of useful
knowledge thank you that means a lot to
me I'm glad you find it useful uh it's
good to know that I'm helping somebody
out it goes on it says anyway I recently
came into contact with my parents old
seed stash what a gift you just found my
friend it says so these are seeds from
the 80s is there any chance these seeds
are viable or are they way too old uh my
dude Cool J mans you have found a great
uh a great stash there a great
motherload there um there's only one
good way to find out if those seeds are
still any good and that is to germinate
them but before you germinate them have
a grow space ready I don't know if
you've already got a grow environment a
grow room built in your house a grow
tent somewhere but before you germinate
these seeds uh have a grow room setup
just in case they do work what if you
germinate them and they sprout and they
look super healthy you're going to want
to get them into some dirt into some
pots under some lights get them growing
so uh my advice my first advice is don't
even [ __ ] with them until you've got a
grow environment a grow room a grow
space ready to dedicate to some of these
seeds uh doesn't have to be a lot of
room but if you're going to sprout them
grow them make sure it's worth it then
the other piece of advice I've got is uh
germinate a bunch of them see what
happens if they germinate like I said
get them going get them growing treat
them just like any other plant that you
found uh take clones keep Mother plants
do whatever you can do to preserve it
just in case you find a winner grow that
[ __ ] out sample it smoke it choose the
best one you may have uh you may have
something [ __ ] amazing in there you
also may have a bunch of dud seeds just
keep that in mind but you may have some
real gold in there so my first step uh
set up a grow space have a grow room
ready to go step number two attempt to
germinate some of these seeds uh the
only thing I can recommend to really
help you out is if they're real thick uh
shelled seeds maybe uh take some light
sandpaper and kind of rough up those
shells just a little bit to make the
water easier to penetrate that shell
make it easier to get that shell open
for when the water hits it it can open
and grow a little bit better also the
other thing I would recommend there is a
product called herb it is spelled urb
herb uh that product will be very
beneficial in helping you uh germinate
those seeds before warned it is not
cheap that is a costly product and I say
follow the instructions on the bottle
and use that to help assist in the
germination of your seeds but if you've
got a bunch of them if you've got like
you've got did you say what you found
them in no your parents old seed stash
um they're probably in one of those
little black film canisters that's what
I'm assuming that's what all parents
from the 80s and 90s had their seeds in
but um pour a few out pour out 10 20%
germinate them see what happens uh if
they don't germinate naturally the way
you do it uh then get some of the herb
product and try that way and if they
don't germinate that way they're
probably not going to but really have a
room set up have a place for them to go
before you even germinate them because
what if they they pop what if they
sprout you're going to want to grow them
and if you don't have space uh that's
kind kind of you just wasted a bunch of
seeds that I could have ran that could
have been hot fire we could have found
the next chem dog we could have been
slinging
packs all right oh excuse me for the
throat clearing not even going to edit
that uh it's that time of year it's
starting to get cold I got the beanie on
it's the first night it's been cold in
the grow a in the recording area I'm
starting to get the that winter shift
you get the the stuff in your throat and
the stuff in your nose and the winter
shift that's coming so you're going to
hear a couple Thro clearings I shouldn't
even talk about it that long excuse me
is what I'm trying to say uh let's get
back on track here cool J man's my dude
thank you for the great question I hope
I helped you out a little bit I hope I
encouraged you to get in there and grow
some of those seeds and when you do this
when you try this uh let me know the
progress send me some pictures let me
know how it went for you also uh maybe
wait a little bit because you've got
some free seeds coming all you've got to
do is visit IR
redirect.sh that way if these old seeds
don't work you got a backup plan for
that grow space I told you to get ready
all right thank you for the great
question my dude Cool J mans let's keep
this momentum going I've got a good vibe
flowing today uh this next question came
from our friend Megatron shout out to
Megatron Megatron make sure you check
your inbox because you've got a coupon
code for that free pack of seeds at
idirect decom this question did come
from the growel tab on iry genetics.com
I know I say the website so many times
uh trying to get it programmed in your
head is it programmed are you programmed
yet have you assimilated what did I
smoke it's [ __ ] working all right
where are we this question came from
Megatron Megatron had a real quick real
short question this short one two 3 4
five six-word question could be a
complete podcast I can answer this with
a complete podcast I'll try to keep this
short and sweet so that you understand
what I'm saying but Megatron had a
really good question it says how do you
find stable genetics that is a very good
question I think the first thing we
should focus on is the word stable what
do you mean by stable uh in the Cannabis
realm the word stable is kind of thrown
around misused a lot of people think
that stability has something to you to
do with the with the interex trait uh
yeah maybe those plants aren't sexually
stable but most of the time when we talk
about stability and agriculture we are
mostly referring to uniformity amongst
progyny amongst phenotypes in a
population what that means in layman's
terms is if I grow a 100 plants I want
to see one phenotype amongst those 100
plants that is stability if I grow out a
100 seeds all 100 should look just like
each other that means that that line is
stable that's what we talk about in
horiculture and agriculture when we mean
stability is if we run a population of
seeds how many phenotypes are you going
to get if you're going to get four six
12 different phenotypes that is not
considered stable it may be sexually
stable it may not be interex but in
terms of stability in the Horticultural
realm that is not what we refer to so in
this case I'm going to focus on uh the
phenotypical ility of a plant let's talk
briefly about sexual stability uh
because I'm sure that that's what a lot
of people are thinking of when the word
stable comes up in cultivation in
cannabis sexual stability how do we get
to that uh buy seeds from a reputable
breeder most of those seeds should not
be intersect should not be uh sexually
challenged most of those should be
sexually stable if you want to do it
yourself breed them find a male and a
female plant that are both sexually
stable on their own breed them if you
find any interex lines don't or any
intersex plantss in that line don't
breed with those uh find more plants
that don't express intersect traits and
breed more and keep breeding you can go
forward in filial Generations you can go
back crosses but breed with plants that
don't express intersect Straits and you
can breed the intersects out you can
create sexually stable plants that's my
brief sexual stability talk we're not
going to focus on that let's talk about
main uniformity that is mainly what I
think this question should be about if
we're talking about stability in
cannabis so how do we find stable
genetics first we're going to Define
stability in this case I'm going to talk
about uniformity amongst the phenotypes
like I said before we're going to plant
50 seeds uh where I said 100 seeds
before we'll plant a 100 in this case
they're Rags at this point 50 males have
been removed from the population we've
got 50 females that look just like each
other that is uniformity that is
stability amongst that population
amongst those progyny there that's what
we're going to start with how do we get
to that point uh like I talked about
earlier breed them breed uh fill
Generations you could start with
whatever plants you like I recommend
plants that are vastly different in a
lot of ways so in this case we're going
to talk about arise we're going to use
arise as our example arise was a cross I
made several years ago I have worked the
arise to F3 since then but let's focus a
little more on this arise what I think
made arise successful was I used a
daybreaker male and a Golden Goat female
to make that that cross and those plants
are completely vastly different and
since I took two plants that had no
matching characteristics no traits that
were similar when I bred those together
it made a great combination and a rise
was an amazing cross so I recommend
finding plants that are vastly different
breed them together create your brand
new cross then here's where we start
working on the stability find the
phenotype you like out of that first
cross the F1 find the phenotype that
really gets your attention the male and
the female find that phenotype breed
those together now you're going to make
f2s and the f2s you're going to find a
lot of different wild phenotypes the f2s
are Pandora's Box you're going to get a
lot of crazy [ __ ] find the phenotype you
really like you've got to really start
thinking about what you you should have
already really been thinking about what
you want from this cross now you see
what it expresses really think what you
want to narrow down find a phenotype
that has all of the traits you want um
and we'll talk about another option here
in just a second if I remember I'm going
to write parallel down because that's
another thing to think I spelled it
wrong but it's a note all right so we're
gonna find our f2s um one thing we're
going to do we're going to find a plant
that has the traits we want the aroma
the structure the shape the Vigor
hopefully uh resistance to powdery
mildew resistance to bugs find that
plant find the male find the female
breed those together guess what we just
made F3 we're going to repeat that
process finding the perfect phenotype
every time if you don't do it right you
will know because when you grow the Next
Generation it's not going to look how
you want don't be afraid to do it over
again or go backwards and do a back
cross to the filial generation that has
the traits that you're looking for so
what we're going to do basically uh the
easiest way to do this is to uh keep
filial generation breeding this all the
way up to F5 if you do this selection
properly it's all about the selection
the male and the female every generation
if you do it properly by the time you
get to the F5 definitely the F6 you will
have uniform stability amongst the the
phenotypes in that population so if you
pop 100 seeds you pull out 50 of the
boys all 50 of those remaining girls
will look like you cut clones uh there
are a lot of uh lot of plants that
happen that way in the Horticultural
industry a lot of the fruit and
vegetables have been filial generation
or genetically modified to appear that
way but you can make that happen with
your cannabis plants breed them to F5 F6
and you will find uniformity amongst the
population in that population if you
have bred this properly like I said it's
all about the selection breeding is all
about selection C uh you could mess this
up very easily and you could also make
this happen perfectly very easily if
you've got a good eye for selection a
good eye for detail and if you're
realistic about what you are looking for
um pick a few certain traits and really
narrow those down if you're looking for
32 traits to come out of one plant
you're not going to lock that down in
your breeding project uh it's going to
be a mess it's going to take a while now
that's where I'm going to talk about
this other option this is called
parallel breeding we're going to do the
same project just two different
directions now let's just say uh we're
going to focus on Golden Goat to
daybreaker again we're going to make a
rise but we're going to make a rise
version a and we're going to make a rise
version B now in version a I'm only
going to focus on tric Combs and flavor
that's all that matters these plants
could be ugly they can grow goofy as
long as they taste good and they're
fully potent it's all I care about now
in the other project in line B that's
where I need to have the beautiful
growth structure uh that's where I need
to have the resistance to pathogens and
resistance to bugs it's really all I'm
looking for and these are just
hypotheticals that I want to breed for
in my two different lines so I'm going
to breed both of these lines in
different projects these are totally
different projects different male
different female but same seed batches
um I pulled seeds I got an I got a male
that really is Frosty I got another male
that's really resistant to bugs two
different breeding projects happening a
female on the other side a female on the
other side that match my criteria two
different project so I'm going to breed
both of those to F5 or F6 until I've
reached the stability that I want then
I'm going to breed them together and
make my own true F1 that way I can get
whichever if I've got a bunch of traits
I'm looking for I can get that structure
and that resistance and that flavor and
Aroma once I get those both of those
lines to F5 or F6 I can then breed them
together and then I can combine all four
of those traits together in a brand new
F1 because they're both going to be very
dominant traits on both sides of my
cross so then when I cross those
together I'll get all the tricomes all
the tpin I'll get all the resistance and
all the structure in Vigor breed that
together my new F1 should have a lot of
those traits combined if I've done it
properly then you get to play with that
brand new one and keep going in filial
generations with that that is really how
to breed for super stability when you
ask why breeders aren't offering plants
that are super stable why a lot of Us
sell f1s f2s uh while we're doing
reversals as ones r1's because it takes
years and years to do these filial
generation projects especially if you
want to run parallel lines and then if
you're focused on uh you can kind of
focus on making more seeds or working
these lines but it's hard to do both to
put the seeds out for production and
really do what you need to do and focus
you get one or the other um I found a
really nice line in the middle there
I'll do uh two or three seed production
runs and then just a personal run that
is just for me to get data and [ __ ]
around also I've got a few different
locations where I'm able to play around
with so that helps me expand but let me
stay focused here if you really want to
get dialed in if you really want uh
stable seeds uh make them breed them get
to that F5 generation uh breed them um
also you could buy seeds from reliable
breeders I mentioned uh buying seeds
just a moment ago if you want seeds that
have been bred to the F5 generation the
only breeder I really know of that is
doing that is DJ Short big shout out to
DJ Short for putting those out
commercially available I've made arise
f3s but I've not made them available
because there are not a lot of them
there's not enough of them uh to make it
worth putting out on that sort of a
level the f4s and F5s those will hit uh
the website but it's those are years
away that's that's a while away uh where
were we now so uh how do you get stable
seeds divine define stable we did that
uh breed them to the F5 buy seeds from a
reliable breeder such as DJ Short or uh
if you really want to get involved breed
them do that project yourself so that is
how you find uniform and phenotypically
stable plants if that's what you're
looking for once again we did touch on
those sexually stable plants uh I sell
very sexually stable plants if that's
what you're looking for uh and that is
very advantageous to you because you my
friend uh Megatron have got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at I
direct.com all right podcast world
that's all the questions and answers
that I have got for this episode before
I wrap up the podcast I do want to let
you know that the pre-black Friday sale
on idirect decom will start on November
16th that's right make sure you check
idirect decom on November 16th there
will be a restock of many of your
favorite soldout items also there will
be a fresh drop that's right there are
new items coming to iy direct uh we will
have a brand new drop of Ruby waves that
is the Cherry Paloma to the BC Lemon
Skunk there's another drop of a brand
new uh secret strain is a feminized
cross that I will not say the name of
that one here on the podcast that one is
coming up November 16th also there will
be more of the double Lemon Skunk many
of the items that have been sold out
will restock also there will be crazy
Black Friday sale pricing that's right
so be ready the pre Black Friday sale
will start on November 16th at I
redirect.sh there will be a lot of great
stuff on there well there will be some
limited items some exclusive deals uh
what I'm saying is don't sleep stay
tuned be prepared uh November 16th at IE
direct.com I think that's all I've got
for you for this episode uh make sure
you check
patreon.com fromy yourheart uh make sure
you check iry genetics.com everything
you need is at iry genetics.com I'll be
back in a week with fresh new content I
want to give a big shout out to Jordan s
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] tell take another DB grab
your p in I about the
B is in the
lab relax
[Music]
roots and wisdom start to show from the
knowledge seats we grow tuning now to
hear the
V je in our
conscious the truth in every word every
voice must not be heard healing like
through canit Ro on your heart your lims
rise up higher find your way
Row from your hearts every
day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the
[Music]
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a d educates and elevat
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof R not death will guide you
through and this Gard finding
you rise up high and Find Your Way find
your way go from your heart every day
every
day in the light we stand and real
strong real strong join the movement
sing the
song open minds to see the
TR forgot
you in this gard and find the mo rise up
High you find your
way grow from your hearts every
day
o in the light We Stand real
strong real
strong join the movement sing the
song wo
oh
[Music]
[Laughter]