[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome to the podcast everybody
I'm your host rosta Jeff this is episode
857 of the grow from your podcast you
know I've got another great episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds hang on
we'll talk more about those free seeds
later on in the show before I get too
far I do want to send a few thank you
shout outs to a few of the great folks
who continue to support the show on
patreon let's kick it off with a big
grow fromy heart podcast thank you shout
out to my friend Kyle Hines I want to
send a big thank you shout out to
Badlands let's also send a big thank you
shout out to my buddy OG purple thumb
and also let's send a big thank you
shout sh out to the captain and
commander of the iy army let's send a
special thank you shout out to my buddy
lemur priest big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you would
like to support the show all you have to
do is visit
www.patreon.com
fromy yourheart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen once again thank you for all of
the patreon support in the last episode
I did mention that I was selling clones
on edirect decom many people took
advantage of that clone drop a lot of
people got GMO clones a lot of people
got lemon Jeffrey clones unfortunately
it has been 30° outside in Colorado and
I am not comfortable shipping those
clones so they have not left yet those
clones are still in the cloner being
well taken care of those clones will
ship as soon as the weather is better it
should be warmer probably Monday or
Tuesday I will get those clones in the
mail for you as soon as the weather is
better you do not want those clones in
the mail while it is 30 agrees they will
not survive they will not make it you
will be very mad at me so I did us both
a favor and I waited a few days to send
those they should go out Monday or
Tuesday when the weather goes better I
promise they're ready the shipping
labels have been printed the boxes are
folded all I have to do is put that
little clone into the uh the packaging
and send it to you it's just a matter of
weather at this time trust me uh you'll
be a lot happier if I do wait one full
week all right I think I've covered all
of the news and updates here for the
start of the podcast let's work work our
way into everyone's favorite portion of
the show this of course is the question
and answer portion of the show I have a
website that website is iry genetics.com
on the top of that website there is a
row of tabs one of them does say grow
questions if you click on that tab you
were given the opportunity to send me a
grow question send me a good question if
I read that question here on the podcast
I will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds from idirect decom the
first question on today's episode came
came from our new friend who is going to
be called biscuit biscuit welcome to the
iy Army thank you for the good question
and make sure you check your inbox cuz
you have a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at edirect tocom the question
from my new friend Biscuit Goes just
like this it says Hey Rost to Jeff I've
got a question for you and you know what
dude this was a great question it will
really get me rambling so thank you for
the good springboard here on the podcast
the question goes a little bit like this
it says can you please tell me the
difference between a bx1 and an S1 seed
that's a very good question and yes I
will give you a very good detailed
explanation of the difference here the
question does go on it says uh my
understanding is that a bx1 is the plant
back cross to itself uh that's a little
different I'm going to explain that um
there's a lot of stuff in here then it
says I have a pack of permanent marker
S1 from another breeder and on the
package it says permanent marker to
permanent marker Now isn't that a back
cross no um and I'm going to explain why
uh in some detail here in a moment it
says please help me understand this you
always explain things the best I
appreciate that then it says thanks in
advance my dude you are very welcome
thank you for the great question I've
got a lot of great notes Here let me try
to stay focused we will talk about this
we've got two very specific questions to
deal with here we're talking about what
is an S1 and what is a BX and then from
there we're going to talk about what are
the similarities and differences in
those things we're also going to touch
on a whole different realm called an R1
but you'll see where that fits in so
what are we going to start with let's
start with the BX or the BC if you will
the back cross what is a back cross why
would somebody do a back cross what's
the purpose why does it exist let's dig
into this a backat cross a backat cross
is essentially if you take um I'm going
to have to take a minute to unfold this
but it will all come together in the end
a backat cross if you take progyny of a
parent plant and breed them together if
you go backwards in a filial generation
that is a back cross you have bred back
to a previous generation back to a
previous parent that's why the word back
is in there you're going backwards in
the breeding which is not necessarily a
bad thing that is to stabilize things
that can lock things in let's talk about
the main reason why someone including
myself would do a back cross let's talk
about the plant Golden Goat everybody
knows I love working with Golden Goat
Golden Goat is what is known as a clone
only uh Golden Goat SE were never put
out until I did it the original breeder
never put out the Golden Goat seeds
there were no seeds released the only
way Golden Goat was put out to the
public was the breeder that made it
released a clone it was released as a
clone only that's a term that will be
important for the rest of this podcast
and learn about clone only it means a
lot clone only means the breeder that
made it never put out seeds of it so
there's no boy there's that one clone
it's that clone only version that's
what's available is the clone of Golden
Goat now I can make feminized seeds of
Golden Goat and those are widely
available so that's one way to make
seeds but many people in the growing
Community are not into feminized seeds
they do not like fem seeds for whichever
reason and that is fine uh there's a lot
of stigma a lot of questions a lot of
miseducation around feminized seeds many
people simply do not prefer it and that
is okay that is the market that is what
people want so perhaps a grower wants
Golden Goat seeds but like I mentioned
before Golden Goat is a female clone
only so there are no pure Golden Goat
seeds now I want to make Golden Goat
what am I going to do to create Golden
Goat seeds that are not feminized what's
the easiest way to do it would be to
create a bat cross but to do that we
have to open up that Golden Goat we have
to adulterate with another plant it has
to be pollinated by something to create
a starting batch of seeds so what I
would recommend what I have done this is
how I made my Golden Goat BX seeds I
took the original Golden Goat girl
I found another plant that was
completely different in all ways than
that Golden Goat plant I used a
daybreaker mail is the plant that I used
it's got giant leaves uh the golden
goat's got uh skinny thin sharp very
serrated leaves that daybreaker plant
has giant leaves that are they look like
dinner plates you could build a canopy
underneath them you could build a canoe
with them you could build a hammock with
them these were gigantic leaves uh the
Golden Goat grows kind of compact kind
of tight nodes kind of tight node inter
space ing uh the uh daybreaker was real
stretchy and real wide so I used that
daybreaker to pollinate my Golden Goat
plant The Offspring was really easy to
identify the plants that looked like
Golden Goat because they had skinny very
serrated leaves not big wide fingery uh
big fat leaves they were very different
anything with a big fat leave with a
stretchy shape I got rid of that
immediately CU that was not Golden Goat
that was daybreaker Heavy I got rid of
that I found a male plant that looked
just like the original Golden Goat so
what I'm doing is I'm washing out all of
the traits from that daybreaker I've now
found a Golden Goat mail that looks just
like the original Golden Goat Mommy I
went as far as to pull leaves off of
both plants and hold them up next to
each other and look at the amount of
serrations and the shape of the leaves
and the spread between the fingers I was
really OCD about this selection so I
found a male that looked just like that
Golden Goat and then I pollinated the
Golden Goat with that now why is that a
batross because this Golden Goat was the
original mom in that cross I took the
daybreaker I took the Golden Goat I made
seeds from those seeds I found a male
Golden Goat it's basically go it's it's
a cross but it looks just like Golden
Goat I took that pollen and I went back
to the mom and put that pollen on there
now that is now my Golden Goat backat
cross first generation that is why we
would do a batross that is how a batross
is done why would we do that because we
want seeds of that that are pure Golden
Goat but there's no way to make a Golden
Goat pure seed uh because perhaps you
don't have the parents there's only the
female so that's the first way to do it
you have to open up the line make seeds
you have to adulterate it adulterate it
make seeds and then the next step is to
start washing out the adulteration so I
have now made seeds I have found a plant
that looks just like my Golden Goat I
breed that to Golden Goat that's going
to make more seeds I'm going to take
those seeds and guess what I'm going to
do again I'm going to find another one
that looks just like that Golden Goat
and put it back on the original Golden
Goat clone that is my batross 2 that's
my second filial generation of that
batross there's a lot of different ways
you could go about doing that depending
on the traits you want what you're
looking for but that's the way that I
would do it keep keep making seeds back
to that Golden Goat and then what we're
doing is every time you go to the Golden
Goat plant with that pollen that progyny
has less and less of the daybreaker in
there so we're washing out that
daybreaker with each filial generation
if we do it correctly so that is a
batross that's how why and what I would
do a batross for now let's talk about
the other part of the question which was
s1's what is an S1 why would we do an S1
how was that useful let's focus again on
the original Golden Goat plant many
people out there in the world want the
Golden Goat plant I have got the
original Golden Goat clone there are a
lot of breeders a lot of Growers out
there a lot of medical consumers a lot
of recreational people out there they
would really enjoy and really benefit
from having Golden Goat seeds so they
can grow it and benefit from the effects
of this plant so I am able to offer pure
unadulterated feminized Golden Goat
seeds to the market now how do I do that
it is a very easy process once you
understand it I take a clone of the
Golden Goat I take another clone of the
Golden Goat I've got two clones of the
exact same plant they are both Golden
Goat so we are not introducing anything
new in this process at this time I will
treat one clone with a solution I'm
using silver tho sulfate I'm also
experimenting with the new product but
we will treat this clone with a solution
uh it's got to be the proper dilution
the proper intervals uh the proper time
there's a lot of stuff that goes on to
it I'm going to spray this plant seven
times over the course of its life and
what I'm going to do is create a
reaction in this plant that will create
this female plant to create pollen that
only contains female chromosomes yes I
know it sounds like a lot of Wizardry a
lot is going on once you understand the
science of it it's really not that
amazing that hard to understand I'm not
going to explain it here I've done a
full episode on this but I treat this
plant and right now I'm going to give a
big disclaimer the word Herm
hermaphrodite in sex is not involved in
this at all when you are making
feminized seeds the word Herm should not
be involved at all if Herman is in there
don't use it to make interex plant or
don't use that to make feminized plants
don't use any interex plants in any
breeding there is no Herm happening when
making fem seeds I'm treating a female
plant with a a solution I'm treating it
with silver thiosulfate the silver gets
into the plant it disrupts the copper
movement in that plant that creates a
hormonal reaction inside that plant that
makes it create anthers which create
pollen it is not a hermaphrodite it is
not a male it is a reversed female it is
a big difference than the other things I
mentioned those anthers will drop pollen
that pollen will be feminized pollen
because there are no male chromosomes
available in this plant so I'm going to
take that Golden Goat reversed pollen
put it on a Golden Goat female plant
guess what I just did I made pure Golden
Goat seeds that are all females so S1 is
all Golden Goat to Golden Goat the BX
one is Golden Goat to something else
then back to the Golden Goat to wash out
all that other stuff so the basic
difference is regular and feminized the
other difference is one is adulterated
and one is unadulterated Golden Goat uh
we can do filial generations with that
batross and wash out the whatever we use
to open it up or start the batross with
you can wash that out through two three
definitely through four batross
generations but with the fem seeds
there's no need to wash it out with the
feminized seeds in the first batch 50%
of those seeds are going to look just
like the original Golden Goat then
you're going to get about 20 of them
that look like the mom of the Golden
Goat 20 that look like the dad of the
Golden Goat and then you're going to get
10% that are just [ __ ] weirdos
they're going to look like grandparents
great grandparents
uh weird mutations of all of the above
that is just the way the genetics kind
of mix with that plant so let me check
my notes make sure I'm on track here to
keep myself going we have talked about
bat crosses we talked about when where
why and how that works we've talked
about making an S1 of the Golden Goat
now let's talk about r1s what is an R1
an R1 is very simple so let me give you
a phrase that you're going to remember
here that you'll never forget it's a
little crude it's a little crass promise
you're never going to forget it and S1
uh self plant that plant selfed itself
it went and [ __ ] itself and S1 is
because that plant selfed itself it's an
S1 now an R1 now we're going to talk
about the r1s the S1 is if I were to
take the pollen and put it on the same
plant itself in R1 is if I take that
Golden Goat pollen and put it on any
other plant that is just indicating that
I have used reversed pollen to indicate
that this is a feminized project here uh
the R1 is the first filial generation a
reversal project the S1 is the first
filial generation of a self project so
S1 is a self R1 is a reversal meaning I
put the pollen on any plant other than
what I reversed I'm just opening up
doing more breeding and that is very a
very uh very viable breeding idea I do
that with a lot of stuff that is how
orange gasm is made that's how lemon
Jeffree is made uh so when I'm making
Golden Goat fem seeds I I reverse one
Golden Goat plant and I put that that
pollen from that one plant on another
Golden Goat I just made Golden Goat s1's
while I'm in the room why not put it on
a Lemon Skunk to make some lemon Jeffrey
r1s put it on the uh the Platinum Tangi
to make orange gasm r1s why not just get
creative and do stuff like that so that
is the backat cross that is R1 and that
is S1 that's my story and I'm sticking
to it uh my dude biscuit bro thank you
for the great question oh also I can't
speak for the breeder that made that
package I don't know exactly what
they're doing but with what the details
you have given me um that is going to be
an S1 they took just like they said they
took that permanent marker plant the
other permanent marker plant uh they
reversed one put the pollen on the other
they did not add anything else they
didn't go backwards if it's feminized
you have got yourself a permanent marker
S1 is what you've got there once again
my dude biscuit make sure you check your
inbox cuz you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds from IR
direct.com all right podcast world let's
keep this good momentum going I do have
another question here in front of me
this question also came from the growel
tab on iry genetics.com the question
came from our new friend Barry Bryant
Barry Bryant welcome to the IR Army
thank you for the good question once
again make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds the question goes a
little bit like this it says greetings
my dude greetings bro good to hear from
you it says this thought was brought to
you by by orange GM the tasty breakfast
treat to get your day started that's a
really good tagline a really good ad I
should have put that on the packaging
but I did not there is more it says
anyhow I do have a hypothetical idea or
question for you this is a good question
I like this it says what if I have a 2
by two veg tin with one big pot of soil
then I throw in a handful of seeds and
let the seeds fight for survival one
plant remains is that one actually the
keeper or is that a dumb way to sort
through a batch of beans uh that is one
way to do it but in my opinion you're
not going to find the plant with the
best TPS the best Buzz the best
resistance to pathogens the best
resistance to bugs uh you're going to
find the plant that uh just fights the
best which might not be uh the best
plant for smoking consuming selling
medicating whatever you're going to do
with it uh that is the plant with the
strongest Roots the most aggressive
plant uh before I've talked about
selecting male plants from a population
I'm going to say that this may have the
same sort of criteria let's just say
that you do find one plant that is super
vigorous and super strong in winds that
is going to be the plant with the most
robust Roots the most fibrous stocks uh
that is not necessarily going to be the
plant with the biggest fattest juiciest
stickiest stinkiest most Tricom Laden
buds um just just like when I talk about
selecting males I say if we've got five
male plants to choose from that first
plant that grows real tall and shows
that it's a boy and is real vigorous get
rid of that because it's just too
vigorous you're making hemp fiber it's
going to be all male in the breeding mix
I feel like your your female plant that
survives this run is just going to be
real hempy real fibrous it's not going
to be good smoke it'll be a badass
grower it might be something to breed to
to add uh productivity Vigor strength
and all that into another plant but I
don't think it's going to be the one uh
that we're going to want to smoke it's
not going to be the one that makes
people say damn it'll be the one that
makes the grower say damn but not the
consumer not the clientele not the
patients not the customers and that's
who we're trying to impress uh the
people that actually smoke the [ __ ] so
it's a good idea it's a fun game to play
I do like the battle of the fittest idea
the uh the Beyblade idea you got going
on here but I would not do it that way I
would give them all their separate pots
um because like I said the one that wins
isn't going to be the best smoke it's
going to be the strongest plant and that
that's a big part of selection but that
is not the only thing and I think you
could find better um if you grow them
separately I'm rambling I have made my
point my dude Barry Bryant this was a
good fun question so make sure you check
your inbox because you have a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from iy
direct.com all right I've got another
great question here in front of me this
one also came from the growel tab at
air.com before I read this question it
is my duty as a host of a podcast to
remind you that if you like this podcast
now's a good time to click like and also
if you love it click subscribe that way
every time I put out an episode you'll
get a notification you'll never miss any
of my amazing cannabis educational
content all right let's stay focused
this question came from our friend
Special K I feel like I've already made
friends with Special K a long time ago
shout out to my new friend Special K
this is a fun question it says Hey Rost
Jeff thank you for the continued Good
Vibes and good advice hey that's what
I'm here for thank you for noticing
it says when you are gifted seeds how do
you decide if you want to try them
thanks again I hope it's going smoothly
bro everything is going iy for me uh the
podcast is coming out well the day has
been good um been having some fun in the
grow so everything is iy let's answer
this question here a little bit uh how
do I decide that I want to grow gifted
seeds that is a very very good question
uh every couple of months I do like to
pop a new batch of seeds I uh pick out
some of my stuff a couple of I pick out
stuff from other breeders and I want to
see what my stuff does right next to
theirs in my rooms I want to see what my
New Creations do compared to my old
creations I'm very curious is what I'm
saying here so uh after I choose what of
my seeds I'm going to run sometimes I
pull out my whole seed collection the
big horde of seeds that I've got and I
look through and I decide like o this
looks interesting or oh I've been
thinking about that but really it's all
about do I have room that is the main do
I have space to grow these seeds and
then um what else is in the room and how
much time are those plants going to take
if I'm picking a bunch of OG kush or a
bunch of Indica stuff I'm not going to
find other hazes to go with that cuz
that's going to [ __ ] up the whole room
so if I'm running let's just say I just
found a bunch of random something
something OG cush seeds and I'm going to
run some kush and some [ __ ] that I cross
to OG I'm going to go look into in my
batch for one more OG Kush varietal from
a friend that may match up with that so
that's one of the first criteria do I
have room and then does whatever I'm
thinking about running does it match the
rest of the room cuz I don't want [ __ ]
uh one plant 5 foot tall and the other
plant 8T tall I don't want some [ __ ] 55
day which is hypothetical you're never
going to get a 55 day flower I don't
want something at 55 and something at 82
days of flower CU that's going to be a
[ __ ] to manage so I think about plant
compatibility in the room is one thing
um then what is the cross is there
something that's getting my attention is
there did I smoke something recently uh
um I keep saying OG Kush did I smoke a
cush that's got me thinking damn I want
that turp or I really need that in my
arsenals there's something I'm missing
um if there's something I'm missing
maybe that's what I'm looking for maybe
I got a pack of seeds that uh somebody
said hey do you have guava in the lineup
and I thought I don't so I'm packing
popping a pack of guava from nothing but
gas big shout out to my boy nothing but
gas but I will have guava so there are a
lot of things that dictate me deciding
which pack of seeds to grow it could be
uh something I need it could be a trait
it could be a flavor it could be a turp
I'm after it could be a breeder that I
just want to give a chance uh could be a
friend like my friend nothing but gas
he's been putting [ __ ] out for a while
it's time to give him a run and see what
he's up to see if his seeds are good
he's a good dude he's a cool guy why not
run his seeds while I've got some room
and see how those seeds are going to do
in my grow uh like I said it's all about
to the plants match up do I need that
turpine do I need that flavor do I need
that growth do I need a trait from that
plant for a breeding project so it could
be a turp that I'm looking for it could
be a specific trait in a pack of seeds
I'm looking for a growth structure uh
maybe I've got a breeding idea that
that's going to be a precursor to maybe
I want to make strawberry vanilla
biscuit cookies and this one's got
vanilla biscuit and I'm just trying to
find that turp to get maybe it's a
springboard or a stepping stone uh maybe
I've got a friend that's been breeding
for a long time and as I'm going through
my seeds I've got like a bunch of stuff
that's going to be 90day flowering and I
see his pack and it says 90-day flow and
I go hey let's run this um or maybe just
like I'm letting my buddy nothing but
gas have a spot in a grow space uh maybe
I'm just running those guavas uh because
it's time to give my friend a chance
he's been at it for a long time he's
been putting in the work I've got his
seeds they fit the criteria why not run
those and see how they do so there's a
lot of determining factors do they fit
uh the timeline do they fit the growth
shape are they a stepping stone is there
a trait that I need uh is there
something hyped up in there that's got
my attention is did a friend breed it
that I looked at it and said that guy
deserves attention um or also with all
of that being said it could also be
complet completely [ __ ] random I
might look at a pack and go wait
starberry skunk weasel I want to grow
that I don't know why but I do just like
a lot of times out there you guys see a
strain name uh people are going crazy uh
people went crazy for anything with the
Ninja Turtles on it you guys go crazy
for that I've got a new strain coming
out that I haven't said the name on a
lot of public forums I do talk about it
in the uh the Discord server every time
I say the name people want some of that
people wanted Cherry skunk before they
ever saw the plants uh when I said I
have cherry skunk they said take my
money uh so a lot of it is names a lot
of is just random packaging it's
whatever gets my attention advertising
and marketing works on me too uh
sometimes I'm try not to fall for it but
that [ __ ] does get me so this was a
really good fun question um I just
decide based on does it fit the criteria
of the room uh flowering time
growth-wise is there a turp or a trait
that I need is it a stepping stone for a
breeding project or honest it could just
be a random pack of seeds chose to fill
in that section of the room cuz I needed
more seeds there's a lot of random there
are a lot of details and a lot of
nothing that helped me decide that so
there's no Rhyme or Reason but there's
also a lot of criteria take it that what
you will um but also make sure you take
your free pack of seeds from I
redirect.sh ago I don't know if I even
have any notes left we may be
freestyling the rest of this show I'm
trying to get it back there we go it
needs a password I'm not even going to
edit this it looks like we're back I
have saved the notes we've got some
structure once again um ladies and
gentlemen thank you for all the great
questions on this podcast if your
question did not get read on today's
episode please do not feel discouraged I
have got a mountain of emails here in
front of me and eventually I work will
work my way through all of them so
please continue to send me those
questions and if I did not read your
question keep listening who knows this
one right here on the top of the pile I
won't show it to you but it could be
yours I might read it on the very next
episode so keep listening and please do
keep sending me those grow questions
from the growel tab at I
genetics.com I think that's all I've got
for you don't forget there is a Black
Friday sale coming I'm going to do an
early pre-black Friday drop that's right
November 16th at I direct.com there will
be a bunch of great stuff on iir go
check out the new Ruby waves will be
available the restock of the double
Lemon Skunk will Avail will be available
there will be a brand new freebie
restocks of a bunch of great stuff uh
the Bobby Knight will be very affordable
tinf foil hat will be very affordable
there will be a huge sale on regular and
feminized seeds I have said enough
already uh the 16th is the day uh I
redirect is the website tell them rosta
Jeff sent you um for updates and details
join the mailing list that's right iry
genetics.com halfway down on the page
there's a tab that says stay up to date
type in your email address when I do new
drop new sales new releases you will get
an email with an update when I put out
more clones or new strains also you'll
get a reminder about the Black Friday
sale if you sign up for the newsletter
all right everything else you could
possibly imagine is at iy genetics.com
you guys my voice and throat are burning
out and simply getting tired it it's
time to wrap up the show thank you for
listening I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
shout out to my friend Kurt Z and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another DB
grab your p in I about the
B is in the lab sit back relax
[Music]
roots and wisdom start to show from the
knowledge seats we grow tun in now to
hear the
V Jeff in our
conscious the truth in every word every
voice must not be heard healing light
through canit roll from your heart your
Li rise up higher find your way
grow from your hearts every
day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the
[Music]
song not from medicine
Al throws within us like a d educates
and
elevate join the Journey Don't Be Late
open minds to see the truth in the soil
lies the pro R not death will guide you
through and this G find
you rise up higher Find Your Way find
your way oh from your heart every day
every
day in the light We Stand real
strong feel strong join The Movement
singing the
song open your minds to see the
truth forgot you through in this gard
and find the mo rise up high Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every
day
o in the light We Stand real
strong real strong join the movement
sing the
song wo
oh
[Music]
[Laughter]