bless up family this is Natalie rise and
you are tuned to the highest frequency
the grow from your heart podcast with
rusted Jeff the grow from your heart
podcast Starts
Now Rost Jeff you bad mother
[Music]
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode
859 of the grow from your heart podcast
you know I've got another fun episode
lined up for us in today's show I'm
going to give away free seeds that's
right hang out we'll talk more about
those free seeds later on in the show
before I get too far I do want to remind
you that the pre-black Friday sale has
begun at idirect decom that's right
check idirect
for Black Friday sale pricing and
current inventory once again that is
idirect decom because the pre-black
Friday sale has begun all right I also
do want to send a few thank you shout
outs to a few of the great folks who
support the podcast on patreon let's
kick it off with a big grow fromy heart
podcast thank you shout out to my friend
T Clemy thank you for joining us on
Discord bro it's good to have you over
there I also want to send a big thank
you shout out to my buddy 8bit thank you
for the support then let's wrap it up
with a big grow from your heart podcast
thank you shout out to my friend to Guru
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com forward SLG grow from
your heart all of the information you
need will be right there on the screen
once again big thanks to everybody who
supports the show all right I feel like
I've covered all of the business here at
the start of the show let's work our way
into everyone's favorite section of the
podcast that is of course the question
and answer portion of the show I do have
a couple of websites my main website is
I genetics.com everything is listed at
IR genetics.com there's a link to the
Discord server there's a link to the
patreon uh there's a link to iir to get
the beans everything is at iry
genetics.com but there is also a tab at
the top that says growel or grow
questions if you click on that growel or
grow question tab guess what you can
send me a grow question if I read your
grow question here on the podcast I will
send you a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at idirect
docomo is going to be called deham I
think that's how we say that dcoms deams
I'm going to call you D for today hey D
thank you for the great question also
make sure you check your inbox and your
spam folder because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom one more rambly piece of info
before I jump into this question if I do
send you a gift certificate or a coupon
code for free seeds at IR
redirect.sh that coupon code there are a
couple of reasons for that mostly
logistic reasons um I don't like having
gift certificates just out floating in
The Ether and owing people uh money
essentially owing you seeds off of my
website it makes it challenging to keep
inventory it makes challenging it makes
it challenging to predict some things I
need those to expire so that means I
need you to use those gift certificates
uh before they do expire so please when
you see that expiration date uh please
use that promptly because I do get
emails people saying hey I didn't use my
gift card it expired can you replace it
unfortunately I cannot and will not do
that uh there are a couple of logistical
reasons behind that first of all it
tells me you did not listen to the
podcast I tell you hey you got a coupon
code for seeds go use it um if you
listen to the show you probably heard it
you got excited you went and bought
seeds if not you simply were not excited
enough you didn't hear the show you
didn't go grab the beans I understand
maybe you don't need seeds right now but
go get them um so it tells me you didn't
listen to the episode and it tells me
you didn't go get your seeds but I need
those to expire like I said for logistic
reasons and logistic purposes so please
use them uh before they do expire that's
all I'm going to ramble about that that
was a side note a side quest if you will
let's get back on track my dude D make
sure you check your inbox check that
spam folder and use that coupon code uh
make sure you use it on the Black Friday
uh month because you will be able to
grab some great deals where are we the
question goes yo brother hey brother
nice to meet you it says much love and
appreciation for you and what you do
mucho blessings bro uh mucho gratitude I
return uh the blessings I return the uh
the thankfulness it's reciprocal is what
I'm trying to say here I am high and
rambly today it is reciprocated uh you
guys enjoy the lessons I give and I
enjoy the praise and gratit you send my
way so thank you it goes two ways it
says I thought of a question this
evening as I was getting in my veg tent
and my question is what non-growing
related items do you use in your grow to
help you out this is a really good
question it said I really like using zip
ties for all sorts of situations that
probably when I shop outside of the grow
store for Stuff zip ties are one of the
first things I buy I buy a lot of zip
ties I use them I got ducting hanging
from a ceiling I put an ey hook in the
ceiling use zip tie to keep it in place
lots of zip ties going on it goes on it
says I would love to hear what you use
daily or longterm bless up my friend
from dcoms or decom dcoms I'm not sure
how to say it bro but I still love and
respect you either way um so let's talk
about some of the things that I may use
for my grow that are not necessarily
designed or created or intended or sold
as grow room items everything we buy for
the grow is more expensive because the
people that made it and the people that
sold it to us know we're going to grow
cannabis with it so they just charge us
extra for it any cannabis growing item
cost 10 20% more than it should simply
because they know what we were going to
do with it if it wasn't for growing the
same exact freaking item would be 10 20%
cheaper uh you can go get it almost
every store except it's a specialized
item so they mark it up just because
they know what we're going to do which
is unfair but it's America that's how
some [ __ ] works so there are many items
we can buy that don't come from the grow
store that you can get at your big Box
Store maybe a local Mom and Pop shop
that will help us in our Grow rooms um
I've got a short list here let's just
talk about things that are not
necessarily grow room specific devices
that I rely on and do use the first
thing on my list was door security um
I've got a little sensor thing it just
it's got one piece and another piece one
goes on the door frame one goes on the
door it's got a magnet on it when they
click together this little dot turns off
when they unclick the Red Dot lights up
and I get a notification on my phone uh
door sensors door alarms I love it if my
grow room doors open I know it my phone
beeps and I go who the [ __ ] is in my
grow room the next thing that goes with
that wise cameras I really like cameras
in the grow so if that thing beeps and
says hey there's someone around I can
look and see who the [ __ ] is around I
keep uh so I've got a pretty decent
sized grow room with multiple tents in
that room I've got a camera in each tent
the veg and the flower and I like to
have a camera in the main part of the
room as well so I can see if there's uh
we'll talk about another thing here in a
second but I can see what's going on in
that room so if I do get a notification
then I can open up the cameras and I can
look and see what's happening um another
thing I'm going to talk about am I going
in order because I don't know if I am
I'm going to skip something one thing
that just came to my mind to tell you
about is water sensors and all of your
hardware stores even on Amazon you can
buy water and moisture sensors so if
you're running a reservoir or if you're
running anything that automatically
fills up you've got an RO system you've
got water running to that constantly it
fills up it's filling a reservoir you
should have a float valve to make that
stop sometimes that will fail that float
valve is going to [ __ ] up one time
you're going to get water all over the
floor if you're gone you're at work
you're on vacation maybe you're out
running errands whatever you're doing uh
maybe you went to get some tacos
everyone loves tacos but whatever you're
out doing if you've got a moisture
sensor on the floor where moisture
should not get to when water hits that
guess what your phone's going to ding
you're going to get a notification pull
out your phone open your way cameras or
your wise cameras and look to see is
there water somewhere uh that water
sensor will ding your phone and let you
know hey there's water in places it
shouldn't be I use those in my Grove but
I also have a leaky pipe in my basement
uh there's an area that is known to kind
of cause a problem so anytime water
starts to happen there that [ __ ]
moisture sensor goes off and tells me so
that if I'm sleeping if I'm across town
if I'm at the store uh if I'm at the
sneaker shop I could just get right back
to where the grow is either one of the
grows and I can fix that water and not
cause more problems because water can
really destroy some [ __ ] so door
security is one of the first things I
like uh water sensors and cameras are
things that I really like then let's
work on another really important thing
smoke detectors I really like some sort
of smoke detection we've got a lot of
electricity going on in that room even
if you just have one light and a fan
that's a lot of electricity running in a
growroom I don't know if it's in a
closet a bedroom or whatever but we
don't want to be the person that causes
a fire in the neighborhood because we
were cultivating cannabis that's a
really bad look on the entire Community
it's a bad look on the plant that's a
rough look my dude so don't be the
person uh catching a fire starting a
fire in your cultivation room um
especially in a residential area so I
recommend a smoke detector that way if
something does happen you could put that
[ __ ] out as quickly as possible how you
going to do that with the next piece of
advice I recommend the next piece of
equipment would be a fire extinguisher
that's right have a fire extinguisher
outside of the grow space uh if you walk
up to my main grow room right outside on
the floor I know it's on the floor I
could kick it and trip it where it is I
won't but there is a fire extinguisher
right on the floor if some [ __ ] goes
wrong I can pick up the fire
extinguisher pull the pen kick the door
like the [ __ ] FBI and go in and just
start spraying and praying and handle
some [ __ ] so um where are we so far door
security you want to know if people come
and go um if they come and go you want a
camera so you can look at them um if
[ __ ] floods you want a water sensor also
when that water sensor goes off look at
the cameras that's pretty simple smoke
alarm we want to know if a fire happens
I don't have a smoke alarm that hooks up
to my phone it's simply
[ __ ] loud hopefully I'm here or there
or wherever the fire happens hopefully
there's no fire to be honest with you
but um do they make and sell a smoke
detector that hooks up to your phone yet
that should be something you know what's
going to happen my AC Infinity monitor
is going to let me know it's 170,000
degrees in there it will be B tell me so
we do have some sort of fire warning if
we are away so we got a smoke detector
we got a fire extinguisher um now we're
just going to work our way into other
random those are big things I thought we
should definitely cover safety safety is
important Safety and Security
um door locks do you have good locks on
your doors that's more [ __ ] to think
about I did not even write down locking
door knobs those are important but then
I really like the spin mop the Spin Mop
is just another random fun thing that
I've bought for my grow uh it's got the
thing that spins inside of it so you use
the mop you get that [ __ ] dirty and then
you stick it in the one part and you hit
the pedal and it spins the thing around
and cleans your mop for you I really
like the Spin Mop they don't I don't
work for Spin Mop I don't work I don't
nobody pays me to advertise except IE
genetics cuz I own the damn company but
Spin Mop is a great [ __ ] product it's
fun it's cheap and it it makes things
easier you know the janitor bucket if
you can if you got a big space get the
janitor bucket Spin Mop is a small
version of that um it's carry it's
portable uh it's really easy to use and
it's you got to mop the damn floor and
if you have easier gear to access and
use you're more likely to use it so the
Spin Mop that was a fun uh little
investment also something I use a whole
bunch in the grow space is a doctor
stool if you got that little rollable uh
rolling adjustable doctor stool that
will save your back that'll save your
legs um sometimes I'm just scooting all
the way across the floor I don't want to
stand up and go over there to get the
scissors and come back I'll roll my high
ass right across the floor get them
launch myself right back but that doctor
stool really helps a lot I don't need to
be standing all day I don't need to be
hunched over and bent over little doctor
stool makes things a lot easier for me
there are a lot of options I like the
doctor stool uh works great for what I'm
trying to do uh the next thing that I
use a whole bunch in my grow space and
this is not grow related but how I said
if you enjoy being in there you'll be in
there more which some of you just need
to get the [ __ ] out of the grow and quit
messing with the plants but if there's
work to do like popping twisting
lollipopping defoliating uh working the
plants into the trellis net which I
really enjoy doing the environment helps
a lot so it's really nice to be in there
something I'm going to add right now
glasses good grow room sunglasses they
make specific glasses to protect you
from the spectrum of light which you
were using if you're using HPS LED
ceramic metal hly they make a pair of
glasses to protect you from that
Spectrum um our eyes are the most
sensitive organs on our body that are
exposed to the elements and also one of
the most critical uh senses we've got
for survival so protect your eyes invest
in your eyes get some good glasses to
cover your eyes but another thing I
wanted to say uh if we're going to be in
there a lot make it comfortable Jam some
good music get a good Bluetooth speaker
for the grow space that's not unheard of
at this time those Bluetooth speakers
are so affordable you can get a good
cheap speaker for like 20 bucks at the
gas station and it's going to bump you
could get something really nice at
Target or at Home Depot but those $20
little pieces of [ __ ] at the gas station
are going to bump and give you some
music especially if you're just
listening to the grow from your heart
podcast there's no super sound quality
to try to put out here other than my
voice you don't need like cool bass
riffs or there's no guitar chucking
through so just a decent speaker will
make it go a long way some gentle
entertainment in the grow space or some
airpods one of the to uh little little
Bluetooth speaker or some airpods so you
can get some music or a podcast going
that'll encourage you to go in there
sometimes I'm like I just want to listen
to this podcast I'm going to go
defoliate just so I have something to do
while I listen so get some music going
in there I don't care if it's Bluetooth
speakers or airpods get some sound
happening it's good for you it'll make
you feel better and you'll enjoy your
time in there then other things we're
going to talk about um Uline is your
hero if you're a weed grower you
probably get a catalog from Uline in the
mail about once a month with all their
cool [ __ ] that they offer you they offer
some cool things they offer a push cart
that I really like you can load up all
your nutrients on the bottom of that you
could put a bunch of stuff on the bottom
of the cart all the heavy stuff and then
up top put like your scissors a box of
gloves your drink can go up there your
Bluetooth speaker I got a little cart
that I just push around it makes life so
much easier if I need something it's on
the cart I know most of what I need is
probably on the cart and I can roll the
cart from room to room wherever I need
it all my stuff can be close to me um I
can put a lot lot of things on that cart
I clean the cart you guys the cart gets
messy uh don't put your food and stuff
on there I just said have your drink on
there but no Doritos not a lot of that
stuff um I got a sprayer I got some
scissors I got gloves the Bluetooth
speaker sits there my phone is probably
on there um there's a pen and a pad of
paper for some notes uh just all the
random [ __ ] my glasses will be sitting
on there uh just random shits on there
uh just that little cart makes life easy
I just push it around from room to room
from grow to grow space to space um I
mix in another area so I can roll it
over the mix area and then bring it it
provides a lot of purpose I can set a
five gallon bucket on it I can carry
like eight five gallon buckets on there
no problem get a little rolling cart
from Uline or a little basket of some
sort just to carry your [ __ ] around you
save a lot of time not going to get
individual items all all the time like
in my clone area my cloning happens
right here most of my nutrients are in
one area my mix area my cloning stuff
the uh the purple gel the Clone X and
the PH down and the pH pen are
um it's a thing I got it's came from
Target I'm pretty sure it's designed to
go in the shower it looks like it could
hang right on the shower head and hold
your shampoos and your loofah and
whatever but it's perfectly big enough
to hold the PH down the clonex gel the
clonex juice a Paras scissors a pH pen
and a box of gloves all fit perfectly in
this like little shower rack thing and
that just hangs on the wall by my cloner
um it was designed to be for the shower
you know you put your shampoos and all
that stuff in there girls probably hang
a plant in there uh I've got all my
cloning stuff right there so that if I
do decide to move the cloner to another
area just grab that all my cloning
supplies come with me makes it super
[ __ ] easy so a little Uline basket a
shower
organizer um I've got this yeah the
shower organizer is [ __ ] awesome
that's one of my favorites um where else
where else do we go from here oh um
something that I buy quite often that is
not definitely not meant to be for
growing and you'll see this uh in so
many grows uh is beer cups I buy a lot
of beer cups the red solo party cups or
even the rainbow pack will work I don't
care what color they are but I like to
use those cups to put my little baby
clones in uh if I cut clones right when
I put them into their first pot they go
into a beer cup a lot of the time uh one
thing I should stress is poke holes in
the bottoms of those beer cups um I
usually take a drill and I can stack up
a bunch and just put one big hole
through the bottom and then do a couple
more just R right in the middle and then
a couple randomly through there you want
drainage I've also seen guys heat up a
hot poker and just push a poker through
a big stack of cups however that's going
to stink it's going to make smoke be
forewarned but put holes in those beer
cups and they work perfectly for little
containers for small plants I've done
full breeding projects in beer cups so
uh that's something to think about not
going to tell you too much about that
now but beer cups and a drill just get
some beer cups in a drill and you can
make uh like 52 pots for like eight
bucks you know it's not that expensive I
got a bad itch on my a ankle here I hope
this doesn't disrupt the show that
probably looked weird but it feels
better all right where are we um duct
tape you you guys duct tape and zip ties
are your hero um I don't know who said
it but someone one wise man it might
have been confucious confucious once
said if you can't duck it [ __ ] it so get
some duct tape you can fix almost
everything in the grow space uh get some
of that aluminum like the foil tape uh
you can cut your fingers on it real good
get some of that tape uh that stuff
sticks to everything you can fix a lot
of [ __ ] with that that and duct tape and
zip ties bro you cannot go wrong
everything is fixable with duct tape and
zip ties also something I use you're
going to say bro you're 6'5 why do you
have one of these cuz sometimes there
[ __ ] I need to get to I have a step
stool just a little it's a shitty step
stool from Home Depot and I use it way
more than you might imagine yeah I'm 65
but sometimes just getting up above the
light and be able being able to work on
top of the light without being on my
tippy toes makes it a lot freaking
easier so maybe a little step stool uh
one of those folding um get the size you
need you know what I'm talking about but
if you need to get up top and get some
[ __ ] go get a step stool don't be shy a
little trash can for the grow is always
nice too I put a trash can with the
trash bag in it anytime I defoliate or
whatever if you use some of that silver
tape it's got a backing you need a trash
can I recommend a trash can with the lid
and a bag and get rid of that trash
every day take that trash out of your
grow room not just out of the grow but
if you can get it out of the house the
facility whatever get rid of it as far
as you can from your grow uh let the
bugs go to those Dead Leaves outside
instead of in your environment you're
just asking for problems with Dead
Leaves and full foliage around it's a
little trash can and some trash bags and
a duct tape or and some duct tape are
always your friend um I did not write
this on here but I just thought of this
all of us Growers get [ __ ] sticky
trim time is sticky working is sticky we
need something to clean all that
stickiness off I like a bottle of
coconut oil uh go to your local health
food store or the Whole Foods or Sprouts
or uh natural groceries whatever you got
in your neighborhood go get a jar of
coconut oil when your fingers are super
sticky when my arm hair is sticky I'll
just take coconut oil and just give
myself one of these and just give it a
good rub and all that stickiness will
come right off then you got to wash with
soap and water after that but coconut
oil will get rid of all that stickiness
it helps a lot it will also help to
clean your scissors and all of your
other gear uh so if you got some sticky
[ __ ] coconut oil if you want to clean
surfaces that's when I recommend 91% ISO
uh try not to put the ISO on your skin
although it wouldn't be a surprise to
walk into the room and catch me washing
my hands with straight ISO cuz I'm
[ __ ] sticky don't do that you're
better than that your skin means more to
you than that do as I say not as I do
some [ __ ] like that I learned it from
you Dad um where are we a pH pen um I
recommend just getting a new pH and an
EC pin um I recently bought one that is
a combo it is EC pH and temperature all
at the same time I drop one thing in
there and it tells me everything I need
to know that one tool makes me save a
couple of minutes every day which is
encouraging it makes me want to play
with it like I have a new toy that works
real well it stick stick it in the water
see what the EC pH and temperature are
all in one move instead of having to
dump multiple devices in here um get
yourself a good reliable EC and pH meter
it will make your life much better and
it'll make the plants happier we're
banging off [ __ ] on this list here we're
going pretty quickly um dude something
uh something I use a lot in a commercial
or in a regular uh commercial or homeg
grow environment is coat hangers when I
harvest my plants I put them on coat
hangers I just chop them and hang them
up on coat hangers I buy a lot of coat
hangers for grov also here's a dad hack
take a coat hanger right get the plastic
kind uh or even the old metal ones will
work for this matter get the plastic
coat hanger it's got the piece that
comes down it's got the part where your
clothing would hang cut that part out
just get I use the Snips that I cut the
[ __ ] plants down with clip that [ __ ]
off there clip it off there now you got
your coat hanger that goes like this
with a big gap put a roll of paper
towels in that Gap and hang that [ __ ]
up what free idea there for you that's
probably the best advice I gave you in
this whole episode take a coat hanger
cut out the middle part slap on a
[ __ ] roll of paper towels you've got
an awesome paper towel hanger for the
grow space right there [ __ ] genius
dude also something else I use a lot
that you can get at Walmart Target
anywhere that sells [ __ ] cheap
plastic items uh Amazon is good for this
the container stor has got them they are
under the bed bins designed to put your
clothing or whatever you want to store
under the bed but they're real shallow
they're like I don't know I want to say
68 maybe 9 in deep I don't know about
that far um 6 or eight 9 in deep and
they're like 2 feet long and a foot wide
maybe 18 in wide but I like those for
putting all kinds of [ __ ] in there I can
fit I think you can fit 48 uh maybe 24
48 beer cups perfectly in the tray that
I'm talking about so if you just want to
fill one of those up do a little feno
hunt maybe a quick breeding run in beer
cups that sterlite tray will hold a
bunch of Cups perfectly also when I'm
harvesting I'll chop down plants and put
it right into that bin and let it sit
there till it dries sometimes it will
work in a pinch also when I'm harvesting
for seeds I hang the plant up till it's
dry once it's dry enough I put it in
that bin so that I do not lose my seeds
they don't fall out of anywhere except
into that bin then I'll take gloves and
bust all the buds off the sticks into
that bin then grind it all up real fine
into that bin now I've got all my
material and my seeds in that bin that's
how I keep that bin of seeds kind of
isolated so I use a lot of stirl trays
uh they sell a bunch of different sizes
they will make your trim life and your
storage life much easier also I use a
lot of ball jars I thought of that cuz I
could see ball jars there's a box of
ball jars sitting over there uh my
long-term storage goes in ball jars or
turkey bags uh get you some turkey bags
it's going to be hard right now at this
time of year but or maybe it's easier I
don't know maybe they're available
turkey bags are great for storage um I'd
give you the paper towel hanger idea
that's probably the best one you're
going to get all day I told you about
sterlite bins I told you about the
hangers you guys I think we have covered
most of my ideas that I've got for items
we can use uh that are not not meant for
the grow room things we can reallocate
for growroom purposes this is where I'm
going to do what we call a podcast call
to action that's right iy Army grow from
your heart podcast listeners what are
you using in your grow that was not
designed to be used for growing purposes
what are you buying somewhere else how
can we save a few bucks how can we save
some time share your ideas down there in
the comments and my favorite comment
will win a free pack of SE that should
be pretty encouraging right uh there's
no time limit to this uh I've got all
the time I want in the world to choose
the winner I will know the comment when
I see it uh I will tag you I will let
you know that you wanton I will request
an email address from you is how you
will know but the best contribution to
this comment section for uh what are you
using that is not designed to be used in
a grow uh for your grow give us your
ideas my favorite uh comment wins a free
pack of seeds from I redirect.sh
I'm going to make this question the
entire podcast that's all we're doing
this episode so my dude uh dcoms thank
you for the great question make sure you
check your inbox for that coupon code
for a free pack of seeds and everybody
else out there that sent questions
please do not feel discouraged if I did
not read your question on this episode
I've got a stack of wonderful questions
here in front of me I've got a stack of
subpar questions also over here keep the
questions coming because there are more
episodes coming maybe I will read your
question on the very next episode all
right ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps and hoes friends and foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
each and every one of you for listening
to another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast once again don't forget
about that pre-black Friday sale at
edirect dcom go check edirect dcom now
for current pricing and inventory also
join the mailing list on my website that
way when I put out new sales new drops
new updates sometimes I do release new
clones you will get an update you won't
miss any exclusive offers or deals
everything else you could possibly need
is on my website at IR genetics.com
there's a link to the Discord server
there's a link to iir there's a link to
patreon everything is at I genetics.com
if you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
fromy yourheart at hotmail.com don't be
shy if you've got some constructive
criticism I would love to hear from you
even if you've got hate mail don't be
shy I can handle it right I think that
is all I've got for you for this episode
I'll be back in a week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy Drew turps 420 and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug
[Music]
farming roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another Dam
grab your p and I go find the
back is in the lab sit back up relax
hold
up roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning out to hear the vibr that Jeff in
our conscious
tribe spreads the truth in every
word every voice must now be heard heing
light do cannot this go from your heart
your this rise up high up find your away
grow from your hearts every day in the
light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
do educate and Elevate join the Journey
Don't Be Late open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof r that
jef will guide you through in this
Godard and find the new rise up high up
Find Your Way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the
[Music]
song
o open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find a new rise up higher Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing song
[Music]
[Applause]