bless up family this is Natalie rise and
you are tuned to the highest frequency
the grow from your heart podcast with
rusted Jeff the grow from your heart
podcast Starts
Now Rost Jeff you bad mother
[Music]
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 860 of the
grow fromy heart podcast feels like a
milestone to hit 860 it kind of blew my
mind to say that number let's stay
focused at this part of the show welcome
it's time for episode 860 of the grow
from your heart podcast once again in
this episode we're going to give away
free seeds hang out you'll know we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in the podcast I do want to remind
you that the black Friday sale has begun
at idirect decom that's right make sure
you visit idirect dcom because the Black
Friday sale has begun make sure you go
check iir for the current pricing and
current inventory go grab what you can
because things are selling out very
quickly once again that is iy direct.com
uh somebody recently asked me a question
on YouTube they said are those free
seeds really free uh there are three
ways to win free seeds on this podcast
or three ways to acquire free seeds
uh the first way to acquire free seeds
is to send me a grow question on the
growel tab on my website I have a
website that website is I genetics.com
at the top there's a tab it says grow
help or grow questions click on that tab
send me a question if it's a good
question and I read it here on the show
I will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at edirect tocom that is
one way to win a free pack of seeds
another way to get a free pack of seeds
is every time you buy seeds at edirect
decom if you spend more than $ you get a
free pack of seeds if you spend $100 you
get another free pack of seeds those
seeds do stack those bonuses happen at$
30100 uh $200 and $300 so the more you
buy the more freebies you do get there
is a page at edirect that shows you all
of the freebies for your purchases those
have recently been updated by the way so
go check it out so those are two ways to
get freebies uh the third way to get
free seeds is to join the patreon server
that's right if you join the patreon
server at the right level every month
you will receive a coupon code for free
seeds if you join at the Right coupon
code level you will get a coupon code
for two packs of free seeds you'll get
two individual coupon codes each one
available for one pack of seeds just to
be clear it is two packs for the higher
subscription so that is three ways to
win free seeds now the question was do I
have to pay for shipping unfortunately
yes I do make you pay for shipping full
disclosure here you will have to pay the
$10 shipping fee uh but for free seeds
you've already got free seeds 10 bucks
in shipping shouldn't kill you uh I'm
trying to do you a favor you do me a
favor you cover the shipping we should
both be happy that way so there are
three ways to get those free seeds that
I talk about the first way send me a
good grow question and if I read it free
seeds the second one make a purchase at
I redirect if it's over $30 free seeds
the Third Way join the patreon server at
the right tier and guess what free seeds
all right we've covered the free seeds
portion of the podcast we've talked
about the discounted pricing and
inventory at I
redirect let's keep this show moving I'm
sorry to get choked up right at the
start of the show I'm not even going to
edit that out we're going to keep going
while we are flowing if you watched the
last episode that I put out that episode
was about upgrading your grow room
somebody sent me a wonderful question
about using items that were not grow
room specifically designed and using
them in our grow environments to uh
improve our grow to better our grow uh I
read a lot of good ideas on the podcast
and then I asked you guys for updates in
the comment section you guys did not let
me down the audience sent me a lot of
great updates in the YouTube comments so
I don't want to waste a l a lot of time
these items I'm about to talk about are
things that we should use or could
possibly or are recommended to use in
our grow spaces that are not
specifically growroom recommended I've
got a long list and I want to make a
short podcast so let me keep this rambly
energy going and we're going to jump
right into it before I do that please do
click like And subscribe I'll make that
part short the first thing that we
should have in our grow I don't know why
I didn't think about this cuz I walk
past mine every day I trip over the
little hose I Stumble over it all the
time it's always in the freaking way cuz
you always need it and then it needs to
be somewhere else real soon it never has
a real home but what I'm talking about
is the shop vac dude to have a shop vac
for the grow a wet dry vac a shop vac uh
that will help you a lot also if you
spill a lot of water and you don't have
that water Center I talked about get
yourself a good squeegee learn how to
squeegee water into um the little trash
can that you can flip over and then pick
it up you know what I'm talking about
cuz it may come right next to the
squeegee learn that technique so a shop
vac and squeegee and a bucket uh those
are things I definitely recommend also a
little small dirt devil or a dustbuster
those little plug-in uh little tiny
handheld vacuums you can charge it with
USB comes unplugged go clean the corners
of the grow space with that whoever sent
me that idea very good recommendation I
like that one a lot also when [ __ ]
builds up in the corners and you can't
shop back it out air duster that bad
[ __ ] blow some air into there move it
out of the corner then shop vac it or
sweep it if you can but sometimes I get
it there's plants in the way so that
little air duster that will help you out
got a hair right here my face tickling
me let's keep on moving air duster is a
good idea get the stuff out of the
corner also you can air dust off a lot
of your fans and blowers that [ __ ] does
need to be cleaned so the air duster
works great for that then shop fact that
[ __ ] off after you do that where are we
um a really simple idea that often gets
overlooked is using a pot as a riser if
you're plants are a little too short or
if one plant is shorter than the rest
you can flip another pot upside down
you've probably probably already got an
extra Nursery pot use that as a riser
for the plants that are too short also
another great recommendation that came
from the YouTube comments is a Big R
feed trough as a reservoir if you've got
a big batch of plants that you want a
lot of water for you don't want to spend
a lot of money some of those Big R feed
troughs will qualify as a reservoir you
do have to keep them clean if you're
growing on a budget anything will work
that is a great idea and there's
probably a Big R near you most places
have a big r or some sort of farm
tractor supply sort of thing uh that's
where you go get those sort of troughs
those the smaller the area the more
likely to have one of those to be honest
with you so if you don't have a grow
store around you that may be a good idea
also a journal I don't care if it's a a
paper Journal a digital Journal but I
recommend a way to keep notes I'm
apologizing once again for the throat
clearing I did of course take some dabs
before the podcast here but a journal
also a thing and a pen to go with the
journal another thing I recommend is a
dry erase board I've got a dry erase
board by my nutrients and I write down
what I fed last time I write down what I
sprayed last time I write on my ideas if
I think oh I should feed it this and
that plant in the back there's got a
nitrogen deficiency I should spray for
that I write all that down just to have
some sort of thought process because I'm
going to leave the gro I'm going to go
smoke I'm going to go do my normal day
I'm going to come back in 12 hours and
go what the [ __ ] was going on in here
having a little map a little note on a
dry erase board that definitely helps
you can buy a decently priced decently
sized TR a race board a lot of places in
town maybe at that big the same Big R
maybe at Costco uh maybe you got a
Target that's my favorite spot uh if you
got to go to Walmart there's one there
of course but a dry erase board is a
good idea also some Sharpies maybe you
want to label some [ __ ] you don't want
the label coming off of a Sharpie is
always a good idea um something that I
like are my name is stickers like if
you're going to a meeting you buy those
little tags that says hi my name is and
everyone just went Slim Shady if you're
my age you just said Slim Shady when I
said that but the stickers they say hi
my name is then you can put the name of
your plant on there and slap that on
your plant pot now you know which plant
you've got growing right there those
little tags are affordable very easy to
find a lot of other people will use
white duct tape for that you could write
the plant label on white duct tape slap
it on then somebody else recommended
using painters tape so you could just
peel that tape right off when you're
done reuse that pot not have any issues
all of those are quality ideas another
thing I'm going to recommend is a lot of
us right now it's winter time here in
Colorado when I fill my buckets with
water in some areas it's too cold I need
to put a I put an aquarium heater and
that 5 gallon bucket to heat up the
water to get it to temperature so if
your water is too cold an aquarium
heater may work if you're buy one of
those big RS by one of those big uh like
outdoor stores the farm store uh a horse
trough feed heater is basically the same
thing and it will do the same idea for
you it'll keep that water from freezing
from being so cold uh that way the hores
can drink also makes it warm enough for
your plants to be watered where am I I
see a lot of people recommending
homemade clone machines like a easy
cloner a turbo cloner there are many
ways to make those you can make it out
of a cooler out of a tote out of a
bucket lots of recommendations on how to
do that I'm sure you could find a lot of
ideas online but you can save a lot of
money by making your own Easy cloner and
they're awesome you still got to buy the
Clone collars if you have an alternative
to the collars send me your
recommendation I have a long list I'm
trying to go fast here you guys multiple
people recommended knee pads uh so knee
pads if you're down on your knees a lot
in the grow knee pads may be the thing
for you I don't get on my knees a lot
because it's hard for me to get back up
but knee pads are not for me they may be
for you how about velcro cord organizers
if you buy stuff from AC Infiniti a lot
of times it comes with a little bundle
of cord organizers those things are
awesome if you can get those also if you
don't want to use Excuse me once again
if you don't want to use the uh vcro
version they sell little they're
actually paper clips is what they are
but not the folded bent kind they're the
kind you squeeze them and it's like a
they're for putting legal documents
together it's more fancy than a
paperclip like a highgrade paperclip you
squeeze it it folds open you stick your
cords in there let it go and it will
secure all of your cords that is another
wonderful idea um also somebody
recommended condiment bottles like
little ketchup mustard bottles uh the
little squeezy kind for watering your
small seedlings that is a brilliant idea
I really like that idea that's a great
one uh somebody also recommended using a
dryer sheet to clean your scissors I
haven't tried that but I see visually
and understand how that will work you
got that coarse texture uh with the
dryer sheet stuff in there when you
start rubbing scissors it'll definitely
help remove the sticky the goo the resin
the junk that's a great freaking idea
also if you put those in your ducks and
your vents in your house it'll make it
smell fresh and the neighbors won't
smell the ganja as much if it's me
they're going to smell it anyway where
are we we got a a lot of other great
stuff to cover here several people
recommended using uh pool pH testing
strips instead of just a pH meter an
expensive meter they recommend a pool
testing strip uh for a backup that way
we could double check the accuracy of
our pH pen occasionally calibrate that
bad dog but then also once in a while
pull out the pool strips and see if they
match up because those things will
always be correct the battery can't die
they can't go out of gauge they can't go
out of uh what's it called calibration
they will always be right so use those
little drops to second guess or to
second check double check yourself I'm
going to clear my throat real hard not
going to edit this episode going to move
away from the mic excuse me then we'll
keep
going all right thank you for that
moment a couple people recommended Home
Depot racks or cheap shelfing for clone
uh storage and spaces I really like that
that's kind of what I do uh if you've
got a lot of clones in a commercial
facility you can line them up on those
racks put a light up there put more up
there hang a light from the top lots of
avail avability for space with those
small racks I'm trying to keep track of
where I am on these notes Here we are
plant ties and pipe cleaners a lot of
people were anti- zip tie when I said to
use zip ties people are like ah zip ties
are bad because you got to cut them off
uh when I put them there I want them
there semi- permanently I'm not worried
about cutting them off but you're
correct they do have to be cut off later
so people said to use like plant ties
little bread ties twisty ties and I
recommend a long time ago I was buying
those little pipe cleaners and using
those to tie down plants to just fasten
[ __ ] together they work for a lot of
things so anywhere you use a zip tie you
could use a plant Fastener or a pipe
cleaner that's a good idea then one big
recommendation that I can't believe I
skipped over was a paint sprayer that's
how I apply pesticides in a commercial
environment we bought a gry CO paint
sprayer it was about 400 bucks and I can
spray 100x 100 foot uh grow space in no
time get in there and douse every single
plant individually so a paint sprayer is
a good idea IDE this is a growroom
related device but I recently purchased
the small uh pump sprayer it's not I
thought it was a pump sprayer from AC
Infinity turns out it's electric uh
Boogie yogie yogie but I just push a
little button and my [ __ ] sprayer
sprays my plants for me I've got to
carry it around but how bougie how fancy
I did not realize it was electric until
I got to me but I got this new sprayer
from AC Infinity also uh probably by the
next episode I will have an announcement
for you with AC Infinity I don't want to
make any promises cuz I don't know how
long it will take for them to activate
my coupon code but I'm sure you see
where this is going by the next episode
or try it now uh who knows let's see go
to AC infinity and use coupon code iy uh
and you'll get 10% off your order by
using coupon code iy with our friends at
AC Infiniti that's the official
announcement right there I'll talk more
about it when I am certain that the code
works if it doesn't work be patient I'm
telling you it's a holiday weekend I
don't know if they've activated the code
yet but it's coming so stay tuned uh big
shout out to my friends at Infinity for
linking up with me uh where were we the
little
sprayer uh the little sprayer was great
the next recommendation I can't believe
I glazed over this in my last episode
little turkey pans you guys can buy
turkey pans well probably not right now
they're probably sold the [ __ ] out next
week turkey pans will be restocked you
can go get turkey pans they work good
for trim bins they work good for sorting
seeds and they work really good also for
underneath the pot if you overw waterer
you need a saucer want some more for the
water to go that bad [ __ ] right in a
turkey pan so you it's got multiple uses
once you use it for the drainage don't
trim weed into it again but you can trim
over it you can get seeds out of it very
useful device that cheap turkey pan I
talked a minute ago about the paint
sprayer uh how about a cheap deck
sprayer just a pump sprayer for your
pesticides you can get those on Amazon
you can get at all your Hardware shops
they are affordable I prefer the kind
with a pressure release valve once you
pump it up to get it real nice and tight
to spray uh now you've sprayed what you
need to you need to take off that top
and refill it or dump it out if you
don't have a pressure release when you
twist that [ __ ] off all the pressure
comes out of that one spot uh into your
eye inevitably so find the kind with the
pressure release that's what I highly
recommend I'm doing a lot of things very
highly today uh we got turkey pans on
the list twice I must have really meant
that um this one uh will sound weird at
the beginning but hear me out bro uh I
recommend some panty hose or nylon
stockings over the end of ducting um
that will help you keep out small bugs
it'll help you keep out debris leaves
whatever um I've got a duct that runs to
the outside over that is a piece of
panty hose it's actually about 6 in up
so that uh it doesn't get destroyed
right away but if anything was to go up
or in through that duct hopefully that
panty hose is a little bit of a barrier
it doesn't stop the air flow but it will
stop a spider hopefully maybe maybe
it'll deter a mouse I don't know but
it's a good idea put a little panty hose
on there it'll help you get some dust
knot in the grow space little prevention
will be good for you they do sell
expensive versions of that uh there are
actually carbon filters that can go on
the end of your ducting those are great
as well but I'm trying to tell you non
grow room related things and that is a
very grow room related device um in the
last episode I did mention that uh I
like to use a fire uh alarm a fire
device a smoke detector is the word I'm
[ __ ] stumbling over I like to have
one of those to let me know if there's a
fire but then I said it doesn't hook up
to my phone but then a lot of people
several people you freaking Tech genius
has reminded me that my wise cameras do
have a fire alarm detector that will
then notify me it'll say hey this
thing's been [ __ ] beeping something
is beeping it doesn't know exactly but
it will know you can set that in your
settings so go Tinker with your settings
uh your wise cameras will let you know
uh let me read the message it said Rost
to Jeff you mentioned phone
notifications for smoke detectors just
to let you know the wise camera has a
setting under sound detection to notify
you of smoke detector noises and it
works pretty good so that's a good
comment thank you I'm glad you mentioned
that I'm going to go Tinker with that
and make sure that works for me the next
thing I'm going to write down or that I
did write down is a mechanic crawler for
moving around heavy things it could be
uh I get the uh the big five gallon
bottle of Ruby from New Millennium and
that bad [ __ ] is heavy bro moving it
from one spot to the other with the
shitty handle on there I put that on the
mechanic crawler cart set it on there
push that bad [ __ ] right to where it
needs to be and then also you could put
a big plant on there if you need to move
it it's useful for a lot of things we
call it the skateboard around here
where's the skateboard uh where's the
stick I mean the mechanic crawler the
little four-way roller thing we move a
lot of [ __ ] with that something else we
need a staple gun bro I use a staple gun
for so many things uh if the white panda
film comes down tac tac tac just put
that bad [ __ ] back up I have made rooms
with the staple gun and Panda film uh it
looks like my bedroom is real fancy it's
ball built with panda film so yeah it's
really not that snazzy Panda film and a
staple gun will get you a long way and a
grow environment what do I mean by Panda
film that white poly film it's black on
one side white on the other that's why
they call it Panda um it's Panda black
and white and it's h you can get it in
different thicknesses like six mil is
probably the most common maybe three or
four you can use it as flooring you can
build walls with it it's really easy to
wipe down uh that white color is great
for a grow uh Panda film bro they just
got a [ __ ] free ad from me use that
[ __ ] in your grows it's way better than
myar myar sucks in my opinion we'll talk
more about that in the future uh did I
mention aquarium pumps for mixing teas
and for stirring your hydroponic tank if
you got a hydro tank with nutrients in
there you don't want them sitting still
go to the aquarium store get a fish tank
pump put that [ __ ] in there and point it
sideways it'll stir your [ __ ] Hydro
tank all day long for you there you go
big [ __ ] tips right there um where am
I where am I I missed I lost my spot oh
did I mention a heat and a VPD gun um I
like to use a heat gun to point at my
leaves and see what the leaf surface
temperature is uh not to be a shill but
our friends at AC Infinity cell a leaf
surface temperature and VPD gun that is
a great Christmas gift so go grab one of
those for yourself or your grower loved
one uh somebody else said a generator is
a good idea it's [ __ ] expensive but
yes if you can afford a generator
especially if you live in a low
populated area to be honest with you I
have a struggle with the word rural but
if you live in a rural area you may want
a generator if you live somewhere that
runs out of power uh frequently if the
power goes out if you got bad connection
if the snow comes and it's going to be
Buck cheeks cold a generator will help
out the whole house and help save the
grow space so get a generator somebody
else recommended also a tape measure why
didn't I think of that bro a real tape
measure we're measuring a lot of [ __ ] in
the grow how much Panda film do I need
to cut how far apart of the lights how
far from the canopy to the lights uh are
as much space is in there lots of [ __ ]
very useful with a tape measure my
grandpa said measure so a tape measure U
but get a tape measure a good one um you
can construction guys out there argue in
the comments uh what the good brand is
I'm not a construction dude but I know
we're not supposed to buy Milwaukee so
link us up let us know what to do um
another very important thing to think
about um this is very important I can't
believe I didn't mention this a first
aid kit I don't want [ __ ] to go wrong in
your grow I really don't but I have a
first aid kit what if you cut yourself
what if I don't want I'm not even going
to you know what could go wrong a lot of
[ __ ] could go terrible have a first aid
kit uh Burns scrapes Cuts bruises
ouchies be prepared for all of it
another thing you may want is an eyewash
station uh just a squeezy eyewash thing
to get fluid into your eyes and get um
[ __ ] whatever you're spraying I don't
even know what [ __ ] I was going to
say a bloom booster but I didn't want to
go with a specific product but get the
the bloom boosters when you're mixing
and you splashed it get that [ __ ] out of
your eye with a little eye rent station
here's another thing that is just a
random OG piece of advice I have a
friend who lived in a non-legal State
and allegedly he was cultiva ating
cannabis one day he dropped something
and it splashed into into his eyeballs
he was unable to call 911 for help
because he was growing weed in an
illegal environment he basically had to
call Emergency Services to his house to
come help him what he did was he used
Siri I don't want to say what he did
because I've got Siri on my phone I
don't want it to happen he told Siri to
call his wife and Siri called his wife
and he just yelled into the phone babe
come home help me and finally she caught
on cuz she couldn't hear him the phone
was over there he had to yell until she
[ __ ] caught on she came home and
helped him out but have a plan like that
put somebody's name in your phone that
you can call and trust and have a plan
with them say hey bro I got you in my
phone as like [ __ ] emergency number
two so that if something goes wrong I
can call you and you can come to my
house maybe leave a key somewhere give
the homie a key maybe I have a backup
key so they don't have to kick in the
[ __ ] door have a strategy I don't
want anything to go wrong but strategy
is thinking about it planning for it now
is way better than going I got PH down
in my eye what do I do looking for your
phone being [ __ ] blind stumbling over
just tell Siri to call your friend that
you need to help you and Siri will do
that for you and it could save you a
whole lot of headaches um where are we
all right that was a piece of OG advice
my phone really keeps trying to do all
the stuff that I was telling Siri to do
I had to turn it off a couple times
sorry for the quick glitchy edit there
um all right I think I've covered all of
the super important things on the
updated list of really uh good ideas of
things to have in your grow space and
things that can make growing better and
easier year I've got one more thing that
I found very entertaining a lot of you
will laugh at this a lot of you think
that it's really funny a lot of you
especially if you've ever worked in a
commercial cultivation facility we know
how freaking serious this one is how
about a coffee maker bro I don't drink
coffee I'm not a coffee guy it makes me
a spaz I've already got this energy
after 22 dabs you don't want to see me
drink coffee but I worked with a bunch
of dudes and uh the night before we
would leave they would brew a pot of
coffee and let that [ __ ] sit overnight
and then use that as the water for the
next pot of coffee because they could
not get enough caffeine and enough
coffee coffee coffee uh but they kicked
ass all day at work for it so some of
you folks out there may need that coffee
maker uh whatever kind of coffee maker
it is do your thing pimping get that
[ __ ] right outside to grow get it set up
so that you can have the energy that you
do need um I think I've covered all of
the things that I wanted to add to that
list I hope you guys had as much fun as
I did on this episode um if you have any
questions Corrections comments concerns
please do send me an email the email
address is grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy I'd love to
hear your input if you want to tell me
about more things that could go on this
list do it on this episode or the
previous episode if you do it on the
previous episode episode 859 I do have a
contest going my favorite comment on
that thread will win a free pack of
seeds at IR
redirect.sh episode uh maybe I'll do it
for this episode too [ __ ] it both
episodes favorite comment free seeds
what have I got to lose a pack of seeds
that's all bro so both episodes uh best
comment free seeds start leaving
comments now you guys I do appreciate it
I think that's all I've got for you for
this episode don't forget about that
Black Friday sale at edirect do.com uh
uh be good to one another I know I talk
a lot of stuff about growing cannabis I
talk a lot of things but let's also
remind each other to be grateful have
gratitude and be [ __ ] good to one
another uh we're all people we all
struggle we all got [ __ ] to do uh [ __ ]
to deal with uh [ __ ] be good support
each other love one another all right
ladies and gentlemen that's all I've got
for you for this episode I'll be back in
a week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy purple
skunk and until next time take a fat dab
and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another day
grab your P the
back in the lab sit back them
relax roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we grow tning
out to hear the vi that Jeff in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every
word every voice must now be heard
healing light to canis for from your
heart your this rise up higher Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a dog educate and Elevate
join the journey won't be late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof RF will guide you through in
this GED find the new rise up high now
find your way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the song
[Music]
open the minds to see the truth in the
soil lies the proof rer Jeff will guide
you through in this Garden find the you
rise up high up Find Your Way brow from
your heart every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the song
[Music]
[Applause]