hey everybody this is Doug bensson and
you're listening to the grow from your
heart podcast hosted by my buddy roster
[Music]
Jeff Rost Jeff you bad mother
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode
861 of the grow from your heart podcast
in today's episode I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in the
podcast before we get too far I do want
to let you know that the holiday sale
has begun at idirect decom that's right
check for new stock and reduced pricing
at air.com whichever holiday you
celebrate here in December we are
celebrating as well at IR
redirect.sh outs I want to give a couple
of shout outs to a few great folks who
support the show on patreon let's send a
big fist bump and a thank you shout out
to my friend Jerome I want to send a
thank you shout out to Austin Ron and a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my buddy War posum big
thanks for all of the patreon support if
you want to support the show on patreon
all you have to do is visit w ww.
patreon.com fromy yourheart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen once again thank you for
all of that patreon support ladies and
gentlemen in the last episode in the
last two episodes we have been talking
about growroom improvements and things
we can add to our growroom that weren't
necessarily designed for growroom
purposes there were a lot of great I had
a lot of great ideas and then the
audience did contribute a lot of great
submissions a lot of great ideas I have
another sub Mission here of something we
overlooked something we should have
thought of as we were working on our
grow room supplies list this is a very
useful idea very good suggestion
somebody said that we can use a gallon
Ziploc bag over a uh clone and a cup as
a clone Dome so if you want to take one
clone you can fill that clone that beer
cup up with uh dirt you can moisten that
dirt cut your clone dip it in rooting
gel put it into that dirt and then use a
baggie a gallon baggie over that as your
clone Dome that will work very well that
is a very good idea
I can't believe I did not think of that
also I've seen people use a lot of those
boxes from The Container Store as their
own clone uh device their own clone
environment so you can get a plastic bin
from The Container Store flip it upside
down put the Clone plugs on the bottom
part there uh do all your work and then
just put that bin right on top of that
that works as your clone environment
can't believe I did not think of that so
great update there use a Ziploc baggie
over a Solo Cup when sprouting clones
and this person said seeds I don't
recommend putting anything over the
seedling I like to leave them exposed
because it does make a weak seedling if
you put a dome over that but for a clone
that is a wonderful idea ladies and
gentlemen if you have more ideas on how
to uh improve our grow room our growroom
experience with products we can buy not
necessarily from the grow store because
all those prices all those products are
overpriced uh send me some ideas let me
know uh put it in either you can put it
in this episode in the comments or the
two previous episodes and my favorite
comment from each episode will win a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
idirect decom uh keep in mind I have not
given a deadline for those once the
comments get stale uh then I will choose
my favorite and we will give some free
packs of seeds all right let's stay on
track here I do have a bunch of great
questions here in front of me I do have
a website that main website is iry
genetics.com that's where almost
everything is hosted there's a link to
the Discord server uh the patreon link
is there and there is a link on the top
that says grow help or grow questions if
you click on that tab it's over to the
right is why point this way every time
it's over to that part of the screen if
you click on that tab it does give you
the opportunity to send me a grow
question if you send me a good grow
question and I read that question here
on the podcast I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at I
direct.com today's question came from
somebody that is called Hobbit from the
family Shire shout out to my new friend
the other Hobbit from the family Shire
we've already got another friend named
Hobbit shout out to that dude as well uh
family Shire Hobbit make sure you check
your inbox because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
decom this is a really good question
I've uh I talk about this I've addressed
this a lot it is a very good time to
address this on the podcast once again
it says if I had a grow we're off to a
good start and one plant got stressed
and made male flowers so your female
plant got stressed and produced male
flowers that is now an interex plant it
is not a male it's not a female that
plant showed you both sexes it is now
determined to be an interex plant it has
proven that to us now it says um perhaps
this uh interex plant pollinated some of
the other plants that's very likely that
does happen it says will the seeds be
female and will they produce Herms it's
really hard to predict what may happen
you do not have feminized seeds you did
not do anything to those seeds to make
them feminized so they are not all going
to be female uh there's no guarantee
they will all be female uh you're likely
to get female seeds out of there you're
also likely to get intersect seeds out
of there to expect these seeds to be all
female or feminized you would have had
to have done something to them to be
feminized um the plant that the pollen
came from was not a true female that
plant was interex you have now
technically bred with an interex plant
to another female plant which possibly
could be interex as well that's a whole
another conversation uh maybe that one
hasn't expressed its interex traits yet
but we know one plant was an interex
plant so it doesn't have two x's it has
an X and a y floating around somewhere
giving it that interx expression the
other plant possibly could be a female
it received pollen now we've got female
and interex genes in there and that's
all in our plant mix we could get more
females we could get more intersex
plants you could possibly even pull a
male out of this we don't know what that
uh plant that uh showed its interx
expression we don't know what it passed
on we don't know what it did to the mix
so to think that they would all be
feminized would not be accurate thinking
uh you're likely to get females but pay
very close attention to them all the way
through the flowering phase because at
any time they could show you that
they've got that intersec trait it could
be week one it could be week nine uh you
never know but they could be intersect
so keep an eye on that so the first part
of the question was will they all be
females that part is unlikely nothing
was done to feminize the seeds when I
make feminized seeds there's a process I
am doing something very specifically to
make those seeds be female I am
feminizing them making feminize seeds
this was nothing was done here for the
feminization of these seeds the next
part of the question is will they
produce Herms uh that is quite possible
because they've got Herm traits in them
um if you think about breeding if you
think about genetics if you take a
person with blue eyes and a person with
blonde hair and a person with brown eyes
and brown hair and you breed them
together that blue eyes and blonde hair
will pop up in The Offspring The Blue
Eyes the whatever the [ __ ] I said in the
mixes you will see those combos pop up
within the offspring that Herm trait
that you bred with with is a possibility
that will pop up in The Offspring just
like any other breeding trait I think
intersect is a trait that could be
passed down so the main questions was
will they be females uh some will
possibly interx who knows what else you
got will they produce Herms quite
possibly yes also keep this in mind I
would grow some of these uh you grow
them don't share them don't pass them
out don't give them to any friends
definitely don't sell them but you grow
them and see what you've created maybe
just maybe you've got some new amazing
hot fire maybe you've created some
amazing [ __ ] on accident all of the chem
dog stuff came from bag seed which means
somebody bought weed that had seeds in
it and they grew those seeds and found
amazing fire that's essentially what
you've got is bag seed in the long run
you're going to have buds with seeds in
it you're going to pull those seeds out
you're going to grow them and you may
find that you've got some amazing [ __ ]
also you could find you've got a whole
bunch of trashy mutant intersex plants
so the only way to find out is to grow
them uh grow them yourself like I said
don't share them don't trade them don't
give them away don't uh dilute and
pollute the genan pool with them until
you've grown them tested them and
verified them yourself and had fun with
them uh I just said have fun with them
that of course is the most important
part have fun as long as you're being
ethical you're not lying to anybody
you're not messing up anybody's Garden
you're not stealing money from anybody
have a good time in the garden do what
makes you happy uh grow from your heart
breed with love and enjoy the experience
don't make it stressful and uh yeah have
fun that's the most important part if
it's not fun then what is it all right
that was a really good question got me
rambling quite well uh my dude Hobbit
from the Shire once again check your
inbox because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds from iy
direct.com all right let's keep this
momentum moving I do have another
question here in front of me this one is
from somebody who called themselves my
plants talk back um bro if you listen
they are talking just pay attention to
what they're saying and they will tell
you exactly what they need big shout out
to my new friend my plants talk back my
dude make sure you check your inbox and
check your spam cuz you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from my
favorite website edirect Doom let's jump
into the question it says hey I love the
show hey thank you for listening it goes
on it says I need more help I like that
I'm here for you it says what was the
latest in flower you have had a
successful reversal so they're talking
about reversing a female a female plant
to uh create anthers to use that pollen
to create feminized seeds
um how what is the latest into flow
you've had successful is two weeks into
flow two fing late yeah bro you are way
too effing late um I had a weather issue
had to go shut down um and I put
everything into flower and now I have a
banger of a plant um yeah bro you're too
late when it comes to reversing um I
recommend starting a week before the
flowering phase with your sprays or
starting the day of flour if not that
plant will be so far into flow you won't
be able to reverse the hormones before
it's just done then it won't create any
anthers then you won't get any pollen um
also if your females are two weeks into
flour like the plants that will receive
the pollen you're way [ __ ] out of luck
bro cuz that then they're going to be
way too far done by the time your pollen
donor creates pollen they'll be dried up
all the pistols will be done uh they
will not be able to receive pollen they
will not create any seeds for you so I
hate to say it but it sounds like you
might be [ __ ] out of luck for reversing
this plant there may be ways to do it
there are new products out there I
wouldn't do it with silver tho sulfate
it will not work on time what I would
probably do is I would get a clone of
this even if it's in flour uh take a
couple of clones and rev that clone you
can put it in a clone Dome you can put
it in an easy cloner I'd probably do the
easy cloner uh put a little bit of
nitrogen feed in there along with the
yellow clonex uh the juice that clonex
sells you the yellow stuff dip it in the
purple fill the clone machine with the
yellow stuff an EC of 1.0 and a pH of
like you could do 62 is probably where
I'd recommend right now do 2 I'm not
looking in my notes so I don't remember
the exact what I would say but 62 would
be a good uh pH for that so you're 1.0
EC 62 then add a little bit of Base
nutrients in there just to give you that
nitrogen just to speed up that reveg
process then put that bad [ __ ] under 24
hours of light if you can maybe 18 hours
if that's all you could do but rev that
bad [ __ ] put some clones under light
and rev them then you can get that
genetic that cultivar back you won't
lose it or simply finish out the Harvest
and rev the plant that you are growing
now now I don't know what the best
option is for you but you can definitely
however far into flower you are with a
plant you can cut a clone and you can
rev that bad [ __ ] and you can save
those genetics or you can let it finish
and then you can rev it we'll do a quick
rev chat right now not going to go too
far Harvest time comes right cut off all
the top parts of the plants at the
bottom here you got a couple of buds the
size of my thumb you got a branch coming
up a branch coming up leave some buds
like about the size of my thumb leave
leaves on that bud uh leave leaves on
the bu I mean to say that word twice you
want foliage on there because that's
what is going to receive the light
that's where the hormones will develop
that is what is going to make that bud
rev itself so leave some foliage on a
bud you got two or three three or five
little bottom buds on a plant leave some
leaves on there let the [ __ ] light
get to those leaves give them 18 hours
24 hours if you can uh if that plant is
root bound put it into a bigger pot
it'll happily uh speed up your process
if you put that root bound pot plant
into a larger pot let the root spread uh
some plants will just flower simply
because they are too tightly root bound
so give it some legs give it some room
to spread uh have just a few bottoms
there then put it under the 186 or 24
hours of light then you'll see in about
it'll take a while it's going to take
you two three maybe four weeks you'll
start getting new growth coming out of
the top of that bud stuff will just
start coming out of the top of there
it's going to look wonky and twisted and
Whirled and it's going to look like it's
really sad but it's going to work out of
that just give it some time it'll keep
growing it'll grow it'll work itself out
of that weird Twisted [ __ ] and then one
day it'll just spit out a perfect little
Shute that looks like a little clone let
that grow let that happen till you got
two or three of those so you can [ __ ]
around and find out then take one of
those clones two of those little shoots
that it's spitting and clone those I
know that sounds wild but put that in a
cloner and get those to root now use
those new shoots that you've just cloned
as your new mother plants that's your
new mother plant let that grow out now
you've got that cultivar secured you can
cut clones from there uh feed that plant
a basic veg like you would your mom's
maybe boost up the nitrogen a little bit
um and that's the quick version of rev I
hope I covered all that because that was
spontaneous I did not have any notes
there I just decided that I would tell
you that now uh rev is pretty easy you
just got to be patient that's really all
it takes lights and patient give it
plenty of light uh give it a bigger pot
and give it some patience and it will it
will reveg on you so I think you're too
late with your reversal to be honest
with you I hate to bust your bubble but
I did give you some backup plans a
couple of different options cut some
clones uh get those clones reved or
simply rev that big old Mama plant that
you're working with or suck it up
because you got a free pack of seeds
coming from edirect decom and you can
just grow those my dude uh make sure you
check the spam folder and once again
thank you for the great question all
right I've got some good momentum here
let's keep rolling I've got another
question here in front of me I've got a
couple of questions this one is the one
that I wanted to get to all right this
one's been cooking for a little while
this one came from somebody who wants to
be called ham biscuit ladies and
gentlemen big shout out to my friend ham
biscuit if you want your question right
here on the podcast uh go to the iy
genetics website iy genetics.com on the
top of that website there's a row of
tabs one does say grow help click on
that grow help tab send me your question
if I read your question guess what free
seeds ham biscuits question goes like
this it says from the time a seed breaks
the dirt when do you start to feed that
is a really good question um when I see
my friend this um Let me give a
disclaimer if you you put your plant
into soil that's got um High nitrogen or
a lot of nutrients in that soil like
some amended soil or a store-bought
soilless mix that's got that brags about
having its listed to have an NPK value
sometimes those plants can go for a
little while without being fed that is
up to you if you want to Turbo feed that
plant if you want to let that plant live
off of what's in that soil some of those
soilless mixes claim to be good for 2 to
four weeks some say 6 weeks um I don't
ever let them go that long without
feeding in that soiless mix but but
before we go too far keep in mind that
some of your soil soilless mixes will be
preed and that's got to come into play
you've got to adjust that to my response
here but usually within the first two to
three weeks when I see the first true
leaves pop up um then I pay attention
then I'll probably feed right when I see
those first leaves spread out sometimes
I'll wait for the second set if it's in
like a hot soil then I'll just pay
attention to the plant the first sign of
yellowing then it will get fed but it's
usually the first two or three weeks uh
all mix up a nitrogen a basic base feed
sometimes I'll feed it a bean sauce give
it a little bit of microbes a little bit
of phosphorus a little bit of potassium
just to get that little tiny plant
growing a little bit more quickly uh but
that's all just uh that's Advanced
growing stuff if you're asking this wait
two to three weeks depending on the soil
or soiless mix what you are playing with
then we got a follow-up question do you
plant directly into your soil or medium
no I do a uh paper towel germination
sort of thing um sometimes I float the
seeds in water for 12 to 24 hours before
most of the time I do not do that um I
fold up a paper towel into a square and
I soak it with water and I put it on a
plate and I tip it to where the excess
water runs off unfold it put some seeds
in there fold it back up and then I put
that in a warm dry dark place and
usually within 24 hours my seeds sprout
then I put them in a usually a beer cup
honestly I use a Solo Cup uh just like a
party cup that you use to play flippy
cup or beer pong um shout out to all the
flippy cup gang you know who I'm talking
about um I fill that cup with soil
soilless mix Pat it down then I water it
before I even put my seedling into there
water it then I put just a little
indention all just just about a knuckle
deep is all I really go Bo just a little
press put my seiling in there and then
just gently press dirt right on top of
it and then just press that under or put
that under the light usually under a
small LED or a T5 uh give it 186 maybe
24 hours of light usually 186 for the
seedlings uh but that's uh the quickest
germination into a cut method I can
teach you right there there let me stay
focused you didn't even ask about that
part the question does go on it says the
reason I ask is because I have used
several methods successfully but I do
get more helmet heads with the paper
towel method I flipped my Golden Goat to
1212 this past Sunday and it's looking
super happy uh bro congrats on Flipping
The Golden Goat I hope to see those
photos um so he's talking about helmet
head let me describe what helmet head
even is here uh on the podcast before we
talk too much about it helmet head let's
talk about helmet head a little bit here
a lot of times when you plant a seed it
will pop up through the soil or the soil
is mix when it pops up a lot of times it
should have two little miniature leaves
that want to spread open and get life
started a lot of times the seed will get
stuck on one of those little parts and
it will not spread properly and a lot of
people really freak out they have a lot
of panic attack about that um there is a
little bit of debate on what causes that
some people will tell you that you're
planting the seed too deep and some
people will tell you you're not planting
the seed deep enough so there's a couple
of uh School of thought I want you guys
in the comment section please leave me
your opinion uh your bro science your
real science your edicated uh factual
input on why we're getting helmet head
when we plant our seeds what is the main
cause of that how can we prevent it um
some people will tell you it's too deep
some people will tell you it's too
shallow I am not certain uh I'm going to
leave it up to the comment section what
I can tell you is it's real easy to
remove it is very simple to remove that
helmet head um I've seen a couple of
different methods somebody told me a
real fun method of it the other day
which we'll talk about so what I like to
do I get a spray bottle with just plain
water in it and I will get real close
and just spray that ceiling just just
spray it real good kind of aggressively
to be honest put some Mist into it then
what I'm trying to do is moisten that
helmet head to soften the helmet and
also add some lubrication between that
leaf and the seed shell so that I can
get some tweezers and just lightly pluck
that helmet head right off of there
don't pull hard enough to where you're
lifting up the seed and yanking it all
the way out of the dirt you don't want
to do that gently remove it just
scientifically surgically get in there
just real gently spray it with water and
pull it off of there another method that
a friend recently told me that they do
they spray it with water but then they
do the backwards version of what I do
they take the tweezers and put it inside
the seed shell and let the tweezers open
on their own because the tweezers will
automatically pop open once their
default is open and they will pop that
seed shell open far enough and then the
seed shell will just fall off so that's
a couple of different ways to deal with
helmet head but what I want is comments
you guys please let me know what is
causing the helmet head on my new and
our friends new freshly sprouted
seedlings my dude ham biscuit bro it's a
great name it makes me smile every time
I say it ham biscuit thank you for the
great question make sure you check your
inbox and your spam because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iy direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis and enthusiasts out
there we're going to wrap up a quick
episode of The Grow from your heart
podcast I want to thank you once again
for listening please do leave those
comments please do like and subscribe if
you found any value in this podcast like
And subscribe if you'd like to support
the show financially all you have to do
is visit
patreon.com fromy yourheart all of the
information you need will be right there
on the screen and once again big thanks
to everybody who does support the show
on patreon don't forget about the
holiday sale at idirect decom that's
right orange gasm is on sale go get
yourself a pack also it's giftgiving
season so don't forget about the gift
certificates available at idirect decom
that's right ladies if your partner is
playing this in front of you right now
they want you to hear the website
idirect decom and your partner wants a
gift certificate to iy direct.com so
they can go pick out their brand new
seeds so they can grow some great iy
genetics beans that's right ladies make
it easy on yourself iy direct.com get a
gift certificate let your partner pick
out the seeds that they want everybody
out there IR
redirect.sh Corrections comments or
concerns I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow fromy yourheart
hotmail.com don't be shy reach out let
me know what you think of the show
ladies and gentlemen that is all I've
got for this episode I'm going to go get
some water and some big old fat dabs I
hope you guys do the same I'll be back
in a week with fresh new content um I
want to give a big shout out to my
friend splooch and until next time take
a fat dab and give your Mama hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time take another D grab
your p in I the
back in the lab sit back
relax Roots
ands from the Ning seeds we grow tuning
now to hear the vi Ro that Jeff in our
conscious
tribe he spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard heing like
the canis go from your hul this rise up
higher Find Your Way grow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong join the movement sing the
song
natural medicine and love flows within
us like a do de your Cate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof RF will guide you through in
this goded find the new rise up high or
find your way go from your hearts every
day in the light We Stand real strong
join the movement sing the
[Music]
song open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof
R Jeff will guide you through in this
Garden find a new rise up higher Find
Your Way Blow from your hearts every day
in the light We Stand real strong strong
join the movement sing the song
ooh ooh
[Applause]
[Music]