[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the podcast everybody I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 863
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got another fun episode lined
up for us in today's show I'm going to
give away free seeds hang out we'll talk
more about those free seeds later on in
the show before we jump into the
question and answer portion I do want to
send a couple of shoutouts to a few of
the great folks who support the show on
patreon that's right let's kick it off
with the big grow fromy heart podcast
thank you shout out to my friend mad
Chad listen to Big thank you shout out
and a fist bump to good vibe turps and
let's wrap it all up with a big grow
from your heart podcast thank shout out
to Frogman 420 big thanks and big shout
to everybody who supports the show on
patreon if you are not already
supporting the show and you would like
to learn how to do so all you have to do
is visit
www.patreon.com
from your heart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen once again big thanks to everyone
who supports the podcast all right now
let's work our way into the question and
answer portion of the show lately
Autoflower seeds have been a big topic
online on social media in the grow
Community I've been getting a lot of
questions about autof flowers I've
actually been getting a lot of requests
for autoflowers that's right people are
asking me to breed make and sell
Autoflower seeds uh people have asked me
why I don't do that and today we are
going to briefly address why I don't I
don't [ __ ] with autoflowers it is that
simple we'll talk about why before we do
that let's talk about what are autof
flowers um all of the seeds that I make
every seed you buy from I genetics
whether it's a femin seed or a regular
seed all of those seeds will be photo
period seeds which means they flower
based on the amount of light hours which
they are given those seeds are going to
need 12 hours of uninterrupted Darkness
per day to initiate the flowering cycle
that is a photo period plant the absence
of light the short day that is what
tells that plant hey it is time for me
to flower that will initiate the
flowering phase those are the plants
that I make and I enjoy growing uh those
are the plants I appreciate I personally
do not enjoy uh growing or smoking
autoflow plants I'm not a hater um I'm
not just trying to bash these plants uh
I prefer a plant that I can veg the
amount of time that I want to veg that
plant I can pop it twist it defoliate it
lollipop it um I can do all the
manipulation that I need to it to fill
my canopy and grow the room to the
quality and uh quantity that I need with
an Autoflower plant I don't have that
option those plants are just going to
flower when they are ready I can't top
it I can't do as much manipulation
because it may stress that plant so the
autoflowers can't be topped uh you can't
dictate the amount of vegge time they
are going to flower when they are ready
uh so I don't prefer the Autoflower
plants uh mainly because I like the
first thing I like is the control I like
to be able to top the plant spread it
out veget as long as I need to fill my
space and flour when I'm ready autoflow
I cannot do that the other aspect of an
autoflow which I don't appreciate is if
I were to grow the most amazing fire
most potent tastiest trippiest best
[ __ ] plant I have ever grown with an
autof flower that's a one-time deal I
don't get to grow that again because
it's an auto I did not take clone I did
not take a clone because you cannot take
clones from an autoflowering plant that
clone will be the same age as the rest
of the plant so let's say you've got a
plant and this is a concept that counts
to all plants but just think about this
as autof flowers you've got a mother
plant you take a clone from it that
clone is technically the same age as the
plant which that clone came from if it
came from a photo period or an
Autoflower that clone is the age of the
plant that it derived from so if your
plant's been growing for 6 months those
hormones are moved around in the plant
that clone is also 6 months old even if
you just cut it today so when you cut
that Autoflower clone those hormones
within that clone have already told that
plant it is almost time to go into flow
and it will go into flow before it roots
or very shortly after and you'll have a
little tiny Autoflower clone that just
flowered on you you won't even get to
keep it so the main aspect is I like the
control contr maybe I'm a control freak
maybe I've got some OCD but I like to be
able to veg as long as I need to veg to
fill that grow space I also like to be
able to take a clone for repeatable
results so I said we were going to talk
about what an autoflow is I segwayed
right on into telling you why I don't
make them I don't like that I cannot veg
them as long as I want I cannot fill my
canopy I cannot fill the trellis I can't
fill the whole tent and I need to fill
the whole Space if I'm growing what's
the point in just filling a portion of
my grow space I want to fill it up I'm
using the I'm using the energy let's use
the space and fill it up um I kind of
use the analogy of I am not a country
music fan if you like country music
enjoy it I'm not talking [ __ ] I'm
telling you what I enjoy um I am not a
big fan of country music I know what it
sounds like I can play it on the drums
I've heard it but I'm not a big country
music fan I am a ree fan I love ree
music I love Jamrock music I love rock
and roll type music um if you put me on
the drums and you said let's play ree
that [ __ ] is gonna sound good because
I've got Reay feel I enjoy Reay I
understand Reay I've uh researched and
understood and felt the feeling of Reay
drums I know how to do that you would
think it's a Raye drummer playing on
that track if you had me play country
music it would sound good but it
wouldn't sound like it could If you
hired a Nashville uh Tennessee type of
country drummer a session Studio country
guy to come in and do that it would be
much it would be much better because he
feels country he understands that Nuance
of country music he's in that [ __ ] I'm
not in Autoflower I don't enjoy it I
don't like growing it uh to the best of
my knowledge I don't like smoking it
however now everything is concentrates
you could possibly possibly give me some
concentrates made from autoflowers and I
wouldn't know the difference because
it's concentrates it's not Autos I may
enjoy that I wouldn't know the
difference right now it may be happening
I don't even know so to the best of my
knowledge I don't enjoy smoking or
growing Autoflower plants which means I
would not enjoy breeding them because
there's no passion there uh when I think
about breeding plants it's usually I'm
in a grow and I see a plant and I love
the way that it grows and I see it a few
times I watch it develop and I go that
plant right there that's got something
to it or I smell a jar or I smoke
something or something about one plant
or two plants just tells me some Bells
some buzzers go off with Autoflower
plants I don't get those buzzers there's
no there's no passion for the Autoflower
they just don't they simply do not get
my attention it's just not attractive to
me so to compare that to music to Loop
that back around to music uh that would
be like me just playing country music I
could do it but there would be no
passion there would be no feel uh we'll
leave the playing the country music to
people who enjoy the country music it'll
sound good it'll come out better that's
exactly how I feel about the autoflow
plants we'll let people with more
passion uh grow those autoflow plants
breed those there are plenty of people
out there doing it shout out to my buddy
Daz killing it with the Autoflower
plants um also my company uh the Company
motto is grow from your heart and breed
with love um if I were breeding
Autoflower plants it would it would not
be love I appreciate that you guys want
them but I'm not in love so it would
just be just PA and chucking it would it
would just be honestly it' be a money
grab and that's not what this is about
this has never been a money grab for me
this is always been growing from my
heart and breeding with love which is
what I do and I think that's a lot of
why I am successful that's a lot of why
uh why your favorite musician is
successful is because uh they put music
out that they loved the the music came
from their heart it came from their soul
it took them a long time to make that
music they put it out and it's [ __ ]
good because they did what they love
they weren't worried about will you like
it we hope you guys like our product but
if you don't that's fine as long as I
love my breeding project that's really
what matters as long as a musician loves
the album that they put out that's
really what matters but when you do
something with passion like that and
you're not worried about marketability
finances sales numbers charts when you
do something from your heart from your
soul and this could be anything be
cooking it could be sewing whatever
you're into whatever craft you're doing
from your heart that will show and the
clientele is there if you do it from
your heart don't do it for clientele the
clientele will buy your passion if you
do it with passion uh if it's painting
drawing stitching whatever or whatever
you do um there's a million different
Arts out there and I encourage everybody
to find your Niche but if you do it with
passion if you do it with love and you
don't adjust that art for the market you
will find your audience the audience
will see that and you'll put out a
better prodct product uh if I were to
adjust my breeding uh adjust my music
for the audience it would suck um I
don't want to make commercially
acceptable products or music uh that's
not what I'm trying to do um so let's
talk about now how uh client or artist
or crowd influence comes into play with
this let's talk about your favorite
musician uh remember that first album
they made it was pretty good that second
album it was good the third one it
sucked because they weren't struggling
anymore uh they weren't struggling
musicians they weren't sleeping on the
couch they weren't living in the tour
van uh they were being handed a bunch of
money and then they were forced to make
a product on a deadline and that wasn't
done with passion they didn't record
from their heart uh they recorded
because the [ __ ] record company has a
deadline and we got to make this money
and get these songs out and you can tell
by that third that fourth album All That
passion went away because they forgot
they're they're not growing from their
heart they're not breeding with love
they're making autof flowers to fill a
contract and that's not what I'm trying
to do that's not what I'm here for uh
that's never what this was about I
started off
uh I started off as a consumer I was a
smoker um and then I started growing and
then I got into the medical marijuana
field and when I saw what I was doing
for medical marijuana patients and
clients it changed my outlook on this um
I used to sell black market cannabis
that was how I survived but once I got
into the medical field uh the medical
marijuana side of things and I saw how a
product that I took my time to cultivate
I grew these plants I grew them I
harvested them trimmed them dried them
and cured them and then I had people
come to my dispensary and they would be
brand new there would be little old
ladies that have never smoked weed would
come to this dispensary looking for
Relief and they wouldn't have any clue
what to do so I'd give them three or
four different kinds of bud just say
here's an Indica here's a sativa here's
a hybrid and then here's just something
else just to try and I would give them a
gram of each or pre-roll of each and I
would label it and I would tell them go
home and smoke these on a different day
and figure out what works the best for
you take a couple of rips find out come
back we will work on your medical
marijuana needs and we'll get you dialed
in together uh there was a little old
lady that came in she walked on a one of
the Walkers like the the the one that
goes in front it's got the tennis balls
on it you know what I'm talking about
she was hunched over she looked
unhealthy she didn't feel happy when he
spoke to her she seemed in pain and
miserable and nearly desperate after a
few weeks of coming to my dispensary she
was smoking a product that she had found
helped her her hunch went away her smile
came back her overall health was
improving and her quality of life and
her level of enjoyment of life was
improving moving so that's just one
person out of hundreds of people I got
to see at my dispensary that changed
everything when I saw that sort of stuff
like people coming in and the two or
three minute interaction we would have
just selling them their medicine and the
recommendations I could make and the
plants they were consuming was changing
their life it was improving the quality
of their life and that that changed my
entire Outlook my Approach my everything
to this plant um if you would have asked
me to make autof flowers before that
experience I might have done it because
there's money there I would have said
[ __ ] I'm missing a money opportunity
there's money on the table let's make
these autos and get that part of the
market but uh seeing those clients and
those people it sparked uh empathy and
compassion and it changed my outlook and
it changed my approach to the entire
plant the entire business of cannabis
the entire passion of cannabis it
changed me a lot it changed me as a
person so uh those interactions with
those people at that dispensary um
really changes so this was never about a
money grab this was always maybe uh
maybe back in the day before I got into
the medical side when I was doing the
black market thing that was uh that was
for money but the seed company the
breeding that is never been a money grab
that's always been a lot of it was
because I was very frustrated with the
seeds I was buying I'd spend good money
on the website overseas I'm not even
going to talk about their name I'm not
going to praise them or bash them they
were overpriced and a lot of the seeds
that I bought sucked a lot of them came
crushed I would grow those seeds I'd
spend whatever you veg for four weeks
you flower for nine weeks it's [ __ ]
13 weeks and they would not be
satisfactory that's a lot of what got me
breeding I found a few things I did like
and I realized I can make seeds and I
started making my own seeds because I
wasn't satisfied with what was available
and then I started seeing what the stuff
I was breeding was doing for people and
that definitely inspired me sparked me
and pushed me so um wow that was a great
ramble whoever asked me about
autoflowers recently it's been a lot of
people ah thank you you guys uh I owe
you all a fist bump and a big high five
cuz you got me going on a very good
ramble about autof flowers all right
ladies and gentlemen this is going to be
a quick episode Christmas is coming this
week um so I'm going to get myself out
and do some Christmas shopping get
caught up uh don't hang out and listen
to podcasts all weekend go spend some
time with the family go spend some time
with the loved ones go share some love
uh sometimes the greatest gift you can
give is just time and be there be
present uh put your phone down spend
some time with some people because
Unfortunately they won't all be here
forever uh some of those people might
not be here next year the year after
that so love them while you can love the
people around you love yourself um I'm
freaking rambly so we're going to wrap
up this podcast ladies and gentlemen
thank you for listening to a quick
episode I hope everybody has a great
safe holiday out there um take good care
of yourself what else do I have for you
oh yeah uh make sure you check the
website IR
redirect.sh out to my buddy Eric Wright
and until next time take a fat dab and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] tell take another DB grab
your p in I the
back in the lab sit back relax hold
up roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning now to hear the vi that Jeff in
our conscious triy
it spreads the truth in every word every
voice must now be heard healing light to
canot this go from your heart your bliss
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a do educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof r that jef will guide you
through in this Garden find the new rise
up high and Find Your Way grow from your
hearts every day
in the light We Stand real strong join
the movement sing the
[Music]
song open the minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find the new rise up high up Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
[Music]
[Applause]