[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome back
podcast world I'm your host rosta Jeff
this is episode 864 four of the grow
fromy heart podcast you know I've got
another fun episode lined up for us in
today's show I'm going to give away free
seeds hang out we'll talk more about
those free seeds later on in the podcast
before we get too far I do want to send
a few shoutouts to a few of the great
folks who support the show on patreon
let's start off with the big grow fromy
heart podcast thank you shout out to
Dish Taco let's send a fist bump and a
thank you shout out to high hat and
let's wrap it up with the big grow from
your heart podcast thank you shout out
to my friend philong big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com
fromy yourheart all of the information
you need will be right there on the
screen once again big thanks and big
shout out to everybody who continues to
support the podcast all right let's jump
into the question and answer portion of
today's show I do have a website that
main website is iy genetics.com on that
website you will find a row of tabs at
the top there's a row of tabs one of
them says grow help or grow questions if
you click on that growel or grow
question tab send me a grow question if
I read your question here on the podcast
I will send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at idirect decom the first
question on today's show came from
somebody who wants to be called Ivan
yurin off Ivan this is a great question
make sure you check your box for a
coupon code CU you've got a code for a
free pack of seeds at edirect docomo
check your spam the question goes just
like this it says Hey Rasta Jeff I love
learning all about plant breeding from
your show and I appreciate all you do
for the community bro you are very
welcome thank you for the great uh
compliment there it says on several
occasions I have been successful in
reversing a female photo period using
collodial silver okay so this person is
uh using idal silver which is a common
practice to reverse plants to create
feminized pollen to make feminized seeds
uh it says uh they've been successful
doing it so they're off to a good start
it says my question is here's where we
get fun uh once the plant shows signs
that it has been reversed an example
it's starting to grow uh pollen sacks
would I then be able to cut clones and
grow these plants out as male plants to
be used for future breeding purposes if
so what would be the best time to take
clones from my new father plan all right
that's a very good question it makes a
lot of sense I understand exactly what
you're asking unfortunately it does not
work the way you are kind of hoping that
it is going to work so let me kind of
retrace this question here frame it in a
way that everybody is going to
understand um this person is taking a
female plant they are treating it with
colloidal silver that colloidal silver
will in turn there's a a chemical
process that happens inside the plant
we're not going to focus on that today
what happens is that causes that plant
to create pollen that pollen is all
female because hopefully they chose a
plant that is all female there are only
X chromosomes in there there will be a
lack of Y chromosomes when that pollen
is transferred to another female plant
that is all X chromosomes there's no Y
chromosome available in this breeding
project we will make all female seeds
that is what is supposed to happen here
this person is asking when they treat
this female plant that becomes the
pollen donor can they then cut clones of
that plant and treat that clone as if it
were a male plant so to speak a constant
pollen donating plant uh would that
trait continue would that process stay
permanent unfortunately uh no that is
not a permanent process uh that plant
eventually over time will uh grow out of
that chemical treatment that you've been
giving it it'll say hey all that
chemical spray is gone the Silver's not
coming in my copper is not disrupted I
don't have to [ __ ] with my ethylene
response uh I can start going back to a
normal female plant and growing female
again so if you cut that clone of that
reversed plant uh let it grow it will
take some time it's just like reving but
it will reveg and it will go back into
its female form this is why we've got to
spray the plants so many times when
we're using uh colloidal silver silver
tho sulfate um you've got to spray them
that week before and then uh I do it
every 3 days for seven or eight
sometimes 9 or 10 times I keep going
depending on um so if it's like a 9 or
10 week plant I just spray it up to day
21 if it's an 11 or 12 week plant any
further than that I will spray it like
um up to day 24 27 maybe even day 30
because I needed to continue uh to stay
uh reversed for longer and it may uh it
may decide to go back to its original
female form if I don't keep treating it
with that silver product so um your idea
is awesome it's a really good idea I
wish it worked that way it would save me
uh time money space effort energy a lot
of headaches a lot of heartaches a lot
of questions a lot of concerns a lot of
stress but uh it does not work that way
unfortunately that female will find its
way back to female uh you're just giving
it uh you're just giving it a chemical
that's confusing the plant it's going
hey I'm not sure what to do so this is
how I'm acting now uh once you put that
plant back in its normal condition quit
giving it that chemical uh that that
silver disappears uh grows out of that
all that hormonal disrupt uh disruption
uh goes back into balance sorry I'm
thinking as I'm speaking I'm trying to
have nine thoughts ahead of myself once
all that hormonal imbalance is
rebalanced then the plant will just be
your normal female plant once again just
like it was when you started so I think
I answered that one pretty good if uh if
we cut clones and grow them out will it
be a male no those will go back to
female plants just like you started with
you have to reverse it all over again uh
that's why I'm always doing the
reversals every time so my dude Ivan
thank you for the great question make
sure you check your inbox for a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from
idirect decom and also make sure you
check your spam because often times
those coupon codes those emails do end
up in that spam folder I don't want you
to miss your coupon code because like
I've said before they do expire look for
the expiration date that is real that
expiration date on there is real a lot
of people out there your codes are going
to end by the end of the year I promise
you make sure you give it a lookie give
it a cexy go check your coupon code go
check your spam go see if it's going to
expire and also hit that uh holiday
pricing at edirect decom everything's on
sale we're doing an end of the year
inventory blowout go check the pricing
that's enough advertising let's keep
moving we've got another great question
this one also did come from that growel
tab on IR genetics.com this one is from
our new friend chony chony thank you for
the great question uh chony check your
inbox you've got a coupon code for free
seeds what's better than free seeds you
guys free seeds are the best all right
here we are the question goes hey rosta
Jeff hey Chanty good to meet you says
thank you for the podcast and for always
being there with hundreds of episodes to
escape into I love that uh I'm a podcast
consumer as well I listen to podcast
when the days not going even when the
day is going the way that I want it to
but sometimes if I just need my head on
something else something else in my
brain I just go to one of my favorite
podcast click play and I can escape into
that show I'll be laughing at LS and
Zach or uh getting grossed out Legion of
skanks or something great will be
happening in no time so I understand and
I appreciate it thank you I like being
your uh your little escape and you're
learning something while you're escaping
so that's even better uh there is a
point to this question it says have you
found any companies that can perform hlv
testing on seeds that is a very good
question is a seed seller a seed breeder
a seed maker uh I am a very good person
to ask about this it said did they
validate their test to be performed on
seeds uh than thanks as always have an
amazing day uh cheers Chanty Chanty big
cheers my dude this is a great question
so the question is about testing seeds
actual seed batches batches of seeds for
hop latent vroid um I have been in
contact with somebody I can't say too
much cuz uh things are uh things are in
development man but I can't talk too
much about what's being worked on and
the conversations that have been had
what I can tell you is right now there
is not a way to test the SE seeds
without destroying them to put uh to
test the seed to see if it's got hyate
and thyroid in that individual seed that
seed must be crushed and destroyed uh in
the testing process that's just how the
test Works uh you basically crush the
seed rub the inside onto a little it's
it's easy but you got to crush it and
rub it onto something and then that is
your sample that the test is taken from
but um you have to destroy the seed
basically to do that and then now you
can't grow the seed so so far what we
have come up with the method that we are
using is we can test the batch of seed
and tell you if the seeds that were
tested themselves had hlate and vroid in
them uh so what we're doing is testing
somewhere between 10 and 30% of a
population of seeds so let's just say
I've got a 100 seeds of a new cross
which would be a small number it's
generally going to be a thousand so
we'll say a thousand we'll say we've got
a thousand seeds right I just made a
thousand seeds from a batch we want to
test these and see if there's any hlv in
there out of that thousand we would
scoop out somewhere between 100 and 300
seeds 10 to 30% of those seeds and we
would test those seeds and hopefully we
don't see any virus in there if that
batch of those seeds is clean that's how
we're mostly going to say that we trust
that this batch of seeds is clean if
we've tested 30% of them and the virus
is not present the seeds should be clean
that is the standard at this time it may
improve we may find something different
that's what we're working with now uh
the other thing the other Safeguard the
other uh the other uh redundancy that
we're doing is we are uh checking each
parent plant of those seeds well so if
we made uh let's just hypothetically say
we made so um I don't want to give any
details away I want to share strain
names and things but I don't want to
delve into the future and tell you
what's coming up let's just say we made
some lemon Jeffree seeds we got the
Golden Goat we got the Lemon Skunk uh
both of those have been tested for hlv
both of those have recently been sent in
for hlv tests those two plants are clean
the Golden Goat I think I did Golden
Goat lemon skunk uh those are STD free
ready to go those are clean plants so I
breed with those and then as a double
check a triple check we send in the
seeds as well those seeds are destroyed
and tested but we know that ah three out
of 10 of those seeds do not have the
virus that's uh the mom the dad and the
babies have all kind of been tested but
so far there's not a way without
destroying the seed that we can test to
find the presence or the absence of hlvd
in there unless we Crush destroy and use
that crushed seed as the testing agent
uh it's just how it's got to be done
right now those are the tests that are
available uh when that when it does
evolve and we have more stuff to go by I
definitely will update you because I
would love to brag about it I'd love to
say that every one of my seeds is hlv
tested but if I did that every one of my
seeds would be crushed and destroyed and
it doesn't work that way uh they're bred
from hlv tested plants is what I can
guarantee you um I do a random process
um and I don't I'm not paid by anybody
nobody pays me to advertise with them I
actually use two different hlvd testing
companies one of them is quicker one of
them is cheaper uh just depends on if I
want my stuff right now or if I want it
more affordable uh sometimes they do
sales all bu uh like sometimes far
farmer Freeman will do a holiday sale
and you can get them for 10% off so if
you buy like 10 tests you're basically
getting two for free is the math on that
I think uh and I'll just buy from farmer
Freeman I also use Tumi genomics uh
they're a little bit cheaper but they do
take longer sometimes uh pros and cons
with both plac
uh they don't pay me um and I'm not
going to tell you who I'm talking to and
working with to develop this testing but
occasionally randomly um about once
every two or three weeks I go through
the room and I just pick how about that
one and that one and that one and I'll
just clip off the hlv testing samples
and send those in we'll get them tested
randomly it's like testing the team I
just go into the locker room and I'm
like Bro you've been playing way too
good we got to give you a drug test um
i' just go test everything if anything
looks slow or sad it definitely gets
tested but uh I've been using all the
new AC Infiniti stuff and everybody
looks real happy lately um this is a
good spot to sneak in a Shameless plug
AC Infiniti that's right uh if you shop
with AC infinity.com use coupon code iy
save 15% off your entire AC Infinity
purchase that's right I'm using AC
infinti why aren't you AC infinity and
ie genetics you cannot go wrong let's
stay focused here where were we hlv
testing on the seeds um yeah so um
unless we crush and destroy the seeds at
this this point uh we can't really test
each seed for hlvd we can test each
parent plant and we can test populations
from the batch of seeds but so far
that's the best we've got my dude Chanty
thank you you got me rambling quite well
make sure you check your inbox for that
coupon code for a free pack of seeds
from
air.com before I jump into the next
question now is a good time to remind
you to click like click subscribe that's
right click like And subscribe that way
every time I put out a new episode you
don't miss any my amazing high quality
ganja content I'm just being goofy today
you guys I'm in a good mood I've had a
lot of great dabs shout out to my
friends at green. laabs for keeping me
lit up we've got one more good question
here in front of me for today's episode
this one also came from the growel tab
this one is from my new friend Jerry
Jerry thank you for the good question
this is just a quick one it says Hey are
spiders bad in your grow this one is
controversial it says I have a lady that
I keep finding webs on should I be
worried I always give a little wash
after harvest so does the web actually
matter uh my first question is that a
spider do you have a spider in there
like an arachnid big kind of spider uh
that eats bugs uh keeping an eye on your
plants playing Security in there to eat
up all the freebies that come around or
do you have spider mites in there a
bunch of little creepy crawly plant
sucking leeches um do you have spiders
or spider mites that is my first
question I would say uh verify can you
find find the spider um do you know
where the spider is can you tell the
difference between and I'm not doubting
you I'm just giving you solid advice
that we can cover all of our ground here
can you tell the difference between
normal spider webs that like a spider
would make and spider might webs that
would go across the tops of your plants
can you identify the difference in those
uh let's be very clear which spiders are
present in the grow spider mites we need
to take quick immediate action
especially if you're seeing webbing
regular spiders that's up to you my dude
um a lot of people will say that that
spider like I said a moment ago he's
working security there will not be any
other bugs in there that'll be the only
bug in the room is that spider he'll eat
everybody else nobody else wants to come
around if he's there that's cool uh you
don't want other bugs you really don't
want any bugs but one good spider might
work security uh he's the bouncer at the
door making sure you don't get any Riff
Raff so I would identify is it a spider
or is it spider mites uh once you
identify that it is a spider is it a
spider that you're okay with there are
some spiders you might not want around
uh I don't know your region of the
country but a brown recluse a black
widow you may want to relocate remove
that spider uh do whatever you do in
your humane way that you choose to do it
but I would identify is it a spider or
spider M that would be my first uh my
first plan of attack here um if it's a
spider he's working security verify that
it's a spider uh then see what kind of
spider you've got as for that web that's
gross dude I don't want to smoke any of
your weed with spider webs in it maybe
um work on keeping them off the plants
do what you can do there uh that's just
gross uh even and whatever it is I don't
want any food or smokable products with
spiderwebs on it just doesn't make me uh
gives me the makes me itchy bro is
really what it does and then spider
mites if it's spidermites uh spidermites
are bad okay we don't want that at all
we got to get rid of those immediately
we need to come up and if you've got
webbing you've got serious spidermites
if that's what what is in there so you
need to come up with a strategy very
quickly I would uh consider shop vacing
those spidermite webs off the top if
they made little teepees little domes
getting there at the shop vac suck that
right off uh you can use a rag in hot
water you can use a rag and a spray
bottle spray those webs down and wipe
them right off uh after you do that
clean yourself you're going to be
contaminated with spidermites all over
you uh then we're going to need to apply
either some aggressive Predator bugs or
sprayed pesticide applications designed
to eradicate spider mites uh probably
one or two pesticides together or and
rotation and go hard and get rid of
these bad [ __ ] depending on how far
uh into the progress into the cycle you
are as well but uh yeah if you got
spiders it is time to consider an
integrated Pest Management option step
up your game and consider going hard but
the first thing we got to do is find out
like I keep saying is is it spiders is
it a spider or is it spider mites that's
where we're going to make our big
difference here if it's a spider you can
make your own judgment call do you want
that spider there uh maybe you got a
cool spider maybe you got a terrible
spider I don't know how you feel on
spiders plenty of people would say any
spider has got to go but many people
would say that that spider is just fine
there so that's up to you um the webbing
is gross to me I would probably
reconsider that part but like I keep
saying make sure it's not spidermites if
it's spidermites send me another email
we will plan a uh mode of attack because
if you're getting webbing that's a lot
of spidermites all right I think I said
the word spider and spider mites how
about relisten to that segment every
time I say spider take a dab see if you
live through it all right my dude Jerry
thank you for the great message uh
ladies gentlemen boys and girls pimps
hoes friends foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
this is going to be a quick episode
because it is the holiday season here
I'm in what I'm calling the Holiday Tain
it's not Christmas it's not New Year's
I'm right in the middle got a lot of
stuff going on so we're going to keep it
quick keep it short we're going to wrap
this one up I want to thank each and
every one of you for listening to
another episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast once again make sure you
support the patreon campaign and what
else do we got oh make sure you check
iir everything is on sale at idirect
domcom uh over the next few days I will
be doing a short inventory um shout out
to the person who helped me with that
inventory you know who you are thank you
bro um there will be an inventory update
many of the things that I thought were
sold out that were extra packs left
because uh orders were made and payments
didn't go through or orders were
cancelled or inventory was miscounted or
[ __ ] goes wrong and things happen
there's stuff left over guess what I
found more packs of a few things uh
those will slowly be drifting onto
edirect decom um allegedly there's some
big mountain fudge cake uh I saw some of
the Golden Girls um there's a lot of
stuff that I didn't realize was in the
box it is still there it is available so
I'll be loading that into I redirect
slowly over the next couple of days make
sure you check that out um I think
that's all I've got I don't need to
round he too much at the end of the show
um I hope you guys have a great safe
holiday if I don't see you before the
new year I don't think there's another
episode before the new year so uh take
good care of yourselves is there let's
check we're just going to play with the
phone for a brief second here no this is
it bro this is it we're wrapping up the
year together right now no more episodes
until next year ladies and gentlemen
thank you it was a [ __ ] great year I
hope you had as good of a year as I did
um and I'll see you next year no no need
to get mushy here and start rambling uh
yeah I'll see you guys next year I want
to give a big shout out to two who did I
write down where is it I got to scroll
all the way down these notes way down
here there we go let's make it feel more
natural not even going to edit that part
uh boys and girls thank you it's been a
fun year uh it's been a great time of
podcast I look forward to another
prosperous year um take good care of
yourselves be good to everyone around
you uh love your garden it will love you
back I'll see you next year which is
just a week away boys and girls I'm
going to give a big shout out to my
buddy Gro and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another DB
grab your pie in I the
back in the lab sit back
relax roots and wisdom start
to from the knowledge SE we grow tuning
out to hear the vibr that Jeff in our
conscious
[Music]
tribe he spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard heing
light the canis go from your heart your
this rise up higher Find Your Way grow
from your heart every day in the light
We Stand real strong join the movement
sing the
song not your in I love flows within us
like a do educate and Elevate join the
Journey Don't Be Late open minds to see
the truth in the soil lies the proof RF
will guide you through in this garded
find the new rise up high up Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the
[Music]
song open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
with will guide you through in this
Garden find the new rise up higher Find
Your Way broke from your hearts every
day in the light We Stand real strong
join the movement sing the song
o
[Applause]
[Music]