[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome back
podcast world I'm your host rosta Jeff
this is episode 865
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got another fun episode lined
up for us in today's episode I'm going
to give away free seeds hang out we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in today's podcast today we are going
to focus on listener generated content
that's right I have a website that
website is IR genetics.com at the top of
that website there's a row of tabs one
of those tabs does say grow help or grow
questions if you send me a cool grow
question and I read your question here
on the podcast I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom today's first question came from
somebody who wants to be called Mike
diesel big shout out to my new friend
Mike diesel Mike's question goes just
like this Mike says I've got a two-part
question and I will answer both of those
questions for you buddy it says what
size grow tent and type of seed do you
recommend for a firsttime grower now
this is a very good question a very fun
question um for a firsttime grower I
would recommend something like a 3X3 or
a 5x5 if you have room for a 5x 51 that
is definitely what I would recommend and
suggest if you've got a 3X3 do that if
you need to go smaller of course work
your way down but I would recommend that
5x5 that 3x3 those two tents are very
easy to manage uh very easy to maintain
uh very easy to get equipment that fits
perfectly inside those tents uh our
friends at AC Infinity if you do go
check out AC infinity.com use coupon
code iy that will save you a few bucks
our friends at AC Infiniti make a
perfect package for a 5x5 tent a 3X3
tent you can order everything in one box
it will show up on your front door
you're basically ready to go all you
need are some seeds and some nutrients
it is really easy to do so I would
recommend starting with a 5x5 or a 3X3
like I said go smaller as you need to if
necessary I really like the 5x5 for the
amount of space uh the canopy space in
there and just managing that much space
is much easier that's the right amount
of space honestly right now uh the next
seeds that you purchase from me will
have been bred in a 5x5 AC Infinity ttin
I like the 5x5 because I can control
that environment very perfectly that 5x5
space is very easy to manage uh the
temperature the humidity the overall VPD
uh it's easy to manage the amount of
plants that fit into there it's the
right amount of space for the right size
light um I just think it's a really easy
perfectly manageable space that 5x5 is a
really ideal space for a new grower so
I've said it enough a 3X3 a 5x5 of
course I'm going to advertise the AC
Infinity tents uh the lights the blowers
the fans everything AC Infinity kicks
ass they make it super easy check out
the new AC Infinity AI controller uh you
basically tell it uh I want a veg and
then it says you're in veg and it sets
all your gear to veg for you and you veg
then when it's time to flower you tell
it I want a flower and it goes oh we'll
flower for you and AC Infinity basically
puts the plants into flowering mode for
you so AC Infinity 5x5 tent is the way
to go so the second part of the question
is what type of seeds would you
recommend for a firsttime grower would
you recommend Autos or fem um of course
you know I'm not a big fan of the
Autoflower seeds I just did a full
episode about that so I'm going to
recommend photo period feminized seeds
for a new grower uh that sets you up for
Success uh the photo period gives you
the opportunity to learn the cycles of
the plant if you want to do lollipopping
defoliation popping twisting uh certain
manipulation techniques and low stress
training techniques to your plants you
can learn that stuff with the photo
period plants the autof flowers don't
give you as much of an opportunity to
manipulate and play with them uh you
don't get to experiment with that veg
cycle when you were doing the Autoflower
plants so I would recommend the photo
period feminized of course the fem
that's going to help you uh minimize
your risk of male plants and of course
for new Growers I do always recommend
the feminized seeds that just sets you
up for Success one more Step Closer To
Success you don't need to watch as
closely for male plants in the garden
there is the opportunity with all
breeders with all seeds that there is
that opportunity of a rare male or a
rare intersex plant the dreaded intersex
plant from your fem seed uh no matter
who the breeder is how good those seeds
are that is still an opportunity so do
pay attention but the photo period
feminized seeds are what I would
definitely recommend um and you've got a
free pack of seeds coming your way so
make sure you check your inbox for a
coupon code from edirect decom that way
you can get yourself a free pack of
seeds I do recommend those photo period
feminized seeds those are easily
accessible and readily available on the
website let me jump into this and make
sure I covered everything a 3X3 or a 5x5
uh feminized photo periods AC Infinity
iy genetics and recently AC Infinity
teamed up with Athena nutrients so I'm
just going to say jump in get the whole
Trifecta there AC Infinity I genetics
and Athena that big triangle of power
you can't go wrong jump in grow from
your heart you will do it right once
again check that coupon code check your
inbox for that coupon code for free
seeds from edirect decom all right I
like the flow of this show let's keep
this going I've got another great
question here in front of me this one
came from I don't have their name this
one is from electron Dawn electron Dawn
I like that name check your inbox my
dude because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at idirect
decom the question from electron Dawn
goes a little bit like this should I be
flushing my mother plants to get rid of
excess nutrients and then give them pure
water for two weeks and then start
nutrients back up um absolutely not then
it says about every two or three months
give them a flush what do you think
guidance would be much appreciated thank
you for your time or maybe there's one
of your videos you can point me to that
can help me out with this question bro
here it is this is the video with the
answer to your question uh I gently
replied to this listener this viewer I
said why would you flush and then they
said I'm using two gallon fiber pots for
my mothers how often should I be
flushing the soil I'm using basic
Botanicare veg nutrients and my reply to
this my response to this is um why do
you need to flush what are you flushing
what are you flushing out uh those
plants are using the nutrients that you
were feeding them so um you're feeding
the plant the plant is eating that
unless you see some sort of major
problem with your plants I never
recommend a flush and let me talk about
quickly what a flush is a flush a purge
if you will I think it's the same idea a
flush that is when uh we would take an
amount of water um and we would run that
through our soil our media soilless mix
and run that through our plant until we
get drainage of that water coming out of
the bottom of the plant that is a flush
feed it just water the idea is to flush
all of the nutrients out of that uh the
rizosphere we want to clean that out
give ourselves a fresh clean medium is
the thought process here and this
listener said uh flush it and give them
pure water for two weeks dude your
plants are going to be freaking angry if
you don't feed them for two weeks
they're going to starve they're going to
get yellow they're going to get
everything deficient you're going to
start seeing problems uh within the
first 7 to 10 days maybe 3 to 5 days
depending on how big the plant are how
big the containers are how powerful the
lighting is you're going to notice
issues if you flush and do not feed
there's not going to be any nutrition
available so I never recommend a flush
with just water even if it's phed water
unpaged water clean water I don't ever
recommend a flush with the intentions of
just cleaning out that rizosphere
cleaning out the root Zone I never
recommend that flush the only reason
that it would be reasonable in my
opinion is if you had a major problem in
your plants if they were showing you
everything is [ __ ] wrong we've been
overfed everything that's when I would
consider the flush but that would be my
last option what I would do instead of
that um and this is not this does not
apply to this situation in this viewer
situation no flush not necessary don't
do it business as usual will keep going
if you do see a problem then consider a
flush but consider this option first and
just hear me out think about it this way
let's just say you've got a plant it's
showing you a lot of problems it could
be overfed it could be under fed it
could be a nutrient lock out we're just
not quite sure what's happening uh
you've showed it to the internet you've
come to the Discord server everybody's
done that thing like a bunch of old guys
with a beer in one hand a cigarette in
the other [ __ ] stood around the truck
and went I think it's your alternator I
think it's your timing belt I think it
could be the muffler bearing everybody
has said their statement what they think
it is but we don't really know what's
wrong there's so many issues appearing
and presenting in this plant we're not
exactly sure we could flush but that's
going to lead to like I said deficiency
it's going to cause more problems now
the plant is deficient in everything
that's not going to correct anything in
my opinion uh I think in my experience
that's going to make the plant more
angry and worse now you've got an
overwatered rizosphere your root zone is
all saturated with water and now it's
just water now the plant's going well
now I'm [ __ ] overwatered and hungry
and I don't know what to do with myself
so it's just going to start freaking out
what I would recommend mix up for
whatever stage of growth you were in if
you were in veg uh early flow midlow
late flow those are your basic stages of
growth with the cannabis plant you get
four or five different phases here three
trimesters of flour whatever phase you
are in mix up a batch of a nutrient
solution so whatever you mix you got
your 5 gallon bucket your 250 gallon
Reservoir makes up a feed solution that
you are very familiar with and you know
works every time every Grower's got a
go-to recipe that they go up the shit's
messing up I better go back to this when
you go back to that recipe that you know
works every time it's going to fix your
problem so go back to this recipe make
sure that everything you need is in
there your base nutrients your cow mag
whatever you're going to feed put some
definitely throw a bunch of recharge in
there put some silicates in there I
don't know what you feed uh we'll go
through I'm trying to think of my lineup
it would be uh Botanicare pure blend Pro
um the if we're it depends on what stage
we're in we're just going to say we're
in veg it'd be the Botanicare pure blend
Pro veg bottle would be the first bottle
actually that's wrong probably Silica
Blast some potassium potassium silicates
are going to go first so we got our
potassium silicates we got our base
nutrient a little bit of cowm Mag a
little bit of liquid Karma what else are
we going to do in there some
carbohydrates a nice carb product would
be nice in there um and then some
recharge that's probably enough to
liquid Karma we're going to add liquid
Karma almost every time oh and Ruby
fulvic from our friends at New
Millennium uh so then we're going to mix
all that stuff up properly we're going
to pH it uh before we put the recharge
in we'll pH it get it at the correct pH
I don't know what PH you're using but
somewhere between 62 and 65 probably get
it dialed in use a consistent pH then
we're going to add the microbes the
recharge give it a good stir then we're
going to water the plants to a little
bit of runoff I want some water coming
out of the bottom of these pots um
enough to where we can actually collect
it and measure the EC and pH of that
runoff would be really cool uh so I
recommend mix Your solution uh check the
EC check the pH of that solution write
that down water your plants get runoff
measure that runoff write that down as
well we'll deal with that in the future
what I want to do is I want to basically
reset the settings in that rizosphere
whatever is in there I want to water
that [ __ ] right on out and I want to
water it in with brand new feed
basically give it that whole new meal
whatever that last meal was it's sitting
in its gut I just want to push it out
with a new meal make all that stuff fall
right out and put a whole new dinner in
there so that it can start fresh that in
my opinion is the way to restart
whatever plant you think needs to be
flushed because really that way we're
giving it everything it needs at the
proper dose at the proper pH and that's
the best thing you can give the plant
right the proper feed the proper
nutrients the proper ratios uh the
proper temperature hopefully the proper
pH give it everything that it needs and
fix it just reset that instead of
completely [ __ ] disrupting it and
then trying to chase it because this
dude said uh pure water for two weeks at
the end of that two weeks everything is
going to be bright yellow everything's
going to be sad then you're going to
need to overfeed again then you're going
to need to catch up with that and it's
just going to look worse it's going to
cause more problems so um I never flush
I think it causes more problems I would
feed with the Mel well- mixed solution
at the proper pH and try to achieve
approximately 20% runoff if you can so
that means if you poured a gallon of
water into that plant you want 20% of a
gallon gallon maybe a quarter of a
gallon to come out of the bottom of that
plant then you want to scoop some of
that up and we will measure the EC and
pH of that if it's drastic high or low
then we will make adjustments if it came
out close to what it went in we're doing
okay if it's higher or lower we can
understand what's going on from there we
can make adjustments if necessary but
that's my long rant about why I do not
flush and why I would recommend mixing a
solid solution uh just imagine if you
didn't feel good like if you were sick
like if you woke up tomorrow and you
just felt like complete [ __ ] would you
do you think it would be more beneficial
to your body to your health if you mixed
up a tea and put some vitamins some
nutrients some minerals whatever you're
going for if it's an emergency packet or
if you actually go get some fruit and
juice and make a fruit juice anything
like that going into you is going to be
better than just water and you're just
peeing out all your own vitamins your
own minerals your own nutrients you need
some electrolytes you need some vitamins
you need to be replenished so I think
your body would do a lot better if you
fed it a little bit instead of just
adding water and having to piss a lot I
think the plants are going to act very
similarly we're going to push out all
the the junk we don't want replace it
with stuff that we do desire you guys I
am quite rambl on this episode big shout
out to our friends at green. laabs I
took some dabs of some lemon tree I
think it was or was it the no the lemon
buttered rum uh batter from Green Dot
Labs it has got me uh battered and
rambling big shout out to my new friend
electric Dawn electric Dawn thank you
for the great question you got me
rambling quite well I would not
recommend flushing ever unless you see
major major problems and still I would
flush the little way that I talked about
all right ladies and gentlemen now is a
good time to click like And subscribe
that's right if you enjoy what you're
watching go ahead click like also click
subscribe so you never miss any of my
amazing cannabis content before we go
any further I'm going to do a couple of
shoutouts to a few of the great folks
who support the show on patreon that's
right I do have a patreon campaign you
can find the patreon Campa paying it
patreon.com grow fromy yourheart you've
got to type all that in because I am
shadowband because we are a weed show
patreon does not approve of that so you
got to type in the whole thing
patreon.com fromy yourheart I want to
give a few shout outs I want to send a
big shout out to my buddy lemur priest
lemur dude it's so good to see you back
on the Discord my bro Also let's send a
big shout out to my buddy Danny pots
Danny it would be cool to see you back
on the Discord I understand the new jobs
got you busy nothing but respect but we
do miss you my dude let you know we're
thinking about you also big shout out to
my buddy Roman roots Roman roots thank
you for all the patreon support then
we're going to wrap this part up with a
big grow from your heart podcast thank
you shout out to my good friend Oki
Braden Braden much love thank you for
all the great pictures uh thank you for
all the support cannot wait to see you
again at the dgc cup in
2025 that's right dgc cup 2025 all right
ladies and gentlemen thanks for all the
patreon support let's keep this party
moving move in I do have another great
question here in front of me this one
came from somebody who is going to be
called atlan
415 feels like I've heard that somewhere
before big shout out my dude this
question oh also make sure you check
your inbox for that coupon code for the
free seeds at iir decom the question
goes a little bit like this it says I
have some general questions I wanted to
bounce off of you uh you sent me three
questions I'm only going to give you one
coupon code for one pack of seeds but I
do appreciate the content it says light
leaks uh light leaks can wreak havoc on
an otherwise tuned in run how exactly do
outdoor grows deal with a light leak
that is a very good question I generally
address this question around the
beginning of outdoor season because
people are like hey I'm putting my
plants outside there's a street light
there's a [ __ ] porch light what's
going on this is a good question so
Outdoors why don't uh little lights
disrupt our plants Outdoors let's see uh
outdoor grows deal with light leaks so a
light leak what is a light leak that is
probably a good spot to start indoors a
light leak is what we call it when your
nighttime cycle in your grow environment
when it should be dark when that dark
cycle is interrupted and light gets in
there whether it's a little crack in
your um in your tent a little split in
your seams whether a door gets opened
whether a light gets left on that is a
light leak that can cause dri
detrimental issues to your garden uh
depending on the frequency the power um
a lot of different factors of that light
the plants simply may not go into flower
uh it could cause them to express
intersect traits it could wak havoc on
everything or sometimes nothing could
happen but so that is a light leak a
light leak is when the light gets into
your dark cycle now we put our plants
outdoors and we expect to get full
Darkness from the outdoor environment
and our plants should flower as usual
however we now live in society where
we've got a whole bunch of freaking
lights I don't know if it's your porch
light like I said earlier it could be a
car driving by it could be a headlight
on a dude on a bike now it could be a
[ __ ] drone with a bunch of spotlights
on it there are light leaks and light
and darkness interruptions now happening
to our plants Outdoors why don't those
plants and also we've got the moon let's
not forget about that big old Skylight
that a lot of us use to walk our path at
night the moon Nature's favorite light
the moon out there um why isn't that
light [ __ ] up our garden that's all a
very good question the first quickest
answer is phytochrome red so let's talk
about this when the Sun is setting when
the sun is going down and also I've got
another theory we'll touch on this with
as the sun sets it starts to put off a
spe it doesn't put off when the sun sets
it hits the atmosphere in a way that it
creates a spectrum of light known as far
red lighting it is a spectrum of light
that triggers our plants to do what is
called a phytochrome red response so
this the Sun comes to a certain angle of
the atmosphere it creates a certain
color a certain spectrum of lighting
that lighting hits our plants that light
that color of that light tells our plant
hey it's sleepy time I should go nigh
night that's why sometimes outside at
the outdoor grows you will see your
plants their leaves are up and perky
they're going and as the sun begins to
set they will go and you'll go oh the
plants know it's nighttime yes they do
because they are getting far red
lighting which is triggering a
phytochrome response in those plants
that is telling them hey it's time for
me to go to sleep and when those plants
are tucked in by the far red lighting
they sleep mud
more deeply than they would in your
basic grow room when you're going from
an LED light with [ __ ] six different
colors that was made up by man to
Darkness um maybe a th000 watt LED light
in there is probably what most of us are
running in a 5x5 so you got 1,000 watts
of light uh just a little mix Spectrum
uh that's really cool for your plants
it's working really well and when that
goes off it's pure pure Darkness but
compare that to the power of the sun
when that sun is cooking it is the
perfect Spectrum for your plants it's
the most powerful Spectrum no light
meter will ever measure how much sun
we're getting uh compared to a grow
light so all that sunlight compared to
your grow light is such a vast
difference so when that sunlight uh
tells those plants hey it's time to go
to sleep compared to your grow light
it's like giving them a quadruple dose
of Nyquil versus just going sweet dreams
kids it's such a big big difference so
that's why light leaks are so
detrimental indoors and can cause such
major problems but Outdoors the plants
can take a lot more light problems
because that far red light has tucked
them in and they're sleeping they're in
their they've been comos they've been
tucked in real tight they've been given
that double dose of Nyquil they took a
fat dab they rubbed one out they got a
full tummy they're [ __ ] sleeping
they're not going to wake up until that
opposite Spectrum happens when the Sun
rises it creates a blue and wide
spectrum that tells those plants hey
[ __ ] it's time to wake up and get to
work and you'll see the leaves the
leaves will start swimming they'll start
perking up and start doing their day uh
that's what happens with that blue light
from the sun as it begins to rise so uh
the main factor is that far red lighting
tells them hey go to sleep and then
they're soundly tucked in and the second
factor is your little flashlight your
little headlight on the car does not
compare at all to the Sun that it's used
to seeing so uh that's like just pulling
the curtain open a little bit and just
going hey there's a little LED light out
there the plant's going to go yeah a
little LED whatever if you pull open the
curtains on the sun's up we're all going
to go ah [ __ ] the sun's up that's the
big difference about it different
Spectrum different uh intensity uh
different overall kind of light so the
first answer far red the second answer
is that major difference in intensity
now there are two more parts to this
question which is fun because I'm quite
rambly Today part number two or number B
if you want to uh do you have any
personal experience with World plants
World plants that is when uh your leaves
that should be sticking straight out and
kind of doing this that's when they look
like they're curling they're getting uh
they're just twisting all over each
other the leaves are twisting World
means twisting leaves so if the leaves
look like they're spinning around you
got a tornado plant that's what we're
talking about most of the time in my
experience that is a light problem most
of the time 99% of the time that is a
light um like a REV process so you've
gotten you've given the plant more light
than you were you've increased the
amount of hours
that the the plant is receiving light
that was harder to say than it looked
but you do podcasting you'll figure it
out uh that plant probably went from um
we'll say 186 to 240 and that lack of
sleep made that plant go what the [ __ ]
and it starting to spin around or it was
on 1212 and you put it on 186 or 240 and
now those leaves are starting to twist
and curl going I don't know what to do
so most of the time that world uh plant
the world leaves come from too much or a
changed light cycle an increased light
cycle is generally what I've noticed
that from it could be other things most
of the time you're going to find that it
is a lighting issue because it's kind of
a hormonal thing uh which 90% of the
time does come from the lighting so you
probably changed the timer and that
plant went [ __ ] nuts or gave it too
much light now there is a part three
number c it says when using some type of
chemical induced method for creating
pollen from female plants all right so
when I'm making silver tho sulfate is
what they're being specific about and
deciding to do open air pollination so
I'm going to reverse a plant and let
that pollen fly into the air what type
of spacing do you give male and female
plants during the tail end of the
chemical schedule okay I see what you're
saying where the plants will be into
pre-flow if not flower um so I see what
you're saying um and you have kind of
overthought it there's no time on that
overlaps there's no overlapping in this
period what this viewer listener
questioner is asking um I treat a plant
with silver tho sulfate so I've got a
plant I treat it with silver tho sulfate
I will treat it seven times over the
course of its life maybe eight or nine
that's Up For Debate but it's going to
get seven solid treatments of this
sprayed application of silver tho
sulfate then after that it is going to
get moved to another room to pollinate
some female plants this person is asking
um how much space do I give the male and
female plants during that tail end where
the plants will be into pre-flow and not
flow or and
flow um are those chemicals transferable
to nearby plants by the air and if to if
so what to extent So it's b these the
product I use is uh it's water-based so
I'm spraying a water a liquid product on
there it's not really in the air it's
not a gas it's a liquid so I'm able to
maintain it um I've got so basically
I've got a 5x5 tent in one section of
the room and in the other corner of the
room is a 3X3 with the reversals I keep
them separate for timing purposes but I
basically take the reversal candidate
out of the tent and it sets right in the
corner the other corner of the room and
I apply the silver thyo sulfate uh
sprayed application to it way over there
it's a spray it's a liquid spray so it's
not like really Airborne uh I'm not
getting that fine of mist I'm just using
a [ __ ] spray bottle like you'd use to
clean the window it's the same I buy
those from Uline I could see a box of
them I just buy those from Uline and I
makes up a 10% and a 30% silver thio
sufate and I got two plants one's marked
with the 10 one's marked with the 30
they're sitting over there and I just
spray them and I don't spray willy-nilly
where the spray is going everywhere so
just right behind that plant which is a
white wall is all that's getting hit
with my overs spray so it's not really
going anywhere and then I let it dry
completely before I put it back into the
tent because sorry my computer just went
to screen saver and I need my notes here
man there we go um I let it dry before
it goes back into the tent because um I
don't want the 10 and the 30% dilutions
touching each other because I don't want
to get confused on which uh dilution
works because I'm making notes on what
to use in the future so I let them dry
because also I don't want them under the
light when they're wet that's not good
so I let them dry before they go back
into the tent and then that process
concludes around day 21 or day 24 and I
do not do my pollination until about day
uh and so also that process starts um
two weeks ahead before the other plants
so there's only a time period of two
weeks when this plant is being sprayed
or a week one week when this plant is
being sprayed and the females are in
flour and then I stop spraying that one
and he starts creating pollen she
creates pollen and it's been hasn't been
sprayed for 7 days before I move it to
the other room at least 7 Days uh in
this situation it's taking a minute for
my girls one of them isn't showing
enough pistol so I'm uh hesitating on
the pollination but it's going to be a
week or two weeks since I've sprayed
before the pollination even happens um I
quit spraying I'm trying to do the math
here so let's just say hypothetically I
started spraying silver tho sulfate on
December 1st then I would have sprayed
at the first third uh 1 3 6 9 12 15 18
21 up to the 21st of December the that
plant would have gotten sprayed with
silver tho sulfate so we got 21 days of
spray then I honestly did not put the
females into flow until the 16th of
December I gave them two weeks uh
advance I gave the mail the pollen
donors a two week Head Start to get
building up their pollen then I put the
females into flower kind of should have
timed that about 3 or five days
different now that I'm seeing what's
going on but they didn't know um so they
were into flower 21 days in uh then they
went went to flower 16 days in so that
means that 5 days in to the flowering
process of the females I stopped
applying sprayed solutions to the pollen
donors and they will not receive pollen
for probably 10 12 14 days after that
maybe even more so there's going to be a
three or 4 week time I think if I time
that properly where there's no sprayed
application in the room at all before
those female plants will receive the
pollen and there was no overspray so
those females will not be exposed to
Silver thyo sufate in any way at all and
if they were they're not going to get
smoked none of that is going to get
smoked nothing in that room will be
consumed it is all seeded material so
the plants that got sprayed they are
fully pollen donors uh they will get
chopped and moved over to the other room
and [ __ ] sprinkled all over once
those plants are done donating their
pollen everywhere they get cut into
small pieces put into a compost bin uh
they are gone they're done the boy
plants are the female pollen donors
they're removed from the room they're
not even a thought anymore uh and then
those female plants they've received
pollen none of that's going to get
smoked it is all loaded with seeds if I
do it correctly there's nothing smokable
so um there's been no overspray and
there's been a long time Gap so there's
no uh concern for chemical what's the
word you're using uh chemical methods
transferable no chemical transference to
nearby plants by air and to what extent
so um it's a good idea but I think
you're kind of overthinking it uh
there's a Time Gap uh day 21 is when I
quit spraying and that's like day five
of when I put the other girls into flow
and they're not going to get pollen in
for like 20 days from that so there's
like a a nice period from when the
pollen has been flying to or when the
Silver's been flying to when the pollen
flies and a big space in the room all
right I think I rambled about that one
for quite some time all right my dude
atlan 415 thank you once again for the
great question uh make sure you check
your inbox for a coupon code cuz you
want a free pack of seeds from iy
direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another episode of The Grow
from your heart podcast I'm going to
wrap this up quickly because this has
been a good show and all I could do now
is ruin it so let's get out while we're
winning uh thank you once again for
listening if you have any questions
Corrections comments or concerns you
know that I would love to hear from you
my email address is grow from yourheart
hotmail.com reach out let me know what
you think of the show if you want your
grow question read on the podcast the
way to do it is through that growel tab
at IR genetics.com everything else you
could possibly need is at IR
genetics.com there's a link to the
Discord server there's a link to the
patreon server and there's a link to iir
so you can get those seeds or the New
Year's pricing is happening that's right
check edirect decom for New Year's
pricing I think that's all I've got for
you for this week I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to my friend Kevin B and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] tell take another DB grab
your pie in I about the
B is in the lab sit back
relax roots and wisdom start to
so from the Ning seeds we brow tuning
now to hear the vibr that je in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard healing
light to canot this go from your heart
your this rise up high up Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a do educated Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof RF will guide you through in
this goded find the new rise up higher
Find Your Way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the song
[Music]
open minds to see the truth in the soil
lies the proof R Jeff will guide you
through in this Garden find the new rise
up higher Find Your Way brow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong join the movement sing the
song
o
[Music]
[Applause]