[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome back podcast world I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode
866 of the grow from your podcast you
know I've got another fun episode lined
up for us in today's podcast I'm going
to give away free seeds hang out we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in today's show before we get too far
I do want to remind you that the New
Year's sale has begun at idirect decom
that's right make sure you check air.com
for current New Year's pricing and
inventory and don't forget that all seed
orders over $100 do come with free
shipping all right I don't want to waste
too much time with advertising here at
the start of the show let's work our way
into the question and answer portion of
today's podcast I do have a website that
website is iry genetics.com on the top
of that website there's a row of tabs
one of those tabs does say grow help or
grow questions if you click on that tab
you can send me a grow question if I
read your grow question here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom our first question came from a new
friend who did not send a name their
question says wagan rosta Jeff big UPS
on so many hundreds of podcasts bro
thank you for the congratulations on all
of the podcast 866 episodes and no sign
of slowing down or stopping so thank you
for that thank you for noticing we're
going to jump right to the question part
there's a lot of a little setup here
we're going to get right to the question
it says anyway my question is this when
flipping back to 186 in the last 2 weeks
or 10 days won't the tri coms just be
ripe and immature many thanks big man
all right so this question is referring
to a technique that I've been talking
about that gets a lot of feedback a lot
of response and a lot of controversy I
have been using a technique where at the
end of my flowering cycle so I've been
flowering for seven eight and 1 half
maybe nine weeks for the last 10 maybe
14 days of my flowering cycle I change
my timer from 18 hours on to 6 hours off
now a lot of people's heads just [ __ ]
exploded why would you do this what is
going on you're in flower why are you
putting those lights back on a a
vegetative light cycle essentially
that's a very good question I do have a
very good reason for doing this so
essentially what I'm doing and there are
a lot of questions that come with this
I'll try to address a couple of those as
we talk uh but so I turn so 10 days
before I going to harvest generally 10
days before Harvest and do this with the
cultivar you are familiar with don't do
this on the first time you've ran a
plant because you don't know how long it
goes do this with with a plant you know
how long it goes and then adjust your
schedule accordingly so if you have a
plant you've ran it multiple times it
goes 70 days at day 60 I would change my
light cycle from 12 hours on 12 hours
off back to 18 hours on and 6 hours off
a vegetative light cycle I'm increasing
my light by 50% per day a lot of people
like I said are freaking the [ __ ] out
why would you do that well the first
reason I want to do that is I have found
that it makes my plants finish a little
bit more quickly I can get them to speed
up by several days sometimes two three
maybe four or five days depending on the
cultivar also I have noticed that it
increases in Bud density it makes the
buds a little more bulky a little bit
more dense and it also makes them weigh
a little bit more so it's making them
finish faster and it's making them more
dense I have never in my whole teaching
about this whole method I have never
said um that we should get more tricomes
from this that's never been part of the
theory part of the practice Ice uh
that's never been the idea because I
agree with you if this did promote
tricomes those tricomes would be
premature not immature but premature
troms they wouldn't be ripe they
wouldn't be worth smoking so you're
right there would be no advantage to
that also I feel like that the Bro
Science of putting your plants in
darkness for 24 hours to achieve more
tricomes uh that would do the exact same
thing you would get more tricomes but
they would not be uh they would not be
ripe they would not be amber in color
they would not be filled with the proper
oils they wouldn't be ready when I
started telling everybody about this
technique the intention was never to
encourage or increase or promote triome
development this was always about Bud
development about Bud density and
speeding up the uh the finishing time I
learned this technique and started doing
this uh with seated crops when I
pollinate crops I put them back on 186
very quickly after pollination because
that light source gives my plants more
energy and I wanted my seeds to get more
robust more quickly and then I thought
if it works on my seeds why not do it on
the flowering crops however we can't do
it too early because they will rev if
you do this too early so I learned to do
this the last 10 days of the flowering
cycle and it does make my buds uh more
dense and they finish more quickly so
from the very beginning this was never
intended to uh increase or promote
triome development that's the the bottom
line of this question it's only been for
Bud density and to speed up the Harvest
Time of that plant now a lot of people
ask me a lot of different questions they
ask how do you do this why do you do
this when do you do this I I will
explain uh very simply and very quickly
and very uh much why I do this it's
really easy um like I said before we've
got a plant that we have grown several
times we know what this plant does if
you harvest this plant consistently at
Day 70 and you have a solid outcome that
you're happy with um I would say turn
that light at day 60 put the light back
on 186 and allow that plant to get that
50% more Photon energy in my opinion um
in my experience in my education light
is the number one source of energy for
our plants so giving that plant more
light more energy will allow it to grow
more quickly it will get more density
and it will finish even sooner because
it is photosynthesizing more
metabolizing more while those lights are
on it is getting the energy to do so
while the lights are on and it will do
those processes when the lights go off
with more Vigor I also use green
sensation to make these processes a
little bit easier on the plant so we're
doing 186 adding green sensation green
sensation comes in at week four but it
sticks around so uh the reason for
changing the light is I believe that
that light gives me more Photon energy
that Photon energy is more production
people are going to ask do you change
the intensity of the lights no I simply
change the timer nothing changes but the
timer I don't adjust the intensity I
don't go less I don't go more I go more
hours that is all that I do and I highly
recommend that you do this with the
plant that you know how long it takes to
flower I keep saying that because you
may be wasting potential or you may be
triggering issues find a plan that you
know how long it takes to flower that
you're satisfied with the outcome if you
flush that's a whole another topic I
don't really flush that's not something
I do if you flush during that flush
phase go back to 186 that will speed up
the ripening uh and it'll give you more
dense buds but this was never meant to
be about triome production so I don't
want that to be a confusion the number
one question I get around this is when
to do it 10 days before flower the uh
number two question I get is do you
change the light intensity no leave it
right how it is change the timer keep an
eye on the plants third question I get
is won't this make my plants rev yes if
you do it for 18 22 days then they will
rev but 10 days they will not rev if
they do you've got a problematic plant
and that plant was going to give you
some [ __ ] anyway and if you are looking
to work on a reveg project now you are
way ahead of the game because you've
been in the reveg light it's already
been receiving that light it knows I'm
in 186 it's starting to do stuff
hormonally so when you do harvest the
lowers and leave a couple lower buds you
are way ahead of the game for your reveg
project so my dude who did not send a
name I appreciate the great question
I've got your email address so make sure
you check your inbox for a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at I direct.com
all right let's keep this show moving
this next question came from our new
friend Matthew Matthew thank you for the
great question make sure you check your
inbox because you've got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at edirect
tocom before I read this message I do
want to remind you to click like And
subscribe that's right if you enjoy this
podcast please click like also click
subscribe that way you never miss any of
my amazing cannabis educational content
all right this question for my new
friend Matthew goes a little bit like
this it says hey rosta Jeff I was
listening to your podcast and that got
me looking at your seeds and I want to
ask a question about them I appreciate
that it says are your feminized seeds
self-pollinated that is kind of a trick
question we'll get into that it says
will their genetics be similar to the
seedling mother other or can they still
have a fair bit of variance all right so
I want to talk about that um are the
seeds self-pollinated now if they were
self-pollinated you could only make one
strain so what I do I take one female
plant and I treat that female plant with
a solution we're going to talk about
that at another time I've talked about
it a lot in the past I take this female
plant I treat it with the solution it
creates pollen that only contains female
chromosomes because it is a female plant
I then take that poll
and I can put that pollen on a clone of
the same plant and that would be
considered a self-pollination that is an
S1 that plant definitely is
self-pollinated when I take that pollen
and put that pollen on other plants to
create other outcrosses those are what
is known as a reversal an R1 or an R2 if
it's a further filial but we're getting
carried away so we've got a difference
between a self and a reversal is what
you're basically talking about here some
of my plants are
self-pollinated um Golden Goat is a
self-pollination Golden Goat is a Golden
Goat clone pollinating a Golden Goat
clone so you are getting pure
unadulterated Golden Goat that's what
you get with that lemon Jeffrey on the
other hand is the Golden Goat pollen put
on a Lemon Skunk female that's how we
make the lemon Jeffree so that is a
reversal it is the female pollen put on
the lemon Jeffrey that makes the lemon
Jeffree that makes a feminized seed
because of that feminized pollen so
we've You' got two different types of uh
breeding projects here two types of
feminized breeding projects one is a
self one is a reversal let's talk about
the second part of this question will
their genetics be similar to the seeding
mother or can they still have a fair bit
of variance that's a very good question
let's focus first with the Golden Goat
S1 the self Golden Goat what I see with
the Golden Goat a lot of the times I see
about 40% of the phenotypes look just
like the original mother 40% of them
look just like the original mom then
there's about
25% that look a little bit like one of
the parents on one side the father then
there's about 25% of The Offspring that
look like the mother so we've got 25 dad
25 Mom that's 50% we got 40% that looks
just like the Golden Goat and then
there's 10% of them that are just
[ __ ] random weirdos there's a
phenotype in there that grows real tall
real skinny real wispy it takes a real
long time to finish but it is the most
potent out of the batch it doesn't look
anything like the original golden go but
it is amazingly potent and it tastes
like a tart sour funky grapefruit and it
makes my head spin when I smoke it so
that phenotype is in there but that is
not the common phenotype that is a
little bit of an outlier like I said
that's probably 10% I'm going to even
narrow it down to say probably 5% of the
phenotypes will Express that the other
five are just going to be weirdos that
I'm not even sure what you're going to
get so approximately 40% of The
Offspring are going to look just like
the mother just like the Golden Goat
clone that I've got that we started with
25% are going to look kind of like Mom
25% are going to look kind of like Dad
5% [ __ ] weirdos and 5% make that real
tall lanky wild [ __ ] phenotype that
I'm talking about so that's what you're
going to see from the S1 from the Golden
Goat now let's talk more about the R1 um
we're going to focus again on the lemon
Jeffrey lemon Jeffrey um there's one
common fenot type that you can see a
perfect 50/50 mix of the lemon skunk and
the Golden Goat that is kind of the
common phenotype and once again I'm
going to say that's about 40% that is
about 40% the 50/50 mix uh you're going
to see about 40% of the time then once
again 25% of the time we're going to see
stuff that looks a lot like Golden Goat
then 25% of the time we're going to see
stuff that looks a lot like the Lemon
Skunk then 10% of the time we're just
going to get weird outliers that kind of
they're curious they could look like
grandparents they could look like great
grandparents they're just going to be
weirdos that is kind of how breeding
works when we're doing these crosses but
we've got the opportunity with these
crosses now to see something that I do
see commonly um with the Reversed Golden
Goat crosses especially with and we're
going to talk about specific parents
here the lemon Jeffrey when I make the
lemon Jeffrey The Lemon Skunk dominates
that cross and most a lot of the
phenotypes I say 25 are going to look
like Mom 25 are going to look like Dad
because of just genetics the way this
one skews the way it sways probably 35%
of them look more like the lemon skunk
and the remaining 10 look like the
Golden Goat that's just how it works
with this cross now let's shift gears
and talk about orange gasm which is the
same Golden Goat pollinating a platinum
Tangi female more of those phenotypes
are going to look like the Golden Goat
the Golden Goat shines through on that
one and the Platinum Tangi doesn't come
through the mixes dominantly so it's
going to kind of vary plant to plant but
with the s1's uh the selfed ones most of
the time I'm seeing 40% mom 25 25 and 10
that's mostly what we get it just also
depends when we start doing the
reversals you see similar but you start
opening up the options because there's
another ingredient in the breeding mix
something is going to be dominant
something is going to be recessive um in
those plants you could have some traits
from this plant that are dominant and
some PL trades from this plant that are
dominant you might get weird [ __ ] you
might find totally recessive traes you
have no idea where it came from when you
start doing that but most of the time
and that's my new math that I'm going to
stick to uh 40 25 25 and those two can
sway a little bit side to side it could
be 35 and 10 based on how the genes
[ __ ] mesh together but we're going to
get 40% that are 50/50 or 40% like the
original mom we got 50% to play with
that are going to shift back and forth
10 35 25 25 sound like a [ __ ]
Auctioneer and then we got that 10%
available
for the outliers the outliers are always
going to be there that's how genetics
works sometimes the outliers are the
best so I think I answered that part of
the question there is more to this it
says I'm trying to understand genetic
variance between your feminized seeds
and say a clone you may drop in the
future I hope that's all right to ask I
apologize never apologize for asking
questions uh the only stupid question is
the one that you do not ask um then it
says I'm picking up some seeds ah pick
up some seeds yes so you're asking about
what is the difference between a seed
and a clone that you may pick up those
seeds uh I run the same seeds that I
sell you guys occasionally if I want to
run some new seeds I'll go to my
inventory my stash My Vault I'll say hey
I want to run some lemon Jeffree seeds
I'll pull out a pack just like I would
have sold to you I'll pull out two packs
just like you would have bought I'll
germinate them and I will grow them and
I find the keeper out of those two packs
the lemon Jeffrey that I'm selling on
the website now it's sold out I
apologize but the lemon Jeffrey that I
selling on the website is simp L it came
from a pack of seeds that I ran and I
found it and I thought that is a badass
keeper and I kept it and I've been
running it that is where it came from
the cream plant that I will be using in
the future uh my buddy Brian shout out
to Brian it's Brian's cream cut my
friend Brian has a grow local near me
and I went over there one day and saw
the cream and I went that [ __ ] plant
right there and he was like I know bro
so he gave me a clone of it and I'm
using that cream cut um those are just
cuts that we found in packs of seeds and
I make them available because I think
they're Stellar their standout they're a
very good representation of the product
that I was trying to sell you so since I
found that I just decided to offer that
to you uh so that you could get the cut
that I found and I could share my work
and my Discovery with you so um yeah the
seeds are self-pollinated or they are uh
reversals um very little of what I'm
doing lately is just a regular male to
female pollination I've still got my
boys I got my lovely ladies but the
regular seeds simply do not sell 90 85%
of the market lately has been feminized
seeds I could put reg seeds on sale they
will sit there fem seeds charge regular
price you guys will buy them so um that
is my answer I'm sticking to it my dude
Matthew uh thank you for the great
question make you make sure you check
your inbox because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com all right before we go any
further I do want to remind you that I
have teamed up with AC Infiniti that's
right AC infinity.com the leader in
growroom gear make sure you check out AC
infinity.com or use the link in the show
notes when you check out use coupon code
iy to save 10% off your AC Infinity
purchase all right I do have one more
great question here in front of me this
question came from my new friend Aaron K
big shout out to Aaron K Aaron make sure
you check your inbox because you've got
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds
at edirect decom also if you do not find
that coupon code in your inbox please do
check your spam a lot of your email
servers think that my coupon codes are
spam it's not spam bro it's all good
also while you're watching this podcast
make sure you check your spam folder
because I sent out an email today that
you want to read all right my buddy
Aaron thank you for the great question
it goes a little bit like this it says
my question is will a plant get stronger
or better with each generation the story
we always heard about G13 was that it is
the 13th generation thank you for all of
the knowledge and Good Vibes this is
very interesting I do not believe or
think that G13 was the 13th generation
that is not my belief um for that to be
the 13th generation that means that they
took two plants and bred them together
that is the F1 the seeds that came from
there were the first filial generation
then they would have made seeds of that
and bred them together and they would
have done this all the way up to
f-13 I do not believe since this was
supposed to be a university-led
government bred project um I have no
faith that they went to f-13 f-13 means
that if you grew seed from that plant
every seed would be completely identical
um they would be homozygous everyone
would look exactly the [ __ ] same and
I've never seen anything bred to the G13
come out uniform like that so I do not
think that it was the 13th generation my
thought process is that there was
probably uh plants were put in a grid
there was uh what is it columns and rows
you got a B CDE e f g hi and then one
through whatever number it was and I
think that plant that happened to be in
spot G Spot 13 Bingo uh you sunk my
battleship I think that is the plant
that whoever was working with this
product that's the one that they kept uh
that is just the way that I think it
happened um I have no proof no evidence
no reliability no reason to believe that
G13 is 13 Generations through um that is
not true in my opinion I can't [ __ ]
prove it but uh just the things I know I
don't believe that in any way now your
question about a plant getting stronger
each generation do you mean breeding
generation because people have a lot of
misnomers and misconceptions about the
way cannabis Works do you mean if I
breed this plant to itself or to its
filial generation 13 times will it get
better it should if we are selectively
breeding properly if nature is doing it
maybe maybe not it will breed for the
survival traits that work best in that
environment but it may not be the best
Aroma flavor or smoke that you're able
to find if you were selective breeding
Generations you better be improving
every generation that is the purpose of
breeding if your breeding isn't
improving then you're taking the plant
backwards and that's not what we're here
to do each generation should be better
better better every time so um does it
get better each generation now are you
asking every time you grow that plant
like if I cut a clone because some
people I've heard this before some
people do believe that if I grow a plant
cut a clone and grow it again it gets
better each time no that's the same
[ __ ] plant every single time what got
better was you as a grower you got more
adapted to the environment you learned
how to grow that plant it's like taking
that plant out on several dates the
first date you go out uh with somebody
whoever it is uh it's awkward you don't
know what they're into you don't know
what they want you don't know what they
need you have no idea who they are
you're meeting them that's like the
first time growing a plant by the third
or fourth time growing a plant you know
in week six it needs a little more of
this or a little bit less of this or
defoliate or don't defoliate just like
you learn a person so I think it's not
the generations I think it is you
getting better if that's in fact what's
happening so the question is does it get
better with each generation no uh not
clone wise but if you're breeding it it
better um the breeder better be
improving upon that generation every
time and 13th generation of G13 I don't
believe that's true at all I would say
that's complete [ __ ] but that's what
I'm here for breaking up rumors and
telling the truth My Buddy Aaron C thank
you for the great question make sure you
check your box cuz you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at idirect
tocom ladies and gentlemen boys and
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers
All of You Beautiful cannabis
enthusiasts out there I do want to thank
you once again for listening to another
quick episode of The Grow from your
heart podcast I notice you guys watch
all the way to the end if the episodes
are about 25 or 30 minutes long trying
to keep it right about there also thanks
for all the great comments on the song
at the end of the podcast if you have
any questions Corrections comments your
concerns you know that I would love to
hear from you the email address is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
send me that constructive criticism or
that hate mail if that's what you got to
do I've got thick skin I can take it
also make sure you check out the website
iry genetics.com everything you need is
at IR genetics.com there's a link to
irir where you can get the seeds there's
a link to the Discord where you can come
hang out there's a link to the patreon
campaign everything is at IR
genetics.com all right I think that is
all I've got for you for this episode
I'll be back in a week with fresh new
content I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy Jersey Jake to baked and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another Dam
grab your p i find the
b in the sit back relax
roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning out to hear the vibr that Jeff in
our conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every
word every voice must now be heard
healing light through cannot this go
from your H your this rise up higher
Find Your Way grow from your your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
do educate and Elevate join the Journey
Don't Be Late open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof rust
that Chef will guide you through in this
goded find the new rise up higher Find
Your Way grow from your hearts every day
in the light We Stand real strong join
the movement sing the song
[Music]
o open minds to see the truth in the
soil lies the proof R Jeff will guide
you through in this Garden find a new
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light with
stand real strong join the movement sing
the song w o
[Music]
[Applause]