let's smoke and have a good time whoa yo
yo what up M if you done know this is
the vi of jir Morgan and right now
you're locked into grow with your heart
podcast right here with my Bren rer
[Music]
Jeff R Jeff you bad mother
yeah welcome to the show podcast world
I'm your host roster Jeff this is
episode
868 of the growth from your heart
podcast I've got a fun quick episode
about breeding lined up for us before we
jump into the breeding conversation I do
want to remind you that this podcast is
brought to you by our friends at AC
infinity.com that's right check out AC
infinity.com and use coupon code IA
checkout to save 10% on all of your AC
Infinity equipment also don't forget
about the sale at edirect decom that's
right everything at iire direct.com is
on sale and all seed orders over $100 do
get free shipping also a lot of people
have been asking about clones if I owe
you a clone I will ship those very soon
it has been negative degrees here you
don't want me shipping your clones in
negative temperatures they will not make
it most of the Clones will go out by the
time this episode airs and you're asking
when clones will be back in stock on iir
as soon as it warms up a little bit it
is stressful trying to ship clones and
manage clone orders in this weather so
give me until about the springtime when
it warms up a little bit across the
country we will put clones back on
idirect decom all right that's all of
the advertising I've got here at the
start of the show let's jump into the
breeding portion of today's podcast I do
have a website that website is iry
genetics.com at the top of that website
there is a row of tabs one of those tabs
does say grow help or grow questions if
you click on that Tab and send a good
grow question and I read your question
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
edirect
docomo and check your spam because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at idirect decom this is a fun
question and it goes just like this it
says bro bro it says I've listened to
all of your podcasts and some of them
more than multiple times I don't know
what more than multiple means but bro
thank you for listening so much uh thank
you for the loyal listenership thank you
for the multiple clicks and the views on
YouTube I do appreciate that it does go
on it says I love all of the knowledge
you put down hey bro thank you for
listening I love the support there is a
question in all of this that says I
would like to conduct a small breeding
project of approximately 10 plants I've
have heard you say at times that you can
use beer cups when breeding or feno
hunting can you talk about your process
say keep it going brother yes this is a
great uh this is a great project a great
idea this is a fun project for me to
talk about so this listener has heard me
talk about breeding projects that happen
in beer cups a lot of you people right
now are going what you can breed in beer
cups yes we don't need giant plants for
breeding we can do this in beer cups
also this listener said they wanted to
do about 10 plants um if I was going to
do beer cups part of why I do beer cups
is to do a lot more than 10 I can fit
I've got a tray that holds 24 plants I
put 24 in there I don't know what your
limit is I don't know what your plant
count is I don't do 24 anymore because
of plant counts and plant limits where I
am but I used to do 24 on the tray uh in
the commercial environment I would put
multiple trays of 24 to be honest with
you but I can fit 24 on a tray they can
fit under one light very easily that is
a very easy breeding project so in this
episode I'm going to focus on about 24
plants in a tray that's kind of what
we're going to talk about just cuz
that's how I would do this project I
don't encourage you to break the rules
violate the laws I'm not a lawyer I'm
not uh anybody that could tell you what
to do legally so enter at your own risk
follow the rules at your own risk you're
a [ __ ] adult do what you want I can't
encourage you to do illegal [ __ ] I'm not
doing illegal [ __ ] nobody here is doing
anything illegal let's follow the rules
and do this properly so where are we
we're going to talk about a small
breeding project uh this listener said
10 plans I've already touched that we're
going to do more than 10 in my idea um
so yeah breeding projects we're going to
jump right into this uh who what when
where why how how much are we going to
do this um let's say that you want to do
a a small breeding project why not this
is going to be a lot of fun this is a
way to do a breeding project very
quickly why do I choose a breeding
project in beer cups let's just start
right there uh you could use a much
larger pot you could do bigger pots and
have much more success with larger
plants yes but for a home grower for a
home breeder who just wants to make a
few seeds for themselves to play with uh
if you just need 30 50 maybe 100 seeds
of something this is a beautiful project
you can put so what I would do I've got
a tray it's a sterlite tray it's made to
put clothing or Goods to store it under
your bed it's real flat it's kind of
long and wide it's made to slide under
the bed so you can put your stuff in
there and stash all your goodies under
the bed and get more storage I said
under the bed enough times it feels
awkward now but it's an under the bed
storage bin um it's approximately I'm
holding up my hands I think that's about
2 feet by 16 in uh and it holds 24 beer
cups in it perfectly you can fit them in
there I think it's Rosa 4x6 is how it
fits and they just fit in there
perfectly so if you rattle it around
they won't fall over that's why I like
to fill the tray it keeps it full
nothing tips over so what I would do I
would cut 24 clones and I would put 24
clones in these little beer cups uh two
of those cuts would be the same male I
would do clones of the same exact male
so I've got 22 females and two cuts of
the same dude now all you've got to do
is veg those until they're four or five
maybe six or seven Ines tall at the most
and then flip them all at the same time
it doesn't take a lot of space it
doesn't take a lot of room it doesn't
take a lot of light doesn't take a lot
of soil water nutrients it really
doesn't take a lot of energy but if you
put 24 little plants in beer cups and
veg them up um maybe two GI Jo's tall
that's seven inches two GI Jo's I know
that's boy math but every boy knows what
I'm talking about two GI Jo's tall flip
them uh those plants will grow up to be
about 15 in tall you may need to put a
stick in there to keep them supported uh
if you don't have enough wind and light
going on depending on your environment
they may need some support but what will
happen is those plants will go into
flower on about 14 days the girls will
start telling you we're girls in about
14 days the two boy plants will verify
we are boys about 21 days in 22 25 days
in pollen will start coming out of your
boy plants you could simply leave them
all right there in the room and it will
pollinate or you could take one of those
boy plants and pick them up and dust
them around all those girl plants every
pistol in that room is going to get
pollinated by those two male plants that
will produce enough pollen I know it
sounds wild but uh it's really quick and
easy a short veg we need to veg them uh
like I said seven maybe 10 in tall at
the most that's going to get floppy in a
beer cup so keep them shorter it will be
easier to manage uh keep them short you
got a short veg time you're going to
flip them when they're s in tall so
we're already ahead of the game most
people aren't even done vegging yet most
people are going to transplant two times
before they flow you're already flipping
these plants so they're already into
Flower by the time you're pollinating I
haven't even transplanted to my next
bigger pot by the time you're done now
I'm transplanting so uh short veg flip
them pollinate then I would wait a week
or so make sure that the pollination is
successful if you've still got one male
plant that you haven't cut down in there
take that dude and do another
pollination with him at this point you
could chop down your mail plants get rid
of those maybe leave the cups in there
uh just to keep that tray from tipping
over if are the plants from tipping over
in the tray if you've packed 24 in there
like I suggested uh but you could do as
many as you want I'm just saying that 24
is how I do it uh then once you've done
your second pollination what I recommend
at this point and this is where a lot of
people are going to think I'm freaking
crazy I would turn those lights back to
18 hours on and 6 hours off I would do
that until these plants are finished the
plants are not going to look pretty to
be honest with you they're going to look
like [ __ ] 186 will make the plants look
ugly but you're not growing for flowers
at this point every pistol every calx is
filled with a seed there's no bud to
smoke there's no flow you're not going
to have anything useful to smoke out of
this it is all going to be completely
seated when we cut down these plants
which we'll talk about in a minute it
will be fully completely seated so when
you're running 186 and these plants
start to look completely shitty they're
going to go into rev Edge you're going
to see some whirl leaves but that's not
a big deal we are going for healthy
happy fat seeds and that's what we're
going to get by going to 18 hours on and
6 hours off so 6 to 8 weeks later it
will be Harvest Time at that point uh
what we're going to do it'll be very
very simple uh there's going to be
nothing but seeds in these plants so
don't even try to conserve any of it for
smokable material what I recommend is a
separate container container for each
plant if you've got multiple uh plants
of the same strain you can use that
container for multiple plants of the
same strain but we don't want to mix up
the seeds here so I would get some sort
of a bin uh turkey pans are a great
suggestion right now uh recently
recently I did an episode about
affordable grow equipment turkey pans
little turkey pans from uh the grocery
store those would work beautifully right
now so get a turkey pan get a plant uh
cut the plant down hang the plant let it
dry until it's completely dry when it is
completely dry take take that plant and
your turkey pan and pull the stick out
of all the buds just hold the buds with
your finger and just pull the stick
right out out of that it's a real short
stick all the buds will fall off into
your turkey pan then just use rubber
gloves and just Grind All That flour
material up real good uh real well then
all your seeds are going to fall out of
there all your weeds going to fall out
then simply tip that turkey pan to the
side all your seeds are going to roll
down to the bottom it's all going to be
seeds you can if you really want to make
edibles or something out of that
leftover flour product you can most of
the time it's so beat up that if you
make edibles or concentrate it comes out
green because the removal process it
beats it up it gives it so many broken
edges and so much surface area and so
much chlorophyll is freed that your
Edibles and your concentrates come out
green and funky so um to put it on 186
let the seeds finish it'll take six to
eight weeks for them to finish then chop
them hang them upside down let them get
dry as [ __ ] is my unit of measurement
then pull the sticks off the the buds
off the sticks grind it up separate the
seeds now you've got your first new new
cross now depending on the size of the
plant the amount of pistols on the plant
when you did this how far into maturity
that female plant was when it received
pollen there are a lot of factors here
uh but you should receive somewhere
between 25 and 150 seeds per plant if
you do this properly and if you've got a
tray of 22 plants you do the math 25 to
100 seeds per plant you've got quite a
few new seeds to play with as a very
experienced grower and breeder and
person who has had their heartbroken I
recommend you carefully label all of
these plants and do your best to keep
all of these seeds if you're running
multiple strains do your best to keep
them separated and very carefully
labeled this is your new passion project
you just spent weeks doing this uh make
sure you keep everything carefully
labeled once you get the seeds out of
the buds put them in a jar or a baggie
and label that jar or that baggie uh
whatever cross to whatever cross made on
this date um then put those somewhere
that you know they're safe cool dry dark
environment um let's talk a little bit
about feeding these seeded plants you've
got little beer cups don't overwater
them don't overfeed them that could be a
problem that could cause you major
problems if you overfeed these cups um I
basically feed uh it is kind of a flour
mix but I stick with the base nutrient
for the grow bottle if you're feeding
bottled nutrients I stick with the grow
base because I want that extra bit of
nitrogen in there to give me those
healthy fat seeds I'll also increase the
cow mag a little bit when I'm making
seeds and here's something I do not say
a lot on podcast this is a golden nugget
of information that I kind of keep
secret something I don't share a lot no
need to gatekeep anymore um I'm doing
very well I want you guys to do as well
as I am um a little bit of amino acids
will go very well for your seeds amino
acids are the building blocks of life
why not feed the seeds amino acids give
them a strong healthy start um I feed as
soon as I start seeing seed development
I start feeding the amino acids uh one
thing I skipped I didn't even write this
down when I said seed development brain
went ding ding let's talk about this
what about how do we tell when these
seeds are ready I keep saying about 6 to
8 weeks and you will have seeds um a lot
of people are really uh we have a hard
enough time judging when to cut down our
[ __ ] nonseeded plants when do I cut
it when do I cut it is one of the
biggest questions I ever get um the
answer to that is use a magnifying glass
and check out your tricomes most of the
time at this point we've got a seated
plant when do I cut it down um you're
going to see seeds popping out of some
of your buds some of your buds the top
cxes are going to explode and a little
seed is going to pop out of there when
you start seeing those seeds it is
almost time to harvest there are a lot
of seeds in there what I recommend is
just grab a seed you can see them
popping out of the buds out of the cxes
grab a seed from somewhere anywhere on
the plant if you see one grab that bad
[ __ ] just pick it out you you might do
a little bit of damage to the plant but
there's so many seeds in there it's
going to be okay don't don't freak out
pull out a seed shake off all the husk
the hole all the material all the green
material get that off of your seed find
that seed get in the palm of your hand
get it clean look at it what does it
look like does it look like it's the
right color is it getting tiger stripes
is it dark is it green is it pale if
it's green if it's pale if it's
yellowish it's probably not ready if
it's starting to get a dark color a
little bit of a shine to it starting to
get some tiger stripes you're probably
looking at a seed that is ready or very
close to ready the ultimate test to find
out if that seed is ready um my fingers
are trained for this I've got drummer
fingers and Seed breeder fingers drummer
fingers are different if you played
congas and drums for years I realized
recently my fingers are different I got
hard fingers uh but grab those seeds and
give them a squeeze just squeeze it I
squeeze it between my thumb and my
forefinger if it uh if the seed hurts
your finger when you squeeze it that
seed's ready if the seed explodes that
shit's not ready um I squeeze them
pretty hard before they break and that's
how I know that they're ready grab a few
seeds grab two or three grab them from
multiple plants you'll know when they're
ready they'll be really [ __ ] hard
wait a little bit longer if you don't
think that they're ready uh the pros and
cons of waiting too long and going too
early if you go too early and cut down
your seeds will not be done that's
heartbreaking let them [ __ ] finish if
you wait too long uh those seeds could
have a hard time germinating they may
become a little bit too strong the outer
shell becomes a little bit tough you'll
have to soak them you'll have to scarify
them to get them to germinate don't
worry most of the time you guys take
your [ __ ] down way too early so uh start
squeezing those seeds see if they're
hard if they're hard enough then they're
probably ready if
if you see Little Sprouts coming out of
your soil your seeds are ready uh what
happens a lot of times is a seed will
fall out of your plants that are growing
and this is what's supposed to happen
this is [ __ ] nature doing its thing
the seed will grow strong enough to grow
out of your plant it'll fall right out
of the plant into your soil you'll water
it not knowing that it's there and it
will germinate and it will grow right up
out of your soil now you got your
original plant and you got a sprout
growing out of there that's a sign that
your seeds are ready if the seeds are
falling out like that they are
absolutely ready for Harvest let me
check my notes um you're going to get
between I wrote down 30 to 100 seeds a
minute ago I said 25 to 150 that depends
on the size of the plant the health of
the plant um you'll learn after you do a
couple of breeding projects that
different plants want to be pollinated
at different times and you'll also learn
that different male plants put out
pollen at different times there's a time
frame where you can kind of standardize
it um the the method I if you put the
boys and the girls in the same room with
at the same time it's going to work
nature it works that way if you put Let
me I always use these two plants as an
example I've got a strawberry fields
plant that is the mom that makes uh
Raphael uh strawberry burst uh what else
does that bad [ __ ] make it doesn't
matter it's a strawberry fields plant
from Crockett it's amazing it makes a
lot of good [ __ ] I've also got a
platinum Tangi plant that is the mom to
the Michelangelo the orange GM uh that
one makes a lot of good [ __ ] also they
are both amazing plants however they are
very different in a lot of different
characteristics uh the Strawberry Fields
plant grows real tall and real lanky and
gives me real long buds the Platinum
Tangi kind of shorter squatter smaller
tighter buds uh more Maple Leaf kind of
a leaf structure the strawberries got
those big tropical long leaves the
strawberry plant wants pollen much later
than the Platinum Tangi plant um ideally
I would pollinate the strawberry plant
around day 35 and the Tangi plant around
like day 25 five so they're like 10 days
apart on when they want pollen so you'll
learn these sort of things as you grow
you'll learn that I should put this plan
in here on this week and then wait a
week and then put this plan in here you
learn to get the mail plant a week ahead
or a week behind it just takes
experimenting and and it's like learning
a partner it's like taking people out on
dates you got to see what they like do
they do they like your jokes do they
hate your jokes are they into the cow
mag or do they hate cow mag do they want
Bloom boosters at week six or would they
rather you just give them uh just
straight go with whatever your basic
feed is I'm just trying to make [ __ ] up
as we go but you've got to develop a
relationship with these plants that's
the art of breeding that is uh there's a
lot of science behind breeding I could
write you Sops that will work but you're
going to have to get in there and learn
the plants to figure out how to optimize
them make as many seeds as possible uh
by timing it by learning the mail when
does this male dump the most pollen some
boys uh start dumping at like 23 24 some
boys day 32 like I said earlier some
girls want pollen at day 23 some want
pollen day 33 so you just got to learn
how to time all of that when to get the
females that the ripest when they're
peeking for pollen and get the boy when
he's dumping the most pollen try to time
that up uh that is an art and a skill
that you will develop over a few crops
so at this point you have made a bunch
of brand new seeds you've got a bunch of
brand new crosses hopefully stuff that's
never been made before sounds like you
started off with at least 10 maybe you
did 24 plants maybe you did a 100 who
knows but you have got a bunch of brand
new seeds that you grew from little tiny
pots it only took a little bit of space
uh you could do this in a 3X3 tent you
could do this in a little tiny closet
you could build a little makeshift room
for this cuz they're not going to get
very tall uh there's a tent that lays on
its side uh it's a really short tent
that lays on its side it's not very tall
it's a propagation tent you could breed
seeds in that propagation tent if you
followed this advice that I just gave
you so at this point hopefully you've
got a bunch of brand new seeds now the
excitement is growing those seeds you
get to see what you just created maybe
you've got 10 new crosses maybe you've
got 20 new crosses uh you've got
somewhere between what's 20 times 25
that many do the math fill that in put
that number here you got that many new
crosses to grow with if you did a 100
you got 2500 new seeds to play with um I
recommend when you use a new male plant
when you use any male plant to pollinate
multiple females and then run the
progeny from those projects because what
we get to see now is that male and so
the male and female are going to breed
and all and instances they're going to
cross you're going to get an outcome and
we're just going to make stuff up for
this part of the conversation let's say
that the male is chocolate cuz that's
easy to remember I've got a male that
produces chocolate that's just the trait
we're going with and then we've got
strawberry and lemon females we're just
going to go hypothetical because I can
remember those I get high and forget
[ __ ] let's just say that we pollinate
chocolate to Strawberry we're probably
going to get chocolate strawberry turps
right we're going to get combos you're
going to see stuff that looks like
chocolate stuff that looks like
strawberry and chocolate strawberry what
so we're going to find traits in there
but how do we know what consistently the
Father the chocolate is passing to that
cross I want to see what he did to Lemon
Let's see if we get chocolate lemon are
there lemon turs are there chocolate
turs are there chocolate lemon turps or
do both of these crosses completely have
dominant chocolate turps was the other
flavor allowed to shine and I'm not just
going with just flavor but other traits
maybe chocolate put um a funky Leaf
shape in everything do all of my crosses
show this weird Leaf shape or does it
only come through on strawberry so let's
see how this male plays with others
let's see how it mixes amongst other
plants that's really the fun part of
discovering what your male plant does in
your breeding uh Crossing it to one
plant that could be an anomaly you could
say it makes the frostiest plants ever
how do you know that came from the male
that could have came from the female you
could say it makes the most amazing
chocolate turps yeah in that cross let's
do it with five six 12 different crosses
and see what the commonalities and the
differ differences is differences is you
guys know what I'm saying I talk a lot
you're going to make some weird
differences is kind of weird stumbles
not even going to edit that [ __ ] you're
going to see commonalities and
differences and that's the fun part of
breeding uh then you get to take those
traits further and what's really crazy
is when uh you don't see certain traits
in your breeding until F3 and then
something that was in the original
Parent pops up and you're like there's
that trait again anyway now I'm rambling
and getting excited about breeding I
hope you are as excited about breeding
as I am ladies and gentlemen cuz I love
breeding and growing cannabis
uh my friend Buckeye 420 my dude thank
you for the great question this one was
a full podcast episode I do appreciate
it make you make sure you check your
inbox because you do have a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at I direct.com
and I do encourage you and welcome you
and invite you to add my seeds to your
breeding project don't be shy a lot of
breeders out there have weird rules and
uh stick up their ass about breeding I
encourage you breed with my seeds you
bought them I made them with love so
that people out there can be successful
with them that's that's what I want
breed uh do your projects make yourself
successful why wouldn't I want you
successful I want to give you a good
foundation good building blocks build
that [ __ ] Castle my dude uh where are
we I feel like I've been rambling I
covered all of this stuff I think it is
time to wrap up a podcast this was a
good quick Show Ladies and Gentlemen
boys girls pimps hoes friends foes
smokers Growers clone Cutters pollen
Chuckers experienced
breeders activists dab heads uh maybe
you're just new and figuring out
cannabis and just Jumping In For the
First Time welcome and also thank you
again for listening to this podcast I do
appreciate uh the big audience you guys
are growing I've been getting a lot of
support I do appreciate it so thank you
again for listening to this episode if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns you know that I
would love to hear from you the email
address is grow fromy yourheart at
hotmail.com don't be shy reach out let
me know what you think of the show uh
everything else is on iy genetics.com
the growel tab is at IR genetics.com
there's a link to the Discord server
once again if you are stuck on the
Discord server uh we did update the
rules if you can't get past the new
rules page please do send me a message
we will help you get through that
basically click on the new rules and
etiquette page agree to that we'll let
you in we changed the rules and
etiquette Discord did some updates we
had to play along I invite you come back
there's a few of my friends that Miss
also you guys last episode I said that I
missed doobie dobie's [ __ ] back bro I
feel good I feel happy I feel relieved
it's good to have my buddy dubie back
big shout out to the whole Discord gang
uh we do talk a lot of trash in there we
do burn each other pretty hard in there
but don't know what the [ __ ] I would do
without the Discord gang much love boys
and girls join us on Discord it's a
party um everything else iir I
genetics.com there's a link to idirect
you can get the beans there's a link to
patreon you can support the show there's
also a tab that says join the mailing
list click on that guess what it will do
sign you up for the mailing list that
way every time I put out new episodes or
I put out new products or I put
something on sale you will get an update
all I think that's all I've got for this
episode I've been rambling on for no
reason and dragging this good episode
out uh let's wrap it up now and say
goodbye um I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
shout out to my buddy Tony Minnesota and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] tell take another DB gra
your p in and I about the
b in the lab sit back
relax roots and wisdom start
to from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning now to hear the vibr that Jeff in
our conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard heing like
the canot this go from your heart your
this rise up higher Find Your Way grow
from your hearts every day in the light
We Stand real strong join the movement
sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a do educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof r that jef will guide you
through in this GED find the new rise up
higher Find Your Way grow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong join the movement sing the
song
[Music]
the minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find the new rise up higher Find Your
Way grow from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
[Music]
[Applause]