[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the podcast everybody I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 86 9 of the
grow from your heart podcast in today's
podcast I'm going to talk about
selecting a phenotype before we get to
that part of the show I want to send a
couple of shout outs to a few of my good
friends on patreon let's send a big
thank you shout out to my buddy Danny
pots let's send a fist bump to Roman
roots and let's wrap it up with a big
fist bump and a shout out to my buddy
Wasted Years big thanks and big shout
out to everybody who supports the show
on patreon if you would like to support
the show all you have to do is visit
www. patreon
/g fromy yourheart all of the
information you will need will be right
there on the screen I also cordially
invite you to join us on the Discord
server that's right we have updated the
vibe on the Discord server there are new
rules on the Discord server so if you've
been stuck on Discord and can't get past
that rules and etiquette page click on
the rules and etiquette click on the new
rules and agree to that and you will be
allowed back on the Discord server if
you haven't already joined I do invite
you come hang out with us there are a
lot of great things on the the Discord
server uh first of all there is a strain
description and a strain report on
almost every strain available from IR
genetics right now they're in
alphabetical order they're separated by
regular and feminized uh you can click
on those strains and you can see grow
reports from the grow Community from the
IE Army you can see pictures uh grow
details you can ask questions you can
interact with people that have grown
those strains so if you want full grow
reports full grow details join us on
Discord those reports are on the Discord
server there are also a lot of grow
guides there are Sops on there uh clone
care sop uh the STS and reversal sop is
on there a lot of great things on the
Discord server also there are several
lounges where you can come smoke and
hang out with us there's a smoker Lounge
at Gamers Lounge come hang out join The
Vibes uh we have changed a lot of Vibes
and a lot of energy in the room lately I
Cally invite you to come hang out with
us on the Discord server there will be a
link in the show notes and the video
description also there is a link on my
website iry genetics.com okay I feel
like I've been rambling for a long time
let's get out of that let's work our way
here into the question and answer
portion of today's podcast I did say
we're going to talk about selecting a
phenotype I have a question that came
from my website iry genetics.com this
question came from my new friend
Alexander K the question goes a lot like
this it says rosted Jeff when you were
pheno hunting what parameters do you
personally search for in flowers and
hash this is a very good question so in
this episode we are going to focus on
selecting a phenotype for flour I mainly
grow personally for flour um I'm working
my way towards growing things for
concentrates but I'm not a concentrate
maker I do love to smoke the
concentrates but I grow mostly for
flower when I do grow the flower the
flower gets smoked as flowers um there
are plenty of other great concentrate
makers out there doing that uh let's
stick to the point here so in this
episode we're going to talk about
selecting a phenotype for flower now
what do I mean about this what do I mean
by selecting a phenotype a lot of people
uh might not even know what that means
what am I talking about when we buy a
pack of seeds uh whether they are
regular or feminized or even autoflow
seeds when you make seeds uh depending
on the filial generation of how far down
those seeds have been bred when seeds
are created there are going to they're
going to express different phenotypes
when they are grown so if I take we'll
just say we're going to say Golden Goat
and daybreaker I cross those two plants
together that makes my famous strain
called arise when you grow the arise f1s
that first filial generation not all of
the seeds look exactly not all of the
plants that come from those seeds will
look exactly the same some are going to
look more like golden goats some are
going to look more like a r or more like
daybreaker some are going to look just
like both parents perfectly combined
some are going to be weird mutants weird
different uh weirdos uh different
expressions of the genes however they
collided within that uh that breeding uh
think think about if think about
families that you know think about
brothers and sisters that you know uh
they've got the same parents but the
brother and the sister they'll have
similar uh characteristics and also uh
very different characteristics maybe one
of them's got so we'll say dad's got
blue eyes mom's got brown eyes maybe one
of The Offspring maybe both of The
Offspring have brown eyes that means
dad's got a dominant gene that he's
passing down that browney genan uh if
they both have different color eyes then
nobody's carrying a dominant eye color
Jean so it just depends on how the jeans
col slide when the breeding happens I
think I said that correctly that all
came out of the top of my head somebody
check me on my [ __ ] breeding chart
right there with mom and dad and my Gene
passing uh Theory there uh argue about
it in the comments I encourage you
educate me please if I said something
because I said it really quickly I'm
guessing second guessing myself so a
phenotype is just the different
expressions of those genetics also it's
based on it could be based on
environment a lot of this could be based
on how the plants are fed so it's a the
expression of a plant in a certain
environment the expression of that
genotype in a specific environment so
we're going to run uh we'll say that you
got 10 we'll just go with femin seeds
this time we'll say you got a six pack
of seeds we're going to see some
differences in there when we grow those
plants we're going to see uh maybe very
drastic differences maybe very minute
differences maybe you won't see a lot of
visual difference but when you smoke
them you might notice a lot of aromatic
or flavor or effect differences so a
phenotype a phenotype is the different
variation that we're seeing amongst the
population in the room I didn't Google
gole that I'm just pulling that
definition out of what I understand as a
grower that's what a phenotype is to me
uh the different when we grow plants we
see different Expressions that is a
phenotypical expression it can change if
you so if we take the same clone and
grow it in a different room we'll see
different Expressions that's a whole
another thing to [ __ ] talk about so
how do you find or how do I find when
I'm hunting what parameters do I
personally search for uh when finding a
phenotype one thing I want to touch on
is um when I've started putting strains
out on the internet and talking about
strains that I've bred I highlight
specific phenotypes that I have found
amongst these seed packs or amongst
these breeding projects or amongst the
progyny of cultivars I'm just trying to
use big words at this point um I have
given some of these phenotypes like
people know about the Mean Girl
phenotype and people know uh they're
just certain phenotypes that come from
certain plants they've been given names
and labeled uh they've gotten wellknown
I like doing that that's really cool
there's the uh the Painted Lady cut of
the Afterglow which has gotten famous at
this point kind of that's the Painted
Lady cut it's got its own name because
it came from the Painted Lady so those
cuts have their they get their own names
but what I saw the downside to that is
now sometimes you guys will run a pack
of seeds and you'll be looking for the
phenotype that I liked which is super
cool I bred it I understand why you want
the one that I liked but I'm not going
to smoke the pack that you're growing
you are so find the phenotype that you
like I appreciate I love I respect I
admire the fact that you guys want to to
find the phenotype that I'm smoking and
uh you want to find that one but what
about the one that grows best for you um
the way I like to describe it is you
agreed when you bought the pack of
whatever you got we'll say arise um
we'll say that arise I'm just making
[ __ ] up as we go here is Italian food
right you'll say you went through the
website you're like I'm not sure what I
want you settled on a certain pack of
seeds for a reason you're like oh it's
got this it's got this and it does this
I want this so you bought it you know
that the the thing you want is in that
pack of seeds that you've got the Allure
already you're looking you've got a
taste you've got an idea of what you
want you have to find the phenotype that
your brain makes you think you want the
way I describe it is that arises Italian
food right you're scrolling around
you're like what restaurant do I want oh
Italian food sounds good you've settled
on Italian now the phenotype is which
dish at that Italian restaurant do I
want because it's mostly all going to be
red sauce it's going to be noodles or
maybe you want the white sauce and the
Noki but it's all going to be Italian
it's going to have that Italian flavor
to it so you bought a pack of Italian
food now it's just your turn to pick off
the menu the favorite Italian food that
you want the way to do that don't listen
to me um I'm not going to choose you
don't want me to choose your meal for
you I'm uh mostly vegetarian most of the
time and I like garlic [ __ ] I like kind
of spicy I put some capers in there that
might not be for you at all you may be a
full red sauce and meatballs kind of guy
I don't judge you just don't order my
food I won't order yours so what I'm
saying is don't pick the phenotype that
I want pick the phenotype that you want
the way to do that is to grow those
seeds grow them and I highly recommend
grow them all in the same conditions you
can't tell uh what's standing out you
can't tell who's better if you didn't
give everybody the same thing if you
gave this one plant recharge you gave
this one grow dots you gave this one uh
green sensation of course you're going
to see different [ __ ] give them all the
same exact thing uh do the feno Hun so
grow your plants until you can get a
clone take two or three clones off of
Every Plant label your plants I like to
give them numbers or letters plant one
plant two plant three it's not that hard
um especially if you're just running
small numbers a six pack of seeds 1 2 3
4 5 six label them when you take clones
give the Clones the corresponding number
clone one goes with plant one clone
number two came off of plant number two
then now we've got clones for those now
we we've got Keepers just in case we do
find something phenomenal and we want to
run that again we've got Keepers in the
Clone Dome they're over there waiting
for us pot those later when the time
comes so you run the pack of seeds you
get clones from everybody put them into
flour feed them all the same thing take
some notes as they're growing here's
where you're going to have two different
um different opinions as a grower
there's going to be one phenotype that
[ __ ] bangs out for you it's going to
put out all the weight uh it's going to
be huge it's going to be Frosty there's
going to be another one that smells
super good there's not those are never
the same [ __ ] phenotype the super
good smeller or the Frosty and the big
weight two different phenotypes you'll
get all three of those traits broken
down maybe two of those traits into two
different phenos but it's hard to get
all three when you find all three that's
a [ __ ] 10 that's a keeper so run the
pack of seeds watch them as they grow as
the grower take notes which one was the
easiest or most pleasurable to grow also
take notes which one was the most pain
in the ass to grow there will be one
that's harder than everybody else to
grow that's just how it goes uh one's
going to be harder one's going to be
easier were those your favorite or least
favorite plants to grow think about that
then later on or also did one of did you
get spider mites did one handle that
better uh did one give you more weight
did one taste better did one give you
more tricomes uh did one have just a
crazy good [ __ ] smell uh was one
indestructible did you beat the [ __ ] out
of the plants and this one just shine
through like a warrior uh pay attention
to the plants as the grower then uh
Harvest them finish the plants grow them
to your best possible ability then
Harvest them dry them cure them trim
them to the best of your ability
then put them have them all in separate
jars the entire time plant one through
six all in separate jars all the buds
all the way through so that when we
smoke them we can take a bong rip or
smoke a bowl or smoke a joint or vape it
however you want to do it if you're
boofing it whatever you're up to but
take sample number one start with the
fresh clear head first smoke of the day
and take a smoke or a boof of sample
number one and see what it does to you
sit there for a minute taste it does
that taste real good does it taste bad
does it taste like what I want uh does
it taste like something I do not want or
maybe does this taste like something I
can sell that might be what you got to
worry about then enjoy number one take
notes if you're that kind of person um
write down your notes try not to let
here's the hard part try not to let your
um your bias as a grower uh come into
play as the smoker you may already be
thinking number two was the easiest to
grow put out all those tricomes I want
number two to be the winner don't do
that separate the grower from the smoker
you and let's just smoke them uh very
discerningly uh smoke number one get
your judgment then the next day wake up
fresh whenever you start smoking smoke
sample number two think about it how
does it taste how does it feel is it
what I want is it not what I want uh
there's a lot of things that you can
think about when it comes to selecting
your product uh is it first you're going
to see visually is it visually appealing
to me is it bright green is it dark
green is it blue is it black we is crazy
colors now is it [ __ ] purple is it
visually appealing does it smell good
not only does it smell good does it
smell like the flavor I was hoping to
get out of this package of seeds smoke
it does it taste the way that I was
hoping to get out of this package of
seeds the buzz exactly the same story
how is the buzz is this what I want are
you an Indica guy is this indica weed uh
are you a daytime smoker is this going
to be good for a daytime smoke do you
have a medical requirement will this
meet that requirement uh will this reach
your clients your client tells demands
so think about that as you're smoking it
work your way through sample one through
six try them all um try some with your
friends if you got a couple of good
friends at like I've got Mike that would
come over if I was like Mike we got to
do a feno hunt smoke selection Mike's
[ __ ] by the time I hung up the phone
the door would open he'd like come here
buddy let's smoke like everybody wants
to come help you out with a feno hunt so
do that pay attention to the jars the
first jar to get empty in your feno hunt
it's probably the plant that you should
keep that's probably the one you should
smoke the first one to go empty is the
one you liked the most uh you don't go
for your least favorite [ __ ] candy
every time you go for the first favorite
candy if there's a color of whatever you
got some candies INF ferny you got a
chocolate strawberry vanilla whichever
one your favorite is disappearing first
right you're going to take that
chocolate one every time most people
they going to be left with strawberry
and vanilla and be sad but that's how
you know which one is the best one that
jar that runs out of weed first grow
more of that that is probably the
phenotype that you want not even looking
at the notes let me get back on track
grow the pack run them do all the same
[ __ ] to every single one of them uh take
a clone from them so that oh yeah we've
got that clone that we took earlier that
one maybe two maybe do like a a tiered
system do a bracket match start with six
narrow it down to two take your favorite
two phenotypes and if you're allowed to
grow six plants cut three of each one if
you're allowed to grow you see the point
here fill half the room with one half
through them with the other run them
exactly the same round two fight let's
see who comes out better this time one
of those phenotypes is going to stand
out now you only got two to choose from
now which jar empties more quickly yeah
let's see how that happens so narrow it
down like a cage match start with six
then run your favorite two but you got
those clones back there that's what I
was [ __ ] talking about we got the
Clones keep the clones from your
favorite too we can run that forever we
got a mother plant if you took
successful clones don't let those clones
go away take clones keep Cuts
preservation all the time you can always
have those always do your bracket uh
cage match system so run the pack run
them all the same get your clones finish
them properly smoke them enjoy them try
not to let the grower in you be the
judge and let the smoker be the judge
because that's really what matters
that's where the money is no one's going
to see what happens in the grow except
you if one plant yielded you two pounds
and one yielded one pound I get why that
one even if it [ __ ] smokes the best
you still may have to do some
consideration with that if you're a cash
Cropper but weigh your pros and cons and
see what you got to do so um let me make
sure what Fen what are your parameters
now I've talked about I told you to how
to check yours I'm going to kind of tell
you how I do mine um most important to
me and I've kind of hinted at this um
the most important is Buzz and effects
where I'm not smoking just to taste it
I'm not smoking I'm not growing to look
at it I'm not grow growing I am not
growing just to post the [ __ ] to
Instagram I'm smoking this [ __ ] growing
it to smoke it to get high that's what
I'm trying to say here uh you take seven
dabs and come do a podcast and don't
stutter seven times you'll be all right
uh most important thing to me is of
course the buzz what else matters we're
we're going to [ __ ] smoke this to get
high that's what I want so the buzz does
it have a good Buzz a strong Buzz a
longlasting buzz and the type of Buzz
that I enjoy I like a lot of different
buzzes I like a nice head ringer
something that makes me [ __ ] like
when you're doing a podcast you think
you saw [ __ ] moving over there but
there's nothing over there about a wall
but sometimes bro the shit's moving over
there that's how you know you're smoking
good [ __ ] right or when you go to Target
and you got a shopping cart filled with
stuff and something in your head goes
hey man we got to leave man and you're
like but we're just shopping and your
heart goes I'm racing man we got to go
man and you just have to leave Target
that's the [ __ ] smoke I love so if
it's got that kind of buzz for me
awesome uh some people don't want that
kind of buzz some people smoke that buzz
and just grab their head and be like bro
I got to go lay down like it's just not
for some people so does it have the buzz
I want uh does that buzz have legs does
it last a little while for me I noce
some stuff I could smoke it and I get
[ __ ] wrecked for a minute and I'm
like that was really good weed hey wait
a minute I'm I got to smoke more weed
and I'm just not even high anymore like
some weed has no legs is what we what we
call that the next category that I think
I check on and this is as a smoker this
is not as a grower I'll talk about as a
grower I guess next um the next most
important thing is flavor and Aroma it's
got to taste good like if it doesn't
taste and smell good uh what's the point
there's so much good [ __ ] out there why
have something that doesn't taste
[ __ ] delicious so it's got to taste
good it's got to burn right um that goes
along with it that's the smoke ability
the flavor the aroma and overall smoke
ability do I enjoy the smoke does it
taste good how does it feel some weed
will leave a a funk on your lips some
will make your tongue [ __ ] dry and
crusty which sometimes I'll enjoy if
it's good weed uh the GMO will leave
that just coating on your tongue so we
going and everybody knows you got truck
mouth and you're like [ __ ] my [ __ ] is
dry bro
uh but smoke ability does it burn good
um most of the time that's a dry and
cure issue but some of it you just don't
like the way it even [ __ ] smokes it
gets hot it doesn't burn well it's a dry
and cure issue but uh flavor and Aroma
are my next uh categories there then
obviously visual I talked about that a
moment ago um visuals are a lot of it
even if the visuals don't have anything
to do with how it tastes or how I get
high from it but I like looking at
beautiful photogenic quality well done
weed so first C atory Buzz it's got to
get me [ __ ] lit up second category
flavor that shit's got to taste good
third category it's got to look pretty
for the bag so now let's talk about
growth characteristics and then we're
going to get out of this fine show here
uh growth characteristics that I do look
for in a pheno uh hunt uh basic shape
and structure and frame of the plant can
it hold itself up is it going to is it a
wispy piece of [ __ ] is it toppling over
can it support itself are the is it big
enough strong enough branches to hold
gigantic buds um then the next thing I
think about is leaf size and shape
because that's going to indicate a lot
of the buzz to me like it tells me long
skinny leaves probably [ __ ] crazy
sativa going to give me that [ __ ]
sort of Buzz that I like also going to
take a while to grow if it's got those
big fat indicia leaves uh that you could
camp under and build a shack with uh
it's not going to take as long to flower
it's going to give me a nice chilled out
sedative Buzz so that's a good hint of
what's going to happen uh then Bud type
and density how does that bud grow
um if it just grows wispy and shitty I
might not want to [ __ ] with it if it's a
nice looking bud is it Rocky is it
fluffy is it cone shaped is it got a
bunch of rocks a bunch of Blockhead at
the top I pay attention to that sort of
stuff then I want to think about like
tolerance uh can it handle uh problems
like heat cool overfeed underfeed uh
forgot to feed uh too much humidity um
drought all of the above problems
whatever you're going to do to it all
the things you [ __ ] up and forgotten
or accidentally did to your plants how
are these going to react that's what I
want to know like cuz sometimes I'm
going to [ __ ] up I'm a really good
experienced grower sometimes I [ __ ] up
sometimes the equipment [ __ ] up just
[ __ ] goes wrong so are the plants going
to handle it if there's a small medium
problem in the grow uh resistance then
or tolerance was what I was talking
about now resistance do these plants are
they prone to getting insects there are
some strains they just [ __ ] love bugs
and some strains uh blue dream is such a
shitty strain that spidermites don't
even like it I'm just joking around you
guys there's a bunch of hate for blue
dream in the commercial industry um it's
just a joke it's not that bad but um
yeah spidermites don't even like blue
dream so there are some cultivars that
spidermites won't go toward them there's
some that you could put three cultivars
in a room and the mites go that one and
they just head right for that
[ __ ] for some reason so is it
resistant uh to spider mites thrips
fungus snats powdery mildew Bud rot uh
is it the right type of so maybe perhaps
you're going to be growing outdoors in a
specific climate is it the right kind of
phenotype for your environment all my
friends on the coast up in the North
Coast the East and the West like do have
something that can handle a lot of fog a
lot of moisture and finish before I get
[ __ ] too wet outside that's a
phenotype that you guys could look for
um so those are things that I would pay
attention to the growth uh the shape the
structure a lot of same things I look
for when breeding um how does it grow is
it a pain in the ass does it handle does
it handle my room my program my feeding
that's also going to be a big factor CU
I'm not going to change the entire room
for one [ __ ] plant it's got to fit in
like fit in or get out that's the way I
feel about it so let me make sure that I
have covered all of my notes here
because I got a lot of stuff going on
basically pick the grow it grow that
[ __ ] pick the phenotype that you want
all of the advice that I give you about
phenotype the bottom line is pick the
one that you want the one you love to
grow and the one you love to smoke the
bottom line probably I must have watched
some Stone Cold [ __ ] cuz that's the
bottom line and and Stone Cold said so
but [ __ ] the end of the day the empty
jar is the one that people like the most
uh the one that's going to sell the best
it will probably get smoked up and
consumed the quickest so I think I've
covered more than enough on how to
select a phenotype this is going to be a
quick episode I'm not even sure how long
I rambled it maybe a full length episode
with all the chattery [ __ ] going on in
my head today ladies gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers uh
pheno Hunter All of You Beautiful
cannabis enthusiasts out there I want to
thank you once again for listening to
another fun episode of the podcast I
didn't take many notes and I talked for
a long time those are always my favorite
shows hope you had as much fun as I did
uh make sure you check my website iry
genetics.com everything you need is
there there's a link to the Discord
server join us on Discord like I said
earlier there's a link to
iir and iir you can get seeds all seed
orders over $100 do come with free
shipping that's right over over
not even going to edit just going to
keep cruising one take uh orders over
$100 do come with free shipping at
edirect decom there may be some cuts on
there when you check that I'm not sure
if the cuts have sold out by the time
you look there might be some new Cuts
coming up pay attention stay tuned also
join the newsletter on IR genetics.com
to scroll to the bottom click stay up to
date type in your email address you will
be on the mailing list all right niece
and nephew that's all I've got for you
for this episode I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content I want to give a
big shout out to skunkman Sam and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another DB
grab your p in and I find the
back is in the lab sit back relax hold
up roots and wisdom start to s from the
Ning seeds we grow tuning now to hear
the vibr that Jeff in our conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard healing
light to can this go from your heart
your bliss rise up higher Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
We Stand real strong join the movement
sing the
song Natural Medic in and love flows
within us like a do educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof RF will guide you through in
this God did find the new rise up high
up Find Your Way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the song
[Music]
open minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find the new rise up higher Find Your
Way broke from your hearts every day in
the light We Stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
o
[Music]
[Applause]