[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother welcome back podcast world I'm
your host rosta Jeff this is episode 870
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got a great podcast lined up
for us in today's show I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in the
show before we get too far I do want to
let you know that I have updated the
coupon codes at AC infinity.com that's
right this podcast is brought to you by
our friends at AC infinity.com if you
use my coupon code iy Army at AC
infinity.com you will save 10% off of
your purchase the reason I did have to
update that coupon code is because now
those codes are available for Amazon and
eBay the big benefit to that is if you
are shopping on Amazon you can use your
Amazon Prime for free shipping on the
smaller AC Infiniti items also the taxes
will be cheaper if you shop on
amazon.com depending on your location so
use that coupon code I Army at AC
infinity.com or the Amazon and or eBay
store for AC infinity and get that 10%
coupon code all right there's no more
advertising at the start of the show
let's jump right into it I do have a
bunch of great content planned out for
you I got a great comment on YouTube
that I wanted to address here on the
podcast this one came from YouTube like
I said it came from somebody called ZZ
trop and they said something that's been
getting my attention a phrase that's
been popping up something that I just
wanted to address uh this could almost
be a pet peeve if you will I'm sure if
you've been watching you remember for a
little while I was doing growroom pet
peeves uh things that just drive me
crazy uh the phrase in this message just
for some reason it bugs me let's jump
right into it it says hey rosta Jeff how
does a seed increase work multiple
multiple male pollination or a selected
male so the question is how does a seed
increase work and uh I don't even know
man what the [ __ ] is a seed increase a
seed increase is a new word that I've
recently heard popping up in the
Cannabis industry uh people are like I'm
going to do a seed increase um you're
going to make more seeds is what that
means yes I get it but the problem with
that is it's not an increase every time
you put that male plant to that female
plant you work creating a filial an F1
filial generation of something and or at
the same time progressing a filial
generation or you're doing something a
backat cross it's not just a seed
increase unless you're doing s1's
possibly you may consider that a seed
increase that's the only possible way
that the term seed increase would work
in my brain but I see this term being
applied and maybe it's a real
Horticultural term I did not Google it
I'm just saying uh that drives me crazy
what the [ __ ] is a seed increase you're
either making more fem seeds or making
reg seeds and at that Point use the
correct terminology are you making
because you're making another generation
and label it properly if you took a pack
of we'll say Jack Tripper seeds you
could get a boy you could get a girl you
could pollinate you've made more seeds
but you did not make more Jack Tripper
f1s you've now made f2s so label that
properly it's not a seed increase it's a
forward in some sort of filial
generation so uh how does a seed
increase work I don't know man um that's
just something that recently popped up
in the [ __ ] cannabis ganja growing
breeding seeding world I don't like the
phrase seed increase because that just
makes it sound like I'm going to create
more seeds but to do that like I've
stated there's got to be a forward
filial generation unless you're only
making s1's which then just say I'm
going to make s1's I'm going to self it
I'm going to make fem which makes a lot
more sense I've got more notes I wrote
down on this paper it's a new term what
the [ __ ] does that mean that's what I
wrote uh every pollination is a
generation so just label it as such it's
either an F1 an S1 an R1 uh maybe it's
an F7 very unlikely but it could be but
that makes more sense to me than the
phrase seed incase I don't know what
that means I I understand what it means
you're going to make more seeds to make
the seeds available but it's deeper than
that bro label it properly have some
more uh some more care for your project
label it tell us what it is uh I get it
you're making more seeds but what
generation are these seeds cuz that will
matter um some people are going to say
why are you so picky why you so critical
about it uh that's my job to be picky
and critical about this part if you're
going to make more seeds they should be
properly labeled with the generation
that's part of what breeding is part of
what a good breeder does so just label
it properly uh that is my ramble rant
for the day all right zey trop thank you
for the great question you got me fired
up uh we're going to keep this podcast
moving I do have a website that website
is IR genetics.com at the top of that
website there is a row of tabs one of
those tabs does say grow help or grow
questions if you click on that tab you
can send me a grow question if I read
your question here on the podcast I will
send you a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at idirect decom the question
that came from the growel tab today came
from my new friend green te hey green
tea make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for
free seeds the question goes just like
this it says this is more of a breeding
question oh it actually starts with
greetings from Ireland big shout out to
my friends in Ireland it's great to know
we've got Irish Growers out there it
says this is more of a breeding question
please how do you store your pollen long
term we are still in an illegal country
so we have to do things on a very small
scale that's understandable also will
lemon Jeffree seeds be coming back
that's a very common question yes I will
make more lemon Jeffree seeds um I like
making new things I like I've only
limited I'm limited on how many things I
can make uh the lemon Jeffree is super
popular but I like making new [ __ ] I
will make more lemon Jeffrey is the
bottom line but it's going to be a
little while so the question here um is
uh how do we store pollen long term
because we're in an illegal country have
to do things on a small scale uh yeah
that's a great question make sure you
check your inbox for the free seeds now
let's adjust or let's uh address this
question how do we store pollen long
term I recently used some pollen that
was stored for about a year and it did
not give me great results I have used
pollen that has been stored for 3 months
and 6 months the 3-month pollen seems to
be the best that six-month Mark is when
it really starts fizzling out 3 months
is good two months is cool a month is
great but after two three months I think
really it starts losing its potency it's
Vigor so uh don't store that pollen for
too long as my first piece of advice uh
my advice you may find better advice
that will say you can store it for a
long time uh I can take if I take a big
bag of pollen and sprinkle it across a
room and that pollen is 2 months old uh
I should get so many seeds If it's 6
months old I'm going to get half as many
seeds as what I've noticed a year old I
bar got any seeds so that older pollen
it just starts to degrade it's pollen uh
it's not going to last forever but let
me get to my notes here um first thing
pollen collection a lot of this is going
to start when you were collecting the
pollen we've got to get that pollen bone
dry so when you collect the pollen
however you do it uh you can take it
from the plant while the plant is alive
and upright or you can chop the tops and
put them on a container and collect the
pollen some sort of way on a glass
container a cardboard box um collect it
that way tap it get the pollen out let
it dry get more pollen one of the most
important parts is to pull out all of
the vegetation all of the male flowers
that are that come with your pollen get
that out of there anything green
anything leafy anything that is not
pollen use a sifter a screen and some
tweezers and get all that [ __ ] out of
there because that will contaminate your
pollen with moisture and moisture is one
of the number one problems the number
one Killers for this pollen so when you
collect it make sure that you get all
the greenery out all this male flour
Parts anything that contains any
moisture get that out of we don't want
any moisture I'm going to say that a
bunch of times we want to get this
pollen nice and dry I would recommend
adding a silicate packet if you can not
a bovita packet not a moisturizing
packet we want something to suck up the
moisture and make it as dry as possible
the silicate packs that they put in food
products the silicate packs that they
put in your jacket pockets when you buy
those they we want this nice and dry
something like that so get the pollen
dry get all the male flowers out then
put it into an airtight container uh you
can use a glass jar if that's your
preferred method you can use a plastic
baggie if that's your method sometimes a
plastic vessel will give you uh static
electricity and your pollen will move
around it will be a pain in the ass so
maybe not one of those plast I've seen
people try to use like a plastic peanut
butter jar and the static electricity
went crazy the pollen went everywhere it
probably killed the pollen if you now
that I'm thinking about it but I
recommend a glass jar or I've been using
plastic baggies and putting the multiple
plastic baggies inside of a glass jar
uh so I recommend an airtight uh
sealable container so we got the pollen
we've gotten all the [ __ ] out of it it's
dry now we seal it into an airtight
container uh if you can get an opaque
glass jar that would be ideal label and
date your jar or whatever vessel you use
right uh whatever pollen arise F3 pollen
January 5th 2029 I'm just making [ __ ] up
here write the T the date and the strain
on there so that you've got a clear
indicator of what that was especially if
you're [ __ ] with more than one kind
of pollen so now we've got a dry batch
of pollen with silicate packs and an
opaque jar that is labeled and it's
airtight now at this point that pollen
is pretty preserved the best you're
going to get it now at this point I
would put it in either the crisper
drawer and the refrigerator or maybe
even the freezer I've done both and I've
had similar results with both options
the crisper drawer where the vegetables
should go that's also where I keep my
seeds uh you can put the the pollen jar
right in there
uh maybe put that in a bag a brown paper
bag to keep it dark uh just add that
extra layer of Darkness cuz darkness is
also your enemy when it comes to pollen
so take that pollen it's dry it's got
all the [ __ ] removed it's got a silicate
packet in there it's in a dark jar it's
sealed it's airtight it's in a brown
paper bag then I put that either in my
freezer or in that crisper drawer and I
store it uh Mark the date on that then
you know how long it's been in there
have an idea of when you're going to use
it have an idea for it coming up uh cuz
it will expire so I I think that's most
of my notes it's only reliable for about
3 months maybe six uh some of the notes
that I definitely wrote down are once
you store this pollen in a cool dry dark
space especially if it's the freezer
don't remove it from the freezer until
it is time to use it uh I say this about
seeds as well coming from the cool into
the warm environment uh especially if
you're in a warm like a summer
environment and your fridge is nice and
cool you're going to create condensation
this bottle here there's no condensation
left it's been sitting out it's going to
show you my condensation it's been out
of the fridge for just a little bit
that'll start dripping down your jar you
don't want any of that condensation to
form near your pollen so don't pull it
out until you're ready to use it that
one time is just enough leave it in
there until it's time to pollinate then
go get it don't take it out and show
your friends a bunch of times don't get
it out and stare at it and think about
it if you put it in the freezer leave it
in the freezer until it is it is time to
use same thing with that crisper drawer
we don't want to create any moisture any
condensation in that pollen I used to
say that moisture killed the pollen
that's sort of true but not accurately
true the water uh activates the pollen
and makes it do its thing so it spins
itself is kind of it activates it and
makes it do its process and then after
that then it's spent and it cannot be
active anymore so the way that it is
killing it but there's it's not it's not
exactly what's happening but the water
will destroy the pollen overall uh and
so will the light so don't let too moist
too much moisture get in there don't let
any moisture get in there if you're
using the fridge technique avoid
condensation and then when you do take
out that pollen to use it if you decide
today is the day to pollinate these
plants when you remove that pollen from
your freezer or your refrigerator leave
it in a room temperature area and let it
come to temperature slowly don't rush it
don't speed it up and don't apply it to
the plants while it's still frozen or
still cold let it get to room
temperature slowly let it take 12 hours
if that's what it takes but let it get
to the room temperature before you apply
that pollen uh that'll help you out a
little bit as well so I think I covered
most things collect it get it dry dark
airtight label crisper or freezer only
rely on it for two maybe three possibly
6 months at the most I used stuff that
was a year old and I'm not satisfied
with my results I apologize you are not
getting the seeds I hoped you would get
you didn't even know that they were
coming uh let it adjust to temperature
and don't pull it out of the freezer too
often that's basically my advice on
storing your pollen um I don't have a
lot of advice for much longer term wish
I did uh pollen just seems to degrade
it's a it's a time sensitive uh product
I'm sure there's somebody out there I'm
sure that there is somebody out there
with a much more scientific approach and
scientific advice my friends I'm not
afraid of constructive criticism or to
be educated on my own show if you have a
better more reliable uh scientific way
that a home grower could store their
pollen for future use the comment
section is why it open let's hear about
it tell me how you're storing pollen in
the comment section guys don't be afraid
go have a conversation down there I
encourage Community interaction speaking
of community interaction don't forget
about the Discord server keep this
conversation going on the Discord server
as well uh there will be a link in the
show notes and in the video description
we've made some changes to the Discord
come hang out the vibe is different the
crew is different uh if you're stuck on
the rules I've said this a few times we
updated the new rules and regulations uh
the etiquette and rules it might say you
just have to reclick on that click on
that tab click that you agree it will
let you right back in come hang out back
on the Discord server but my friend
green tea out there in Ireland I think
I've answered your question more than
thoroughly I've encouraged people to
give us feedback and now all I have to
do is send you a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at edirect decom thank you
for the great question and uh keep the
fight going down there in Ireland but
also be very careful I admire you for
going down there in Ireland that is
impressive all right let's keep this
podcast moving I've got one more great
question here in front of me this
question came from my new friend eclipse
and the question goes a little bit like
this it says hey rosta Jeff I love the
show and I wanted to thank you for all
of the breeding knowledge you pass on in
every episode hey thanks for listening
and thanks for noticing that I'm trying
to pass on the knowledge it does go on
it says I do a little breeding myself
and I normally get seeds from seed banks
but I have found one or two seeds and a
few ounces of flour that I've purchased
from dispensaries yes that does happen
especially with dispensary product said
I'm assuming this was I am assuming that
this was due to
rization possibly maybe uh there could
have been a lot of causes to this and
that's we're going to jump into that too
um if I'm not mistaken since it's only
one seed in the entire ounce I was
wondering if these seeds are worth a dam
because the flower was killer I've grown
some out in the past and everything went
smoothly should I just continue using
the cultivar if it doesn't harm or is
that process of seed making inducing
stress that is passed on to the next
generation of seeds hopefully I didn't
confuse you that last line did a little
bit confuse me I think you could tell
but I understand what you're asking you
are finding seeds in your dispensary
herb and you want to know uh are they
worth growing um first of all I want to
address how those seeds could have been
made because that's going to get us
further in this
conversation that seed could have been
made from like you said rization which
is letting that plant go too long uh the
plant's natural defense mechanism is to
make a seed so that it can survive these
plants main goal is to reproduce uh we
think it's to get us High the main goal
of these plants is to reproduce to make
it to receive pollen the females is to
receive pollen make a seed and continue
that generation next year that's the
whole point of that female plant if that
doesn't happen the Jurassic Park effect
will come into play sometimes uh life
will find a way they will seed
themselves that is rization letting it
go long enough until it freaks out and
creates seeds on its own that is
possible it also could have been from
stress it could have been just a
stressinduced panic seed it could have
been from an interex plant it could have
been from actual male pollen uh
contacting that female plant it's
unlikely but possible also could have
been an intersex plant letting out
pollen and contacting this plant there
are a lot of options on how this seed
could have been made so we can't assume
that we know how that seed happened even
if it was in a dispensary in a
commercial cultivation we can't assume
uh somebody could had could have had
pollen at home had pollen in their
dreadlocks came to the grow at work and
got pollen in that grow and now you've
got a just a straight F1 of something
cool that they just they Seated on a AC
so what you've got we call that bag seed
since we do not know how that was made
we we kind of know it's a Mor poic
situation we don't know who the baby
daddy is we definitely know who mommy is
and you know it was good weed cuz you
smoked it and you enjoyed it but we
don't know who the daddy is so we call
that bag seed that's just a seed that
you found in your bag of weed um you
asked are they worth a damn to grow
absolutely yes grow those um don't give
them out don't share them don't sell
them but if you like growing and you
find those your bag grow them that's a
free seed to grow that's a free
experiment keep in mind you could have a
complete interex mutant trash plant that
grows like [ __ ] and tastes like you're
smoking cardboard and mustard or you
could have found something like uh let's
talk about some strains that are
legendary that were bag seed things that
were not meant to happen but are some of
the most popular strains on the planet
I'm going to start with a little line
called chem dog all of the chem line all
of the chem dog seeds came from bag seed
uh the short story is a couple dudes
were selling uh dog Bud on the Grateful
Dead tour traveling around selling dog
butd they met a dude uh known as g g
made friends with the boys that were
selling I'm going quickly here giving
you the quick version uh G made friends
with the boys that were selling the dog
Bud uh after tour G went home and
messaged the boys and said I need more
of that herb they sent him and it's
confusing at this point sometimes the
story says a quarter pound sometimes the
story says an ounce I'm not sure
variations in the story doesn't matter
there were seeds in that delivery there
were 13 seeds was the legend you can
Google uh the legend of chem dog and the
13 beans and you'll find details on this
you'll find names uh you can put it all
together if you really care to do it but
within that I need to take a little sip
not even going to
edit so in that delivery of herb
allegedly there were 13 seeds from those
13 seeds we got chem dog chem 4 chem D
chem sis uh there were a couple of males
they got thrown away and I'm sure there
were more chem that I'm not thinking of
uh chem 991 uh that's probably my
favorite but a bunch of all the chem
stuff all the chem dog stuff came from
that bag of seeds that chem the guy
who's now known as chem dog uh he's
[ __ ] world famous in the weed
industry and the Cannabis Community for
finding these seeds and growing these
out and putting these plants out into
the world uh for us to enjoy to smoke to
grow and most importantly to bre read
with so all of the chem stuff was bag
seed um the guy [ __ ] found he found
these guys on tour bought herb from him
they sent him weed within that weed was
13 seeds he grew those because he knew
he's like I might have the weed was
excellent so he's like I might have
something and he found different
phenotypes that are we can identify the
different uh characteristics of those
chem lines if you put them together and
grow them and smoke them you can taste
and see and smell and feel the
differences in the buzzes and the Aromas
uh the number four in my opinion has got
the kind of the tires and the chemical
sort of a thing and the 91 is more
skunky and a little funkier uh those are
my two favorites the kimd has got that
dies sort of a thing going on to it so
that's just what I've experienced when I
smoke them uh so there are differences
and the chem dogs all of those came from
what is called a bag seed which is
essentially what you're talking about
somebody got weed uh there was seeds in
it and they grew it so you may find uh
also Golden Goat was an accident the
whole story about Golden Goat uh Golden
Goat was an accident that was an
accidental pollination um there was a
male in a room it pollinated a female
plant it wasn't supposed to happen the
seeds that came from that were [ __ ]
incredible so Golden Goat was a straight
up accident also Gorilla Glue was an
accident or gg4 whatever we have to call
it now to avoid getting sued was an
accident jie Wales was pretty open that
that was an accident I'm pretty sure he
said that that was an accident so uh
some of the best strains we we've ever
come across and if I'm wrong about gg4
cuz my brain just questioned on that um
was gg4 an uh purposeful pollination or
was that an accident uh argue about that
in the comments educate me I don't mind
being updated uh but so that's what a
bag seat is and now you see three
examples and I think Girl Scout cookies
was bag seed also to tell you the truth
but who the [ __ ] knows um there's a lot
of Legends around that um do your own
research there but bag seed could be uh
the new hottest [ __ ] and the great thing
about it nobody else has it if you found
a bag seed from something maybe somebody
else has it but what are the chances
that another guy in your re or girl uh
in your region went to The Dispensary
bought the same Bud found the seeds and
thought I should grow this also and then
what are the chances they're going to
find the same phenotype as you so if
you're growing in that neighborhood
you've got something brand new nobody
else has that it's not for sale it's not
available nobody even meant to give that
out you've got kind of a a prize there
and sometimes a phenotype a cultivar
that nobody else has can set you apart
from the market that's why uh that's why
everyone's looking for new [ __ ] all the
time everybody has Skittles now
everybody has gelato everyone's got
[ __ ] Skittles crossed to gelato now
they're looking for what do we cross it
to next who's got the next [ __ ] because
they need the best product to set
themselves apart that's the new part of
the game all right um I feel like I
answered this pretty well uh is it worth
a damn yeah grow it bro you could have
some amazing [ __ ] who knows what caused
that we can't assume what caused the
seed but we know that you've got it and
we know that you could grow grow it pay
attention though uh that could be a
crazy Herm or like we keep saying you
could have chem dog so pay attention to
that I think I've answered this question
quite well my new friend Eclipse uh make
sure you check your inbox because you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds at iy direct.com all right ladies
and gentlemen if you like this podcast
episode now is a good time to remind you
to click like And subscribe that's right
click that like And subscribe button
it's free doesn't take any time help me
out get me in that algorithm a little
bit more all right I think I've answered
all of the questions that I had set
aside for today I feel like this podcast
episode went quite quickly thank you for
hanging out for another great episode if
you have any questions Corrections
comments or concerns I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com don't be shy
let me know what you think of the show
uh positive uh positive feedback
constructive criticism or hate mail
whatever you got I could take it come at
me I got you um also make sure you check
the website IR genetics.com everything
you could possibly need is there there's
a link to the Discord server there's a
link to the seeds edirect is where you
can get the seeds all seed orders over
$100 do come with free shipping so go
check edirect decom I think that's all
I've got for you don't forget about the
new updated AC Infiniti coupon code
there will be a link to AC Infinity in
the show notes and the video description
uh but use that coupon code I Army save
yourself 10% don't forget that coupon
does work on Amazon on the AC Infinity
store as well that is a mouthful that's
all I've got for you for this week I'll
be back in a week with fresh new content
I want to give a huge shout out to all
of my friends at Comedy Works and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me Rost je you bad
[ __ ] time to take another Dam
grab your p and
I in theb sit back relax
roots and wisdom start to
show from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning now to hear the vibr s in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard heing like
through
canis from your hul this rise up higher
find your way grow from your hearts
every day in the light We Stand real
strong join the movement sing the
song natural medicine that love flows
within us like a dog educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof r that jef will guide you
through in this Garden find the new rise
up high I'll Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the song
[Music]
ooh open the minds to see the
truth in the soil lies the proof R Jeff
will guide you through in this Garden
find a new rise up higher Find Your Way
grow from your hearts every day in the
light with stand real strong join the
movement sing the song
oh
[Music]
[Applause]