if you have ever stopped to take a dab
but you forgot to start again go ahead
and click
subscribe Rost Jeff you bad mother
[Music]
welcome back podcast world I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode
872 of the grow from your heart podcast
I've got a fun episode lined up for us
in today's podcast I'm going to talk
about taking care of incoming plants
many websites are selling rooted clones
and fresh Snips we're going to talk
about taking care of those let's jump
right into it I do have a website that
website is IR genetics.com at the top of
that website there is a row of tabs one
of those tabs does say grow help or grow
questions if you click on that tab you
can send me a grow question if I read
your question here on the podcast I will
send you a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at idirect domcom today's
question came from our new friend who
wants to be called uh eist Gardener big
shout out to my new friend eagus
Gardener eagus make sure you check your
inbox check your spam because you've got
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds
at idirect tocom the question does start
off by talking about how they ordered
clones they received their clones they
looked a little bit rough because of the
weather uh they told me how they took
care of them which is exactly what I
would have done the way that they did it
so good job bro uh but then they do ask
a very important question so let's jump
into the question portion of this
message it says finally my question what
would you recommend folks do when
receiving Snips and rooted clones I know
this could help many people as I learned
the oldfashioned way excuse me I learned
the oldfashioned way which was trial and
error through taking losses and calling
it taxes of the game so this is a very
good question uh like we've talked about
many websites out there now are selling
rooted clones or fresh cuts there are a
lot of websites a lot of vendors a lot
of breeders are doing this of course my
fresh cuts are available at IR
redirect.sh they will not ship for
several days because it is super cold
here in my region today I think it is uh
0° uh if I put your clones in the mail
and 0 degrees they will not get to you
in one piece they will be toast they
well they will not be the opposite of
toast they will be ice they will be
frozen uh they will look like [ __ ] you
will be very mad and so will the Clones
so I'm going to wait until it's a little
bit warmer before I put any uh Clips any
Snips any slips whatever you want to
call them or any rooted clones into the
mail putting anything with moisture like
that in in the mail right now is a bad
idea it will freeze it will rupture it
will die so um I am selling clones on
edirect decom there are many vendors
selling clones what do you do if you
order these Fresh Cuts in the mail you
order these rooted clones in the mail uh
you're paying a lot of money depends on
where you buy them depends on which Cuts
you're getting uh they do cost money and
money is expensive right now so I
understand that we want to have and I
want you to have the best success you
can when you do spend money on my
website with my product or even if
you're buying a clone from someone else
I still want you to have great success
so let's talk about this if you do buy
clones from a website we'll specifically
talk about I direct.com um some things
you should keep in mind and some things
that will help you out first of all I
spray my plants twice a week I've got a
very uh I've got a nice uh collection of
different pesticides of different um
efficacy might be the word that I'm
saying of different toxicity might be
the word I'm looking for um of different
gentleness and abrasiveness I've got a
nice array of pesticides that I have on
a shelf and I will mix those I usually
generally use two different pesticides
at a time multiple modes of attack will
uh definitely take out and prevent any
uh problems that may come in so I'm
spraying these plants twice a week with
a nice array of products to be straight
up with you some of them are not organic
if you're worried about 100% organic uh
let me know I will isolate a plant for
you maybe I'll dedicate one to just
organic sprays but I as a breeder in a
state where everybody grows and where
I'm around a lot of Growers
I don't treat with Strictly Organic
products I use a lot of different
pesticides fungicides I rotate my point
is these plants will be clean the Clones
will have been treated over time while
they're on the mother plant with a lot
of different products they will be clean
they will be Pest and Fung fungus free
that's something you can count on
because I spray today is uh Thursday I
sprayed today uh just a couple of hours
ago I sprayed some stuff on the Garden
today the lights are still off they need
to be turned on when I'm done recording
here so the plants are sprayed quite
frequently uh to make sure there's no
pest no problems on those plants also uh
I've got several mother plants in the
garden I've got a couple of different
locations with different mother plants
which the Clones may come from randomly
uh those plants are tested like a sports
team I just picked somebody on the team
this plant here and this plant here and
they get hlvd testing that is hop and
vroid testing so I'm testing the plants
randomly to see if there is hlvd in the
room uh so far there is none so as long
as it stays clean there is no problem
the seeds and the Clones are hlvd free
uh if I do bring in a clone this is
something you should work on as well um
keep this in mind because this is not in
my notes this is something that just
came up in my brain if I receive a clone
from somebody whether it's a vendor
whether it's a bro whether it's a
stranger sending a gift if I buy a clone
from a dispensary if I get it from a
shady Craigslist deal that clone does
not go directly into my grow area that
clone grows into a quarantine isolated
area honestly that quarantine is right
here at this table this area is far
enough from any of my grow spaces that I
can put a plant here I can give it
enough light honestly I use studio
lights it's not I'm not trying to make
it grow rapidly and uh be a thriving
plant I'm making sure it doesn't have
bugs I'm watching it looking for powdery
mildew to pop up watching to see if I
see spidermites on it uh looking to see
if I see any thrips or uh fungus Nets
fly up out of the soil so as soon as
that plant gets here I get it on the
table get it comfortable then I will
spray it with I spray that thing with
some crazy pesticides two or three
different things make sure it's clean I
recommend you do that as well bring your
clones in put them in isolation even if
you get it from me even if you get it
from your other favorite breeder your
favorite vendor uh we all say we're
clean pretty girls have problems too so
make sure you're isolating these clones
when they come in treat them spray them
set them aside check on them uh look
under the underside of the leaves make
sure there's no bugs in there make sure
that plant is clean before you put it in
your general population we just don't
want to contaminate the rest of the grow
that's something I do it's something I
re recommend you do with the Clone as
well so we're checking for hlvd if I get
a cut that sh gets isolated also I will
take an immediate cut when it's big
enough uh you got to take some roots and
some plant material send that B that
that bad [ __ ] into my Farmer my friend
farmer Freeman that was harder to say
than it should have been I might need
more dabs but we send that test in
Farmer Freeman and they let us know that
they are hlvd free before they're put
into the regular population I've already
got the test here I've ordered them so
they're on deck they're in the grow
space uh all I've got to do is take the
samples and send it it takes priority
mail three maybe 4 days to get it there
depending on how busy they are he'll
test it within two to three days of
getting it I'll have an answer in less
than a week most of the time so that
plant can sit here it can chill it'll be
fine I don't want to get hlvd in the
room uh then what else is important
discrete shipping bro I send I send
everything uh either priority mail or
priority Express Mail the clips are just
coming priority mail to save you money
that's the budget cost eff way to do
things I get three clips for 50 60 maybe
40 bucks on some strains uh you get
three Fresh Cuts I go to the mother
plant and I [ __ ] cut that bad [ __ ]
off I wrap it in a wet paper towel put
it in a baggie put it in a priority
mailbox depending on the weather I may
add other things that's on another note
here but it is all in a priority mail or
sometimes a priority mail Express box
which I've been told is going to go away
the priority mail Express will disappear
they're always late Priority Mail
Express boxes are always late I get a
lot of refunds you guys get a lot of
refunds for those because those bad
[ __ ] are never on time you can get
those refunded if your product is not
delivered on time uh but the uh the
postal service has a hard time finding a
contractor to to deliver those on time
is what I've been told so that service
will disappear eventually it's all just
going to be priority mail so your plants
will all come that service which will
save some of you a few bucks but it's
discreet that's my point I don't write
[ __ ] ganja clones it doesn't say
roster Jeff Pot Farm or anything on
there uh depending on when we ship I
rotate the return address a few times
but it will come from a post office box
with a discrete return address on there
you won't know that it's even a clone
until you open it unless you're
expecting it but they are very discretly
shipped also I said a moment ago I'm
experimenting with it is cold it is cold
as [ __ ] is my unit of measurement right
now I think it's 0 degrees to be honest
with you I'm over here in a hoodie got
the heat cranked up uh there's a heater
vent right behind me it's really cold
over here but I've been putting those um
the glove warmers worked better they
were hotter but I bought some of those
reptile shipper warmer things I don't
think they get hot enough they don't
seem to keep the plants warm enough I'm
experimenting I've got the the Clone and
a thermal envelope with the reptile
warmers that are supposed to last 72
hours which should be long enough to get
it to you I'm experimenting but during
this cold time I'm going to take a break
uh but when it's not super cold I still
ship them with those glove warmers to
try to keep them warm for you so I'm
spraying them they're hlv tested
discrete shipping and I'm experimenting
with keeping them warm so that's the
basics of my shipping they get to you
now let's talk about how to take care of
these plants because that's what we're
supposed to be doing here let's say that
you order we're going to start with a
rooted clone most of the time the rooted
clones are uh somewhere between and it
depends on which clones you're buying
and how many of them but they start off
around a 100 bucks they work their way
up some are 250 uh there's one that is
quite pricey that I don't put up too
often if you want it get it cuz they
disappear quick quickly I I chicken out
and take it down so that's what happens
um where are we so you get a rooted cut
this rooted cut comes in the mail you've
got a priority mail Express box it comes
in the mail cut the Box open you pull
that bad [ __ ] out there's a thermal
envelope inside of there uh possibly
with a heat pack maybe even a sticker or
two depending on how much of a hurry I
was in when I packed it you get your
clone out you take it out of the baggie
uh carefully unwrap that root section
that's just in a paper a wet paper towel
uh unwrap that slowly now you've got a
clone that is just exposed it will have
long dangly Roots let me get to my notes
here cuz I know I wrote down stuff these
clones came most of the time so far I
may adjust to the plugs and the Dome and
tray thing here in the future if it's
easier for you guys let me know how you
feel I could do both um but these come
from an easy cloner a turbo cloner the
easy cloner is my preferred method of
cloning it's quick it's easy it's
reliable it gets long fat roots and the
best part is I don't have to use a dome
I [ __ ] hate the Clone domes the
humidity domes a pain in the ass uh it's
just such a learning curve you got to
[ __ ] with it every single day uh with
the Clone with the easy cloner you set
it forget it you check the ph and the EC
once a day and you're good to go so
these all come from an easy cloner
they'll have long roots and they'll be
dangling there's no the roots are just
free they're exposed they're not in any
sort of media they're wrapped in a paper
towel to stay safe during travel but
they're not in a clone plug they're not
in any dirt they're just it's a clone
with roots hanging off of it so you got
to be prep prepared for that when that
comes what I recommend I would get a
beer cup just your uh is it a 16 a 20 oz
beer cup your Red Solo Cup you guys you
know what I'm talking about bro uh just
get a beer cup poke a few holes in the
bottom of it three four holes take some
scissors stab it a few times uh light up
your poker heat up the poker stab it a
few times put some holes we don't want
it to get stagnant water we want it to
drain so you're going to take your cup
your beer cup you're going to poke a few
holes in it on the very bottom then
you're going to fill that with your
favorite your recommended light soil it
could be Light Warrior it could be ocean
Forest it could be happy frog it could
be a mixture of the three a soil that's
going to have plenty of drainage and not
a lot of nutrients in it we don't want a
lot of nutrients to burn this plant
already so you got a beer cup you've got
light soil at this point uh so the we'll
say that the roots are probably 2 and a
half three and a half maybe four inches
long depending on how long that clone
sat in the Clone or [ __ ] waiting for
me to we for weather to get right but
you got some Roots you're going to fill
that cup about 2/3 3/4 of the way
depending on how long the roots are and
how deep you want to go fill that cup up
with soil most of the way pack it kind
of not firmly but not tight just get it
in there to where so the roots have to
work their way through there but not
struggle I know that's a hard thing to
judge but you want it packed but not
stuffed so you got that bottom layers in
there I would start lowering the Clone
in there and sprinkle some dirt in there
at the same time what I want to happen
is I don't want the roots to get in big
ball and I don't want them to coil up I
want it to kind of make a spir Ral
around that new dirt that you're putting
in there so spir Ral that around there
so they've got some more to grow if you
ball them up they're going to grow and
get stuck into a big ball so slowly
lower that clone in there if you can get
the Clone this is hard to do I've gotten
very lucky a couple times you got a
little mound of dirt uh like a cone of
dirt inside your cup if you can lower
that clone in there if those roots will
spread over that clone over the top over
that cone that's so beautiful it's hard
to do it I feel super excited when I see
it happened but it's hard to make happen
anyway we want to spread those roots out
in this medium kind of far get them to
spread that's the best you can do then
fill that plant fill that cup with soil
until that plant is sturdy until it's
staying upright um so you're going to
have roots and then you're going to have
a little bit of stick you can go uh a
quarter a half inch maybe 3/4 of an inch
up that stick and bury that in there so
that it stays sturdy and stays tall
don't go too deep and don't go too tight
is my biggest suggestions if it's too
deep that the part that is buried will
have the potential to get some rot if it
stays too wet too long that part will
start to rot and get funky if you pack
it too tight The Roots can't grow so at
this point we've lowered our clone down
into the dirt we've carefully maneuvered
those roots to they're not in a ball not
in a big coil not in a spiral we've
spread them out the best we carefully
can without breaking them then we bury
that plant we don't go too deep we don't
want to go too deep to get the rot like
we just talked about we don't want to go
too tight now at this point we're going
to water this plant pack that soil in
there fairly smoothly now we need to
water this plant I would recommend
feeding this plant some microbes at this
time of course I'm going to say recharge
cuz I'm good friends with Scotty Reel
Big shout out to Scotty reel and the
dude grows crew but I would add some
recharge to your water and water this
plant don't give it too much nutrients
at this time depending on what you just
potted it into if you put it into
something inert then maybe give it some
very light veg nudes but if you're using
uh most of the fox Farm's products most
of the soil you could buy from the store
you're going to have plenty of nutrients
for a couple of weeks for this little
plant maybe a week or two to get it
started so um we've got our we fill the
cup then we put a little mound in there
we lower the roots onto the mound we
back fill it till it's filled up till
the plant is sturdy pack it in there
with our fingers water it with some
microbes when we water it it's going to
disrupt the soil the top soil is going
to get all [ __ ] up you're going to
have a hole you're going to have divots
or whatever kind of push that around
with your finger smooth that in and kind
of just pack it in tight enough to where
that plant stays sturdy now at this
point let me check my notes and make
sure we're doing all this according to
my notes cuz I haven't looked in a
minute water with microbes okay and then
at this point this is where I recommend
getting a clear beer cup if you can get
another clear cup I would put this right
on top don't poke any holes in this one
this is to trap the humidity inside that
plant we need that plant to have limited
air flow and maximum humidity inside of
that little Dome space uh right now that
plant needs to adjust to your new
environment so I would recommend just
put a little Dome over there and let
that Dome just rest over that plant um
it doesn't need to be there for too long
hopefully just a day or two until you
can tell that that plant kind of perks
out of its shipping stress it may look a
little pissed off when it comes out of
the box uh put that Dome over there and
let that Dome hang out on top of that
plant probably just 12 24 hours see see
what it does if the plant looks turgid
and stiff and it's sturdy and standing
up go ahead and take the Dome off if it
looks a little pissed off a little upset
leave that Dome there that will help
that plant adjust to its new life if it
kind of looks sad you can slowly take it
off and let it adjust slowly leave it on
for a few hours take it off for a few
minutes leave it on for a few hours take
it off for a couple more minutes
introduce it slowly that will help that
plant out so we got your clear cup uh on
top now I would place it under 186 or
more light what I mean by that is 18
hours of light 6 hours off or more you
can do uh 195 240 your preference but at
least 18 hours of light um and then I
would use use uh like a T5 light or a
light fluorescent light or just put it
off in the periphery of your big light
uh don't put it right under the big
light that may be too much light for it
we need enough light to keep it warm and
to generate humidity in that humidity
Dome is our main function right now keep
it warm and get some humidity going to
get it recovering uh to encourage root
growth once those roots start going the
plant will recover and it will be very
happy once that recharge hits it it'll
get some [ __ ] going so we've got it
covered we've got it under a good light
uh high humidity is really good at this
point they should recover quite quickly
I would consider a um a heat mat if your
room is cold maybe put it under a heat
mat if you don't have a beer cup maybe
you can create some sort of humidity
Dome with another vessel maybe some sort
of clear container uh but it' be a good
idea to cover it some sort of way just
to keep it uh you could take a like a 2
L soda bottle cut the bottom off set
that clean it out of course set that
right on top of there just to minimize
the air flow and the wind and the
outside environment to that plant uh
keep some heat some humidity in there I
keep saying those things but they want
it warm and moist that's going to help
your clone survive then introduce it to
your outdoor envir your your regular
growroom environment slowly so that is
the rooted plants uh they should be
pretty sturdy they came from that uh the
easy cloner they should have fat Roots
those should work quite well let me
review uh just cuz I did that quickly in
my own head fill the beer cup carefully
pot it carefully water with microbes put
it under light put a dome over that bad
[ __ ] and take care of it slowly and
take that Dome off uh slowly if you want
to introduce it to the environment
slowly now let's talk about the Fresh
Cuts I said before the Fresh Cuts are
definitely uh the more cost effective
the more affordable way if you're good
at rooting a cut this is the way to do
it uh usually they run from 440 to $60
for three Cuts sometimes if I have a lot
I'll throw an extra one in there for you
they're all going to be the same cut
that way there's no confusion that whole
bag is the same thing let's talk about
these rooted Cuts they are fresh cuts
from the mother plant they do not have
Roots I want to be very clear about that
when we say Snips some people say slips
some people say Cuts uh there are no
roots that is your job I'm going to send
it to you and you if got to root it um I
will take Cuts if you send me Cuts I'm
just fine I can root those bad [ __ ]
uh This Is How We Do It um so the fresh
cuts come straight from the mother plant
once again a healthy mother plant is a
really important part of this they are
ready to put your easy cloner I
recommend the easy cloner the easy
cloner is real simple we'll talk about
that but they're also ready to put into
clone plugs uh the easy cloner let's
talk about that I'm going to go very
quickly uh I will do in the future if
you would like it uh request this in the
comments if you want full details on my
full stepbystep how I do clones uh in a
rapid router and dome environment or in
a in an easy cloner environment comment
if I get enough comments on it that you
guys need that guidance and advice to go
full [ __ ] details I'll do that in the
next episode or uh in an upcoming
episode but right now we're going to go
kind of quickly on how we do the Clones
but this is I recommend if you've got an
easy cloner you should know how to do it
but let's talk about how to do this so
you got the easy cloner the Clones are
going to come you're going to unwrap
them I would clip off the ends just give
them a fresh clip at the ends then um
dip them what do you dip them in your
favorite cloning gel I use the purple
clonex gel the purple clonex stuff is
reliable it works very well for me um
let me back up before we even do this
before we even take the Clones out of
the machine out of the [ __ ] package
set up the cloning machine 100% uh clean
the clone machine go clean it um however
you want to do it you could fill it with
bleach and rinse it out a bunch of times
you can fill it with boiling water you
can use fizan it could be brand new make
sure it is clean and sterile and use
good clean clone collars that's harder
to say than it looks so you got a fresh
clone machine it's all set up you've got
your water is in there you've got your
nutrients in there um the EC is right
the pH is correct we'll talk about that
in the upcoming episode it's bubbling
it's ready to go the Clone collars are
in there there's a light above it so at
this point you take the Clones out you'd
give them a fresh cut just cut the ends
off again brand new give them just trim
the ends just an eighth of an inch cut
those right off then dip those cuts
individually into your purple uh clone X
clone gel clip them dip them then stick
them basically Ronco style bro set it
and forget it make sure to label these
clones some way I take a plastic plant
tag and I write the name and I put it
inside the neoprene collar where the
little Pac-Man bites I stick it right in
there with the Clone so I've got a label
all the time so the easy cloner it's
real easy set up the cloner is the most
important part clip it dip it stick it
put it in the Clone collar label it and
let it ride um let those sit um in about
24 hours then after 24 hours adjust your
EC your pH and at this point I would
also add some stuff called clear res
follow the instructions on the clear res
bottle why did I tell you to wait 24
hours to adjust the ph and the EC
because all that purple [ __ ] that you
dipped your clones in is going to fall
off your clones or get washed off the
Clones into the water it is now most of
that is in your water now is a good time
to adjust the ph and the EC instead of
before if you're using the yellow uh
clonex the piss stuff the clone solution
that goes in the cloner it looks like P
in my opinion uh if you're using it in a
cloner or in the plugs I recommend a
solution of 0.9 to 1.1 EC that range is
perfect one is right where you want to
be 0.9 will get you there 1.1 will be
acceptable but I recommend use the
yellow clonex gel or the yellow clonex
solution pour it into your water Stir It
Up use an EC meter until it says one
that's right where you want to be that's
what you want your cloner or your
solution to measure at
so you got your EC at one the pH I would
go about 62 if you can get it to 62 that
would be ideal uh clone pH solution uh
the EC is
controversial uh I'm going to tell you
another Secret at the end of the show
follow exactly what that secret says
that will get you there every time so
the cloner is easy set it up uh put the
nutrients in there get it running have
it prepared then clip them dip them
stick them label them let it ride for 24
hours then get in there with your EC
meter in your pH pin adjust the EC and
the pH properly and then pour in some
clear res and you are good to go with
the clone machine I'm going to take a
quick drink and then we're going to talk
about how to do it with your clone plugs
all right podcast world through the
magic of editing we are back now is a
good time for me to remind you to click
like And subscribe that's right if
you're learning anything from this
podcast go ahead click like and click
subscribe also don't forget about my
patreon Channel at
patreon.com SLG fromyou heart if you
felt like this content was educational
or informative uh feel free to support
the show on patreon all right enough
blatant advertising enough Shameless
plugs let's keep going speaking of plugs
I said we were going to talk about how
to take care of your clones in the Clone
plug environment let's jump right into
that let's just say you got some
unrooted Cuts in the mail and it is time
to get these bad dogs into some cloners
here's how we're going to do it first of
all I recommend you soak your clone
plugs whatever plugs you bought uh if
they're rapid rooters if they're another
brand that I can't even think of the
[ __ ] name of right now I recommend
you fill a vessel uh with water and then
you make an EC of 1.0 with that yellow
piss looking uh clonex solution not the
purple one the yellow one is what we
want this time uh use your EC meter uh
you don't have the plugs in there yet
you got water uh you got your EC meter
you're adding the solution you're
stirring and making it to get to 1.0 if
you go too high add more water you could
just fix it that way that's a way to do
this then um I would even pH the water
at this point uh pH that water to about
62 is is probably where you want to do
it I'm going to give you a hint in a
little while with the exact pH that's
what you're going to want to use so soak
your plugs with the pH uh clone X
solution uh you got the water drop all
the plugs in there now the plugs are in
there take them out one at a time put
them in that clone tray if that's what
you're doing this is the Clone tray
method is what I'm talking about so at
this point you got your plugs soaked
we're going to do the same thing we did
before we're going to clip the ends off
of them we're going to dip them in the
purple solution and then we're going to
dip them into those clone plugs uh the
Clone plugs are about this tall do not
stick your clone through the bottom of
it I'm going to use a pen and my fingers
as a demonstration here I like to go so
if the Clone plug is this tall I'm going
to say that is we're just going to make
up numbers because I want this to be um
visible uh usable for people who are not
watching for people who are just
listening I think that clone plug is
about an inch tall maybe an inch and a
half tall um I would go if it's an inch
tall I would go 3/4 of an inch into that
plug let's go 3/4 of the way into the
plug don't stick your clone all the way
out of the bottom that will not live you
need some room for that bad dog to grow
some Roots so go about 3/4 of the way in
there if that clone plug is an inch tall
go 3/4 of an inch into there maybe just
over half of an inch we want to leave
some room for those roots to grow in
there but also we need need plenty to
support that plant cuz it's going to be
living in there it's got to be tall
enough or deep enough to support the
height of that plant so clip them dip
them stick them also you guys here's
another tip when you're taking clones if
you've got big leafy cuts that you're
taking don't feel free to cut the
fingers off of those leaves I cut them
right at the knuckles where it gets so
the leaves taper they go fatter fatter
fatter and then at some point they start
to go skinnier right where they start to
go skinnier you could chop that [ __ ] off
if you're making a clone we don't need
all that vegetative part in our clone
dome in the cloning machine just trim
the fingers off your clones I grab them
from the bottom and pull it up and just
give them a little haircut I do it super
quickly I'm real good at it at this
point so if you get a clone in the mail
from me and it's been all [ __ ]
mohawked uh there's several reasons
behind this it's so that when they're in
the cloner they're not overlapping and
touching and creating moisture and
little uh microclimates between each
other which will cause problems in the
long run so clip them dip them uh clean
up the ends of them then stick them into
your clone uh your clone plug then let
me make a quick recommendation if you're
going to put three clones in a clone
tray I also recommend if you've got more
plants that you can get clones from I
would recommend filling this tray the
best you can the reason for that is the
amount of humidity in this Dome will be
affected by the amount of plants inside
that Dome as well just a small piece of
advice it will help you keep the
humidity up in there if you've got more
plants in there so at this point we've
got our clone it's been clipped it's
been dipped it's been hair cuted it's
been stuck into the cloner or into the
uh the uh the plug uh 3/4 half to 3/4 of
the way we put a little bit of the
leftover remember that solution we
dunked our clone plugs in earlier
hopefully you didn't throw it away put a
little bit of that in the bottom of your
clone tray uh we've got the insert with
the plugs in it and that goes into a
tray put a little bit of that solution
into the tray we want to buy ourselves
some moisture to make humidity in this
tray and this Dome is what we're going
to do so just a little bit maybe just
splash enough in there just to cover the
bottom so it's not dry just cover that
bottom eventually that moisture is going
to come up to the top and become
humidity and fall back down also I want
to take now this is what I'm going to do
I'm going to take the Dome the lid to
this tray I'm going to cover and close
all the plugs all the holes on that
thing I'm going to cover all the vents
is the word I'm looking for going to
cover all the vents then I'm going to
get a spray bottle and I'm going to
spray the inside of that Dome so it's
nice and Misty it looks like it got all
humid already I'm going to set myself up
ahead of time here and just Mist it and
get some water in there then I'm going
to put that on top of that tray now I've
got my freshly cut clones and they're
all labeled let me back up a step let's
[ __ ] remember to label each and every
one of these clones very carefully uh
like I said before I use the plant tags
just a long tall skinny plant tag write
the name of the plant on there and stick
it right behind that plug inside that
tray that way you can't get any mixups
you know that every plant's got a tag in
there so label them now we put the Dome
on there we've got a dome a tray filled
with cuts waiting to get rooted this
point I would put this Dome under like a
T5 light or a light what are they called
a an LED light I forgot what an LED was
uh put these put the Dome under a nice
light and put it on 24 hours of light if
you can 186 would be acceptable 24 hours
would be best so you got your Dome uh
also maybe put that on a heat mat uh the
heat mat will help you out be careful
not to barbecue the Clones I've seen so
many people people uh just boil in
barbecue clones you don't want it that
hot you want it warm not boiling so um
let me make sure I've got my notes here
cuz I'm just rambling and trying to get
this out of my head um spray the Dome
cover the Dome put it on the heat mat
put it under the light let that ride for
about 4 days you're not going to have to
check on that for three or four maybe
five or six days look at it visually uh
tap that D if there's no humidity in the
dome you need to open it and create some
humidity maybe spray in there or check
on the moisture level of those plugs but
you should be able to walk by and look
at it and there should be humidity built
up on that Dome tap it the humidity will
fall off look through the Dome at that
point and look into the plugs look at
the color of the plugs you'll start to
tell that they look dry do they look
moist do they look wet you'll be able to
tell by looking at them by the color of
the plugs we want to keep them moist but
not dripping and not soggy but they need
to be wet all the way through from top
to bottom so if you see those Clon plug
starting to get dry what I recommend
take that same solution we made earlier
the 1.0 solution of the clonex solution
pH at 6.2 6.4 or check the thing I'm
going to tell you for the absolute
detail in a minute put some of that in a
spray bottle just a basic your spray
bottle right and spray those plugs until
they're nice and moist again and then
cover them back up and then put them
back under that light leave them there
just like that for about 7 Days around
day seven you can start cracking those
vents a little bit more and a little bit
more once you're comfortable with the
vents all the way open then you can
start taking the Dome off take the Dome
off for 15 minutes a day put it back on
for the rest of the day take it off for
30 minutes the next day 45 minutes
slowly increase your interval until you
start seeing those roots growing out of
those plugs you will see them uh they'll
start getting fat healthy Roots if you
do this correctly at which time then you
can plop those into a beer cup and treat
them just like the other cuts that I was
talking about let me check my notes here
um slowly open the domes and increase
the interval until roots are developed
is what I got now here's where I'm going
to tell you about the secret that I keep
hinting about I have got a Discord
server it is the IR Army Discord server
there will be a link in the show notes
and in the video description there's
also a link on my website IR
genetics.com it says Discord click on
there it will take you to my Discord
server a lot of people are overwhelmed
and confused by Discord it's not as
challenging as it looks I'm going to
open it right now on my computer here
it's going to take a minute for this
MacBook to open it but we're going to
take a peek what's happening is on the
left is a a row of tabs it just says
like um [ __ ] the iy Army chat the
group chat clone care sop uh what did I
just say what the Clone care sop is
hidden on the left in those tabs I'm
waiting for it to open here but if you
look at all the descriptions those just
tell you what's going on in that tab if
you click on the tab that says iy Army
General chat if you click on that it
takes you to just a general chat you can
chat about whatever you want in there
there is a smoker's Lounge which is a
live video chat you can come hang out I
take dabs on camera I come chat I come
hang out if you've got a fun grow
question or you just want to ask me
about something or talk about life come
in the uh The Smokers Lounge chat and
hang out there's a Growers Lounge chat
we talk about growing it's all fun in
there but in that list of tabs one of
them does say clone care sop I'm going
to look for it right now clicking on my
server um so the iy Army Discord is the
one with the big cross is the logo we
click on that there's a row of tabs it
says iy Army Discord at top rules and
etiquette get new rules here you got to
scroll down several tabs down um shout
out to potent ponics for being in the
Smokers Lounge chat right now uh hydrop
or aquaponic Steve is over there
chilling out talking to the crew scroll
down even further there's one that says
grow them themed chats in there on the
very bottom is all the very bottom is
the STS video where I teach you how to
make silver thos sulfate and reverse
your plants but right above that is the
Clone care sop if you click on that
clone care sop and scroll up to the top
and read the original sop that I posted
and it looks like a lot of people have
given me a lot of feedback on there as
well that is the Clone sop that I use in
a commercial cultivation facility
whether it's clone uh the arrow clone or
uh in Clone rapid rooters both Sops are
fairly short they could probably use
some updates if you see something that
needs updates let me know but if you
join my Discord server absolutely free
these Sops are there uh there's an sop
on the silver tho sufate there's a clone
care sop there's an IPM chat a lot of
things that could help a lot of people
out are happening in the Discord server
so I keep talking about these secrets
it's all here on paper pH the cloner to
5.7 to 6.2 is what it says so a lot of
details are here if you need in-depth
details it's here like I said before if
you would like a full if you want me to
do this clone care sop as a podcast let
me know I'll put it out as a full
podcast a long form episode comment in
the comment section and make your
demands all right boys and girls I think
that's the best I've got for you um
where do you get these cuts and clones
these cuts and clones are available at
edirect tocom if you're going to to my
main website IR genetics.com there's a
link for everything there the Discord
server iir is where to get the Clones
patreon is where to contribute to the
show uh it's pretty much
self-explanatory on the tabs up at the
top of the page um like I said if you
want more Sops if you want me to do the
Sops is full podcast please comment let
me know I'll get those shows going for
you all right ladies and gentlemen boys
girls pimps hoes friends foes smokers
Growers clone Cutters pollen Chuckers uh
my buddy eist Gardener I want to thank
all of you out there for another great
episode thanks for watching thanks for
hanging out I hope you had as much fun
as I did I feel like I'm super rambly
today so I'm going to keep this one
short and sweet wrap it up and get out
of here quickly uh I'll be back in a
week you know what I might be back in
two weeks I've said on the previous
episode my birthday's coming up I've got
a lot of fun [ __ ] coming up I might just
take a week off and not record but then
again I might miss it and want to come
do a show so who knows what could happen
here um keep checking on me on YouTube
like I said like And subscribe that way
you don't miss any episodes I'm going to
let you go for now go hang out with your
friends I'm going to go have a good time
I'll be back with fresh new content I
want to give a big shout out to my buddy
GB genetics and until next time take a
fat dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] tell to take another Dam
grab your p in and I about the
B is in the
sit back moment
relax roots and wisdom start
to from the knowledge seeds we grow
tuning now to hear the vibr Jeff in our
conscious
tribe it spreads the truth in every word
every voice must now be heard heing like
the canot this go from your heart your
this
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the
song Natural Med and love flows within
us like a do educate and Elevate join
the Journey Don't Be Late open minds to
see the truth
in the soil lies the proof RF will guide
you through in this goded find the new
rise up higher Find Your Way grow from
your hearts every day in the light We
Stand real strong join the movement sing
the song
[Music]
open minds to see the truth in the soil
lies the proof R Jeff will guide you
through in this Garden find a new rise
up higher Find Your Way grow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong
join the movement sing the song
[Music]
[Applause]