[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Welcome to the podcast
everybody. I'm your host Rosta Jeff.
This is episode
874 of the Grow From Your Heart podcast.
You know, I've got another fun episode
lined up for us. In today's podcast, I'm
going to give away free seeds. Hang out.
I'll tell you more about those free
seeds later on in the show. Before we go
too far, I do want to remind you that
this podcast is brought to you by our
good friends at
acinfiniti.com. That's right. Shop
acfinity.com and use coupon code iie
army to save 10% off of your full
purchase. All right, I don't want to
waste too much time with advertising. I
have got a great question here in front
of me. I have a website. My website is
iiegenetics.com. On the top of that
website, there is a row of tabs. One of
those tabs does say grow or grow
questions. If you click on that tab,
guess what? You can send me a grow
question. If I read your grow question
here on the podcast, I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iredirect.com. This question is a great
question. This may be the only question
for today's podcast. We'll see how long
this one does take. This one came from
our friend known as Lucky Bullpacker.
Lucky Bullpacker. Check your inbox and
your spam because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds from
iredirect.com. The question from Lucky
Bullpacker. It's a short question, but
it's a good one. It goes just like this.
It says, "Hey Ros, how's it going? I
only had one question. What caused your
love for the plant?" That's a very good
question. A lot of people have been
listening to this show for a long time.
Uh maybe people are brand new listening
to this show. Many people may not know
why or how I fell in love with uh
growing ganja, cultivating ganja,
consuming, breeding, being an being an
advocate for ganja. How did I fall in
love with this plant? This is a very
good question. I think I'm going to
dedicate this whole episode, no matter
how short or quick this reply is, just
to talking about how and why I fell in
love with the ganja plant. what I wrote
down in my outline. Now that I'm
rambling a little bit more, I realize
how much more there is to this plant in
my life than I even wrote down. I've got
a few short notes here, but this plant
has done a lot for me. My love, my
passion for this plant has taken me very
far. I have built a business. I've built
a podcast. I've built a career. I've
built a life uh off of this plant, off
of my love and passion and understanding
for this plant. I feel like this
relationship with myself and the plant
uh it is very reciprocal. I give a lot
to this plant. I give you guys a lot for
this plant. And in turn, you guys give
me a lot in return. And the plant is
giving me a lot in return. Uh I do live
a very blessed and maybe a privileged
life. And that is because of my love and
my passion for this plant. Uh added with
a few other skills, but without this
plant, uh my skills and passions might
not have lined up the way that they were
supposed to. I feel like um I'm right
where I'm supposed to be because of this
plant. Uh it's given me a good life, a
good future, a good career. Um, I might
not be as mentally, physically,
spiritually, financially, uh, socially
stable as I am without this plant. I
would be a different person. Uh, I've
been consuming cannabis for my mid early
teenage years. Uh, I'm now in my mid to
late 40s. I'm still consuming strongly,
heavily. Uh, so I started as a smoker.
That was my first love, right? We all
fall in love with smoking the plant.
Then after I was smoking, I began
growing. Um, now I don't know if you
made me decide between smoking, growing,
and breeding. I don't know which one I
would choose. Uh, growing, and breeding,
have a good chance of winning. If you
made me quit one, smoking might be the
one that I eliminated, which sounds wild
because for a lot of people, that's the
most important aspect of the plant. As I
get older, I understand what I'm able to
do with the plant. I can grow it and
breed it in a special way. A lot of
people in the past 10 years have really
caught up. There are some amazing
growers out there. When this uh cannabis
revolution was new, a lot of us growers
that were growing and learning quickly
and being advanced uh at our skills, we
were kind of a uh a very special niche
group of people. But now my skills are
not rare. There are a lot of people that
can grow. There are a lot of people out
there that have surpassed me. A lot of
my apprentices uh they now grow in
larger facilities than me. They're
growing better product than me. And I am
not ashamed or embarrassed to admit that
in any way. I love that the next
generation, the younger guys behind me,
the younger gals behind me. That's
another beautiful [ __ ] thing to see
some ladies in this industry. When I
first jumped in, it was a sausage fest.
Uh it was Maddie and a couple other
ladies. And now there's a lot of women,
a lot of ladies in this industry, and I
love that. But, uh, a lot of those
ladies and gentlemen and everything in
between, they have surpassed me in grow
skills. They even surpass me in breeding
skills. I don't feel like I'm some weed
wizard or some uh some sort of guy at
the top of the mountain. But for a while
there, I was one of the advanced guys,
the advanced people in the grow
knowledge. And now a lot of people are
catching up and they're right on this
level. And I have no problem uh
admitting it or acknowledging it. I
think it's beautiful. I love that the
evolution of the cannabis legalization,
the industry, the community, podcasting,
the internet, it has made everybody a
much better grower. It has uh con uh
informed and educated consumers. All
right, I'm off on a good ramble here.
You guys could tell I love this freaking
plant. But not only am I a smoker, I'm a
grower. I love to grow the plant. Um, I
love being in the room with the plants,
smelling the plants, smelling the air
that comes off of the plants, walking
into the room and just that smell in the
grow room. Everybody's grow has a
different smell. Each uh I go to
different commercial facilities, they
all smell differently. Some of them
smell like the pesticides they use. Some
of them smell like the flowers they're
growing. Some of them smell like the
facility. Some buildings just have a
smell. I love that smell. I love the
feeling of being in the room. And then I
love working with the plants, touching
them, seeing them, feeling them, looking
across the room and going, "Ah, that
plant over there, all these other plants
are bright green. They look beautiful.
That one right there, she's got a little
problem. Let's go find out with her. Uh
go find out what's up with her. Go walk
over to that plant, touch it, feel it,
smell it, see what's wrong with it. Uh
identify its problem, correct it, and
then watch that plant grow even better
uh in the next couple of weeks. Then
after I grow that, I get to give it to
people and they do the same thing. I get
to So, let me get back to my notes
because that's going to get me, this is
getting into my notes that I've got
written down. Um, why do I love ganja?
How did I fall in love with this plant?
Um, before I even smoked ganja, I had
uncles, family members, cousins, people
around me who were smoking, loved the
smell, and they always seemed the adults
were cooler after they smoked. That's
something I noticed. I grew up around uh
I had three rowdy uncles. Two of them
are gone. Rest in peace, boys. I love
you and miss you every [ __ ] day. But
those three dudes taught me a lot. A lot
of what to do and what not to do in
life. Uh they were my rowdy uncles. They
were uh some of them were smokers, some
of them were drinkers, some of them did
other things. I learned not to do those
other things by watching my uncles do
it. I saw when some of them drank, they
would get rowdy. I saw that when people
drank, they would get rowdy. There would
be fights when people drank. But I saw
when people smoked ganja, we all
laughed. People went to Taco Bell.
People ate a bunch of cookies. It wasn't
problematic. People were cooler. The
adults were better when they smoked weed
is what I noticed as a child. So I, as I
got older, I was like, "Well, I need to
try that. You know, it makes the adults
[ __ ] better. Let's see what it does."
And the minute I smoked, you know, I was
getting stoned before that. I was
hanging out with my uncles and just
being around them, I was catching a
buzz. But the minute I smoked, I was
like, I get it. I understand this. So,
uh, the first time I smoked, I'm trying
to catch myself up on my notes here. I
grew up around some savages and I saw
that them drinking [ __ ] them up, made
them [ __ ] Actually, it kind of kind
of actually killed the two two of my
uncles. They should still be here if
they did not drink the way they did. Uh
if they just smoked, uh they would still
be alive cuz the uncle that quit
drinking, he's still with us. But that's
the poisons of alcohol. Uh all my ganja
smoker friends, they're still healthy,
looking good, looking young, having a
good time. So I saw from an early age
that some drugs were bad, alcohol was
bad, and smoking weed made everybody
cooler. It made the adults easier to
hang out with. They they liked the kids
better. Um I'm a I'm a parent now and I
noticed that when I would smoke as my my
daughter's 21 now. I smoke with my adult
daughter now. Uh when she was a kid, I
would I'd be like, I got to spend time
with the kid and I just might not be
into it as much. We might be playing and
I might want to We didn't have cell
phones as much then, but I might want to
be distracted by something else just
because life was distracting. I would
notice I'd go smoke and then go sit at
her little playhouse or her play
kitchen. And now I'm making uh whatever
fake Starbucks Frappuccinos on her
little kid playset thing and enjoying it
and having a little tea party with her.
I would just get more into it. I would
play more. And so I saw that happening
with me as well. Uh the the adults in my
life were more fun and it worked on me
as I became a parent. So I do have
notes. I keep saying I'm going to get to
them. Um it makes things better. Why do
I love Ganja? Because it makes things
better. What does it make better? Life.
Um, it just makes life better. It feels
better. Life feels good. Um, I've been
going to therapy for a couple of years.
Nothing's wrong. I just Everybody's got
some [ __ ] to work out. Go to go to
therapy. It feels good. Uh, I've been
going to therapy. I'm mentally well. Uh,
I'm physically well. I'm spiritually
sound. I feel good. But when I smoke
ganja, feel even better. It just feels
better. It's like putting uh, it's like
putting little chocolate sprinkles on
life or rainbow sprinkles even on life.
It's like putting glitter on boobs. It
just makes it a little bit better. Um,
it makes music better. Um, I did not
understand reggae music until I got
super blazed one day and got in the
shower and I was grooving and I was
like, I [ __ ] understand reggae music
right now. It's different, Ray. If
you're a musician, reae is different.
Uh, music makes reae way better for me.
It makes it I understood it completely.
Uh, I just like music when I'm smoking.
It sounds a lot better. Also, different
enhancements make music better, too. But
that's not the point today. Uh, what
else is better? Food. Food is better
after you smoke, bro. Um, if you're
going to go out to dinner and you go get
your favorite meal, it's going to taste
good. But if you smoke a fat joint
before you go, that food's going to
taste even better. I don't know why. It
just makes it taste even better. Uh,
what else did I put on my list? Sex is
even better. Sometimes you get a little
distracted and it takes a minute, which
the [ __ ] is wrong with sex taking
longer, right? Sex is better when you're
stoned, too. I wrote down comedy. Comedy
is one of my favorite things. They say
laughter is medicine. Comedy makes me
laugh. Sometimes when I smoke a joint, I
just laugh anyway. So, comedy and a fat
joint. Comedy is better after you smoke.
Cartoons. Imagine. So, this is the
scenario. You're sitting in front of the
ta in front of the TV watching cartoons
eating a bowl of cereal. That's a cool
story, right? Smoke a joint. Do the same
thing. Bro, those cartoons are way
better and that cereal just tastes way
better. I don't know. Something about
smoking that joint, taking a dab,
hitting the bong just makes everything
better. It's like, like I said a minute
ago, it's like boobs but with sprinkles.
Just a little bit better. Then, um, I
like to meditate. I've been talking
about my spirituality and my mental
clarity. That comes from a little bit of
meditation. You got to you got to be
able to to close out the outside world
and go inside and really see what's
inside yourself or myself. And that's
how I'm able to deal with me the best.
Just close my eyes, shut out everything.
What's in here? because this is what I
can do. I can control. I can manage. I
can correct. I can adjust. I can adapt
by what's going on in here. What little
things do I need to work on? What
bothered me today? What made me glitch
today? What did I get hung up on? What
do I need to get over? I can deal with
that. Right? Sometimes can't get into
it. Sometimes I want to open my eyes and
check my phone or look and see what's
going on. Take a little bit of a puff of
a nice joint, close my eyes. H that I
meditation comes on so strong. I can get
there so quickly. I'm already seeing the
little bubble zone that I get into. Uh,
but a little meditation, smoke a little
ganja, get in that iie meditation. That
is as I as you could feel right there.
So, it just makes things feel better.
Uh, it's like sprinkles. It's like
glitter on boobs. It just makes it a
little bit better. Um, and then it I've
got a brain injury. Um, I think it was
2015. I hit my head. Uh, I'm not going
to tell you the whole story. I hit my
head. Uh, almost died. Uh, deleted a lot
of the files on my hard drive. I [ __ ]
up my memory pretty good from that brain
injury. I've got some glitches. Um,
they're fixing up. It's been a long
time. It's been nearly 10 years, which
is amazing. Wow. It'll it'll be 10 years
here in a month. Um, but I still have
some glitches and issues from that.
They're clearing up. But when I would
smoke ganja, specific strains,
especially Lemon Jeffrey, it would quit
the little skips in my brain from
happening. I kind of described it as uh
there was a scratch on my CD. If you
guys are from the CD era, how old are
you? Um if you had a scratch on your CD,
sometimes your CD would just have a
little skip, a little skip, a little
skip. Or maybe it's a record player if
you're even older. That record would
skip, the record would skip, and then
you got to clean the record or clean the
CD. I feel like smoking ganja cleans my
CD sometimes or cleans my record. Now,
don't get me wrong. The first two dabs
are medical marijuana. If I take two
dabs, those are medical. The first one
that gets me right, that gets my [ __ ]
my brain to not skip. The second one
makes sure that I won't skip for a few
hours, fixes me, balance me out,
balances me out, gets me going. My third
dab, no [ __ ] That is a recreational
marijuana dab. That third one is
different. That third one is because I
like to get high and consume. So, don't
don't get me wrong here by saying that
I'm smoking to fix my glitches. Uh, that
is what the key is here. It makes me
feel better. It stops the glitches. But
that third, fourth, fifth dab, uh, those
are for enjoyment. I'm not going to lie.
I'm not trying to hide it. That's
because I like the effects and the
feelings of consuming five dabs. It just
feels good. Um, and I'm not going to get
sick. I'm not going to die because it's
not any of the crazy drugs that are out
there. It's not going to damage my
liver. I might drink an extra Horritos,
which is going to put me at risk for
that type two diabetes, but uh some
water and a good meal. I will be okay.
The most damage I'm going to do is I'm
going to eat like [ __ ] for that day if I
take five dabs. Where are we? It fixes
my glitches. Uh medical benefits, not
just me, but I've seen cannabis improve
the quality of many people's lives. I
can't tell you that it has healed
people. I know people that have used
cannabis to uh overcome problems and
symptoms and ailments and diseases, but
I can't tell you too much about that cuz
that's kind of making medical claims and
I can't say that. But I've seen things
like that happen. Uh but I've seen it
improve the quality of people's lives is
what I can technically legally say
without any sort of ramifications. It
makes people's lives better. I had a
dispensary in 2008. Some friends of mine
and I, shout out to the whole crew, uh
you all know who you are. We had a
dispensary in downtown PBLO. People
would come in and I had a large
demographic of people um 21-year-old
dudes that would run into the dispensary
and run out and people would say,
"What's wrong with that guy?" And I
would say, "He's got a heart condition
that if he doesn't consume cannabis, his
heart rate starts going all wonky. The
cannabis helps his heart rate stay in
line. You can't see what people's
conditions are." So, he's 21. He runs
in, he runs out. He still buys cannabis
to improve the quality of his life. I
had a little tiny old lady. We'll just
call her Carol. Uh she was all hunched
over. She had a plethora of medical
problems. She was on a mountain of
medications. She came to my dispensary
looking for some type of relief. She had
never smoked cannabis
before. This was before a lot of the
rules. Uh there were no rules at this
time. We were kind of developing the
rules at this as this was happening.
Since we didn't have any rules, I
grabbed her a chair. Her husband was
with her, so she was safe. Let me put
this in in line. Give her a disclaimer
here. Carol had her husband with her.
she was safe and he approved of what we
were doing. I grabbed a chair and I
said, "I really think from your
description smoking this product and I
grabbed I think it was chocolate chunk
if my brain serves me correctly." I
said, "I think you want to smoke some of
this chocolate chunk. Would you like to
try it?" And she said, "Sweetheart, I've
never smoked." And I said, "Let's
smoke." And we sat down and I packed a
bowl. I showed her how to pack a bowl of
chocolate chunk. I showed her how to
light it from the top and not the bottom
like we saw that one dude do on that TV
show that made him look like a head. uh
showed her how to take one good smoke
out of that bowl, tap it out with our
put it out with her lighter and set it
down. I showed her how to inhale it,
exhale it smoothly. And then her husband
and I sat there with her for a few
minutes and I watched the symptoms of
her pain and her anxiety. She was bent
over. She was hunched over. She was sad
and she was scared. And she took an
inhale and she blew it out. And you
could watch her shoulders just drop from
the stress. The stress blew out when she
exhaled. her neck went up a little bit
and her curiosity of life went back up.
I watched that lady enjoy life just with
one puff of cannabis. She said, "This is
working. This is doing something for
me." And so I gave her multiple grams of
different kinds of flowers to take home
with her. I had that uh permission from
the from the dispensary. It was I could
give those products away because this
was going to help this lady. Uh, I gave
her like probably seven or eight
different grams and I told her, "Go home
and try these all at different times and
just take one puff and see which one
does your mind, your body, your spirit
the best that we could do for you and
then we'll start providing that for you
on a very regular and cost-effective
basis." So, I got to see this lady over
time. Uh, I keep saying she was hunched
and she was folded over. She was a foot
shorter than she should have been
because her confidence in life, her
confidence in herself had vanished
because of her illness. Uh the pain was
taking over. She was becoming afraid of
life. She was becoming depressed. She
couldn't go out and function. So, she
was becoming a hermit, which was
compounding all of these things. And
then the the results of that I just
stuttered so bad. I don't usually
stutter. That was wild. The results of
this were she was hunched over like the
freaking hunchback of Notre Dame. And
when she started smoking, it gave her
back her confidence, her enjoyment, her
self-esteem, her physical pain went
away, which made her smile, which made
her and her husband get along better.
This is one person out of probably a
thousand people that came to my
dispensary. I'm just guessing a thousand
people that came to my dispensary that I
got to interact with and help and
improve the quality of their life. So if
you don't fall in love with something
and then I was growing that product. I
was working with the plants and feeling
the vibration, the love, the energy from
the plants. I got to grow them and then
we got to trim them, dry them and cure
them and then take them downstairs and
give them to Carol and watch her life
get better. Like how couldn't you fall
in love and enjoy that? That is uh from
start to finish that is a fulfill
fulfilling feeling. There's nothing but
love and care and compassion and
positivity in that. There's no darkness.
There's no downside. There's no
negativity. The negativity and downside
was all Babylon legal ramifications. We
were closed because we were illegally
zoned and then they tried to find us and
do all kinds of dumb [ __ ] but we got
out of that. But um so I got to see
young people, old people, and everything
in between improve the quality of their
life by consuming a product that my
friends and I cultivated in a facility
upstairs. So that was how can you not
love seeing people feel better? like
they were sick, they were sad, they were
scared and now they enjoy life and they
pop in every week to remind me. Um, we
had a burn victim that came to the
dispensary and he was um toasted from
head to toe. He looked like you were
thinking yes. And many people um they
were afraid of him because of his
appearance. And I had to overcome a
little bit of um it might have been
fear. I don't know what it was, but I
had to shake this man's I didn't have
to. I got to I got to shake this burned
victim's hand and look him in the eye
and make friends with him. And then he
was a firefighter that got burned up
really badly and we got to help him and
develop a relationship with this guy.
People were afraid of him when he first
came in and he was afraid of us when he
first came in. But after a few visits,
that guy was our friend and we respected
each other and took good care of each
other. So I remember a lot of those
people that came to the dispensary. They
all have a spot within me still. I feel
like I still carry that energy uh as I'm
breeding, as I'm growing, as I'm
smoking. that is still in me uh and that
is still out there in the community.
Those people still remember me as the
guy that showed them how to use cannabis
and medical marijuana properly. So ah
that's a huge role to play on both sides
of that relationship. Um my next note is
unity. Have you ever seen a bunch of
people smoke and get mad at each other?
Like I've never taken a dab and been
like a you know what [ __ ] you. That's
never happened. I've taken a shot of
tequila and I don't know what they put
in tequila. a Jagermeister. They both
have it, but there's a surprise in the
bottle. It could be in the first shot or
the 17th shot. They just it's in there
somewhere and you never know who's going
to get it either. But you could take a
shot of Jäger Memeister and by the time
you sh set that shot glass down on the
table, you just pick somebody and you
have decided, "Fuck you. [ __ ] you, your
mom, your mom's dog, [ __ ] your uncle."
And I don't even know why, but we have
to fight now. And that's in Tequila,
that's in Jaggermeister. Uh whiskey
doesn't do that. Whiskey has a coyote
arm. Coyote arm is when you take a shot
and your arm flies up in the air and you
go, "Woo, that's coyote arm." Uh, but
you never get that out of cannabis.
Cannabis doesn't have coyote arm.
Cannabis doesn't have fist fights. Uh,
cannabis doesn't have shitalking in it.
Uh, cannabis has unity in there. You
smoke some dabs, you smoke a joint, and
everybody you just smoked with is now
some of your best friends forever. Even
when that buzz wears off, you're still
going to be friends forever. I don't
know what the the magical effect is, but
I've never smoked a joint or smoked a
dab and been like, "Let's go beat
somebody up." I've been like, "Man, I've
been being a dick. I needed to smoke a
joint for like an hour now. I got to go
apologize to some people and get some
snacks." So, the unity, the unity in
cannabis. I've smoked with people of
every color. Um, white people, black
people, brown people, yellow people, uh,
what other ever brown people, whatever
other color there are. or I've smoked
with those people and we all enjoy it.
We all have a good time. There's no
racism in cannabis. Every color of
people loves to smoke. There are some
people whose uh just their brain
chemistry and their mentality, they
shouldn't smoke, but they'll learn that
and they won't and they'll just have a
bad experience on their own and they
won't enjoy it. But um every race, every
religion,
um everybody on the planet can enjoy
cannabis with me. I'm not going to
discriminate. Come smoke whatever
religion you are. Maybe we could smoke a
joint and we could solve some problems
together. If your religion and your
religion don't get along, smoke that
joint. Let's talk it out. Maybe it'll be
peaceful. Um, I wrote uh age, sex,
location. Nobody cares. Smoke. I don't
Well, I do care if you're old enough.
Like, you got to be an adult to smoke
with me. I'm not smoking with no babies
or nothing, but if you're old enough to
smoke and if you can, if you show up
with some weed, I'll smoke with you. Um,
I don't care if you're male, female. Um,
I'm adjusting to being uh more
comfortable smoking with people that are
in between. Yes, it's 2025. Uh, I'm
learning about trans people and becoming
more comfortable with that. It's what we
got to do. I'll smoke with you if you're
trans. I don't care where you are. We'll
smoke. It's more fun to smoke in weird
[ __ ] places. Um, stoners know the
coolest places to smoke. Okay, here we
go. Random. This is out of the top of my
head. In the comment section, please let
me know your favorite place to smoke.
Where's like a creative place to smoke?
a weird place. Where's a notable place
that you have or like to smoke and
consume cannabis? Leave that in the
comment section. I look forward to
reading your comments. That's going to
be a good time. Um, and then I wrote,
"Everyone loves to smoke. The thugs, the
goths, the hippies, the rostas, the
moms, the doctors, the lawyers.
Everybody likes to smoke weed, dude.
Everybody but Babylon. Everybody but law
enforcement. And you know what? So many
of them smoke, too. Trust me, I know it.
So, everybody loves to smoke ganja. How
could you not?" So the question was how
did I fall in love with cannabis? Um
first of all by smoking it and feeling
better. And then second I got to grow
cannabis and then being around the
plants and watching them grow. I can
grow from a seed all the way to a
smokable product by myself. I don't need
any intervention. I don't need a hand. I
can do that. Um me smoking that product
I grew as such a fulfilling experience.
Growing it was a ritual and a meditation
in its own. Smoking it is a ritual and a
meditation and its own. Sharing that
with you, watching you enjoy it is a
whole another meditation and ritual in
its own. And I love every step of it. A
lot of people find growing cannabis to
be daunting and to be a task and to be
work. I could grow weed all day and not
do any work. I love producing and
cultivating cannabis. So, I get to grow
it. I get to smoke it. And then I get to
breed it. Now, my role in the community
is making new strains. I'm creating new
cultivars and new genetics for
recreational and medical consumers to
enjoy. Uh, and mostly what I'm doing is
creating [ __ ] that I enjoy. And then it
just so happens that you guys like what
I'm making. It's like a musician. It's
like I'm making an album and I'm like,
"This is how my heart felt. This is the
music that I heard. I'm going to put it
out. And if you love it, you love it.
And if you don't, you don't. Luckily,
I've got a good uh eye or ear or nose
for growing because you guys really seem
to love it. So, I think my love for the
plant uh shows in how I grow and how I
breed. Uh how I come on here every week
and give you 30 minutes of my time just
talking about ganja for free. I don't I
do have a Patreon channel, but without
the Patreon, I would still do this. So,
I think my love reflects for that and it
developed by uh smoking and enjoying it.
I can remember smoking with my high
school bros, Chris and Shannon and Randy
and Andy and Greg and Todd didn't smoke
much, but he hung out. Um, I'm sure I
missed Dave and Brandon, and there's a
bunch of them. I'm trying not to miss
anybody, but that was my high school
crew. Some of my favorite memories are
just in the car smoking with those boys
or driving around trying to find weed to
smoke with those boys. That was part of
the adventure back then. You guys are
spoiled now. All you new smokers are
spoiled. Back then, we had to drive
around and just hope that one of the
buddies would page us back. Yeah. Pager,
dude. That's how it was. You'd go to the
Burger King and Burger King had a pay
phone and you'd page them and put in
your pager number or your cell phone. We
didn't even have cell phones. It's a
pager. Or you put in the Burger King pay
phone number and hang out by the phone
and hope your buddy calls you on time.
Like, or just drive around and hopefully
we'd see one of our weed dealer friends
driving around town or maybe he's at the
park or who knows. Things were so
different. Now you run out of weed, you
just go to the [ __ ] store down the
street. There are 20 stores within 5
minutes of me. I could go buy weed and
concentrates or whatever. It's wild now.
I don't even remember where I was in
this part of the chat. But but part of
my love for this plant developed just
around finding cannabis. It used to be
fun. And I know it sounds like a pain in
the ass, driving around looking for
weed, but that was part of the mission.
Just driving around trying to find it
and then finding somewhere safe to smoke
it and then figuring out what you're
going to do after you smoke it. What
kind of shenanigans do we get into? And
then after that shenanigans happened,
you and your friends never forgot about
that. You there was some blank [ __ ] you
didn't remember, but you always laughed
about. Remember that time that Chris did
this and then fell off of this into the
pool and whatever. Just some random
[ __ ] You'll always remember that. So
cannabis is always a good time if
respected. You could disrespect it and
uh you could try to get too high and you
will. You'll get the spins, you might
get the throwups or whatever. And you
could definitely uh if you try to do
something silly, this is where we make
that adult disclaimer. Don't drive if
you're all [ __ ] up and don't operate
heavy machinery and don't do dumb [ __ ]
because cannabis will make you respect
it. But if you respect this plant and
love the plant, it will love you back.
Whether you're a recreational consumer,
whether you're a medical consumer,
whether you're a spiritual cannabis
consumer, that's new. I'm just I'm
making that one my own term now. There's
medical, there's recreational, and now
there is spiritual cannabis consumption.
Whichever one you're doing it for, if
you're just doing it just cuz you like
to smoke weed and get high, that that's
fun. That's awesome. All right, guys.
Luckily, I got interrupted or I would
still be rambling about why I love this
plant. It is time for me to wrap up this
podcast. I think I have made my point.
Uh, I have been consuming cannabis since
I was a youngster. I remember one time,
I got to give my uncles another shout
out, then we'll finish this up. I
remember one time being in the back of
my uncle Eric's Chevy El Camino with a
camper shell on it. Uncle Eric and Uncle
Ron, both of them have passed. Miss you
boys. Love you. Rest in peace. They were
smoking a joint. We were on our way to a
concert. They were listening to the
Metallica Black album. That smoke came
to the back of that car and I got so
stoned. Uh I think I've been a pthead
since then and they didn't even know it.
So big shout out to my uncles Ron and
Eric uh for setting me on the right path
and giving me the right idea about
cannabis. I saw them do a lot of other
things and I saw that ganja was the way
to go. I always loved the smell of it
from the beginning. Uh I loved being
around those guys when they smoked and
then I saw it everywhere else I went and
I learned to recognize it. I could smell
it. could see it and I knew. So, I think
I was a stoner before I even was a
stoner. I was born into this. Um, and
I'm grateful that I found this niche.
Without this plant, who knows? I don't
even We'll We'll guess, we'll speculate,
we'll anticipate where I would be. I'd
probably be a failed musician. Um, I
would probably be working at a bowling
alley or something like that right now.
I'd probably be working at Guitar Center
trying to sling drums or some [ __ ] like
that. That's probably what would have
happened without cannabis. So, I've got
nothing but love, gratitude, and respect
for this plant. Uh, my dude, Lucky Bowl
Packer, you are a lucky bowl packer
because you are the only one that is
going to get free seeds on today's
episode. Make sure you check your inbox
for that coupon code for free seeds.
Everybody else out there, I talk about
free seeds on every podcast. Every time
I read these questions, I do give free
seeds. Don't feel discouraged if I did
not read your question on this episode.
I've got a mountain of emails over here
in front of me. Got a whole another
stack of them here in another little
paper holder thing. If I did not read
your question on this episode, have no
fear. It could be the one right on top
of this pile. I could read your question
on the next episode. Also, keep sending
in good questions. Who knows, your
question may pop up on the next show and
you could win free seeds. Don't forget,
check out
iiegenetics.com. There's a link to
IEDirect. That's where you can get the
seeds. There's a link to the Discord
server. Join us on Discord. Come take
dabs. I hang out on Discord. I take dabs
on video. You can ask me direct grow
questions. We can hang out and [ __ ]
Who knows what's going on on Discord.
Pop in, say hello. There's also a link
to what else didn't I tell you? Patreon.
There's a link to the Patreon on urie
genetics.com. All right, that's all the
advertising I'm going to do for today.
I'm going to wrap up this podcast. I'll
be back in a week with fresh new
content. I want to give a big shout out
to my friend, Smell My Fingers. And
until next time, take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me.
Roster Jeff, you bad [ __ ]
Time to take another damn. Grab your
piece and hug the bag of death in the
lab. Sit back and relax.
Roots and wisdom start to
show from the knowledge seeds we grow.
Tuning out to hear the vibr in our
conscious
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be
heard. Healing like canby grow from your
heart. Pure bliss. Rise up higher. Find
your way. Grow from your hearts every
day. In the light we stand real strong.
Join the movement. Sing the
song. Natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
door. Educate and eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth. In the soil lies the
proof. Ra will guide you through. In
this God define the new. Rise up higher.
Find your way. Grow from your hearts
every day. In the light we stand real
strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song. Ooh.
[Music]
Oo. Open minds to see the truth. In the
soil lies the proof. Ra Jeff will guide
you through in this garden. Find a new.
Rise up higher. Find your way. Grow from
your heart every day. In the light we
stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the
song.
Ooh. Ooh.
[Music]
[Applause]