[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Yeah. Welcome back podcast
world. I'm your host Rosta Jeff. This is
episode
876 of the Grow from Your Heart podcast.
You know, I've got a great episode lined
up for us. In today's show, I'm going to
give away free seeds. Hang out. We'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in the show. Before we get too far, I
do want to send a big thank you shout
out for all of the great responses to
the previous episode. The previous
episode, of course, was the Clone Care
Show. I did a full podcast about taking
clones. I talked about making clones in
an easy cloner environment. I talked
about clones did a clone dome setup. I
went on for a full hour. It was a great
show. I got a lot of great response.
Thank you for all of the great
responses. That is very encouraging. Uh
that show was a lot of uh energy to put
together and it definitely was worth it
due to all of the great response. Thank
you. If you didn't see it already, uh
after you watch this one, go check out
the previous show about cutting clones.
And in the very near future, I will work
on an episode about potting those
clones. Uh once you cut them, they're
going to start to grow roots eventually.
We're going to have to put them into
something. I'll make an episode for you
about that coming soon. All right, this
episode is going to be a questionand
answer podcast. I have a website. That
website is ireie
genetics.com. At the top of that
website, there is a row of tabs. One of
those tabs does say grow or grow
questions. If you click on that tab,
guess what? You get to send me a grow
question. If I read your question here
on the podcast, I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at
urieirect.com. The first question on
today's podcast came from our new friend
who wants to be called Ryan D. Big shout
out to my new friend Ryan. Thank you for
the great question. Ryan, check your
inbox and also check your spam because
you have got a coupon code for a free
pack of seeds at
iedirect.com. Ryan's question, there's a
nice intro. Uh, thank you for your
service. I'll start with that. He does
mention that he is a veteran, a disabled
veteran. There's more to it, but then it
gets right to the question. It says, "I
have a question on growing naturally and
scrogging." Scrogging, of course, is
when we put a net down and we work the
plants into the net and we trellis them
out. We'll talk more about that as we go
on. So, it says, "I have a question
about growing naturally and a
scrogging." So, naturally is going to be
uh not scrogging them out, just letting
them grow wild, letting them get big. Uh
they're it's a big difference in my
opinion in my grow. Uh, it says, uh,
when you do, which do you prefer and
why? I've grown both ways and I've hit a
monster number on two plants in an AC
Infinity 4x5. I hit 15 plus ounces on a
harvest. In a 4x4, you got 15 ounces. We
can improve that, my dude. I guaranteed
we can improve that. It's not a bad
harvest, but we can increase that. But
there is more. He goes on. It says,
"I've grown other plants naturally and
only lollipopped them, and I get roughly
200 grams." Thank you, Ross to Jeff. I
look forward to hearing your reply. Stay
cool. Keep pushing them killer strains.
He wraps it up with, I have been wanting
the Lemon Jeffrey, but you seem to be
out. Yes, I'm out of Lemon Jeffree seeds
for the time being. I'm currently out. I
will make more. Those are uh in the
rotation to be re uh remade. It just
takes me a minute to get them back in
line. Uh there will be clones and cuts
available on i redirect randomly. Maybe
join the newsletter on ienetics.com. I
will let you know when those clones and
cutings are available. But the lemon
Jeffree will be back in seed form
eventually. Let me stay focused here. Um
the main part of the question is which
do I prefer? Do I prefer to trellis the
plants out or let them grow naturally
was the other uh the other option here.
So uh kind of depends on the goal and
the situation. If I'm just doing a quick
pheno hunt uh and I want to run small
plants, I might do a bunch of those and
I will not trellis them. I will put up a
trellis net, but it serves a different
purpose in this run. Um, I'm going to
just use that net as a support. So,
those plants are going to grow right up
into it and that one top cola is just
going to be supported by that net.
That's all that trellis net is for. So,
in some runs, no, I don't do it. If I'm
just doing a quick small run of a pheno
hunt uh to pack a tent full of just a
bunch of small plants and see what we
get, then no, I will not trellis them. I
will not top them. I'll do minimal
lollipop, which is just cleaning up that
junk on the bottom. Minimal work to them
on a pheno hunt. Now, once I found the
keeper plant and I'm filling up a tent
and I want to make some production out
of it, I trellis the [ __ ] out of those
rooms. I crop it. I scrog it. So, I'll
start with plants that are approximately
uh waist high, chest high. To me, I'm a
tall dude. Uh that's three or four feet.
And I'll bang those plants down until
they're 2 feet tall to start my trellis.
And then I will work those plants out.
Instead of being this tall, I'll bang
them out to be a flat canopy. And the
reason for doing this, there's a lot of
reasons for doing this. I find, and I do
this in a commercial environment, I
trellis them very heavily. I put out the
nets, and then I work the plants into
that canopy very heavily all through
veg, uh, early flower, and then possibly
late into the flowering phase. I won't
stop working them in. If I can level
that out a little bit, I will still keep
doing it. My reason for this, if I don't
do it, I'm going to get those big giant
glory buds that grow right into my
lights, and then I get a bunch of buds
down here at the bottom that aren't
getting enough light. I could top that
and take that big top out. Or I could
bend that bad [ __ ] over and work it
through the net and work it down the the
canopy a little bit better. I could take
all those side branches and pull those
down. Now, what happens? You have a
branch that is growing straight up or
kind of up. It's growing out from the
plant and growing up. It's growing
upward. These plants want to go up. They
go toward the light. Uh they gravity
tells them which way is up. They want to
go up. That's what they're going to do.
They have aical dominance. One branch is
going to fight for the top at all times.
So when we trellis them down, we do a
few things. The plant starts to say,
"Hey, all the tops have been lowered.
I've got a chance to be the top at this
point. Maybe I could be the top." And
they all start growing more rapidly.
They want to be the top. It evens out
the growth of that plant a little bit.
The hormones move around. Uh it makes
that plant want to grow more evenly.
Now, also, what will happen? Those
branches that we're growing up, we've
now leveled them out. They're
horizontal. Now, your shoots are going
to grow out of those. Normally, you'd
grow a branch and it would get a chute
right here that would grow a bud. It
would get a chute that would grow a bud.
Now, your plant is horizontal. All those
shoots are going to grow vertically up
and you're going to have a nice smooth
even canopy with a bunch of shoots
growing out of that instead of just a
bunch of like three or four big donkey
dicks. Now, we're going to get a whole
bunch of regularsized dicks, which is a
very terrible comparison. I kind of wish
I wouldn't have gone that route. This is
where we are. So now instead of just
those three big [ __ ] glory buds in
the room, you've got a whole bunch of
nice manageable buds across the entire
room. Now if you're growing in a 5x5
tent, um you got that hot LED light,
you're going to have a couple of buds.
If you don't trellis them, you'll have a
couple of buds that are right at that
light. The tops of those are going to
look like [ __ ] They're going to get
crispy. It'll get a little bit better as
it gets down. And then down here at the
bottom, all these plants are going to be
shaded out by your colas. They're not
going to get enough light. Now that
we've spread that out and evened it out,
that light is going to be even across
the whole canopy. You're going to get
nice even buds in the entire tent. And I
can do that in a gigantic room. I used
to run rows that were 6 feet wide and 75
ft long and trellus the entire thing.
And when it came harvest time, those the
canopy was perfectly [ __ ] even. Those
plants, it just looked like you took a
hedge trimmer and evened them out
because we worked that canopy so much.
So, I prefer to trellis them. I prefer
to scrog them uh if I'm going for
production, if I want numbers, if I want
to see some results. Uh even in my
breeding runs, I trellis those plants
down because I can lower it, spread it
out more, uh and not get them up there
toward that hot light, create a more
even space. So, what I do, I take that
branch, and you can watch there are
thousand great videos out there. Uh
what's his name? Mr. Scroggit. Watch
that dude if you want to be a
professional scrogger. I always shout
out Mr. Rob Janie taught me how to
really scrog. I knew how to do it. Was
intimidated by it. Rob Janie was kind of
like, "Don't be a [ __ ] Pop it. Twist
it. Scrog that [ __ ] in there." And
that's where I really learned how to do
it. So, we're taking a branch that's
going up. I'm going to grab it down here
a little bit and give it a little twist.
You're going to hear go pop. And now
that branch is very manipulated, a bowl.
I don't know what the word is. And then
I'm going to I've got my net that is uh
it's about here, right? My net has come
down. I've lowered my net to where this
top is just sticking out. I'm going to
bend that branch down into another
square of the net and work it in. And if
it's long enough, I'll let it pop out of
the other side. And that part's going to
start growing and working its way up.
All these shoots now are going to work
their way up. When this one gets a
little bit longer, I might work it into
the next part of the canopy. If it
doesn't get long enough, I might free it
and let it grow up. This is a a work in
progress. The canopy, the scrogging is a
a daily process. I'm in there every
couple of days just popping them,
twisting them, working them where I want
to be so that I can maximize that 5x5
space. Um, there's a guy named Eric Bixa
that wrote an article called Growing on
the Grid probably 25 years ago that I
read and that stuck in my head. Why
would I want to grow? Let's think about
it this way. You got a 5x5 tent that is
5x5x 5x5 whatever you do the geometry
there. This many cubic feet of grow
space. Would you, if I told you fill
that cubic grow space with weed, do you
want a low canopy with a couple of big
buds sticking out wasting space or would
you try to pack that [ __ ] nice and
evenly to where all of that canopy is
filled with weed? That's what Eric Bixa
teaches us to do uh in the article
growing on the grid. He wants uh so his
ideal uh setup what I would do also now
what I've kind of learned I use two net
systems. One is to pull the plants down
to lower them and I weave them into
that. Then as they grow, I put up
another net to support those colas
because if I do it right, they're going
to get big. In a big commercial
environment, I would put a third net
also. It would get crazy. I know it
sounds wild, but those buds were four,
five, six or seven feet tall. So, my
first uh my first grog is to pull them
down. My second one is to grow uh to
keep them uh supported. What I want to
do is have one cola in every square of
my 3x3 canopy netting. So, one butt in
everything. That is called growing on
the grid and I learned that one from
Eric Bixa. Another thing that I learned
was from my buddy Subcool. Shout out to
Subcool. Rest in peace, brother. [ __ ]
miss you. Wish you were still around to
teach me some more [ __ ] and spread some
good seeds. But Subcool once taught me.
He said the same thing. If I gave you a
[ __ ] cooler, brother, and I told you
to fill it with weed, would you put a
few buds in there this way and stack
them up like baguettes where you can
barely close it, or would you put a
bunch of normalsized buds in there and
just fill that bad [ __ ] all day with
normalsized buds? It's up to you. So, it
makes sense to me. That's why I prefer
scrogging, uh, trellising, working a
canopy. There's a lot to it that's not
just pulling the net down and [ __ ]
narrow, lowering the plants. Uh, I let
the plants grow and then I just drop the
net right on them. Just just pull it
down. I put it on each corner of the
tent and pull two corners at a time and
just kind of work my way around and
watch the plants bend down. You'll see
you'll start getting stressed out. When
you're freaking out those plants are
going to bend or break, go a little bit
further. That's when you need to start
getting in there and spreading them out.
I'm not going to teach you all about
scrogging right now. Mr. Scroggit is who
who to go for for that,
honestly. So many videos out there, but
spread them out. Then I also recommend
popping and twisting the bottom from
where the plant comes out of the dirt up
to where all of it actually. I pop that
main stock. I grab it with two hands. I
give it a little twist, a pop. And then
I do it up again up here. Pop. Then I do
it again up here. Pop. And I'll work the
entire main stock of that plant. Once
I've done from top to bottom of that
main stock, I'll do every single branch.
Start at the bottom. Pop, pop, pop. What
this does is it makes a little nurl, a
knuckle in your branch, and that branch
will get a little bit stronger and a
little bit thicker and a little bit more
robust. This serves a couple of purposes
in my mind. This will allow for
sturdier, beefier plants, which can
support bigger, sturdier, beefier buds,
and those bigger branches are going to
be able to promote more bud growth as
well. Then the next thing I do, I take
off all that [ __ ] on the bottom below
that first net. Once they start to grow
into that uh once they start growing
into that second net, I start cleaning
out all that [ __ ] on the bottom. All the
uh the little sucker branches, all the
lary [ __ ] the stuff that's not going to
be worth trimming. If it's not going to
give me anything worth trimming down
there, take it off. Uh don't take off
the long branches. If they reach up to
the net, leave those branches. If they
don't make it up to that net, consider
taking those branches right off. Clean
up that bottom of that canopy. uh make
all that energy go up to the top. That
is one of my pieces of advice. We're
popping. Uh we're twisting. So, we're
doing twisting. Uh we're popping the
branches. We're twisting them. We're
cleaning up the bottoms. We're
lollipopping a little bit. Once these
plants start growing up into this net,
I'm going to pop th that growth also up
top up here. Uh once that net is looking
like it's full, that's when I'm going to
put that room into flower. When I do
this correctly, if I choose the correct
strains and line up the room and veg the
appropriate time and make this work, uh
it is very easily in a 5x5 tent, uh you
could easily achieve uh two, even two
and a half, maybe three lbs. If you're
paying attention and you're choosing the
right strains and you know your strains,
you know how to feed them, you know how
to pop, twist, lollipop, uh if you know
how to trellis it all properly, you can
hit three lbs in a 5x5 tent. It is not
unheard of. It is definitely going to
depend on your skill level, your
dedication, your genetics, and also your
your environment, your lighting. All of
that will matter, but it's possible if
you trellis and scrog it properly. I've
never gotten that close without doing a
trellis system, to be honest with you.
So, uh, where are we? I think I answered
all of your questions and then some.
Rambled pretty good on that one. and my
dude Ryan D. Make sure you check your
inbox cuz like I said, you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iedirect.com. All right, Ganja farmers,
let's keep this good energy going. I do
have another good question here that
came from the growel tab on
iiegenetics.com. This one came from my
new friend who wants to be called Joe.
Joe, make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at
ireieirect.com. Before I jump into this
question, let me remind you that this
show is brought to you by our good
friends at
acinfiniti.com. That's right. Follow the
link in the show notes and the video
description to
acinfiniti.com. When you check out, use
coupon code IE army to save yourself 10%
at checkout. That's right, 10% at
acinfiniti.com with coupon code army.
Also, that coupon code is good on their
their eBay store and also their Amazon
store. That coupon code works on almost
all of the uh AC Infinity official
stores. All right, that was harder to
say than it looked. Uh I army is the
coupon code. Let's jump into this
question now before I stutter a little
bit more. It says, "If I pollinate a
femse seed with a male from another
variety, so they have a plant that came
from a feminized seed." It's just a a
feminized plant. It is now just a normal
plant at this point. Uh, no real
noticeable difference from this female
fem plant and a regular seed plant. So,
if I pollinate a fem seed with a male
from another variety. Now, I've just got
a male plant just random random dude
came by and they hooked up and they did
their thing. The question is, will the
progyny of them have more interex
traits? My question is, what do you mean
more? Where is the more coming from?
There should be no interex trait at all
in this setup. If your fem seed uh is a
true female, which that that was up to
the breeder before that, then that
should be a female. There should not be.
The misnomer that feminized seeds are
interex or hermaphrodites or herms uh is
inaccurate. That is not how it is done.
So, let me talk real quick about this
because I love to do this ramble. Uh if
made properly, feminized seeds do not
contain any hermaphroditic trait. That
is a misnomer. When you think of
feminine seeds, when you think of making
fem seeds, take the word hermaphrodite,
interex, hermy, herm, all that needs to
be removed from this whole entire
equation. Because what needs to be done
for proper feminized seeds is two true
female plants need to be used. Which
means the breeder that grew these
plants, that bred with these plants, has
grown these plants multiple times in
multiple environments and given them
stresses on purpose, [ __ ] with these
plants a lot to see what they do under
stress. If you see if I see interex
traits present themselves in my breeding
stock, I do not make seeds out of that
breeding stock. So there should not be
any. And then also I test those uh I
grow those seeds that are made and we
should not see any intersects in that
progeny. So my fem seeds there's no and
we were when we do the reversal process
we are reversing it. People say making
it harm that is not what's happening.
That is ignorance. That's miseducation.
Uh that is not what is going on. We are
using a solution. I am using a solution.
There are multiple different products
and ways out there now to make this
happen. But what we're doing is
disrupting the copper movement within
the plant which creates I'm not going to
go too far. It creates a reaction in the
plant, a hormonal reaction within the
plant that says, "Hey, I got to figure
out what to do." And that female plant
creates anthers. It's not making it
harm. It is creating full anthers. We
are treating it with a solution. This
would not have happened without a
chemical solution. I am causing this
with chemicals. It is not a
hermaphrodite plant. There's no
hermaphrodite involved. Plant A and
plant B, neither one of those were
hermaphrodite. The progyny that comes
from that, no hermaphrodites in there.
So, I'm not giving you any
hermaphrodites to start with. The male
plant that you're using, let's just say
that it's been tested and it's not
hermaphroditic at all. There's no
interex traits there. Where would the
herm trait come from? It's got to be
maybe it's a super recessive trait that
is hidden in these genetics. That is
possible that's in there that can be
unlocked. one of the grandparents,
great-grandparents somewhere down the
line may have had the interex trait. We
could unlock that, that's possible, but
highly unlikely if the breeding is done
properly here. So, the idea that will
the progyny of them have more interex
traits? Uh, no. That where did the
interex come from? The way I kind of
think of breeding and this is mostly
accurate except the flaw here is
recessive traits. The way that I think
of breeding is uh the ingredients you
put in or the ingredients you're going
to get out. It is a lot like cheffing uh
except uh there's also with cheffing
there's a lot of [ __ ] happening behind
the scenes that we can't see. We have
only have a few uh senses and traits we
can observe. We can see weed. What does
it look like? We can also see food. When
you see both of them, you go, I want
some of that. There's you know what
traits you like. Do you like fried
looking [ __ ] Do you like stuff that's
been decorated with frosting and [ __ ]
crumbly [ __ ] on top of it? You know what
triggers your brain? What kind of weed
do you like? Do you like purple weed,
bright green weed, dark green weed with
[ __ ] purple [ __ ] whatever you're
into. You know what you like? We got our
eyes. We got our nose. Before you even
see food, you smell it and you know I
want that. Or you go that gumbo smells
like dog [ __ ] Like your brain tells
you. It does the same thing with weed.
We've only got a few senses and we can
use that. It's just like cheffing. So,
whatever you get, if you put chocolate
and strawberry into your uh oven and mix
it, I'm making up a cake here is what
I'm trying to do. If you make a
chocolate strawberry flavored cake,
you're going to get chocolate strawberry
flavored outcome. If you put uh
non-hermaphroditic plants together,
where did the hermaphroditic traits come
from? That's what I'm talking about.
It's what I'm trying to get to in this
long ass ramble here. You're going to
get what get out what you put in. So, if
nothing is interex going in, nothing is
interex coming out. Unless, like I said,
my flaw here is that recessive trait,
uh, that old recessive gene that may
have lied in one of the grandparents,
but I've tested the mom, the dad, and
the mom and the dad of both of these
plants enough times where I know there
should not be interex. So, uh, the idea
of more uh, no, that that shouldn't
happen. Uh, the fems are not herms in
the first place, and your male plant is
not a herm in the first place. The only
real difference, and I've been giving a
lot of shout outs on knowledge in this
podcast. I feel like that's important.
The only difference in a feminized seed
and a non feminized seed is uh the
pollen. The pollen is the only
difference. Once that pollen hits the
ovule and the plant happens, there's no
difference except there's no option for
a male chromosome to get in there
because there were no male chromosomes
uh present in this uh breeding project.
Uh I was going to give some credit to my
friend Mr. Soul. Mr. Soul put this
analogy in my head. This is not how it
works. This is an idea to how to teach
you. Imagine if we took a male plant and
a female plant and we figured out how to
remove the male pollen from the air
before it got to the female. That's
basically what we've learned how to do
when making fem
seeds. And I know that the pollen is
what decides sex because I'm not
treating the female plants in any way.
the pollen receiver are not getting
treated any specially any special way.
The pollen donor is the one I'm [ __ ]
with and manipulating. So, I know that
is where my female traits are coming
from. My all female pollen. That's where
that's coming from. So, essentially,
imagine if you learned how to suck the
male pollen right out of the air before
it got to the girls. That's all we are
doing with fem seeds. There's no
difference. Once that interaction
happens, the difference is over. There's
no difference. People like to think,
say, claim, show me. Get the same strain
in a reg seed, the same strain in a fem
seed. That's going to be hard. Uh, but
get the same thing. Run them side by
side in the exact same conditions. We're
going to have to do this four, five,
maybe 10 times because genetics are
going to be different. Breeders are
going to be different. But I bet
scientifically we don't see much of a
difference. I bet smoking wise we don't
see a difference. Um, I bet it's you
won't notice a lot of difference. People
say that the uh the fem seeds have less
vigor. They are less potent. Uh that's
wild because uh I sell a lot of seeds. I
offer regular and feminized seeds. I put
seeds on the website for very fair
prices. And uh approximately 80% of my
seed sales are fem seeds. So if they're
so shitty, why are people coming back
and buying fem seeds? Also, Lemon
Jeffrey, Golden Goat, Orange Gasm, Rose,
Blanch, my top sellers lately are
[ __ ] killing it. Guess what? all fem
seeds. So, that is my argument there.
Um, I really rambled on that one for a
long time. This was supposed to be an
episode where I banged through a bunch
of these papers and got a bunch of
questions answered. Instead, you're
getting long [ __ ] answers today. I
hope you're enjoying it. Uh, my buddy
Joe, I hope I answered your question cuz
I've been talking long enough, dude. Um,
no. Unless you put herms in, herms won't
come out. I tried to compare it to a
breeding mix and got lost on that or to
a growing mix and a baking mix. Couldn't
put it together today. That's my uh my
brain working for you today. Dude, check
your inbox. You've got a coupon code for
a free pack of seeds at ire
redirect.com. I'm gonna jump into
another question here. Before I do, now
is the time to remind you to click like
and subscribe. That's right. This
podcast is free. All you have to do to
support me is click like and subscribe.
That's right. I would appreciate it.
Couple of clicks won't hurt you. You're
going to be clicking on [ __ ] anyway,
bro. Just jump out of Instagram. Jump
out of whatever you're on. Go click
like. Go click subscribe. Thank you. I
do appreciate it. Also, don't forget
about
patreon.comgrow fromyourheart if you do
want to support the podcast. I said I
was going to read more questions. Let's
get right into it. This one came from a
friend who wants to be called Twisted.
Shout out to my dude Twisted. Is this
like the official Twisted? Is this the
one? I will never know. The question
goes a lot like this. It says, "Yo, Rost
Jeff." And once again, we have another
pollen question. I thought I would stick
with the theme. Can I use pollen from a
reversed female on another plant? If
yes, will that cross be feminized, too?
So, now this lets me piggyback on the
last question. This listener wants to
use pollen that came from a reversed
female. That's totally fine. That's uh
totally viable. We've got a female
plant. We have treated that plant with a
solution that is now making pollen,
right? We've got that pollen from our
reversed female. Can we put this on
another plant? Absolutely [ __ ] yeah,
dude. I encourage that. That is making
new [ __ ] Uh, open up the the gene pool.
Yes, do that. Um, will that cross be
feminized also? Yes. Because like I said
a moment ago, that pollen is what
dictates the feminization. That's a word
I think I might have just made up. Uh,
of these seeds that those uh the pollen
is what dictates the male or female and
we are using all female pollen. So, your
progyny will be all female. This makes
me want to explain um a couple of
growing and breeding terms and labeling
terms with you. So, you said if I use
pollen from a reversed female, let's
start there. We've got pollen from a
reversed
female. Let's just say for shits and
giggles because this is familiar in my
head. The plant we are working with here
is golden goat. You have taken a golden
goat female. You have made reversed
pollen. We're going to take that pollen
and put it on another clone of golden
goat. Same plant, just a different
clone, right? Same [ __ ] genetics. Uh,
just a different version, a different
plant of the same genetics. My screen
just went all blue. I don't know if I
have a computer anymore. That's weird.
Uh, I don't need notes right now. We
will survive. Panic mode has set the
[ __ ] in. Um, so we've taken that pollen
from the golden goat. We put it on the
other golden goat. That is golden goat
S1. That is what is known as an S1 or a
self golden goat. Golden goat. And this
is the way you're going to remember it.
Golden goat [ __ ] itself. Selfded
itself. It just jerked itself off. Made
its own seeds of itself. Golden goat
self seeds. That's a golden goat. If
it's the first time this happened,
that's a golden goat S1. The self first
generation of self seeds is that S1
golden goat. Took the golden goat on
golden goat. Pure golden goat S1. I
think that's going to stick in your
brain the way that I said it. Now, let's
take this golden goat pollen and put it
on some other plants. I took some notes.
What do we put it on? in my notes. We're
going to put it on a lemon skunk plant.
And we're go also going to put that
golden goat pollen on a uh what's the
other one? It's a platinum tangi plant.
Now, that is going to make uh the lemon
skunk to golden goat makes lemon
Jeffrey. That's exactly how I made Lemon
Jeffrey. The golden goat. I don't know
how I said that just now. I might have
[ __ ] up the wording in my head. I'm
thinking too many thoughts with this
blue screen. Let me just fix this blue
screen of doom. It works. I do have a
computer. All right. So, we took the
golden goat pollen. We're going to put
it on a lemon skunk plant that makes
lemon Jeffrey. We take the golden goat
pollen and put that on platinum tangi.
That makes orange gm. Those are both
feminized and also two of my bestselling
strains I've ever made. So, by putting
that pollen on another plant that is a
reversed pollen, so that is known as an
R1, a reversed pollination generation
one. It's an R. If I take the pollen
from a plant and put it on itself, I
have selfded it. If I take that pollen,
the feminized pollen, and put it on
another plant, that is an R, a reversal.
If it's the first time this has
happened, it is a one that goes after
that, an S1 or an R1. I'm not going to
confuse you with other generations and
further things. That will be a future
episode. Let me uh check my notes and
get the fur out of my eye. Got a little
furry from my my hat here getting in my
eyeball. I'm not even going to edit that
[ __ ] out. It's a real show today. Um, so
that's how I made um, so the Golden Goat
S1s straight up that I sell that will be
restocked on the website probably early
fall, late summer, those are S1s. When I
take that golden goat poll and I put it
on the platinum tangi, that makes orange
gm. When I put it on the lemon Jeffrey
or on the lemon skunk, that makes lemon
jeff Jeffrey. When I put it on the red
Lebanese hash plant, that makes rose.
When I put it on the blue raspberry
truffle, that makes blanch. Those last
few plants are what are known as R1s. I
hope you saw the spit. Not even going to
edit it. Uh, but those are R1s. Self and
reversals. All of those will be
feminized because like I keep saying
that pollen came from feminized pollen.
All right, ladies and gentlemen, boys,
girls, pimps, hoes, friends, foes,
smokers, growers, clone cutters, pollen
chuckers, all of you lovely cannabis
enthusiasts out there. I do want to
thank you once again for listening to
another great episode of the podcast. I
had fun recording this one. And if you
can't tell, uh, make sure you mash that
like and subscribe button. Like I said
before, you can support the show on
Patreon at
patreon.com/growfroyouheart. I know I
was giving out seeds to supporters. I
have honestly ran out of new [ __ ] to
offer. So, I've been offering old [ __ ]
and trying to keep up, but have no fear
because there are new seeds coming very
soon. There's been a recent a recent
harvest uh of some blueberry regular
seeds. That's right. I did not talk too
much about it because I've been [ __ ]
jinxing myself by talking about talking
about projects too early. Kind of kept
this one on the download and it worked
like a champ. There's a bunch of new
blueberry crosses. I'll be loading the
website up with stuff very soon. So
check very soon. If you want updates, go
to the website
ieenetics.com. On the bottom there's a
tab that says stay uptodate. If you type
in your email address and click send,
you will join my newsletter. When I put
out new clones, new cuts, new strains,
new testers, maybe I put some [ __ ] on
sale, maybe I give you a brand new code
for AC Infinity, all of that stuff will
happen through the newsletter. So, join
that newsletter. Also, Patreon does get
the first heads up. I make the
newsletter. I make it so Patreon gets
all that heads up [ __ ] first, uh,
because of course they do contribute,
then the newsletter gets it second, then
I go to social media for my advertising.
So join all of those Patreon, the
newsletter, and of course all the social
media to stay uptodate. Also, make sure
you check out
acinfinity.com and use that coupon code
iie army. Save yourself 10%. I think
that is all of the rambling and
jabbering I'm going to do for this week.
Once again, thank you for listening.
I'll be back in a week with fresh new
content. I want to give a big shout out
to my friend Jessica K. And until next
time, take a fat dab and give your mom a
hug for me.
[Music]
Roster Jeff, you bad
[ __ ] Time to take another damn.
Grab your piece in a
ug. Sit back, poke your hungry, relax.
Roots and wisdom start to show from the
seeds we grow. Tuning out to hear the
vibr in our conscious
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be
heard. Healing like the can of this. Go
from your heart. Cure this. Rise up
higher. Find your way. Grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song. Natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
dove. Educate and eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth. In the soil lies the
proof. Ros that Jeff will guide you
through in this garden. Find the new.
Rise up high or find your way. Glow from
your hearts every day. In the light we
stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the
song.
Ooh. Ooh.
[Music]
Open minds to see the
truth. In the soil lies the proof. Ra
Jeff will guide you through in this
garden. Find a new. Rise up higher. Find
your way. Grow from your hearts every
day. In the light we stand real strong.
Join the movement. Sing the song.
Oh. Oh.
[Music]
[Applause]