[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Yeah. Welcome back podcast
world. I'm your host Rosta Jeff. This is
episode
877 of the Grow from Your Heart podcast.
You know, I have a fun show lined up for
us. In today's podcast, I'm going to
give away free seeds. Hang out. We'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in today's show. I do want to start
the podcast with a little bit of quick
advertising. You guys know 420 is
quickly approaching. That means it is
time for a 420 sale. That's right. I'm
going to do a 420 sale on
iieirect.com. That sale will start on
418. Make sure you check erieedirect.com
for sale prices and updated inventory.
There will be new tester packs and new
things available. So, make sure you
check
eriedirect.com on 418 for the 420 sale.
Also, you know, I am affiliated with AC
Infiniti. AC Infiniti is doing a 420
sale. That sale also runs April 18th
through April 21st. AC Infiniti is
offering 10% off the entire store. Plus,
if you use my coupon code IE army, you
will save an additional 10% on your full
purchase. That is a 20% off sale
sitewide by using my coupon code iie
army at
acinfinity.com. All right, I do have one
more piece of advertising, then we're
going to jump into the meat and potatoes
of this podcast. The Dude Grows Cup is
rapidly approaching. That's right,
myself and White Mike will be at the
Dude Grows Cup that will be in Longmont,
Colorado this year. Make sure you check
the
dgccup.com for all of the updated info.
They have moved the event this year. The
new venue looks like a beautiful place.
I will be there for the VIP party Friday
night. I will be there for the Saturday
DGC cup. And uh we are attending and
vending at the Sunday hash bash as well.
So come say hi at the DGCup. Make sure
you check
dgccup.com for all of the info, all of
the details for all of the tickets. Of
course, I will be giving you more
advertising and details about the cup as
the show approaches. All right, that is
all of the advertising. We made it
through the the advertising portion of
the podcast. Let's jump into the fun
part of today's podcast. Of course, that
is the question and answer portion of
the show. This is how people get free
seeds. Of course, at the start of the
show, I said we're going to give away
free seeds. How do you get those free
seeds? I have a website. My website is
iiegenetics.com. At the top of that
website, there is a row of tabs. One of
those tabs does say grow help. Maybe it
says grow questions. You're going to
figure it out when you get there. Click
on that tab. Guess what? You get to send
me a grow question. If I read your grow
question here on the podcast, I will
send you a coupon code for free seeds
from ire redirect.com. Today's first
question came from somebody who wants to
be called Cody. Big shout out to my new
friend Cody. Cody is asking a question
uh that pops up quite often in this
business, this industry, this community.
Uh, this question is sent to me quite
often. I try not to, uh, let this one
fire me up too much. I try to answer
this, uh, maybe twice a year because the
people do ask this a lot. This one
drives me a little bit crazy. I used to
do pet peeves on the show. Uh, this is
sort of a pet peeve of mine, but I'm
going to make clarity out of this. The
question from Cody. And Cody, make sure
you check your inbox, my dude, because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds. Also, check your spam because
a lot of email services think that my
gift cards are spam for some reason.
Check your spam, you guys. Anyway, the
question goes like this. It says,
"Howdy, sir." Howdy, sir. It says, "I
enjoy your show and the way you explain
things." Well, thank you. I appreciate
that. It says, "You make it easier to
digest." Uh, that's part of my goal. I
am passionately curious and I love
learning, but for some reason, I hated
school. I hated going at that teacher's
slow, boring [ __ ] pace. Uh, I hated
learning the same [ __ ] over and over for
four weeks when I learned it a week ago.
Um, so I try to make it to where you
guys are having fun. Uh, I try to tell a
joke every now and then, but I try to
get straight to the point and tell you
what you need to know, but I also try to
tell you in multiple ways because people
learn in different ways. Some are visual
learners. Uh, some people have to touch
things. Uh, I have a way that I can kind
of draw a picture of [ __ ] with my words
and show you how to do it. Some people
learn in different ways, and I'm trying
to get it to everybody, get that info
out, and not overload you. So, uh, thank
you for noticing that, uh, I make it
easier to digest. I do appreciate that.
I also don't try to overload you. Some
people will be like, "The answer is
nitrogen, but then also phosphorus and
potassium, and the answer, nitrogen
would have gotten you there. I didn't
need to overload you with shit." I try
to be conscious of that. It goes on.
There's a lot going on here. It says,
"I've never been able to find a real
answer on this question. Let's say you
have a plant that is a 10e flower. Does
that 10 week start as soon as I switch
to 1212 or does it start after stretch
and you get the puff balls?" Thank you
for your time. Have a great day. All
right. So, I jumped right into the
question part there. The question came
up. The question is, um, if I have a 10
week flowering strain, does that 10
weeks start the day I switch to 1212 or,
and I'm not even going to read the or
because why or? Why are we putting a
[ __ ] algebra equation to this? When
you are growing cannabis plants, day one
of flower begins the day you change the
timer to 1212. That is day one of
flower. You just initiated the flowering
cycle. You just change that timer. That
is day one. No ifs, ants, buts,
questions, substitutes, whatifs, how
comes. That is it. That is day one. You
don't wait until some other [ __ ]
happens. You don't wait until you start
to see this person said puffballs or
pistols. Do not wait for that. That is
not day one. Day one was the day you
flipped the timer. Uh I didn't write on
the package uh 70 days minus 2 weeks
plus 3 days plus 4 days from when you
last water. I didn't do any of that on
there. It says 70 days of flower. So,
when I wrote 70 days on the package,
that is 70 days from the day you turn
the timer to 1212. So, day one is the
day you flip the timer. It always will
be, always has been. Um, the last time I
did this episode, I got comments that
said, "Why do you get to decide that?
Why do I get to decide that? I made the
[ __ ] seeds. I printed the [ __ ]
packages. I know that. I didn't decide
it. Uh, I grew the I bred these seeds. I
grew them. I noticed takes me 70 days to
flower these in my rooms. I sent them
out to other people. Those people said
somewhere between 65 and 75 days. I said
the average of that 70 days. So I wrote
that on the package. That's how I know.
That's why I get to decide. I made the
[ __ ] seeds. I'm the breeder. I'm the
the proprietor of this company. I wrote
that on the package because I have
tested these plants. I've ran them a lot
of times. Other people have ran them.
And we've determined that on average in
most rooms, in most cases, those plants
are going to take 60 to 70 days to
finish. Uh why do we start the flower
timer on day one as day one? Because
that's when day one is. Why would you
wait till you see puff balls? Because
other people are going to see puff those
puff balls are going to appear day 12,
day 17. Now you're 5 days, you're 5 days
off schedule. Why would just do it the
day you flip the timer. Uh there's no
algebra to be done here. There's no
math. There's no questions. Day one is
day one. When you flip the timer, that
is day one. Write it the [ __ ] down. Get
a calendar. Write it down. Make a note
in your phone. I flipped this room on
this date in my calendar app in my
phone. I'll open it up right now. Um, it
shows I've got multiple environments and
different places going on. So, let's
see. The 7th was week three in my main
room. The 14th will be week four. And
then I've just got the 28th is week six.
I just went through April and every
Monday since I started my plants on a
Monday on that Monday, I just went
through and marked the calendar one
through whatever. I go all the way up to
week 10. Uh, sometimes I flower 11
weeks, but I don't I won't need that
note at that far. But I mark it in the
calendar. Room 1, tent A, flowered, and
it's at [ __ ] Today is the 12th. So
the 7th was the beginning of week three.
We're halfway through work three. Uh I'm
stuttering, but yeah, we're about to
catch up and begin week four. So mark
that note. Um and then something else to
pay attention to those numbers on those
packs. Like I said before, I ran that
plant. I ran those seeds and most of
those seeds took 65 to 75 days to
flower. So I marked that [ __ ] pack 70
days. That is the average what you're
going to get. There will be outliers.
Um, I saw a great quote on the internet.
I can't even. Guppy said it. Guppy said,
uh, I wrote 70 days on that pack.
However, the plants didn't read that
note. Some of those plants may take 75.
Some of them may take 85 days. There are
outliers within phenotypes. There are
outliers within packages. There are
outliers in population is the word I'm
looking for. Uh, most of those seeds are
going to finish at the 70-day mark for
you. Some of them may finish at day 60.
Some may finish at day 80. The bulk of
them, 75 to 80% of them will be done in
70 days is why I put that on the
package. You're going to have outliers
based on uh genetics. There's going to
be outliers just genetically. Things are
going to be uh that's how genetics work.
Also, your environment will make a
difference. The kind of light, the
intensity of light, the hours of light,
the spectrum of the light. Uh that's
going to make a difference. Your VPD
will make a difference. Your soil will
make a difference. Your feeding will
make a difference. And possibly, if you
really want to get hippie- dippy about
it, I have no proof of this, but the
moon and the sun and the seasons will
have an effect on your indoor plants as
well. So, all of those things could have
an effect. Um, so the let's jump right
back to it. Uh, when is day one is the
basic of this question. When is day one?
If you have a 10e plant, uh, it says 10
weeks on the package. Uh, does that 10
start as soon as I switch? Yes, that
starts as soon as you switch. So that
first short night, that is day one. That
time that it goes into 1212, that's day
one. Start counting from that point. Um,
dude, I really think I answered your
question and then some. So my dude Cody,
thank you for getting me rambling on
that one. Make sure you check your inbox
because you have a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at iieirect.com. And
just to be nice, I will let that coupon
code ride for a few extra days so that
you can jump in and get that 420 sale on
April 18th at
ieirect.com. I've got a good momentum
going. I'm not going to slow it down.
We're going to jump right into the next
question. This one came from It doesn't
have their name that they want to be
called on it. Uh but I'm going to send
you a pack of seeds anyway. Uh we're
just going to call you Tina. Tina, thank
you for the great question. It says, "I
have a question about light leaks in a
grow tent." Which is a very good
question. Um, is growing outside, wait,
is growing outside more superior than
indoor? Does the moon affect the
cannabis like a light leak would? So,
that's a very good question. I will
reread this and make it make a little
more sense for you. Uh, thank you for
what you bring information to everybody.
I've learned a lot. I love to listen.
Thank you again, Tina. Thank you for the
great question. What Tina is basically
asking, I always talk about how light
leaks are very important in an indoor
grow environment. They're important to
not have light leaks. What do I mean by
a light leak? That's a whole new uh
thing to open up there. A light leak.
When we're growing cannabis, we have a
dark period. That night period, the
sleeping period, that period cannot be
interrupted by light. That dark period
needs to be completely dark for 12
hours. Zero light. No light at all. Not
a light on a uh like if you have an air
conditioner or if you have some sort of
monitoring device, if there's a light on
there, that light counts. We don't want
that light. A light leak is when that
darkness is interrupted. Let's say
you've got a tent and a flap comes open
and light gets in there. Light has now
leaked into your environment. Light
leaks do cause problems in grows. They
can lead to interex traits. They can
slow your plants down from growing. Uh
light leaks can be very detrimental. So
my new friend Tina is asking um
basically uh if we're growing outside,
why doesn't the moon affect these
plants? Why don't we get light leaks
from the moon? And also we're going to
touch on like things like street lights.
We're going to touch on uh cars passing
by, uh planes flying by, helicopters,
um porch lights, just lights like that.
We're going to include that in this
topic here. So keep in mind I don't have
any notes. This is all coming out of
memory. Uh nothing here to give me a
guide on this answer. The answer is the
short answer is phytochrome and far red
lighting. That is the short answer. So
let me explain. Outdoors in an outdoor
grow environment. Our plants are outside
getting sunshine all day, right? They're
getting beat by sunshine. The first
factor here is that sunlight is way more
powerful than any grow light you will
ever imagine, any grow light you could
ever buy. It's the perfect spectrum.
It's the most intense thing that there
is. And it's natural. That is what the
plants are intuitively, instinctively,
primordial, whatever it is. That is the
thing that makes those plants go, "Yes,
that is the main thing for plants." And
they know it. So when they're out there
in the sunshine, they're getting exactly
what they need and it's a way different
feeding than the little grow light in
your house. That's barely a light
compared to the sun. So that's something
to keep in mind as we delve down this
journey here. Another thing to think
about, as the sun is setting outdoors,
it begins to put off a spectrum that
becomes red in the color spectrum as it
sets. Uh I can't tell you exactly how
this happens, but I know it does. Just
trust me. As the sun sets, it begins to
put off a red spectrum because of its
angle in the sky. Now, that spectrum
puts off a far red spectrum of lighting.
The color of lighting is far red. You
can't see it with your eye, but if you
have meters and understand that color is
far red lighting. Now, that far red
light tells that plant, it triggers in
that plant phytochrome. Phytochrome is a
uh is an enzyme or a protein. Somebody
correct me there. Um I told you I didn't
write any notes. Uh so phytochrome is
triggered in this plant. Phytochrome
tells the plant it is sleepy time.
Phytochrome is basically um giving this
plant a little bit of ambient and a nice
shot of Nyquil and maybe even uh giving
it a little tug before it goes to bed if
you want so it sleeps real nice. So as
the sun sets it creates that far red
spectrum. That far red triggers the
phytochrome in the plants. The plants
go, "Hey, it's time for me to [ __ ]
sleep." They put their little sleep mask
on. They rub one out. They take some
ambient. take a shot of Nyquil and they
lay down and they're tucked the [ __ ] in.
So that moon is natural. That moon is
there. That amount of light coming from
the moon is reflection from the sun
technically. And it is not enough light
compared to the sun. It is not enough
light to even bother those plants. First
of all, because uh the intensity of the
sun is so much more intense than that
reflection coming from the moon that
it's not going to bother them. And
that's what those plants are programmed
to do. That's naturally what happens.
whatever you believe in. I'm going to
say jaw because I'm a Rasta man. But the
creator, the most high, mother nature
would not have put a a living thing out
there that would struggle because of the
moon and the sun. Those are natural
things that nature, jaw, the most high,
whatever you believe in, it knows that
[ __ ] is there and it knows that these
plants are going to be out there in that
environment. So, nature wouldn't make it
to where the moon [ __ ] up that plant.
Nature just wouldn't do that. Whatever
you believe in or don't believe in. Even
if you're an atheist, you could believe
you can say nature or science would not
have done that to us or the plant simply
wouldn't survive. So that sunlight is a
very minimal reflection of a big ass
[ __ ] light. So you're getting I don't
know the mathematical percent. But if
the light is a thou the sun is a
thousand, the moon is a two. So it's
it's like it's not even there. It's it's
like that little nightlight in the
corner when you're at home trying to
sleep, you don't even notice that that
shit's there. The plants don't notice
that because the percentage of light
that it was getting all day compared to
the moon reflection and the combination
of the far red lighting triggering the
phytochrome response to tuck the plants
into sleep. Now, the same thing comes
into play when we talk about like your
porch light or a street light. This
depends on a couple of things. How close
to your plants are those lights? How
intense are those lights? How frequent
are those lights? What kind of schedule
are those lights on? Then it also
depends on the sensitivity of that plant
that is being affected. There's
something in a plant, I'm thinking of
the word, I'm scrolling. It's called the
critical period. The critical period is
how much darkness that plant needs to
initiate its flowering cycle. Based on
its location uh on the earth where that
plant came from or its parents came
from, it may need less or more darkness
to go into flower. Also, that same thing
goes into effect on how much light is
going to piss that plant off when it is
in its dark cycle and flowering. So, a
lot of plants, most plants, uh, a lot of
the plants we're growing now will work
well outdoor and not be bothered too
much by a little bit of light. If you
got a porch light right above your
plants, that might [ __ ] them up. If you
got a street light right above your
plants, that might [ __ ] them up. But, if
you if they're a little bit away and
it's not super intense and you've got
plants that have been adjusted to an
outdoor environment, it should not have
too much effect. This is going to be
plant specific like I'm talking about.
Um, as I reached up to describe the
street light, um, I've heard people say
just shoot that street light out. Just
disconnect that street light, ruin that
street light in some way. Don't do that
because when you do destroy that street
light or that lamp, that outdoor light,
the city is going to come replace that
bulb. And when they do, they're going to
look down and they're going to go, "Oh,
this [ __ ] shot it out cuz he's
growing weed down there." And they're
going to be mad at you. They don't care
you're growing weed. They don't give a
[ __ ] until you shot out their light. And
now they're pissed. Now, they're going
to call the cops on you and charge you
for the light and charge you for the
[ __ ] weed you're growing. So, don't
destroy that light. That is just a small
random piece of advice. So, the question
is, uh it was oddly worded, but I got it
figured out. We're growing in a tent and
light leaks matter. Why doesn't the moon
[ __ ] with our plants? Uh first of all,
because John knew better. The Most High
knew. It was like, I'm gonna give you
sun. I'm gonna give you moon. They have
to work together. I can't [ __ ] that up.
So, John knew that one. But then also uh
far red lighting, phytochrome response,
the plants are tucked in. That is
magically what's doing it. I am
affiliated with a grow light company,
but there are grow lights out there that
do have far red lighting attached to
them. Give them a try if you want to. I
have not tried it. Uh I'm not sponsored
by that company, but I heard they do
great [ __ ] All right. Uh my friend
Tina, thank you for the great question.
Um, I am going to send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds. So, make sure
you check your inbox. All right, Ganja
Farmers, I have one more great question
here in front of me. Uh, before we jump
into this question, now is the time for
me to remind you to click like and
subscribe. That's right, mash that like
button. That's free. Also, hit the
subscribe button so when I put out new
content, you'll get a notification. You
never miss any of my wonderful ganja
education. Also, don't forget there are
876 other episodes you can listen to. Go
listen to some of those old episodes.
Leave some comments, click like, give me
some likes in the algorithm. I do
appreciate it. Now, let's stay on track
and jump into this next question. This
one came from my friend who wants to be
called Patient Kuckian. Big shout out to
my buddy Patient Kuckian. There is a
long intro at the start of this one. It
says, "We met at the DGC cup. Yo, it was
great meeting you. Uh, there's a little
more going on. Uh, you've been listening
for a while and thank you. I appreciate
that. I do want to get right to the
question." It says, "On one of your
shows, you said something about a strain
that does not have a male chromosome or
something like that. You went on to say
that the strain would never have a male
plant. Uh, can you go into deeper
details about how this happens and why
you cannot have a male from that
strain?" I do know what you're talking
about and we're going to touch on this.
Uh, there's one small detail you might
have overlooked. It said, "Can this
cultivar ever have a male plant
created?" Possibly yes. Uh, then it
said, "I'm a Desert Storm veteran. Thank
you for your support, my dude. you are a
Desert Storm veteran. Thank you for your
service. Uh I definitely uh do respect
and appreciate the veterans. Said
perhaps I will have more questions when
my favorite plant becomes legal. All
right, there's a lot of stuff going on
on this question, but I want to focus on
this one part here about I said in a
previous episode that there is a plant
that does not have male chromosomes or
something like that. I want to touch on
this and just clear this up because I
don't know if other people caught this.
I don't know if I said something wonky
or misled you. Um, so a female plant, a
pure female plant does not have male
chromosomes. So what I'm talking about
in to recap on your question, what I'm
talking about in that episode, I have a
golden goat female plant, which is a
pure female. So that is two X
chromosomes. That's two girl female
chromosomes. If there was a Y in there,
that would be a male. So that's mainly
what I'm talking about when I say that
um, it doesn't have a male chromosome.
It's a female plant. Um, I've [ __ ]
with this plant. I've manipulated this
plant. It doesn't out. It doesn't give
me stress issues. So, that's what I'm
talking about. When there's no male
chromosome in that plant, it is just a
pure female. Now, here's where the magic
with that lack of male chromosomes
happens. This is where people may have
gotten confused where the uh the things
start to change. We've got a female, no
male chromosomes. That's a normal thing.
That just happens. That's how females
work. There's no Y's, it's all X's,
genetics, genes. What I'm going to do
now is I'm going to treat my double XX
plant with a solution and it is going to
create pollen, which is all X's and no
Y's. So now I'm creating all female
pollen. I'm then going to take that
female pollen and put it on other solid
female plants, XX plants, no Y's
anywhere in this mix. So now that I've
taken a female plant, I've treated it
with a solution. And now that female
plant is creating anthers with all
female pollen. And I'm going to put that
female pollen on female plants. There
will be no Y chromosome in my
mathematical equation here. So there's
no male involved. There will be all
female plants making all female seeds
here. Um that's that's why I said no
male chromosome. So I hope I cleared
that up. Not sure what I said to make
that confusing, but just in case anybody
out there misheard, misunderstood uh the
uh something about a strain that doesn't
have a male chromosome or something like
that. Yeah. Uh it just doesn't. It's a
female plant. There were other plants in
the batch that came from that batch of
seeds that were never released. Those
could have had a male in there, but the
plant that I have is pure female. The
seed that I grew, the seed, the clone
that I acquired is all female. It's a
clone plant that I got. It's all female.
There's no male chromosomes in there.
So, um I'm just going to repeat myself
by taking that female and reversing it
and putting it on another female. I
never said male in there. And people are
going to say the word hermaphrodite when
I talk about reversals. That's not
accurate. That's not true. That's not
real. Ah, that's a a weird random fake
argument. So, that doesn't count. That's
not even There's no hermaphroditism in
my breeding project in any reversal if
done correctly. If there's a
hermaphrodite, an interex plant, it's
been [ __ ] chopped the [ __ ] up and put
it in the compost bin. So, um, there is
no male chromosome simply because I'm
using all female plants. Um, could you
make a male strain? Let's see. And why
you cannot have a male? Can this
cultivvar ever have a male created? You
could treat it with epifon and it will
masculineize that plant. Yes, that's a
whole another process. Whole another
whole another [ __ ] podcast to talk
about, but you could. Yes. Um, my dude,
uh, I think I've answered your question.
I hope so. Um, the females don't have
male chromosomes because they simply
don't. And it's not an interex plant, so
there's no hidden, uh, agenda in there.
And when I reverse it, it only makes
female pollen. I'm going to put it on
other female plants that have been
tested. So, in that situation, no male
chromosomes, only females. All right, I
think I answered this one, my dude. Once
again, thank you for your service. Uh,
and I think that's how we're going to
wrap up this podcast. Make sure you
check your inbox for your coupon code
for free seeds. All right, ladies and
gentlemen, boys, girls, pimps, hoes,
friends, foes, smokers, growers, clone
cutters, pollen chuckers, veteran
growers, brand new growers, outdoor
farmers, tent growers, I respect and
love each and every one of you. Thank
you for listening to another episode of
the Grow From Your Heart podcast. If you
have any questions, corrections,
comments, or concerns, I would love to
hear from you. My email address is grow
fromyouheart@hotmail.com.
Send me your constructive criticism or
that hate mail. If that's what you got
to do, I can take it. Of course, the
grow questions have a better chance of
being answered if you use the website
growh help tab. So, go to iie
genetics.com. Click on that growhel tab.
Send me your questions there. That's how
you get free seeds on the podcast. Don't
forget about the 420 sale coming up at
erirect.com. That will start on 418.
Also, the 420 sale at acinfiniti.com.
They're going to give you 10% off just
for ordering. I will give you an
additional 10% by using my coupon code,
iie army
atacinfinity.com. That sale does start
on April 18th. Go get yourself some new
gear. I am lacing my entire grows up
with all AC infiniti. Uh we've been
slowly swapping out everything. The
whole grow will be AC infiniti before
too long. I support acinfinity.com. Let
me know if you have any questions with
that. I think that is all I've got for
you for this episode. I told you to like
and subscribe. I told you about all the
sales. Um, I said thank you, but I'm
going to say it again. You guys give me
a lot of great feedback. You make a lot
of great comments. I get a lot of great
support for this podcast. Thank you. Uh,
not just a rambly podcaster, but me,
myself, not just Rosta Jeff, but Jeff
says thank you for all the support. I do
appreciate it. All right, boys and
girls. I'm rambling at this point. I'm
going to get out of here. I'm going to
go take some dabs. I'm going to go watch
Story Wars, and I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content. I'm gonna give a
big shout out to my friend Smell my
fingers. And until next time, take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me.
[Music]
Roster Jeff, you bad
[ __ ] Time to take another damn.
Grab your piece and hug by the bag. Rise
the death is in the lab. Sit back and
relax. Hold up.
Roots and wisdom start to show from the
knowledge seeds we grow. Tuning out to
hear the vibr in our conscious
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be heard.
Healing like can abyss. Grow from your
heart, your bliss. Rise up higher, find
your way. Grow from your heart every
day. In the light we stand real strong.
Join the movement. Sing the
song. Natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
dove. Educate and eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth. In the soil lies the
proof. Raach will guide you through in
this garden. Find the new. Rise up
higher. Find your way. Grow from your
heart every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song.
[Music]
Oh, open minds to see the truth. In the
soil lies the proof. Rust Jeff will
guide you through in this garden. Find a
new. Rise up higher. Find your way. Grow
from your hearts every day. In the light
we stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the
song. Ooh.
[Music]
[Applause]