[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Welcome back, podcast world. I'm
your host, Rosta Jeff. This is episode
878 of the Grow from Your Heart podcast.
You know, I've got another fun episode
lined up for us. In today's show, I'm
going to give away free seeds. Hang out.
We'll talk more about those free seeds a
little bit later on in the show. Before
we get too far, I do want to wish
everybody a happy 420. That's right.
This episode will come out on 419. I
hope everybody has a safe and stony 420.
It would not be 420 without a 420 sale
at
erirect.com. That's right. Make sure you
check
irredirect.com for new testers,
restocks, sale pricing, and free
shipping on all orders over $100. That's
right, new testers at
irredirect.com. There is Lemon Jeffrey
to Blueberry. There is Double Dragon to
Blueberry. And there may still be a few
packs of Cherry Skunk to Blueberry. Make
sure you check
irredirect.com now because the sale has
begun. Also, there is a sale at
acinfiniti.com. That's right. Most of my
grove is equipped with acinfiniti.com
equipment. By the end of the year,
everything will be acin infiniti. I am
slowly upgrading. I recommend acinfinity
gear. Make sure you check acinfinity.com
because they are doing a 420 sale. That
sale is live now. It does end Sunday.
Uh, that sale goes April 18th through
April 21st. AC Infiniti is going to give
you 10% off everything in the store. I
am also going to give you a coupon code
for an additional 10% off. That coupon
code is IE Army. Use coupon code IE army
to save an additional 10% for a total of
a 20% discount at
acinfinity.com. All right, I think that
covers all of the news here at the start
of the show. Let's work our way into the
question and answer portion of today's
podcast. At the start of the show, I
said that I was going to give away free
seeds. This is how you win free seeds. I
have a website. That website is
iiegenetics.com. At the top of that
website, there is a row of tabs. One of
those tabs does say growl or grow
questions. If you click on that tab, you
are given the opportunity to send me a
grow question. If you send a good grow
question and I read that question here
on the podcast, I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at ire
redirect.com. Today's first question
came from the growh help tab. It came
from my new friend who wants to be
called HDB. Shout out to my buddy HD
Ben. Ben, make sure you check your inbox
and check your spam because you have got
a coupon code for a free pack of seeds.
Ben's question goes just like this. It
says, "Yo, this is Ben. Uh, I've got a
great question from a new grower. All
right, I like this question a lot. It
says, "I have a tent, a light, a clip-on
fan, controller 69, and an exhaust fan.
I need a humidifier and a tent heater
and a few other small details. What
would you buy and in what order would
you buy them for a new grower?" This is
a really good question. He wraps it up
with, I appreciate the help and I
appreciate what you are doing for the
community. Yo, I'm thank I'm thankful
that you notice what I'm doing for the
community. Uh I'm grateful for the great
message and I'm glad that you trust me
to guide you through this. Um now you've
got a great setup here and of course
most of what I'm going to recommend is
going to be from AC Infiniti. Um you
cannot beat AC Infinity when it comes to
homegrow equipment. So yes, a lot of
this stuff is going to be uh blatantly
I'm going to recommend AC Infinity gear.
Acinfinity.com coupon code IE army. Uh
that code is good on Amazon. That code
is good on Etsy. That code is good on
the AC Infinity store. That'll get you
10% off all the time. If you shop during
the sale, you will save 20%. I'm going
to say that a lot of times in this
episode, but um the things that I
recommend you should buy, you've got a
tent, so you've got the main enclosure.
That's a great thing to start with.
You've got a light. Is it a good light?
I would put a good light in there. The
best light that you can, uh the best
light you can afford, the best light you
can power, and the best light you can
cool. Those are three things to think
about. Can you afford the light? That's
the most uh biggest obstacle there. Can
you afford to run the light? Uh do you
have enough electricity in the house? Do
you have a breaker available for that
light? And can you cool it? Because that
light is going to create heat in your
environment. You need to cool that
light, that environment some way. So get
the best light that you can. Um you said
you have exhaust, so you're probably
exhausting that. Did you say that you
have a filter? I don't see the word
filter in here. I would recommend a
carbon filter. Since you've got the
exhaust, you probably have a carbon
filter on there, but I would recommend
that just for a little piece of mind, a
little safety. You've got a really and a
controller 69. So, I feel like you've
got a tent package. Uh you're off to a
really good start. You do uh indicate
that you do need a humidifier and a fan
heater or a tent heater, which uh
depending on where you live, I never
need um some things I don't need. I
don't need a dehumidifier because I live
in a dry space. It's going to be uh the
humidity. I like to keep the humidity.
So depending on where you are, you will
need certain things and won't need some
things. But yes, I can make some
recommendations to kind of upgrade your
grow experience. Um, you've got the
tent, the light, the exhaust, the
filter, the fans. We've got the AC
controller. Uh, maybe think about
upgrading to that AI controller might be
something else you want to upgrade to.
Uh, but something I would recommend, and
this is not anything that I am sponsored
by, but I like cameras in my grow
environment. You've got the ACI
controller 69. You can look on your
phone and you can see the temperature,
the VPD, you can read a lot of things
based on what gear you've got. If you've
got a camera in there, you can see the
plants. I like being able to look at the
plants. If I'm away and I'm like, man, I
kind of I'm having fun at this gathering
or playing music with friends or at a
drum circle, I know that the lights came
on. I kind of want to check on the
plants. Don't want to stop what I'm
doing, drive all the way home to go
check on plants. Uh, I can just open up
the controller or open up the uh the app
on my cameras and I can I can open up
the controller 69 and see the VPD, but
then I can open up the app and I can
look at the plants and see that they're
actually okay with my Wise cameras. I
use just basic Wise cameras for that. I
got a very good deal on Wise cameras on
Black Friday. I bought a three-pack
bundle. Um, I'm going to buy a lot more.
Those are great cameras. So, cameras in
the grow. They give me a lot of peace of
mind. Uh, they go very well with the uh
the AC Infinity Controller 69. and I can
see the temperature, the humidity. I can
see a lot of things and now I can
actually look at the plants. If you open
up my phone on the front page on the
bottom, those two apps are right there
because I open them up a lot. So,
cameras are something I would check out.
Uh, then something just to make the day
better in the grow, a Bluetooth speaker
or some AirPods. I've always got some
music, a podcast or the Discord crew in
my ear keeping me entertained. Another
thing I can recommend, uh, and these
next two things, three or four things
are very small items that are available
through
acfinity.com that you might not even
have thought about, but they will make
your grow experience a little bit
better, more enjoyable, and easier, and
more successful. AC Infiniti sells a
sprayer. It is a pesticide sprayer or a
folure feed sprayer. It plugs into a USB
and you can charge it up and then you
press the button and it sprays for you.
Um, I did not realize how obnoxious it
was pumping a sprayer all the time. This
bad dog, you plug it in and you f you
plug it in and you charge it. Then you
can unplug it and it's portable and that
bad dog [ __ ] sprays for you. It saves
your wrist. It saves whatever muscle you
were using. You don't have to do that
now. It's a little bit nicer and you get
the consistent spray all the time. You
don't get that. I pumped it 40 times.
It's good for a few. Got to pump it 40
more. It stays even all the time. So AC
Infiniti sells a pesticide sprayer or
any powered sprayer that you can find. I
do recommend that. Uh where are we now?
There is a leaf surface VPD gun
available from AC Infinity. I highly
recommend that. If you are running LED
lights, the temperature of the air in
the room and the leaf surface
temperature could be drastically
different. In my room, it varies as much
as 5 to nine degrees depending on the
day, the heat, the time of the year. But
the only way to find that out is to get
a leaf surface temperature gun that
measures VPD of the leaf surface
temperature as well. You can put that
data into your ACI controller 69 and
that will help you offset your leaf
surface temperature and give you more
accurate readings on what's going on in
your room. So, that little VPD gun is
very useful. Well, not only will it tell
you the temperature and the leave and
the VPD of your leave surface
temperature, but it helps you dial in
the room a little bit better by putting
that data into the controller 69.
Another thing you can add on would be a
pH meter and an EC meter uh or a ppm
meter. Um, that's all in one meter. If
you get it through acin infiniti.com,
they've got that one combo meter. I
recommend that you've got to adjust your
EC, you got to check your pH. Why not
use the ACI meter to go with everything
else we've got? Um, a heater, an air
conditioner. Do you need those devices?
I use a little rolling Solius 14,000 BTU
air conditioner. Uh, and it ducks out of
a window. Uh, unfortunately, I can't use
a window unit where my grow is because
it's in a basement. There's not a window
that would work. So, I use the Solius
rolling air conditioner. It's 14,000
BTUs. I don't cool just the tent. I cool
the entire room in which the tents are
in and then duct that cool air into the
tent as needed. Uh just a little bit. Uh
I'm using a lung room essentially to
control the climate in the lung room. So
that's the way I'm doing that. Uh
humidifier and
dehumidifier. I don't necessarily need
either one of those. I live in Colorado.
It is quite dry here. We don't get a lot
of humidity problems. Uh and the way
that my room is set up, like I said,
I've got the tents and another room. So
the humidity gets ducted out of the tent
into the room and then when the room
reaches a certain humidity that actually
has another extraction that blows the
heat and humidity out of that room to
bring in fresh air. So I don't need the
dehumidifier or humidifier. I just use
the lung room to kind of make that work.
I use the moisture of the plants for my
humidity. But those are things that you
just might need. Um also those devices,
the air conditioner, the humidifier and
dehumidifier, those are going to be high
electricity items. So, make sure that
you're running enough uh electrical for
those. Make sure you have enough
breakers and amperage available for
those things. So, I think I covered a
lot of the gear. Um cameras. Uh I like
to see the room. Sprayers because I want
to spray my [ __ ] once a week, maybe
twice. VPD gun, I can get that VPD
dialed in. EC, PH, and PPM meter so I
can get the feed dialed in properly.
Heater, air conditioner, get the
environment dialed in. Be so [ __ ]
careful with the heater. Uh, grow room
heaters, always any kind of heater,
space heater, portable heater, that's
heat. That is a step away from fire.
That always makes me [ __ ] nervous. Be
careful with that. Humidifier,
dehumidifier, you understand what to do
with that. I said a growroom speaker. If
you got a JBL speaker, some AirPods,
something like that, that will always
make the grow more enjoyable. And if you
can get some sort of dedicated music
player for the grow, uh if you can just
leave some music on all the time, I
really think that the plants enjoy
music. Um they enjoy probably what you
enjoy, maybe. I'm not sure. But I think
plants feel the vibration of the music.
I like music. It makes me feel away.
Even if I don't like the music, it makes
me feel away. And that still counts. So
I think music in the grove is a good
thing. Um, a real simple thing you can
pick up a broom and a dustpan and a mop
and a bucket. Uh, clean that [ __ ] Uh,
clean growroom will make you proud. A
clean growroom will make you feel good.
You'll want to be in there more. Um,
organize that [ __ ] Get some shelves in
there. Clean that and organize it real
nice. Uh, and then a trash can. A trash
can with a lid on it. The kind that you
could step on it and the lid pops up and
you let go and it closes. That is the
kind of can that I would prefer. Then
some other things we could jump into
just to kind of bougie up the grow
space. Good measuring devices. How are
you measuring your nutrients? Are you
[ __ ] struggling or do you have it
figured out? Take a minute, research
what works best for you. Do you just
want to pour it into a measuring cup? Do
you Are you the guy that uses the
[ __ ] syringe type thing? What works
the best for you? Is your watering setup
the way that you want it to be? Are you
pouring into a 5gallon bucket then using
a pitcher? Are you auto watering? Now's
the time to think about how to make the
watering environment, the watering
situation the best you can for your
needs, your environment, your time, your
capabilities. Um, I'm a big dude and
getting to the back right corner of a
grow tent, uh, can be a pain in the ass.
That left corner, I can unzip the side
on the ACI. The right one, it's against
the wall, can't [ __ ] get back there.
That's hard to get to. So, do you need
to build an auto watering system? Is
there something you can improve with
that? That is something to think about.
What about proper nutrient and pesticide
storage? Do you have these products in a
safe storage area where uh maybe kids
can't get to it, your pets can't get to
it, they're not going to get spilled,
they're not going to get too hot, not
going to get too cold, the bottles are
not exposed to sunlight. That's
something people overlook. Um nutrient
and pesticide storage. Do you have
somewhere safe to store that stuff? How
about good personal protective
equipment? I know this is um just
details at this point, but get yourself
a couple of Tyveck suits. Get a couple
of good masks. Get some good goggles. If
you're working with pesticides and
nutrients, you might want some good
goggles. I recommend it. Um what kind of
hair situation do you have? I got
dreadlocks. Get some [ __ ] to tie up your
dreadlocks. Customize that situation. Um
then you got all the personal protective
equipment. Buy boxes and boxes of rubber
gloves. You're going to need the [ __ ]
out of those. Uh then what about
nutrients and pesticides? Do you have
all the the quality nutrients and
pesticides that you need? Do you have a
good base nutrient? Do you have a good
bloom booster? Do you have a good cow
mag? Do you have a good potassium
silicate? Uh what about maybe some amino
acids? What are you using for microbes?
What are you using for a tarp enhancer?
Um just what what's your nutrient mix?
Is that dialed in? Think about that
because that's your fuel. Your light and
your nutrients are a big part of how
your plants fuel themsel fuel
themselves. So, let's think about that.
Pesticides. Do you have a good pesticide
rotation? What about maybe um a dry
erase board or a notebook to write down
your nutrient mix and your pesticide
rotation? Maybe just use an app in your
phone, but write this [ __ ] down
somewhere also. So, good pesticides. Do
you have a decent pesticide rotation? Do
you have two or three three or four
pesticides that are that are based on
different uh base products which I'm
saying what I'm trying to say is
different modes of attack. Uh do you
have something that is a pythine base
and a hazideractinbased and then
possibly like a basillusbased product
and then um whatever else you want to
mix into there. I've got three or four
different products I mix through. I
rotate them. I spray once a week. That
means four products will last me most of
the time last one month long and then I
can just start the rotation over. Um, it
is Evergreen, Azamax, Botanagard, and
uh, Venerate. That's the That's the
process right there. Um,
Azamax, Evergreen, Venerate, and
Botanagard Max. Those are the four that
are generally in my rotation. I'll
switch some [ __ ] in and out once in a
while, but step up your pesticide game
if you have not done that already. Um,
where are we? Oh, upgrade every room
slowly as you learn. When you're in the
room, what do you see? What could you
make? So, first of all, you know what
equipment you don't like? What sucks?
Fix that [ __ ] Slowly improve that.
Then, what do you want to make better?
This is like building a car. Uh, this is
like building a drum set. This is like
building a a [ __ ] AR-15. Um, it never
comes out of the box you way the way you
want it. You got to put accessories and
[ __ ] on it. The grow room is that way as
well. So, what do you want to customize?
What does your light suck? Does your
blower suck? If it's AC infinity, it
doesn't. But if it's not AC, what needs
to be upgraded? So, that's what I'm
talking about. Upgrade each room slowly
as you learn. And then I put a big star
here. It says, "Do not overlook the
importance of your veg and mother
areas." Everybody focuses on the flower
room. We want that [ __ ] rockstar
flower environment. The best lights, the
best blower, all your shit's in there.
Your meters are in there. You know
exactly what's going on at Auto Waters
at nine o'clock. Everything is [ __ ]
perfect, but your veg room looks like a
trailer park exploded and you took all
the leftover parts and made a grow room
out of it. Let's focus a little bit on
that grow on the veg and the mom
environment because the mom is where the
clones come from. If you don't have
healthy mother plants or clone donors,
what are you starting with? You need a
healthy mom plant or a clone donor or
somewhere to get those clones. Then we
need a healthy veg environment. This is
where we're starting everything. These
are the building blocks. This is step
one. If you [ __ ] up from day one, by the
time you get to day 120, you're going to
be really [ __ ] up. If you set yourself
up for success by having a healthy mom
environment, a perfect cloning
environment, a beautiful small veg
environment, a really tight large veg
environment, and then transition
smoothly into a really souped-up flower
room, everything will be real nice. So,
don't forget to upgrade that veg area,
the mom area, the clone area. Those
plants are just as important, if not
more important, than the flowering area.
That's what's coming up. That is the
future. That's the [ __ ] children.
That's what's going to be your next
adult plant. So, love that room. And
once you've got everything all souped up
and all perfect, what else are we going
to buy? Do you have good scissors? Do
you have a way to clean those scissors?
Uh, do you have a trim bin? We'll get to
that. I'm jumping ahead of myself. What
about a clone machine? I prefer the easy
cloners. I think those work the best for
me, for what I'm trying to do. Do you
have an easy cloner? Maybe that's
something you want to try. That'll make
your clones uh much more robust. If that
works for the way you're growing, do
that research there. Um I said a veg
area. How is your veg area set up? Do
you have a good light? Do you have
plenty of fans in there? Do you have
your auto watering system in there? Um
do you have a tray on the floor in the
veg area like you do in the flower area
or are you cheaping out in there? Soup
it up. Make it easy. Take as much pride
in there. the bloom area. We've already
talked about that. Uh harvest. Just a
second ago, I asked about a trim bin.
How is your harvest set up? Do you have
Oh, I'm going to say now, how about a
good camera? How about a good magnifying
glass? One of the kind of magnifiers
that hooks up to your computer so you
can see the tricoms. That's something to
think about. Uh but how's your harvest
setup? Do you have a comfortable chair?
Do you have a good light? Do you have a
trim bin? Um like I said a moment ago,
do you have a scope to check the
tricoms? Do you have a good camera to
take good photos of these buds? How is
your harvest area? Then the last step of
course, well, not there's one more after
this, but how is your dry and cure
environment? Do you have a good safe,
secure area that you can control the
environment for your dry and cure? Some
people are building grow tents with an
air conditioner in that grow tent just
for drying and curing their weed. How is
your dry and cure environment? Then how
is your storage? What are you storing
your dried and cured and finished
product in? Then once you've mastered
all of this, then you get to go buy
yourself how about a rosin press? I
didn't even write that [ __ ] down. How
about some bubble bags and a rosin
press? That's probably the next [ __ ] to
buy, right? You got to make some bubble
bags, whip out some good bubble. Then
you got to turn that into rosin. Then
here's where I was headed. Once you got
all this [ __ ] figured out, we get to
celebrate and go buy a really [ __ ]
nice rig, a banger, um a pillar, a carb
cap, and then depends on if you're a
caveman or not, you get to get a torch
or the dail torchless heating system. Um
but then you get a cool rig and a dab
right. You need a dab right so you're
taking your dabs at the right
temperature. Shout out to Dabbrite.
Dabight sponsor me, bro. Um, this
episode is not officially brought to you
by our friends at Dabrite, but if it
were, the ad would sound like this. Yo,
big shout out to my friends at Dabrite
for keeping all my dabs perfect, keeping
me at the right temp, keeping me
perfectly medicated, keeping my banger
clean, making my concentrates last and
taste the best that they can. Shout out
to my friends at Dabbrite for a truly
marvelous product. Uh, one of the
products I use the most in my
consumption environment. Shout out to
Dabbrite. Hey, sponsor me, boys. But get
yourself a Dabrite. Then take some fat
dabs, get some good con, make some good
concentrates with all your cool toys you
just got and enjoy that whole process.
Buy yourself a really cool rig and enjoy
that. My dude, you got me on a super
good ramble. We went from the beginning
to the end here from all the [ __ ] to buy
to the grow. Then we're pressing it and
then we're [ __ ] dabbing it. There's
no more left. Nothing left to do but
smile, smile, smile. After that, bro, go
outside, have some fun, get some
sunshine on your skin, go see some
music. All right, my dude. Uh HD Ben, I
think I more than answered your
question. Thank you for the great
contribution. Make sure you check your
inbox because you have got a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds at
iedirect.com. All right, we're going to
keep this great momentum going. I've got
another question here in front of me.
This one also did come from the growhelp
tab on
eriegenetics.com. This one came from our
new friend Chris. Shout out to my buddy
Chris. Make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at
iedirect.com. All right, this question
goes like this. It says, "When you see
strain information about the parents of
a strain and it has three parents, does
that mean they pollinated one female
with two males to get that strain?" No,
that's not what happened. It said, "Is
that even possible?" Yes, that is
possible. But you would have the seeds
wouldn't have two dads. It would be each
seed would have a different daddy and
the same mom is how that would go. Um,
it says, "I hope this is not a stupid
question." No, it's not at all. This has
actually come up a few times. Um, I love
your show uh and your seeds. I got some
fist bump and some table seeds, bro. I
plan to restock the table seeds for the
420 sale, by the way. So, make sure you
check for table seeds at ire
redirect.com. Uh, but it says, "I cannot
wait from your new friend, Chris."
Chris, thank you for the great question.
So, what Chris is asking or my
understanding of what Chris is asking. A
lot of times when we see a new strain,
I've got a good example of this right
now. You're going to see um so I've got
a label that says uh Cherry
Paloma X skunk one. That's in
parenthesis. Cherry Paloma to skunk
number one is in parenthesis. And then
that is X blueberry F5. So, what is
going on there? Why are there three
plants? Because what happened was the
cherry skunk or the that that's what it
became. But the cherry paloma to skunk
number one, it didn't have an official
name for a little while. So, it just got
labeled uh whatever why I keep calling
it the cherry paloma to skunk number
one. That's what it was called for a
while. It didn't get an official name.
Not every plant gets an official name.
Not everything has um like like like
that's the best I could say it. Not
everything has an official name. So you
just list it as the cross. So before it
became Cherry skunk and got an official
name, it was just written as Cherry
Paloma X skunk one. That was what that
cross is before it got a name. Now when
you breed to that, you're going to put
an X. And here's a rule that I wish
everybody would follow. This is a
horicultural ind industry standard. When
it comes to botany, horiculture,
flowers, other industries that are not
cannabis, it is customary in a breeding
project to list ladies first. So
anytime, so I just said cherry paloma to
skunk one. There's no question to an
experienced cultivator that the cherry
paloma I said it first, that's the girl.
Skunk one, I said it second. That is the
boy. So cherry paloma to skunk one, we
know the girl to the boy. That's how
that usually goes. So, we're going to go
back to the cherry skunk. We got cherry
paloma skunk one in parenthesis. Now,
I'm going to put an X next to that and
I'm going to write blueberry. Now, what
the [ __ ] is going on here? What that
indicates is I took the what is now
called cherry skunk, the cherry paloma,
blueberry in parenthesis. The
parenthesis indicate that is one plant.
That's what the parenthesis the the
brackets there are for. And then we x
that the new thing on the other side of
that x should be the new male. So that
means I've now pollinated the cherry
skunk with the blueberry. So usually
that's how that's going to work in my
labeling. That's how that's going to
work. The reason that you saw three
plants there and depending on where your
parentheses are, whatever is in the
parenthesis that is I'm going to quit
saying that word because I hate the word
now. Whatever's in that box is one
plant. So you could put and this is
going to get convoluted. I might need to
get a pen and paper to make this [ __ ]
work in my brain. You could do uh Golden
Goat X Daybreaker in parenthesis and
then you could cross that. It would go X
to uh let's pick another strain, Jack
the Ripper X arise and that's the
convergence is what that is. And you
could cross those two things together
and that's going to make a whole new
thing. So that's two crosses, two two
crosses. kind of what the breeder is
doing there is letting you know a little
bit of pedigree, a little bit of
prominence, a little bit of history
about that plant is what they're trying
to do. Oftent times it just becomes
[ __ ] confusing for a new breeder, for
a new grower, for somebody reading these
labels. So what we're trying to do is
let you know what the parents are. Um,
now maybe you'll see a bracket and then
uh an equation in parenthesis. So, we'll
have bracket uh parentheses golden goat
times daybreaker parentheses x um lemon
Jeffrey bracket. That's all one [ __ ]
plant. That's all one plant because it's
in that bracket. That's all one plant.
But it was whatever was in the
parenthesis bred to the one outside of
it. That's one plant. And then there
would be an X to breed that to something
else. So, usually, and it depends on
where the guys are putting or and gals,
there are a lot of ladybreeders in the
game now. Welcome. It's good, great to
have you. There's a lot of people
putting the parenthesis in weird places,
and it just depends on where the
parenthesis and the X and the bracket
lies. So, you're going to have a female
plant to a male plant most of the time.
But how is that broken down? That's also
going to be female plant to male plant
and female plant to male plant. So, it's
kind of algebra, but it's not as
difficult as our brains want it to be
once we figure it out. Uh, just think of
it as boy girl times boy girl
or boy girl times boy because right you
could cross two plants that don't have a
name to a boy and then that could also
be crossed to a bunch of other [ __ ] on
the other side. So, once you understand
once it clicks in it'll all make sense.
It's not nearly as hard as we want it to
be. The boy should be first. The lady
should be first, girl should be second
every time. I'm not even going to edit
that. I'm just trying to catch up with
my own brain. I'm telling me where we
are now, not you. Uh, ladies first, male
second, and then that applies to
everything on this side of the X. That
was probably the lady, and on this side
is probably the boy. I'm just [ __ ]
confusing both of us at this point. So,
what how we're going to do it now is,
bro, just go get your free seeds and
have fun. Uh, Chris, thank you for the
great message. That one got me rambling.
Um, I hope I answered your question. The
way that I wrote it was plant A to plant
B in parenthesis is one plant times
pollen donor. Um, is how what you're
talking about probably goes. So, dude,
thank you for the great question. Thank
you for letting me confuse everybody. If
you need clarity on this, argue in the
comment section. I would love to see the
feedback in the comment section. All
right, ladies and gentlemen, boys,
girls, pimps, hoes, friends, foes,
smokers, growers, clone cutters, pollen
chuckers, all of you amazing cannabis
enthusiasts out there. Um, you could
tell I'm beginning to stutter. My brain
is burning out on podcasting. It is time
for me to wrap up this show. Thanks
again for listening. I had a fun time
recording this one. Uh, thanks for
letting me talk about growroom
equipment. Uh, thanks for letting me
ramble a little bit. Uh, make sure you
click like and subscribe. That's where
I'm headed with this. If you like my
ramblings, click like. If you want more,
click subscribe. It's free and it does
help me out as a podcaster. I think
that's all the podcasting I've got for
you for this week. Make sure you check
out the 420 sale at
ireieetics.com. Make sure you check out
the 420 sale at
acfinity.com. Use that coupon code IE
army. And also, I will see you at the
Dude Groves Cup in June. Make sure you
check
dgcup.com for links, deetss, and all of
the info. That's all I've got. I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy Hire
Dave. And until next time, take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me.
[Music]
Roster Jeff, you bad
[ __ ] Time to take another damn.
Grab your piece and hug the bag. Ro is
in the lab. Sit back and relax.
Roots and wisdom start to sow from the
knowledge seeds we grow. Tuning now to
hear the vibr in our conscious
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be
heard. Healing like a can of bliss. Grow
from your heart this. Rise up higher.
Find your way. Grow from your hearts
every day. In the light we stand real
strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song. Natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
dove. Educate and eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth. In the soil lies the
proof rust that chef will guide you
through. In this garden find the new.
Rise up higher. Find your way. Grow from
your heart every day. In the light we
stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the song.
[Music]
Open minds to see the truth. In the soil
lies the proof. Ra Jeff will guide you
through in this garden. Find a new. Rise
up higher. Find your way. grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song.
[Music]
[Applause]