[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Yeah. Welcome back podcast
world. I'm your host Rosta Jeff. This is
episode
879 of the Grow from Your Heart podcast.
You know, I've got another fun episode
lined up for us. In today's podcast, I'm
going to give away free seeds. Hang out.
We'll talk more about the free seeds
later on in today's show. Before we get
too far, I do want to send a big thank
you to everybody who participated in the
420 sale at erirect.com. Thank you. The
sale was huge. A lot of the new drops
sold out. Uh there will be a restock of
some of those items, but the sale was a
huge success. The drops were a huge
success. Thank you. I do appreciate
that. Also, big thanks to everybody who
used my coupon code on the AC Infinity
420 sale. Both of those sales were a
huge success. I do appreciate all of the
support. Uh to keep it going, I'm going
to continue that 420 sale on i
redirect.com. That is going to now turn
into a tax return sale. That's right.
Everybody's getting their tax returns.
Let's leave everything on sale on
irredirect.com. I will also restock some
of these soldout testers and soldout
items very soon. Actually, right after I
edit this podcast episode, the next
thing I will do is take a fat dab and go
restock
iredirect.com. So, at the time this
comes out, check i redirect. Some of
those testers will be back in stock and
some of the soldout items also will be
replenished. Also, my coupon code is
still valid at
acinfiniti.com. Use coupon code IE army.
You will save 10% at
acinfiniti.com. All right, I'm checking
to make sure that covers Oh, we got one
more point of business here before we
jump into the questions and answers.
Don't forget about the DGC cup. That's
right, the DGC cup is coming uh early
June in Oh, excuse me for that. Not even
going to edit that. We're going to keep
flowing here. The DGC cup is coming.
That's right. The Dude Grows Cup is
coming in early June. Uh this year, we
have moved the event to a beautiful
place in Longmont, Colorado. I will be
at the VIP party Friday night. I will be
at the Saturday uh flower competition
and I will be at the Sunday hash bash.
Uh we will be vending Saturday and
Sunday. Come to the event. Say hi, grab
some seeds, shake my hand. I will be
there. Uh the dude will be there. Scotty
Real will be there. White Mike should be
there. That is the plan so far. Stop by
the dude grows cup. Come say hello. Once
again, check
dgccup.com for all the information. Now,
let's work our way into the question and
answer portion of today's podcast. I
don't know if you can hear it in my
throat and in my voice. I don't want to
talk about it too much because if you
didn't notice, it's not a big deal. But
got a little bit of a sinus head cold
throat thing going on here. This is the
episode I'm recording after the 420
weekend. Humble brag here. I got to go
see Sublime. Uh yeah, that's right, bro.
Sublime with Bradley's son, Jacob. Uh
doing the front job there. I got to go
see Sublime at a small club in Denver.
Mike and I got to go. It was really
random. Sublime was scheduled to do a
show here at Red Rocks on 4:18, I
believe, and the weather uh [ __ ] that
all up. So, they postponed the show for
three or four days. Sublime was in town.
They were bored. They wanted to play.
They threw a kind of a surprise show at
a
smaller Once again, excuse all that.
They threw a a show at a smaller venue
in Denver. And uh I got to go see
Sublime at a small show, a small club in
Denver with Mike. That was on 419.
That's when all of this uh throat and
sinus chaos began. We smoked two joints
in the morning. We smoked two joints at
night. We smoked two joints in the
afternoon. Uh we still didn't feel all
right. So there was two or more uh maybe
four or six more joints. There was times
of peace and times of war. So we smoked
then as well. Uh we smoked two joints
before we smoked two joints. And then we
[ __ ] dabbed a little bit more. So uh
my whole my smoking section for my whole
body, it notices it and it needs a day
off from smoking. So, I think tomorrow
we're going to not smoke. We're going to
take a little break, drink a lot of
water, get some juice and vitamins in
me, get these problems fixed. That was
disgusting. I kind of apologize for
doing that. But, uh, where what was I
even [ __ ] saying, dude? I don't even
know what I was rambling about anymore.
Um, excuse me for all this stuff in The
Voices where I think I was headed. We
got to see Sublime, dude. This is the
episode after 420 is where I think I was
going. Uh, we got to see Sublime, then
it was 420. Uh, then it was Earth Day
after that. Oh, no. Then it was
groundation day. If you're a Rastafari,
uh, you understand about groundation
day. I'm not going to teach you about
that today. So, we had Sublime on 419.
Then we had 420. Then we had groundation
day. Then the next day was Earth Day.
So, I went to an Earth Day celebration
there. Um, my my sinuses and my my whole
respiratory thing. It needs a day off.
Happy 420 everybody. But, holy [ __ ] we
went hard this year. I don't know what
the [ __ ] I was saying. I don't know
where I was. We're going to do the
question and answer portion part of the
podcast. Now, I've got a website. That
website, most of you know by now is
urgeetics.com. That is my main website.
If you go to that website, there are a
lot of cool places to click around.
Click around, find some cool [ __ ] Uh
you just got to poke around. If you
scroll uh if you scroll to the top,
there's a row of tabs. One of those tabs
does say uh grow help or grow questions.
If you click on that tab, guess what?
You get the option to send me a grow
question. If I read your grow question
here on the podcast, I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds off
of my vending website, ire redirect.com.
That's right. There's two websites. Lots
of reasons for that. But today's first
question that came off of the growhelp
tab at ire redirect.com came from our
friend who wants to be called Krispy.
What up Krispy? Uh I have never related
more with the name. I feel crispy today.
Not complaining, but wow. Feel crispy.
We're gonna make a quick show. We're
gonna make it sound good. Krispy's
question is a two-part question. The
first part I answered on a recent
episode. The second part, we're going to
touch on this and I'm going to get a few
questions out pretty quickly today.
We're going to not try to dwell on these
questions too long. Let's get into it. I
know guys, I'm rambly today. Uh you're
welcome. The question goes, "What up,
Rosta Jeff? Two questions. Uh do you
count week one of flower as soon as you
flip?" Yes, we've covered this. Uh just
in case you weren't listening, uh this
person is asking, "When is day one of
flower?" uh we're switching the light
from 1212 or from 186 or 195 or 24 going
to flip it to 1212. The day you do that,
that is day one of flower. That is day
one. The day you change the timer, uh
the first night that those plants get a
short night or a long night, a short
day, that is your first day of flower.
We've covered that. Day one is day one.
The second part, what is your opinion on
defoliation? My answer is yes, do that.
do that with strategy. I defoliate
semiheavily in my opinion. Honestly,
I've been a little bit lazy. I've been
defoliating medium. I should go much
harder, but it is time consuming and
there's a couple plants in the back my
big ass can't really get to right now to
defoliate them the way I would like. So,
they're a little bit furry. It looks
like a 70s bush in there. I like to
defoliate. I recommend in a commercial
environment, I defoliate quite heavily.
Um, don't hit one plant and strip it at
a level 10 and then move to the next
plant and strip it. Go in a spiral
around the entire grow. Do this plant at
a level two. This plant at a level two,
this plant level two. Get them all at a
level two. Then go back through and do
them all to a level four, level five.
Strip them pretty good. As much as
you're comfortable with. Any leaf with a
big purple pedial comes right off. Any
leaf I can strip off easily comes right
off. Any leaf blocking light from
getting to a lower bud site probably
comes right off. I don't need that much
blockage, that much shade in there. So,
I do a lot of defoliation. The reason
I'm telling you to do it in a rotation
is because if you, and this is going to
vary on the size of your room, the
amount of plants, keep in mind I have a
commercial cultivation background, so I
think on a larger scale sometimes, but
if you go and you strip row one down and
rows three and four are still looking
like a 70s bush, you're going to have a
huge fluctuation in humidity levels in
that room. This plant is going to have
this section is going to be a lot more
damp, a lot more humid in the room. The
VPD is going to be funky. Over here,
it's going to be drier. you're going to
have different effects on the plant. If
you've got sensors hanging in the room,
now your equipment's going to be coming
off and going on all random. It's not
sure what's happening because you've
created microclimates. You need more
fans. You need to adjust things. Still
going to be a little bit of a struggle.
So, I do defoliate and I do it heavily,
but I do it in a rotation and I do it
with strategy. I will lollipop the
bottoms of the plants. Clean them up
depending on the room, the light.
There's a lot of [ __ ] factors in
there. Clean up the bottoms. Do some
lollipopping. then do some pruning of
those sticks. Um, I'll clean off the
bottom, shave the legs, then I'll go and
start at the top and I'll do a heavy
defoliation and try to get that light
all the way through the canopy, uh, into
all of those buds. So, uh, what's your
opinion of defoliation? Quick answer,
[ __ ] do it. Second answer, do it with
strategy. Uh, work your way around the
room. Don't hit one plant and then leave
the rest real furry. Try to work with
some strategy. That is my advice.
Anything with a big pedial, take it off.
Uh these plants can take a lot of
defoliation. I will do it uh right at
the start of flower. I'll do it on day
one, day 21, uh sometimes day 42, and
then keep going because now you're just
getting ready to harvest anyway. And why
not start pulling off leaves because we
don't need all those [ __ ] leaves
there for harvest. Uh there are a lot of
benefits to taking off these leaves. It
will slow down some processes. It will
help with the VPD and that's where the
powdery mildew will go. That's where the
spidermitites will go. Uh if you don't
have hotels, then the people won't go
stay in the hotels. So that is my
opinion. Uh my dude Chrisy, uh thank you
for the great message. I've got your
email address. Make sure you check your
inbox for a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds at
iedirect.com. All right, ladies and
gentlemen, before I read this next
question, let me remind you to click
like and subscribe. That's right. Mash
that like button. Also, click subscribe.
That way if you uh like this content,
you never miss any of my amazing
cannabis education. I'm just [ __ ]
around having fun here. But really,
seriously, like and subscribe. It's free
and it helps me out a lot. We're going
to keep this momentum going. This
question also came from that growhel tab
on
ienetics.com. Thank you guys for
visiting the website. This question
says, "I have a plant I want to preserve
in seed form." Oh, this came from our
friend Slick Rick. I should have said
that. Slick Rick, check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for
free seeds, my dude. It says, uh, I have
a plant I want to preserve in seed form.
This makes sense. You've got a plant.
Um, perhaps you've got to move. You've
got to take a break from growing. You
want to preserve this plant in a seed
form. Maybe you just want it in the uh
the box so that when the end of the
world comes, still have this plant in
seed form. Whatever reason, I
understand. It says, "I don't keep a
clone, but I have 40 regular seeds of
this cross. How would you recommend I go
about this? We've got a couple of
options here. Um, I am trying to not
have to keep the mom and I'm okay with
slight variations in each seed, but I
want to avoid a lottery of phenotypes.
I've got two 2x4 tents and I can't run
more than four plants at a time. Please
help. So, you've got a plant you want to
preserve. You've got 40 seeds. So, do
you have the plant? Do you have the
specific plant that you want to
preserve? Have you found the phenotype?
Or have you got 40 seeds? I don't keep a
clone, but I have 40 regular seeds of
the cross. Either way, you're going to
have to grow the seeds. If you've all
you've got is the seeds, you've got to
grow them. Find your favorite phenotype
out of these seeds. I would say run 20
of them and find the best. And we've got
two options here. Find the best girl,
the girl that you like the most. When
you smoke it, that's what matters the
most. Find the female that when you
smoke it, you go Shazam. That is the
weed for me. Find that one. Then also
possibly potentially find a male plant.
That would be another suggestion if you
want to do it this way. Find a male and
a female then or see we got we got three
options here. We got I keep opening up
options in my brain as we do this. Um
the easiest way find a boy and a girl
and let them do their thing and you will
make more seeds. Um there will be
variation but you will find the traits
you're looking for in that offspring.
You're going to make F2. There will be
variation in your F2. Another thing you
could do, find a couple of females you
like and pollinate them with that same
male. That's an open pollination. You're
going to get the lottery you said you
don't want. Let's see. Um, I'm not
trying to have to uh slight don't want
to hunt a lottery of phenos. That's
going to kind of give you a lottery. So,
don't do the open pollination, but
that's the way to find the fullest
expression of that genotype. You're
going to find all the phenotypes, all
the different traits by doing uh one
male to multiple females. you'll find
the open pollination will give you uh
the phenotype you're looking for and a
lot of great other options. Now, here is
what I would do. This is probably where
we should have [ __ ] started, right?
Just jump right to it. I would grow
those seeds. Find the plant that you
really like. Find your favorite plant.
That is what this all is all about. Find
the best
female. Take two clones of that female.
The same exact plant. You got two clones
of it. You're going to have to take
clones if you want this to work this
way. If you're not going to take clones,
the only way to really do this is to
male female this. But um find the the
keeper plant that you like. You need two
clones of that plant at this time to
make this work. You're going to reverse
one with silver thio sulfate or I
haven't shared this yet. I've tried a
product called Elite X. I have tried it
two times. I've got 50% success rate
with it. Everybody told me the one plant
I tried to re reverse was stubborn and
it would not work. I should have [ __ ]
listened. So far, I've got good success
with a product called Elite X. They do
not sponsor me. It's an expensive
product. I straight up pay cash for it
just like everybody else. Uh I haven't
advertised it. I haven't talked about
it. I haven't said that that's what I
use on a public forum at all before. Uh
it is called Elite X as a reversal
spray. Um either use silver thioulfate
or Elite X and reverse one of your
plants. That plant will then make
pollen. Put that pollen on the other
copy of that plant. Put it into flower.
put that pollen on the other clone. What
you're going to do, what you do now is
make S1 seeds of that plant. Whatever
this cross is that you have got that you
love, we're going to call it Slick Rick.
You've now made Slick Rick S1s. Um, and
those will show very similar phenotypes
to what you're looking for. Depending on
the plant, you'll find somewhere between
40 and 60% of the offspring from this uh
procedure will look just like the plant
that you played with. the outliers will
be even better. They'll be cool. Uh
they'll have some secrets you didn't
know about, but some of the phenotypes
will look just like the plant you
started with. So you will find what
you're looking for. Now the catch is you
said uh I don't keep clone. You didn't
keep a clone. So um maybe next time do
keep clones. So here's what you got to
do. Here's what I would do. You don't
got to do a damn thing. Here's what I
would do. I would run 20 of these seeds.
I would find my favorite one out of this
batch. You could find your favorite two
if you want, but I would focus on the
favorite one. Find your favorite two.
You could do three if you want. This is
up to you. But here's what we're going
to do. We're going to take your favorite
one. The best one. You got to pick one
that is the best. Reverse that. That is
my advice. So, you got to grow this
plant. Find it. Keep a clone of it is
the main [ __ ] thing that I skipped
here. Uh, grow this plant. Get a clone.
Grow all these. Get clones of them. Keep
your favorite. The favorite has got to
be kept. Then get two clones of that
one. I know I'm [ __ ] rambling. It's
been a long week, you guys. Uh, get two
clones of your favorite plant and spray
one and pollinate the other one with
that pollen. You can also put other
females in the room when you do this.
Just in case there's another female that
you really like or another strain that
you like, even put a clone of that in
the room also. You're going to throw
pollen. Why not put pollen on two,
three, four, five other plants and see
what you create? I know you want to make
the preservation. That will happen. But
also by pollinating other plants, you
get to do something that I find is fun.
When you pollinate plant, let's say I've
got a mango drink here in front of me.
Let's just say we took strawberry and we
pollinated mango. We're going to get
strawberry mango, right? We should.
Maybe it's more strawberry. Maybe it's
more mango. We're going to find out. We
don't know really what that male plant
is doing in that mix other than giving
us strawberry flavor. And the female
gives us mango. That's what we get. If I
take that strawberry and mix it to
mango, chocolate, and lime, and then we
grow all of those, we can find the
commonalities among the amongst those
phenotypes, and that's coming from the
male, that's coming from the strawberry.
If all three of these plants hold a
similar trait, it couldn't have came
from the females. They were different
females. That's what the male is
contributing to this breeding project.
So, that's why I like to pollinate
multiple females when I'm doing it. I'm
off on a side tangent. That's not what
you asked at all, but that's part of
what I would do if I was doing this. Um,
when I'm pollen chucking, when I'm
making plants, why not put something
new, experimental, brand new, what the
[ __ ] in there every time, and see what
happens. Uh, most of what I do is really
thought out. Sometimes it's a, well,
let's see what this one [ __ ] does.
Just curiosity just because. And
sometimes, you guys, those are the
[ __ ] winners. So, um, you want to
preserve a plant, easiest way, uh, make
S1 seeds out of it. That's what I should
have said in the beginning. Thank you
for letting me ramble, my dude. Uh,
Slick Rick, I've got your your email, so
check your inbox for a coupon code for
free seeds from
ireieirect.com. All right, I know I'm
rambly. I know I'm high as giraffe
[ __ ] but we're going to keep this show
going. Um, this one also came from the
growhelp tab on IDirect. This one came
from somebody who wants to be called new
to growing. Welcome to growing, bro. I
hope it's going well for you. The
question goes a lot like this. It says,
"Are silica additives like armor sigh
and rhino skin necessary in a drainto
waste cocoaquar? And if they are, how
should they be used?" I'm sorry if this
has been asked before. Um, no. I am not
familiar with answering any questions
about silicates before. The question is,
are silicut additives are they
necessary? I don't know that uh they're
not required, but they definitely do
have benefits. You'll notice more robust
plants. You'll notice thicker stems.
You'll notice plants that can handle
stress a little bit better. If you
forget to water, they'll tolerate that a
little bit better. If you give them too
much heat, they will tolerate that a
little bit better. So, uh, the reason
they're called [ __ ] like armor and rhino
skin is because they make the plants a
it's armor. It makes them a little bit
tougher. So, not required, not
necessary, but beneficial if you do it.
If it's in the budget, go for it. Uh,
next part of the question, how would
they be used? Uh, I would recommend the
first piece of advice when you have your
your reservoir, your bucket, your water,
whatever you're mixing into, the
silicate product goes first. Put that
product in there first. Whatever amount
you choose to use, uh, whatever dilution
solution rate you're putting in there.
Uh, the first thing to do is put in the
silicate product very first. Put that in
there and then stir it. Are we stirring
it? I don't remember. I was told which
way. I think we go clockwise. Stir it
clockwise a few times. Get it moved up.
Then stir it counterclockwise a couple
of times just to get it in there. That
does something ionically. All you uh
organic chemistry nerds, fill me in. I
pay attention, but it doesn't all stick,
you guys. Uh so, put the silicut product
in first. Stir it. Stir it the other
way. Then start adding your other
products after that. Then I would go
with my base nutrients. Uh probably calm
mag or not calm mag after that, liquid
karma is what I would do after that. But
work your way down the line. Uh but the
potassium silicates go first. Then the
next thing I would think about is the
recommended dosage. Uh depending on what
product you're using, uh some of the
brands I would use the recommended
dosage. Some of them are pretty strong
and I would use 50%. Maybe start off
with about 50% of the recommended dose.
Feed your plants that uh see what it
does. If it's not giving you any
response, increase to 75. If you don't
see any response, maybe go to 85. But by
the time you get to 100, you'll see if
you're burning them and they'll start
acting weird. Uh the ends of the leaves
will turn a little crispy brown. The
leaf tips will start pointing straight
up. Uh they might curl up a little bit.
So if you're using too much silicates,
the plants will let you know. Uh so
start off with maybe 50 and then slowly
increase the application rate from
there. All right, my dude. New to
growing. I hope I answered your
question. Um it's not necessary, but it
helps. and uh add it to the res first
and start with a 50% of the recommended
dosage. All right, I've got a good
momentum going here. I like giving away
free seeds. Uh how long have we been
going? We haven't even been going that
long. We got time for a lot more, you
guys. This one also came from that
growhel tab on i redirect.com. This one
came from our friend who wants to be
known as cloud. I like that name. It
makes me think of Final Fantasy. Um use
the material, bro. Anyway, the question
goes like this. It says, "Hey, Rosta
Jeff. I love the show. Thank you, man.
I've learned a ton watching you and the
dude grows. Big shout out to the dude
grows. Make sure you check
dgcup.com. Come say hi to me at the dude
grows show. The dude grows cup. It says,
"First, I want to say thank you, sir. I
wouldn't be where I am now without our
without your guidance and knowledge."
Bro, thank you. Uh, I know I read a lot
of comments and stuff like that and I
blow right past it. That does stick.
That does mean a lot to me. So, thank
you. That's that's a recharge. That's
some potassium silicate. That's a bloom
booster for a podcaster. So, thank you.
Uh, there's more. It says, "My question
is, I bought a ton of nutrients at a
grow store that was closing down." All
right, that's a good deal. Um, and now I
wonder um how long I will be able to get
away with how long I will be able to get
away with storing these nutrients before
I see negative effects on them. Do the
products we use have a shelf life or is
it a chemical that will be good for a
decent amount of time? Big up. Keep the
knowledge going. My bro Cloud, thank you
for the good question. And this is
something that uh people often overlook,
something that probably should have been
brought up a very long time ago. Um
those products all have a shelf life. I
wouldn't recommend uh more than a
one-year life on those products. They
are uh sold in different bottles for a
reason. They are um and I was told I say
this word wrong, but I learned it from a
Canadian. So um they are buffered and
keelated. Are they ladated or keelated?
Somebody [ __ ] you can't do it because
you're just going to type it. I'm never
going to know. Is it key or she? Tell me
in the [ __ ] comments because somebody
always tells me I'm saying it wrong. If
I say it either way, it's wrong. So,
we're going to say keelate because it
sounds better to me today. But they are
buffered and keelated inside that
bottle. If I'm saying it wrong, I feel
fully rworded right now. Um, but they
are not meant to sit around for a long
time and they're especially not meant to
be uh together for a reason. They will
bind. They will get chunky. Those things
will start to fall out of solution. Have
you ever grabbed a bottle of nutrients
and shaken it up to use it and it
sounded like there was little bottles or
little chunks of salt in the bottom of
the bottle? There are chunks of salt.
That is your nutrients. All the stuff
you paid for is now bonded up at the
bottom and made a little cake and now
you're pouring colored water into your
feed mix. That's all you're getting. So,
uh, yes, there is about a oneyear shelf
life on most of those products. And
depending on how long they've been
sitting on that shelf, the time may be
ticking. Who knows? I'd like to say a
year from when you open it, but how long
has it been sitting there? Maybe that
that like I said, the time is ticking
from the minute they make that [ __ ] and
start shipping it. The time is ticking.
So, I wouldn't keep it around for more
than one year. Um, give it a sniff. If
it smells bad, it's getting fun. Well,
some of that [ __ ] smells bad the day you
open it. If your photosynthesis plus
smells good, it has gone bad. That's Oh,
man. That one smells terrible. But give
it a smell. It should smell familiar. If
it gets chunkier than it was, it's
probably got a problem to it. So, that
is my advice. Uh, and I am sticking to
it. My dude cloud, make sure you check
your inbox because like all of the great
folks before you, you've got a coupon
code for free seeds at
ireiedirect.com. Boys and girls, I have
enjoyed the rapid fire pace of this
show. If you like it, uh, leave some
comments down below. I do like your
comments. Uh, tell me go faster, go
slower. Uh, let me know if you could
tell that my voice just sounds terrible
in the headphones. Um, but we do not
miss uploads. All right, here we go. Uh,
this one came from our friend Lazy Boy.
Shout out to my buddy Lazy Boy. I know
the feeling today, bro. The question
says, um, "How you doing, Rost Jeff? I
love the page." And, uh, my question is,
can you make seeds in a tent or is it
better to make seeds outside in the sun
or does it matter at all where you make
the seeds? Well, um I would say make
your seeds wherever you can, but indoors
in a tent is my preferred environment.
Um because I can control everything in
there. I'm a control freak when it comes
to growing outdoors. I don't know if
somebody in my block in my neighborhood
um four miles away is growing cannabis
and put a male outside or maybe there's
a hemp farm with the male outside and my
crop got pollinated with that random
stray pollen. There's no way to prevent
that, detect that. Um, I don't know
that. So, I don't like growing um
outside for seed. I would prefer to do
that indoors in a tent environment. I
have, however, had amazing success
breeding plants outdoors in a
greenhouse. Um, I rented a greenhouse
from a friend two years in a row. We put
a few plants out there and we made
impressive amounts of seeds. The seeds
that came from the greenhouse, those
seeds were fatter. They were more
robust. They had a better germination
rate. and there were a [ __ ] lot of
them. Um, and it was basically free to
grow it out outdoors. We had to do
maintenance and care and we had to be
there and I had to rent the space. Uh,
but there was no electrical cost and
that was huge cuz the lights are the
most expensive part. But the reason I
enjoyed that is because I was in a
greenhouse and we had fans and we had
air air exchange system to prevent
pollen from coming in. No pollen would
come in, air was going out. We had
negative pressure blowing the air out.
Uh, so uh that way we couldn't get
accidental pollination. So, if you're
going to breed uh other than indoors, I
recommend some sort of control, some
sort of greenhouse environment, but my
favorite is indoors. That outdoors was
awesome because uh it was very
profitable. It made a lot of seeds, but
also it was very easy to get problems
out there. So, most of my stuff is
indoors. N I think 99% of what I've ever
sold has been bred indoors. There were
two crops of outdoor seeds, and I know
there was no pollen contamination there
because first of all, all the progyny
looked right. And first of all, we made
precautions to make sure no pollen would
get in. All right. Uh my dude lazy boy,
don't be too lazy because you got a pack
of seeds coming. You're gonna have to
get up and go to the mailbox and get the
mail because you've got a gift from
Rosta Jeff. All right, ladies and
gentlemen, boys, girls, pimps, hoes,
friends, foes, smokers, growers, clone
cutters, pollen chuckers, um all you
healthy people, and all of you folks
with head colds. I want to thank
everybody for listening to this podcast.
I do apologize for sounding a little bit
funky. I tried to put out a decent
quality show. It might be a little bit
short. I'm not even sure. But thank you.
Thanks for all the support. Thank you
for all of the comments you're going to
leave down there. Thank you for all the
likes you're going to leave. And thank
you for all of the new subscribers. I do
appreciate it. If you have any
questions, corrections, comments, or
concerns. My email address is grow
fromyouheart@hotmail.com. Don't be shy.
Once again, if you have grow questions,
send them to that growl tab. That's how
you win free seeds. If I did not read
your question on today's podcast, please
do not feel discouraged. I have got
reams of paper over here that I've
printed out with amazing grow questions.
I cannot get through them all, but I
will do my best. Maybe your question
will pop up on the next episode. If
you've got questions, please send them.
I look forward to hearing from you. All
right, I'm rambling. That's all I've got
for this episode. I'll be back in a week
with fresh new content. I want to give a
big shout out to my buddy OG Purple
Thumb. And until next time, take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for me.
[Music]
Ro, you bad
[ __ ] Time to take another damn.
Grab your piece and the bag. Ro is in
the lab. Sit back, poke your hungry, and
relax.
Roots and wisdom start
to know seeds we grow. Tuning out to
hear the vibr in our conscious.
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be
heard. Healing like a can of this. Go
from your heart. Cure this. Rise up
higher. Find your way. Grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song.
Natural medicine that love flows within
us like a
dove. Educate to eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth in the soil lies the
proof. Rosa chef will guide you through
in this garden. Find the new. Rise up
high or find your way. grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement, sing the
song.
[Music]
Ooh. Open minds to see the truth. In the
soil lies the proof. Rust Jeff will
guide you through in this garden. Find a
new. Rise up higher. Find your way. Grow
from your heart every day. In the light
we stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the song. Ooh.
Ooh. Ooh.
[Applause]
[Music]