[Music]
Rost Jeff, you bad
mother. Yeah. Welcome back, podcast
world. I'm your host, Rosta Jeff. This
is episode 880 of the Grow from Your
Heart podcast. You know, I've got
another fun episode lined up for us. In
today's show, I'm going to give away
free seeds. Hang out. We'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in
today's show. Before we get too far, I
do want to remind you that there is a
tax day sale happening at
erirect.com. That's right. Make sure you
check
erdirect.com for restocks and possibly a
fresh drop of new testers.
iredirect.com. Also, all orders over
$100 do come with free shipping at
eriedirect.com. Also, I do want to
invite you to join us at the Dude Grows
Cup. That's right, the Dude Grows Cup is
quickly approaching. The IE army will be
there. I will be there. White Mike will
be there. The Dude from the Dude Gross
Show will be there. Scotty Real will be
there. Uh, for all of the info, make
sure you check
dgcup.com for all the links and details
and of course how to get your tickets.
The event is quickly approaching. Make
sure you get all of your accommodations
set up for that event. All right, that
is all of the advertising here at the
start of the show. Let's work our way
into the question and answer portion of
today's podcast. At the top of the show,
I said I was going to give away free
seeds. How can you win free seeds? It is
very easy. I have a website. That
website is
iiegenetics.com. On the top of that
website, there's a row of tabs. One of
those tabs does say grow help or grow
questions. If you click on that tab,
guess what? You can send me a grow
question. If I read your question here
on the podcast, I will send you a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds off of
iredirect.com. Today's first question
came from the growhelp tab on
iieetics.com. This question came from
somebody who wants to be called JP. Big
shout out to my new friend JP. Hey JP,
make sure you check your inbox because
you've got a coupon code for a free pack
of seeds. Also, make sure you check your
spam because a lot of times your server
makes uh thinks that my email is
spamalama dingdong. All right, the
question goes a little bit like this. It
goes a lot like this. It says, "Hey,
Rasta Jeff. What's up, dude?" It says,
"Thanks for dropping all of the
knowledge about feminized seeds and
reversals lately." Uh, I'm glad you guys
noticed that. Thank you. Um, I make a
lot of fem seeds. I feel like I've
understood fem seeds and gotten it
figured out. So, it's great to share
that with you. There's a lot of myths
and misconceptions that come along with
fem seed. So, I'm happy uh to uh speak
knowledgeably about that subject. Thank
you for noticing. It says, "I have a
question about choosing a female for a
reversal." So, what this listener wants
to do is take a female plant and they
want to reverse it. What that means is
treat it with a product. There are a lot
of great products out there. Uh you can
make your own silver thioulfate or there
are a few uh ready-made products already
sold that you can use. Um, some of them
work, some of them I have not tried.
But, uh, they want to treat this female
plant with a product and put, uh, that
will make this plant, it's a female
plant. They want to treat it that will
make this female plant create anthers
that contain female pollen. Then they
will put that female pollen on another
plant. Let's read about and see what
they want to do with that. Uh, I have a
question about choosing a female for
reversal. So, they've got a female. They
want to know how to choose a female that
they're going to spray. Uh, from effects
to structure, there are probably a dozen
traits to consider. There are like 65
traits that I can think of off the top
of my head to consider. Uh, what are the
most important traits to consider when
making the choice? So, what are the most
important traits to consider when
selecting a female candidate for
reversal? That's a very great question.
Uh, then it goes on, it says, perhaps
you have two female keepers um from half
sibling crosses, one foxtails and the
other has spear top and dense colas.
Everything else aside, which one flower
structure would be better suited for
male flower production? All right, so
there is a lot to go on in this answer.
The main answer is um I wrote the plant
will tell you or no, the plant you like
uh the best or the plant that looks like
your goal is the plant to use. Then I
said the plant will tell you what to do.
Um so this person said they've got two
sibling plants, two half siblings. Which
one do they choose? Uh, you want to
reverse one and then what are you going
to do with that pollen? Are you going to
put it on a lot of things? Are you going
to put it on itself? Are you going to
put it on that other plant that is its
sibling? I kind of want to know what
you're going to do from there. But you
want to know what to select for uh this
candidate for reversal. In my opinion,
it's all about what is your goal. Do you
want to make tall, skinny plants? Do you
want to make short stout plants? Do you
want to make plants that grow wide and
bushy? Do you want to make plants with a
a giant apical top or something with a
smaller top and more equally sized
bottoms? What are you trying to make?
What do you like? What does what grows
best in your grow? What smokes best in
your bong? What sells best in your
circle? What works best for your medical
community? What suits your needs?
Because I like I like tall skinny plants
that take like 77 days and make a giant
top cola and can be trellised out. And I
like specific [ __ ] Maybe perhaps you
grow in a way different environment. I'm
sure that your brain chemistry and body
chemistry are not 100% the same as mine.
So, we enjoy smoking similar yet
different things. So, I can give you
advice on this, but it's all about what
do you want? What do you want your your
offspring to look like? How do you want
them to grow? How do you want them to
smoke? Uh what kind of buzz do you want
them? What kind of medical effect do you
want them to carry? That's a lot of this
to consider. The beautiful part about
using female plants that we're reversing
is we can smoke these plants and we know
exactly what this plant does. So, we
know what it's going to bring to the
mix. Um, these aren't my notes. I'm
going way off of my notes here. I kind
of think of breeding as like cheffing.
Um, if you put uh chocolate and
strawberry together, you're hoping to
get chocolate and strawberry, but if you
pour a little bit of vinegar in there,
that vinegar is going to overpower. Um,
if you want to make a chocolate flavored
outcome, you got to put chocolate
flavored products into that. If you put
garlic and eggs into your chocolate
thing, it's not going to have the right
flavor in the end. If you want to make a
savory dish, use your garlic. Uh that's
sort of that's where and breeding I
think works the same way. So what you
want to come out is what you put in. Uh
you said one of the plants has airier
buds and one has more dense buds. What
do you want? And don't worry about the
reversal. What it's going to look like,
what would be better for reversal. Let's
worry about what's going to be better uh
as offspring for breeding because
they're both going to reverse. They
should both reverse. There's rare cases
where [ __ ] doesn't reverse well. They're
both going to work. Especially for like
a personal breeding project. You're
going to get productivity. Uh you're
going to get pollen. You're going to
make seeds. So, uh you said one makes
foxtails, foxtails, one has a spear top
and dense colas. Which one do you like
better? Um if you're growing for flour,
a lot of people will prefer a nice dense
cola. A long time ago, Dr. Dre wpped
that rocks and hard buds were the way to
go. And now we all believe that. But if
you're making concentrates, if you're a
hashmaker and air your bud, a fluffier
bud is easier to work with. There's more
surface area. Imagine if I dunked my
fist in powdered sugar, I get this much
powdered sugar on the outside. If I open
my hand and moisten my hand and dunk
that in the powdered sugar, I get all
the area between my fingers and in my
palm, I get that much more surface area
for tricom. That's easier to wash and
blast off if you're a hashmaker. So,
which one do you want? I know you're
asking me for my guidance and my advice,
but my advice is uh grow from your heart
and breed with love. Grow these plants
and see. Um and then you'll know. You're
just going to know. In my opinion, you
will know. A breeder knows. An artist
knows. A musician knows. You know what
note goes there. You know what color
goes there. You know which plant to use.
And if you can't decide what's to stop
you from using Oh god, not even going to
edit that. Excuse me. If you're not
going to if what's to stop you from
reversing both of them? Not at the same
time, of course, but run a crop. Reverse
this one. Use the pollen. Clean up.
Start over. Reverse the other one. Do it
again. Then grow a bunch of the seeds
side by side. What is to stop you? Now,
I wouldn't be doing you any service if I
didn't give you some actual [ __ ] to
actually go over and actually look for
to select from. Um, what some traits to
consider. Structure and shape are
probably the first visual things you can
see. How is that plant shaped? How is
the structure? Like I said before, is it
tall? Is it skinny? Is it wide? Is it
stout? How are the branches? Can it hold
itself up? That's shape and structure.
What kind of frame does this plant have?
Uh, that's going to tell you a lot about
the plant anyway. How the buzz is going
to be, the flowering time, you can tell
that by looking at that shape and
structure and leaf shape of that plant.
Then the overall vigor. Uh, does the
plant grow super slow? Does it grow
really quickly? Uh, does it take off? Is
it [ __ ] wild? Does it go every which
direction? Let's think about that. So,
we got a shape and structure. Then I'm
going to think about how quickly it
grows, then does it handle my room and
my style. It could be the most amazing
plant on the planet, but if it doesn't
work in my grow environment, if it
doesn't get with my program, it's got to
[ __ ] go. It just doesn't work. Um,
that's just how it goes sometimes.
Sometimes I'll find a plant that um is
good, but it doesn't fit my style, my
room, and I'll breed it to something
that really suits my grow to try to make
the offspring more suited to my style.
But if a plant doesn't work in my grow,
it's got to [ __ ] go, dude. So, um,
does it handle my style? Do we get
along? It's like dating a girl. Uh, if
she doesn't like riding around in my car
and being in my house, we obviously
aren't going to [ __ ] work out, right?
If she wants to be at a different
environment than me all the time, then
it's not going to work. The plants are
the same way. Then I wrote down smoke.
How are the turpps? How's the buzz? Um,
the buzz to me is what matters. You
know, it doesn't matter what it looks
like, how it grows in the end. Um, we're
going to smoke it. That's what really
[ __ ] matters. Do people do I want to
consume this product is the most
important thing. So, the one that you
want to smoke, choose that one. Um, it's
got to fit my agenda. I wrote, what is
the goal? Am I making hash plants? Am I
making um fast flowering plants? Am I
doing it for sales? Do I want uh fast
flowering, long flowering? Is there a
specific turpp or a specific trait or a
specific metal medical benefit which I'm
after? So many of these things would
play into my breeding. And then also if
you are going outdoors or if you're in a
room that gets powdery mildew, maybe
think about plants. Uh one of the traits
would be the plants that uh show the
least powdery mildew. If you put 10
plant, this is just hypothetical. I
don't know your environment. We could do
other stressors as well. If you've got
any stressor, you got 10 plants, the one
that is most resistant to the stress in
your room, drought, heat, humidity,
powdery mildew, spidermitites, whatever
appears in your room, that one plant
that goes, I don't get that. Breed to
that [ __ ] plant. That's going to
continue that trait. Hopefully, the
offspring have that trait. Um, I said do
both. Now, um, I gave you a list of
things that I would choose from.
Structure, shape, vigor. It's got to
handle my room. It's got to smoke well.
It's got to smell good. It's got to fit
my agenda. It's got to be the kind of
plants that I want to make. Um, and then
why not do both of them? And also, let's
think about, we said resistance. I think
we covered most of the things, the
traits that I would think about. So,
part of your question was which one
would be best suited for male flower. I
wouldn't stress too much about the best
suited for male flower. Best pollen
donor with the best traits is what I
would more focus on. And depending on
how a lot of this is going to depend on
the dominance and uh co-ominance of the
genes of these plants um or the
recessive traits and the dominant traits
when you throw these. So think about you
have just a bunch of red marbles and a
bunch of blue marbles. One plant makes
red marbles, one p plant makes blue
marbles. You're going to throw them into
a bowl. You're going to shake them and
then you're going to scoop them up.
Whatever comes in that scoop is the
traits that come with that plant. I
should get the camera down like this,
right? whatever colors are in that
little scoop are the traits that come in
that plant. So, all the traits from the
mom plant and the dad plant or the
pollen donor in this case is still the
dad plant. Uh, all those traits have
been thrown into a bowl. Some of them
are dominant, some of them are
recessive, some of them are co-ominant.
Some traits from mom, the mom plants,
mom plant will pop up into this mix. And
some plants from the dad on both sides,
mom and dad on both sides. A couple of
those marbles got thrown into this mix.
Those are the purple marbles. Hopefully,
you can identify them when you grow it
out. But all that [ __ ] ended up in your
scoop. It depends on how the genes of
these plants interact on what you're
going to get. Sometimes, uh, you get
exactly what you want. You can see what
you're going to create by looking. You
like, I got red here, I got blue here.
When I mix these, it should come out
purple, right? That's what you would
hope for as a breeder. Sometimes you're
going to see this plant leans more red
or it leans more blue or it's really
purple, but sometimes you're going to
get a orange [ __ ] plant. You're going
to go, "What the [ __ ] happened here?"
That's just the way the genetics can
happen sometimes. Uh sometimes you get a
bunch of blue plants and then a couple
of purple plants out of the mix. That's
just the way the gen the genetics can
mix. So selection is fun. Selection is
great, but you're going to have to
realize also that that the genes are
going to do their thing. So, let me
recap here because I've been talking for
a long time on this. I want to make sure
I answer your question. I gave you my
theory. Um, that the plants will tell
you like just by looking at them,
something in one will go, I'm the one
you should reverse. And listen to that.
You're not crazy. That's intuition and
that's strong. Listen to your gut. Uh,
it will tell you. Um, a question about
choosing a reversal. Okay. I got it from
effective structure. Probably half a
dozen. I think I gave you half a dozen
trades to think about here. Um,
everything else aside. Okay. Yeah. Uh, I
would get away from the notion about
which one is the best male flower
candidate. That's a good idea. Um,
unless you're making thousands of seeds
for production, that's not going to
matter. Both plants should make you a
decent amount of pollen. You should make
uh fem seeds from that. Uh, pick the one
that you like the best. The one that you
enjoyed the best that looks like the
goal is the one that I would reverse.
And then I would pollinate the other one
and a clone of the one you reversed as
well. And do other plants as well while
you're at it. Put a few other in that
room. just hit them and then run all of
those seeds and see what you've made. If
you've been listening to the podcast,
you understand why. I want to see if you
take chocolate and you put it on lemon,
strawberry, banana, and grape, I'm going
to forget all those. But I want to see
what the outcome is. Because if they all
come out with the chocolate turpp, we
know that's coming from the chocolate
plant. But if only one or two of them,
uh, if one plant has a certain trait
that could have came from the mother
plant in the breeding, we want to find
the commonalities that that dude is
adding to the mix. If they all come out
with [ __ ] if they all glow in the
dark that came from the male. Any trait
that all of the progyny has came from
the male. Any of the other [ __ ] that
seems rare in the crosses that you can't
identify from other batches is what the
female is providing. So that's why I'd
say hit a bunch. Uh structure, vigor,
handles my [ __ ] smokes good, fits my
agenda. Um and then what's to stop you
from doing it both ways? My dude, you
got me rambling pretty good on this
podcast. Make sure you check your inbox
for your free seeds. And once again,
make sure to check that spam. Ladies and
gentlemen, boys and girls, if you like
these non-stop ramblings, uh, now is a
good time to hit like and subscribe.
That's right. Uh, go ahead and mash that
like button. Click subscribe. It's free.
And then that way you don't miss any of
this amazing cannabis cultivation
content. All right, let's keep going.
I've got another page here. This one
also came from the growhel tab on
iieirect. ienetics.com. Two different
websites. I direct for the seeds, I
genetics for all of the other stuff.
This one came from a friend who wants to
be called bum clat. Uh, welcome to the
party, bro. Um, the question says, uh,
weird question about seeds that I just
don't understand. This is a good
question because, um, this tails right
off of the last question that we just
asked. This is going to work well. It
says, "I have a plant that's growing
small towers of callalaxes and foxtails,
and the other four are growing in their
own special ways, but my question is,"
and then a little drum roll happened in
my head just now. Did you hear it? A
little drum roll going on. Anyways, it
says, "Is every pack of feminized seeds
going to produce a wide range of
phenotypes?" It's a really good
question, and I can't explain this. I
can't answer if yes or no, but I have
some input. Uh, then what's the point of
listing strain information if you plant
five seeds and all of them have
different morphology, smell, and other
traits? That makes sense. I get your
frustration. It says, "Is this just
something that happens with big seed
companies versus smaller guys? That
shouldn't be an issue. Uh, this is just
a breeding thing." Uh, I'm just trying
to determine if this is the case with
all seeds or just lazy breeders. It's
not really a lot of times I would call
out a lazy breeding technique. This is
not lazy breeding. This is how feminized
seeds work. This is a moment ago I gave
my analogy of pouring. So you've got
plant A and plant B. You got colored
marbles. You fill a bucket with the
colored marbles. You mix them. You take
a scoop. That is what you made
genetically with those plants.
Um fem seeds are usually first filial
generation. It is the first time that
they are made. Uh is the first cross
which means there is no stabilization
happening. In the cannabis realm, the
word stabilization is used incorrectly a
lot of the times. Uh it can be used for
sexual stabilization, but uh most of the
time when we say stabilization, what
we're talking about is phenotypical
stabilization across homo homo gez, I
can't even try to say it now. We want
uniform looking plants across a
population. Homozygous is the word that
my brain would not spit out there. We
want them to all look the same. So that
would take you two, three, four, or five
generations of breeding to get that
plant to to look homozygous. All of the
same. But with fem seeds, most of these
are S1's or R1's. I was just having a
conversation with this. I wanted to
explain it, but I wanted to save it here
for the podcast. Um, most of these are
S1's or R1's. An S1 is if I take one
plant, I take two copies of it, and I
self it. I take that pollen from the
golden goat, put the pollen on the
golden goat, I have selfed it. golden
goat to golden goat itself. Nobody else.
If I pick put the golden goat pollen on
any other plant that is an R1, that is a
reversal. So that's the difference
between an S and an R. The self stuff,
you're going to find more uniformity
because we're not adding as many
ingredients. It is all golden goat.
Golden goat to golden goat. You should
get golden goat, right? The magic part
about breeding, the magic part about
genetics is you're going to see. So
golden goats obviously got parents. We
started with two golden goat plants, but
that plant had parents. It had um island
sweet skunk, Hawaiian sativa, Romulan
and its background. And those plants
have parents as well. So all of those
genes are all in this mix, which means
when you run the golden goat to golden
goat, you could see some island sweet
skunk, Hawaiian sativa, Ramulan
phenotypes pop out. Those are going to
be the outliers. Most of your phenotypes
will look like golden goat, but some are
going to represent the mom, the dad, the
grandma, the grandpa. Those will pop
through from both sides. Uh that's just
the way it's going to work with self
seeds with the S1s. Now, with the RS,
we're taking two different plants and
we're putting them together. So, we've
got the opportunity to see
representations. We hope as a breeder to
get I usually hope for a 50/50 mix. So,
if I throw um I'm going to do the
marbles analogy again. If I throw 50% 64
red marbles and 64 blue marbles when mix
them up when I make my scoop, I'm hoping
to get a bunch of purple marbles, right?
64 purple marbles out of that is what I
would hope for. But it's not going to
work that way because sometimes I'm
going to get marbles that, like I said
before, lean a little bit more red.
There's going to be marbles that lean a
little bit more blue. That's just how
it's going to go because this is the
first filial generation of this cross.
Even though it is an R1, even though it
may be an S1, it is also an F1, which
means it's got that F1 vigor, but it's
also got that hybridization where it
could show filial or phenotypes,
phenotypical expression. Expression
said, I'm not even going to edit that
phenotypical expression from both sides
uh and from further generations. It can
show you a lot of those expressions. So
that's why you're seeing differences. Um
your question is it lazy breeders? No,
it is. Um that's what when we're making
F1s, S1's, R1's, that's how it works
because there's no uh we haven't done
any stabilization work to make them more
uniform. That would take another
generation, two more generations to make
them uniform and stable. F1 seeds work
the same way. If you buy a bunch of F1s
from people, I sell a lot of F1s and
many people enjoy that F1 because it has
a lot of vigor and they can find the
phenotype that they like. Um, you're
going to find the phenotypes you like.
So, you say, why make a strain
description? Because we've narrowed it
down that it is pretty close to that.
You're going to get within this range.
We can't be perfectly accurate with it,
but we get pretty close. You'll notice
my descriptions are pretty close. A lot
of those are F1s, and I'm still nailing
it. I've often described it like maybe
you've decided you want Italian food.
So, you go to a website, you find seeds
that maybe look like Italian food. Be
creative with me here. Uh, you found
your favorite. You found a plant that
says tastes like strawberries and
bananas. And when you smoke it, it makes
your [ __ ] hair fly backward. You're
like, that's exactly what the [ __ ] I
want. Right. So, we go to the restaurant
that drive that [ __ ] u tastes like
strawberries and bananas, makes your
hair fly backward. We're in the right
restaurant. We've given you the menu.
Now, the the phenotypical expression,
the variation you may get, in my
opinion, that's like once you've got the
menu, I can go over and decide if I want
noki, if I want [ __ ] pennet pasta, if
I want spaghetti, uh if I want some meat
sauce, um you that's So, I've driven you
to the restaurant. Now, you just got to
choose the one on the menu that works
best for you. And now, that's where we
go back to choosing the one that works
best for your grow, your bong, your
customers, your wallet, whatever you're
growing for. We got to find the one that
works best for that. So, it's not a
weird question. I understand where
you're coming from. When we put a
description on a pack of seeds, you want
it to come out like that. But keep in
mind, these are na nature's [ __ ]
little beans. It's nature. It's natural.
This is genetics. There's going to be
variation. Just like if your mom and dad
made 20 babies, um they're not all going
to look the same. If your mom's got blue
eyes, your dad's got brown eyes, some
there's I'm sure that one of those
dominant is dominant in the breeding. I
haven't researched which is dominant,
blue or brown eyes, but some of your
siblings are going to have brown eyes.
Some are going to have blue eyes. And
maybe uh one or two of them may have
green eyes because grandma or grandpa
somewhere on the line had green eyes.
It's going to work that way. Maybe one
of your brothers and sisters is super
[ __ ] tall and the other guys are 5'8.
Just a phenotypical outlier. That's the
way genetics work. We wish we could
control it and manipulate it to be
[ __ ] I put pollen here, I put pollen
here, and tada, these are all going to
come out like clones. That is not the
way that genetics work. That it takes a
lot more work. It's not lazy breeding.
It's just when so with fem seeds, the
first filial generations of fems in my
experience uh are the best. After that,
you start unlocking weird [ __ ] Uh you
can make weird plants, mutants, things
that don't grow right. So S1's are the
best. F1 uh R1s are the best um for the
uh for the fems because um like when you
breed with an F2, a normal F2 reggg
seed, that's when you unlock Pandora's
box of phenotypes. That S2 is where a
lot of weird [ __ ] also happens. So
that's why we're doing it that way. Uh
my dude, um was your name? Bum Clot. I I
I get it. Um bro, make sure you check
your inbox and thank you for the great
question. Ladies and gentlemen, boys and
girls, pimps and hoes, friends and foes,
smokers, growers, clone cutters, pollen
chuckers, all of you amazing cannabis
farmers out there. Thank you once again
for listening to this episode. This
might be a short episode after a couple
of edits. I'm not even sure how it's
going to end up, but I do want to thank
you once again for watching, listening.
Make sure you click like, make sure you
click subscribe, and also tell a friend
about the podcast. If you have a friend
who is growing, uh, who is new at
growing, who's been growing for a little
while, somebody that could, uh, maybe
they just need some advice and they're
too stubborn to listen to you, recommend
the podcast, uh, tell them the Grow from
Your Heart podcast will get them up to
speed. I think that is all I've got for
you. Don't forget to check i Direct for
fresh uh, new testers. Also, all orders
over $100 at IDE Direct do come with
free shipping. I think I'm rambling at
this point. That's all I've got for you.
I'll be back in a week with fresh new
content. I want to give a big shout out
to my buddy untrained astronaut. And
until next time, take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me.
[Music]
Roster Jeff, you bad
[ __ ] Time to take another damn.
Grab your piece and hug the bag. Ro is
in the lab. Sit back and relax. Hold up.
Roots and wisdom start to sow. From the
knowledge seeds we grow, tuning out to
hear the vibr in our conscious
tribe. He spreads the truth in every
word. Every voice must now be
heard. Healing light through cannabis.
Go from your heart your bliss. Rise up
higher. Find your way. Grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song. Natural medicine and love flows
within us like a
dove. Educate and eleate. Join the
journey. Don't be late. Open minds to
see the truth. In the soil lies the
proof. Ra that chef will guide you
through this. God define the new. Rise
up higher. Find your way. Grow from your
hearts every day. In the light we stand
real strong. Join the movement. Sing the
song.
[Music]
Oh, open minds to see the truth. In the
soil lies the proof. Rust Jeff will
guide you through in this garden. Find a
new. Rise up higher. Find your way. Grow
from your hearts every day. In the light
we stand real strong. Join the movement.
Sing the song.
Ooh.
Ooh. Ooh.
[Music]
[Applause]