yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 89 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower if you're a professional
grower if you're a new smoker or a
veteran dabber if your cannabis
activists or even someone who's just
curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host they call me Rasta Jeff
thanks again for joining me as always I
need to send a huge thank you shout out
to the mystic roots band for letting me
use their music on the show
big thanks to Kat coot and the entire
mystic roots crew what's up you guys
hope everybody's having a great day I'm
coming to you on a scorching hot
Thursday it is stupid hot today but
we're gonna deal with thing we're gonna
drink a lot of water we're gonna water
up the plants then we're gonna talk a
little bit about some heat issues that
some friends of mine have been having in
their gardens and we'll talk about ways
to cure a little bit of heat problems
and then I've got some ranting to do but
before we get that far this podcast is
brought to you by my friends at hydro
indoor growing supplies
hi Gro indoor growing supplies has two
locations to serve Colorado visit the
Denver store at 62 71 Beach Street or
check out the pueblo location on 618
East 4th Street and beautiful Pueblo
Colorado check out Highgrove for
competitive pricing and a great
selection of indoor gross supplies you
guys when you're checking out at high
grill and/or grind supplies make sure
you let them know you listen to the girl
from your heart podcast and they will
give you commercial pricing on your
entire purchase that's right you'll pay
what I pay I'll put some money back in
your pocket you guys we all know that
money is expensive these days all right
we're gonna get on with the show here I
want to let you guys know that I'm
recording with a new device today I'm
using the new zoom h6 handy recorder I
got the zoom h6 so that I will be able
to take this podcast on the road a
little bit it's a much smaller unit than
what I've been using this thing will fit
in my back pocket and I can carry it
around and I can do shows from events
such as the secret cup the cannabis cup
or wherever we may be so you guys look
for
two episodes with special guests coming
up because now I can take the show to
them instead of trying to get people to
come to me I live in kind of a shitty
part of Colorado where nobody wants to
go so it's hard to get like danzel and
hunt and people like that to come here
but if I go to them they're happy to be
on the show so it's been a few bucks I
got the zoom h6 we will take this show
on the road you guys I'm gonna ask you
to do me a favor since you're listening
to the show let me know what you think
of the sound quality let me know if this
quality is acceptable let me know if it
I've changed anything that you noticed
because if this isn't acceptable I'll go
back to using the main studio setup
I just wanted to pull this out give it a
try see what it was like before I try to
take it on the road and record with
other people so yeah big shot to the
zoom h6 well you know what you think of
it you guys alright so let's get into
the show I told you that I saw some
ducting issues I did a consultation for
a friend of mine I didn't even charge
him for it the other day but he's been
saying dude my room's getting way too
hot this summer what can I do and I was
like you know what that's a good start
of a podcast so I walked in there and
then the first thing I see is messy ass
ducting the students got a decent girl
room he's got enough air conditioning
his plants look good but his ducting was
a complete mess you guys and I've seen a
lot of messy ducting lately on my visits
and consultations so one thing I wanna
tell you is keep in mind that every
single twist and bend in your ducting
Razoo reduces your air flow and adds to
the workload of your blower whatever
kind of inline fan you're using every
Bend puts more strain and more pressure
on that inline fan and slows down the
amount of air you're moving so ideally
ducting would be in a straight line with
zero curves or bends or twists or
anything like that but I know that's not
that's not rational because of course
we're growing in houses and things like
that and you have to move the air around
and not a straight line sometimes but
try to get it as straight as you can
that'll save you a lot of money on
heating costs it'll save you money
because you don't have to run the blower
as hard it'll save you money because
you're more efficiently cooling so
Street now oh I just noticed something
when you put the cellphone too close to
the h6 you get a little bit of
interference so that's good to know
sorry about that guys I hope you didn't
hear that too much I'm reading notes off
of my cell phone here which is why I did
that
anyway try to keep producting in a
straight line another great way to save
some money on cooling you guys
would be to run your lights at night
kilowatts from the electric company are
actually cheaper at night so if you're
not running your electricity at peak
hours it'll save you a few bucks so what
I would recommend if you can do it and
this will only work for some people on
your lifestyle your schedule if you can
have your plants come on right around
here it gets a dark about nine o'clock
eight or nine o'clock hitch right now it
would be ideal to have your lights come
on at 9:00 p.m. that way it's cool
outside the Sun has gone down the lights
kick on and that way you're not fighting
the Sun all day you're not adding Sun
and grow lights to that grow room to try
to cool down so turn on your lights at
night if you can that'll help you out
all right so you guys straighten out
your ducting run your light cycle at
night and you'll save a few bucks on
cooling costs getting your plants too
hot is gonna cause them to become fluffy
and it's gonna decrease your harvest
weight so when you've got electricity
bills to cover every gram counts so you
got to do your best to pull every gram
you can out of the room since you've got
to pay for every kilowatt that you've
used so figure out how to get the
ducting straight start running the
lights at night and that will help you
out quite a bit something else you guys
could keep in mind during these hot
summer months is humidity as the
temperatures rise the humidity outside
is rising also so be aware of how humid
your rooms are this is the first year
that I have personally needed to go buy
a dehumidifier from my main flowering
room fans and air conditioning are not
enough sometimes you guys you need to
remove the stagnant humid air from your
rooms and replace it with fresh co2 rich
air for your plants so you guys make
sure you're pulling that air out that
hot air needs to be sucked out all right
one more thing I can think of to help
you keep your rooms cool is to pay
attention to the filters and your air
conditioners guys those filters are
designed to last for a year without
being replaced but keep in mind you guys
are running them in a grow room or there
may be a lot of extra dirt a lot of
humidity and there's a lot of extra work
on that unit they don't expect that unit
to be competing with four or five or six
whatever you got that many thousand watt
lights they don't expect that thing to
come on when you buy it and never shut
off like a lot of us do with an air
conditioner so if you've got an air
conditioner that has filters replace
those once they get clogged up
if air doesn't flow through you don't
get as much cooling
wasting electricity that electricity is
not turning into a gram of weed so
you're flushing money down the toilet
basically your air conditioner may
require a little extra maintenance since
we're working it so hard you guys and
also keep in mind where you're putting
your air conditioner it may suck up a
little bit more dirt and [ __ ] like that
just depending on where you have put it
all right so that was a good little rant
since we're talking about replacing
things and things that you need to
upgrade in your grow room I figured I'd
make a little kind of a checklist of
things it would be a good idea to
replace and check on one thing that you
guys need to replace is your bulbs in
your grow rooms the HID bulbs don't last
forever if you're using good bulbs you
can switch those out about once every
six months or if you've got the budget
you can toss them every two crops which
would be about every four months if
that's one if you're using moley as a
flowering cycle if you're buying those
cheap plant max bulbs you guys or
whatever generic brand you you're buying
at your grow shop I would recommend
replacing those every single flowering
cycle those aren't high quality bulbs
and they burn out a little bit quickly
all right if you're using those cheap
bulbs guys what I would recommend is
harvest the room empty the room clean it
out and replace those bulbs before you
put new plants in there again if you're
using good bulbs you can go probably two
cycles maybe three I definitely wouldn't
go past for flowering cycles but the
same bulb I would replace that the bulb
will stop putting out as much light but
it will still be sucking up as much
electricity it will still be making as
much heat and again you're not turning
those kilowatts into grams of weed which
is your goal you don't want to pay for
electricity that is just causing heat
which is making your air conditioner run
stronger which is pulling more
electricity you see the cycle hair all
right so don't forget that your bulbs in
your veg area are just as important as
in your flowering room you guys you got
to swap those bulbs out occasionally
also I like those new 315 bulbs I'll
reason those at the shop they seem to
put out quite a bit of light and they're
affordable so if you guys can afford the
315 I would definitely recommend those
if you want to go with your metal halide
bulbs I would recommend those again
every every two months every four months
every six months at the very longest you
guys I wouldn't run longer than six
months on the same Bowl no matter what
you're doing with it if you've got those
t5 bulbs you're gonna need to replace
those quite frequently those things just
crap out
and what I have noticed about the T
fives if you buy a fixture with like
eighty fives in it just pretty much plan
on replacing all eight t5 bulbs all at
the same time because they're all just
gonna start [ __ ] now when one goes out
just go buy the whole set alright guys
we've talked about replacing your bulbs
now what about the ballasts if you're
using modern modern digital ballot
digital ballasts they'll last a while
most of them come with a nice warranty
so you didn't hear this from me but
anything that comes with a warranty that
will be replaced because of the warranty
I make sure to break that thing about a
month or two before the warranty is up
sometimes a few months before the
warranty is up just break it just
[ __ ] break it and then go get another
one on the warranty because these
companies are charging you enough for
[ __ ] anyway it should last a while
break it and go get a new one they're
gonna refurbish the one that you've got
they're gonna resell it as a refurbished
unit don't worry about them they make
plenty of money just break the [ __ ]
thing right before the warranty is up
and get yourself a new one if you're
using those old magnetic ballasts those
things will go forever you won't see any
drop in light power from a ballast from
what I've noticed they'll just die one
day it won't even warn you so when your
ballast warranty is about to be up go
get another one you guys that should be
enough ranting for now about fixing your
rooms one thing I should remind you of
that I have mentioned in a previous
episode since we're talking about
replacing things calibrate your pH
meters you guys your TDS pins your pH
pins whatever else you want to call it
your EC meter if you're in England or
Britain you guys calibrate those things
quite frequently because when that
messes up you don't even notice and
you're just in there trying to adjust pH
and you're doing it wrong and you don't
know so you're gonna start causing
problems all right guys I've been going
for just over 10 minutes here I need a
quick dab so uh you know let's do a dab
on the air together I was recently
gifted some blueberry headband shatter
from the spa it's actually the shatter
is from our boys at tur pecs I got it at
the SPOC out in Pueblo West I'm gonna
take a quick drink of this bubbly
carbonated beverage I got here and then
we're gonna put together a dad and we're
gonna take a dad together so here we go
[Music]
not right I needed it carbonated drink
there that was much deserved I'm gonna
get a DAB together real quick you guys
[Music]
big shout out to something called the
perfect jar I was gifted a jar called
the perfect jar by my buddy hunt the
grimy Gatsby and they might be right
this might be the perfect jar ban this
thing is nice it's uh I don't even know
what kind of plastic this is it's real
sturdy plastic it's got a nice screw on
lid it's airtight it's nicely it's got
dividers inside I'm able to carry my
herb in one container I got a dabber in
one container and then like four or five
different kinds of shatter and the other
little containers there nice container
bro thanks huh I appreciate you kicking
that down so today we are going to dab
the what did I call it's blueberry
headband from our friends at tur pecs
and I'm putting a dab of it on the dab
right now as we speak you guys we're
dabbing out of the air across 4.0 custom
prototype that's autographed by Eric
Ross on the back it's got his little
signature itched in the back to that
it's got the highly educated D male
bigshot it's a highly educated and task
rock and that D nail attachment is
attached to what is called the G nail
coil by our friends at emote F shout out
to giddy up and emote ekam burping from
that drink excuse me so I've got the dad
together you guys let's take a DAB
blueberry headband to shatter from
torpex available at the spot dispensary
you know by the time you hear this
they'll have a totally different brand
of shatter a nor does a totally
different flavor but let's review this
anyway here we go
[Music]
it's definitely smooth nice and smooth
no joke
I like that um so let me back up a step
here by looking at it it's nice and
glossy it's got a nice shine to it ah
it's nice and clear it's got a nice
clear amber yellow color so it looks
great on the inhale well let me talk
about the smell it just smelled like
hash let's smell it again let's put it
up to the nose
dad just smell like shadow mostly smells
the same it's got that shatter II like
almost a honey kind of a sweet smell to
it but anyway it looks good that smells
good when I taste it on the inhale I
definitely tasted the blueberry on the
exhale it had a hint of um Cushie chemi
type of stuff I'm an earthy flavor on
the out so the N is blueberries and
there's a hint of blueberry on the
tongue still but you know what the
feeling is straight headband it feels
like I just put a headband on my head it
feels like I just slowed down to tell
you the truth it was like feels like I
just slowed down a whole bunch so let's
get back into doing a podcast I
certainly approve of the blueberry
headband it tastes like blueberry it
feels like headband it's smooth I'm high
as [ __ ] from it to tell you the truth
guys excuse the cough alright now that I
buy a [ __ ] I want to answer some
questions that people have sent to me
these questions have come from periscope
they've come from Twitter I've gotten
them in emails and I have gotten them on
Facebook you guys if you're not checking
it out on periscope every occasionally I
jump onto periscope and just I take a
couple of dabs and I rant and I hang out
with my friends I talk about a few
things that are on my mind and then I
just sign out and say goodbye and I
usually delete the videos pretty quickly
but if you ever check out the periscope
app make sure you follow me and you can
check out some of the videos in the
future I'll do a full podcast on
periscope and you'll be able to jump in
and ask me questions and I'll be able to
answer them live for you the only
problem with that right now is you guys
I'm taking over as the leaf grower at
the spot dispensary and there's been a
lot of work and some days we work until
noon other days we work until 6:00 it's
hard to guess so right now scheduling
things is a little bit of a pain in the
ass but I promise you I'm gonna do this
periscope episode I just promised you so
that means I've got to do it I've never
promised you something and not done it
on
show all right so let me get to the
point here questions and answers with
Rasta Jeff our first question is about a
product called OGT quite a while ago I
mentioned that I use a product called
OGT veganic secret sauce is what I think
it's called
somebody asked me to talk a little bit
about it
I like that product a whole bunch I'd
like it it's what it is I don't have any
of the product with me I've used all of
what I have and I kind of haven't been
using it since I ran out I replaced it
with something else
but what it is is an organic tea that is
able to be mixed almost instantly and
then fed to your plants a lot of teas
that we're using need to be mixed up and
they need to brew for 24 to 48 hours
this stuff you can pour the powder into
some water give it a nice stir and feed
it directly to your plants one thing
that I did notice that it promoted
ridiculously healthy roots my roots were
growing quickly my roots were growing
out of the holes and the bottoms of my
pots the drainage holes my roots were
coming out of there looking for
somewhere else to go hide I have a
friend who breaks down the soil from my
harvested plants he gets paid to help me
out a little bit and when Mike was
breaking down those root balls
he asked me dude what have you been
doing differently lately because these
things are amazing a lot of that I will
attribute to the secret sauce the og tea
I think it was doing a lot of it it was
really great for the early lifecycle of
the plants and for veg now when in when
I went into flour here's something that
I didn't realize was happening I noticed
there was something weird and somebody
else pointed it out to me when I was in
flower and I was feeding OGT I would
feed it every other week and on those
weeks I would notice that my plants
would progress more into what looks like
a nutrient deficiency on some strains I
had strains that I'd I was feeding it
just like I have before and it looked
like it was becoming nitrogen deficient
the plant couldn't keep up with itself
and it was just burning out really early
and I mentioned that to our friend Sean
and I mentioned that the only thing I
was using differently was the OGT and
Sean said that the rock phosphates that
they are using to produce the OGT speed
up the nutritive cycle of your plank so
if you're going to use this stuff I
would only use it during the veg cycle
and use it very
sparingly during the flowering cycle
because when I used the recommended
dosage it sped my plants up almost too
much and they weren't burned but they
were almost not able to they were
growing so quickly and using nutrients
so quickly that they were eating all of
their food for the week within the first
couple of the days and then starving
themselves is what it looked like was
happening so that is my little rant on
OGT it's a good product but if you're
going to use it be prepared and you're
gonna have to adjust your feeding
they're gonna have to pay attention but
I hope you're doing that every time you
put a new product into your garden
anyway alright so our next question I
want to move on where did I put it here
we go our next question comes from
periscope and somebody asked me and this
is gonna take me a little bit today to
describe here but somebody said what is
solvent list because I was talking about
solvent list on periscope and they did
not have it in context so let me try to
describe to you what solvent list is
first off let me say that solvent list
is a marketing term solvent list is
owned by McAtee of the essential
extracts I don't know if it's owned by
him but it is the marketing term that he
has put on what he calls solvent lists
now that being said not all solvent list
hash has to come from nicotine anything
any hash that is made without solvent
can will be considered solvent less in
most cases in 99% of the cases in the
cannabis industry you know I've never
seen anything else called non solvent
maybe dry sipped but that's totally
different
water hash or bubble hash is solvent
list it's made with ice and water it's
not the solvents that we are using is
BHO Pho there are a couple other gases
that people are using to extract hash
with lately but the propane and the
butane are the solvents and I know a lot
of people are gonna say but water is a
solvent as well right in this case and
I'm going to paraphrase what nicotine
says all of the time big shout out to DJ
nicotine when we're talking about
solvent less hash water is not being
used as a solvent it's being used as a
mechanical separator we're not trying to
dissolve the trichomes we're not trying
to dissolve the plant matter
we're just simply using it as a way to
wash the trichomes off of the leaves so
solvent less hash is basically hash made
by using ice or water solvent list made
by DJ naked tea is kept at a certain
temperature at all times and it never
gets warm it never gets dry and never
hardens up it's always got a nice greasy
texture to it it's always real tasty
that's solvent list alright so since
we're talking about solvent list let me
describe a couple of other types of hash
just to kind of put that in perspective
a little bit other types of hash that
are super popular right now that
everybody talks about our BHO which is
butane honey oil or butane hash or dabs
or shatter or wax that's pretty much the
most popular right now and then of
course there is live resin live resin is
basically it is BHO that is made from
fresh frozen plants and then it is
blasted through an obidos machine by emo
tech the only way that you can make live
resin is through an emo tech machine and
I know that sounds crazy but like I said
earlier nicotine has made the marketing
term solvent list the boys at emo Tech
have come up with the term live resin so
unless you're running it emo textile in
an emo tech machine you're not making
libraries and a lot of people are gonna
hate on me for that but that is my
theory and I'm sticking to it
alright guys I've got time for one more
question this question comes from
Facebook and it's from our friend Bobby
Bobby is starting his first grow and
he's asking if it is ok to use Miracle
Grow plant food or Miracle Grow soil for
his cannabis plants and you guys I
definitely have to say I strongly
recommend not using any miracle girl
products in your garden The Miracle Grow
soil has time-released
fertilizers in it which will last for up
to six months and you don't want
nitrogen being released into your plants
for six months so I would recommend not
using that soil use something like a fox
farms product or a roots organics
product use something like that if
you're a new grower it gives you a solid
start there's not nutrients in it that
are gonna screw you up
it'll have things in it that will help
you out from the very beginning as for
the nutrients if you are trying to use
Miracle Grow nutria
I would throw those away right away get
rid of the plant food head your hydro
shop head to hydro indoor growing
supplies and get yourself a basic two or
three part nutrient solution there will
be a bottle a a bottle beef of a brand
that sounds good to you the guys at the
hydro shop can definitely talk you
through what you need they'll help you
pick a brand they're mainly if you're
just starting out they're mainly the
same thing I would say go with something
like the tannic hair bio biz something
simple just something with an A and a B
the general organics or general
hydroponics Florida Nova stuff that's
all fine any of that stuff you want to
go for it's pretty much all the same
thing if you're starting out get
yourself an A and a B maybe a bloom
booster and then maybe like some sugary
or something to sweeten it up but
definitely get away from that Miracle
Grow stuff go to the hydro shop get
something designed more toward cannabis
something that you can control for each
cycle of your plants cuz you're not
gonna want the same nutrients from
beginning to end you want a little bit
of grow in the beginning you're gonna
taper the grow off as you get into
flower and you'll start using the bloom
solution so bill gets something that's
more designed for the plants that you
are growing Bobby I hope that helps you
out you guys that are thinking about
Miracle Grow soil I hope I got you away
from that also here's something to think
about you guys Miracle Grow products are
all from Scots and Scots is a Monsanto
brand and we do not want to support
Monsanto because Monsanto does not
support the world so that's something to
think about think about where the
products you're buying are made and who
they affect and the impact that you will
have on the world all right you guys I
think that was enough questions for one
episode I really want to thank everybody
who sent me questions if you want to
send questions to me via email if you
want to hit me up on Twitter if you want
to Facebook me however you want to get a
question to me if you're one of my
friends if you're one of the homies feel
free to send it to me via text message
you can message me directly on Instagram
on the hydrogen etics Instagram because
I love the questions I love the
interaction I love helping you guys
that's what I got the show going for so
I really appreciate it big shout out I
appreciate all of those questions
alright guys I'll be back next week for
another episode I got a question from a
listener asking what are the difference
or what's the difference between THC and
CBD that maybe the next episode
be one before that episode it's gonna
that's gonna be a lot of putting
together there's a lot of work going
into that episode I'm not sure if it'll
be ready by the next one but I will
definitely have it ready by number 91 so
you guys I'm gonna wrap up the show
thanks for listening to another episode
I'll be back in just a few days don't
forget to check out our sponsor hydro
indoor growing supplies if you're
interested in sponsoring the podcast or
if you've got a product you'd like me to
review just send me an email it's go
from your heart at hotmail.com I'll get
you all of the information that you do
need you guys now that the show is over
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for grow from your heart
give me a 5 star rating and after that
type in a review and let me know what
you think of the show and I will read
your comment on a future episode guys if
you want to leave a comment on stitcher
i'd appreciate it but it's really hard
to find the comments on stitcher
stitcher is always changing things so I
would recommend just send me a Facebook
comment if that's what you want to do on
Facebook it's just grow from your heart
you can find me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast on instagram i'm at i read
genetics you guys if you have something
seen or not into all the social media
stuff you can email me it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com don't forget
the show is available on iTunes and
stitcher every single episode is always
and forever archived on I read genetics
Colorado com we've got that donation
button up there on the podcast page you
guys if you feel like this show is worth
a couple of bucks you can go to my
website I read genetics Colorado com
click on the girl from your heart
podcast tab at the top right there's a
donation button it's a little PayPal
logo that goes directly to my PayPal
account
I'll never charge you guys for this
podcast this podcast is always going to
be free this is my gift to you but if
you do feel like making a small
contribution to say thank you it would
definitely be appreciated and I would
give you a shout-out on the show you
guys like I said we're on all the social
media sites make sure you check us out
there I'll be back in just a few days
guys big shout out to my ninja spin so
let me know what you thought of this
recording I recorded this on the zoom h6
I had to stop one time and do an
adjustment to the recording settings but
I think I've got it all figured out so
let me know what you think send me a
comment on Facebook on Instagram on
Twitter however you want to do it I
would appreciate it until next time you
guys thanks for listening shadows my
ninja Spence until next time take a phat
dab
and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
sweet
come on everybody
[Music]
let us on the track no one can't contest
and now go nah weak among the names look
inside yourself a teacher the game
global domination major routes
[Music]
I raised a debate to stay positive all
the homies on the track spitting the
truth
[Music]
like living my life because Mike