[Music]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 91 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversations I try to fear a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a hardcore dabber
if you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you I'm your
host
they call me Rasta Jeff thanks again for
joining me I need to send a huge thank
you shout out to the mystic root band
for letting me play their music in my
podcast
big thanks to cat food and the entire
mystic roots crew you guys I don't have
any commercials for this week I want to
get right into the episode before we get
started I want to let you know that this
is a part two episode a few days ago
Jesse was here and we recorded for quite
a while I put up the first half of the
conversation on Monday this is part two
it starts off with me I asked Jesse if
he had any guidance or advice to give
growers and then we'll just jump into
right where he started before we get
there I do want to make an apology I
posted episode 92 iTunes and my website
and stitcher and for some reason episode
90 did not make it to stitcher I like it
normally would have that was not my
issue it was stitchers issue they have
since been emailed as soon as stitcher
gets episode 90 up I will post episode
91 I don't want to cause any confusion
with stitcher I've emailed them and let
them know that my latest episode did not
post so I don't want to have another
episode on to that and confuse them as
soon as stitcher gets episode 90 out
episode 91 will be posted right after
that I appreciate you guys for being
patient I do apologize for any
inconvenience that may have caused I
feel like I've been rambling enough it's
almost a two-minute intro let's get
right down to the part where Jesse and I
are talking so here we go I asked Jesse
I basically said do you have any
guidance that you would like to share
with our listeners and then here is what
Jesse had to say don't sell junk clones
don't sell junk clones don't sell
untested seeds oh my god I don't sell
clones of plants from seed that you have
any
floured yet yeah definitely I've heard
so many horror stories at the gross
store like I feel so bad for people like
I can't help them but it just it really
sucks if you do that stuff do it right
if you get a bag seed out of what's this
hash this is Startalk I'm taking a dab a
star dog from there just give it to max
if if you I wasn't even gonna say now if
you get a bag seed of it okay you grow
it out and then oh oh if you get if you
grow some weed and it's got a bunch of
seeds in it that star dog plant just cuz
it's wholly seeded to [ __ ] doesn't mean
you can call those seed star dog those
are not star dog seeds no no those are
unknown seeds unless you hit that star
dog girl with male star dog pollen or
manipulated the plant in some other
fashion to create s1 seeds it does
happen you know if you don't it's still
not exactly it right but if you I thing
is if you don't know what did it yeah
don't call it start yeah yeah because it
could be there could have been some
pollen in there it could have been
another one of the plants that firmed on
it it could have been a male in there if
if all you had was seven star dog plants
in there I guess you do have star dog
seeds if you light stressed it and it
produced a bunch of seeds you do now
have star dog seat that could have been
a a really special recessive clone
phenotype and and what comes out is the
dominant piece of junk you know Riya yes
you're gonna see grandpa when you see
what the grandpa was you're gonna see
what grandma was and sometimes those
plants were shitty or something you just
never know a lot of what we have now the
plants that we're growing now are like
your dad's fault you know what I mean so
Jessie's dad they're the ones who chose
these actually did some breeding back
then so they had to use to steal
streetlights they couldn't run too much
electricity they didn't know what the
hell they were looking for they had the
shittiest books everything in the books
back then was hand-drawn uh people were
still they were still in electricity
back
yeah and hand-drawn books that you had
to go to shady ass head shops to buy not
to Mel Frank I'm gonna take this dad
here then we'll start doing this but
yeah those that generation is
responsible for the plants that we have
now those guys some of the guys that
went to war in other countries brought
back seeds from those regions they grew
those seeds they found that somewhere
too damn tall they found that some took
way too long and they got rid of them
and I bet you bro I bet they're now that
we've got room and space and lights and
Technology I bet some of the gold was
thrown the [ __ ] alone oh I guarantee if
you've got a bag of old-school seeds if
you're like 50 or 60 years old and
you've got a big sandwich bag full of
seeds that you had when you were let's
see I want to go back to the 70s so if
you got some 35 year old seeds 40 year
old seeds and you want to share them
send Jesse and I a sandwich baggie fool
we'll take pictures and we'll give you a
clone of our favorite [ __ ]
yes I got some pretty old TV other day
shout-out to mr. G and I can't remember
is a llama box llama box yeah thanks for
the hook-up guys I've heard llama box is
very familiar oh yeah he won a yeah he
was one of the winners for the 50 show
that is true in his little Twitter icon
is a little llama yeah I knew I
remembered that I was taking a dad and
that still made sense to me shot at the
green and healthy wellness while I'm
thinking about it you guys I wrote it
down to say this I was supposed to say
it in the intro but I just took a DAB
and I want to make sure I don't forget
green and healthy wellness is not closed
forever no I know I hyped this shop in
Colorado Springs shout out to hunt shout
it to damsel shout it to Haley shout it
to Jordan Jordan Jordan and John
Randall's Junie but they had to shut
their doors for a little while
the building I don't know how much of
this business is mined air the building
in which they were located was sold and
the new owner did not want a dispensary
there it's basically the story so they
were forced to move they do have a new
location by the time you hear this it is
likely that they are open to back for
business and if they are not trust me
you guys green and healthy woman is fast
like dude I saw them working to tear
down the building and it was like army
ants and they're just going buck wild it
was crazy
everybody was sweaty and had this
stressful look so they're getting melty
crow to everything yeah so that's always
fun yeah
so they are eager to get the new
facility open they're not gone forever
you guys the tur pax hookup at green &amp;
Healthy wellness we'll be back damsel
we'll be back back if I understand it
right they actually got a better
building they got a better location is
bigger that building was a little tight
the parking would get a little cramped
in there sometimes yeah so they will be
back and it will be better than ever
they do apologize for the inconvenience
we know the lot of people rely on them
for their medicine they are a medical
only shop so a lot of patients are
looking for a new spot for medicine
they'll be back you guys I promise I
certainly promise big shout out to hunt
was here the other day at the house and
hung out and we did make promises to
record together very soon next that
episode will feature the lovely dude its
damsel my favorite Suicide Girls she's a
little famous on the interweb you know
she's a little popular shout out I sent
her up
I took I'm sure I've talked about it on
the show I'm growing a strain called
damsels Dayne I'm hunting from seed I'm
running three different seed lines of
stuff that I've crossed and I'm looking
to find her favorite phenotype and then
we're gonna name that one damsels DANC
and it's gonna be marketed at the
dispensary youth that I represent and
the dispensary that she represents and
so I took a picture of the seedling and
sent it to her and I said at the
beginning and she put that on Instagram
and within an hour I had a hundred new
followers Jesus yeah so shut up dude
it's danzel that's my favorite Suicide
Girl that's hard to pick yeah that'll be
yeah that'll be a little bit popular
that'll get some stuff going for both of
us yeah those both brands suicide girls
do that the damsel Clinton will be part
of that the Grammy Gatsby will be part
of advertising green and healthy
wellness will be carrying the flowers
for sure in the near future the spot
will have the flowers but you guys this
is a year-long project don't think this
something this is something that's going
to go in a few weeks we bred a strain we
bred a seed line
red 3c lines we took those seedlings
they germinated they are now in veg they
just got put into three gallon pots I've
got to run
I think 22 of them out of the original I
think 30 started 22 of them have made it
to where I think they'll make it to the
flour room I may take one or two out
ones too tall and lanky it's a boy I can
tell just by looking so I kind of want
to just pull that one but then they'll
flower once they're flowered there's a
private party set up the dates already
been chosen as a location being put
together and the Graeme Gatsby is gonna
throw a tasting party and there will be
scorecards and video done and full-on
reviews so yeah we're taking this one
quite seriously and this just a Fino
hunt imagine if he was actually taking
the seeds to market right so two year
project yeah exactly because I would run
a run at least a hundred of those seeds
myself after I ran 20 or 50 of them
myself I would start sending 10 packs
out to friends I'd give you ten of them
no sin amounts of friends that are eager
to grow they would grow them right away
they would send me pictures they would
send me feedback if they're local I get
to go I get to go to Rasta Ralph's
garden and look at my blue heeler growin
I get to go to people's places and see
my plants growing in their garden to get
feedback which improves my breeding
because then I could say oh god I never
want to breed with that [ __ ] plant
ever again what is the blue heeler blue
heeler is the blue band The Grateful dog
okay shout out to Spencer for the name I
was like I'm gonna cross through the
Blue Dream and The Grateful dog because
that's blue heeler packs of seeds for
that I I don't think I've ever grown a
blue dream cross it's not my favorite
strain in the world to be honest that
was Colorado was in love with Blue Dream
and the girls in California are in love
with blue dream it's a cash crop plant
it does have some medicinal value but
it's used too much here as a cash crop
plant for what it is it's uh I forgot
the cross of it suddenly that blueberry
and Silver Haze yeah yeah I guess it's
by DJ shorts son or something like that
isn't it yeah or son-in-law I'm not sure
if that's actually true because I
yeah that's up for debate guys if you
know the truth of where the Blue Dream
came from but it's a haze and it's a
blue dream and it's got some og I think
in there but you would think from what
I've read I remember thinking that would
be the ideal strain but then I remember
getting my hands on a couple of
different grows of it and smoking it I
mean like this is medium there's a
amazing [ __ ] phenotype of it and
these blue dream phenotype is the most
impressive I've seen yeah there's just a
phenotype you guys it's labeled abd it's
an easy thing that's just the blue dream
that's everywhere yeah it's all over
Colorado oh I'm pretty sure it's the one
i bred - yeah but the blue dream kicks
out you can pull two pounds under a
thousand watt light and soil with that
blue dream Co easily with a short short
veg time we did a one with a real short
veg time last year outdoors that did
like three and a half pounds but the
problem is it doesn't have an appealing
hi to me and it doesn't make enough hash
to make it worth its time space energy
nutrients whatever else you know what I
mean I could replace that with a Bounty
Killer and have way better medicine if
it smelled like it
or if it tasted like it smelled would be
the most popular strain in the world
yeah my going to hit it with the
Grateful dog was to put that resin on it
it worked it definitely worked it made
it i shortened the flowering time it
made the plants a little stockier and it
put some resin and a little bit of funk
to it which is what all that's all that
blue dream was missing was resin and
funk and it was getting too tall for a
lot of indoor grows I bet the DJ short
came out of I mean hit anything with his
stuff's always seems to be really
dominant a lot you know it says a lot
for his breeding it's because he's
taking it to the five before he releases
his packages which is pretty impressive
and he has a style of his own I've heard
him argue with many people on podcasts
and interviews yes you know a couple of
minutes ago I dissed the old generation
DJ shorten is the old generation bro we
got to give him mad love oh he's one of
the guys back in the day that was doing
it right for genetics if it weren't for
DJ Shore I don't think you and I would
be where we are in the cannabis game no
I don't think anyone would be
I mean yeah DJ's done a lot for the
preservation and just everything it's I
might be a brick in the wall but DJ's
short was part of the foundation oh yeah
cornerstone yes it's up there with some
of the original authors and stuff like
that guys like that yeah
I'll get some cool mad credit also he's
not as old as sub cool or as DJ short
but he's in that generation between them
between us and DJ gotta give him mad
love for his breeding and for what you
did for the community also since we're
chef first readers yeah and if we're
gonna go with old guys you guys know I'm
gonna say it
soma deserves a high five okay so what
taught me how to grow on og I did not
know anything about I'd never I read so
most posts but I never realized he was a
dreadlock and I never knew he was a
dirty hippie and I didn't know we had
amethyst everywhere and crystals on
everything I figured he was an Indian
dude the country India yeah and my
friend Donovan one day who was a big
user of overgrown calm
he was always on there and one day he's
like bro you remind me so much of so my
the way that you talk because I was
preaching my Grove from your heart
theory you know what I mean you own your
grow room and I still think this you
gotta go in a grow room once in a while
and just sit there and just meditate and
just close your eyes and think about the
goodness that those plants are gonna do
because you're growing a plant that is
going to heal somebody in some sort of
way they're gonna feel better even if
they're a recreational smoker if they're
a medical smoker somebody is gonna be
uplifted and better because of the
product that you're growing and that's
got to feel good inside so I go in there
and kind of meditate a little bit on
that and feel that golden we'd share it
the plants learn me I love them and then
they heal somebody else and that person
hugs me when they see me the next time
they go do that then I get to go grow
better we because I just got a good hug
and it just perpetuates this golden
cycle so I was talking about that exact
hippie [ __ ] that I just said and my
buddies like dude you're like [ __ ]
soma it was like a person read his post
and he's like no go get his book and I
went got his book and I was like this
guy is who I was going to be in 20 years
if I didn't know I was already on the
path of being soma so much respect we
just got off on a random tangent he
didn't know two organic
before any of y'all thought of as cool
as it is no one's doing nothing new
there
true yes I built for my kids I built him
out of Rubbermaid containers but I used
the same you know principle with the
drainage do you think I can support 99%
of what psalmist says sub cool I love
his growing style sometimes he says some
shoot that I'm not gonna put my
signature on yeah I don't I don't
discredit that the dude's got [ __ ]
integrity he's made a lot of strains and
he was one of the first people to take
good pictures with a good camera buds
and send him into High Times anybody
that's followed me on Facebook since the
beginning knows without any saying that
[ __ ] sub cool inspired 50 percent of
my photography that's a gross style or
style like the whole thing I didn't know
that until someone's like you should
check out the weed nerd knows like okay
there's a lot to learn in some of his
older episodes if you're interested in
the way he does things yeah sub cool on
the youtubes the you to buy some weed
nerds the weed nerd yeah check that out
the older stuff is really good there
came a point when it got to be too
redundant redundant and he had maybe
even yeah even he knows he says it all
the time - a hundred episodes and
there's only so much you could talk
about about cannabis you know what I
mean like there's always news and stuff
so that's why I fall to the news
sometimes but it's going to be now that
once we get to episode 100 we're gonna
go a little more in depth I've gone
through the basics and now it's time to
dig in a little bit I think our friends
our listeners periscope I think that's a
really great tool for a podcast okay so
I've been opening periscope and doing
random [ __ ] on there occasionally but
now that we've got this good foundation
you guys have had your basic rudimentary
classes I think it's almost time around
episode 100 to start pushing it and
start going to the B level courses we're
in a college level you guys here pretty
soon okay Sean back you'll have to get
out the notepad again we're gonna do
real ones so we're gonna wrap this part
up we've been doing for a long time dude
Jesse thanks for coming man oh yeah no
problem
oh let's see let's do outdoor update
real quick okay here lately in southern
collar
at least it has been cold and humid at
night and hot and dry during the day
yeah that is a recipe for powdery mold
so bud rot it's part of the reason Cali
bud stands out and they get a marine
layer with this too but you know this
year I've seen some a lot of Cali style
or what I always call Cali style
problems that we've never had here
before so be prepared for that stuff how
can we prevent getting powdery mildew
with these crispy cold nights that we're
getting there's a lot of moisture in the
air tonight yeah yeah there's I mean any
number of things
I'm personally using AK teen ovate I
mean we're in bloom too but it's you
know that's I see it on the cucumbers I
see it on the squash I see it on the
watermelon that's a different strain it
doesn't really affect cannabis from what
I've seen and been told but to me it's
an indication that the the climate for
to grow is oh yeah this presence yes I
can't speak on that now but in the next
within the next thirty days I am going
to become what is called applicator
certified by the Department of
Agriculture nice my cousin's up yeah
it's it seems I've looked at the test it
seems to be fairly easy it's an
open-book test somebody that works I'm
now the lead grower myself and my friend
John are now the lead growers at the
spot dispensary and today we had our
first pre inspection from the Department
of Agriculture before we grow anything
in there in our new grill areas Wow
dude it's I've only been out of the
industry for what nine months and Wow
things have changed yes yes you have to
have Department of Agriculture meetings
there's about an hour and a half long
meeting they told us basically what we
need to do to be compliant which is it's
all basic stuff and it's mostly since
the spot was designed well it's [ __ ]
that we're already doing but you have to
have one at least one person on the
staff that can train employees on a
pesticide and insecticide and fungicide
safety
yeah and so I took it upon myself to say
hey I'm lead grower I'll go do this and
it's the boss is gonna pay for it of
course cuz it's a work-related thing and
it's something that I feel like I should
do anyway like when they offered that
course I was like I want to go to this I
want to go to this yeah okay yeah that's
that's great man within 30 days I will I
have to take those two spot - I know
some owners would be really pissed about
having to do [ __ ] like this right you've
heard of you got yes I can make money in
the cannabis industry you guys yeah it
is hard to survive right now if you
don't have some money to put in
inventory if your shelves aren't stocked
with 20 different kinds of buds if your
shelves aren't stocked with 20 different
kinds of edibles for different topicals
a lollipop over here some t-shirts over
here socks over here you guys got a
filter Chinese water pipes yeah yeah
good water pipes Chinese water pipes
knock off nails high-end yeah shut up -
Three Rivers organics I got some cool
hitman [ __ ] in there wow your eyes are
really red only seeing short sentences
all right my red and my shirt yet pretty
close nice back to the outdoors let's go
but yeah activate Green cure I don't
really see that as a preventative but if
you do use it make sure you use it at
night and follow the directions one of
you know there's all kinds of stuff you
can be spraying on it just get it get a
good one to stay away from neem oil
since it's all your plant should be in
bloom yeah I was gifted a product called
stylin oil I've heard of it
I did a consultation and somebody an
older gentleman who is not as
able-bodied as most of us he's a little
he's a little slower he might call in
handicapped
he's trying to grow his own cannabis
it's his first grow that's the second
growth and I give him a free
consultation
and he had just the starts of powdery
mildew and I was like man I and he was
in
about starting week three of flower and
I like man I don't really want you to
spray anything on there but you're gonna
lose your crop if you don't and he said
I googled some stuff and they say oils
and things and I said don't put neem oil
on there I said put some worm casting
tea on there the world didn't do a damn
thing that's most definitely preventive
yeah [ __ ] so I told him I said well
you're gonna his crop is gonna be [ __ ]
because the powdery mildew was getting
it wasn't thick but you could see it
popping up into little circles ooh and
so I said you know I've got a product
called stylin oil that I've never used
and a friend of mine sent it to me to
encourage me to use it and he said that
it will destroy powdery mildew on
contact and he says spray it on there
and he's an old dude I said this is your
medicine that you and he said yes I know
I need this spray that on there he knew
what I was doing and it was it was his
decision I sprayed the stylet oil on
there dude that [ __ ] took down the
powdery mildew on contact it destroyed
it nice I've never actually used it I've
heard you can burn the [ __ ] out some
plants with it absolutely that's one of
the things a guy named I don't know if I
should say his real name he's known as
tree town is what I know him as a tree
town farmer he's the one that
recommended this to me and hooked me up
with a vendor for the product of course
he's like check this out so uh I didn't
well I didn't have anything to use it on
in my grows like I didn't have any
mildew or anything like that so when
this dude was like I got powdery mildews
like this is what I've got to offer you
and something about the way that it
coats the leaves it causes it breaks the
membrane of the powdery mildew and it
doesn't allow it to grow on your leaf is
basically what I read and when that [ __ ]
hit the leaf it just washed it right off
we do it with the lights off turn the
lights off just turn in normal yeah as
you should with most pesticides actually
with any with any spray you want the
lighter RFU that you actually need the
lights on but sometimes you need to heat
the room up do yeah yeah that's what the
deal is
yeah actually need to heat the room to
activate the oils and the plants so well
we sprayed it with the the the stylet
oil and then let it sit overnight and
then we went back the next morning and
rinsed the stylet oil off with just
clean while
also very important yes the most
pesticides yes you want to unclog the
plants they want to be able to breathe
so don't rinse that [ __ ] off and then
dude those plants just came out of it
and they're amazing nice yeah you got to
harvest his crop this was several weeks
ago he got to harvest his crop I looked
at it I helped him trim something I
showed him how to trim it
no signs of powdery mildew gorgeous
crops smelled pretty good I haven't
smoked any of it so I don't know if it
tastes like stylet oil but he's an older
cat he's been he's like your dad you
know just needs a bunch of herb to smoke
so he doesn't get hurt what what is mine
stylin oil I think that's a hybrid it's
you know I don't have it in this room I
should have had it handy before I
brought it up but I wasn't prepared for
that so fail on my part oil yeah I did
some research on it once and I said
white it's not it's not colored white
it's just considered a white oil it's
not thick and white or anything nice
yeah when I heard about it it was kind
of pre Amazon times I just couldn't get
my hands on it yeah it's it's available
now and it's cheap it's actually quite
affordable so smooth as a preventative
as an outdoor if you need to rescue
something it's something you could look
into and drink your if you hit it just
right we'll we'll take care of a light
infestation but it's kind of touchy too
right it's anything when you're in the
flowering phase and applying a foliar
spray of any type is a touchy so such de
leafing just removing the leaf of and
taking it out of the area washing your
hands don't touch them when they're when
it's wet that's actually I've been told
it spreads easier at that point so okay
that's something I've been told so I
would believe it I haven't been able to
put that to work too much but yeah I
haven't had a need to if you've got
powdery mildew in your grow room you've
got something to correct in the room and
you've got some work to do it's gonna
take you a little bit to fix that you
cannot spray away that problem yeah
there's an environmental problem gotta
clean it you get started getting fresh
air out of the refresher into the room
stealer out of the room lower the
humidity but if you get it all so don't
feel bad I mean it can even happen
outdoors happens yeah yeah I was talked
about having it in a grow
it happened the first time I moved into
a new house it was August when I moved
in so it was warm and then that first
winter crop I got powdery mildew was in
the back corner of the room because it
was the concrete basement walls drastic
climate change season changes yes easier
to run that room in the fall probably
wasn't prepared for that
yeah mildew boom experience don't I've
been told that when I talk about powdery
mold and both of us have been told that
we make people feel bad so don't feel
bad if it happens now you guys the
person at the store told me that it's
because I just don't take pictures nails
you never take a picture your poops do
you post the gold on Instagram so don't
worry you guys I will I'll [ __ ]
something up and post a picture of it on
Instagram just for fun no it's just to
show you that roster Geoff [ __ ] up
good some folks recently no [ __ ] happens
the next time I make a mistake I'll get
out the camera and I'll own that [ __ ]
this is my dumbness right when I get
lazy straight into the floor only a
couple of gallons of water but still
when you hear that [ __ ] overflow just
totally focused on what I was doing and
I heard oh [ __ ] you just sit there and
you feel like a slow kid have to take
the short bus to work tomorrow after
this [ __ ] I was with some people that uh
in the early days we were Phil and
Reza's and took off to lunch and went to
the bar had a couple beers came back two
and a half hours later and water was
still running
it was luckily it was a big like an old
mechanic shop just a big steel building
with a roll-up door on one side this was
still real early days it was most
definitely Trap House worthy but uh it
was a early legal girl it was fun we
just roll up the door and I was a blast
back then yeah back in the day you could
do all kinds of dumb [ __ ] that you can
do no [ __ ]
smoked in the grove while your girl like
we had our grow and our dispensary was
attached they were one floor was the
grow one floor was the dispensary and so
I would be I'd have we had a camera of
course with the monitor up there so I
could just look at the monitor and hear
the doorbell so I've been water similar
situation smoking a fat joint just water
plants living my life got reggae on and
then you hear the doorbell just run
downstairs I wouldn't even put up the
joint I've seen barefoot and shirtless
felons working in a felons running them
with like little hippie drawings and
colors like my girlfriend did it and
[ __ ] because that's how it was done
there was nothing printed on a printer
back in the day there's no bar code on
any weed product it was all just grown
in someone's basement or upstairs from
the from the dispensary then trimming
that brought right immediately to the
grow or to the dispensary put in a jar
and sold and just what do you mean we
had some weed just surviving it money
and despite all that certain shops still
just boom had the fire I used to be
better I do I think it is the dispensary
grows a lot of the growers grow was like
honest I used to grow I worked at madam
our dispensary I was the manager my
friend Tom was the owner I was the
manager right underneath him
Tom handed me the keys one day and he
was like here you got a dispensary have
fun he paid me very well so I've worked
at this dispensary and I would grow
cherry widow at home in my own home Russ
and then I would take that cherry widow
to the shop and sell it to the boss for
a decent price put it on the shelf and
that was the most fire we we had in
there that week all right podcast rolled
I want to thank you guys for joining
Jesse and I on this lovely Thursday I
will be back Monday with a regular
episode now the show's over you guys
please go to iTunes go to the iTunes
Store search for the girl from your
heart a podcast give me a 5 star rating
and type in a comment and let me know
what you think about the show I would
love to hear your opinion when you give
us stars on iTunes that makes more
people see the show and of course the
more people see the show the more people
will grow better cannabis more people
will become cannabis activists more
people will fight for the plant the
will become legalized worldwide and we
will not have to hide ourselves anymore
all right
so please give me a five star rating let
me know what you think I definitely
appreciate it
um if you've got something to say find
me on social media you know we're on
Facebook we are on Twitter on Facebook
it's a girl from your heart on Twitter
it's @gf wih podcast we do have an email
address it's grow from your heart at
hotmail.com be sure to follow I region
etics on Instagram we are almost to
18,000 followers I'd love for you to be
one of them
you guys don't forget that the show is
available on iTunes the show is
available on stitcher and every single
episode is always and forever archived
on I read genetics Colorado calm you
guys I want to thank you for listening
to this long rambling Thursday episode
Jesse and I talked for a long time I
thought you guys would want to hear a
bunch of it so I put it out as a
Thursday episode let me know what you
think
all right big shot it's my ninja Spence
thanks again for listening until next
time take a phat dad and give your mom a
hug form
you