[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 93 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right if you're a
new grower is your professional grower
if you're a new smoker or a veteran a
bird secure cannabis activists or even
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff thanks again for joining me as
always I need to send a huge thank you
shout out to my friends in the mystic
roots band for letting me use their
music on my show big thanks to Kat ku
and the entire mystic roots crew hope
everybody's having a great day I'm
coming to you on a Thursday evening
it has finally cooled down a little bit
it's almost 9 o'clock it's been hot as
[ __ ] all day it's been hard to cool down
today so I'm excited for a little bit of
coolness I hope you're getting a little
bit of sweet weather so that your grow
room is not going crazy these hot temps
have everybody struggling it's almost
over you guys the fall is coming it will
cool down I'm looking forward to it so
we don't have any sponsors this week you
guys but we do have some good news let's
just jump right into it I hardly ever
have like news that we want to celebrate
on the podcast and this is definitely
some news worth celebrating I just have
to make my computer cooperate here we go
I'm getting to the news article that I
want to read um this is a great headline
this an article comes from the cannabis
it is written by summer Ballantine and
the headline says Jeff Maz in ski
sentenced to life for pot freed from
Missouri prison that's right this dude
spent 20 years in prison for cannabis
and he has been released from prison
this picture of him shows him with a
big-ass smile the dude looks happy to be
out of prison who wouldn't be so I've
got a huge article here let's just get
right into it and make this podcast get
down to business here we go I'm looking
for the article because my computer is
pissing me off here we go alright
it says Jeff Mezvinsky sentenced to life
for pot freed from Missouri prison he
says I spent a third of my life in
prison
it's a shame now i 62 after serving 20
years of a life sentence without parole
for
nonviolent marijuana related convict
convictions the article says from
Jefferson City Missouri a man sentenced
to life in prison without parole on a
marijuana related charge was was freed
Tuesday from Missouri prison after being
behind bars for two decades a period in
which the nation's attitudes toward pot
have steadily softened family friends
supporters and reporters flocked to meet
Jeff Minsky as he stepped out of the
Jefferson City Correctional Center into
a sunny morning wearing a pair of white
tennis shoes and a shirt that read I'm
Jeff and I'm free I want a shirt that
says I'm Jeff and I'm free
I mean I'm Jeff and I'm free [ __ ] will
keep going it says he says I spent a
third of my life in prison said
mizanskey now 62 who was greeted by his
infant great-granddaughter
it's a shame after a breakfast of steak
and eggs with family Lozinski said he
planned to spend his post prison life
seeking a job in advocating for the
legalization of marijuana
he criticized sentencing for some
drug-related crimes is unfair and
described his time behind bars as hell
his release followed years of lobbying
by relatives lawmakers and others who
argue that the sentence was too stiff
and that marijuana should not be
forbidden Basinski was sinced in 1996
the same year California became the
first state to legalize marijuana for
medical purposes medical marijuana is
now legal in 23 states and recreational
marijuana has been legalized in Alaska
Colorado Oregon Washington State and
Washington DC the reason he's getting
out is because the public clearly has
changed it's changed its opinion about
marijuana and it's just one of many ways
in which that has been reflected in
recent years said Mo's in skis attorney
Dan meets such extreme cases should
further feel changing perceptions of
nonviolent drug crime sent Michelle
deach a senior lecturer at the lyndon b
johnson School of Public Affairs at the
University of Austin at Texas that's a
long title geez school john lyndon b
johnson School of Public Affairs at the
University of Austin Texas I'm glad I
don't have to say that [ __ ] in my title
every day I say hi I'm Rasta Jeff so
much easier the article says these cases
really become Exhibit A and the need for
sentencing reform said D I think that's
how you said that an attorney and expert
in criminal justice policy just last
year the heavily Republican Missouri
legislature passed a law
to allow certain people of epsilen
epilepsy to seek treatment with the
marijuana extracting extract containing
little of the chemical that causes
marijuana users to feel high and larger
amounts of a chemical called Kenna
cannabidiol or CBD the patients can
include babies Veet said nobody saw that
coming he said that's a pretty radical
statement police said he conspired to
sell six pounds of marijuana to a dealer
connected with the Mexican drug cartels
at the time the life with no parole
sentences was allowed under a Missouri
law for repeat drug offenders mizanskey
already had to drug convention
convictions one for possession and one
for sale of marijuana in 1984 and
another for possessing possession in
1991 he was the only Missouri inmate
serving such a sentence for a
non-violent marijuana related offense
when Democratic governor jay Nixon
agreed in May to commute his sentence
the commutation allowed mizanskey to
argue for his freedom before a parole
board which granted his request in
August
Nixon Nixon's actions are a reflection
of political confidence in changing
norms around marijuana use said Cecilia
clincal a criminal justice policy expert
at the University of Wisconsin law
school the governor cited mizanskey 's
nonviolent record noting that none of
his offenses involved selling drugs to
children the law under which he was
originally sentenced has since been
changed other states are reevaluating
punishment for drug possession crimes
motivated in large in large part by the
high cost of imprisoning low-level
nonviolent offenders you guys imagine
how much it cost to keep this dude in
prison for twenty years we could have
sent people to it cost more money to
send people to prison for years than it
does to send somebody to college is what
I recently read we probably could've
send three or four he was in there for
twenty years probably could've sent five
or ten people to college for the cost
that it cost to house him and nothing
came of it maybe maybe in the long term
he will affect people being released
maybe he did some good I think that's
called a martyr is that what he was
maybe he was a martyr so maybe it was
worth it for the movement but not for
him and not for you no but they could
have [ __ ] educated some people for
this cost I'm gonna keep reading my
article here it says in Connecticut a
new law will make possession of small
amounts of hard drugs including heroin
cocaine and crack cocaine a misdemeanor
for a first-time offense rather than
allowing for the current maximum
seven year prison sentence Nebraska and
Alabama expect to save hundreds of
millions of dollars by using new laws to
cut down on the number of offenders
locked up for possessing small amounts
of drugs in Missouri backers of two
ballot initiatives to legalize pot have
permission from the Secretary of State
to begin collecting signatures to put
the issue before voters in 2016
another petition proposes reducing
sentences for nonviolent drug offenders
who were serving time without
opportunity for parole mizanskey said he
will not smoke marijuana now that he's
free he's on parole after all but if it
ever becomes legal on the state and
federal level mizanskey said definitely
so big congratulations welcome home I
think he's gonna help out the movement
if they're releasing one guy why aren't
they gonna start releasing all of the
people who are in jail anybody that
committed any nonviolent cannabis crime
I think they should all just start
releasing them just go and lock the cage
and let those dudes out and I'm a joint
and a hundred bucks and sent them on
their way all right
that's uh my good news that is my good
news I do have some other good news this
is article number two this one comes
from the cannabis also I have to give
you a little ketchup story behind this
recently let me see if they tell you in
this okay there was recently a bunch of
marijuana products in Colorado that were
taken off of the shelves because they
were suspected of having been produced
with cannabis that had been sprayed with
pesticides that are banned from the
marijuana production laws we have what's
called the marijuana Enforcement
Division and they have made laws in
conjunction with the Department of
Agriculture to regulate the sprays that
can be put on these plants so recently
on the first a bunch of these edibles
and products were taken off of shelves
because they were suspected to have been
made with contaminated cannabis I had
that article planned to read to you when
I opened up my computer today and went
reading for news and seeing what was
going on the cannabis has posted this
article and it says update Denver pot
products passed pesticide test hold
lifted so I'm gonna say that one more
time just to make it clear a denver pot
products passed pesticide test and the
has been lifted the sub-headline says
marijuana products from mountain high
suckers and MMJ America showed no trace
of an unapproved pesticide did among
their ingredients the company owners
said they were using old labeling so
here we go
now this articles by David McCoy from
The Denver Post I found it on the
cannabis and it goes like this Denver
Health officials Wednesday lifted a day
old order to hold hundreds of marijuana
infused lozenges and raw marijuana from
two businesses after lab tests showed no
trace of unapproved pesticides did among
their ingredients the owners of Mountain
High suckers and MMJ America each said
they had been using old labels they
included among their ingredients a
pesticide that today is not approved for
marijuana use the pesticide spinosad had
not been barred for use when the labels
were made the owner said it looks like
this was just an unfortunate labeling
issue said dan roland denver spokesman
for its office for its office of
marijuana policy sorry for my stumble
there a state law requires marijuana
companies to list on their product
labels all pesticides contaminates and
herbicides used in the production
process the city's enforcement action is
the latest in a series of actions
related to pesticides used on
recreational and medical marijuana
because the drug remains illegal under
federal law the US Environmental
Protection Agency will not establish any
allowable pesticide uses on marijuana
technically no regulated pesticide can
be legally used on marijuana but state
agriculture officials have said as long
as its use does not violate it
pesticides label warnings and
restrictions it can be used on Monday
Denver Warren businesses that products
listing of unapproved pesticides should
be removed from shelves and destroyed or
returned to the manufacturer inspectors
ordered tests on the product holds
Tuesday after spotting spinosad listed
among other ingredients of mountain
highs lozenges and raw marijuana at MMJ
America shop on a rapaho Street excuse
me the test did not detect spinosad city
officials confirmed mountain-high had
been using old labels from when it
purchased marijuana trimming from a
grower that had been using spinosad
mountain-high co-owner Chad Tribble said
that was before the state said it could
not he said back then it wasn't a
problem Tribble said
he just didn't look back on the labels
it was a mistake it was on there but the
tests were clear undetected we've never
had a black mark before now said now he
said news of the city's action brought
calls from as far as Las Vegas not only
did we test negative for all pesticides
we were told by the city that just
crossing off the name because we're
already had the bags printed was
acceptable MMJ owner Jake Salazar
that's what MMG owner Jake Salazar said
officials later told him he needs to
reprint the labels we ordered
pre-printed bags 70,000 units every time
last time we ordered them this wasn't a
banned substance we now have to throw
all of those bags away and reorder
70,000 more without that ingredient
which we clearly don't use Salazar said
the state's list of pesticides approved
for use on marijuana has been in the
drafting stage for about 18 months the
state will not say the pesticides are
safe for use on marijuana only that
their use does not violate label
restrictions on how they should be used
some pesticides are so non-toxic that
the EPA does not require them to be
registered nor restrict their use those
can be used on marijuana but the
industry has complained that they aren't
potent enough to eradicate the kinds of
pests in mildews that can decimate a
crop potentially worth millions of
dollars the city in the spring held more
than 100,000 marijuana plants at 11 grow
operations over concerns that unapproved
pesticides had been used on them so this
article was from David McCoy and those
products did not test for spinosad they
were using old labels now this really
sparks a little bit of question in my
mind because I advocate spinosad I like
spinosad I've used a spinosad recently
so this has me thinking I need to go in
here and go to the Department of
Agriculture website and figure out why
or whichever website it is it may be the
meed
I need to go and figure out why I'm not
allowed to use spinosad because I run a
shop I run a grow at a shop I need to
find this list of pesticides I'm not
quite sure where I find this list of
pesticides I'm sure that the operations
manager at the dispensary has it so I
asked him for that list we're not at
that point yet so I don't need to know
that but I'm sure the marijuana
Enforcement Division webpage has a list
of approved
or unapproved pesticides all we got to
do is go there and look I really want to
know why spinosad has been banned cuz I
use that quite quite often I will
definitely figure out why because
something that will help prevent this um
every dispensary will now be required to
Train all plant handlers in pesticide
management everybody every dispensary
needs on staff one person that can train
every new employee on pesticide safety
and to be able to train them you have to
be certified by the Department of
Agriculture you have to take an
applicator safety test and I have been
required to do that since I am the lead
grower at this spot dispensary so I will
be taking I will be studying and taking
that test and then I will know a lot of
stuff about pesticides and we will find
out why spinosad is unacceptable um the
Department of Agriculture representative
actually told me the reason that Eagle
20 is not allowed in commercial grows
drumroll please because when it burns it
turns into cyanide that's what the guy
from the Department of Agriculture told
me it had nothing to do with the danger
and toxicity of the chemical it was
actually because when it turns if
there's a fire it turns into cyanide and
the fire department doesn't want to deal
with that I found that rather
interesting all right guys I have got
one more news article this one is from
local news here this one comes from the
beautiful city of Pueblo Colorado I
talked a little bit about Pueblo last
time on the last episode talking about
how Colorado and Pueblo in general was
booming with cannabis and Pueblo
Colorado may become the may already be
the new Emerald triangle so this article
says funding college scholarships via
pot grows proposed in southern Colorado
so the headline says gosh excuse my
throat I'm gonna take a drink before we
even get into this I'm gonna take a
drink and then I'm gonna take a DAB
alright that was a good drink excuse the
throat-clearing on the podcast I
probably won't even edit that so I'm
sorry so far there's no editing to be
done in this show and I like it I'm
getting a DAB ready you guys I'm getting
ready some amnesia haze from our friends
at Colorado's best dads I'm about to
take a fat chunky dab I'm getting it
going I hope you guys are gonna take a
dab with me on the podcast if you listen
in to the show get a DAB ready get a
ball ready if you're at work or
something sneak your vape pen out let's
do it you guys let's get stoned together
on the count of six four five six that's
how we do it we take dads in the middle
of the podcast we used to smoke so much
more hash on this show I've been trying
to get it a little tighter and not be
dad the [ __ ] out it also helps my throat
last longer all right so well yeah
that's Anita Hayes from Colorado's best
dads and it makes my head [ __ ] spin
it's so great he gets me amped up that
makes me lively hypothetically if I were
going to come home on my lunch break and
smoke a bunch of dads and need to go
back to work all energized and in the
zone hypothetically I would take four
dabs of that and I'd be in the [ __ ]
zone when I went back to work all right
before I get on to this next news
article I am going to mention that I am
recording this podcast live on periscope
what up all my friends on periscope
thanks for watching
if you guys don't know what periscope is
make sure you or don't make sure but
please I invite you to use your Android
device or your iPhone device or your
Apple device and download an app called
periscope and then look for me I'm Ross
- Jeff 420 easy to find look for me on
there follow me and usually daily I will
do a DAB on periscope with my friends
you'll get a chance to ask me a question
and I will rant for several minutes on
your question if it gets my brain going
so check me out on periscope you guys
big shout out to everybody that's
watching on periscope right now what up
Nemo Punk what up El Diablo I can't see
who else is on there unless they send a
comment or something but what ups
everybody that's on there thanks for
joining me I hope you will join me on my
next periscope video sometimes I
randomly decide that I want to put the
podcast on periscope while I'm doing it
and right now it's kind of cool because
I feel like I'm talking to somebody
there's somebody just someone to look at
instead of just staring into the
computer over here I'm looking at my
periscope friends I can't see them but
it feels like they're there all right
I've got another news article up on the
screen I took a DAB and got all [ __ ]
ad D in sidetracked but shout out the
dabs let's read this article I read the
headline right funding caller funding
college scholarships via pot grows
proposed in southern Colorado the sub
headline says Pablo County Commissioner
Sal pate says he hopes the measure that
would Institute a five percent excise
tax on wholesale marijuana transfers
will give webelo kids a boost I am going
to read this article
I have mixed opinions on this right now
but it's by Jesse Paul it's from the
Denver Post I of course found it on our
favorite news website the cannabis you
guys I don't bring you all of the news I
select a few I pick and choose what I
think is best for the audience if you
don't get enough news from me I can
definitely recommend the cannabis high
quality cannabis news it's ran by a dude
named ricardo Baca who was a really cool
dude I support that [ __ ] go check it out
if you don't get enough from me
alright the article goes like this a
public county commissioner is proposing
a ballot measure for a program to fund
college scholarships through a marijuana
excise tax commissioner Sal pace says he
hopes the new measure will give webelo
kids a boost and help fight college debt
the County Commission is set to vote at
their Monday meeting on whether or not
the proposal will be placed on November
ballot elections the excise tax would be
levied when marijuana is transferred
from cultivation to a store paces office
said in a news release Wednesday he said
that Wednesday sorry I read that really
weird pueblos counties perfect economic
and weather conditions have created a
boom of recreational cultivations
without yet generating a tax on these
grows beginning in 2017 graduating
seniors from all high schools and
pueblos who attend a public college or
university in Pueblo County will be
eligible for scholarships from the
proposed program that release said every
kid deserves an opportunity to succeed
they said in a statement
Pablo County has potential new tax
revenue from a marijuana industry that
can benefit the kids of pueblos the
ballot measure would propose a 5% excise
tax on recreational marijuana grows from
Pueblo County it asks that on an annual
basis
no less than 50% of tax revenue be
designated for scholarships 50% well if
you're doing it for this shouldn't 100
where's the other 50 going Sal where is
the other 50% going okay the rest of the
revenue would be used on community
projects like Colorado State Fairs
streetscape refurbishment medical
marijuana academic research and a
feasibility study on the potential
connection of Amtrak south on track
Southwest Chief to Pueblo and those all
sound like feasible options those seem
like they're worth some investment the
program may be expanded in future years
depending on revenue that really said
Tyler Hinson president president of the
Colorado cannabis Chamber of Commerce
said he hopes the chin the County
Commission will fully examine the
measure before sending it to the ballot
under amendment 64 we gave local
governments two permission to make these
excise taxes he said I would just
caution the county commissioners to look
at how this will affect sales in Pueblo
and be surrounding areas that's the
first thing I think of they're gonna add
5% more tax the tax is already really
high in Pueblo it's approximately 25
percent I don't know the exact
percentage to tell you the truth guys if
anybody on periscope maybe an emo Punk
if you want to throw up the actual
percentage of tax I'll say that on the
air and I'll give you a shout-out also
make sure you guys follow my friend Nemo
Punk 15 on Twitter he posts a lot of
great cannabis [ __ ] seventeen and a half
percent plus the ten percent excise tax
that already exists so that's 27 percent
plus they're going to add another five
which will make it 32 percent excise tax
so this extra excise tax is just gonna
end up falling on the customer in the
end no matter how it works which is
going to make cannabis tax 32 percent
here in Pueblo which means it's gonna be
roughly 185 dollars for a quarter of
cannabis which is ridiculous when you
can go to the street and you can get
probably you can get an ounce for that
price on the street you can get an ounce
for $200 you can get outs for one
hundred and fifty dollars on the street
in Pueblo Colorado so this is going to
turn around and put everybody back at
the black-market
they're just gonna ruin it they're
trying to squeeze too much blood out of
one turnip i think is what my grandma
used to said trying to squeeze blood out
of a turnip
I think I think that's what these guys
are trying to do and they're gonna crash
the whole marijuana thing alright guys I
think that's enough podcast for this
week I'm gonna wrap this up I'm gonna go
see fish this weekend so when I come
back on Monday I will have a lot of cool
[ __ ] to talk about I want to thank you
guys for listening to another episode I
want to thank all my friends on
periscope for joining me thanks an emo
Punk thanks to El Diablo thanks to all
my friends that are on there we don't
have any sponsors this week if you'd
like to sponsor the podcast send me an
email it's girl from your heart at
hotmail.com we'll get you all the
information that you do need you can
sponsor the show oh you guys now that
the show is over please go to iTunes go
to the iTunes Store search for a girl
from your heart give me a 5 star rating
please 5 stars that'd be really cool and
then type in a little comment let me
know what you think about the show and I
will read your comments on a future
episode I love hearing what people have
to say about the show so um yeah once
you guys follow me on all the social
media sites please find me on Facebook
it's grow from your heart find me on
Twitter it's at g f YH podcast don't
forget you guys the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is available on I read genetics Colorado
com if you want to follow follow me on
Instagram dude it's a tyree genetics I
should be at 18,000 followers by the
time you check it out I hope that you
can be one of those 18,000 followers I
don't have a lot else to say so I'm
gonna wrap up the show and go take some
fat dabs only give a big shout out to
manager Spence thanks again for
listening until next time take a phat
dab and give your mom a hug for me
[Music]