[Music]
yeah welcome back into this community it
is time for episode number 95 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation try to fear a new grower if
you're a professional grower if you're a
new smoker or a veteran dabber if you're
a cannabis activists or if you're just
someone who's curious about the current
state of cannabis this my friends is the
podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I want to thank you guys for
joining the show as always and you just
send a huge thank you shout out to my
friends animistic roots band for
allowing me to use their music on the
show big shout out to Kat too
mystic roots crew what's up guys I'm
gonna turn down this music that was a
little bit loud this time I apologize
for that I do not have any ads for this
show but I do want to give a shout out
to all my friends that joined me for the
reggae show a couple of days ago um on
Tuesday I got to go up to the Fillmore
auditorium in Denver Colorado and I got
to see Morgan Heritage Taurus Riley
Stephen Marley and Damian Marley it was
a great show
lots of reggae lots of good vibes lots
of love lots of ganja smokin big shout
out to our knee and reveille for being
great friends they join me up there we
had a great time at the show and also
big shout out to Danielle for being a
great reggae date also big shout out to
Rasta Stevie what's up brother it was
great seeing you there I think sometimes
you might listen to the podcast all
right you guys I've got a couple of
things coming up in this episode we're
going to address an email that was sent
to me from a friend he wants to talk
about something I said in the episode
about bagged seeds so we will discuss
that but first I want to read a news
article that just came out this article
came out on September 16th I found it in
the cannabis of course this article was
written by David McCoy and Ricardo Baca
and the article headline says Colorado
AG examining pot industry use of organic
term sub-headline says because marijuana
is illegal under federal law the use of
the term organic is federally regulated
the state licensed cannabis business
can't be certified as organic no matter
their practices I'm gonna turn up my
headphones just a little bit and then I
will read this article for you and
phone's allowed enough here we go Mic
Check headphones that's much better all
right the article goes like this
Colorado's Attorney General is
investigating several marijuana
businesses over concerns the word
organic in their names or advertising
might be misleading to consumers the
office is reviewing complaints from the
from the consumers that the merchants
have been misrepresenting their product
when they say organic or organically
grown said Roger Hudson spokesman for
state attorney general cynthia coffman
we're looking for information inside
those complaints to make a determination
on what those next steps are is it
consumer fraud is it criminal the agz
office would not give more detail on the
scope of the investigation but a lawyer
who
a marijuana business contacted by
investigators said it appears to have
limits the inquiry includes grow
operations some with organic in their
names recently caught up in Denver
quarantines over pesticide concern
concerns attorney Sean McAllister said
sorry guys I read that statement a
little bit oddly but you caught what I
said
or what it said the AG is ensuring that
business is ensuring that businesses
that use the word are at least
consistent with the concept of organic
McAllister said because marijuana is
illegal under federal law and use of the
term organic is federally regulated a
licensed cannabis business cannot be
certified as organic no matter its
practices as such no marijuana
businesses in Colorado can technically
use the word in its name or in selling
its product according to officials and
industry insiders potential fraud
penalties under the Colorado consumer
protection act include fines of up to
$10,000 per violation Federal Rules say
that businesses wrongly selling a
product as organic could face fines of
up to $10,000
yet those rules have not been enforced
in Colorado's marijuana businesses until
now state marijuana license records show
that twenty nine businesses growers
retailers and dispensaries use the word
organic in their name some use a trade
name containing the word organic to
market marijuana products or use the
term or do use the term in their
advertise a spot check of websites by
the Denver Post found businesses
claiming to sell 100% organic cannabis
offering organic treatments of medical
marijuana or use only organic methods to
produce their product some shops
describe their product as grown in
organic soil or that they use organic
growing techniques another website touts
certification or of organic standards
and testing that mirrors the US
Department of Agriculture organic
certification Brook Weis owner of the
growing kitchen in Boulder said that
she's willing to take the risk of
labeling her company's edibles made with
certified organic seeds and fruits as
organic even if the marijuana in them
isn't it's a principle an ideology that
doesn't belong to anybody she said
nothing her plants noting her plants
would be certified organic if that
existed on the list of sacrifices and
Gamble's I take organic is definitely on
there but Riverrock cannabis in Denver
has backed away from using the term
until recently the company had been
known as river rock organic medical
cannabis the Attorney General sent
something saying that no dispensary can
be certified as organic retail manager
Chris Haggerty said the company changed
signs stopped handing out promotional
items with the company's name and even
stopped selling t-shirts with the old
company name Haggerty said a group
seeking to have marijuana certifiable as
organic said a system for informing
consumers how marijuana is grown is
needed the word organic is being used
inappropriately by people who are using
very toxic chemicals there's no
governing agency that is regulating that
said John Paul max field co-founder of
the organic cannabis Association in
Denver in the absence of a body coming
through and branding organic cannabis
that term can be used by everybody even
if it's not done properly the USDA
accredits companies and state
governments to certify any farm is
complying with federal Organic
regulations for agricultural products no
company may use the term without this
certification marijuana may not be
certified organic under the USDA Organic
regulations said a USDA spokesman who
could not be named because it's the
agency's policy when discussing
marijuana marijuana is considered a
controlled substance at the federal
level an organic certification is
reserved for agricultural products the
USDA's National Organic Program rules
say companies with organic in their name
cannot prominently display it on a
product and cannot use the name at all
if it misrepresents that a product has
been certified organic it falls to the
Colorado Department of Agriculture to
certify and accredit agricultural
businesses in the state as organic as
well as police for inappropriate and
illegal uses of the word on behalf of
the USDA if the state chose to certify
marijuana as organic it would have to
ignore federal rules and that's unlikely
said Mitch here director of CDA's plant
industry division
um that's weird because we've already
ignored federal rules and we have
legalized recreational cannabis so why
wouldn't we just do it again anyway
that's my opinion on that the state's
inquiry came after the Denver Department
of Environmental Health this year
quarantined more than 100,000 marijuana
plants over pesticide concerns one
company organic greens tested positive
for unapproved pesticides but because it
operates publicly as natural remedies
the agz office allowed it to keep its
name said McAllister its attorney their
actual corporation name is organic
greens but they don't use it in
advertising so they don't publicize
themselves as organic they don't do any
advertising as organic so nobody's being
misled McAllister said confirming the
company name under AG scrutiny
McAllister said the AG is focusing at
least in part on companies that have
used pesticide that have used pesticides
not allowed by the state for use on
marijuana they understand you can't get
federal certification for the word
organic in marijuana he said the agz
office is not substituting themselves
for a certification agency but if they
clearly but if it's clearly not organic
if someone's using Mallett or Eagle 20
they're also looking for those cases
ballot in Eagle 20 our pesticide trade
names well whose active ingredients
contain chemicals the state has not
approved for use on marijuana and I've
said this on a previous episode but I
was speaking with somebody from the
Department of Agriculture they actually
came to I'm the master grower at the
spot dispensary so I had to meet with
the Department of Agriculture they sent
two reps down to come talk to us um and
the main rep told me that the main
reason that Eagle 20 has been banned
from dispensary uses is because if there
is a fire and the Eagle 20 burns the
off-gassing
turns into cyanide and the fire
department doesn't want to go into a
building that is filled with the gas of
cyanide so that's mainly why Eagle 20
has been banned also it's completely
toxic but he didn't even seem to care
about the toxicity of the product he
just wanted to tell me about it turning
into cyanide is why it's been banned
from use in commercial growth facilities
so I'll keep going with the article
there's one more sentence here left one
more short paragraph it says although no
chemical pesticide can obtain federal
approval for use on cannabis state
agriculture officials have
termined which products have labels
whose restrictions are so broadly worded
that using them on marijuana would not
be a violation so they were cracking
down on it you guys when I first started
in the medical marijuana world I was
shopping at a dispensary that had the
word organic in it and I knew right away
when I looked at the medicine when I saw
how they grew I knew there was nothing
to do with actual organics they were
just trying to use the word organic as a
marketing ploy and it was working and
also just to put this out there they do
require that all of the ingredients used
in the grow anything that was sprayed or
fed to the plants does have to be listed
on an instruction list or instruction
ingredients list I'm sorry an
ingredients list on the outside of the
container so all of that [ __ ] does have
to be listed on the package that the
cannabis or hatch is sold that actually
let me reach over here this is just the
inner packaging this one doesn't have
the ingredients on it sorry
but most of the time it's got a few
things written on it and if you come by
cannabis in the state of Colorado you'll
get a little jar like a childproof jar
or whatever they put the cannabis in and
it'll have some ingredients listed on it
and you'll see things like calcium and
you'll see things like mykos and
beneficial bacteria and you'll see stuff
like that that's all what was used in
the growing of the plant so they will
also hopefully list any pesticides that
were sprayed on there alright so they're
cracking down on the name organic then
they are also cracking down to make sure
that your [ __ ] is organic which I really
appreciate I really like that because
there are a lot of shops serving up do
do that you can tell it was not
organically grown you can taste the
fertilizers in it I know friends that
own hydro shops and I know friends that
are reps and consultants for
dispensaries and they go to places they
claimed to be running organics and then
when they make their order from the
hydro shop or when they set up a
nutrient schedule with the consultant
they go with the product that is
completely not organic and they don't
seem to give a [ __ ] but you can't say
anything you just got to let them do
their thing
so I'm glad now somebody is going to
call them out and make them accountable
alright I'm gonna take a DAB in a quick
drink and then we're going to address an
email that was sent to us by a listener
about something I said in episode number
90 so hang out for a few seconds and
I'll be right back all right you guys I
am back I just wanted to let you know if
you hear a bunch of a ruckus in the
background there there are no hostages
in my house there's actually a football
game happening right now there's a
Denver Broncos game and my neighbors are
having a party and I got my window open
a little bit so whenever something
happens in the game you can hear them
either cheer or jeer whichever way it
goes it's pretty entertaining so if you
hear the screams no I don't have
hostages here in the house it's just a
football game and people are going crazy
um so all right just a few days ago I
received an email from a friend of ours
let's get into this email and pulling it
up in my phone right now here we go
all right this email is from our friend
Justin and it says I just listened to
episode 90 I guess I was operating on
some incorrect information you and Jessi
seemed to feel like Herms are really bad
I was told her seeds were pretty much
feminized seeds
since the genetics all came from female
so basically we would revenge out plants
after harvest and then light poisoned
them to make seeds for the future so I'm
wondering if those progeny from the
seeds would be predisposed to Herm in
the future if you could just explain a
little to me or cover this on the show I
would super-duper love that thanks Ross
to Jeff from Justin G all right so the
seeds you're talking about are not
necessarily Herms
hermaphrodites either different
hermaphrodite seeds come from when there
is a female plant in the room that
suddenly pops a male flower and that
male flower pollinates the room and a
few seeds happen from that small
pollination so there's a big difference
in kind of a hermaphrodite seed and what
you're talking about I took a few notes
and wrote a few things down I'm gonna
kind of try to read this to you and
sound like I'm not reading something to
you but here's what I wrote those seeds
that you made are made by stressing the
plant so it has so as long as there were
no males or stray pollen available to
the females and also the females are
solid females the seeds produced will be
females because of the lack of a why
male chromosome so technically those
won't be herm seeds if the none of the
females hermaphrodite it and made male
flowers that release pollen on in there
and they should be feminized so
as long as none of your female plants
are throwing off bananas or male pollen
sacks you will be making female seeds
here um if a plant is allowed to flower
for too long it'll often make seeds if a
plant is light stressed which is what
you guys are doing then those plants
will make seeds and those seeds are
feminized another way to make feminized
seeds is soma takes a plant that is
almost finished it'll be around week six
or seven for like a nine week plant
he'll take it around week six or seven
and then he will light a small fire and
put that fire next to the plant to make
it feel like it's in a forest fire he
will heat the [ __ ] out of the plant
he'll move the heat around the plant and
kind of freak it out and that plant
thinks it's in a forest fire and it's
panic reaction is to start making seeds
so he'll have to give it four to six
weeks from there to finish seeding but
by week twelve summer will have a big
batch of feminized s1 seeds that don't
have any other chromosomes in them
except this chromosomes coming from that
plant so you're going to be basically
copying the plant that you just stressed
so you are making feminized seeds there
when Jesse and I were talking about
hermaphrodite seeds we were talking more
about seeds that were caused by a
hermaphrodite issue in a room say one of
your females were to pop a pollen sack
during week seven or whatever a week six
or seven and that hits another plant and
it pollinates and it makes a little bit
of seed that seed will be kind of
questionable it may have hermaphroditic
traits but it still could be gold as
what we were talking about so there is a
little bit of difference in her seed and
what you're doing herm seed is kind of a
trait issue what you're doing is kind of
a manipulation sort of a stressing and a
panic reaction sort of a thing I
encourage you to keep doing that if you
got any extra seeds man I'd love to grow
a couple of those and see what they do
I'll take some pictures for you so one
thing that I do that's kind of on this
realm and this is just because I wanted
to rant about this it's kind of what
this reminded me of before I breed with
plants I will take my females and I will
put them in the flowering room and I
will set the timer to twelve twelve and
I'll let them flower for about two weeks
and as soon as I see Bud set I will
reverse the timer for
9:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. I will now have
them off from 9:00 a.m. and 9:00 p.m.
and they will come on at 9:00 p.m. to
9:00 a.m. for about five days and then
after five or six days I will put the
timer back to the original 12:12 they'll
come on at 9:00 a.m. and go off at 9:00
p.m.
and I'll pay real close attention to
them for about a week and a half and
then I'll [ __ ] with the timer again I'll
turn it on for twenty four hours
why not and then I'll just do weird
random [ __ ] with my schedules in there
and then I'll put it back on twelve
twelve for a few days and watch the
plants and if they start freaking out
real bad then I kind of get rid of the
plants that can't handle some stress ah
sometimes I go light stress testing cuz
a little bit will tell me what I want to
see but sometimes you get curious as a
grower and you want to go through and
really pummel a female plant and see
what that [ __ ] can handle before you go
putting her into a major breeding
project so I've actually got a couple of
plants that I can take them to week two
and totally reverse the light cycle and
it doesn't piss them off I can do it a
couple of times and they don't her mout
however if I let those same plants go
long enough without any light stress if
I let them go too long they will start
to produce seeds because I've let some
strains go up to 80 days strains that
should only go 60 I've let them go 80
just to see what happens when you grow
as much as we do you need a plan with
some things that's how you learn a lot
of [ __ ] I let him go a little bit long
just to see what happened and it was
seeded the plant had by that 20 extra
days put seeds in my plant so you can do
it by light stress you can do it by
extending them there's a lot of
different ways to do it if you're going
to stress test your females I kind of
just told you how I would do it I would
just [ __ ] with the light cycles as a
breeder one thing I want to say is when
you grow out those seeds that you're
making from manipulated plants really
pay close attention to hermaphroditic
traits you may not find the
hermaphrodites until like week eight of
a nine week plant or of a ten week plant
so really pay attention to that that
shouldn't be there but you are making a
manipulated seed that's not natural so
there is a chance for some weirdness
all right I hope that answered your
question in your email go ahead and grow
those seeds out man that's a great way
to keep yourself self sustainable and
keep yourself supplied in seeds you'll
be one of those guys that has seeds when
the
apocalypse comes so we'll be hanging out
alright guys if you want me to read one
of your emails on the show all you got
to do is send it to me it's grow from
your heart at hotmail.com I'd love to
answer your questions you know I love
the interaction I'd love you guys to
follow me on Twitter it's at G fyh
podcast find me on Facebook it's just
grow from your heart I love all of the
social media interaction I do try to
interact with everybody if you send me a
message I will try to respond it does
take me a little bit sometimes because I
do get a lot of messages of course I've
got the IRA genetics email account that
fills up I've got my own personal email
account that fills up since I've been
doing periscope videos I've been getting
a lot more messages so things are going
a little bit crazy Facebook Instagram
Twitter all that stuff keeps me tied up
and I've been working at the spot doing
quite a few hours every week so that
limits my time for social media but I
will answer your question is what I
think I am getting to please interact
with me I would love it all right you
guys I think that's holy crap what
happened to my throat geez I apologize
for that
I think that's all I've got free for
this week I thought those that news
article in that email would take a
little bit longer to answer but I pretty
much covered that in 20 minutes so I'm
gonna wrap up this show I will be back I
am putting together at the episode about
CBD I'm trying to get more guests to
come be on the show now that uh it's
almost harvest season you guys so once
everybody cuts down everybody will be a
little bit more available we'll be able
to get all the growers back on the show
I got the zoom h6 so I'll be able to
take the show on the road now will go a
few places I just bought four
microphones and four new cables will be
able to take that wherever we want and
go do some recording with a lot more
people that's gonna open up a lot more
options on the next episode I plan to
answer another email that we got I want
to address something that I saw at a
growers house when I went to do a
consultation something that they did in
their grow their garden that I had to I
felt the urge to correct them and I kind
of gave them some guidance on it so I'm
gonna share that with you guys you might
be making the same mistakes as this
other guy so I'm gonna share that with
you I've got a lot of great stuff
planned you guys I'll be back Monday
with another episode I want to thank you
guys for joining me um we don't have any
sponsors if you want to sponsor the
podcast all you got to do is send me an
email let's go from your heart at
hotmail.com I'll let you know everything
you need to know about
during the show if you've got a product
that you would like me to review same
thing grow from your heart at
hotmail.com we would love to review your
products we'll give you an honest
opinion we will expose your product to
at least 5000 consumers that are right
up your alley so if you have a good
product let me know we'll get it out
there for you if you have something to
say find me on all the social media you
guys already said that right alright
don't forget that the show is available
on iTunes stitcher and every single
episode is always in forever archived on
I read genetics Colorado dot-com don't
forget I did put a donation button on
the podcast page um if you feel like the
show is worth a couple of bucks go to
the website it's I read genetics
Colorado com click on the Grove from
your heart podcast tab at the top right
there's a donation button it's a little
PayPal logo that goes directly to my
PayPal account
I'm never gonna charge you for this
podcast you guys this podcast will
always be free the show is going to be
free I grow from my heart I give it to
you from my heart I hope you grow from
your heart in return but if you do feel
like making a contribution it would
definitely be appreciated um I just
bought the new zoom h6 with partially
with contributions that came in to the
podcast so shout out to everybody who
has made a contribution in the past also
you guys know the show's over you can go
to iTunes search for the iTunes or go to
the iTunes Store search for girl from
your heart find the girl from your heart
podcast leave me a 5 star review and
type in a little comment and let me know
what you think about the podcast and I
will read your comments on a future
episode the reason that we want more
ratings and more comments and more
reviews is because that makes us more
exposed to a larger audience the more
likes you get the more comments you get
the more Facebook shares you and exposes
you so the more people that see the show
the more people will learn how to grow
quality cannabis more people will quit
spraying [ __ ] on their plants people
will learn how to look out for
hermaphrodites people will learn how to
just grow better cannabis overall
everybody will grow cannabis people will
get the right idea they will get a
proper education maybe somebody will
listen to the show that has never smoked
pot before they'll listen to the show
and they'll say you know what this guy
smokes a gram of hash every single day
and he's mostly articulate I know I've
got some stoner moments on this show but
that's just me but I'm mostly articulate
maybe they'll say this guy has
[ __ ] together maybe weed isn't so bad
then maybe they'll lighten up and then
maybe they'll be on our side and then
maybe one day we can legalize cannabis
nationwide and then worldwide that's my
mission legalizing cannabis one click at
a time here at the girl from your heart
a podcast that's what we are doing all
right guys I don't have a lot else to
say so I'm gonna wrap up the show um
yeah follow me on Instagram you guys I
just hit 18,000 followers I'm an 18
point 1k on Instagram right now find me
it's at I read genetics on Instagram you
guys I want to give a huge shout out to
my ninja spin so thanks again for
listening until next time take a big fat
dab I'm just a little dad you guys like
a big one like a half a gram make it
count you ready get it on the dabber
take a phat dad right after you blow it
out
go give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
[Applause]
Oh
[Music]
thank you feel