[Music]
[Applause]
yeah welcome back cannabis community
it's time for episode number 98 of The
Crow from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation that's right new grower
your professional grower if you're a new
smoker or a veteran dabber if you're a
cannabis activists prepare someone who's
just curious about the current state of
cannabis this my friends is the podcast
for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff thanks again for joining me you
guys sitting across the table from me
once again is my good buddy white Mike
how you doing buddy don't wanna how are
you I am great I'm a little bit dab the
[ __ ] out I got a couple of new rigs I've
been hitting them like a champion
they're working the hash is working
working well I drop that music right now
I didn't mean to go so abruptly with the
music sorry about that trying to be
smooth try to transition we ended up
just dropping that [ __ ] to zero well
thanks for coming bro yeah do you work
today I did yeah you look like you've
been at work all [ __ ] day I have no
no last time Mike was here we we kind of
talked a little bit about the spot last
time we're not gonna do that we were
gonna talk about some other stuff so I
just want to give Mike a big thanks for
getting here cuz I use a a new father I
know it's got to be kind of rough
pulling away from the kids so thanks for
showing up at this kind of late hour on
a Saturday night right there's a couple
of reasons I'm a half awake right now
will slap you around if you fall asleep
I may push the mic right in your face
and make you talk a lot because I keep
turning [ __ ] up and it's not gonna go
much higher all right there you go there
you go that's what we need nice so um
let's see where do we want to start
we've got a lot of great news articles
to talk about you guys um before I get
too far I want to give a huge shout out
to my new friends at elevate glass in
Colorado Springs elevate glasses on
South Day hone I should have the exact
address in my hand I think it's 5:00 I'm
gonna see 512 South Tejon it's on the
500 block of South Bay hone there is a
dispensary right there altitude organic
medicine and then there's a tattoo shop
and then right next to that is elevate
the glass shop go there they've got
great glass at affordable pricing and um
they might have super hot chicks working
there maybe you know that might be one
of the bone
is of why I like to go there I can't
confirm it or die yeah Mike has not gone
with me I've been there twice and both
times there was a very lovely lady there
ready and willing and able to help me
with all of my glass needs it was great
I'll definitely be back I got a new I
think I talked about the it's a
mothership knockoff basically that I got
there about a week ago and then just
last night I went and picked up a little
hitman it's a mini with the hammer head
on the inside and I had to grab it it's
got a yellow logo I've never seen a
hitman like this with the yellow logo
before and I thought it was super cute
so I picked it up and man it hits like a
Mack truck so I'm super impressed
it really does it's uh your collection
has grown by leaps and bounds and the
new editions were wonderful was the
first word that comes to mind nice nice
I don't have as many rigs as you might
think because well I got rid of a couple
through a place to make room for these
so great I swap them out with the old in
with the new that's the truth I'm not as
much of a rig junky as you might think
by Master Shake the a Master Shake was
fun slop he's got that shot at the
sloppy make sure you guys check out oil
impe and arts on facebook that's my
buddy sloppy it's his glass trading page
if you're looking for a new glass our
artistic glass functional glass at a
great price my buddy sloppy is now in
the glass business so make sure you
support that shoutout to sloppy
all right so somebody sent me an email
let's start off the show with an email
from a friend this is kind of not
cannabis related and it's funny because
he starts his email this is from my
buddy Justin and now the email says so
this isn't really a show or growing
question just a matter of personal
curiosity what do you think of Matisyahu
do you feel like his music is reggae or
not or not really listen to him just
wandering doing fat dabs from Justin G
Justin dude I want to give you a big
shout out you follow me on Facebook you
follow me on the podcast you follow me
on almost every periscope video that I
make I really appreciate your support
it's great to have a little cult that
will listen to almost everything that I
put out I definitely appreciate you guys
that are my little following there
that's freaking awesome I totally
appreciate that so let's talk about
Matisyahu Mike's ridden around in the
car with me and heard what happens when
Matisyahu comes up on the shuffle you
gotta join in and get out those pretty
big it door did you do a choice you got
to get there and get going
with him do that [ __ ] is so much fun
I've learned to meditate while you drive
not just hold on yeah well kind of wedge
yourself in there for impact and then
tune out and pretend like it's not
reggae all day you put yourself in your
happy place
now your reggae did enough work bro oh
they do play some reggae at work all
right so let's talk about how I feel
about Matisyahu um dude that's kind of
so one day my buddy Ross Christian who
was one of the guys that taught me a lot
about Rastafari I shot it - Chris much
respect
Ross Chris gave me a little CD with one
Matisyahu song on it I came home and
listened to it and I was like that is
the [ __ ] right there
I just really liked the flow like the
music was good but I liked the way it
felt it just flowed really smooth his
lyrics were really smooth over
everything so I downloaded more right
and I loved it I found shake off the
dust of Rhys and I found why VAT stubs
or what was available at that time
so I was driving from Pueblo Colorado to
Lawrence Kansas on a regular basis I had
a band out there and I was lived here
and had a band out there and then I
travel back and forth all the time to
take care of life I had a CD player in
the car and all of my CDs got stolen
except for the one that was in the CD
player people I know and it was why if
it stubs it was the wife it stubs album
so that's what I had to drive back and
forth to Lawrence Kansas and it's about
at an 11 hour drive depending on traffic
and depending on how things go so that's
10 or 11 opportunities to listen to that
CD from beginning to end both ways yeah
I totally fell in love with that album
dude shake off the dust rise came a
little bit later in my life I think I
got that one right after I got tired of
the Y right after the theft after
everything got stolen
but yeah so I went to Lawrence Kansas
and showed a couple of my friends I was
like check this guy out and then we saw
him at Wakarusa and on the first night
at Wakarusa fest in 2005 I believe there
wasn't anybody there there's like 40 of
us up front checking out Matisyahu the
second night there had to be a hundred
and fifty people there the third night
that place was packed bro he took one
night off it was like a four night
festival he takes a Saturday off for the
the Sabbath by the Sunday night when he
played it was packed you couldn't even
get in the tent to see the man anymore
yes over three nights you just blew up
like that so i I've seen ma kiss I got
to go see Matisyahu on my one of my
birthday's my girlfriend took me to see
him at the Beaumont theater in Kansas
City Kansas
I'll vol random places when I lived in
Lawrence so yeah I got to see Montes a
few times have seen at the bottleneck
and Lawrence I've seen him a lot but
yeah that artist meant a lot to me just
from that time period it really brings
me back to that whole time period of my
life thank God no water was my favorite
matcha song and then unfortunately when
he came out with the album Youth I feel
like he put all of his life's work into
the shake off the dust arise album like
all of his writing for 20 years of being
a person he put into that and then he
did check out our live at Stubbs which
was basically the same thing just live
and they're like all right now you've
got a production deal in a record deal
it's making an expensive album and he
was like oh [ __ ] I already put it all
out it's like he'd already kind of done
almost like his new stuff I don't I
don't like the new stuff as much as I
did the old stuff but that happens to a
lot of artists I feel the same way about
spearhead kind of the older [ __ ] was
much better
there's something about music that
whatever drives you to create it dies
weren't enough money lands on top of it
right that's kind of how I feel about it
like especially if you're like an angry
band that's where you see it the most
you already just got like a 12 million
dollar contract why are you still angry
right and unless they really start
buying just more expensive heroin or
something right yeah yeah
where would we board with music this
we've really gotten off the rails this
is odd Cass but what are the music Jim
was a lot about weed he knows so much
more about music I do know a lot about
music yeah I could probably can do a
music podcast I've played the drums for
so long I can read and write music and I
know a lot about music music playing and
listening and then I also know about
bands yeah we could do a whole show
about that cuz we've gotten way off
topic but where would we be where would
music be where would musicians be if
they didn't alter their minds a little
bit the Beatles would it never came up
with any of that [ __ ] if they didn't
start life would be very exploring there
my missions done smoke weed yeah for
sure the Grateful Dead would not have
been fun if I was not tripping my face
off
I think there's a great Lenny Bruce rant
to that effect alright so I want to put
the show back on track just a little bit
we're almost 10 minutes in and we
haven't talked about weed at all hey
Justin thanks for the email dude you
really like made me time-travel in my
mind when I read that it was really
reminiscing on those days matisyahu's
great he's got a great message
he's a positive dude he doesn't use any
profanity so it's good for the kids
ah he only talks about good stuff and to
pump your head and heart with good stuff
is always better than listening to some
negative [ __ ] that makes you want to do
stupid [ __ ] I don't listen to things
like Insane Clown Posse and [ __ ] like
that it doesn't support anything good
for your mind so listen to some Montes
Yahoo listen to some spearhead a lot of
people around here in tunak oh I can't
get into NACO for some reason not going
medicine for the people but a lot of the
hippy kids or all the dreadlock kids are
loving it now so check that out if you
need some good positive music in your
life all right let's get onto something
that has something to do with cannabis
do you want to talk about let's see you
want to go I got three topics here
they're all equally important we've got
the 30 shops we've got recreational
cannabis is now legal in the state of
Oregon
should we start or end with goodness uh
well all right that's our good news and
then we've got an article about somebody
getting shot so let's go bad bad good
let's end on a positive note this time
last night it was a down note we had to
come up with positive [ __ ] all right
well then let's start the bad bad if you
want to go worst first let me open up
Google here I've already got this
article saved where is it here it is it
happened again this year you guys it is
outdoor season and people people that
are growing outdoors are sitting outside
waiting for thieves
the past two weekends over the past 14
or 15 days I have heard of about seven
or eight maybe nine or ten outdoor grows
getting stolen it's that time of year
people it is Ripper season yeah or
Ripper homie Susan I hate it it's uh
I've had a lot of people in my world
have just wrecked winners because
of Ripper's do they they spend all
summer throwing their life into a crop
and then it vanishes days before it's
done you wake up you go out there to
water your plants and guess what they're
not there anymore I saw something about
a van get busted I want to say it was in
California that was just packed full of
plants that had just been ripped oh [ __ ]
and I've seen a number of posts on
Facebook of security cam footage with
people's faces apo tripping plans yeah
right now if you are in any pot group on
Facebook
somebody has posted a picture of some
[ __ ] and it says this guy stole my
pot plants do you know who he is it's
all over Facebook right now everybody is
getting ripped off so it happened in our
town somebody let's just get right to
the news article here you guys I've got
it on the on the screen the headline is
you need something up there bro yeah no
no you need a dab my brain wants
cigarette but you know oh yeah you can't
do there if you have a vape all that
you've ADA here but no came unprepared
came unprepared I apologize for your
lack of preparation maybe if you take a
dab a little [ __ ] settle down your
urge I don't know I'm already stoned I
appreciate that
keep you slightly coherent you are half
asleep on the show already guys we can't
we can't make fun of Micra be in a bleep
he's a new father he worked a long shift
he went home and ate dinner and then he
came over here it's like 11 o'clock on a
Saturday night and the students here
recording with me if I went to bed at
7:00 a.m. thanks baby
got up at 11:00 yeah father and I'm here
recording a podcast at almost midnight
on a Saturday that's how cool we are
getting it done for the people yeah
that's what we got to do I'm running out
of time to do things I've been dedicated
to the spot lately were there all the
time all right let's not talk about that
we can't talk about the spot on this
show ixnay on the optimatus while we're
here at midnight bro that's it
so the truth are they the truth the
headline says my brain the headline says
before I get that far this is from
Jessie Paul of the Denver Post I found
it on Denver Post calm
it says Pablo police that's our town you
guys puddle oh the city of Pueblo
Colorado the seven one nine that's where
we are
Pueblo police teen shot after
verbalizing burglar
Verizon burglarizing was the word that I
couldn't say teen shot after
burglarizing illegal marijuana grow
investors investigators say Vincent
Durand the homeowner shot at the two
alleged burglars you got anything to say
Mike he looked like you're about to
speak up and I heard about this story
the next morning and yeah it's a
horrible incident everybody's going to
jail everybody both of the kids are
going being charged with burglary the
homeowners being charged with first
degree assault that's what happens when
you shoot somebody who's running away
from your property okay all right well
let's read the article here it says a 17
year old boy was shot early Friday in
Pueblo after authorities say he
burglarized a man's illegal marijuana
grow now let's update the people why
it's illegal before we even go too far
because we are in Colorado everyone is
allowed to grow six plants of their own
every adult if you have a medical
marijuana recommendation from a doctor
you are able to grow possibly more
plants but in the city of Pueblo within
the city limits of Pueblo it is now
illegal to grow any sort of cannabis
recreational or medicinal outside of
your home in your yard that is not in an
enclosed building greenhouses are
illegal it has to be like a sealed
normal building like a it has to be like
in a fountain date a building with the
foundation as part of the rule it has to
be so many square feet like there are
thorough rules that you have to follow
excuse me no worries at the dabs you you
can't just plant six plants in your
backyard anymore um they did away with
that a year ago statewide you just have
to have it in a locked enclosed space
but every city and county in town now
have their own little rules for the most
part right so here we kissing them and
so his grow was illegal and he's being
charged with nuisance violations if I
remember correctly a thousand dollars a
pop per plant Wow yep so that 6,000 and
city fines plus he's got to destroy the
plants plus he's being charged with
first-degree assault for shooting a
teenager and destroy them then I would
just cut him down to take him inside
it's just about time he has to destroy
them how it
they could be small fires yeah he's got
to cut them down and they can't be out
there anymore but it's harvest time
anyway yeah so he's just got to chop him
down now take him inside but had this
garden been discovered by city
inspectors or regulators or if the
neighbor called the cops for whatever
six months ago when they were knee-high
and there was nobody there he would have
had to cut him down then - okay all
right I'm gonna continue with the
article we just wanted to explain why
his grow was illegal since it is
Colorado that may be confusing to some
folks the article goes on to say police
say the teen showed up at a hospital at
about 4:15 a.m. Friday with a gunshot
wound to his right leg the juvenile male
initially stated he was shot after
leaving a party on the west side of
Pueblo police said in a news release
however it was later determined that he
had uh uh he and another individual had
jumped a fence into a yard on the 1600
block of Western 13th Street in hopes of
finding marijuana plants in an outdoor
grow investigators say Vincent Duran age
55 the homeowner shot that the two
alleged burglars striking of the team
the juvenile was treated released and
taken to the Pueblo Youth Services
Center where he was booked on burglary
charges police say got imagine how that
would suck dude you gonna steal some
weed or just a teenage kid thinking I'm
gonna go Jackson bud end up shot in the
leg at the hospital and then in [ __ ]
jail I have no say I don't either but if
the homeowner didn't kill him yeah I'm
glad he didn't I'm glad he just got he
was only injured but Jesus this article
has been all over Facebook because our
friends posted it to Facebook and shared
it and people have commented [ __ ] kid
got what he had coming to them and
people have commented I woulda shot him
again ah
guys this is cannabis I know this is
your investment I know this is your
business
please don't [ __ ] shoot people over
weed you should be growing it legally
anyway it's legal here just follow the
simple rules and if somebody's trying to
steal those plants call the cops that's
what they're there for
that's why legalization is beautiful as
we finally get to use law enforcement
when somebody tries to steal our weed
yeah and we had a friend recently stolen
from who actually called and reported
his plants stolen and the cop asked him
how much was that plant going to harvest
was it going to yield and he told him
how much it would yield and he said what
would that cost you to buy at a
dispensary and he told him what that
would cost per ounce he called me and
got a price quote right I thought it'd
be this much per ounce dude and so on
the police report they value each plant
at what an ounce would cost at my shop
yep and now those people that will be
caught because they've got video of them
they'll be charged with felony theft
because they took over a certain amount
of dollars worth of product it like the
beaut the real beauty of legalization is
that we can use courts and lawyers and
cops like the violence doesn't have to
exist there that's the truth even there
in your backyard they're stealing your
[ __ ] you guys let the dog out yeah you
let the dog out you know make them run
if you've got a firearm pointed at them
don't [ __ ] shoot them you're 9 times
out of 10 is teenagers or [ __ ] kids
and just flip the lights on and I'm
gonna run away there's a 17 year old boy
if you would have said freeze get on the
ground you gonna call the cops you could
have dealt with it a little bit better
Reza dude shot a young kid who was
running away he was already running away
that's not cool nose on his way out okay
let's continue with the article um where
was i Duran was arrested on suspicion of
first-degree assault and police say
he'll also will be issued a summons for
the marijuana grow he'll also be ordered
to remove the Grove police say
investigators say they are searching for
the teens accomplice in August of 2014 a
13 year old boy was wounded by a man
after allegedly trying to steal
marijuana plants from a back yard so you
can see this is gonna happen every year
if we keep having these illegal outdoor
grows just put it inside grow indoors
nobody can see it if you're doing it
properly nobody can smell it nobody
knows it's there you can control it you
can grow year round right just go get a
carbon filter and a grow light and a
grow book read the book listen to the
show listen to the show I know the Sun
is free you guys but you got it in the
city of Pueblo it's illegal and if you
grow and it gets something like this
happens it puts a black eye on our
entire industry our entire community on
the plant on the movement on everything
somebody got shot over some weed because
somebody was growing it outside okay
just
ballpark a decent little gross setup for
six plants is gonna run your what the
best gear three grand
oh dude I could set you up ready to grow
for less than a thousand bucks right but
like if you want with the best like
three or four Oh 25 how much would you
pay to not just sweat for six months
eight months while your plants are out
back right if someone's gonna steal your
effort that's the truth like for me it's
definitely worth more than a grinder to
and if you think about it this way if
you're growing enough outside to make it
worth shooting somebody for it you are
doing you're growing more than you need
probably maybe you're growing your
entire year supply I can't judge you but
think about the situation if you need if
you're growing that much you might be
asking for something if you're trying to
get greedy you might be asking her you
might be inviting trouble if you're
trying to get greedy is what I think I'm
saying right this dude's gonna end up
harvesting enough weed to get him till
he's gotta turn himself into gopher to
jail like it sucks they decided to shoot
the kid trying to steal his weed and now
he's gonna end up in jail for it the
kids going to jail for trying to steal
it like it's just shitty all around
because this dude wanted to skirt the
law in a place where it's illegal
no let's change let's just change the
item being stolen from excuse me guys
sorry let's change this item from
cannabis plants to a car if it goes down
like this everybody's still going to
jail yeah but would you have shot at
somebody still in your car I have a
feeling this guy would yeah okay you
know we had an incident as in the city a
couple of years ago it got a whole lot
of press because it was particularly
brutal this guy kind of lived in the
middle of nowhere and had a trash pile
with a bunch of scrap metal in it and
people kept pulling up in the middle of
the night and stealing his scrap metal
so one night he got his rifle and turned
all the lights off and when the pickup
truck showed up people climbed out and
turned flashlights on he opened fire he
killed one of them wounded another one
held one of them at gunpoint all the
cops got there it was looking at like
first-degree murder charges because
that's first-degree murder
you can't lie in wait and kill people
you flash the [ __ ] out of that like I
don't know it's just people oh man well
this is gonna happen all over the
country just happen in Oregon - its
Ripper season you guys don't like that's
a big part of growing marijuana it used
to be because it was illegal but it was
always also because marijuana is worth a
lot of money especially in places where
it isn't legal and if you can steal it
from someone your your cost is zero and
you can take it somewhere where you can
sell it for six eight thousand a pound
so people are gonna try to steal it and
the people that are gonna try to steal
it are [ __ ] some of these guys are
professionals yep there's a story I was
told a story of somebody who got into a
greenhouse with a poly vinyl cover I
don't know exactly what that shit's
called the greenhouse covering thick
covering they cut a three foot tall slit
in the cover just a slit three feet tall
and they took every [ __ ] plant out of
the greenhouse did not leave a footprint
nor a leaf behind and cleaned the entire
greenhouse out right these guys are
professionals there are experienced
rippers out there and they're at work
all for the next week or two just taking
crops that are finished all right I hope
you guys get your plants cut down dude
if someone comes to steal your plants
please don't shoot them don't go to jail
really really really think about what
you're gonna do do not go to jail and
earlier I said let your dogs out don't
let your dogs out if you let your dog
out your dog bites somebody you gotta
put your dog down so and that person may
shoot your dog so just keep the dog in
the house like there's there's really
not a great option here like that's one
of the things that sucks call the cops
definitely call the police yeah if
you've got yeah I guess so huh or grow
indoors bro we just had a guy get shot
for confronting some taggers in the
alley so I'm really kind of anti you
know doing anything right now other than
like bring an official that's what
they're there for just call the cops
yeah don't try to be a vigilante and I
always hated the not doing it because I
had weed there were so many times was
like I should and I didn't because I had
weed or smelled like weed or just smoked
right yeah sometimes just call 9-1-1 and
say hey there's a car upside down on the
interstate
don't you stop some high as [ __ ] all
right guys gosh excuse my throat
clearing I'm gonna give it one good one
I'll be done that was just exaggerating
and I think I'm good though all right
that's a no that's the worst that's the
bad news let's find this is some not
great news
yeah not great news this one I'm I was
saying that we're not going to talk
about the spot on this episode but guess
what the spot will be as as an example
in the following this spot the spot pass
all these tests with flying colors we do
not get any violations everything is
legit at the spot we are champions so
with that being said the headline for
this article is 7 Denver marijuana shops
cited for underage sales the byline is
police say they conducted checks on 30
Denver retail marijuana shops on Friday
I found this article on the cannabis
this Arabic article is written by Jesse
Paul of the Denver Post I actually first
heard of this uh from our good friend
Dave Munn so shout out to Dave for
putting me on the case to find this one
yep
Dave's a good dude nipples are sticking
out Dave Denver police issued seven
citations for underage retail marijuana
sales during an enforcement operation at
thirty shops last week officials said on
Wednesday police say they conducted
checks Friday in an effort to audit any
potential underage sales and found there
to be lower underage compliance rate to
be a lower underage compliance rate
sorry I read that wonky we're
disappointed said Lewis Koski director
of Colorado's marijuana Enforcement
Division in a statement
up until now these compliance checks
have been a bright spot for the industry
this recent check drops compliance to
92% yeah we were at 99 before [ __ ]
[ __ ] making us look bad the news
comes as a blow to recreational
marijuana in Colorado especially since
the in the roughly 21 minutes months
since recreational marijuana has been
legal stores mostly have been lauded for
their compliance owners and operators
have been praised for their handling of
the hot-button topic of underage
possession and consumption so in
Colorado what they're mainly worried
about is this weed being sold to people
who are not
and also we'd being sold out the back
door of the dispensary that isn't being
documented if underage sales and product
and leaving a shop headed out of state
you know in bulk in bulk yes that are
the two things that were really really
really seeking to avoid here they call
those the fatal flaws yep those are the
things that will trigger federal
intervention if they get out of hand yes
and I mean just in my world all of the
anti pop people love [ __ ] like this like
it doesn't matter that we only dropped
down percentage-wise to inline with
alcohol and tobacco retailers like all
three of those businesses sit at about a
92 percent compliance rate like 92 92
and we're at 92 now thanks to this we
were at 99 thanks to Aspen dip shits dip
ship there were two shops in Aspen that
were busted a while ago after they were
busted
pretty much every shop in the state got
a letter saying hey make sure your ID
check system is up to snuff we're doing
compliance checks we're not trying to
scam you like they're not gonna pretend
that they're 21 and show a fake ID or
something it'll be an under 21 ID and
you'll [ __ ] it up yeah that's how you
get stung and in the state of Colorado
our IDs are vertical horizontal yeah if
you're over 21 it fits one way on the
card and if you're under 21 and 50s so
that should be obvious you have to look
at the verticals like I just had a
family member turn 21 and her ID so good
for several months so you've got to read
the date but how it's not hard
happy birthday I know who you are happy
birthday everybody go get a little flip
calendar with the you can't buy [ __ ]
here if he was born before somebody up
front who's trained and experienced and
checking IDs right we have armed
security checking every ID that comes to
the store and we turn away 65 year olds
all the time because their ID expired a
week ago this is how strict our shop is
and I know you said we weren't going to
talk about the spot but this is an
example of what should be done ah you
gotta do it right right now the fire
inspector showed up and the fire
inspector said hey I'm here to look in
the back of the building and the
security guard said and who are you and
he said I'm the fire inspector and the
security guard said sir can I see your
ID and he said I don't have
'i'm the fire inspector and the
security-guard stuck out his hand and
said I'm John on the security guard good
to meet you can I see your ID and the
guy was like I'm the fire inspector I
don't need an ID and he goes I don't
know who you are you can't come in here
and scent the fire inspector away
because he didn't have proper
identification he was in a fire truck
but dude didn't have ID so we can't let
him in there that's it period yeah
period that's the rule you don't have ID
you can't come in will okay you could be
Barack [ __ ] Obama and I don't think
we let you in there unless you pull out
that ID we had cops come to the shop
because the crazy guy said we stole his
wallet one day and the security guard
checked their IDs it was really funny to
watch all of the blood tenders were
standing there like dude he's really
checking their IDs it's the third one in
a row he's getting his wallet out he's
pawning his driver's license and giving
it to our security guard the AUSA's is
crazy shout out to whichever security
guard that was yep that's a good job
it's everyone that comes in gets ID'd if
your IDs expired you can't come in not
at all anyone you can't come in yep
every shop in the legal industry needs
to be able to do this it's not
complicated we make vendors wait in the
entry room if they don't have their ID
with them no you cannot go back to the
offices you have to wait right here in
this chair we'll come and then we make
them wait if they have a delivery for us
and they don't have their ID we handle
everybody else first and because all
right let's get back to this article we
were talking a little bit about the spot
we said we weren't gonna we're just
praising the rules that were followed in
Washington state by comparison which
legalized recreational marijuana at the
same time Colorado did but implemented
recreational sales six months later
several stores have been reprimanded for
selling to minors Koski said despite a
lack of repeat violations at any one
licensed shop this represents a downward
trend in compliance that is concerning
that is very true we've been at it for
just over almost two years now holy [ __ ]
time flies there was a lot of
information in that last paragraph there
re stinging purposefully restating
businesses that failed to make sure that
they're back in compliance where they
need to be yes another piece of
information you might enjoy dear
listeners is if you're at Ibaka or
alcohol retailer the fines usually about
ten thousand for screwing up an ID check
if you're a marijuana retailer the first
two penalties you face or a hundred
thousand dollar fine and you can lose
your life
$100,000 so it's 10 times the fine if
you screw this up as a marijuana
business that could close a shop yeah
that could absolutely close a smaller
dispensary that can shut it down a new
dispensary they could be gone yeah ouch
I know a lot of shops that that would
have closed down in their first year
that would have closed down that Mike
and I worked we met each other well I
don't know we we became good friends
through that probably would have closed
matter mark that would have destroyed
madam are they wouldn't yeah a hundred
thousand dollar fine that woulda just
closed that place down if that weren't
there I would have been hungry all right
I'm gonna continue with the article here
it says when reached by phone
representatives at five of the shop
cited either declined to immediately
comment or said they could not discuss
the citations because of ongoing
criminal investigations
obviously we failed in our mission to
keep people under 21 out of our shop
sent Ryan Fowler owner of the cited
store red eye relief I'm incredibly
disappointed I must say I like the name
red eye relief that sounds like
something I would have said I Drive by
two of these shops regularly when I'm in
Denver I almost stopped at one of them
the last time I was up and never just a
few days ago should have stopped to let
you in so Fowler said four employees
including a store manager were fired in
the citations wake he added the shop
will stop accepting vertical
identification cards and begin using
electronic verification to ensure there
are no underage customers so even if
you're 21 and you have a vertical card
they're not gonna let you win
yep which is nonsense yeah you can fully
let in people that are 21 and you should
they're perfectly legally allowed to
shop in your business um same thing with
the electronic card reader if you're you
can't look at the date and see what it
says the electronic card reader I can
help you that's true yep it shows your
age actually when you slide that card
reader it shows the actual age yeah but
if you can't read a year can you read a
number at all that's true you guys there
are a few dispensaries if you come to
Colorado and you shop at a dispensary
there are a few that run your card
through that little card reader like
they have at the bar that thing does not
save any information you guys it does
not save any information it scans your
ID and it processes the information on
your ID and then it shows how old you
are is all it does a lot of people are
paranoid that that thing is showing your
ID it does not or that it's keeping your
information it does not we're not
allowed the dispensaries are not allowed
to track your information the only thing
that we do keep track of is oftentimes
dispensaries will document what state
you are from and that is mostly for
advertising and just marketing purposes
so we're not keeping your information we
don't want to know where you live we
don't care we're out of room for records
[ __ ] has to be a dick about it but like
we're sort of busy yeah like we don't
have time to even process that
information let alone compile it a need
or anything to do with it either
alright I'm gonna get back into this
article um where was I there we go
we were very concerned about this matter
the healing house said in a statement to
the Denver Post we are 100% committed to
compliance in all aspects of the law we
have had no issues in the past and we
were taking this matter very seriously
officials say the citations for selling
marijuana to a person younger than 21
were issued at 7 separate businesses the
charge is a class 1 misdemeanor oh so
they could also face criminal charges
huh the person who made the sale faces
has already been cited with a criminal
criminal charge and they'll be going to
court for it no I know we said we're not
gonna talk about the spot but when you
walk into most dispensaries there's a
security guard up front checking IDs
then he sends you back to the budtender
who sells you bud Huson then he rings
you up who's responsible therefore that
the security guard or
the budtender me you should be checking
an ID again
I worked we totally asked if we're at
all worried about it we have a lot of
faith in our security guards we don't at
all tolerate the security guard not
doing his job correctly right there most
of those guys are there already goes the
whole company's ex-military and everyone
in that company's event nice so they're
used to doing everything perfect when
they have to it work and so it's simply
done correctly every time we still ask
from time to time we've got a couple of
people that come in the shop that looked
very very young and they're both well
over 21 but they don't look it
yeah and so every time there's a new
budtender there and even sometimes when
you know there's just a lot of people
there and we want everybody to be
confident that we're not some under 21
people will just hey can I see your ID
again real quick man I'm sorry I just
got to be sure right because my butt on
the line true yeah you're way too pretty
for jail yeah it's like I really like
you dude but you're not worth a thought
okay no or your job yep this $40.00 sale
is not worth $100,000 fine and my job
right yeah and the criminal charge and
I'm gonna continue with the article and
I just realized that at the bottom of
the article I didn't see this when I
skim through this the first time all of
the shops are listed I like it so avoid
them yeah or if you're not 21 go there
I'm just getting to the hall so it says
those dispensaries need to be held
accountable said Tyler Henson president
of the Colorado cannabis Chamber of
Commerce your job as an owner and
operator is to ensure your employees are
readily trained that can't happen again
he added Henson said employers and their
employees need to understand at what's
at stake here
officials say the violations can mean a
license suspension a fine per individual
violation a fine in lieu of suspension
up to $100,000 and license reeve
occasion man that sounds so serious when
he put it like that I mean think about
it dude what what did the one shop down
here do they got their license pulled on
site consumption on site wasn't like
they were giving out dabs in the bedroom
nope
they had roaches in an employee bathroom
and it was enough for them to
to store licenses underage sales they
haven't closed the shop that I know of
yet but I don't think any of the cases
that have screwed this up have gone
through that process completely yet time
will tell it's brand-new
yep my guess is a couple of people are
gonna lose their license if you get
stung twice I would bet on it oh yeah
twice they should yeah yeah
so it says sanctions may also include
restrictions on the license police said
in a news release investigators say they
will file the cases with the Denver City
Attorney's Office which could issue its
own discipline raging from license
suspension to license revocation
according to the Colorado Department of
Revenue the marijuana enforcement
division has conducted 172 compliance
checks since January 1st of 2014 and
found 16 total violations so it goes on
to say Denver marijuana shops were cited
where citations were issued and then
enlists them it says the herbal cure on
South Logan Street the healing house on
South downing pure medical dispensary on
40th Avenue Laconte 's clone bar and
dispensary on East 7th that's over by
where they host the cannabis cup herbs
for you on East 9th Mile High Green
Cross those guys have a cannabis cup so
does LeConte A's there are a couple
places on here that have cannabis cups
that are professionals that have a
reputation that are [ __ ] up I don't
know how a [ __ ] some of these shops
messed this up red eye relief on South
Cherokee Street you know we can chalk a
couple of them up to a lazy employee or
somebody up at the front not giving a
[ __ ] and you just hand him an ID and
like they look I've been not old enough
and gotten into clubs just by handing
the bouncer an ID here any was my ID
that said I was not 21 and he's like oh
you got an ID here just hands it back
like you said some people aren't [ __ ]
smart enough to read an ID to figure out
that nineteen seventy whatever means
you're this how old you know people
can't do that math in their head
sometimes so we can give a couple of
those just to dumb employees some of
it's just brought one of them one or two
is probably just somebody letting
somebody slip through just like I don't
know what it is but if you
if the you know if selling to people
under 21 is part of your business model
you can go yeah where'd you we're trying
to set a positive standard here and do
things correctly we're literally front
and center on the world stage when other
nations bring up marijuana legalization
as an idea or a concept that they might
want to pursue they discuss what's
happening in Colorado yes we are the mom
every now and then I hear about someone
from France or London coming through
Pueblo and taking a look at what we're
doing here in Pueblo which this never
would've happened five years ago true
there's no reason for any of these
people to be here every trial and be
interested in what we're doing but
they're coming here to see how marijuana
legalization works in practice and if
they see teenagers waiting in line it's
not going well it's not gonna spread and
it should that's the truth all right you
guys we've got one more article that I
want to get in we've been going for
close to 40 minutes we get this one in
here I like it the people seem to like
when I've got somebody else with me
they'll listen a little longer
so about 36 minutes is the limit when
there's two of us now listen that's good
news time suppose so let's start this
one off with a big congratulations to
Oregon we're gonna enters recreational
arrow with tax-free pot sales October
first documented the beginning of
recreational pot sales in the state of
Oregon I've got a lot of friends out
there big shout out to my Oregon crew
the pmw crew hope you guys are out there
enjoying recreational cannabis sales so
I've got an article once again from the
cannabis this was written by Jonathan JQ
/ and Bob Seavey of The Associated Press
it's like a cool parent named John
Cooper and Bob Seavey yeah alright just
when I think I was gonna ready for
another Deb you say some really high
[ __ ] and remind it's probably not a
great idea let's take let's celebrate
Oregon's recreational cannabis with I
taking a DAB yeah that's good to me
consider my arm twisted yeah I'll twist
the [ __ ] out of it um we've got two rigs
on the table I'll let you hit the email
and then I'll go ahead and take the one
that requires a torch you got a dab over
there yeah I'm gonna take myself a
medium medium dad
hey guys I want you to take a DAB with
me first of all but then I want you to
find me on social media either Facebook
or Twitter or you can even email me you
want if you want but I want to know how
big of a DAB do you take do you take a
point one do you take a point - do you
take a point three do you take point
four or do you do a [ __ ] half gram
dab tell me what you think I want to
know about it it's a girl from your
heart at hotmail.com you can find me on
Facebook it's a girl from your heart or
if you want to search me out on tweeter
find me on the little tweeter it's at G
fyh podcast let me know how big of a DAB
you prefer to take so you're looking for
regular dab sighs not this one time my
friend dared me to take well I want to
know yeah yeah like what if you're about
to just pull off the dab for yourself if
it's your normal day if your dad but I
want to know what you pull off what's
your average and then tell me how many
of those you take in a dab session also
because if you take a half gram and you
only take one of them then that's cool
if you take five-point ones that's cool
so I just want to know how you do it
I'm just curious I myself like to take a
whole bunch of 0.3 like 0.3 is about
where I like to be and I like to take a
bunch of like about 6 or 7 of them
sometimes on a lunch break I'll take 3.3
ziz what I like for a lunch break I'm
gonna take a cab right now right now I'm
hitting the hit man let's do this oh
that hits really well you don't remember
how bad I cough no cough little cough so
recently I picked up a mothership and
knock off it's not really it looks just
like a mothership kline but it was
thinner I think if the glass maybe a
little thinner not that not so much the
glow yeah maybe a little bit the glass
way too but the overall size of the rig
the cylinder going up is is thinner in
diameter okay yeah maybe a little bit
shrunken of a ship but it was a fifth of
the price of a mothership right it's
like a truck
it's a great rig so shout out to elevate
in Colorado Springs I know I've said
that once or twice this show but I've
been buying a lot of glass from them and
I appreciate the hookups this little hit
man it's like a goddamn truck I'm trying
to act like I'm not trying to choke and
trying to act like I've got my breath
together everything but guess what
there's almost no resistance is straight
nails along oh that yeah some choke is
expect you just get a fat rip every time
so I feel I can get my brains back
together sometimes you guys want to take
a big dab it sounds like Charlie Brown's
the adults in the Charlie Brown cartoon
[Music]
is what it sounds like after a big dab
sometimes it takes me a minute to dig
through that hole but I feel like I'm
back we're a celebrating Oregon having
recreational sales of cannabis right and
welcome to the club you're the brother
see the cool kids justice all right
let's get into this article this is from
Portland Oregon and it says excited
shoppers looking to score some of the
first recreational marijuana sold
legally in Oregon bought up baggies of
Bud early Thursday taking advantage of
doorbuster prices and other deals
goddamn that's such a poetic opening
line for a news article whoever wrote
this is majestic some of the more than
250 dispensaries that already offer
medical marijuana in the state welcome
to recreational users soon after
midnight just moments after it became
legal to sell to anyone who is at least
21 it's a really long sentences in this
article right at Shango premium cannabis
in Portland co-founders Shane McKee said
the first sale came about a minute after
midnight and many others quickly
followed I think it's not only
historical for folks in Oregon but
nationwide anytime people start selling
that as an alternative to alcohol or
tobacco he said in a telephone interview
Brad Suzman co-owner of canna daddies in
Portland said more than 90 customers
bought pot in the first two hours at the
store opened at 7:00 a.m. so people are
out there at midnight buying weed out
there at 7:00 a.m. by and weed that's
pretty neat it's like when a new video
game goes on sale something like that
lines out the door people just buying
weed I'm torn with this story I first
I'm elated that another state is joining
the legalization ranks I'm glad they
they're celebrating I'm glad people came
out and that the lines were good a lot
of medical shops are converting so
supply might not be the problem it's
been another legal states which is
awesome but at the same time it's time
to
off the shenanigans and step all the way
up into the legal industry you got to
put your best foot forward or you're
gonna [ __ ] it up for everyone and there
were a couple of things about the
rollout in Oregon that could [ __ ] it up
for most of Oregon half of the state has
banned shops period the other half of
the state allows a shitload and if you
look at a map it's like right down the
[ __ ] mountain range in the middle of
the state the coast side approves in
their shops everywhere the other side of
the mountain range
not a single shop of course and stuff
like opening at midnight when there are
hours that you're allowed to open and
not allowed to be open and they don't
involve 12:01 in the morning
there's the main reporter covering
marijuana out there that I follow on
Twitter one of her colleagues was handed
marijuana gummies outside of the shop
waiting in line doing news reports he
was just handed free pot candy pot
edibles specifically candy or [ __ ]
banned
so we're giveaways
and it's not like this stuff is that
it's very shy on day one it's I mean
it's a celebration shenanigans happen
there was a truck driving up and down
the street not at all affiliated with
the dispensary we were waiting in line
plants right it was the funniest [ __ ] a
guy in a truck drove by and threw out
bags of edibles
he drove buying gave out plants yeah I'm
90% sure it was somebody advertising for
another shot that was not at all getting
business right but it might have just
been one of us who had blown his stack
with joy it could have gone either way I
didn't get up-close and investigates I
didn't want to lose my awesome spot in
line
right because by then I was halfway
through a two-hour line but there's some
shenanigans to be expected but it's day
four seven now or whatever whenever this
is gonna air we've had a week now
every ID gets checked every rule gets
followed if you've got a problem with
the rule get a lobbyist and get a lawyer
change the rules to stay level so that
they work better for everybody you
should already [ __ ] skirt it right
different kind of lawyers
but yeah it's it's really important now
that if you're in the legal industry
that you step all the way up we have to
put our best foot forward right now
every state you guys every state in
every upcoming state this applies to you
know if the medical shops in California
headed all tried to put their best foot
forward ever
from 1996 till now it would have [ __ ]
legal a decade ago [ __ ] but I mean
just like in Colorado we had to deal
with dr. reefer the boulder city council
right now is talking about dialing
regulations back down to reality because
we've gotten rid of and I [ __ ] quote
the doctor reefers of this world like
they're done now they're all out of
business talking about how they used to
own a dispensary you don't even know
that one of my buddies owned a shop
called doctor reefer in Colorado Springs
do you know remember the kid they used
to sell us the Hindu Kush vaguely doctor
reefer there was a the doctor reefer in
question is the one up in Boulder he had
a twirling sign guy and that's what
everyone in Boulder was fired up about
this is wildly inappropriate twirling
sign yeah we can't have whirling sign
guys there's specifically banned because
of this [ __ ] you can you can twirling
sign for your tax return place you can
totally sign for cheeseburgers
you can't whirling sign for El Pollo
Loco but not for cannabis you can't eat
for your vape shop yep yep yep alright
we're way off topic here I'm gonna give
this article has more words written in
it and they say he said customers told
them they've been writing waiting all
their lives for a moment like this they
expected to sell sixty thousand dollars
worth of marijuana throughout the day
there were no reports of arrests or
other problems involving the early sales
in the state most stores planned to open
later in the day Oregon is one of four
states that have legalized the sale of
recreational marijuana business began in
Oregon with far more dispensaries than
did Colorado or Washington state where
pot shops have been up and running for
more than a year Alaska could begin
retail sales next year big shout-out to
Charlo Greene foster buds PD exes you
might be going to jail you've been
following that story no she has not or I
have not her if it keeps getting rated
because as you said shops not till
whenever they're trying to do
Janklow of some kind yeah yeah Sharla
take care yourself beautiful don't end
up in jail I need you out there fighting
the good fight for us um or why my
foster buds in PD a foster buds PDX in
Portland had a couple hundred customers
since opening just after midnight shop
manager Ken Martin said it's just been a
steady flow he said adding that
employees repeatedly refill jars with
pot to meet the demand two customers
came in used to that ship oh yeah just
keep filming you'll get there start
writing down how much came out of the
bag which bag number which jar it went
into yep keep going I've watched it a
billion times two customers who came in
had just turned 21 he said davia Fleming
I don't know if I read your name right
Divya Divya Divya Fleming of Portland
the first buyer in the keys store said
the atmosphere was upbeat for the launch
of the new industry it's the end of
prohibition said Fleming who uses the
drug for many medicinal purposes you
guys if I ever mentioned that I was the
first person to buy recreational
cannabis at the greener side dispensary
in Pueblo Colorado woohoo I was first
[ __ ] anyway I'm pretty sure I talked
about that that was like way a long time
ago the store offered its first 25
customers 35 to 40% discounts and was
handing out soda coffee juice and other
refreshments McKee said many stores in
Oregon were trying to lure customers
with extended hours food giveaways and
discounted marijuana shoppers who have
shoppe errs have one more incentive to
buy early and often under Oregon law
Papa purchases will be tax-free until
January a savings of up to 20% that's a
good way to do it get people to come in
and see how it goes and then start
charging tax that's pretty nice the one
thing I really like about Oregon's law
is they're really looking to kick the
black market in the balls nice so no
taxes for the first little bit so you
know it's the old street theory that
they threw at us in middle school in
there yep you get a taste that cheap yep
you want a free joint
welcome to the selection welcome to the
quality control welcome to the quality
increases welcome to the guy being here
on time we'll hit you in the nuts with
the taxes manana yep yep yep no more
watching how it's made for two hours so
that it doesn't look like foot traffic
none of that just walk in have your mind
blown with awesome weed product and
right alright the article goes on to say
store owners say they're hopeful they
can avoid the shortages and price spikes
that followed the start of legal sales
last year in Washington and Colorado
Alaska could begin retail sales next
year I think I already read that huh
once were offered a goodie bag with
t-shirts but no free marijuana it sounds
like the spot another we'll have a live
band and 10% discounts several stores
have erected billboards in Portland a
shop in Maryland is advertising on the
radio I'm just trying to basically stock
up from maybe four or five times with
the normal volume would be said Chris
Byers owner of River City dispensary in
Merlin customers can buy as much as
seven grams at a time of dried marijuana
flower and leaf the part that's
generally smoked Plus plants and seeds
dried flower and leaf hopefully there's
not a lot of leaf in there yeah
basically buds is what they mean yeah
some of the some of the people that
write wheat articles need to hang out
with some weed heads right for the next
year or so
pop infused candy cookies oils and
lotions will be available only to people
with medical marijuana cards as the
state works on retail regulations for
those products Oregon has a robust
supply supply system that has supported
medical marijuana users and the black
market companies have invested in
massive warehouses in Portland to grow
the drug indoors and Southern Oregon has
some of the nation's best conditions for
outdoor cultivation growers don't face
strict regulations yet so the supply can
more easily flow into retail stores than
it did in Washington and Colorado still
there is concern summer has historically
been a time of marijuana shortages in
Oregon and most of the outdoor crop that
is ready to heart and most of the other
crop is not ready to harvest sorry I
skipped were there indoor growers have
had minimal time to ramp up production
because lawmakers only approved the
October 1st start date three months ago
and they had time to get one quick crop
in we've got a seasonal drone I said
Jeremy Pratt
he said we kind of have a seasonal
growing market here in Oregon said the
owner of nectar cannabis which has four
stores in Portland we have lots of
products in the fall and then it kind of
gets tight this time of year anyway
green oasis which has two locations in
Portland and more on the way has
prepared by trying to cultivate strong
relationships with growers
it will entice customers Thursday
evening with an outdoor band and offer
10% discounts to those who spend at
least $40 Kohinoor Matthew Schwimmer
said we don't know if anyone else is
doing a band and we thought it was a
good idea to give back to the community
Schwimmer said so that's the article you
guys big congratulations to the state of
Oregon they have now got recreational
cannabis sales it is tax-free until
January so if you're doing the circuit
make sure you go stop in Oregon make
sure you get yourself is that where the
[ __ ] donut shop is and everybody
talks about that's where those donuts
are go get some tasty donuts and then go
get yourself some recreational cannabis
shout out the donuts haven't eaten to me
donuts lately but shout out to donuts
yourself some recreational cannabis in
the state of Oregon you guys yeah make
sure you're 21 and make sure they check
your ID and if they don't check your ID
call them out on it and tell me that
they're not following the rules they're
gonna [ __ ] it up for the future yeah if
if you listen to the show and you
haven't had a chance to legally purchase
cannabis start saving for a plane ticket
if you're 21 if you're 21 if you're 21
just change your world when I think of
what I used to deal with to buy weed
like what was just standard when I was
in high school and in college and then
in my 20s it was just a nightmare
especially in retrospect like it was
just life when it was happening it
wasn't that bad like I didn't mind
watching how it's made that much but now
that it's totally legal and I work in a
pot shop and it's just like picking up a
cheeseburger on the way home it's so
much better yeah if I was afraid of it
at first big it's so much better I can't
adequately put it into words well I came
from the black market and I was afraid
of all of this and it's I don't know
freaky to a lot of people it's a huge
change if you live in a non legal state
you worry about what do you I don't know
how much weed you buy but when half of
it is gone you start thinking about [ __ ]
where am I gonna get more wheat cuz
there's no reliable spot I never have to
think where am I gonna get my next bag
of weed because
if I don't if I don't grow it I can go
to the shop in which I work or I can
drive to one of my other buddy shops or
I can drive to one of my other friend
shops or I'm also a medical marijuana
patient so I could drive to a medical
dispensary excuse me I'm trying to burp
I can drive to a medical marijuana to
shop and get whatever cannabis I need in
there so it is a little bit better that
way it made our more available way more
available
it made weed more advanced the
innovations that have come with this
legalization have been incredible
so I like it I think it's way better but
I fear this so much better legalization
it's beautiful we can do so many things
like it's not so like I never had
trouble finding pot before in my life it
never came up
I might have trouble locating good pot
or the same pot Wow and it was always
horseshit whatever you bought like it
was never what they said it was right
you'd ask do you have any of this and
they go oh yeah and they'd go get a
handful of something different if you
like this is the name you said yep um
and you just believed it that was the
best you had hopefully you weren't
getting cheated and that was just life
now weed there's ten stores within a
15-minute drive from both our homes yeah
and that's pretty much true across
Colorado with this yeah and you can go
to two or three of them and see what you
do and don't like if every shops got
different pricing every shops got a
different selection there are major
companies across Colorado where you can
kind of find their stuff everywhere sort
of like Coke and Pepsi like you don't
have to go cheap with you store yet she
would choose cheap you choose
Incredibles there in almost every shop
that appear like there's a handful of
major edible companies that are
everywhere now I feel bad for the
delivery people that's a lot of
paperwork
Dixie like there's a bunch of them and
it's just beautiful you walk in and
there's 3040 I mean sometimes only five
or six but there's a selection of buds
you get a look at them smell them you
get to know the price like it's not
weird that you drove someone's house and
spent 20 minutes in the living room and
you don't want to buy this you can just
thanks and leave ya if you know why if
you go to the dispensary you don't like
what's in there you can leave you don't
have to buy anything there yeah and
people ask me what the minimum purchases
it's like nothing if you don't want any
of this please you don't have to buy
like I'll show you around everything and
you can leave knowing what's going on
but dick and then go look at a few other
places you can find nothing yeah like
half the time when you do that I give
you a coupon book with everybody in the
town listed there you go I just need
something to do for the day so guys
don't feel obligated to buy something if
you're in a dispensary and you don't
like what you see don't ever bet your
money you work for that you're not
wasting their time that's a store you
can go there and do what you need to do
if you're a marijuana fan you're gonna
like what you see yeah it almost any
shop you go to especially if it's the
first shop you go to I went I was in
Colorado Springs hiking one day and I
had a friend with me I had hash with me
I just travel with dads I don't really
take flowers with me we called them you
guys that aren't Colorado connoisseurs
we called the buds we just call it
flowers no I didn't have any flowers
with me and somebody wanted to smoke
some weed and so we're driving and I was
like a look at dispensary and we pull up
dude I would not smoke anything in that
[ __ ] place it all smells exactly the
same there's no difference on any of
these strains like it was yeah I just
left I didn't need anything out of there
I've left many a mini shop yes some of
them aren't up to par some of them only
still exist because enough of the
population legitimately had to stop
smoking weed 30 years ago because it was
too risky for him and only now that
they're retiring and that their kids are
grown are they getting out and trying to
buy weed again I mean for 30 years they
didn't know who to call
yeah and we're too worried about asking
their friends and neighbors about losing
their jobs or custody of their kids or
whatever yeah you know they just didn't
and now they can just pull up to a ship
walking and ask for an eighth I don't
know those people
I talk to every day have super silver
hair and huge smiles it's fun I've been
working outside of the shop lately at my
job that I've been doing - just required
some cleaning of some [ __ ] that's taken
about a week and I've been out in the
back
with the door open and I see a lot of
people walk by because there's a parking
area of there and they walk by me most
of the people that I see are older folks
it's not a lot of young punks buying
weed it's older folks that used to smoke
back in the day like you're saying that
have kids that are in college now like
yeah you see him come in you see a
20-something college kid come in with
his mom or his dad and they go buy weed
together and I think it's really funny
to see that [ __ ]
most of the 21 22 year-old people I see
you're on family vacation that's awesome
yeah it's a lot of fun we get a lot of
younger people too but definitely the
tourist economy is is retirees if you
think about it it makes sense if you're
22 there's no reason to fly to Colorado
to buy weed except for the enjoyment of
buying legal cannabis and getting to see
what the selection and the hypes all
about because you know 30 people this
we're happy to sell you a bag of weed or
at least one or two yeah there's no
reason to come here and spend the money
on the flight for what you can do at
home already but if you're 65 there's
still a lot of risk in Oklahoma
[ __ ] yeah there's none here and it just
blows people away I heard that at least
twice three times a week know where I'm
from this is that this is really frowned
upon we would get in so much trouble for
this everyone would think bad about us
if they knew that we were here doing
this like please don't tell my friends
and family and it's like lady you're
from Georgia I don't know your people
I'm not gonna call your congregation you
guys if you come here and get some weed
don't try to take it home smoke it all
here smoke it all here if you can't
finish it call me you can drop it off at
my spot there are a lot of locals that
are happy to help you finish the bag you
over purchase it is it is legal to give
your weed away to somebody who is over
21 if you've got cannabis and you bought
it in Colorado and you're about to get
on the flight you're about to fly home
or you're about to drive back across the
border stop at the last gas station in
Colorado before you hit the border or
[ __ ] while you're at the airport you
see some dude with some dreadlocks and
try not to give it to someone who's at
work
yeah that's a good idea don't get well
unless it's me cuz I can't a queen I
can't actually if they have dreadlocks
that last statement doesn't apply right
so yeah if you're walking through the
airport you got extra weed on you and
you see somebody with dreadlocks they
just flew in they need some weed just
hand him your bag maybe I should
rephrase that like okay so the guy that
works at McDonald's really wants your
unfinished bag of weed he could really
use that kind of charity and sort of pat
on the back but if you give it to him at
the drive-thru window he's gonna get
fired you were trying to do something
nice so have him meet you outside real
quick yeah catch him in the parking lot
way off topic we've gone for a long time
let's wrap up this show hey Mike thanks
for coming over dude happy team you look
like you're beat by now I am I'm ready
to go home grab something take another
dab and pass out all right well then I'm
gonna let you do that you guys I want to
thank you for listening to the show and
I think each and every one of you for
tuning in to the girl from your art
podcast episode number 100 is on its way
I'm not sure what we're gonna do yet I
think we're just gonna party I'm gonna
try to get a bunch of people on the show
I might take a bunch of big fat
ridiculous dabs
we go around table a bunch of coffin
yeah that's pretty much it a square
table with a bunch of coughing I like it
I like it
all right you guys I would appreciate it
if you'd support us on all the social
media stuff the book Twitter email you
know all that good stuff
on Facebook it's just brought from your
heart on Twitter it's at G fyh podcast
on Instagram you guys I use I read
genetics that's my seed company I read
genetics check it out on Instagram
ordered about eighteen point three
thousand followers right now so please
jump in there I'd love to have you as
one of my followers I've been posting a
lot of cool stuff been posting pictures
of a commercial grow that is pretty damn
impressive
those pictures are just gonna get better
and better yeah the rest as time goes
I'm just taking my iPhone using the
iPhone I've been taking the good camera
to work it and taking any pictures so
when I do that people will chip they
pants yeah all right
um let's see I'll be back on Monday with
another episode gosh I just realized how
close number 100 is next is 99 and then
after that is number 100 we're gonna
have to have a party
yep yep Mike you sound like you're beat
bro let's wrap this [ __ ] up guys I don't
think I have a lot else to say there is
the donation button on the podcast page
check it out go to I read genetics
Colorado comm click on the girl from
your heart podcast on the top right
there is a PayPal tab you can click on
that and if you feel like that this
podcast was worth a couple of dollars or
a contribution of some sort you can
throw in 50 cents you can throw in 50
thousand bucks or anywhere in between
they will all be appreciated I will give
you a shout-out on the show but I'm
never gonna charge you guys for this
podcast but if you feel like making a
contribution I would love it the podcast
is always going to be free free free
free free free you guys the show is
available on iTunes and stitcher every
single episode will always and forever
be archived on I read genetics Colorado
dot-com I think that's it you guys
thanks to Mike for taking time away from
his kid big shout outs a little Davey um
big shout out to mama
and also big shot with minun just Vince
thanks again for listening you guys
until next time take a phat dad and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
iluminates from inside
searching strange places times and
travel then you lose the battle and get
left behind when you throw your left
mitzrayim four-fifths got left behind yo
yo yo yo
[Music]
you