yeah welcome back hand of his community
it's time for episode number 99 of the
girl from your heart podcast your source
for cannabis news education and
conversation it's right your new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a veteran dabber
you're a cannabis activists or even
someone who's just curious about the
current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Rasta
Jeff I wanna thank you guys for joining
me stop down that music a little bit
we're getting carried away already today
dude I said 99 and it blew my mind 99
man Wow thank you I means next 100 we're
just gonna park my mom yeah cool well
I'm honored to have Vargas with us
sitting in front of me is a regular
guest a frequent guest how many ups does
you've been on lately bro a bunch in a
row a bunch in a row well thanks for
coming back we got our buddy white Mike
over there what's up looking good on
Mike too and sitting to my left is a
good friend of mine I'm actually Doug's
medical marijuana caregiver welcome to
the show my good buddy Doug thank you
very much I wish we had some crowd noise
for that Doug's a good friend of mine I
am his caregiver and our topic for the
show is going to be the way that
different ways of consuming your
cannabinoids the way of using your
cannabis the way taking your medicine
differently affects your mind and your
body and maybe even your spirit a little
bit differently but before we get there
I'm gonna brag a little bit yeah I know
we've been talking about the spot to
spend three a whole bunch on this
podcast because it's awesome Mike and I
spend a hundred and thirty two hours per
week there and it's a great spot to be
it's a great place to be I think that's
what I meant to say whatever it's a
great spot to be in ah but anyway
yesterday we were wrapping up work and
the boss walked up to me and he said
mandatory meeting today five o'clock at
the Pueblo Convention Center and I
smiled and I said really and he goes
yeah I put on your Sundays because we're
in the top three
so we
get there and it was the best of pueblos
convention and our spot won the best
dispensary in Pueblo we took first place
we got the gold
if anybody can vote it's a local
competition for I think they're 180
categories this year ranging from like
best teacher to best cop to that's a
very best lawyer dresser and we wrote
one best dispensary yep best dispensary
so we've got a little gold plaque in the
office and we're gonna be well
advertised and now we've got something
to brag about in the paper today for our
picture yeah we have a really cool
picture we took a picture in front of
the Bob Marley mural nice picture
everybody out there there's a color
tomorrow 8:00 in the morning taking a
picture a bunch of people that work at
our dispensary where that you were the
best now they know now they know and
we've got a year to brag about that yep
one whole year all right well let's get
into there I'm done bragging big shout
out to Rob at the spot big shout out to
the whole team at the spa everybody that
does everything they do the grow team
that a bud team the trimming team the
bud tenting crew all the managers
everybody that signs the paychecks Big
Shot it to everybody that's involved at
the spot I like working there you guys
are kick-ass and let's keep kicking ass
you guys well done everybody
ya know then let's get off the Tooting
our own horn and advertising or work all
the time on the show not a why we're
really here today yeah so these two guys
have been responsible for their medical
marijuana for over five years that I can
say for sure without a doubt yeah
probably closer to five or six years
okay I was gonna say closer to eight or
ten maybe even it's getting there it's
getting there okay yeah I don't have a
good sense of time I honestly do not do
that honest I used to remember time
periods by what fish shows I went to
yeah I've been doing a lot of fishes yes
I used to document yeah how much time I
was spending places all right so I've
been responsible for these guys as
medical marijuana and I have noticed
that when Mike wants to get high he
wants to smoke some sativa like some
Jillybean that we just took dabs over
some golden goat but when Mike needs
medicine he reaches for the heavy CBD I
got this jar over here if either one of
you would like a dam this big crystal
clear oil that's almost pure CBD that
was given to me
we're both staring
when these guys excuse me for the coffee
when these guys are hurting when they
feel pain they hit me up and they're
like do you have something extra CBD for
me right now cuz Mike's got sore hands
Mike's our Doug was an old railroad
worker over here you got a picture this
guy he's in jeans and a flannel shirt
with a big-ass knife on his Bell this
man looks like he is ready to do some
work whatever you need done I'm sure and
confident Doug can handle that work I'm
gonna certainly give it a shot
yeah I'm sure you'd get it done a little
better than myself well maybe depending
on water was that's true that is true
there are some things that I bet I could
do but Doug's a confident man he can
work it but he's an old railroad guy and
so he's pretty much broken all over the
place
broken all over the place yeah back
knees all the joints all the joints are
in bad shape and so I think that AG E's
got a little bit you know yeah well yeah
you're getting a little bit up there do
you mind if I ask you how you'll old
you're on the show my friend not at all
I'm 61 years old so my friend Doug is 61
and medical cannabis is keeping this
student moving then he hurts we give
them some CBD do you have a family were
just gonna kind of jump into this part
do you have a favorite way to consume
your CBD medicine um my my favorite way
to consume is with my little electric
pen okay my old lady calls it the
pacifier because it's always around my
neck it's hanging on a lanyard you never
know when you're gonna need it and it's
one of the most resin coated you can
tell that that thing has been around the
block well you know it had to have a
little extra work done to it because
those glass tops just don't work for me
oh yeah I know how you get been a little
modified there that's pretty it's custom
but it but it works really good it's
there at a moment's notice
okay and it's the way out that seems to
well anytime you smoke it we all know
that that that's the quickest way to get
it yes and when you're in pain and you
want relief now I find that's the
quickest way so what's gonna hurt most
frequently if we're hanging out what are
you gonna say [ __ ] this hurts what are
you gonna grab first my hip your hip my
hip my lower back okay so then you're
probably gonna say [ __ ] that hurts
Kanade is gonna be where's my vape pen
right exactly how long from inhaling off
okay first how many rips off that pen
does it take to kind of give you a
little relief to notice some easing of
the pain mmm
to notice easing of the pain Republican
doctor as I asked the Robley within two
or three two or three ribs off the veil
tell you the truth I'd like the truth
holding you're not under oath or holding
the damn thing in my hand and knowing
that I'm about to take a hit off of it
starts the process right there because I
know relief he's an honest way is on its
way and I think I've told you this
before your definition of what a pain
killer is we know that CBeebies help
control pain but marijuana in general
changes your outlook on pain okay so I
think it's and what is pain relief I
mean that's what that's what pain
killers do is they well we know that
there there's chemicals that go in and
right shut down certain receptors maybe
uh maybe the THC part is making you
forget that you her and helping your
mind go to a better place and stop being
focused on that exactly going out on you
and hurt okay right okay so two or three
rips and you start feeling that
forgetting about the pain and a little
bit of pain going away yes how long does
that take hmm okay so it starts right
then immediately within about two or
three rips which only takes you know
thirty seconds okay able to go back to
doing whatever you needed to do take
care of the kid water the dog yeah walk
the dog
I see why he's got a dog that needs a
lot of walking so ya seen walking with
buddy buddy the dog yeah so within 30
seconds now if you were to take and I
won't even ask any about about any
pharmaceuticals that I know you take but
if you were to take a pharmaceutical to
treat that pain oh no 20 minutes 20
minutes you know if you're lucky and
then what are the side effects
well he just leaned back into the life
flow you got all day and we do so I take
your truck opioids right which is the
major ones okay
anywhere from the dry mouth to listless
feeling to constipation okay for that
well that's their that's the way they do
medicine anymore at all absolutely it's
just prescribing other medication and
see how that work is it you on skype no
I know that I've done that before I will
never do that again
skyping with your doctor is not a good
thing
I want my doctor to touch me yeah well
you know you'd like to be able to look
around the room and see the diplomas
with just a shirt on cuz that's you know
that's all you see it's not like you can
look around and you're like you know
there's interaction between humans that
doesn't happen on Scott absolutely right
especially someone from your generation
yeah Skype is probably [ __ ] Fingal
technology for you yeah yeah and try to
keep current but sky we don't expect you
to be that current I was periscoping
earlier you guys and Doug had no idea
what was happening for the first thirty
seconds of that periscope video no
what's he talking to I actually said I'm
going to periscope for a minute alright
so we'll get back on topic here so
within 30 seconds to a minute you're
feeling relief from the CBD your pain
and your hip isn't earn but 20 minutes
if you take some medicine and do it all
so thanks a lot for getting let me get
so personal ask about your medicine and
tell me the side effects I'm sure that's
gonna deep compared to taking pills and
I don't see why we can't grow our own
why they don't want us to grow our own
medicine when this dude can feel better
in 20 minutes from taking a ripoff of a
vaping blow it's money it works so well
I like what you say it is money if
cannabis didn't do half of what it does
like it would be legal we discovered it
right now it would be celebrated
everywhere so it should print that on a
shirt if cannabis didn't do half of what
it does it wouldn't it would be illegal
yeah yeah it's true if it if it just
worked as medicine if we could just
replace you know cotton with
like all the pharmacies we can just do
one replaced by it yep I don't know
about all like there's still use for
plenty of what Pharma has to offer it's
just cannabis replaces a lot of what
we're using in a Pharma inappropriately
for now you bet
anyone that's taking vicodin realizes
that just up the uptick from I think a
grade two or grade three to agreed to
narcotic yep so there's no refills you
have to go to your doctor you have to
get a hard script from them and walk it
to your pharmacy it has to be filled out
on a certain day it's it's incredible
and and the reason is because of the
incredible losses that we've had of life
due to overdose right and it's on the
streets everywhere it's easier sometimes
to find stupid drugs and pills than it
is to find weed before we had
dispensaries dispensaries we could find
the weed but back in the day it you'd
run into other drugs and can't find the
weed right yeah and it's not that hard
it's actually would be easier for me to
get some of this medication on the
street than it is from the dog right or
anyone and then that's what
unfortunately results to in heroin use
when you can't get those pills any more
from your insurance company without your
doctor being unavailable then you're
gonna have to go and I know you wouldn't
do it you're another dude you got a
strong mind and keep you medicated with
good weed but other folks that don't
have good weed and a good caregiver and
a good family like yourself they would
have to go to the street and get
something because everybody hurts
they're sick from not having their pills
that's what these states are facing an
increase in heroin use right now and
that's exactly why is regular folk get
hurt they go to the doctor the doctor
throws opiates at them
they take the pill until their bones not
broken anymore and by the time they're
healed though they're now addicted to
whatever painkiller they were alright
find it eventually they get cut off or
it becomes too expensive and they turn
to heroin get some help if you need help
you guys that's what I'm saying please
and feel free to tell the doctor no you
don't need pain pills like sometimes you
pain pills I'm not saying people don't
because I've used them many many times
but like when I broke my finger I had to
refuse pain meds six different times I
kept asking if the pain was gonna get
any worse
I kept looking at me like I was insane
vibrates stupid loud music what is
happening figure out no problem no
worries at all alright
so Mike I won't ask you the same
question kind of that I was asking Doug
since we got off track here and I need
to find a good launching spot um can I
ask what your medical condition is that
you smoked for and you don't have to go
to any detail if you don't feel like it
the short version version is I damaged
my neck and never had cartilage in my
knees and so I need something that helps
with inflammation and nerve generated
pain and cannabis works wonderfully
where most of the drugs available on the
pharmaceutical market don't do anything
for nerve generated pain no so how long
if you took it what's your preferred
method of smoking right now dabbing yeah
we boil we've currently upgraded like
smoking status month or two ago those
flowers he was a heavy flower smoker in
a pipe right yep pipe in pipe and
flowers are bong in bong and flowers if
I had a bong handy but I broke my
beautiful bong a while ago rest in peace
bond yep and have just been piping it
for a long time and then recently
upgraded to an oil rig and a nice nail
and a torch and I've been doing a lot of
dabs lately but flowers are still sort
of my first love Mike should I put some
delicious Jilly bean hash today big
shout out for that right on thank you
that's a delicious yeah yeah but
honestly the most common way I consume
these days is with tincture really I do
three milliliters of synergy which is a
half THC half CBD tincture compound
that's really really low dose and I take
it sort of as a preventive morning and
evening to help keep the inflammation
down before it gets bad and that seems
to work wonders for my knees and for my
back what do those cost for a customer
uh
forty forty bucks before tax for a
hundred milligrams total so for me
that's a week's worth of meds okay Wow
okay forty bucks for a week worth of
meds yep you get thirty doses per bottle
and I'm taking six a day so it's not
even a seven-day week for me it's a
five-day week for me all right
dang okay so it's worth it for 40 bucks
I was paying more when I was just taking
pills oh yeah oh yeah pills are
expensive yep even if you've just got a
copay or something pills yeah I was just
doing a copay and it was still 90 bucks
a week
I got some vicodins when I got some
wisdom teeth pulled they're going to get
those was like 14 bucks for like seven
pills and that was the generic [ __ ] I
don't even really need them why not a
bunch of money for when I stopped taking
pills I was on two different pain
medications
neither of them were opiates but neither
of them worked for [ __ ] either and then
I was on a third med to help cope with
some of the side effects from the first
two of course and when I started smoking
regularly and first got access to CBD
flour I didn't have a need for the pills
at all the next day so I just didn't
take them one day and then I didn't take
him the next day either nice so now
you're drug-free well except for
cannabis your drug-free bro I don't
think is like a drug that's a plant man
it's a plant totally a drugs just a very
good one so how long does this go ahead
to get some sale well no I was just
interesting what he was saying but I was
thinking while he was saying that that
since I'm primarily using concentrates
now I got incomplete
of two narcotic medications that I was
getting through my doctor Wow
from smoking concentrates on a daily
basis
smoking concentrates on a daily basis
how long how often do you smoke probably
starting within an hour after I wake
okay
yeah because you got to keep the pain
away before it sets in right yeah so get
a head start on the pain and then
throughout the day it's not like a sit
down smoke fest for me it's it's just
you've dipped the pacifier hanging on
your neck so you got it right around my
neck take a couple of rips and as I'm
going on my merry way that's one of the
things I really like about my pen I find
myself using it when I get home
between like walking in the door from
work and then like getting the dogs
taken care of getting the kid taken care
of getting dinner around getting you
know checking in with you other family
members seeing how their day went like
I've got [ __ ] to do I don't have time to
sit down and take a dad I put my feet up
for single life is pretty great isn't it
yeah the single life [ __ ] beautifully
male on and [ __ ] it's ready to go like
four rigs on the table to hit okay I
can't have this kitchen setup you had
four fourteen year olds walk into my
house at 3:30 today like looking for a
place to spend an hour you know it
becomes a permanent roosting place oh
yeah all right
so how much hash how long does a grandma
hatch last year that's what I think I
want to ask I'm kidding grandma hash
lasts me maybe four days tops okay so
you're getting out in about a quarter
grandma of good quality you guys this is
the same house that I smoked this is
Doug gets the hash that I smoke when I
get a slab I break some off and it goes
to Doug's direction every time I know
when Doug needs hash I've got I'm kind
of on a good schedule I see this and
yeah so I tried to get mine around the
same time and we all like it
he gets the same [ __ ] that I get he
smokes what I smoke you guys so he's
smoking top quality shatter sometimes
it's wax if others
good wax around but it's usually top
quality snap in general type shatter -
yeah we shatter garden of Weeden shatter
90% of the time or your terp expose when
the Turks boys which is also very good
there we go so he's smoking the same
stuff as me about a quarter gram a day
through a vape pen to keep himself
medicated you guys you can get that at a
medical dispensary it's gonna be thirty
thirty-five bucks at a rec shot Mike how
much is a gram of turn pax ash gonna
cost us 50 plus tax comes to 50 and
change at the door yeah yeah 55 58 bucks
at 58 58 bucks if you don't think that
scares all of us that are on medical
marijuana that see dispensaries changing
from just medical to medical and
recreational and possibly to just
recreational you're wrong it does oh I
see it yeah well I'm gonna do my best to
keep taking care of you guys and that's
why you guys are here I'm actually gonna
take Doug to renew his medical marijuana
card on Wednesday yeah we keep up on
that you can find wreckage in a range of
prices between like 25 and 30 gram up to
98 gram here locally but it's not always
quality no there's still a lot of real
mediocre amateur product on the market
right now because we're are even our
legal market doesn't have all of the
things in place that it should quality
standards are still a little axe we're a
little off topic did you buy any of the
live wax from the spot the tiara
concentrates I have not purchased any
but I have consumed some I would like a
review of that stupendous stupendous
that works for one word just the word I
got some dozen flavors on the shop now
but I got some of the star dog and it
was incredible guys I maybe investigate
investing in so I just the night I
dropped my rig I got to try it and so
that was the consolation ten minutes
later while I was mourning the loss of
my original rig
I got to hit some what was 98 gram is
now 75 gram hash
uh-huh very cool yep very cool let me
step in there after after work tomorrow
and grab some of that and a couple other
things all right call me if you do yeah
all right so I asked Doug how quickly it
works how he consumes it and how much of
it he uses now I want to jump to Mike
we've talked about how he's using
tinctures I want to ask about when
you've been dabbing lately how many dabs
does it take for you to feel relief one
to feel relief two to kind of push the
pain down to where it's sort of like
your toe edge is it's no longer
something of it's something you're aware
of but it's not something of importance
and that's how I feel after work is
usually about three what I think of as
Mike sighs dabs which are fairly small
dabs after a third day yeah I was gonna
say maybe 0.1 a dab maybe even a little
less than that sometimes but after about
three like there's some intoxication and
like a lot more fun going on then then
just medical effect but that first dabs
all just turning the pain down from a
five down into the one or a two range
all right so two and a half dabs would
be cool but you take that number three
because you can't take a half dab right
and then uh then there's something then
there's some intoxication going on all
right but get but you can handle six or
eight - yeah I can sit here and take
eight or ten and still be coherent a
little giddy all right so let's get to
the the synergy drops that you've been
taken um you said you take three
milliliters how often a three
milliliters in the morning and the three
at night and the dosing is 1.7
milligrams of THC and CBD per milliliter
so if I remember this I'm taking about
5.8 milligrams of each in the morning
and then in the evening now I could
drink the whole 100 milligram bottle so
50 milligrams of both it just drink it
down like a shot or a chug like a beer
and not get much intoxication from it
but if I take it in small doses in the
morning in the evening it feels like my
knees now
we get to the point where they're really
swollen and stiff and achy okay and my
neck never gets to the point where it's
just a solid bar of muscle cramped up
trying to protect those vertebrae that
are squeezing nervous it's nerve stems
going down that arm all right and you
guys I feel like my mic is really hot
I'm sorry part of what why they're doing
the THC CBD combo is I believe that you
need both cannabinoids to get into your
bloodstream to work together to hit the
mind a little bit to take your mind off
of things to work on the the THC hits
the nerve pain I think the CBD goes for
the like the swollen stuff I think
together you don't get super high from
it you don't feel much high from the CBD
THC 50/50 combo because the CBD really
feels like it calms down the high it
does it's there's research into that CBD
keeps the THC high from being quite a
psychoactive so the the CBD helps kind
of tone it down there's I've heard
people carry CBD pills from time to time
when there's gonna be extreme
consumption going on just in case
anybody goes a little overboard they've
got sort of a come down lever that thank
your girlfriend takes a big dab and
can't handle her [ __ ] you just give her
a CBD dab and she'll relax a little in
theory in theory I hope so cartoons yeah
all right so how much does this energy
cost 40 a bottle yeah that's right yeah
okay and it lasts you a week five days
five days all right and Doug's plinth
pan if you go to a dispensary it's gonna
be 40 45 30 maybe 25 if you kids because
and find like member pricing and you get
that first-time shopper there's a couple
that I've seen advertised on certain
days at certain times right have a
special or something something like that
what
never been able to find a constant
quality like you deliver right well
that's the garden of Weeden so uh the
difference yeah between a good caregiver
a bad caregiver is being sort of
hammered out on this show I wish that I
did not have to charge Doug anything for
the hash that he consumes but it doesn't
always come from me so I have to go get
it so I have to just relay it and I
don't make a penny off of my my
caregiver Ernest for people like people
that I am their caregiver I don't know
Doug Steve's pretty well medicated yes I
do yes he does he's got some flow right
now yes I do tasting life some white
widow in a couple few days so will Mike
like just look to me like you know I
have that ever so often craving for the
flower just yeah you know I I'm a dad
okay what's uh [ __ ] gonna jump into
this one I take fat dad you guys my
knees hurt my knees [ __ ] hurt he does
river near me and heard me bend over or
crouched down my knees sound like
shotgun you can't be as tall as we are
and not have any issues yeah I think so
I think that's true cuz my knees get
wobbly sometimes when I'm tired like
they just get like shaky and my hips
hurt and then uh I've got some stomach
issues you guys and not a lot of but my
stomach sucks I've got some stomach
problems but so I take fat fat dabs you
guys I take some more between 0.3 and
0.5 I like to smoke about a gram and a
half a hash a day I do that in about
three sessions throughout the day I'll
take about one dab in the morning right
one like not right when I get up give
myself like get up get the morning
shower and get dressed
right before I leave I'll take one dab
just so that I'm kind of crispy when I'm
getting where I'm going at lunchtime I
may get a little dab like about a point
three and then do it bro take some of
that CBD oil and then after work I'll
come home and take like a point five and
then before the show I did about a point
five and then later on in the evening
before bed I'll just drop like another
point five instead of taking thirty dabs
throughout the day I take like six or
seven of them I guess maybe three to six
fat dabs throughout the day mm-hmm and
that keeps me well medicated it's
expensive but since I'm the I produce it
myself mostly like that part or I get it
from Spence garden of Weeden kind of
guys I don't know if I should be saying
that much on the show but since the
Weedon can supply us with quality hash
and dispensaries I work at a shop that
can supply me with quality hash then I
go to a medical shop and buy a bunch of
[ __ ] all the time but I smoke a lot and
I stay well medicated I like to eat
edibles but they hit me hard yeah hard
hat edibles hit you the yeah they hit me
hard too but it's because you're
consuming a hundred percent of it right
is sting within your body you're not
blowing out thirty five percent of what
you just to again right okay
it takes a little longer the rush is a
little different the way that it feels
when it starts to get into your
bloodstream I feel like it comes on
slower but hits a lot harder yeah I do
too I can more of a body healing crow
how did you do that did you take some
CBD oil and some of the jellybeans
prepared with the email cord and the dab
rig and the microphone in his face it
looks like the pothead Olympics yeah
some kind of stoner obstacle course
management [ __ ] cord management
alright cuz I want to ask him when he
gets done coughing I'm gonna ask him
about how he likes edibles and how they
work for him but Doug you were talking
earlier about how medicine just totally
uh helps your like psychological the
whole thing is that do you need a sativa
or does a CBD medicine get to your head
a little bit as well when you smoke the
Tora Bora the Tora Bora is really high
in CBD so you can use that as a specific
okay yeah and I really like the Tora
Bora
shout out to DNA genetics for breeding
it and shout it to the person they got
me a cut there we go yeah you can tell
between different strains even with some
that say there are the same string of
different ways that it affects you as
you as you're ingesting it
you know some more mentally than
physically so you kind of forget about
the pain before the relief of the pain
and sometimes just the opposite
all right the Tour Boras more of the
relief of the pain and then okay aspect
so it comes it knocks out the pain and
then later on it gets you high yeah all
right okay
okay I don't smoke a lot of the CBD
stuff you guys it doesn't do much for me
so these guys get all the CBD products
that I get I was gifted that hash if
Doug want to dab it out one give him a
dab of that one too Mike
make sure Doug get some TV it's hard to
get big dabs the CBD oil bit is super
this snappers got a flat tip on it they
may work a little bit better trouble
yeah mom's new was so cold it felt like
it was burning for a second you guys
winter is here in cold I don't know
about what your the fall is certainly
here in solar on Oh yep you need a
long-sleeve shirt when you drive to work
in the mornings and done changed yeah
you know and speaking medically I know
we're talking about pain yeah I'd love
to hear what you have to say but I'm
disabled with post-traumatic stress
disorder okay and I know there's been a
lot of studies looked at I think that
it's probably the best medicine for it I
had been prescribed many other things
but I believe that cannabis is probably
the best thing that I've ever had that
helps me control what goes on with that
you know I I don't want it yeah I
probably got a similar thing I don't
want to compare myself and I probably
got something I'll agree with you and if
I start thinking about [ __ ] then I don't
even want to think about I can make
those things not happen in my mind it's
just by coming and just taking a couple
of dads and it may be part of the ritual
like you were saying earlier I've just
done grab a dad get into the internet
play around for a minute my brain will
change yeah yeah it's also you know for
me it's real hard for Easter love to go
where anywhere there was lots of people
it's not that way anymore I really have
to get prepared to go to the grocery
store not because I don't know what I'm
gonna get because I get the same thing
every time but just to deal with with
people in close quarters is make you
nervous
it just makes me uncomfortable Oh guys
would rather not do if I come up in
parking lots completely full or you look
over in the baskets are almost all gone
I just go back home okay you know which
even if I really need the food go back
Oh chill for a little bit and wait for
the crowds to die down cheesy yeah not
that bad you know sometimes you can't do
that you know you got other people
depending on you then you suck it up and
you do it and sometimes faced with those
types of situations cannabis definitely
helps me deal with them okay it's a
little bit of anxiety oh yes a little
bit of social anxiety okay all right so
if anybody's listening that doesn't
think that this [ __ ] is good for PTSD
because in Colorado we cannot get it
validated as a No I can qualifying
condition for medical treatment or for
medical use if you guys think that
that's not a reason to use it
listen to this dude this is an honest
guy this dude has never lied to me I
believe every single word that Doug has
ever said yeah he's got a reason to lie
to me dude these kids and beyond the
[Laughter]
person that gave it to me I don't know
if they want to be mentioned on the show
or now they do nice work the pain is
mounting as we speak yes yeah that
cherry flavor yep yeah the CBD I saved
all that for you guys it's way over here
just kind of tucked away until you guys
showed up
that's delicious cherries it is it's
like a mouthful of cherries out of the
Hitman rate with the elevat-- drop down
on the e nail because we're champs over
here al you son climbed up there oh yeah
this carbon cap needs to be cleaned a
little bit they get quite filthy around
here anybody needs a dad there's a
little wax in here I think you guys be
cool for a minute
all right so Doug was talking about you
were talking about how
with the PTSD yeah you know and we you
know the military was looking into it
they found out that they didn't want to
do it right now but I think that if you
were toxin people that were suffering
from it I think we see a lot of them
around town now yeah absolutely
because this is where the help is yeah
yeah oh man so many people are coming
here any guys unfortunately what I've
discovered through some conversations
lately that a lot of children moving
here for CBD treatment betcha and those
people are falling into traps with
people that advertise that they can give
them CBD medicine and they're not
providing the CBD medicine unfortunately
if you're looking for qualified
legitimate CBD medicine in Colorado
somebody that can take on a new person
and provide that it's going to be a
three-month wait maybe six months yeah
the caregivers are strapped and with you
the new regulations taking effect in
January I doubt many more people will be
becoming caregivers I expect a number of
caregivers in business now to end up not
being caregivers sometime by the middle
of next year the state's really looking
to clamp down and kind of snap out that
whole section of our industry which
sucks for people like me and I
absolutely that's that's depressing
right now myself yep there's a lot of
new rules coming down the pipe that are
gonna make it incredibly difficult for
people to produce the amount of meds
they need for their patients and yeah
and that's been that's by design so they
want everybody buying from the stores
and we're gonna see Walmart type stores
in the future right yep well like we
talked about earlier I'm already having
this source other chatter to get you
guys supplied in your shattered because
everybody stepped up I don't know if it
was a good idea for me to step everybody
up to shatter smoke so much yeah I'm not
complaining but between the three of us
we clean out the garden that I grow yeah
you know and other people that I know
are everybody's looking towards
concentrates right because so much more
convenient and it works better all the
way around it's just a better product
right for me it's the time saver is what
I've been enjoying lately yeah if my day
is full my hours are very
well allocated I don't have extra time
to grind up some bud pack a bowl sit
there and puff on it for a little while
I just don't have that kind of time
anymore right
yep and a quick dab gets me where I need
to be and I can get back to doing
whatever I need to be doing you say take
a DAB cough for a minute chug soda and
get back to whatever I was doing oh the
other half of the yard I'm gonna make
fun of Mike for a minute but this is all
in good fun because he's one of my
favorite people to hang out with Mike my
bro he knows it
if you're ever with Mike and you were
thirsty just tap him on the shoulder and
say because Mike has a mountain dew with
him Mike probably has six to 12 Mountain
Dews I got mouthing yeah some people
carry like their cigarettes in like a
safe spot Mike's not Mountain Dews up
his sleeves aren't like you spider-man
all right so I appreciate you guys gonna
let me talk a little bit about your
conditions and [ __ ] you have any I want
to change your subject in just a second
but before I do I want to give you guys
the opportunity do you have anything to
add to this part before I kind of move
on to a totally random question that I
want to ask you guys about just cuz I'm
curious I'm looking forward to more
bigger selection of CBD edibles that
would be nice wouldn't it be nice to
just get up and eat like a muffin or a
bagel or whatever the way that this
industry is working you guys aren't
gonna be able to eat muffins and cookies
for much longer they're gonna regulate
the [ __ ] out of it so much that a muffin
will not be allowed you know if they can
airbrush that dumbass yellow triangle on
it they're good okay airbrush my poppy
seed muffin people get on it the
regulations are becoming really
ridiculous and it sucks some of my
favorite products you're gonna be
leaving store shelves and coming back in
ten milligram maximum containers which
sucks I like the drinks there's the kick
in times a lot quicker yeah oh yeah you
bet you did an empty stomach
I forget how spoiled I am being a
medical patient being able to walk into
a shop and get a drink with a hundred
milligrams
that sucker living on the REC side you
guys have to put ten milligrams in them
and drink ten of them the same effect
that's coming you can get a hundred
milligram drink right now but they're
taking that away if you can't carry the
stamp it's got to be in a 10 milligram
package period so if you can't stamp
your [ __ ] no more I mean you can't stamp
like what's periods two liquids
popcorns granolas that kind of things
got to come to ten milligrams so they're
actually going to put a stamp on
everything that's the plan yellow yellow
trying so that the teacher can see it
from across the room is like I've got a
triangle I'm like why isn't society
buddy whyatt but shouldn't be parenting
should you focus on parenting instead of
labeling a [ __ ] up analogy that I came
up with is we we put a special symbol on
the fake guns not the real ones we got
we got to put a special pimple assemblee
yep right now off all your toy guns got
to come with a little orange nub on the
[ __ ] front of it they do no real gun
doesn't need nothing on it that's like
just so you know this is a gun gun and
not like a look-alike gun or a squirt
gun I wish somebody could have seen me
pressing my for microphone in
retardation but but now that all the pot
cookies have to carry a special [ __ ]
warning symbol because people that have
never been in a marijuana shop are
convinced that they look just like Chips
Ahoy oh yeah and that they're gonna be a
party one day and one of us is gonna
change out the real Chips Ahoy
for the medicated chips of Hawaii no
wait and then they're gonna kill
everybody at their trip just nuts I'm
gonna share the cookies about you guys
my friends and I'm gonna tell you that
hey there's weed in these eat them with
me they've so much fear last Halloween
that we're definitely gonna pose get
ahead that way that was part of what I
was gonna ask here and then a minute I
had two questions for you in the
Halloween it was one of them because we
were putting up Halloween decorations at
the spot I was like do you guys really
think that somebody's gonna give out
some weed candy this year it might kind
of beat me to it so yeah last year
though they're gonna eat it themselves
yeah
the two big anti pod groups in the state
like took out billboards
with edibles out of their packaging next
to candy edible treats that they look
similar to it was like if you can't tell
the difference how were your kids and
not a whole bunch of people in this
state were convinced that the day after
Halloween like the ers would just be
full of kids that were just high yet it
didn't happen and it didn't happen for a
lot of reasons mostly because it's the
dumbest crime ever right like there are
so many better ways to get a felony you
can't hand out dirty candy on Halloween
and have like that leads right back to
you and there's no payoff for the
criminal there right you got about three
hours worth a he's a sick [ __ ] that
likes to hurt kids like doesn't like to
hurt kids in theory and it was expensive
right like 25 bucks a [ __ ] piece like
who's got that kind of money to get
local kids stoned right I'm gonna eat
them all if you guys think that you have
candy that your kids got on Halloween
and you suspect that it is medicated
with cannabis you seen that [ __ ] you can
send it right to me my name is Worcester
Jeff I've got a p.o box you can send it
now I shouldn't do that we'll come pick
it up in person let's [ __ ] all this mail
I want to get myself in trouble we'll
come pick it up call me I will eat all
of it or half of it whatever you choose
and a little bit I'll tell you if that
[ __ ] hasn't medicated cannabis in it
we'll see we'll see if it's a if it's
medicated with with THC it's always it's
always the scare tactic about the
children you know when I was a child and
went trick-or-treating people gave out
popcorn balls and fruit and then one
year there was a massive scare that
someone was putting razor blades in
those fruits and other things in your
cookies and all of a sudden you couldn't
take grandma's treats anymore they had
to go buy them from the store and they
had to be packaged and Mars company
loved it oh yeah who do you think did it
yeah the best marketing campaign Mars
can ever come up with that's almost too
smart just for a corporation a lot of
their kids let me feed you the snicker
oh no let me feed you this rednecks
brand can it's going
never put you on the news and will make
you rich I'm the type of [ __ ] who
spent four hours on the internet looking
for cases of there's no it's happened
like three times two of them were family
members that were like [ __ ] my dumbass
nephew I mean it's not funny but it's
really funny because if when you think
that the links we've gone to as a nation
to like every nice old lady that's ever
tried to make sugar cookies with all the
kids that come by and then like three
hours into Halloween they realize that
their [ __ ] sidewalks covered with
sugar cookies and all the parents think
they're insane because that they just
happen to miss that part of their our
mass education against taking delicious
treats from people on Halloween I need a
cookie from a whole lady she had no
reason to hate me a doll I've been to
Grateful Dead shows man you don't take
candy from strangers they got [ __ ] up
their whole weekend and as a responsible
try you look through that candy before
you gave your child just to make sure my
parents loved that rule I never got back
the number of Snickers I know I [ __ ]
something wrong with them maybe yeah we
used to go to the fancy neighborhoods
and find out where they were giving out
the best candy yeah I would take two or
three masks in my car because the
University Park hey at least I wasn't
stealing the bags some of my friends
were I've just taken bags from other
kids that was actually trick-or-treating
go Pueblo I pled my case the same lady
she's like you're too old I could have
just been out stealing candy from kids
and she's like here take two thank you
that's that's what I get yeah so um
let's shift gears happy Halloween oh you
guys this will be coming out a little
bit before the Halloween show
no since number 100 is gonna be
celebration the one after a hundred and
one will probably meet Halloween show
but whatever it's October this is the
fall celebration show cool it's harvest
party the boob
Parvez birdie or like that it's almost
darvis time we should get Jesse on here
just talking about more a lot of people
harvest then Java or if they got to keep
it it was also rather than just if you
have to keep it all right number 100 is
next holy [ __ ] so awesome great we're
gonna have a bunch of people on the
podcast and we're gonna talk about stuff
cool you know those shows when I set up
like six microphones and it gets chaotic
yep that's what we're gonna do
those are fun yeah we're gonna take dabs
it's gonna be loud Spence I'll hit
Maddie in the face with the microphone a
lot hopefully and get Maddie and Spence
over another episode yeah 50 times - it
would be twice as great kudos you guys
if you're listening to the podcast this
far I'd love you for listening to our
random banter be dedicated there's
something you remember from the first
hundred episodes that you'd like me to
reminisce about
send me your favorite moments of the
show let me know what you're thinking
about what makes you laugh your favorite
memories something that sticks out to
you on the show let me know what you
think of like remember that one time you
said this you can send a couple of you
know you're not limited to just one but
tweet it to me
it's @g fyh podcast email it to me it's
grow from your heart at hotmail.com or
find it on Facebook it's the girl from a
heart podcast on Facebook message me let
me know and we'll kind of reminisce
about it and go talk back about it on
the show if you let me know what episode
episode this you said this or just
whatever you know let me know what you
remember and we'll laugh about it again
I did say that sometimes they say some
goofy [ __ ] sometimes I say some great
[ __ ] remind me what stood out to you I'd
like to hear it yeah same goes for me if
you like something I said on the show
you guys have been getting a lot of me
lately you like it tweet me guys follow
Mike on Twitter what's your Twitter
handle
Nemo Punk 15 yeah at Twitter 5050 yeah
following cuz he wants some more
followers and when you follow him let
him know that you found him on the girl
from your art podcast let me know you're
tweeting earlier following me from the
POC just hit hashtag girl from each
podcast you saw me [ __ ] with
prohibitionists and thought it was funny
I wanted more of it yeah and if you find
me you're too stoned I'm not there we'll
keep him on the down-low
so lately guys the hot topic has been
we're just gonna go on this one for a
couple of seconds because I wrote it
down and I just want to be able to cross
it off because I'm a completionist how
do you guys feel about professional
athletes being able to use marijuana
first in their on season and also in
their offseason it's two different
subjects you're on the clock and not off
the clock i think when you're with the
team they kind of own you so we have to
make two separate separate subjects then
I say that wrong is I'm not good to say
you don't look like no I don't mean it
like that bro I do kind of maybe you do
yeah it really depends on your take on I
just you always be careful with that
particular verbage yeah in this case
you're not totally in the wrong they
live under some pretty insane [ __ ]
regiment yeah you're under seasoned well
it doesn't their house yeah so alright
so you're on the clock basically during
the on season the whole season from the
time season starts from whatever
preseason training times bring whatever
spring training when it starts you're on
the clock until that Super Bowl or
whatever your team is [ __ ] finished
do you fail or win right you're on the
clock so should you be able to use
cannabis to alleviate your pains or for
whatever reason [ __ ] it's a it's a
recreational state the genero protectant
research coming out that's really
promising it might really help deal with
concussions brain injuries that kind of
thing really yeah it might be insanely
[ __ ] helpful from the only get bashed
in the face for a living rugby players
people like boxers are just taking place
right now so you feel that on their
offseason is what I'm asking about now
you to consume cannabis medical or
recreational oh for sure yeah on there
during the offseason as much as they
brought as much as they'd like right
they can they can drink alcohol or only
takes in color okay in any state there
are adults in all 50 states
if I was King the world would have been
legal for everybody a long time okay
okay so then I'm sure you're gonna say
that yes to this one also do you think
that these guys and I'll ask about
specific sports after I generalize we'll
just will kind of narrow
down do you think that professional
athletes should be able to consume
cannabis on during the on season like
the night after a game maybe the day
before a game maybe what if you're a
better one
what if you're a better player when you
smoke a fat joint what should they be
able to play okay right
but how many other performance-enhancing
drugs are those other football players
using well see this is so not a joking
well no they're legitimately testing
people as though it's steroids right and
that when they're looking for steroids
they also look for pot is no they're the
same and that's nuts like about it the
best it's helping you focus on keeping
you from being in pain while you you
know what I mean it's not making you
stronger or faster no issues with people
consuming cannabis when they're not at
work okay like there are a lot of people
who do [ __ ] that's kind of well that's
why I'm thinking about sports like
football players crash into other people
with bodies yeah and yeah there's a lot
of power there like that needs to be
precisely controlled or somebody's gonna
die right and like I'm down for us to go
watch people kill each other but we need
to give them like swords and just call
it gladiatorial getting football players
intoxicated and letting them rush to
each other's not how we get there that's
gonna be one of the things people tweet
about Mike's point and me saying that
people own people I apologize now I
realize what I said sometimes we step in
the trap words are hard these days yes
I'm politically erect well everything
means eleven things
yes exactly alright so we all think that
sports athletes the professional
athletes should be able to consume
cannabis they're allowed to drink
alcohol if they so choose yeah and in
Colorado we've pretty much put the same
rules on booze or on the same rules on
cannabis so what they mirror it on yeah
they can most of us can go out after a
hard day of whatever we do
and we how many how many other people
slam into other people all day for a
damn living like why can't these people
go smoke a little bit of reefer if their
buddies can smoke and drink some beers I
can't I can't drink beer
beer is no good for me beer does nothing
good for me but smoking cannabis I have
plenty of medicinal value employment
benefits yep so I don't go drink beer
after work like several people do and
I'm not judging I'm saying that doesn't
work for me yeah I come home and smoke
some weed smoke some dad's it works
wonderfully we should have an
alternative hell great yeah completely
excellent so I mean it didn't have to be
confined to places where you can't be
seen absolutely yeah where you have to
hide adults like to gather and enjoy in
toxicants with other adults I mean it's
literally this way it's always been
you're taxing us for us or it give us
some more to consume it the first humans
around the first fire got there like
they gather to get [ __ ] up around it
like that's just how humans work there's
always been a tavern or I mean in
different parts of the country is the
street corner or in many cultures this
is where people get together enjoy
intoxicants and yeah having a place
where people can go and consume pot
together those are necessary we need to
get on it yeah yes we sure do that would
be great the whole country needs places
one or the floor in every state where we
can all just meet and have little puffs
sessions yep yep nails dab rigs be
awesome and not be harassed not be
harassed by the police that's all we
want you guys are just to be able to
smoke cannabis peacefully and hang out
and socialize there won't be as many
problems as you have with alcohol
consumption facilities stoned people
don't want to fight no no no no we can
all get pretty heated in this room we
have some arguing beliefs between us I'm
sure we should something big flying
swinging anybody there was beer and
dazed and confused right they were
drinking at the time do you wanted to
fight cuz he was a tepee I've watched
that movie with a number of people for
the first time and typically that's the
one comment that gets made through the
whole film is like why is he aggressive
he was just smoking weed was his weed
bad
that dude was drinkin he came there to
drink beer and kick ass or something
like that right they were all out of
beer yeah alright so we're gonna we're
gonna start wrapping up the show man I
really appreciate you guys for coming
don't you anything else you want to add
to us um yeah keep medicated keep
healthy there you go
[ __ ] I should I just we should just hit
stop points I feel like we didn't give
enough credit to edibles there's a lot
of really wonderful edible products in
the market right now that you should
definitely check out if you can yeah
what would you recommend to somebody
choose just [ __ ] went that recreation
about that I'm so sick of telling people
no they're not recreational yet the
recreational now you can look for them
on store shelves it's your ex ops in
Colorado so if you guys are out of state
if you're in if you're anywhere in the
world and you're 21 and up you can come
to Colorado fly to either Colorado
Springs or Denver Denver right at Denver
and drive [ __ ] the Colorado Springs
Airport Denver Airport it's gonna take
you two and a half to three hours to get
to our to our dispensary come on down
tell everybody that you heard about the
spot dispensary on the Grove from your
heart podcast grab yourself some Chiba
choose and grab yourself some quality
flower and then what else do they grab
all there at the shop if they're coming
whatever they want that's the beauty of
legalization is that's really huge like
something will catch your eye in there
oh my gosh there's so much stuff in
there but come check out a Chiba to you
guys come get if you want to get like
kind of high and be like trippy dippy
get like a sativa Chiba chew
they're one of the first edible
companies to really nail the sativa
indica hybrid yes and they've got a
seaweed eat you now that I'm just
waiting to test I've just been delivered
just a few days ago the Chu guy was
there yes so if you want to get kind of
trippy give this a diva
if you want to mellow out and giggle get
the indica the indica are intense that's
right if you want a kind of a balanced I
get those hybrids go to the movies take
a hybrid and go to the movies if you're
just looking for straight pain relief
and you don't want to feel high if you
don't want anybody to know that you're
consuming cannabis for pain relief get
the CBD that's what the CBD choose yeah
make your head they don't make you head
high they don't make you giggle II they
just make you feel better
so you've got an option so come to
Colorado come get some cheaper cheese
check it out see what they do for you
maybe don't take them home what I heard
a little cocoa there some Joey Diaz yo
some cheaper Jews dawg
yeah we said she would choose the second
time you couldn't happen Oh
subconsciously my heroes I guess
subconsciously Joey Diaz just slipped at
me
alright I'll go get some Juba Jews dog
these stars of death dog yeah Joey's my
hero shot at the Joey Diaz come back to
Colorado man if you're listening to this
Joey Diaz come back to Colorado please
I'd love to come see you again
I miss you bro yeah Joey Diaz check him
out Joey Coco Diaz hilarious is a
[ __ ] all right I don't think we
have a lot else to say we didn't give
edibles enough credit edibles are
awesome they're very medicinal they take
a little bit longer that work but when
they do boy they really right you have
to plan a little better without a way
yeah it's smoking so much simpler
because you can titrate your dose really
really well you know how hard what
you're to what you just took is gonna
hit you immediately if you want a little
more you can take a little more if
you're good you're good you know that
with edibles it takes and I want to have
to kick in and you can't honey drugs
yeah which is a bonus if you can't sleep
eat yourself edibles and then get stoned
and then try to go to bed and then
hopefully you're sleeping and those
edibles will kick in while you're
sleeping and keep you asleep through the
night that's what I've been doing with
edibles all summer long yes I'll get a
hundred milligram package and eat like
ten milligrams at eight ten milligrams
at nine twenty at ten and twenty at
eleven and then when I go to bed they're
kicking in for the first few hours of a
sleep sweet there you go and then have a
full night's rest yeah wake up eight
hours later feeling great so let's
quickly we've talked about dabs and
smoking dabs and flowers
we've talked about edibles we talked
about teachers we talked about your vape
pen there we've kind of left out like
rubs and creams is all I think that's
left and I've got one other product that
we can talk about if we have a couple
seconds but you look like you got
something to say about no I when you
said rubs and creams I've talked to some
people in my age bracket that are using
some of the creams for arthritis
and in swear Brian think it's it's it's
the best thing since sliced bread I did
not take them seriously and then a
friend of mine gave me a bottle as a
sample and I gave somebody a massage
just from the shoulders to the mid back
is all she let me do but by then my
fingers felt fluffy Wow like I was
wearing balloon gloves so now I take it
seriously she was like wow that was like
a huge massage I was like it's that
Apothic and it was Apothic can of pain
cream is what I used and it I definitely
give the pains and saps credit no I did
not before but after that I believe I'm
a believer yeah yeah I had one of the it
was one of the first generation topical
lotions in Colorado just just random
lotion in a bottle with like a company's
stick around I don't remember what the
brand was but I use it for after
trimming to help absorb the rest of the
trichomes off my skin that I can get
washed off I'm gonna work wonderful for
that but it would also help ease the
pain from trimming wow I mean you spend
seven eight hours is room like a madman
your fingers cramp up one hands holding
a little stem all night all day and the
other ones working a pair of scissors
for that whole shift it hurts yeah yeah
that pain cream I mean an hour after I
used it I felt like I hadn't been at
work although it was great shadow said
the ladies that trimmed my weed for me
the other night yeah good job so we've
covered it seems like we've covered 90%
of the consumption methods have either
of you guys tried Mike's had some teas
but those work they did have any
medicinal value uh the teas that I was
really into on most of that I mean the
dose was so low and the quality was so
sketchy back then that it was probably
just a good flavored tea that I liked
paying five dollars a bag for okay um
but there's a couple of teas on the
market that people swear by I haven't
tried them yet I'm still working my way
down the Edible case nice how about a
transdermal patch have you tried one of
those yet I have a friend who did in an
effort to treat fibromyalgia with the
CBD patch and she said it worked but not
as well as smoking okay and she really
likes uh she's got a CBD oil cartridge
for her vape pen that she really really
I suffer from fibromyalgia myself used
to be on lyrica okay yeah about 9,000
side-effects on the commercial yeah yeah
okay they're all smiling and talking
about anal drainage and stuff yeah
but then again this is one of the drugs
that I got rid of excellent once started
using the content straights
on a regular basis from medicine that
myself and the garden of Weeden produce
there we go damn that feels good yes sir
well thank you sir that makes me proud
don't think use of lyrica is gone out of
your diet yeah things that's Benson I do
Spencer I hope you hear that bro lyrica
methadone so house holy [ __ ]
all out of the no more you know uh this
may be too much but a while back when
I'd go visit you sometimes you'd be
[ __ ] out of it yeah I'm playing and
lately you've been sharp I've been
Douglas again yes cool yeah it is cool
to be yourself again yeah yeah not under
a haze of medication yeah yeah you can
find the remote now you can find your
phone now and you don't want the remote
as much now if you want to go out and do
something nice because you've got energy
again there you go you know you've got
mobility again I wish you guys could see
the look on Doug's face he's sincere as
[ __ ] dude he's not bullshitting at all
it just dials back every other part of
your life my whole week it's just a tiny
booboo I could imagine I mean I've got
some pain but I can imagine having like
hip pain at your age like I'm falling
apart it's it's not just like when my
knees really start throbbing it's not
just the knee is the muscles on either
side of it tense up trying to protect it
huh and then you walk a little funny
trying to protect and by the end of the
day everything below your nipples is
sore because it's trying to keep your
knee from being really sore right and
then living like that for weeks and
months on end you just become exhausted
and after years you start walking
different you just are you know there
being different it affects you greatly
yeah and when you can't think of
anything else except pain when it's like
a high note right between your ears and
all that you can do is hear that scream
that your mind is giving hey we're hurt
yeah you know do something sometimes she
changes it up not enough you can do at
that point right sometimes it's just you
know sometimes it's just with that curl
up and and invite the bullet until
something you can do to give some relief
you know sometimes heat sometimes cold
sometimes pharmaceutical medicine so
many people go to alcohol for though
that's you know what we've seen since
the beginning of alcohol right yeah
people of always I remember my
grandparents we would talk about they
take their shot and go that's our
medicine for the night at the end of
their lives however they wish that at
least that's what they told me was that
they wish they had quit that earlier and
they yeah yeah and that's one of the
reasons I stopped earlier in my life I'm
glad you did like the way you are I'm
not sure we'd get along if you drink no
such good bro I'm sure that I was a lot
like you were when I drink yeah yeah
yeah we're a lot like each other that we
don't yes absolutely
fist bump bro God every day so there's
one more way of consumption that I can
think of that we have not talked about
that I have tried Mike's looking at me
like the Lube brought the lube so I work
at I were gonna dispensary and I got
some Lube dude it it's called evos I
believe there's a couple different
companies Gloria
make it aureus the main one and then we
carry evil okay because I got it from
the spot dispensary oh I didn't get high
at all from it but yeah Doug's looking
at me like that kind of Lube yeah dude
that's the nice thing about topicals is
there's not an intoxication with them
right it's just a medical effect so the
instructions said like spray three to
four sprays on her so I went with like
hate because you know it wasn't spraying
that much I just like spraying it on
there and then it totally had sex with
this chicken it felt warm and tingly and
like hot it was like hotter
normally the temperature was higher and
it took a little more effort to finish
up to tell you the truth like it had to
like wrap it up okay let me try a little
harder I think you did a big review of
this on a previous show yeah we kind of
did but we also did a review of what
happens when I smoke too much CBD and I
can't finish up at all we talked about
that as well
coconut oil and then they infuse it with
THC they just pretty much think they put
coconut oil in a crock pot throw a bunch
of bun there and then strain out the bud
what I really think they do would not be
surprised to find that that's the recipe
it was just coconut oil it's good for
everything if your hands are all sticky
and you can't get the resin off your
hands from trimming a little bit of
coconut oil I'll take that [ __ ] right
off real quick yep million in one uses
that's the first one I'll tell you about
some of the other ones you don't even
want to know
nope all right so we're gonna start
wrapping up this show I tried to do it
earlier but we've got so much [ __ ] to
say I think we've covered all ways that
I am familiar with consuming cannabis we
did touch on on children about people
coming here because we talked about that
a little bit yeah yeah I just like to
make a quick point because I I know
someone who has a special needs child
seizures multiple times throughout the
day finally was able to get medication
great and has changed their life yeah
180 degrees around good I mean if you
don't believe in this stuff you need to
come and see what it does if you're
worried about the children worry about
the ones that need this medication and
right get it because it's made this not
just this child's life much happier
enjoyable productive but if you've ever
been a caregiver of someone who suffers
from something you realize that that
ripple expands out there far
Oh far and when you give relief to the
one that everyone cares so much about
that ripple expands and gives relief to
everyone that cares
about them absolutely you know if if
you're a family moving here with a kid
looking for CBD oil or if you're just
moving here looking for CBD oil take
your time to hunt down legit product yes
there are a lot of places we or Jeff
talked about a news article recently
that there's hemp extract oil being sent
from China if you can buy it online and
have it shipped to you it's not the real
thing if you can get it outside of a
dispensary you have to be standing in in
Colorado there's a 50/50 chance it's not
the real thing that's the truth if
you're lucky and you live in another
state that has a really solid medical
marijuana program and lab testing for
cannabinoids is required you should be
able to get the lab tests right there
with your product you can check and see
what you're buying right there in the
store if you can't be a little sketched
out that you're buying stuff from a
store that doesn't come with that that
should be standard now with with
legalization in Colorado if they don't
have the lab tests they're full of [ __ ]
it's it's just that simple
yeah he's right he's telling the truth
home if it's legal product in Colorado
you have to have that lab test that if
the store clerk tells you they don't
have the lab test they're lying yeah
they just want you to see something or
they don't want to they don't want you
to see there's at least 18 percent THC
or whatever right I'm or they're being
lazy and don't want to grab it but yeah
it's it's standard information now we
you should be able to find CBD meds in a
range of ratios with THC anywhere from
like a hundred to one CBD to THC to one
to one and two to one THC to CBD there
should be a good selection available to
you you just have to take the time to
find it from a little legitimate dealer
I hate seeing people come in here
looking for what we've got and finding
stuff that's fake
that's just terrible dealer you mean a
dispensary yep the word dealer and
they're made that a funny a sentence in
my mind I would like to catch and
release it legitimate dealer yeah yeah
we don't have dealer's any retailer yeah
legitimate retailer storefront your
legitimate MMC yep
MIPS number MIPS yeah an OPC number it
should have a lot of [ __ ] those labels
once in awhile check out see what's
going into the cannabis that you're
buying from the dispensary there's so
much interesting [ __ ] on the labels yeah
yeah take your time grab some of the
pamphlets from the front too sometimes
when they got those like informative
brochures that tell you about what
certain cannabinoids do read that [ __ ]
for yourself stay informed yeah that's
how people like you know so much about
we don't read some [ __ ] right i've got
google i didn't go to a magic weed
school yeah alright so this time i think
we're serious anybody got any other
methods of consumption no everybody went
blank any shoutouts or anything you want
to give alright make sure you guys
follow mike on twitter it's at nemo punk
fifteen support the legalization of
cannabis and listen to mike he'll give
you advice on how to do it on twitter
mike is getting pretty popular there on
the weed twitter a wee bit yeah you guys
next week dude is episode 100 we're
gonna party it up I'm not exactly sure
what's gonna happen I'm gonna invite six
or eight people we're gonna put about
five microphones out on the table we're
gonna get down and have a good ass time
we're gonna take dad you're gonna play
music we're gonna dance around we're
gonna be joyous stoners I love it so I
hope you guys join us for episode number
100 I appreciate you for joining us for
episode number 99 this is a good time I
hope you like this guys you guys thanks
for coming out this is a great great
episodes fun we need to get Doug on the
show more often you've got so many
things in your head that we need to get
out just fine in that trap door that
leads to that story yeah if you guys are
ever interested in sponsoring the
podcast or if you have a product you'd
like me to review on the show send me an
email Mike and I would love to sit here
and review some products you send him
some stuff we will unbox it on the show
we will set it up we will try it out
whatever it is we'll take a DAB out of
it well write it around will fly on it
we'll film something with it whatever
you want to send us some sort of
cannabis related product if you want us
to check it out a grinder a storage
container whatever you got there's so
many great products out there we will
review it we'll shout it out
this show gets over 5,000 downloads
every single episode and the episode
stay up forever so if I talk about your
product if I advertise your product on
episode number 101 it will be there
forever it doesn't go away it's on the
internet all the time people can listen
to it every time I get a new listener
they go back and turn in episode 1 so
they'll hear your [ __ ] for the most part
yeah they do that's like there's a good
percentage of listeners that if they
hear the show at episode 80 whatever
they discover me bad it's going back
through there's a lot of good info it's
sometimes interesting thinking that
people are going back in here at number
1 when I'm like hi welcome to my show
it's great I love it if you guys want to
find a good if you're new to the podcast
make sure you listen to episode number
55 I think that will really introduce
you to who I am and what I'm about and
what my company is about 55 is it great
when I talk about I read genetics my
seed company gonna introduce myself
pretty good at that point we are
rambling hi we must have been smoking
other Jillybean it is good to take loves
dabs dabs more dabs appreciated if you
went to the iTunes Store go to the
iTunes Store search for the girl from
your heart a podcast find the review
section give me a 5 star rating come on
5 stars man you just click on 5 after
that type in a comment let me know what
you think of the show I will read your
comment on a future episode I love
hearing what people think if you love
the show if you hate the show either way
I would love your opinion I would
appreciate it make sure you follow us on
all the social media I think I've said
all that I've told you the email address
it's go from heart a hotmail.com if you
forgot anything you want to say please
get in touch with us I freaking love it
don't forget the show is available on
iTunes stitcher and every single episode
is always in forever archived on I read
genetics Colorado calm I will mention
the donation button go to I read
genetics Colorado calm click on the
girlfriend heart podcast app there's a
donation button up there it's a PayPal
logo I'm sure you can figure out what to
do with that I'm not gonna beg I'll
leave that right there just like that
I'm you guys I want to thank everybody
for coming on to thank everybody for
listening to the episode 100 we'll be
back in a week so while Shadow Twain and
dispensed thanks again for listening
guys until next time take a phat dad and
give your mom a hug for me
[Music]
everything
you