[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome to
the podcast everybody I'm your host
rosta Jeff this is episode 844 of the
grow from your heart podcast you know
I've got another great episode lined up
for us in today's show I'm going to give
away free seeds hang out we'll talk more
about those free seeds later on in
today's episode I do want to remind you
that there is a restock and new items
available at IR redirect.sh
updated is to join the newsletter on my
website at iry genetics.com if you go to
that website down toward the bottom
there's a little tab that says stay up
to date type in your email address every
time I put out a new drop a new sale I
will send you an email also don't forget
that patreon members do get the first
heads up a few patreon members got a few
free packs of seeds this month and also
randomly I did put up a sale of The
Golden Girls packs the first 10 people
to see that coupon code on patreon got
the Golden Girls bundle for $70 so make
sure you guys join the patreon at
patreon.com fromy yourheart to stay
updated on those exclusive drops and
freebies and special deals all right I
think that covers all of the advertising
I want to do here at the start of the
show I know you guys love advertising
let's segue into what I call the pet
peeve portion of today's podcast now I'm
sure most of you out there know what a
pet peeve is just in case you don't a
pet peeve is something that simply
drives you crazy I like to talk about
growroom pet peeves here on the podcast
some sometimes I'll go to a commercial
grow sometimes I'll go to my friends
grow sometimes I'll see something on the
Internet that simply drives me crazy as
a pet peeve today I'm going to read a
listener pet peeve if something out
there drives you completely crazy I
encourage you to send me your growroom
pet peeve if I read your peeve here on
the podcast you will receive a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at edirect
tocom send me that pet peeve at grow
from your heart at hotmail.com and put
the word pet peeve in the subject line
that way I can find them more easily
today's pet peeve started off kind of as
a question but I'm going to turn this
into my pet peeve this question came
from a friend who wants to be called
Full Throttle this question came from
that growel tab on iy genetics.com
that's right my main website is iy
genetics.com at the top of that web page
there's a list of tabs one of those tabs
does say grow help if you click on that
grow help tab guess what you get to send
me your grow help question tell me
what's going on in the grow let me know
what the problem is in the grow space if
I read read your question here on the
podcast I will send you a coupon code
for a free pack of seeds off of I
redirect.sh it came from my new friend
Full Throttle there's a lot of prep to
this question and then they get right to
the point which I'm going to jump
straight to the question goes a little
bit like this and this is also my grow
room pet peeve of the day it says I've
been growing since 1989 and about three
years ago I started making feminized
seeds bro congratulations on the seed
making welcome to the party it says my
question is if I can turn a male into a
controlled hermy now that's not at all
what is happening here so that is my pet
peeve when people talk about feminized
seeds when they talk about reversing and
they use the word Herm in the
conversation that's a pet peeve when you
are breeding making femin fed plants
making feminized seeds there should be
zero Herm word interaction reason in
this conversation at all the word Herm
especially hermy hermy isn't even a word
Herm is short for hermaphrodite uh which
the appropriate word is intersec uh that
word those words should never come up
when we are talking about making fem
seeds if you have any interex traits in
either one of your plants when you are
making fem seeds you're already [ __ ]
up you're going to make guess what more
Herm more interex plants so my big pet
PE pet peeve is when people talk about
making feminized seeds is when they say
anything to do with the word Herm
especially the word hermy that's not
even a real thing and if you're using
the word Herm and your fem seeds you're
already doing it all wrong now I
understand what you're saying uh you
said if I can turn a female plant into a
controlled Herm to make fem seeds that
is not what's happening at all let me
explain more of what is happening that
plant is not a male um that plant is not
a male plant in any way that plant is
not a hermaphrodite plant in any way
that is still a fully female plant the
way we identify that plant and verify
that is that we have ran that plant
multiple times in several conditions in
several rooms if that plant shows
intersect uh traits in that plant I
eliminate that I do not breed that into
my breeding mix we don't breed with
intersects with her plants at all we are
taking a solid true tested female plant
with true XX chromosomes we're taking
that female plant and we're reversing it
uh by doing what I'm doing is I'm
spraying it with a silver solution there
are several different silver Solutions
you can use I make my own silver thyo
sufate solution I spray it with that
when that silver penetrates those leaves
it creates a copper disruption in that
plant the copper can't move around
properly because the silver blocks that
then the plant says something's going on
then that creates an ethylene response
which is part of the ripening process
and most of the fruits and vegetables
which we consume that process goes into
a lot more detail I'm not qualified to
explain which creates pollen sacks those
pollen sacks are all female pollen sax
it's all female pollen in there there's
no male chromosome there's no
hermaphrodite hermy interex chromosome
involved in here it is all female it is
not a controlled Herm that is not the
word it is reversed we say reversed you
said reversed so when we're reversing it
uh that is what we're doing it's not a
controlled Herm that is not the word
Herm should my pet peeve is the word
Herm when it comes to Fem breeding get
that out of there if the word Herm is in
there you're [ __ ] up already you're
doing it wrong now let me keep going it
says um is there a spray that can turn
male plants into female flowers to make
seeds I'm guessing there is but every
seed would be male and that's why no one
does it now you are absolutely correct
there are chemicals sprays applications
products that we can put on our male
plants that will allow them to show us
what they would look like as a female um
I don't know about seed production with
that I've never tried that but we have
reversed a male plant to look like a
female before it looked just like when a
normal female changes itself to look
like a male you could definitely tell in
my opinion uh I don't do this I don't
think it's worth the time because and
the time it took that breeder to reverse
that male plant to show us what it would
look like as a girl I took my male plant
and pollinated female plants with it and
now we can grow those seeds and I've
actually made forward progress in my
breeding so yes there is is a chemical
called epon um I did not write down the
uh dilution and application rates but
epon is available you can reverse male
plants uh you can what would be called
it wouldn't be feminizing it' be mascul
them right so you can make masculine
seeds if you really wanted to I don't
see a reason to do that that would be
shooting yourself in the foot in my
opinion but there is a product there is
a chemical out there that will do it um
you can reverse that plant and it will
show you what it would look like as a
female if you want to know what traits
it would bring to the table as a female
but like I said
while you're doing that project I'm
using my male that I've already selected
with visual traits that I can rely on
and I'm pollinating females I'm a step
ahead of you you're flowering out that
dude and trying to do the tricks and do
the Wizardry I'm already making seeds
that we can grow that we grow those
seeds and those seeds show me what my
pollen donor plant actually would have
done in the mix so uh my pet peeve I'm
going to answer the question but my pet
peeve here is uh stop saying Herm the
pet peeve is the word Herm when it comes
to making fem SE that is not what is
happening let me make sure I covered all
this uh yes I did so my dude your name
is on the other side so my dude Full
Throttle thank you for the great
question here make sure you do check
your inbox CU you have a coupon code for
a free pack of seeds from iy direct.com
all right we're going to keep this
momentum moving this next question is
about paen also this question came from
our friend who wants to be called
trumpus good to meet you my dude the
question goes a little bit like this it
says when you reverse a female and you
pollinate another female with that
reversed pollen okay makes sense so far
is the Reversed female a male van no it
is not it is a reversed female kind of
like the previous question uh it is just
a reversed female that's exactly what it
is it's a girl that has been treated
with silver or whatever you want to
treat it with that is will cause it to
reverse and it has reversed it did not
get a gender change it is still a female
uh it has got all X chromosomes uh this
could be a very controversial subject if
we wanted to go that way but this is all
female it is still a female plant you've
just treated it with a solution that has
caused a reaction there a chemical
reaction is all that's happening in this
plant that plant is still a true female
so much so that the pollen that comes
off of that plant is true female um that
pollen that comes off if you gather that
pollen that is all female pollen no
matter how many other female plants you
put that on it's going to make female
seeds because it is all female that's
how truly female that plant is said
please help me understand you rosta Jeff
you're the man I appreciate everything
that I am learning from your podcast yo
thank you for listening thank you for
the great compliment I know this is a
really short answer and I hope it makes
sense and you're going to win your free
pack of seeds but um is the Reversed
plant uh male no it's still a female it
has just been treated with chemicals
that's all there is to it we haven't it
hasn't changed its name it doesn't wear
different clothes uh we simply sprayed
it with some [ __ ] and it's having a
chemical if it were a human it would be
a medical reaction a chemical reaction
is all it would be same story we're not
going to do this comparison with people
and plants cuz this is weird when it
gets to this borderline but uh no it is
still a female plant I just sprayed it
with some stuff all right I hope that
answers your question that was quick and
straight to the point so my dude uh make
sure you check your inbox because you've
got a coupon code for a free pack of
seeds from iy direct.com all right we're
going to keep this momentum moving but
before I jump into this third question I
do want to remind you to like And
subscribe that's right if you like my
ramblings please make sure to click like
on this video and if you enjoy it please
do click subscribe that way every time I
put out a new video you will get a
notification and you will not miss any
of the videos now let's jump our way
into this third question here on the
podcast of course once again this did
come from the growel tab on my website
IR genetics.com go to the website IR
genetics.com on the top there's that row
of tabs one says grow help click on that
grow help tab this one came from our
friend who wants to be called skunky
Steve shout out to my new buddy skunky
Steve I like the name the question says
hey rosted Jeff I appreciate everything
you do for the community and I've been
following for a while now hey thank you
I'm glad you notice what I do for the
community I'm glad you see that I try to
create a community and if you are not
already part of the community I invite
everybody out there to join us on the
Discord server we've got a great
community over on Discord that's righty
it's completely free come hang out uh
make a Discord account make yourself a
username find the I Army Discord server
the uh link will be in the show notes
and in the video description and then
come join us if you're new to Discord we
will be gentle go poke around on all the
tabs just go click on everything you
can't go wrong click on everything see
what all the tabs are about navigate
yourself around it will take a minute to
get used to it but eventually it will
all make sense then one day you will
find the smoker's Lounge what the smoker
Lounge that is a video chat where I hang
out a lot of my friends hang out we talk
about growing we talk about smoking uh
sometimes we talk about food we talk
about dogs you never know what we could
talk about in there if you've got a grow
question uh if you've got a grow problem
something is just stumping you and you
need immediate input from an army of
people that know what they're talking
about there's somebody in the Smokers
Lounge or The Growers Lounge right now I
could be in there you never know who may
be in there we may be able to answer
your question just pop in show us a
picture show us a video of the grow let
us know what's going on we may be able
to help you out in real time uh give you
real recommend advice there may be
somebody in your region in your area
that's growing that has the same problem
that knows where there's a store nearby
that can help you get a solution it's a
great resource I do invite you to join
us on the Discord server the IR Army
Discord server pop in that smoker Lounge
don't be shy if you don't want to be on
video uh you don't have to put your face
on video if you don't want to smoke on
camera you don't have to you can come be
a little blank icon it'll say whatever
uh roster Jeff smokes all day could be
your name up there um you could just
have that name displayed and you can
come have a conversation with us as much
as you're uh confident as much as you're
comfortable you can hang out you can
share your experience just want to make
sure that everybody feels invited to the
IR Army Discord server that was a lot of
rambling let me keep myself a little bit
focused here um my question is about
reversing females I'm sure you guys have
caught on that this episode is going to
be mostly about feminized breeding
projects we're going to jump into it it
says I wonder if reversing with silver
is contrib to the hermaphrodite traits
my quick answer with positive confidence
is nope those are the plants which you
are choosing that are contributing to
your hermaphrodite traits it says um I
am starting with solid genetics that
have been grown to harvest with no
hermaphrodite traits in sight tested
some of the seeds that were made and
have a very high rate of Herms is there
something other than silver I can use to
reverse not what those two plants no
whichever two plants you were using one
of them definitely is carrying the
intersex Gene it is not the dominant
trait in that plant but it is in there
actually we've never bred with these
before it could be a dominant trait we
haven't seen it express itself it's
hidden in there you unlocked it by
breeding to it so one of these two
plants has that intersect trait in it uh
I'm not sure which two plants you used
I'm not sure which two plant which of
the two you reversed but uh it is
definitely not the silver that is
causing the intersect tray it is the
plants the plants are what is doing it
if the silver what is what was causing
this all of my projects all of your
projects everybody's projects involving
silver would have intersect traits the
common uh common denominator here is
your plants that is the thing that is
showing the intersect traits I want to
know um which plant did you reverse and
then I also want to know how many plants
did you pollinate and then did you
pollinate one or did you pollinate
multiple plants of that pollination how
many of those seeds have you grown was
was it a project or was it an outcross
where there were multiple do the s1s do
they show F or hermaphroditism or do all
of the population show hermaphroditism
that would really help us narrow down
where the Herm trait is coming from but
I am super sure that the Herm trait did
not come from the silver um you said
that you've grown these plants to a
harvest before but have you stress
tested them have you taken these plants
in a room and [ __ ] with the timer have
you messed with their light cycle have
you messed with their feeding have you
messed with drought have you messed with
flood uh these are all conditions that I
would definitely experiment with before
breeding to that plant push them to
their limit find out when they snap see
what it takes to really piss these
plants off before you breed to them I'm
going to go over this and make sure I'm
covering everything here because I've
been going really quickly with this
episode it feels like this may be a
short but powerful episode um uh
hermaphrodites coming from Silver solid
traits grown to harvest no hermaphrodite
traits in sight in sight see that's um
it was in there it's in one of these
plants so what I would recommend um I
wouldn't breed I may pick totally
different plants but if you insist on
using these plants again here's a way to
find out which one is the interex plant
whichever one you chose as your pollen
donor do the same thing again and then
pollinate whichever plant you chose last
time again but then pollinate other
plants as well if the other plants all
show intersex traits from the progyny
it's your pollen donor if only some of
them show the intersect it could be the
plant that is receiving the pollen and
not the pollen donor but we've got to
start doing a process of elimination
here then my next run I would do a
different pollen donor and hit all of
those Fe I moved the one that was the
pollen donor before move it right into
the line and or the and make it a pollen
receiver this time with a different
donor and that's the only way you're
going to find out where that intersect
trait lies where it's hidden but I
guarantee you that the intersect didn't
come out of any of the uh the silver the
intersects guaranteed came out of the
plants that you start Ed with so uh
sometimes that's the magic of breeding
sometimes you put plant a plant B
together those chromosomes mixed the x's
and y's they all jingle up together they
land how they come out sometimes you
create the hottest new fire sometimes
you make a big old bag of Herms you
never know what might be happening
that's why uh you just got to grow them
and test them out and this is one of the
big reasons why I recommend pollinating
multiple female plants with the same
pollen donor because like I keep saying
I don't know if it's your and maybe I
don't know how how many plants you
pollinated I don't know if you made s1's
I don't know if you made a bunch of r1's
but if it's just the we're just going to
say um what's your name your name is
skunky Steve we're just going to say we
took skunky Steve S1 or skunky Steve
we're just going to call a plant skunky
Steve and you took two cuts and tried to
make s1s if those are Herms there's only
one plant in there contributing to that
interex mix that's your intersex plant
if youve read it out to other things uh
then we could see where that intersect
lies but if it's just an S1 one then
skunky Steve is a Herm if you pollinated
skunky other plants with skunky Steve uh
if half of those are Herms I would say
it came from skunky Steve if none of
them are Herms I would say that that
that's how we would figure it out I'm
talking in circles now trying to figure
out that process of elimination but it
is definitely in those plants it's not
in the uh it's not in the silver but
that's why I would pollinate multiple
females that's what I was saying
pollinate multiple females then we can
see what is actually happening is it the
pollen donor or is it the females where
the problem wise process of elimination
more data it makes it a little bit
easier all right my dude skunky Steve
thank you for the great question uh this
is going to be a quick episode of
today's podcast Steve make sure you
check your inbox because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds and
ladies and gentlemen if I did not read
your question on today's podcast please
do not feel discouraged I have got a
mountain of emails printed out that are
ready to be read on the podcast so make
sure you subscribe to the show so that
way when I do read your question you do
not miss the episode all right I I think
that's all I've got for today's podcast
uh once again hit like hit subscribe uh
follow me on patreon at
patreon.com grow from your heart
anything else you could possibly need is
on my website at IR genetics.com there
is a link to the Discord server there's
a link to iir to get the seeds there's a
link to the store so you can get a
grinder a rolling tray uh you can get an
ashtray you can get a stash pot you can
get a grow from your heart podcast hat
there's a bunch of great stuff available
at the merch store all of those links
are available at IR genetics.com ladies
and gentlemen you can hear my voice
starting to burn out already this was a
well-timed episode I'll be back in a
week with fresh new content I want to
give a big shout out to my buddy T
Greenery and until next time take a fat
dab and give your mom a hug for
[Music]
me Rost a Jeff you bad
mother time to take another Dam grab
your pie in and I go find the
is in the lab sit back relax hold