[Music]
Rost and Jeff you bad
mother all right here we go welcome back
podcast world I'm your host rosta Jeff
this is episode 867
of the grow from your heart podcast you
know I've got another fun episode lined
up for us in today's podcast I'm going
to give away free seeds hang out we'll
talk more about those free seeds later
on in today's show before we get too far
I do want to send a couple of shoutouts
to a few of the great folks who support
the show on patreon let's kick it off
with the big grow from your heart
podcast thank you shout out to my good
friend Mel I want to send a fist bump
and a thank you shout out to shotgun
Yoda let's send a big thank you shout
out to grap Vine grower then let's wrap
it all up with a big grow from your
heart podcast thank you shout out to my
friend slowly rolling stoned big thanks
and big shout out to everybody who
supports the show on patreon if you are
not already supporting the show and you
would like to learn how to do so all you
have to do is visit
www.patreon.com SLG grow fromy yourart
all of the information you need will be
right there on the screen and once again
big thanks and big shout out to
everybody who continues to support the
podcast I also want to remind you that
the grow from your heart podcast is
teamed up with AC Infiniti that's right
I believe AC Infiniti is the leader in
growroom evolution it is making growing
easier and more fun for hom Growers if
you have not already checked out AC
Infiniti I highly recommend you check
out AC infinity.com use the link in the
show notes or the video description uh
the next seeds that you buy from iir
will be made in a full AC Infinity
environment that's right the tent the
light the blower the fans the controller
the entire room is AC Infinity if I'm
using using it I recommend you use it as
well that's where the seeds are made why
not grow the seeds in the same
environment check them out at AC
infinity.com or use the link in the show
notes in the video description and use
coupon code iy when you check out to
save 10% off your full order at AC
infinity.com all right I think that
covers all of the business here at the
start of the podcast um I do want to let
you know that we made a few changes to
the Discord server that's right uh we
changed the rules and we added a new
chat room along with that came a new
gate to get into the Discord server it
appears that many people are hung up on
that new rules gate when you go to the I
Army Discord server and it appears that
you are stuck click on that little box
that says rules or new rules I'm going
to go look I can't see it because I've
already clicked on it there's a new box
that says rules click on those rules and
reclick that you agree and then you will
be allowed into the server it seems like
many people are stuck on that age gate
on that new rule gate uh if you can't
get past that send myself or another
friend from Discord a message and we
will guide you through it I miss you
guys I want to get everybody back on
Discord uh when we made the new rules
when we added the new chat we had to add
the new box and that seems to be
tripping a few people up so the Discord
did not go away the Discord is still
thriving it's even it's actually
stronger and better than ever before uh
we made some new rules we did some
moderation we did some updates and I
invite you to come join us on the
Discord server and if you lost it come
back if you can't find it send me a
message I will help you get to the
Discord server there will be a link in
the show notes and in the video
description once again if you've been
stuck click on the part where it says
rules and etiquette that's actually what
it says click on the new rules that will
get you right back on in there come join
us in The Smokers Lounge there is a new
chat that is called the gloves off
lounge or the gloves off chat it is
exactly as described uh it is gloves off
people may say things to you that bother
you in there but you can say [ __ ] that
bothers them WR back in that chat uh
keep it respectful keep it fun it's all
in good fun but there are no rules in
that chat so if somebody pisses you off
and says something weird you just got to
deal with it in there if you're not into
that stay upstairs in the smoker's
Lounge the Grover's Lounge there are a
lot of rules there but be prepared for
that gloves off Lounge because it is
exactly what it sounds like all right
I've made the Discord update we have
talked about oh the next thing I want to
talk about if you've been following
along you have heard that I have been uh
working on some GMO reversals that's
right I've got the skunk Master Flex cut
of the GMO plant uh quickly that does
not stand for garlic mushroom onions in
any way the reason that GMO is named GMO
is because when that plant became
popular also at the same time the Girl
Scouts of America were selling their
cookies and it was discovered that those
cookies were highly made with a lot of
GMO products there's a lot of
genetically modified product going into
the Girl Scout cookies so uh the GMO
plant is a Girl Scout cookies cross it
is chem dog I think it's chem 4 uh and
the Girl Scout cookies they br that
together to make a plant uh a dude named
skunk Master Flex was growing it he
found a phenotype uh that smelled super
funky and he called it GMO because the
Girl Scout cookies of America Scandal
had been so popular in the news so the
GMO idea kind of inspired the name to go
with the GMO plant it does not stand for
garlic mushroom onions quit saying that
that's not real it's because of the Girl
Scouts of America controversy at the
time uh that's what that name came from
uh I love the plant it grows really well
it grows kind tall and stretchy but you
guys know that's the [ __ ] that I seem to
like uh it makes amazing concentrates it
makes super funky Aromas and flavors
like this uh garlic pungent funky dirty
bar trash can sort of a garlicky mashed
potatoes sort of thing I really love
that Aroma and flavor I wanted to
reverse the GMO and put that pollen on
nine different females I had nine ladies
in a tent ready to rock everything
looked like it was going well you can
see where I'm headed with this cuz I'm
talking that it failed ladies and
gentlemen I Ed used three different
solutions of products to reverse the GMO
all of the reversals were successful I
got beautiful anthers pollen sacks if
you will I treated a female plant with
three different Sol three different
clones of the same plant with three
different solutions in an attempt to see
which would work best for reversals all
three reversed the plant beautifully
lots of male flower clusters on this
female plant lots of pollen sacks if you
will all over this plantet looked ready
to go uh but one thing I noticed it was
not making any pollen I let these plants
go much longer than I've ever let
reversals go before and I did not get
one single flake or dust of pollen out
of the reverse GMO plants um they went
for a long time I gave I gave up on them
I let them go and I just put them in the
dark I thought [ __ ] it we'll see what
they do they didn't even do anything
after being left in the dark for several
days they turned really purple and
looked really beautiful but I did not
get any pollen from the Reversed GMO so
if you're out there working with GMO and
you've reversed it and made pollen share
your secrets with me I [ __ ] give up
I'm not doing it again I wasted too much
time on that but uh so the reverse GMO
project did not work a lot of people ask
me have you ever had reversals or
breeding projects that just completely
failed uh yes reversed GMO was a
complete waste of time I've got nine
females in an AC Infinity tent that are
uh ripe and ready for pollen and that
reversed GMO looked like it was going to
give me pollen It reversed it made the
pollen sacks they were empty his nuts
were empty no pollen at all I put some
on black paper and rubbed it around and
you could not find one flake of pollen
on the black paper uh completely empty
dry no pollen at all so that was a
failure what I did since I had a bunch
of female plants that were ready to go
they were itching for pollen it was
prime time I had some other pollen in
the freezer I grabbed that pollen I let
it adjust to room temperature before I
used it I didn't want to go sprinkling
Frozen pollen that didn't seem smart I
put it on the table right here I let the
pollen warm up for several hours uh
later on that night I had a nice bag of
pollen uh then I took that pollen and I
sprinkled that bag of pollen all over
the room the pollen was a little bit old
so I'm not sure how well it took some of
the pistols have turned brown and
withered up that could be because of the
age of the plants that could be because
of the pollination at this point it's
too early for me to tell if any seeds
have formed if the pollination took
however if it did take I will let you
know which plant I used for that
pollination right now I don't want to
tell you what pollen donor it was
because if it doesn't work that's two
times that I've hyped you up on a cross
let you down so I'm not going to do that
but the update is that the GMO reversal
simply did not give me any pollen so all
of those GMO reversals we were drooling
over we were excited about not going to
happen I apologize [ __ ] happens that's
breeding life um as a breeder as a
grower as a farmer I understand that's
[ __ ] life that's how it went that's
how it goes guess what I'm going to
gather my sticks and I'm going to move
on and keep going and try again I had a
backup plan I used other pollen we'll
see if that pollen was viable if not I
get a whole 5x5 full of great flowers
that Mike and I are going to get to
smoke and we will try again with a
different plant in the near future I
know what the next crosses are going to
be I've got another feminized cross
coming up um then after that we'll be
more Golden Goat crosses but yes it's
just keep going keep trying uh so the
reason for this was to let you know uh
the GMO did not make any pollen those
crosses are not coming and then also
just to share with you not everything is
a wild success this was a crazy
miserable failure not miserable there's
no misery to it it was heartbreak breing
watching these plants build these
beautiful flowers and no pollen come out
of them for days and watching the girls
go hey we want pollen so bad and this
guy's going I just can't do it bro I
just can't do it uh that was
heartbreaking but bottom line pollen
didn't work the next bottom line going
to keep moving forward the crosses
aren't coming we adapt we adjust we
overcome we keep going that's what we do
in the iy Army all right where are we I
feel like I covered that we are covering
a lot of ground very quickly here on
this podcast did I remind you that there
is a sale at iy direct.com that's right
um all orders all seed orders over $100
do come with free shipping that's right
IR
redirect.sh on sale for $25 a sixpack
and regular seeds on sale for $10 a 10
pack that's right what uh to get them
straight from the breeder when there's
no middleman we can definitely give you
better deals better prices check edirect
decom I have said enough let's work our
way into the question and answer portion
of today's podcast I know you guys come
for the questions and answers not the
random Rambles um this question came I
have a website that website is iry
genetics.com on the top of that website
there is a row of tabs one of those tabs
does say grow help or grow questions
click on that Tab and send me a good
grow question if I read your question
here on the podcast I will send you a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds off
my website idirect decom today's first
question came from my new friend Vince
Vince good to meet you bro great
question make sure you check your inbox
because you've got a coupon code for a
free pack of seeds at iy direct.com
the question goes just a little bit like
this it says hey rosta Jeff I'm a new
listener and a new subscriber I just
popped my first seeds in Rapid rooters
and I transplanted straight into 5
gallon fabric pots all right so you got
your first seeds they popped in the
rapid rotter then you pop them into 5
gallon fabric pots all right this makes
sense I understand it says my question
what is the benefit in transplanting
into smaller pots first and have I
hindered M grow in any way by by
skipping the smaller pots thank you for
your help your new friend Vince hey
Vince this is a great question uh
quickly just to make you feel better
right at the beginning you did not
hinder the plants in any way um I will
talk about why we do this the reasoning
we do it the pros and the cons and then
next time you can decide if it's
something you want to do or not the
first reason I myself and most uh
cultivation spaces Growers areas prefer
to go we call it graduated pot size I'll
start off with a 6-in net pot maybe a
small 1gallon pot so my clone comes out
of the cloner or my seeding Sprouts goes
into a 6-in net pot or a 1gallon pot the
reason I like that is because that
little tiny pot only takes up this much
space in my grow room so while my plants
are only 1 in 2 in 3 5 7 8 9 in tall I
only need a 6in net pot one gallon pot
that's probably 10 in in diameter 8 in
in diameter worth of space for that
plant um I'm probably going to pop a 10
pack of seeds so now I've got 10 small
pots if I put all of those pots in 5
gallon pots or all those plants in 5
gallon pots my 10in root zone now
becomes what is that like 20 in it's
probably 18 inches for a 5 gallon pot at
least 14 inches I'm a drummer so I'm
going off snare drum size it's about the
same size as a snare drum maybe a little
bigger you're looking at 14 or 16 in I'm
able to fit those 10 one gallons under a
very tiny light and very little space so
the First Advantage is the amount of
space I can get them all in a smaller
space since they're in a smaller space I
can use less light because they're not
spread out so far they're all in one
confined contained area so I'm using
less space as a grower you're a new
grower it sounds like um space will
become very valuable to you the more you
grow the longer you grow the one thing a
grower wants more of is more grow space
constantly so that real estate is very
expensive so the smaller pots for
smaller plants give me more real estate
I don't have to waste big pot space for
little tiny plants then I can cram more
in there and then I can veg more and
then if you're setting up a Perpetual it
gives you more space space is the bottom
line then the second uh issue is light
if I've got uh 10 pots in big [ __ ]
space I need more light to cover that
that starts to get expensive now I'm
running light which costs energy when I
run that light now I have to have a fan
now I have to have possibly an air
conditioner a humidifier a dehumidifier
the more space you use the more light
the more gear it starts compounding and
getting more expensive quite quickly at
that point the next thing I think about
is feeding and watering these plants uh
there's a couple things to think about
if your root zone is only this big you
only need this much water to saturate
your plant and water it satisfactorily
sat to satisfaction fill in the words
there ad lib however you will but you
only need so much water to water this
little space there's a couple of
advantages to that uh water costs money
the nutrients you are feeding those
plants cost money if you've got to feed
a one gallon pot you only need one
portion of water if you're feeding a 5
gallon pot you need five as much water
hypothetically that brings me to another
issue when that small plant is in that
big root Zone in that big pot and all
that soil it's easy to overwater and uh
flood that plant and drown it because
you've got such a big root Zone such a
big dirt area that you need to get water
to the whole Space where the roots are
but the roots aren't established and
strong enough and big enough and going
deep enough to handle all the water that
you're giving it so now you're creating
issues with that the soil is nice and
saturated but the plant is actually [ __ ]
[ __ ] struggling because it doesn't
have the root Zone to handle that much
water so in a smaller container The
Roots would develop more and they would
establish more and you wouldn't over
water is easily because you don't have
there's not much room for as much water
so it makes it easier to water it makes
it safer to water and it saves you water
and nutrients so we're already saving
lights air water oh and it doesn't take
as much soil to fill that space so if
you need to if you're on a budget you're
going to buy that soil next week you can
just let them grow in those small pots
for a couple of weeks once they get
bigger start to get rootbound then put
them into those bigger pots so the first
thing is space the second thing is light
the next thing is watering and feeding
them you're going to need more water and
more feeding so your bottom line is did
I mess up by not uh graduating pots what
I prefer to do is I go from that clone
into the one gallon I let it grow until
it's almost root Bound in there I like
to if I lift that pot off the plant I
like to see Roots all over that pot I
like to see it nice and full then I'll
take that one gallon and move it into
either a three a five or a seven and
this situation just like you I'm going
to go to a five I would fill up my 5
gallon pot and then I would take the pot
that the plant is in and I would plop
that pot right into my my pot my new pot
follow along it makes sense and bury
around that pot what I'm doing now is
making a template of where that pot is
going to go then I take that pot out of
the dirt and remove the pot off the root
ball then I grab the root ball from the
bottom and I kind of stick my fingers in
there and pull that root ball apart a
little bit those roots in and that dirt
are super tight in that pot they've kind
of grown into there they've made this
nice perfect cylinder shape just like
the pot they came out of I want to grab
that and disrupt that I want to break
that a little bit up then I want to put
that into my new soil and I want to
leave maybe a/ inch exposed uh out of
the new soil I don't want to bury that
whole that whole thing I want to leave
excuse me I'm burping and trying to
fight through this but I want to save
about a half inch exposed because that
is a good space for air to get to my
plant if I do over water those roots can
receive oxygen through that top little
layer of soil there I will not drown the
plant so I pop I dig that hole I make
the little template hole take the pot
off break up that soil a little bit and
then just plop that right into that hole
and leave it up just just a little bit
just a fraction of an inch maybe a half
of an inch just to leave a little bit of
air space for that uh for those roots
then I back fill it and then I water it
just like that but my reason for
breaking up those roots a little bit is
I believe that that encourages them
they've been going into that pot and
wrapping around and spinning and just
trying to find somewhere to go they
filled all the space within that pot
within that soil if I break them up a
little bit it kind of encourages them it
goes hey we can go play guys we've been
freed up a little bit and they start
traveling different directions and it'll
fill your soil your container much more
evenly and much more rapidly if you
break them up a little bit give it a
little Head Start give it some
encouragement uh so I fill the pot with
dirt most of the way put that pot with
the plant in it in there fill it up
around the pot make myself a nice
template take that out uh pull the pot
off the the plant break up the roots a
little bit plop that in there and then
just bury it kind of kind of nice and
not snug not tight just pack it in there
just brush the dirt over it don't cover
that top you you might see just a little
ring right at the top in the middle
that's your little air area and then I
mix up a decent feed I'll do a basic
base mix uh maybe a light CAG a little
bit of liquid Karma um depends on if
you're going to put potassium silicates
in there or not that's up to you but at
this point I would definitely feed some
sort of root inoculant uh some sort of
microbes of course I'm going to
recommend recharge shout out to my buddy
Scotty reel uh but get some microbes in
there and get those roots grow and you
got a really good opportunity to feed
those roots and get them going shebang
right now so that is my basic how I
transplant and that is why uh because I
don't want to waste all that space the
plant's only this big why do I need a
pot this big for it wait till the plant
gets this big then give it a pot this
big I think it'll really help out save
you some space water time energy maybe
you can build a Continuum with all your
free prizes my friend Vince I think I've
answered your question quite well uh
make sure you check your inbox and check
your spam because you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds at iy
direct.com all right we've got some good
momentum going now is a good time to
remind you to click like And subscribe
that's right if you enjoy the podcast
please click like And subscribe and also
leave a comment because that definitely
does help the
algorithm all right this next question
also came from the growel tab on iry
genetics.com this one came from a friend
who wants to be called Black Ray 3K big
shout out to my new friend black Ray 3K
check your inbox cuz you've got a coupon
code for a free pack of seeds the
question goes a little bit like this it
says hey rosta Jeff I appreciate all the
knowledge you have been dropping on us
hey I'm glad you're here for it it says
my question is about organic versus
synthetic nutrients that's a this is a
very good question and a great debate it
says which one is best for H Growers to
use and with what growing medium this is
a very good question um I am a little
bit biased but let me try to stay uh
even here and not biased at all and stay
objective and give you some solid advice
um both work very well for you both will
work very well for home Growers both uh
will give you very great results it is
kind of what you prefer there is no
better or best I'm not going to there is
not a better or best when it comes to
synthetic or organic uh there are pros
and cons to both uh the pros I think to
synthetic nutrients or you can buy a
bunch of bottles from the grow store and
you can go to the website uh let's just
say you went to the store and you bought
botanic hair you bought five bottles of
Botanicare nutrients you can go home and
you can go to the website type in
Botanicare Nutrient calculator and it
will show you on week one feed 10
milliliters of this per gallon feed five
Ms of this per gallon on week two feed
this and this and this on week three so
the advantage the pros to bottled
nutrients is you can go to the store and
buy everything you need in a bottle go
to the website and find a recipe week by
week that will work for your garden and
you will have a successful grow that's a
huge Pro it's that easy they hold your
hand they sell you the [ __ ] they tell
you how much to put in how often to do
it you do it if you pH it correctly and
feed it like they say it works every
time repeatable process repeatable
results that is the pro my favorite pro
to bottled nutrients you can go to the
store when you buy bottled nutrients
it's the same thing every time it's
there all the time you can order it all
the time it's reliable repeatable
processes and results that's my favorite
thing that is the pro the cons uh it's
not organic there are you're paying for
a lot of the time you're paying for
water to be shipped across the country
you're buying bottles of water [ __ ] that
is mixed with water and you're paying
for it also it's not organic let's talk
about the pros and cons of organic a lot
of people like the pro of organic
because the word organic it means it
comes from the earth it is healthy it
gives us the idea that it's safer and
cleaner organic just basically means
that it is carbon based so now let's
talk about the cons of organic cyanide
is organic and it can [ __ ] kill you
so don't get too caught up in the word
organic um in this case when we're going
to talk about Organics we're going to
focus more on the products and the idea
of building an organic uh product and
not the buzzword of it's natural so it's
better for me because like I said a
moment ago if we put cyanide in our weed
it's not going to be good so let's just
focus on the organic construction we're
not being sold by the it's better cuz
it's organic we're just going we're
going to use the natural version like
the building blocks naturally version
organic for this conversation here I
hope that makes any sense to you because
it barely makes sense in my [ __ ] head
so organic I like the organic idea
because depending on which meth there's
so many different methods you want to
take to you could take to this you could
go to the store and you could buy boxes
of uh all the meal the bone meal blood
meal fish meal Kel meal you could go get
all that stuff that is organic um to
that you're going to premix all of your
soil and let that cook and then you'll
put the plants in there and that stuff
will become bioavailable over time so uh
that is how the Organics are going to
work for your bottle nutrients you're
going to feed today and basically what
you feed today those plants are going to
start eating that today with the
Organics you got to let it break down
it's got to become bioavailable to the
plants um the bottled nutrients have
what are called keates and buffers
inside of them those keates basically
force your plant to eat so with the
Organics The Roots roam around and go
hey there's minerals and nutrients and
vitamins and [ __ ] that I need over here
oh look nitrogen oh phosphorus potassium
I'm going to eat some of that and then
it goes oh I'm hungry I've had a lot of
phosphorus there's some here but I'll
kind of wait until I need that we'll
metabolize that later when you're
feeding the bottle nutrients the plant
goes ah [ __ ] phosphorus I'm going to
take all that just because the way that
it's chelated the way that it's
processed in that bottle the way that
it's formulated the roots touch it and
the roots go I'm supposed to eat this
and they just take it up right away so
there's pros and cons there with the
Organics you're going to mix your
nutrients all into that mostly into that
soil depending on how you do it that's
why I'm talking about the so many
methods uh if you go buy all the boxes
you premix it make sort of a a super
soil sort of an idea out of your
Organics that's going to cook and it's
got to release over time and your PL if
it's not in there if you did not already
put it in there it's not going to be in
there for your plants it's going to take
a little while for your plant if you do
feed a tea or a top dress it's going to
take a while for the plants to notice
that if I'm feeding bottled nutrients uh
they're going to notice right away very
quickly if I'm feeding a soilless mix
I'll see results two to three maybe five
days if I'm feeding cocoa I may see
results within four to 6 hours maybe
even quicker depending on how badly I
[ __ ] up feeding those plants so there
are a lot of pros and cons the the
chelation is a big difference it's like
um it's sort of like eating I'm trying
to exp it's sort of like uh so it's like
eating a big healthy meal or taking a
bunch of steroids um the Organics is
like eating you got a plate of food in
front of you you just keep eating and
you eat and you get what you need with
the bottled nutrients it's like I'm just
shooting the minerals and the nutrients
and the vitamins directly into your neck
and you're [ __ ] getting them if you
need it or not you're going to get too
much of something you're going to get
possibly overloaded on something and you
might see some detrimental effects so
that's the kind of the differences on
Organics and synthetics uh I prefer and
this is just me I run fully bottled
nutrient systems a lot of dry nutrient
powder nutrients but I do the synthetics
the salt system is my way to go the
reason I do that is because I came I
developed I learned very strongly in a
commercial production environment and a
lot of times I'm teaching other dudes
how to do this I'm the cultivation
leader I got a group of dudes that are
going to mix up these nutrients when I'm
not there there are going to be guys
mixing up these Solutions and feeding
the plants so like I said earlier I need
to be able to write a recipe on Monday
feed it like you're going to mix up 500
gallons of water and put this many
milliliters of Base nutrients this much
cow mag this much Bloom booster this
much cic uh cissi oh excuse me for the
burps but I want to write down a recipe
that the guys at the grow or the gals at
the grow can repeat to Perfection on a
daily basis and in a commercial
environment I need to be able to adjust
on the fly if I see that this room is
doing something weird I need to be able
to feed it and correct it Organics is
just not my my way for a commercial
environment many people out there do it
successfully and they do it very well
it's just not how I prefer to Do It um
they're mixing up their super soil their
living soil before they even put plants
in it they're letting that cook for a
little bit they plant the plants and the
plants live in that soil forever they
don't ever have to get fed any bottled
nutrients but if that mix is not right
at the beginning you're screwed all the
way through you're going to be mixing up
teas and chasing it and trying to find
Solutions so in a commercial environment
I think that for a large scale
production for me the bottle nutrients
are just easier and more repeatable uh
every time there's the same amount of
everything in the those bottles in the
Organics um if you're making ferments if
you're making teas depending on how much
of what you put in you could get highly
variable results so but that's not as
critical because your plants are going
to take that up as it needs it so there
are pros and cons I keep saying there
are pros and cons I'm going to tell you
there's no better uh neither one is best
or uh least least or less than is what I
think I'm trying to say they're both
great it's all about your approach how
do you want to do it do you want to do
like fermented fruit juices and um fruit
extracts and [ __ ] like that to feed your
plants which I'm not knocking it it
sounds like a lot of fun I have a couple
friends who are into jadam and my
buddy's like bro I was out hiking today
and I came across a whole bunch of
whatever flowers and I cut a bunch of
them put them in a bag brought them home
made a [ __ ] tea out of them and fed
it to my plants and I'm like that's
actually pretty cool like that's much
more sustainable than what I'm doing
I've got to go to the store and buy [ __ ]
so if the store runs out of [ __ ] I can
fall back on those Organics uh but uh I
don't know how to do it right now but my
buddies that are doing the Organics
they're all already doing it uh one
friend that I do have that uh grew
organically uh with Organics for several
years since I met him he's been growing
Organics then our friends at New
Millennium gave him a box set of all the
New Millennium nutrients and he ran it
and the first thing he said to me was
that he wished he had all of the weed he
had been shorting himself by running
Organics uh he was quite impressed with
the uh the size of the yield he improved
his yield quite a bit by shifting to the
bottle new nutrients I was the only
thing that he mentioned was different
he's like bro I wish I had all the weed
I've been shorting myself all of these
years I'm not going to call you out bro
you know who you are still a great
grower he's actually running a
commercial facility now and I'm pretty
sure it's all on bottles and not organic
so he shifted uh went from the Organics
to the bottles I am rambling let me
check my notes Here I said cide is
organic don't get caught too much caught
up on buzzwords if you're going to grow
organically uh make sure that there's a
reason behind it make sure that you
didn't just choose it for hippie
nonsense reasons um also the Organics is
much more long-term and sustainable if
you want to do this forever if you want
to do this when Babylon Falls and the
lights go out and we're relying on the
sun and mixing our own nutrients the
organic way will still be viable I won't
be able to go to the grow store and buy
a bottle of liquid Karma I'm going to
have to learn how to make that [ __ ] on
my own which I got all you hippie
friends for that thank you I'll trade
you seeds for some knowledge but um
that's one of the big advantages when
Babylon Falls when the trucks quit
running when the stores are gone jadam
will be jaming still um it's um it's
sustainable that's the best part of the
Organics in my opinion um and you don't
have to keep going and buying bottles
I'm getting bottles shipped to me and
there's water in them and that feels a
little bit ridiculous uh both can have
repeatable results if you understand
what you're doing I can't repeat the
results in the Organics because I don't
know what I'm doing yet so I think I've
been rambling long enough the question
is my question organic which one is best
um and with what growing medium uh
neither one is best they are both
equally awesome um you can mix them but
when you mix them you're not organic
anymore because organic means when
you're growing organically it means you
haven't added those synthetic salts as
soon as you add that no longer organic
the word Sanic is not a thing organic
means you don't have the synthetics in
it to say I I mixed the two don't say
Sanic people are going to comment on
that you already know what I'm talking
about um I think I've been rambling on
about this one for long enough I'm
trying to pull more info out of my head
cuz I know I got more to say uh the te's
are fun I love Brewing up a good tea uh
you can feed a compost tea too your
synthetic mix if you want add those
Organics in there but the Organics are
beautiful especially see I'm a city boy
maybe that's part of my thing I'm a city
boy my neighbors can hear me [ __ ]
recording this podcast right now with
three different directions that side
that side and the folks behind me
they've heard every [ __ ] episode
every edit they know the whole podcast
by now I'm a city boy growing um with
bottle nutrients in the city just seems
to be a little bit easier for me if I
had some land a more private backyard
where I could do some [ __ ] uh I may work
on some Organics and do it that way if I
were growing outdoors I would probably
go organically if I grew outdoors I
Would Do It full hippie organic style uh
but indoor commercially production wise
I feel like bottled nutrients are the
way to go uh my dude black Ray 3K bro
you got me rambling pretty good uh thank
you for the great question make sure you
check your inbox because you've got a
coupon code for a free pack of seeds at
iy
direct.com all right ladies and
gentlemen boys and girls pimps and hoes
friends and foes smokers Growers clone
Cutters pollen Chuckers All of You
Beautiful cannabis enthusiasts out there
I do want to thank you once again for
listening to another quick episode of
The Grow from your heart podcast if you
have any questions Corrections comments
or concerns you know I would love to
hear from you my email address is grow
fromy yourheart hotmail.com let me know
what you think of the podcast of course
if you have grow questions do use that
growel tab at IR genetics.com anything
else you could possibly need is on my
website IR genetics.com there's a link
to the patreon server there's a link to
the Discord server there's a link to iir
to get the seeds everything is at iy
genetics.com once again don't forget to
come back to the Discord server if you
got lost in the shuffle if you got lost
on the new rules if you need some help
please do reach out I miss my friends
out there on Discord also this wasn't
the shout out that I had written down
but my dude doobie I haven't heard from
you in a minute I hope you're well um
reach out bro let me know that you're
well I miss you brother I hope
everything is good dubie was on Discord
all the time haven't seen him in a
minute [ __ ] miss you bro that's right
I make friends on there you guys are not
just the IE Army you guys are close
homies and I wonder where my dude went
anyway join the Discord uh pop in and
once again enter at your own risk in
that [ __ ] gloves off chat um like And
subscribe that's right like And
subscribe and argue down in the comments
keep this uh conversation going in the
comment section for that algorithm all
right that is all I've got for this
episode I'll be back in a week with
fresh new content I want to give a big
shout out to taxidermy kitten and until
next time take a fat dab and give your
mom a hug for
[Music]
me roster Jeff you bad
[ __ ] time to take another Dam
grab your pie in the
b in the lab sit back
relax roots and wisdom start to
s from the knowledge seeds we brow
tuning out to hear the vibr that Jeff in
our conscious
tribe spreads the truth in every
word every voice must now be heard
healing light you canot this go from
your heart your this rise up higher Find
Your Way grow from your heart every day
in the light We Stand real strong join
the movement sing the
song natural medicine and love flows
within us like a do educate and Elevate
join the Journey Don't Be Late open
minds to see the truth in the soil lies
the proof r that je will guide you
through in this garded find the new rise
up higher Find Your Way grow from your
hearts every day in the light We Stand
real strong join the movement sing the
[Music]
song open the minds to see the truth
in the soil lies the proof R Jeff will
guide you through in this Garden find a
new rise up higher Find Your Way grow
from your hearts every day in the light
with stand real strong join the movement
sing the song
o
[Music]
[Applause]