oh [ __ ] Rasta Jeff in the house yeah
welcome back cannabis community it's
time for another episode of the girl
from your heart podcast your source for
cannabis news education and conversation
that's right up here a new grower
if you're a professional grower if
you're a new smoker or a dedicated
dabber if you're a cannabis activists or
even someone who is just curious about
the current state of cannabis this my
friends is the podcast for you
I'm your host my friends call me Roscoe
Jeff I want to thank you guys again for
joining me this episode of the podcast
is brought to you by my friends at the
hell a dank seed company if you need new
genetics for your gardening I highly
recommend the hella dank seed company
you can find them at dank seed dot store
ladies and gentlemen roll up a fat joint
pack up the bong or start heating up
that dab rig because it's time for
another episode of to grow from your
heart a podcast
what's up podcast world it's time for
episode 3 11 of the grow from your heart
podcast thanks again for joining me
before we get too far this episode is
brought to you by my friends at the hell
a dank seed company let's write the
hella dank seed company just got a fresh
drop of eye region etics feminized seeds
that's right there are a whole bunch of
blueberry cookies feminized Cross's
available at the hella Danks seed
company there is Leonardo there's
Donatello
there's Raphael there's Michelangelo and
there are bebop and rocksteady all six
are available you can get all six for a
special price or get them individually
you can find them at dank seed dot store
make sure you jump on there and get them
soon because they are very limited and
they will sell out very quickly make
sure you check those out and just cuz
I'm sure some of you are curious the
Raphael is Strawberry Fields cross two
blueberry cookies and the bebop is
Durban poison cross two blueberry
cookies they're all feminized if you
want to know what the others are make
sure you check out dank seed dot store
for all the information alright enough
advertising for today I like to start
these podcasts off by letting you know
what I'm smoking on today I've been
dabbing on some star dog ambrosia from
apothecary farms I've been in love with
a star dog lately I love the way it
smells I love the way it smokes I love
the high it gives me I love growing star
dog I like taking pictures of it star
talk has just been
it's been a great plant for me lately
I'm giving it a smell right now it's got
that fuelie earthy thing that I've been
into lately and then it's got something
else on top of it something just dirty
and funky and I really love it fuelie
dirty feet funk right up my alley just
the exact thing I've been in love with
lately I've been so in love with the
star dog lately that I crossed it to a
rise and I came up with the name I've
been trying to struggle for a name for
it and I was in an Instagram live feed
the other day and one of our friends who
I'm not sure if he wants his name said
on a podcast but he shouted out or he
typed out I guess he typed out
starstruck and I'm going with it
starstruck is awesome starting to arise
that is called starstruck so coming soon
to a seed bank near you starstruck all
right so we got starstruck named we got
blueberry cookies crosses available and
I am smoking star dog ambrosia I think
we've covered all the business for the
start of the podcast let's get into the
main topic if you pay attention to the
podcast you have probably heard me talk
about a dispensary known as sweet leaf
sweet leaf is a chain of dispensaries in
Colorado that got in trouble for doing
something known as looping now before we
get too far I'll tell you what looping
is in the state of Colorado when you buy
recreational cannabis you were allowed
to buy one ounce at a time per
transaction now a lot of people found
that word per transaction as a loophole
they would buy an ounce of cannabis they
would then drive around the block or
maybe just go get lunch or something and
then come right back to the same
dispensary and buy another ounce of
cannabis which means they have now
purchased two ounces of cannabis from
the same dispensary in one day now at
some point the marijuana Enforcement
Division sent out a memo saying no more
looping the rule is that you were
allowed to sell one ounce of cannabis
per person per day from your facility so
at that time it was expected that
looping would stop it appears allegedly
that sweetleaf continued with the
looping and that puts us kind of in the
article that I've got before me this
article comes from the cannabis and it
was written by Alicia Wallace and it was
originally published on April 30th and
it was updated yesterday and it goes
like this
the sweet leaf dispensary chain shut
down in December after police sting was
a criminal enterprise that pocketed
millions from an illicit looping scheme
that allowed customers to purchase the
maximum amount of marijuana multiple
times in a day a municipal hearing
officer has ruled as a result sweet leaf
marihuana sinners could be stripped of
its 26 retail cultivation and
manufacturing licenses according to
recommendations released Monday by
Denver hearing officer Suzanne phasing
sweet leaf scheme at the very least
permitted the unlawful possession by its
customers and it's scheme was not the
action of a reasonable licensee she
wrote
not only did sweetly fail to take action
to stop the illegal purchases but it
actively aided and abetted the illegal
purchases through it's looping scheme
Ashley Kilroy the city's director of
Marijuana Policy will have the final say
on sweet leaves faith following a 10-day
period for objections and a 5-day period
for a response
gilroys determination could come in the
next few weeks officials for the city of
Denver said sweet leaf could not be
immediately reached for comment
sweet Leafs licenses were suspended on
December 14th when police raided eight
sweetly facilities in Denver and Aurora
following a year-long undercover
investigation into illegal marijuana
sales more than a dozen arrests of bud
tenders and customers have been made in
connection with the case the
investigation zeroed in on alleged
incidents of looping in which sweet leaf
bud tenders would make repeated sales of
up to one ounce of recreational
marijuana the maximum allowed for
individual possession under Colorado law
to the same customer multiple times in
one day
looping accounted for at least six point
seven million dollars of medical
marijuana sales in the 18-month period
that ended when the stores were shut
down and at least 1.5 million dollars in
recreational marijuana sales according
to the hearing officers report at least
half of the loopers had out-of-state ids
phasing wrote she found that people from
Arkansas Nebraska New Mexico and Texas
purchased large amounts of marijuana to
resell illegally in their home states
some of those customers were convicted
of criminal charges after being arrested
with multiple pounds of sweet leaf
marijuana in their possession now I'm
sure a lot of people are gonna go how
can they prove that that was sweet leaf
marijuana well because when you buy
something
from a dispensary it comes very nicely
packaged but then they put a sticker on
it with their logo right on it I'm
looking at a couple of containers
I've got apothecary farms logos all over
my table I've got a Three Rivers logo
right here I've got a whole pie I've got
a cut above logos right here they could
tell where all of my products came from
and if you couldn't tell by the logo on
it there's a number on it every one of
these packages let's see if I can find
it on here there it is right there it's
actually got the dispensary the address
the city the zip code the phone number
followed by the MMC number the Medical
Marijuana Center the 402 dash number
that number right there indicates
exactly where that came from so it's
that back that's how they know where it
came from they know what day that was
grown they know what day that was
purchased if any of those stickers are
on there all the details are right there
and a lot of people out of state they
want that labeling on there because it
makes the product worth more that came
from Colorado it's got labels on it
that's a quality product the price goes
up so people are [ __ ] up there taking
those labels with them that's how they
know that it was sweet leaf product all
right let's move on with the article
where was I facing her testimony in
sweet leaves case over several days and
March and April essential a central
issue raised then was what constituted a
transaction Colorado's marijuana rules
were amended on January 1st to define a
single transaction as including multiple
transfers to the same consumer during
the same business day where the retail
marijuana store employee knows or
reasonably should know that such
transfer would result in that consumer
possessing more than one ounce of
marijuana sweet Leafs attorneys argued
that Colorado marijuana rules in place
prior to January 1st did not explicitly
prohibit the sale of more than one ounce
of recreational marijuana per day but
rather it barred any single sale of more
than one ounce of recreational pot
multiple transaction to the same person
would not have been in violation of
state law they said fazing disagreed
citing a marijuana Enforcement Division
public notice that outlined how sales
that are structured as multiple
standalone transactions may be viewed as
an attempt to evade quantity limitations
on the sale of recreational marijuana
sweet Leafs owners matthew aiken
christian johnson and anthony saguaro
encouraged and directed the practice of
looping including training new employees
to allow looping for retail customers if
the customer left the premise after each
purchase she wrote evidence cited by
phasing included messages from
management on sweet leave slack channel
promoting multiple sales to the same
customer looping is going to be going on
and tell the new year most likely they
wrote please talk it up with extended
plant count patience we need med sales
up the evidence is clear in this case
that respondents implemented a looping
scheme that was intended to evade
quantity limitations on the sale of
retail marijuana she said so it looks
like there's a huge chance that sweet
leaf will lose all of these licenses and
if that happens there will be a lot of
hot license is up for sale we're gonna
see some changes in the game when that
comes but it looks like a lady by the
name of Ashley Kilroy has the final say
on what's going on
looks like they get a 10-day period for
objections and then a five-day period
for a response and it looks like they
say the determination could come in the
next few weeks you guys I will do my
best to keep everybody updated and I
want to give Mike a huge shout-out for
sharing this article with me hey do it
thanks for the great text message it
made a great podcast episode ladies and
gentlemen it just started if you live in
Colorado if you live in southern
Colorado you know about the Miller moth
season every year on southern Colorado
we get invaded by these little moths
that fly around all of your lights they
come out of nowhere ah the first one
just arrived in my house I just flew
around the light it has begun they're
really not that bad they're just
annoying they fly around all the lights
all the time and when they bump into the
lights all that moth dust that butterfly
dust comes off their wings so you gotta
just keep [ __ ] covered up and honestly I
start turning off more light so it
helped me remember to turn off all the
damn lights I got to cover up all the
hash on the table I can't have any
concentrates open cuz I don't want that
moth dust in my concentrates I think
that's disgusting the worst part is when
they get in the damn grow room because
they just want to fly around your light
and all on the light they smack the if
you got glass over the light like I've
got vented lights they bounce all over
that and if you don't have glass over
the lights they fly into the [ __ ]
bulb and cook themselves and it smells
so yeah they're annoying more than
anything but they have arrived it is
Miller season all right you guys I want
to give a few shout outs before I start
wrapping up this episode I want to give
a huge shout out to my friend the can of
crap what's up bro also a huge shout out
to will Parsons and an extra fat
shoutout to Miles Porter ladies and
gentlemen oh and thank you guys for
listening to this podcast I would
appreciate it if you stock me on all of
the social media you can find me on
Facebook simply search for the
girlfriend heart podcast you can find me
on Instagram you guys I've been doing
super fun Instagram live videos on
Instagram I'm Irie underscore genetics I
RIE underscore genetics
I read genetics is my seed company I
make regular and feminized seeds they're
available at dank seed store follow my
Instagram feed you can check out my live
videos I kind of do
mini podcasts sort of on the Instagram
life I go and hang out with my friends I
take dads and we talk about cannabis we
talk about life we talk about whatever
comes up I have a lot of fun I think you
would too come join us
it's Irie underscore genetics on
Instagram you guys if you want to follow
me on Twitter you can find the show it's
@g f YH podcast if you want to follow me
it's at Rasta Jeff 420 come follow me
show me some love give me some support I
would appreciate it also you guys if
you've got a product you'd like me to
review or if you'd like to sponsor the
show or if you've got something you'd
like to say and you're not into all the
social media you can send me an email
it's grow from your heart at hotmail.com
I would love to hear from you I like to
take the emails and turn them into
full-length episodes that way I know I'm
helping people out also YouTube you guys
YouTube has been knocking down cannabis
channels so far I have survived I've got
over 250 videos on YouTube now to make
sure you check out the girl from your
our podcast on YouTube last one you guys
patreon patreon.com slash grow from your
heart if you'd like to support the show
financially you can do so by visiting
patreon.com slash grow from your heart
all the information that you need will
be right there on patreon.com slash grow
from your heart ladies and gentlemen I
will be back Monday with a brand new
full-length episode I want to thank
everybody for hanging out with me for
these Thursday episodes just a little
bonus chat for you just do something to
brighten your day just something to make
Thursday suck a little less just
something to make Friday come that much
sooner ladies and gentlemen thanks again
for hanging out with me I want to give a
huge shout out to my friend Elle
slub from medical marijuana radio and
until next time take a fat dab and give
your mom a hug for me
[Music]
you