chris
and just for just for further context so
you actually and so lou elizondo came
out um and was uh was disappointed in
the uh i believe it's the aoi
um
and i saw tim you had you had similar
concerns do you want to you want to tee
us up for that
sure yeah yeah um
yeah
it's kind of funny you know i think
i i guess concerns as much as
this
we talk about not having expectations
but this is what i kind of expected
and uh you know people are wondering
what's going on like why have you got
now you've got this really broad robust
amendment but then you've got the
government you know the dod coming out
of the blue with this other
you know really watered down kind of
expectation what they're going to
achieve
and people like what the hell is going
on is it the cover-up is it the you know
whatever no it's it's it's the
government the government is happening
and you've heard me probably say this
was on twitter i may have said it last
time i was on your show
is people are getting a crash course on
how the government actually works
and uh
it's not pretty and and i hate saying
that but and i think to to some degree
you know the ufo community some of the
some of the more well-known researchers
or authors at times have done a bit of a
disservice because they've given this
picture that the government is capable
of this coordinated effort in anything
uh and that's not really the case uh
probably one of the best examples to
give you an
idea of what's going on here and i
talked to this a little bit about with
the guys and and girl chrissy last night
um
you know did anybody read the psychology
today article that was published was it
yesterday or the day before
micah
where was where was it published
it was psychology today okay then no i
yeah
no i didn't i didn't
i missed it okay well there you go ufo
twitter you're dropping the ball there
was a
exceptional article done uh in you in
psychology today uh
about uap and what it could mean in
terms of new science and everything and
the author of that article was dr eric
hasseltime
dr hasseltine is a brilliant man he once
headed up uh
disney's imagineering
and then he was the
chief science and technology officer for
the office of director of national
intelligence odni
he was essentially the chief technology
officer for the entire intelligence
community so very brilliant guy for a
long time
and he wrote a great article there but
he also wrote a great book a couple
years ago and i loved it now i know
you're wrong it's kind of right up in my
alley
it may get too technical for some people
but it's called uh the spy in moscow
station
and it tells this fantastic story and if
you want to understand how the
government works it's a great insight
into how it works in the
short of the long there is a very true
real story of events that happened in
1978 the the nsa
discovered a
soviet bug inside the embassy in moscow
okay when i say discovered it they found
it they removed it they physically had
it it was an rf receiver hidden in a
chimney inside the embassy
they said that the soviets are listening
to all of your communications they told
the cia this and the state department
and in fact the cia had had
russian agents killed during this time
because of it
and the cia in the state department said
we don't believe you
and they had it in front of them like
they could have showed it to him no we
don't believe him
and the nsa pushed it and it was this
big turf war and i'm not going to get in
the weeds of this book but you really
get an idea of how it works where you're
like
why are they fighting this like it's
isn't everybody supposed to be on the
same team like why is there this
resistance here
into this idea that the russians are
spying on us and the cia was adamant
about it and the state department was
adam about it to the point where they
got a executive directive telling the
nsa stop mentioning it
stop talking about it because you know
we don't want people we don't believe
you
and this went on for five
years
until the nsa was eventually by
uh order of president reagan allowed to
go in remove a lot of the property that
was in the embassy found the bugs
discovered and said
they've been listening to you this whole
time so for five years from the point
they found it for five years all right
wow
there was so much resistance to this and
so much craziness and even at a point
when the nsa had difficulty finding
these bugs they they actually thought
that uh this maybe the cia removed them
so that they wouldn't find them to cause
friction in fact when the nsa technician
went to do the inventory the cia tried
to get him drunk and and had russian
prostitutes because they wanted to know
what he was doing there because it was
so compartmentalized they it was that
point a covert option where only the nsa
knew
now
picture that in perspective to uap okay
picture that in perspective that
now you know adversaries spying on you
is a real thing they all know that's a
real thing it goes on we spy on other
countries they spy on us but imagine the
resistance to the idea that the russians
or the soviet union was spying inside
the embassy when you had the proof of
evidence
so the us government is a sprawling
complex and now what you're seeing is
that the uap subject is not going to go
away per se and they're kind of
acknowledging it so you're going to see
a lot of infighting here as in who
controls the topic and you you that's
one of the things in that whole
that calls so much friction between the
cia and nsa is
whose job is it you know they all say
well nsa is their job isn't security so
screw them and it's like yeah but this
is going on and so you're going to see
this now and you're going to see this
now with this idea okay well fine if
you're going to make if you if you're
not going to let this go away and
somebody's going to look at it well then
it's our job but then you're going to
have other agencies that are like no
this is my job
others are going to say it's my job
because at the end of the day nobody
wants to get embarrassed
and say oh yes this is really something
uh
when it
when it could when technically it should
have been their job
and if nothing else i think probably one
of the most fascinating things for me
and maybe it's not as frustrating
because it's fascinating to me to watch
this process
is
i can't think of a more complex problem
to watch a government have to solve and
especially one like the us government
because it's everything is so segmented
and compartmentalized
where different agencies follow their
different branches they have different
jobs but you look at the uap subject
that is something that is
government-wide and it is a mysterious
problem that frankly the us government
is not equipped to handle and so it's
interesting to watch how are they going
to handle that because the dod i think a
lot of people when they saw that i'm not
going to attempt the acronym i've
forgotten from memory i don't want it
uh you know they they cried foul but
they were only going to look into
military ranges and ranges under
military control
well that's because by federal law the
department of defense only has limited
power they don't have the power to
operate on u.s soil except under very
very strict circumstances
so they don't have authority so then
goes into well some of this authority
bleeds into the coast guard some of this
bleeds into the faa some of this bleeds
into homeland security some of this
bleeds into the fbi all everyone i just
named all fall under different executive
branches so when the the secretary of
defense can't tell the fbi what to do
can't tell the faa what to do likewise
none of them can tell
but to comprehensively look at that
you've got to get all of these agencies
that aren't equipped to look at it they
don't work together as is and in many
instances they work against each other
they're in competition with each other
but they've got to work together to try
to solve that
now tackle on the fact that
every taboo that you can think of in
anything any conversation that you've
had about the subject with anybody who's
not from the ufo community maybe they've
just seen the new york times article or
something or or they've read it an
excellent and informative piece on the
deep reef uh and you're trying to
explain it to them and they're
they're like oh that's bs those that's
now imagine the government just multiply
that so you're going to have people that
are like this is bs
the infighting and squabbling
and even if let's say the gillibrand
amendment passes um who what office is
going to take that authority it is
something to really look at but i did i
i said that you know when i said my
concerns it was more of a people are
about to get a crash course into this
ufo problem
and then because of how robust how how
structured that amendment was
um
it wouldn't shock me to see not just the
dod but you're going to see all these
other people be like oh hell we're
starting one too because we're not going
to be outdone and everybody's going to
try to muscle in this and it's going to
end up in this really interesting
dynamic
where a year ago
people were upset because the government
wasn't taking the topic seriously at all
now fast forward we're upset because
there's too many people saying they're
going to look into it
well here here's here's my question on
that though and i think
the reason at least lately the reason
why people got upset is because there
seemed to have been
a message coming primarily from lou
thing this af msg office is undercutting
and undermining the gillibrand amendment
and you also compared it to um
you said in a tweet that it's
administrative terrorism
um and so people heard that they're like
what's going on and then when you dig
deep into it when you just simply dig
into it you find out that oh wait a
second
the dod has no jurisdiction over this
this bill so if this bill becomes law
they really can't do anything and it
seems by the statement by kathleen hicks
that this office that the dod is
creating they're doing it without
anyone's permission they're doing it
just because they can't
um and figure it sort of this idea of
well
they're not going to be the only ones
who look at this we're going to look at
it too
and so i guess my question is
why is this administrative terrorism if
this office really can't do anything to
if this law passes if the
amendment goes through which maybe we
find out tonight if it could have
happened already as we were on the show
um but
if that
can you explain a little bit as to why
that's sort of the feeling with with
this new office because
six months ago we would have been all
aboard for this we would have been
absolutely
filled with an office like this and um
and it seems like for me more data is
more data i don't care where i'm getting
it from if we're gonna get more data
from different sections of the
government great maybe we could paint a
better picture with that data um or we
could get at least a little bit more
clarity for the american people as to
what exactly we're dealing with here so
um so yeah i mean can you touch on that
a little bit
sure yeah yeah no and i i it's one of
those things where i said it and didn't
realize after and until i said it
people might not be familiar with the
term
yeah
yeah the term administrative terrorism
and anybody that's worked in government
even at the local level is very familiar
with that term we used it all the time
because administrative terrorism is just
that it's bureaucratic stuff that slows
things down you know you're getting
ready to run out the door to go to the
mall and somebody says wait wait wait
wait we got to inventory all of your
clothes and you're like what the
this is administrative terrorism and so
that term is yeah anybody who's working
in government has heard that term in
fact used it frequently so so please
don't take anything away from that is
that being uh i guess analogous with
terrorism
right right right yeah but uh but i mean
it does make it sound as if though you
know like like this is a bad thing this
office is not good for the topic
and at least that's the way it seemed it
seemed like that was the and that's why
ufo twitter sort of rallied around like
letting their senators know hey this
office isn't good enough like we need
more we want the gillibrand amendment to
make sure that that passes into into the
new ndaa um but it's you know you know
what i'm saying i just i think part of
there's there's a part of a little bit
of fear here that
like you want to be used to construct a
narrative or a message like that was
gonna be like a follow-up question in a
second was is it
is there anything with this amendment or
with these new offices that you might
see as like
as maybe
not good for this topic is there
anything that we're just not reading
correctly or we're not deciphering
properly is there anything in the
language of the bill that maybe worries
you that hey this is actually going to
do worse for the topic not better
well i think the biggest concern and i
think that's what louis lozando i
haven't read everything he said or
listened to it but i think that uh when
he he was upset about it is because he's
been in that system and understands kind
of what's going on
and the other thing is that it is
everyone is correct in saying that the
release of that information uh very much
was
it it had a lot to do with the
gillibrand amendment you know the timing
of it and everything i think everybody
could recognize that even though
kathleen hicks had said we're going to
do this uh you know i believe the
timeline initially was six months and
it's been five months and they come out
with it the government does nothing
early
okay they do nothing so you think it was
you think the odni this was a direct
response to the introduction of the gila
brand amendment
sure i think that the phone calls phones
started ringing when that went out it
hit the airways and everything
people were saying hey what are we doing
with our stuff what are we doing with
our stuff we don't want to get caught
with our pants down what are we doing in
addition to the fact that you've got the
office of the inspector general digging
into it too so there's a lot of cya
going on a lot of people are trying to
cover their ass
and they're trying to say you know again
like i mentioned nobody wants to get
caught with their pants down where they
haven't been doing anything so the idea
that od and i is going to take over this
massive office and have all this
jurisdiction and then prove all these
things the dod hasn't been doing well
does not sit well with the dod so
they're like whoa whoa
if nothing else we need to know what's
going on within our jurisdictional
bounds uh so that we don't look like a
bunch of clowns here
with no answers if this other agency has
answers now
beyond that tim do you think there's
actual information that they're they're
trying to get a handle on and bury prior
to the gila brand amendment do you think
that's a possibility or are we really
just talking about hey we're just trying
to cover our asses here
it really depends on what the executive
officers think now i can say that if it
was going out of the under secretary of
defense for intelligence office which is
louis elizondo's former office i think
you've seen the pushback that he's
offered i think he is a good indication
of how he feels they view the topic and
how their uh reports their analysis and
going into it you know going back to
something uh micah said earlier
if you you know go with this expectation
of what you're going to find you often
find it and so
the expectation of that office by all
accounts from everyone that i've spoken
to
is that they want to find bs that this
is not something that they need to be
exerting time effort and money on and so
therefore
the idea that that's going to be their
outcome it could be very highly likely
because that's what you know they don't
i think the department of defense at
large
has
really made it abundantly clear uh not
direct statements because they don't
like talk about it they don't want to
talk about this they don't want to deal
right
whereas some other agencies do uh you
know odni has
taken the lead the navy has taken the
lead
so
one of the concerns there is when in
having these fragmentations so you see
that the dod has their uap office well
od and i was like screw it we're still
going for it and space force says
hold my beer uh i think the army the
army is my favorite because the army is
is like and i come from a big army
family so i can say it's like everybody
i know from the army it was just like
hey man if we're going to strip club
you're driving i'm down you know like
they're
don't matter to me man
but the problem is there is that each
one of those compartments will control
their information and then the topic of
uap you won't have this centralized
focal point office
instead you'll have
uh you know a pilot had a sighting and
reported it to the navy office or the
odni office and they're do we have any
satellite data we've got to go to talk
to
a geospatial or the nro or the nsa to
try to get uh sigint or electronic
intelligence on it
and then those agencies don't
necessarily always hand over
what they have quite frankly they often
don't
and so you it's this idea that uh who
had
is there going to be a central office
that has the authority power and muscle
to really use all of the resources the
united states government has behind it
because whenever we do put all those
resources whether it's terrorism or
fighting wars
uh they tend to be pretty successful and
they have a lot of their disposal but
the problem is these things are not
centralized and they're not under one
umbrella authority outside of the
president you need the president you
know if the president would step forward
and say no damn it just same example i
gave you the nsa cia with the moscow
thing it took the president of the
united states to tell the nsa no go do
this and i don't care what they say
so i think that's part of the concern is
that if you've got a odni office you've
got a dod office and you've got these
other offices is that they will each be
examining the topic from whatever is
within their purview and when
one doesn't share with the other then
it's never
you're going to have mufon and all these
other things you're going to have these
competing it's going to turn into ufo
twitter
in the government
that sounds terrible micah
i've got i've got 17 seconds left so
in fact we're gonna have to roll over on
into the top of the occasion yeah i have
plenty to say and again tim really has
kind of given us you know the the the
full scope of the issues that government
is facing right now to an extent you
know i've got to kind of sympathize with
any element within the government or if
we even want to refer broadly to the
military
having to be tasked with trying to
resolve an issue that let's face it
they've been looking at for more than
half a century and haven't been able to
resolve when we talk about how as tim
mentioned some agencies seem to be more
willing to chime in on this and more
willing to weigh in on the topic like
the navy has been
whether that is necessarily by choice or
it is by virtue of the fact that other
agencies simply won't the air force
dealt with this in the longest-running
systematic military study by the u.s
government project blue book between the
1950s early 50s and 1969
and they remained stone silent
at every opportunity uh for for decades
thereafter with a couple of notable
exceptions after the closure of project
blue book again at the request of
congress men and women back in the 1990s
because there was a lot of public
interest
in the roswell crash at new mexico uh
and this in part due to books that were
being published on it television shows
like unsolved mysteries that were kind
of reinvigorating the debate a lot of
people were like what's really going on
here and so the air force kind of had to
get back into the game there for a time
they produced a couple of official
documents and did their own
investigations
which offered not one but several you
know different explanations for parts of
the roswell mystery um which raised a
lot of questions for people one being
okay well
which version is the definitive
narrative because they had said that
everything from crash test dummies to
charred bodies in an airplane crash to
um project mogul and you know high
altitude balloons that were used during
the cold war i mean a range of different
things put together over several years
constituted what was remembered or
misremembered as the roswell event
the reason that that's important is
because people look at that and they go
well first of all which is the narrative
or
how can we take this seriously given
that we first heard of course that it
was a flying disc then it was a weather
balloon then they say it was a mogul
balloon we know that they had lied
several times so how do we know they're
telling the truth now now in my opinion
having reviewed roswell you know again i
like a lot of ufo researchers have
become less and less enchanted with that
case as time goes on because if you
really look at it again i refer back to
the fbi single page document on that it
was actually from i believe let's see
let's refer to the newspapers i keep
them right here so i can look at all
this right july 8th 1947 i believe that
on the same date the fbi documents said
it appears that a high altitude uh
balloon was recovered they were
reporting that in the fbi's document a
day before it appears in the other
newspapers and it's actually stated we
had a weather balloon in our possession
so it seemed the fbi already been tipped
off and again the historical documents
seem to pretty clearly show
there probably wasn't as much to roswell
as it once had been thought but again
it's an interesting point to look at in
terms of history and what it takes to
get an agency like the air force back
into the game
it's no wonder they don't want to have
to deal with this right now and people
say where's the air force been why is
the navy doing this the air force never
wanted to have to get back into this
game and here again i do sympathize with
almost any element within government who
is tasked with having to do what the air
force tried for almost two decades to do
and weren't able to to achieve and so
the thing about you know bringing this
around to the gillibrand amendment you
know i'm not particularly surprised by
what has been outlined with the new aoi
msg
um
and yeah we'll we'll just refrain from
further jokes about the name but almost
everybody tim burchett in congress
actually got up and made a statement
about this recently and even he said i
don't know where they got that name from
but everybody's joking about this name
you know my theory would be that it may
be intentionally unpronounceable and and
obviously forgettable with the hope that
people won't be able to pronounce it
people won't remember and they won't
focus on it and worry about what they're
doing because they can't pronounce the
name they know the ufo thing that
they've got up there but i wasn't really
surprised by what it actually is
according to the dod release from last
tuesday what was outlined because
essentially all those points were in um
kathleen hicks memorandum that coincided
with the release of the odni report back
on june 25th you know again she's saying
we are very concerned with these
incursions in our military airspace we
want to try and you know be proactive
with looking at these and dealing with
these we want to collect information
about them
they never said you know we're going to
look at everything that happens anywhere
in the skies and again to tim's earlier
point they're not able to there are
jurisdictional issues with their ability
to even do that and so something we have
to take into consideration with all of
this is that according to what hicks
outlined in her memorandum if we look at
the odni report delivered by the uap
task force they state in the report this
is to guide future policy and future
efforts on this issue they seem to have
done essentially exactly what they said
that they would but the surprise had
been that as tim pointed out also
congress you know again senator
gillibrand specifically got into this a
little bit earlier outlined a much more
comprehensive plan one that would be
both more costly and likely would have
to require on the assets and abilities
of many different agencies again this
would be a much more elaborate plan and
i think that the dod looking at this
this is pure speculation on my part but
it's very much in line with what my
colleague has said here they're seeing
this and they're going whoa whoa whoa
hold on let's hit this off at the pass
because we don't want to have to mess
with anything as elaborate as what
they're proposing in this amendment and
so they launched this investigative
agency and it's interesting now to see
how those who have co-sponsored the
proposed amendment to the uh defense
authorization act for fiscal year 2022
are responding to this you know
gillibrand has spoken about it but she's
been a bit
um let's say she's been a bit vague uh
marco rubio issued a statement to air
force magazine he had said look you know
i support the government in looking into
these aerial incursions and these
mystery objects so i think that the
sense at least from what i'm getting
among you know members in congress right
now is that this may not be what we
wanted if this is what we get you know
we'll go with it but obviously luella's
ondo and many others and of course ufo
twitter they've expressed their concerns
because no this wouldn't be the
comprehensive plan that's outlined in
the gila brand amendment uh this is
going to be very limited in scope we
don't have any assurance that there will
be again annual reports delivered to
congress uh semi-annual reporting
updates and again will the public have
any information provided
now strange and paradoxical though it
may sound there's a part of me that
hopes that whatever comes of all this
we won't be handed all the answers
because again at the end of the day we
talk about this all the time at the
debrief we got into this because it's a
fun topic we do want to know the truth i
think we can handle the truth but i
doubt the government has all the answers
and a part of me still enjoys the quest
i enjoy the process of looking into this
and trying to understand what it's all
about and hopefully applying science
toward it so it's anybody's guess where
it'll go from here and we may find out
within a few hours but again i'm not
surprised and i certainly hope that
they're going to be a few surprises on
down the road maybe that civilians will
still be privy to
i think you guys make it such an
important point and i think this is so
critical and luis and i have been
talking about this for for months now is
how critical it is that we don't attach
our identities to a specific belief
system or outcome when it comes to uap i
think that's one of the things that
causes so much harm whether it's
psychological um or you know
sociological harm when it comes to this
topic because
if you do if the outcome is so important
to you a specific outcome is so
important to you when faced with an
alternate reality
then you're you're subject to anxiety
depression all of these things and i
think it's so
dangerous really when it comes to and
especially and tim you brought this up
earlier and i think it was such a such
an important point that you know when
society is in struggle when when when
the world is unknown when outcomes are
ambiguous it's very easy to put your all
your hopes and your faith and your
energy and passion into one basket
and i think you guys represent this
topic in a very with a lot of
journalistic integrity you represent it
in a way that really focuses on you know
let's let's have at this right let's
let's pick let's pick away
what is truth and what is fiction in
order to get to the truth because no
one's preconceived notion no one's
self-fulfilling prophecy is going to be
spot-on and it's so critical that we
don't allow ourselves to personally as
individuals
you know go into spirals of anxiety or
depression or
violence even
over topics like this
sure and i think you know i've had these
discussions with uh
people who've worked on the programs um
can you know in the contemporary program
so the task force that kind of stuff or
people who have worked with them
in different capacities whose names
aren't out there uh but one of the big
questions i had and micah brought this
up that the first time we ever met and
chatted we talked about psychology and
because that's really where kind of my
bread and butter is in cognitive
psychology
and i asked them i said you know
how much effort has been gone how much
effort has been put into this idea
how certain are we that we could
perceive correctly something that is
uh you know inherently alien right and i
say alien not just as not from this
planet i mean something totally
anomalous totally abstract there's no
guarantees there and i think that this
idea that we could have it right
is actually probably pretty wrong
because we can only draw on what
knowledge and information that we have
available to us you know what we can
read in a book what we've been told
we can all imagine a dragon because
we've seen movies by we've had them
described to us but but something that
is just totally you know outside of a
total anomalous discovery what is the
expectation that we could perceive that
correctly and i don't you know there
isn't any you know if we don't have the
language to describe something you're
not gonna be able to describe it and so
that's an interesting aspect of all of
this because we it is such a fleeting
topic i think you know that would be one
of the uh
cornerstone tenets of this topic is it's
always just a little bit you know maybe
it's a fleeting glance or something or
it's
a very intense experience but it's not
captured on video or audio and all these
different things so it's never this full
picture of what we define as being true
factual
or just ground truth reality
and so you know what does that mean
about it i don't know
other than perhaps there is aspects of
this it's very difficult for us because
we don't
we can't perceive what's going on and so
to your point mike
absolutely you know there there is this
idea that if we encounter anything truly
anomalous uh we're not gonna have the
the knowledge base uh existing we're all
gonna be done in kruger here you know
we're gonna believe that it's something
but uh there's nothing that says that's
what it is so yeah if you put all your
eggs in in one basket um you're right it
can cause a lot of distress both on
yourself emotionally psychologically and
just in general and so
part of that fun of as long as there's
an unknown it can be anything and so
that's kind of fun you know it is fun to
me and so let's enjoy that aspect of it
because even if aliens flew in there's
really
we have nothing on our plate here that
says we would see them understand them
or even comprehend it because it would
be alien right
abstract
right
um real quick just i wanted to go back
to what senator tim burchard said
yesterday on the floor um just touch on
it because he did kind of mock the name
of this new office but then you get also
yeah after you do that louise we're
gonna let these guys go yep absolutely
um
aft but then right after that he wrote a
letter
to um ronald s moultrie the under
secretary of defense for intelligence
and security uh basically thanking him
for this new office
and then
but also saying um
you know i'm i'm requesting that the aoi
msg uh brief members of congress on
their findings in a classified setting
followed by a public hearing which means
we could worst case scenario maybe get
some public hearings out of these
offices what do you think that would
look like
and could we trust this office to
provide the american people with
whitney you know
would we get david framer and alex
dietrich in a public setting like that
from this office do you think
i highly doubt it i think when they're
talking about public hearings we would
see
uh something consistent with what we see
all the time with the public hearings
especially the national security public
hearings where you have an agency the
the head of whatever agency comes and
briefs congress publicly
and uh they're oftentimes um
not all that informative you know if
anybody anybody else is a nerd like me
that watch the the 2021 national threats
uh hearing where they have all the heads
the cia the nsa od and is all there and
they all brief what are the big threats
uh you know one of the ones that
obviously came up was covet you know it
was questioned well do we know where
covet came from and uh it's this uh
well we you know
it could have been this it could have
been that and so you very likely could
see the exact same thing with uap you
could see uh
the the director of national
intelligence sitting there telling
congress yes we what you read in that uh
report in june being said verbally
you know yes we have this that the only
nice thing i guess would be in these
instances you do have lawmakers that can
ask questions they can ask follow-up
questions you know marco rubio can stand
up and demand
is it aliens you know
and some of these politicians do a
really good job
of of grandstanding so you know i think
that's where the the idea that people uh
i would say that the public has
definitely had an impact when you see
these lawmakers
talking about it as much as they have
yeah so yeah you know there's um
who's the co-sponsor from south carolina
why am i drawing a blank on it lindsey
graham
lindsey graham yeah yeah i mean good
gosh he could get all sorts of animated
you know i don't know somebody's ever
seen him in the confirmation hearing so
yeah who knows
you'll be up there screaming jumping up
and down
an interesting day that's for sure
i mean just politically speaking i would
be so confused i wouldn't know what to
do with myself
i think i was like oh i like i like what
he's saying but god i really don't like
oh but him that's
if there's any positive you know if it's
not disclosure perhaps the best positive
uh
outcome that can come from all of this
news is people are actually paying
attention to how the government operates
and lawmakers operate and everything and
they they may go this is
stupid like how we how do we get
anything achieved like we've never
we haven't faced another attack because
nobody's wanted to evidently because how
does anything get achieved so if nothing
else hopefully maybe people pay
attention to that and go man some things
need to be changed here yeah and if
congressional hearings occur let's just
hope that it's not congress asking
robert mueller questions can you repeat
the question right right
yeah right i'll refer to the report the
language in the report
and i think that was sort of like a
secondary goal so the of the phone home
was just hey teaching people how to
interact with their government is a good
thing you know how to find the
representatives and you can take this
formula and apply it to whatever
activism you want and it works the same
way
yeah that's just you know it's fun
absolutely no i think that's great i
think that's that's always been a big
thing of mine that's how government's
supposed to work it doesn't matter if we
want the government to go look for
unicorns if enough people in a democracy
want them to look for unicorns well
that's what they need to do then because
that's the way it's supposed to work so
yeah
i definitely commend you guys for that
um we appreciate you guys yeah we
appreciate you guys so much and uh
congratulations again on the one-year
anniversary of the debrief uh if you are
not following these guys make sure you
go to thedebrief.org to check out the
news magazine and um maybe you guys
could tell us uh quickly uh where we
could find you tim uh if people want to
find you on social media if they want to
find a debrief what's the best way to do
that
uh at lt tim mcmillan uh on twitter you
can find me there i go on my little
twitter spats where i'll be on there and
call someone
you can probably argue with people and
then
i disappear for a couple weeks
you are the kind of like the houdini of
twitter
well i just you know and it and micah's
got a half-hearted grin there because he
knows you know he's always like oh god
what did tim do tim's in a twitter mood
because i'll get on there and
just rile up with mike turber or
somebody like that
you gotta talk to that guy right
no you have to you have to
thank you
you just gave him permission you've
completely disrupted the debrief's inner
operations now louise well done
yeah it wouldn't be the first time
[Laughter]
i swear to god every time it is an
accident it is not on purpose
um tim thank you so much for joining us
today again guys go check out the
debrief and we'll talk to you again soon
tim thank you so much thank you thank
you so much guys all right bye-bye
uh ladies and gentlemen the micah hanks
if folks want to find you on social
media if they want to find the micah
hanks program or the debrief how do they
do that yeah well if you want to find
the debrief is thedebrief.org
debrief media on twitter and it's
usually debrief media on the various
social media platforms definitely check
it out again keep in mind we report on a
whole lot more than just uap but even a
lot of people who come there for that
news have you know expressed to tim and
to me and to chris and
many of the other staff uh there that
you know you guys
beautifully tie a lot of this stuff
together you know whether it's defense
developments like you know the
hypersonic glide vehicle that was
apparently tested by russia and it's
miscible missile deployment capabilities
the pentagon looking at that and saying
wow how did they get to that point and
then like what days later they
established this new uap investigative
unit again we're saying that there may
be a lot of things that may uh be
catalysts for what we're seeing
happening with regard to the uap topic
and again we do sometimes look at
tangent areas you're going to find a lot
of that at the debrief if you want to
learn about me
just go to micah hanks.com and you can
find all the podcasts that i produce
i've got
four different podcasts that i'm doing
right now but the mica hanks program is
the flagship it goes out every week
chris is going to be on there with me
this week along with tim we're going to
do a bit of a debrief round table year
end where did we come from how did we
get here and who the hell are all of you
so it's going to be a lot of fun
definitely check that out and uh you can
follow me on twitter at micah hanks i've
made it really easy everything's just my
name so you have a repo you have four
podcasts now oh yeah i mean i've had
four podcasts for a while you can find
all those at mygangs.com by the way but
yeah i mean there's the main show i do a
weekly uh curve events and news podcast
called middle theory um in fact tonight
i'm gonna be taping an episode hence why
i gotta run here in a moment but uh an
episode of the seven ages audio journal
which is the archaeology show i do
and because of my passion for
anthropology i also have a show called
sasquatch tracks where we talk with
actual scientists field researchers
anthropologists investigators biologists
about the possibility that a relict
hominoid like sasquatch could actually
exist so yeah i i stay pretty busy and
you know there's been some discussion
about a possible debrief uh podcast in
the in the year to follow so
you know i'm not going to get any less
busy am i chris plain
amazing well thank you so much micah
it's always a pleasure getting to spend
time with you and uh i mean you you
you're looking smoking hot in the uh the
men in black uh get up so we appreciate
it that's right yeah i didn't actually
wear this just so i could look nice with
you guys wearing your ties this is what
i wear all the time yeah that's your
that's actually your pajamas yeah
you'll have a great one and chris plain
um i'm gonna leave you to these
gentlemen you guys go easy on him please