some folks have asked about the uh madj
pack um and the skunk one the original
art and this is it as he gave it to me
it's actually really big for a pack like
like uh size of normal flower seed type
pack and this is the
back I'll leave it there for a few so
you going read it see set it
down hopefully the shadow doesn't mess
it up too much
but that is an original pack of skunk
one from
1981 sacred seeds handed from Rob
Clark
to my buddy
magic also we have another one that
isn't normally seen especially not in
color and this is if I remember
correctly
carala
beautiful they sacred went way above and
beyond with their packaging here's what
it says
here so shout out to Mr Rob Clark Mr
David Watson laying the groundwork for
everything that was to come um their
ideas really gave a lot of us a a career
and a future you know um so we owe these
men a great great deal of
gratitude here's the flip
side and I'm going to do a short version
of it
too there you go original sacred seeds
corala and skunk
one thanks for looking