still says Green Room
there we go welcome everyone this is
breeder Syndicate and today we have CSI
Humboldt and our coach not so dog so I
hope everyone's stoked uh this is gonna
be a good one so we're going to be
talking today about breeding goals not
so you want to take it away and run with
the topic yeah sure so I mean the last
few episodes or whatever we've been
chatting a little bit about like
breeding history and various aspects of
it we talked a little bit about terms
and we thought maybe it would be better
to chat about something that's not
talked about too often which is like
what are your goals when you take two
things and you cross them together what
are you hoping that each parent might
give the children of that and then talk
a little bit about like sort of the
state of where things are and what's
popular and methods and things like that
so
um yeah I mean that's kind of where
we're gonna bring it obviously this is
the first time we've had three people on
it so it's a little different super
stoked that uh our buddy was willing to
come on and join us because he is one of
the most uh prolific uh breeders that I
know of so uh he's lots of he has lots
of experience uh success failures all
that type of stuff so we're pretty
excited to uh have him on and to be able
to chat it up about this subject so uh
we're just gonna kind of get started
what do you want to start at
uh you know maybe maybe we could just
start at sort of like
um
you know maybe we could just started
breeding goals yeah you know so maybe
we'll start with there's a lot of people
out there today and this is this is a
legitimate thing to do but I think it's
a little too common maybe where uh oh we
just lost anyway so well hopefully he
pops back on but we
um a lot a lot of breeding today is um
you know people crossing two things that
they don't you know that most people
don't have access to right and then when
you buy that when you buy that hybrid
you're hoping to find you know one of
those cuts that you don't have access to
right something they consider Elite
hopefully find it something that they
can that they can consider Elite right
so maybe a really really good example
that's like fairly recent uh yeah uh
somehow Caleb was uh was perfect for the
30 minutes and then within 30 seconds of
joining he got booted so hopefully he'll
pop back on in a minute but yeah
um you know well maybe we'll talk about
like for instance Skittles for a second
so you know Skittles comes out Skittles
starts winning a bunch of awards uh the
Skittles crew held on to Skittles pretty
tight for a bit so I get emerald cup and
some different other events
people buying hybrids of it was
literally the only way that they could
get a hold of it right and so that's one
of the way that's one of the things that
drives breeding in some in some
instances something gets famous
it could be Skittles could be cookies
could be Kush could be any number of
different things and then most people
don't have access to that cut because
maybe it's hoarded or maybe the circles
are still pretty tight or whatever and
so
um the pricing and the desirability for
people to buy seeds of that thing become
pretty high yeah
supply and demand how it always works
yeah it's supply and demand basically
and so that that is driven actually a
lot of breeding
um because you're just you're just
offering up you know hey you can't get
the cut but you know maybe you'll find
something in Skittles by TK that you'll
like yeah you know and that that drives
a lot of breeding and so that's kind of
been like one of the the modern ways
that people do things is that they're
mashing together a bunch of Famous Cuts
yeah uh it was certainly the the the
revolution certainly happened with
feminized breeding and it allows you to
eliminate males for the most part
um and read you could take two very
famous cuts and mash them together
and so that sort of started this era of
like I'm gonna take a famous cut I'm
going to try to reverse it and I'm gonna
put you know however many 10 or 20 other
Famous Cuts in the room with it
and boom now I have all these different
lines
um you know so that's kind of that's one
of the the more modern ways that people
do things but a long time ago
uh and by long I mean say 12 or 13 years
ago because I think yeah Matt can clear
this up but I think 0809 you know that
was sort of like the first era that
people started reversing females yeah
right around that 0708 I would say that
some of the first people to do it would
be uh uh OG rascal absolutely Matt
himself uh CSI uh there wasn't very many
people doing it the technology wasn't
very well known at that point in time
um but previous to 12 years ago or 13
years ago everybody used males
yeah that was the you use males so we'll
talk a bit about males because that's
sort of where
um you know that was the state of
reading for the longest time yeah you
know uh and one of the things about
males that was that's a lot harder than
taking two Elites that you already know
people like two females that are already
awesome and Crossing them together is
males don't give you nearly the same
level of
um what's the best way to describe
the traits that you can sense we use we
use the we consume the females
and we only really use males for
breeding so males you know what traits
they're going to pass on was a lot more
mysterious yeah right so uh what people
used to do is let's say that you have
some females that you think are amazing
um and you know you want to cross them
back in the day you would have to cross
it to a male and see what and grow
actually grow out the beans and see what
that male gate
yeah right and sometimes people would
take like let's say for instance you
know
um you might take four or five different
males yeah cross them separately to the
same female
and then grow out each batch
these two these two males I don't like
what they gave to their kids that's not
what I'm looking for yeah but male three
male feet three through the traits that
I'm looking for
right yeah so a lot of times it was
pretty laborious in the sense that you
didn't really know which one you wanted
to work with until you started growing
their kids yeah and that's that's
typically how most breeders do it and
that's how most breeders have done it uh
throughout time so breeding used to be a
much more time consuming process yeah in
that regard to find things out you know
um and uh you know so so that's kind of
how that's kind of how things started
but there was a lot of
throw some pollen on your favorite
females
and see what happens right a lot of
things people don't that people take for
granted when it comes to males first is
that there is one one single thing that
you will use for selection on a mail
like I only select males that are sturdy
you know or I only select males that
have hollow stems because that's going
to tell me it's going to breed the way I
want
um but back in the day yeah you had to
run the progeny to see what traits are
going to be bred for it's not males
don't have that that uh a a high terpene
content like females so even if it did
even if you have a male that you can
smell the terpenes on it doesn't
necessarily mean it's going to breed
that way it's just an expression it's
just an expression so yeah uh you know
there's um you know and and so maybe
maybe we'll we'll talk about a few
really famous lines uh just because
they're they're famous so everybody
should know about them and this is what
people back in the day so now what's
very common is people mishmash a bunch
of famous stuff together
and then they sell it and they're hoping
that people will find some nice plants
or some Elites or some whatever in their
progeny yeah but most breeding is not
done like that uh in cannabis and
especially in other areas correct most
breeding is
I have traits from this line that I want
there he is
you made it back can you hear us
he's back he's smiling it okay so man so
you know um most breeding back in the
day uh was you would take you would have
two lines and you would have certain
traits from each line that you were
hoping to combine into one line
right that was kind of that was kind of
the goal so yeah maybe we'll take
something like
um like nl5 Haze because it's super
famous and we chatted about it before so
you know there was this Haze plant it
took 18 to 24 weeks it didn't form the
greatest buds but it had great High it
had a great great terp profile had a
bunch of stuff and they were trying to
figure out how to make it
semi-reasonable to grow and so they
picked this NL plant which had basically
no smell but had a lot of a lot of
crystal and a lot of um you know a lot
of a lot of resin a lot of good
structure and it took way way way less
time so they were trying to blend the
flavor and the effect and the
stretchiness of the haze with the resin
content the shorter flowering time and
the fudge structure of the NL yeah right
and that was kind of the goal they
mashed them together and then you know
another point we should probably make is
that the more traits you're trying to
find from each parent line in the
children the harder it is
yeah
you know they were talking about this
yesterday
um it's really really hard to select for
more than one or two traits in cannabis
because it has so many [ __ ] traits uh
trades we don't talk about like root uh
one of the main ones we don't talk about
is root Expressions uh different
different root sizes different root
hairs you know there's so many different
expressions and you really can only
breed for a few traits in cannabis at a
time so yeah it makes it tough I mean
there was a there was a line that uh
that Shanti Baba released a long time
ago uh used to be called Peacemaker it
was also called great white shark now
it's called shark shock I think and uh
you know it was it's skunk it's skunk by
White Widow and I ran through a few
hundred of those seeds I really liked it
it I found some incredibly potent pot
but all the potent stuff didn't taste
like much
and all the stuff that's was really
skunky didn't get me high very much yeah
and I kept trying to find one that had
both but I couldn't
you know I still liked it I kept one for
a long time that was really really
potent but it kind of tasted like it
didn't have bad flavor it just kind of
tasted like like good smoke
yeah that was about it right and so
um you know most people they don't talk
today about like you know and maybe
Caleb can jump in on this too but you
know when you're looking at two
different things right if you're gonna
cross Skittles by this what do you want
each what are you hoping that maybe each
parent might give the seeds might give
the children that you are excited about
like what are your goals and that's kind
of like the theme of what we want to
talk about today is like breeding goals
oh we lost them again
so uh humble but I I teed him up to
start talking and then he disappears
right so
um you know but anyway so I guess I'll
check are you there
he's there he just doesn't have video
right there
yeah your video is gone but you're here
you can hear me yeah I can hear you I
just can't see you sir
my phone's acting up all kinds it I even
have a thing that says warning it looks
like you're B so I'm thinking that's
battery is overheating
oh wow yeah so maybe try audio without
the video
okay okay yeah we'll try it this way
shouldn't shouldn't be too hard on it
that way oh right when connections Get
Low we'll cut the video so maybe you've
got some like Humboldt Style
80s connections that uh so maybe maybe
audio Maybe audio will work yeah
my connection is actually weak I don't
know why can you hear us well yeah yeah
yeah yeah I can hear and see you just
fine
what I was talking about right before is
sort of like when you CR when people
cross things what are the ideas and what
are the hopes behind what they're
looking for to for each parent to give
right what are the traits they're
looking or they're hopeful that the the
parent might give
um right
you know and so one of the things that
one of the things that kind of I I think
separates uh CSI from a lot of other
people is that a lot of people cross
things and never test them and they just
release them to the public right yeah
right right but if you if you go back on
uh on csi's page you can go back years
and see him running crosses of his own
hybrids for a long time and what that
does is that actually gives you an idea
of what the parents you're using throw
in their progeny
which ones are consistent breeders which
ones are a mess and are all over the
place you know there's some things out
there that it might be amazing clones
um that breed like crap
you know they they don't transfer the
qualities of the mother cut into its
children very much and so breeders
naturally when they find things that
work they tend to go back to them
right right
I mean most people generally want what I
consider mythical plants
they want plants that are high yield
High potency extremely flavorful just
like you were talking about you know
they want everything in one plant and
not only one plant but they want all the
seeds to be everything and that's not
the reality of it you know yeah like
with your Skittles example I mean it it
if I'm breeding with Skittles my goal is
to take the best characteristics of
Skittles which would be the flavor and
the smell
and hopefully incorporate that into
something
um with another desirable characteristic
from the other parent which would be
maybe like yield or potency you know
what I mean
special for breeding
for your purposes
say what what
some of the other lines you've worked
with that you feel have special traits
and characteristics that maybe maybe
they that breed true for it that you
really enjoy that you found over the
years
oh I mean you know I love the love the
urkles the whole family yeah I love
triangle Kush you know OG Kush in
general I think it's just you know a
great building block
um and then the chem family
um you know which you know most people
know
uh my opinion on that I I think it's
just really chem 91 and everything past
that is a chem hybrid or poly hybrid
yeah you know I agree
yeah I uh you know that it's a it's a
delicate subject but I think that uh you
know plants don't lie and when you've
grown a lot of these chem chem plants
for a long time and especially cross
them and see what's in them uh it does
seem that way you know uh you know one
of the things that uh that came from me
but I don't think anybody has used it
more than than uh Caleb is
um the the Mendo perps is probably a
good example uh because the Mendo perps
is it's fast it's fairly fast finishing
it's got crazy colors in it it's got
very unique Terps uh but it's pretty low
potency uh you know in regard and so you
know um
one of the one of the you know one of
the things that uh that he he released
that that you know got a name cut was
this Obama kush where he married uh
Mendo P to uh Bubble Kush and the Bubba
added a bunch of frost it added a bunch
of structure it added much more potency
and then the Mendo P seemed to add a lot
of pretty color and gave the bubba some
different unique smells
um
that's the really good example of like
taking the strengths from one plant and
Crossing it to something else where
those strengths or weaknesses
right yep you know
um you know and then you know there's
things that there's things that interest
people so what I always recommend people
do when they're breeding uh because
breeding is a lot of work uh it's time
consuming and there's a certain amount
of failure involved is if you have goals
or you're passionate about certain
plants you're using then that to me
that's the coolest kind of breeding you
know if you're like I want to take these
traits from this plant and I want to see
if I can get these traits and these
traits from these two plants into one
plant yeah right and you know when
you're passionate about something you
know as as Caleb just mentioned he just
rolled through you know favorites and he
might be able to explain at length why
each one of those strains
um you know why you know there's
probably a combination of traits that he
likes in each one of those and there's
also probably a combination of not only
those traits he likes but they pass
those traits onto the kids you know
pretty consistently
um you know
so I don't know I mean maybe you want to
like one of the things you've told me in
the past Caleb is that of a lot of the
things that you use the chem 91 seems to
be one of the most consistent breeders
for adding potency to its progeny right
right and you know uh
on on that one I uh I also think that
you know and I I've told you both this
you know plenty of times I I have a
strong suspicion that I think the chem
91 itself is an S1 from its original
Source in Colorado
um so I think that might have something
to do with the with the you know it's
propensity to pass on that strength
because it's it's kind of like a
bottlenecked S1 already you know yeah
and uh
you know um anytime you go you know S1
F2 etc etc you know things I think are
more stable and easier to pass forward
as long as they're not like a recessive
yeah yeah but
um it's very consistent in up in the
potency on whatever you cross it to you
know whether it's you know feminized or
regular seeds or whatever
you know what are some of the traits you
like about bubble gum I know that's one
you use extensively and and uh your
advice uh I used it for the bubbleberry
I'm super stoked on it how it breathes
I mean I love the bubble gum cut because
it's one of the best plants I've ever
grown Out outdoors
um
just almost mold proof you know yeah and
it's extremely Frosty has a sweet you
know bubble gum smell
um
and it's just a nice all-around plant
now yeah does it does it compare with
today's you know hypey stuff and
probably not but you know for for you
know somebody who's farming outdoors and
you know looking for something uh you
know that's you know fairly stable and
you know mold prone uh or mold blue
proof I mean you know those are some of
my favorite characteristics of it yeah
for sure and that's that's one of the
things that we should probably mention
too is that so if you're really if
you're passionate about breeding and
you're trying to combine certain traits
I mean amongst us you know we might back
and forth uh a lot of different ideas
and get excited about a lot of random
stuff but there's also this thing in the
back of your mind and in which in order
to be a successful breeder uh people
will have to want to buy your stuff and
have success with it so a lot of these
practical traits uh like he was just
talking about
um great outdoor plant highly mold
resistant that type of thing those
things can be really important right
because you know people want like as
Caleb was mentioning earlier people want
buy a pack of seeds and that to be the
best growing best yielding greatest
structure crazy Terps you know super
potent they want all the beans to be
that way which is rare but then if even
if it had that but it molded like crazy
people would be pissed yeah yep you know
so if if you if there's problems
inherent in a line like high mold or
hermaphrodism or something else like
that you can better believe that people
are going to focus on that rather than
this is the most potent flavorful
fastest growing thing I've grown in
forever I found four bananas and a
couple of the big of the biggest colas
rotted and now I think it's a [ __ ] cross
you know it makes it difficult you know
uh because there's a certain amount of
commercial satisfaction that's required
right oftentimes it's the environment
that causes the problems
yeah that is very true you know or or
you know I can't I can't even imagine
I'm not a I'm not a public breeder uh
but both Matt and Caleb are the amount
of you know the amount of uh responses
they get of like hey these seeds didn't
pop right or they died a few days after
I cracked them or they turned out like
like [ __ ] and I blame you you know I
mean most of the time sometimes
sometimes it is you know uh of the scene
maker but a lot of times it's breed it's
it's user error uh I've never I've never
gotten any comments like that mine
everything's always perfect everything's
always perfect
you know and and we don't need to we
don't need to name names or anything
like that because that's not the point
of it but there was a super famous line
that was released a number of years ago
that was very expensive and very hyped
up and the people that made it didn't
even bother to do a germ test yeah and a
germ test for people that don't know is
if you're a breeder you take 50 or 100
or 200 of your seed and you pop them a
few times in paper towels or or in dirt
or whatever and you make sure that
there's nothing funky and they germinate
well yeah you know there's occasionally
crosses you make that don't germ well
and so there was there was a line that
was released that they didn't even do a
germ test on and then people bought
expensive seeds and then 70 of them
didn't even pop
and it was so consistent that it wasn't
really user error because when you start
getting just hundreds and hundreds of
complaints about the same issue yeah
um a germ test is something that takes
you know less than a week to really
figure out yeah
what do you what do you think causes the
you know poor germination rates like
that
you know you know the I mean Matt you
can speak to it if you want you know uh
what What's it called the the spermas
that's in the uh in the Shell might not
be developed properly so it wasn't
getting proper food it could be minor
cracks I mean sure there's all kinds of
[ __ ] reasons but some of it would
probably be what recessive genetics
people are calling it out in in the
comments because it was obvious what it
was it was candy rain and I'm not trying
to diss anyone but one of the things one
of the things that I was going to say is
that you can inbreed in cannabis uh more
so than you can in other things a little
bit
um but when you start inbreeding too
much and your and your hybrids are a
mishmash of the same four or five cuts
over and over and over again you will on
occasion start to get undesirable
recessives or undesirable traits that
pop up and one of those traits could be
like some mutant funky seeds uh
blueberry I mean yeah yeah but you know
Caleb can talk about it too but you know
because he does a lot of s1s and he's
even done some S2s but as you start
going to S3 S4 S5 things start getting
significantly more difficult the plants
start getting way weaker the germination
rates become a lot tougher so there's a
real limit there uh you know in in how
far you can inbreed before you start to
hit problems
um and I haven't inbred that deep but
but uh Caleb Caleb has a little bit more
than I have in terms of experimentation
so
um
you know uh yeah there's there's issues
with inbreeding you can combine
undesirable traits and have them become
a little bit more dominant even even in
S2s there's a lot of plants that will
not produce pollen
yeah they won't move forward when
reversed of course you know yeah
yeah
and so you know reversals reversals have
become sort of the norm uh it's flipped
in this in the 60s 70s 80s 90s and the
first decade of the 2000s uh the all
breeding for the most part uh was was
right what we call regular breeding
using males and females
um you know the only feminized breeding
that happened was typically accidental
uh you know hermaphrodism or something
along those lines bag seeds uh that type
of thing and uh you know and then the
revolution happened uh you know 13 12 13
years ago where the technology on how to
reverse cannabis became more well-known
and now I would say it's flipped and the
percentage of people that uses actual
males is extremely low
and the vast majority of the seed game
today is feminized in some way you know
um and it's a really it's a really
valuable tool but as both of uh my
co-hosts today can express uh you know
we were joking before we came on live is
that you know when I use traditional
males and a lot of my breeding I never
had a single breeding failure yeah um
where when you reverse things you can
have failure you can have not very much
pollen you can have sterile pollen you
can have the pollen sacks not open and
you have to go through a lot of manual
labor to extract using screens and stuff
the pollen from the pollen sacks
um you know in the old days you have one
male in a room you're guaranteed you're
gonna pollinate the entire room right in
today's world uh you know Caleb was just
chatting about it he might use 10 or 12.
uh females that are marked for reversal
yeah in the hopes that a few of them are
you know dump a lot and some a couple of
them dump some and a few dump a little
and then you've got a few failures
um and so it's it's uh it's pretty
difficult because it's not consistent
um you know people have great success
reversing a plant once and they do the
same thing again and for whatever reason
it doesn't work
yeah so uh the the you know we have a
lot of theories as to why uh is the mix
too strong or too weak is there a range
of of the mix that leads to you know
pollen dumping with some strains versus
others but it's mostly like
observational because we all don't have
labs to really analyze why the failure
went wrong yeah
um you know and uh you know it also
leads to you know in some cases uh you
know people get mad at hermaphrodism but
there's some plants that don't harm and
therefore they're a [ __ ] to reverse
[Music]
like I was telling you guys uh you know
just just a couple days ago I had to
chop down a a whole room at four weeks
flower because you know I reversed eight
you know nice big bushes of old Betsy
and none of them produced any pollen
whatsoever and the way I do things I I
don't really have a fallback a lot of
the times and so if it fails I just have
to chop a whole room down and start over
again and
that's just the price of doing business
but it old Betsy not reversing kind of
made me sad because she's one of my
favorite old girls you know so yeah and
you know there's some there's some lines
uh you know uh there's a lot of uh
there's a lot of people uh that have
tried to reverse various Diesel and sour
Cuts
they're notorious for not giving you
commercial viable amounts of pollen to
produce a bunch of candy miserable uh
people have been having really great
results with some of Caleb's TK crosses
yeah um but you know Caleb can speak to
this but I think he failed two or three
times three times
yep yeah three times and then when he
did even have success it was probably
like a fifth of the success that he
would normally have on a good reversal
yeah
um
you know so there's there's a lot of
that like there's a there's there's
failure a lot of a lot of breeding
failure used to be
you breed something and then the progeny
the children don't give you what you
were hoping for yeah but in feminized
breeding there's a lot of actual failure
to fertilize
right you know that goes on
even by extremely experienced people
that do it all the time and for a living
and have real good techniques down and
have done it a bunch and had a lot of
success
you you know I'd like to add too though
um that when breeding feminized
um you tend to have a better idea of in
in general kind of more consistent
better results with your feminized you
know progeny than like a normal a normal
breeding where you know you can observe
certain things about a male plant so you
really can't see what it's going to pass
forward whereas with the Femmes you you
know your girl on the left you know your
girl on the right you know it does tend
to kind of give you a a little bit
better of a idea of what you're gonna
get you know on that F1 hybrid you know
absolutely yeah
yeah and I mean so like if you were to
talk to breeders say that we've been
talking about you know in the last few
podcasts in the 80s and touch on the 90s
and stuff I think most of them would
tell you that the most important the
most important plants they had in their
rooms uh were the consistent males yeah
like once you've found a consistent male
back then you tended to cross it to
everything
because you were so stoked I mean a
recent example would be you know uh Matt
found a really good Blue Bonnet male
yeah and he was really happy with it and
he was really happy with the with the
traits that it passed on to the progeny
um and because males are so much harder
to find ones that pass the traits you
want
they tend to get used over and over
again it's really hard to move on
sometimes it gets really hard to move on
and so you know you have you can look at
some of these old seed banks like you
know Neville stuff or some stuff in the
90s and you know they have a they have a
handful of males
um really a handful and they use those
handful of males with everything right
right because you know failure you know
failure and means that like you get
something that the customer doesn't want
and that just ends up being a big zip
lock in your fridge
you know you know or you you test
something out and you feel like it's got
too many harms and it might affect your
reputation even though you think it's
good weed and you don't want to deal
with all the complaints out there and it
ends up being a big zip lock in your
fridge
you know maybe it'll be a project you
want to use later maybe it won't and so
you know uh one of the big aspects of
this that we want to chat about is that
you know the term breeder is used
Loosely uh and this isn't to diss anyone
but it encompasses basically anybody
that wants to cross and make seeds
and you know there's some people
um you know there's not very many of
them uh but both uh Caleb and Matt are
two of them that they are actually they
actually do what I consider to be
traditional breeding in the sense that
they take plants that they found from
previous breedings and they use them in
further work
right there's a lot there's a you know
and and everybody listening right now
you can have the power to affect
breeding right because the breeding game
right now is crossing a lot of hybrids
together and releasing them the public
with absolutely no work so a lot of
breeders are crossing famous things to
it to each other they're giving them a
sexy name and some good packaging and
they're releasing them and they're not
actually popping them themselves okay
and they're not doing any further work
which is fine but then what happens is
is that when you take somebody like like
you know Caleb who runs a bunch of his
own work
he gets to see what varieties in my
collection breed well and which ones
don't
which ones throw traits that I like and
which ones are all over the place and
crazy and that knowledge
informs the next steps you want to make
you know so for instance
um you know uh Caleb has a a plant uh
they call t-1000.
right uh which is uh you know it's it's
a named cut from uh from one of his
lines I believe it's Urkel and TK
correct yep triangle Kush times purple
Urkel triangle Kush times purple Urkle
and he you know it was found in in Hunts
of that line and you know I I saw on his
Instagram and he's told me and stuff you
know he's reversed that he's taken that
cut and he's used it in further work
that was one of my that was my one of my
buddy tiger Farm selection uh from you
know up there in Portland
sure yeah from my work yeah so it you
know sometimes sometimes it's stuff you
find in your own work sometimes it's
stuff your buddies find in your work
um but you know he Caleb liked that one
enough that he's now doing further work
within his own lines and so the most
effective and the cheapest and the most
profitable way to grow seeds right now
sadly is to make the cross give it a
name give it some cool packaging and
sell it and never do any further work
yourself
uh that's a pretty profitable path the
other path which is you test and you
grow rooms full of your own stuff and
you try to look for traits amongst that
stuff that you want to keep working with
um that's a lot more sustainable
breeding because it gives you the
ability to you know do multi-stage
breeding which is real what real
breeding is really but it's time
consuming and it's costly and it takes a
while and you've actually done indoors
yeah and you have to have a goal in mind
right you know
um and in that regard and so you know I
don't know if he's I don't know I don't
know if you're are you selling you're
probably selling the T-1000 hybrids now
aren't you oh yeah oh yeah you made them
a while ago you know yeah and so you
know he's got you know how many breeders
out there are doing two or three or four
step processes yeah not a lot
you look at dog breeders or you look at
fish breeders or you look at corn or
anything else and you know the idea that
you just make hybrids and sell them and
never
try to like advance in any way is not
normal in breeding
most breeding has goals
yeah some of my favorite projects you
know that I'm working on now
um are the S2 projects where you know
I've you know grown out a hundred plus
you know plants of you know at my s1s
and made selections from those and now
I'm doing S2s
um I'm doing back crosses to the moms
I'm making hybrids between you know S2s
of the various you know
um you know s1s like you know taking the
Urkel S1 cross it to the you know
triangle kush or chemdog S1 and you know
kind of making new versions of those
same hybrids that I did with the
original Parent Cuts but you know
they're going to be unique and hopefully
a lot more you know stable in uniform
you know versus the previous generation
yeah there's a lot of work you know
going into all that yeah no [ __ ] and so
we could you know maybe one thing we
could talk about and these are these are
also observations from Caleb but he's
run out a bunch of
um you know uh chem 91 s1s and you know
we all think that it it already is an S1
and what leads us to think that is the
lack of ver of variability in the line
right it passes potency it passes looks
that look very similar to it or there's
a small range in there and so you kind
of you kind of get what you get with
that right but then he's also done a
thing and I got to go up and see it
where he's reversed you know Mendo p and
he's grown out a bunch of Mendo PS ones
and uh that has so much diversity in it
that you know he's made comments to me
in the past where you could give out
seeds s1s of Mendo perps to various
different people and they could make
their own selections and the lines would
be extremely different from one another
there's so much variation in there
um you know you know and then
maybe we should make a comment about s1s
because there's so many clone only
Elites and there's not
um there's not lines available of many
of these things anymore most of the
stuff that we hold uh in our collections
you only have one cutting of that line
you don't have any sisters of it and you
don't have any boys of it you don't have
any way to look within the line and so
one of the benefits
um of doing s1s with that kind of thing
is it's really the only way to look
within the genetic without another
genetics you know genes coming in there
and altering it right so
um you know so that's why we didn't know
how narrow the chem 91's gene pool was
until he s-wund it and grew out a few
hundred of them and we saw that it was
narrow you don't know how wide Mendo
purple was until you did that and grew
out a bunch of them and you were like oh
my God there's a lot of different stuff
in here yeah and so s1s s1s give people
selfing gives people an ability to look
through a line when they only have one
example one female example of the line
itself
right yeah and so it's one of the ways
that modern breeders get to save and
preserve old lines like a lot of famous
stuff that Caleb has run recently like
Mendo purple or snow or Trinity or chem
91 or you know Urkel or you go down the
list and if you don't S1 it it's really
hard to see what's in it by itself you
can outcross it to other things and you
can see what traits that are dominant
that pass to the children and out
process but if you really want to look
within a line most seed lines today you
know most clone only is are that they're
clone only
that's all you get so and so a lot
I'm sorry to interrupt a lot of these
steps for it you know Consulting you
know they're they're all cuts that are
you know as you well know you know Mendo
purpose is over you know you sprouted
that seed over 20 years ago you know and
a lot of these cuts are 30 40 years old
so if we don't you know stash away some
S1 seed in that fridge you know before
it's too late before those cuts you know
disappear
uh yeah we'll lose those genetics
on that tangent are you gonna do redo
the the old Betsy are we gonna make
another attempt at it I want to see real
old bull rider stock pulled out of those
s1s my my problem is is I don't I have I
only have rooms that are three four and
six so you know
um it's hard doing some of these
I I wish I had like some single light
rooms to do these things right yeah yeah
because then it wouldn't be so much of
an expense too
you know yeah yeah every time every time
it fails yeah for sure and that might be
that might be something good to talk
about is that it's pretty amazing how
much cool stuff we have to work with
these days considering like most most
normal breeders from other walks of life
would laugh at The Limited selection
pool we pull from uh how many plants how
many plants we get to run to make the
Next Generation selections
um you know uh prohibition and things
like that have made a lot of breeding
happen especially in America inside so
inside means you have electricity you
have a lot of lights you have the cost
money it's time all this different stuff
and so most breeders have a million
ideas in their head the ones that are
passionate about it and their ability to
realize those ideas is quite Limited
you know uh you might have a fridge full
of of ideas and passion projects and
whatever but right almost breeders you
know you have to sell enough stuff while
you're doing your passion to fund the
passion part right right right so for
instance you know when I was doing a lot
of breeding in the late 90s and early
2000s
it was a terrible financial decision uh
because I wasn't selling any seed I was
just giving it away to friends and it
was just for my personal and back then
cannabis was super expensive
well at least other people made money
off your [ __ ] yeah well but whatever but
that's fine but it's just a matter of
it's just a matter of like most people
back then weren't willing to take a four
lighter when you could get you know when
weed was 4 500 a pound or something yeah
and instead of getting six or eight
pounds of sellable cannabis out of that
four lighter to get thousands of seeds
that you you know uh you know didn't
even have an outlet for you know and
that's another thing that we should talk
about too for a second is the fact that
most seed breeding in America did not
have an American Outlet to be able to
get it to the public
right so there was a lot of private
breeding going on and there was a lot of
like you know there was some passion
going on and different things like that
but the Public's asked access to it was
Tiny yeah in the 90s and in the early
2000s which is when I did most of my
stuff
I don't think there was American small
American seed companies that were
getting it out you would you would have
to make them here send them over to
Europe and then they would have to send
them back to here
there was companies that's why like
certain Americans partnered with
Europeans dude worst decisions I ever
made in my life over there you know lots
of American breeders think that way you
know uh I mean for instance in the 90s
um you know uh the blueberry stuff DJ
Short you know he partnered with sag
Martha first and then Dutch Passion uh
doesn't sound like he was very pleased
with either one of those things but
um you know it uh it at least allowed if
you didn't partner with somebody in
Europe
nobody had access to your stuff the
forums changed it a little bit because
it at least allowed private DMS and some
and some low-level trading and stuff but
even like yeah even Matt back in the day
I mean you know you you would have a web
address that had the Netherlands you
know I'll comment on that real quick
back in the day I get this question all
the time the only reason that I have a
DOT NL address it wasn't because I was
going to get more traffic because of it
obviously nobody types anything.nl if
you live in the US but back then it was
just a just one more step to keep people
from looking at me in the U.S and and
nowadays it's irrelevant so it's funny
when people still Americans use dot NL
because they think it's some kind of
special thing but but really you know
the the IG era and you know the Forum
the forums a little bit and then
Instagram and then loosening laws and
stuff it allowed a lot of very small
time private breeders to be able to uh
to get out there you know um and there
was some people back in the day 20 years
ago uh when you know when Caleb and Shaw
and some others and I first met
um at some Harvest parties and such you
know the people that were internet
famous back then were like Vic high and
uh DJ Short and you know the uh the you
know The Brothers Grimm and the c99 work
um and they well they got famous because
there was there was such a there was
such a limited pool
right it was like it you know there was
some there was a few Canadians
um there was a few Americans it got
famous on the forums but there wasn't
now it's like anybody can you know can
breed seeds in their closet or a bedroom
or something and they can have an IG
handle and they can get their work out
there and they can spread their work to
friends and they can so test grows and
people can see pictures and so now it's
become it's become a lot more common
but 20 years ago
um you know uh the vast majority of
breeders I knew in Mendo and Humboldt
and stuff were private you know unless
you met them you had no way of getting
access to any of it like zero you know
if you were in North Carolina or
Illinois or Colorado or something like
that like you weren't going to meet the
people in the Triangle or the people in
Santa Cruz or the people wherever
um and so I you know the combination of
reversals and the combination of you
know Instagram and some other forms of
communication really exploded the small
seed breeder yeah in a way that never
happened before
and I don't know I don't even know that
you know people would even know who CSI
or Riot would be without those two
innovations they still don't know who
Riot is but it's all right
um you know we're about let's see four
uh 50 minutes in so if you want to start
doing some questions that are uh uh you
know if you want to start answering any
Caleb we could do that or if you want to
talk anymore on the breeding topic we
could do that I'm okay with whatever
all right well I can tell you dude that
uh uh questions for you predominate the
questions this week so I'll try to do
every week
um to be honest yeah even even the weeks
that you're not here uh there's a bunch
of stuff that people want to for us to
ask because they know you
um so maybe uh you know let's see let's
talk about
um
here's a basic one what was your very
first cut
and what what what is one of the cuts
that you could say you hold closest to
your heart amongst your current
collection
well my very first cut
um was a Northern Lights from my dad and
uh he he gave he gave me that cut in in
uh in 94.
um
and I had that one all the way up until
I think 2002 and then stupidly lost it
um
but uh the the closest thing to that
anymore is like chem number chem dog
number four you know yeah that stuff is
very similar to the old Northern Lights
I got from my dad
um
as far as favorites go I I always talk
about it you know just just in case
anybody has ever come across it but you
know my dad also gave me uh around the
same ERA this Uriah cut and I mean that
one is still one of my favorites and I
think it might be possible to recreate
something like it with like say a pine
tar Kush a bit of OG Kush and maybe
something super super just Piney lemony
blah blah blah even more so than OG yeah
I don't know but uh as far as what I
have
uh still I mean I love uh you know the
purple Indica that you know my good
buddy Fletch you know got in the early
2000s and I'm pretty sure that cut dates
back to the 80s
um yeah you know up there up there in
Portland and Washington and all that
um but that one's that one's extremely
unique but then again uh you know you
already know I'm a fan of the purple so
I absolutely you know love francis's
Mendo purple I mean not those
um
and then uh you know uh you know I've
I've had Urkel for damn near 20 years
now and you know she she's she's a tried
and true favorite so if I lost any of
those three I'd be a little bit upset
yeah I'll take the next one because it's
super simple uh can you please confirm
the timeline for super skunk
uh I can it's real that one's really
easy
um it was released by Neville in the
final year that he owned the seed bank
outright uh so super skunk was released
to the public in the 1990 the seed bank
catalog uh he took a maple leaf Indica
uh which is supposedly called uh Afghan
T and he crossed that to one of uh Sam
skunk man's skunk lines and he said that
put the funk back in the skunk
um and it became a it had a it had a
great name it had a great look uh it
became super popular in the 90s
um so super skunk was uh when people
talk about oh I had you know mid 80s
Super Skunk or whatever I'm not saying
that there wasn't skunk Aromas out there
but the actual Super Skunk name came
about in the 1990 uh uh seed bank
catalog uh this one is for Caleb it's a
pretty good question uh do you feel that
males have a place in modern cannabis
breeding or a reversals the future and
why
oh I absolutely do
um I'm I've never been one of those
types to rule out anything so I think
there's a place for feminized seeds and
you know feminized breeding and I think
there's just a value as valuable a place
for regular breeding
um so absolutely I mean you know I I
started out doing just as much regular
work as feminized work I just didn't
really capitalize on selling you know
much of the regular work because it kind
of just took an aside because you got to
select out all those damn mails yeah
right yeah
um the next question I'm actually not
going to have Caleb answer I'm just
going to make a joke about it and it's
nothing against it's a great question
but could Caleb please talk about
interesting things he learned from any
or every line he selfed so you're gonna
have to wait for Caleb's 10 10 volume uh
Opus on every line he self because uh
he's constantly uh selfing things over
the last 10 years or so and that's such
a that's a that's uh we could just talk
for hours
um there's just dozens of cuts that he's
done that to at this point so it's a
little too wide it is a good question
but boy it really is a novel
um I will say I will say I take uh
pictures
um and you know they help with mental
notes on more or less every single S1 I
grow so I'm I think I'm headed up to
about 2 million pictures strong as far
as you know the the S1 S1 pictures are
going
I'll ask this one again because it got a
lot of votes are you gonna try or
continue to try to reverse the Irene
Kush
um
I don't know I mean yeah when you get
when you get 20 s1cs from half a half of
a light
yeah
that's a little
and and also I don't know if people know
but
um the the Irene you know for half a
thousand watt light produced 20 seeds
but the the the triangle push uh that
got the side pollination from that in
the bed next to it produced like 750
seeds so the pollen was viable it just
didn't pollinate itself
yeah very interesting yeah so and that's
an interesting statement too and that
um even when people get viable pollen uh
there's some cuts out there's some cuts
out there the Mac would be one
um there's some others that Matt could
talk about that you have a viable pollen
and it pollinates everything around it
just fine and it doesn't pollinate that
female plant very well at all there's
several plants that have very few
pistols on them and the pistols don't
seem to be doing a very good job of
transferring that that pollen grain to
um where it needs to go to fertilize the
egg and create a seed so there's some
interesting stuff in that uh this is
another really good question for Caleb
and I think uh it's pretty valuable I'm
interested to hear inspectus speak on
growing large populations in relatively
small spaces
um I mean ideally I like to do
no more than 36 plants per light when
I'm growing large populations of like
feminized seeds out
and you know I'll do that in a four to
six K room so you know I'm doing 100 to
200 plants generally
um
it just it just gives you a better
better idea of you know what's in that
genetic pool
um I have done like single light you
know rooms where I pack in like 80
plants you know under the one light and
I flour them out you know at you know
four or six inches tall whatever
and uh I mean you know
for for anybody limited on space I mean
that's an excellent way to go I mean
especially if you're doing them in like
small six inch pots where you know you
can make selections out of that larger
pool you know and uh then you can pull
them out and you know
um you know re-vege them and you know
actually have you know have fairly
heavily selected stock to work with so
you know you don't have to grow your
plants out in a five gallon pot or 10
gallon pot or whatever you don't have to
grow big to know what you want you know
yeah I mean if you're looking for
potency uh smell flavor
um you know any of the the really main
criteria you don't need just big plants
I mean if you're expecting them for
structure or hemp maybe you need a
little more room right
yeah so I'll add to that I'll add to
that as well uh Caleb has a little bit
different style than I do and and that
he grows uh small seed plants like that
fairly tightly packed together and just
so people know when he's talking about
doing 36 plants a light
um that generally it's it's on like a a
SL you know one of those uh old tables
like a four and a half by four and a
half kind of area so it's kind of a six
it's kind of a six wide you know six
deep type of scenario there
um if you're I used to do it slightly
differently than that
um I would I would grow out a bunch of
seed I would take cuttings from that
seed uh as soon as multiple cuttings had
rooted I would ditch the seed itself
because I found when you were growing
regular stuff the seed energy I didn't
want to know what it did as a seed I
wanted to know what it did as a clone
because sometimes that can be different
and I wanted to see its growth structure
as a clone
um and what do you mentioned is is that
when you grow up things too big and you
flower them and all of a sudden you get
10 or 12 pounds or something and you
have a lot of boof uh or at or average
not every not everything is is a home
run you know even among lines that
produce great plants there's still a lot
of you know and so then you end up with
a lot of ants so what I would do is
somewhat similar to him in that I would
throw away the seed plant and then I
would pack tables with you know four to
six inch tall cuts and I would flower
the cut because as Caleb just mentioned
if I got a half ounce or three quarters
of an ounce or an ounce off a plant and
I got to see what the cola looked like
there that's all I needed you know yeah
you know and and you you would get
enough of the Terps you'd get enough of
the smell you could you know if you have
a quarter seven to ten grams to smoke
that'll give you enough indication that
you need to
um that you can go back and grow some of
those selections uh in a larger in a
larger scenario grow more of them grow
them bigger see there see their um
because that way if you get a bunch of
bunk it's only 5 to 14 grams a bunk per
per plant you know and you get enough
and that's what you need to start doing
in order to really run through numbers
uh in that regard and and have it only
take up so much space the other issue
that happens and you know I have a
different method than Caleb but it's a
universal problem is when you start
growing out large numbers to test and
you don't want to lose something you end
up needing to keep backups
of the things you're flowering so you
don't lose them yeah right there's
basically two methods you can either
keep backups which is time consuming and
takes up a bunch of space in your veg or
you can start pulling if you grow in
pots you could start pulling out small
pots of things that you think are
amazing when they're only part of the
way through flowering and then revert
that's kind of a European method and
kind of and start reverting them back to
veg
um you know uh but you know it's you
know it's a real issue
um because you know it's happened to
Caleb talks to me about it all the time
is that you know uh you know I grew a
room of 240 plants and my two and my
three favorites two of the cuttings
didn't make it by the time I realized it
was my favorite yeah
you know and so trying to save copies
that you can go back and actually deal
with and the space involved is a real
pain in the ass
for lack of a better way to put it uh it
takes up you know you want to do a big
hunt and you want to keep that thing
around that means you got a big bench
with not so on uh taking cuts off of the
seed plants and growing the the cut the
cuttings versus the seed plants because
seed plants will never give you an
accurate representation of what that
clone is going to become past the seed
stage so there's really I fully agree
there's no reason to grow the seed
plants themselves when you're just
selecting for future you know you know
clone stock that's that's going to give
you the best yeah ones don't have a Tap
Root you grow a bunch of seeds they can
be taller they can be lankier they can
have some more life energy in different
ways in them than the Clone and since
you only get one shot at the seed that's
why a lot of people like back in the day
would want to grow seed outdoor because
the Vigor contained within a seed plant
would give you could give you a larger
plant uh a bigger plant than a clone um
there's some famous clones my Maui cut
does it the blue dream does it uh Green
Crack does it there's some famous clones
that despite being clones will give you
huge plants outside yeah but if you went
back to the 215 era five or six years
ago a lot of the big giant Gardens you
would see on Instagram uh in terms of
outdoor were all seat
right but you got an eight or nine foot
tall room with you know thousand watt
lights or something and all of a sudden
you got some seed energy and the thing
wants to be seven feet tall and you're
doing bending and trellising and and
corriddling of the plant and it's a huge
pain in the ass you know
so you know that's the you know Caleb
actually has a had a pretty good method
of taking clones off of plants when
they're a couple weeks into bloom
um which a lot of people wouldn't do
um but in that regard it it the plants
kind of freak out for a while because
they're into flower but that's actually
a benefit because one of the things
you're trying to do when you're keeping
clones in a different room for veg is
you want to keep them kind of small
until you figure out which ones are
worth it
you might have 180 clones and like you
only care about six of them
right yeah you don't know which six
so the end when they're in flower it
takes uh you know a good month maybe
even six weeks or so before they start
vegging out of it so you buy yourself
some time keeping them in those Flats
we actually just took uh uh 12 Flats of
clones this week of TK ABC F3 so yippy
skippy to that [ __ ] yeah the other thing
I should mention just because Caleb has
told me about it a bunch is that
when you start judging plants on growth
and structure and weight and Frost and
all that those are good things to judge
on but a lot of the times he finds out
his favorites end up being some shitty
ass runt that wasn't very impressive
didn't look very good he wasn't very
happy with it never thought much of it
and then you know him and his crew end
up testing it which is actually the the
part that matters at the end and they're
like oh man this is special
but you never would have thought it was
special growing because it just looked
like a it just looked like a runt it
looked like it was odd it had funkiness
to it it didn't have the greatest bud
structure and then of course that's
going to be like the tastiest one with
the best time and I'm a huge fan of runs
the screen
in general you know I would say too that
we could mention this because because
you know he laughed about it but really
if you look at like Caleb's work with
freak Show or you look at the ABC or you
look at uh you know runts and things
like that like what he's really talking
about is like he's a huge fan of
outliers
he's a huge fan of things that are
abnormal things that pop up in a
population that might be rare things
that you know might not be that common
but then it popped up and you're like oh
look at that little thing you know what
direction could I take that and
strangely you know we should mention
this too is that
so I'll I'll stretch it out a little bit
but if you go into the store any
vegetable you buy in the store whether
it's a tomato or a zucchini or whatever
else
that thing has been picked
to grow because it yields well like for
instance let's take a tomato right the
most important thing for a tomato for
tomato Growers is weight color does the
skin break does it rot in transit you
know all these things can you stack it
in transit does it bruise easily all
these factors are huge taste and flavor
and texture are way down on the list
right so the whole reason why heirloom
tomatoes made a comeback is because
these things actually taste good where
when people were growing things for
production okay
um
zucchini anything you name it they're
grown because the producer it it grows
well for them right it produces a lot
for the space cannabis is pretty unique
in that
the stuff that becomes really popular
became really popular because consumers
enjoyed it
no one would ever in a million years
pick any kind of OG Kush as a production
plant
viney small buds doesn't hold itself up
a pain in the ass to grow a weak root
system all those things would prevent
you from ever seeing it in most normal
agriculture because they would eliminate
it because it didn't have the qualities
needed to be put to scale right people
would want every you'd get blue dream
right because it's a fast-growing
vigorous thing that yields a ton doesn't
take that long and so cannabis is a bit
unique in that even like something like
sour diesel uh Sour Diesel is kind of
tricky to grow well a lot of people find
it finicky if you have too many Bud
sites on Sour Diesel it'll give you a
lot of feathery almost wheat right
um you know there's a lot that goes on
with that so there's a lot of very
famous strains that have really really
crappy production traits right
you know all kinds of things you know um
you know and so you know so there's the
you know Matt way earlier in the thing
was talking about root structure which
is not a very bred for trait
um there's certain plants that you grow
in the same room that some plants drink
like crazy and I'll use OG Kush as an
example a lot of OG cushes have
typically weak root systems
they don't grow vigorous root systems so
as a result they can only drink so fast
so as a result they only grow so fast
so you know that's a consideration too
is that cannabis has been I mean I'll
tell you guys a funny story really quick
when Skittles first came out uh Skittles
is notorious for growing slow
right uh Caleb and I had had a mutual
friend that made an IG post where he was
like you know in in October he's like
I'm vegging these Skittles for my next
year's light depth hopefully there'll be
three hopefully they'll be three feet
tall in six months right where Skittles
might be like winning awards for its
Terps and winning awards for its
extracts and everything else but try to
get the thing higher than four feet tall
outside yeah it's a slow growing bushy
little hedge of a plant and so my point
to that is that most of the famous
strains that people like either for
their terp profile or their High
wouldn't make the cut in normal
agriculture because they don't have the
growth traits yeah and it's really
really difficult because that's what I
was that's what made me think of it when
I was joking about Caleb's love for runs
is that a lot of times the the freak the
mutant the one that grew short the one
that was a pain in the ass to grow that
one's the one that tastes amazing
that's the one that will get people
excited right and the one that was like
five feet tall and threw huge colas all
over it and grew like a champ and barely
required any work that one ends up being
a little bit more boring
right and you're like man I wish I could
merge those two I'm sure you can talk
about that for a minute Caleb I I swear
the biggest biggest girls at least
biggest feminized girls I grow they
always seem to have a little persuasion
to hang in the balls
I don't know if you've noticed that but
the big girls yeah I wouldn't say that
about me all the time
I got a question for both of you that
that I'll follow up with on after after
I ask you guys so Hayes brothers and me
and Caleb actually talked about this
yesterday and I think me and me and not
so talked about it a few days ago uh I
know crybaby was a part of that Hayes
Brothers vintage California Kush 1980s
picture in High Times in the 79 issue
they talk of a new hybrid known as
c-u-s-h Kush uh in NorCal a cross
between Hawaiian hash plant and Thai
specifically calling it cush by 79 they
already knew of Hindu so what the [ __ ]
is this Cali Kush is it pure kush the
picture does look like the Malibu in the
article they straight up say Afghani
skunk weed it's been driving me crazy
for 10 years
Caleb anything
I don't know well
I can make a couple General comments so
cush is a general term right
um there's a huge mountain range it's
the second tallest mountain range in the
world next to the Himalayas and it runs
through Afghanistan and Pakistan down to
the ocean and it's called the Hindu Kush
so uh you know we talked in a previous
podcast about how names are relatively
new and back in the day people talked
about people named things uh per their
region of origin right oaxacan Michoacan
Panamanian Hawaiian you know various
various aspects like that they rarely
had names that weren't Regional so Kush
could literally be anything collected
from the Hindu Kush Mountains and the
Hindu Kush mountains could be as low as
one or two thousand feet above sea level
and as high as five six seven eight
thousand uh above sea level and some of
these big valleys so
you know and then secondly to that and
what peop what he's probably really
asking is that
there are there are a few plants
um that popped up and became famous uh
everybody mostly knows the story but if
they don't
um there's a there's a Bubba Kush line
um and there's a cush line that has
various origin stories but
um is most likely a mix of Northern
Californian and European genetics that
popped up in Florida came to La became a
craze people got extreme amounts of
money for it and then it became very
popular and so what most people today
know is cush you could classify as TK or
ghost or that's what most people know
because that's what became popular
that's what's been traded on forums and
traded on IG and everybody else and
bought in clubs and so that's what most
people today know know of as Kush
but that's a lot narrower of a gene pool
than [ __ ] that came from the Hindu Kush
yeah well right so you go all the way
back to Hindu you go back all the way
back to 1979 and you have Matt and I
might do a short about this soon about
the hippie hashish Trail but
you have some you have some Euros or you
have some Americans come back from India
Nepal Kashmir
um you know uh Pakistan or Afghanistan
and they bring seeds back to their buddy
and they're from Kush
so
what what date was was that article from
again 79 79 issued they talked of a new
hybrid known as Kush
okay well you know remember I was
telling you how
um they were hating on humble that back
back in the 70s I think it was I think
it was kind of that same issue they were
all bitter you know that Humboldt's all
popular because they're indicas or their
cushes right yeah and you know they they
were upset that their hazes you know
were getting downplayed
well you know like we've talked plenty
of times back in 78 you know that was
that was roughly the year that pretty
much it seems like everybody around
Humboldt you know
um Trinity all that
have you know we're growing uh Purple
Kush there was a huge influx you know of
of Purple Kush seed you know and
obviously just like um not so I was
talking about that's that's just Hindu
Kush seed and the purple is of course
the the purple Fino
or purple genotype of that so yeah I'm
I'm almost wondering if they didn't just
get a hold of some of some of that seed
and incorporate it into their hazes to
kind of you know up up their market
value
yeah it's very possible
and one thing I could add to that is
that in modern breeding today
um that same thing holds true which is a
cut becomes famous and everybody breeds
that cut into everything right right
right so in the last 15 years
um the amount of people that have used
cherry pie Girl Scout cookies
five or eight different Kush Cuts
Skittles you so you name it if it became
famous and desirable people would blend
it into everything and so one of the
things you know you see people out there
that are like pumping up their various
hybrids and you know some of the stuff
you see Caleb do that people might be
like oh why the hell is he working with
ABC that looks weird oh that's funky
freak show is [ __ ] up too why the [ __ ]
you messing around with that I don't get
it some of it is like honestly with the
amount of work that's been done with
cherry pie and cookies and Kush
what new and exciting do you think is
going to pop out of that that someone
hasn't already done in the last 10 years
yeah and if you take two hybrids that
are mostly a mishmash of those things
all smashed up together I'm not dissing
Crossing cushmans with this but what are
you going to find that's not something
that's already somewhat similar to a lot
that's out there it's very hard to find
novel and new and okay so people people
have been ever ever since the name game
came around and ever since popularity
came around like Caleb was just
mentioning people might be Crossing
these Afghans to their hazes to increase
its popularity right
people have been doing that for the last
forever but it's increased dramatically
in the last 20 years where it's like you
know uh there was uh I mean this is a
funny example but there's no cush in
blackberry kush
right in the sense that cush for the
most part like the reason why people
added Kush to blackberry kush was
because people wanted to buy Kush
you know sour gets added to a lot of
names or diesel gets added to a lot of
names or names get changed because
there's a desire to sell
certain things and then the desire to
feed that market either makes a lot of
breeding happen around a few Select Cuts
and you're trying to get a hybrid that
you can call
you know um there's a famous there's a
there's a good cut up here called doxog
and I would say that it's it's not the
greatest guide it doesn't have very much
uh OG flavor it doesn't have very much
in the way of uh you know the the the
high that I like but it looks like a
traditional Kush
um and it yields like crazy and so then
people are gonna grow it because it
produces well and they can call it cush
oh I'm looking for Kush oh well I have a
ton of kush here buy this Doc's cush
right and that's for rare maintenance
yeah I think yeah and so I you know and
I'm not even trying to diss them or
anything like that that's not the point
the point is that is that you know these
names get added onto things because as
long as it's desirable and easy to buy
for instance
um you know uh Caleb has become pretty
famous with his Urkel crosses
in
04050607 I would say that you know
eventually there was probably literally
thousands of growers in Mendo and humble
that had lavender Urkel Grape Ape uh you
know you name it half a dozen of these
different cuts to meet the purple craze
and then is the purple craze phased into
the sour craze and the Kush craze and
the cookie craze and the Skittles craze
it ends up like there's like six dudes
that held on to the the Urkel yeah right
but 15 years ago how many people did you
know in Humboldt that had some kind of
Urkle
right a lot everybody because it was
everybody because it was popular and a
lot of buyers wanted it which means lots
of people that produced had it and as
soon as the market shifted so did the
holding of the cut
and before that before that it was
Salmon Creek big bud and train wreck and
snow and stuff like that yeah sure and
so that's a thing right is that what
happens is and this is sort of the thing
is that when things are popular
everybody has it and everybody wants it
and people want it from their friend and
as soon as it becomes unpopular the
percentage of people that are willing to
hold on to Old cuts when there's no
Financial value to it because it's tiny
right and you know uh then you have a
bunch of people you know now we have a
bunch of stuff going on in the community
where most people there's legendary
strains that very few people to relative
to today have actually seen or smoked
and so fakes proliferate
um because they get passed around and
maybe the person passing it around
doesn't even realize it's a fake because
he never had it in 1998 so he doesn't
know right you know and so he's passing
it around he's like oh I think I have
real snow
I'm gonna trade you this but he doesn't
know I thought that was real soon I
thought that was real snow it was given
to me by my buddy who's had it for
forever and he swears it's real snow and
then you talk to somebody like me or
Caleb or whoever who actually grew snow
back then or you know someone who or
kale who's held it for a long time and
they're like I'm sorry
but that's not it
yeah that was a snow was a bad example
I've never seen a fake cut of snow
been a bad example but like maybe maybe
the Trinity would be
would be an excellent example yeah that
might be an act because people will get
mad at me because they would give me
their Trinity and they'd be like oh man
I gave up the farm for this cut right
and then I'd smoke it and I'd be like
it's not even a hybrid of it it's it's
not it like what do you mean I I like I
you don't know what I did to get it and
I'm like dude I'm sorry it's it's not it
you know and and so there's so there's
some Cuts where it's like I mean one of
the things I have no idea what sour cut
I hold
um but if I lost it I've collected six
or seven or eight different sour Cuts in
the last four or five years and none of
them are the are the cut that I have
yeah which means that like if I lost it
me trying to find it again would be
would be would be shitty it'd be hard
right and so that that's what happens to
a lot of old cuts and then you get
arguments about whether it's real or
whether it's not real
um and there's a group of collectors uh
you know there's three of them on this
call right now but there's not that many
people that are willing to hold on I
have a joke of give me your old and
unpopular
yeah right because you know having a big
mom room is a huge pain in the ass
it's a lot of money it's a lot of time
it's a lot of cloning it's a lot of
trying to keep plants healthy and bug
free it's a lot of and then you know 98
of it isn't commercially viable
they're holding on to it for
preservation you're holding on to it for
maybe some future breeding you're
holding on to it because most of the
stuff that I hold I hold it because I
personally like it
that's the determining factor I don't
care what the public thinks but most
people you know it's they don't have the
time they don't have the space they
don't have the will uh or they just want
to hold what's currently popular because
that's what works for them and they
think this is this is how everything
gets lost right I can always get it back
from my buddy he's got it
that's I wanted to chime in real quick
yep before we get way too far from the
question of the California Kush so
um I was actually given the seats that's
way far from that yeah way far I
apologize to whoever's question it was
we got real far afield there for a
minute that's what we do
um that's what you do when you're a
[ __ ] nerd you nerd out but uh yeah no
I was given seeds by a guy that was on
the forum's name Walking Man a lot of
people that around back in the day knew
him
um I I sat on these seats for a long
time and they were labeled Hayes
Brothers California Kush and the reason
I sat on them because I was like what
the [ __ ] is it
California Ace Brothers they're [ __ ]
Haze you know so I sat on them for a
long time until I came across a High
Times issue that I have and I was going
through it and I see Hayes Brothers
California Kush and I'm like what the it
you know and by this time walking hands
uh or walking dude's dead you know so
I'm trying to figure out you know what
are in these things so I did pop them I
did run them and I would say the closest
thing they look to is what I would
associate having grown with Hindu Kush
before
um they're stretchier they're not like
OG the buds the buds are dense they're
smaller more golf ball more spread out
it's stretchier that is where the OG
connection probably ends with the
California Kush that I have grown now
are they the original ones from the
Hayes brothers who knows that's what
they were labeled but we did fgn those
and let them out just in case
uh-huh
there you go I want some
yeah you now you need to grow them so
you can answer the question not
oh all right
oh my gosh
so uh we have a question that's pretty
funny is uh Caleb why when are you gonna
come back and why did you make everyone
wait so long to come on
[Laughter]
oh man I'll answer that one for him is
uh he's real busy you know uh he's got a
lot of stuff going on part of being
really a prolific breeder is that that's
a lot of work uh it's a lot of work to
make seeds it's a lot of work to run
rooms and have things come down and
catalog and
what do you mention the 20 million
pictures that he has on file and answer
and answer be responsive probably on his
website and deal with his life and
family stuff and eat oh I haven't
responded on the website for about three
months apologies to everybody
so it gets it gets difficult especially
if you're a one-man show and you're and
you're holding on and you're trying to
do a lot of actual work and you're
trying to have a life and friendships
and families and different things like
that we're really appreciative that he
gave us some time uh he's like one of
our really close friends and we chat
like this all the time about things
um you know and uh one of one of the one
of the aspects that Matt and I are
trying to do is that some of the most
knowledgeable people
are not great at self-promotion
um you know and there's a lot of people
who are really good at self-promotion
and not that much great at everything
else uh Caleb's kind of the reverse uh
he's really really good at observation
and breeding and he has a long history
of plants and he's definitely a weed
nerd and has a lot of knowledge in there
um but you know public speaking and
making the time for this kind of thing
can be relatively hard uh you know so
um you know we're super appreciative
that he came on and we're hoping that
we'll be able to occasionally get him to
pop back in so I would say you know uh
be thankful he's here and let's hope
that he liked it and uh we'll get some
other subjects that interest them enough
that he'll pop back on you know I really
want to do a show with Fletcher and
Caleb together I think that would be
pretty phenomenal
really
maybe some Bodhi
yeah you know I mean there's uh you know
both those guys uh both those guys are
on the same vein you know they're both
really knowledgeable they both have a
lot of passion for what they do they
both have a lot of projects they both do
a lot of hunting
um you know uh Bodhi would be quite
interesting because you know he's done a
lot of traveling uh which is not common
in the modern in the modern times
um you know he's gone to a lot of these
regions of origin and poked around uh
and so those are probably some like
really cool stories that he's got in his
head he is helping us on the hippie hash
Trail
um episode we haven't really talked
about it much but we will be doing that
and Bo's gonna be a major part of that
so yeah we're Clippers uh we haven't met
we haven't we haven't talked about that
but one of our episode ideas is to sort
of talk about the hippie hashish Trail
because that's the way that the vast
majority of Afghan seeds actually made
their way to America
um I talked about in a previous episode
how all the sativas
free seeds came with every kilo of Bud
that came to America but yeah Afghans
they had hash and hash didn't contain
seeds generally speaking on rare
occasions it did but for the most part
no and so we talked about it a little
earlier uh but you know
um in Humboldt where Caleb is from you
know and Mendo and stuff like that in
the Central Coast of California it seems
like there was Afghans in the early and
mid 70s but the wave where most Growers
that were tied into people really
started seeing them was more 77 78 79
80. that's when the waves of Afghan
seeds really started hitting America and
and hitting groups of Growers and
getting passed around
um and I believe that's mostly due to
the hippie hashish Trail and people's
travels to the Far East and so there's a
lot of interest I think in talking about
that uh and we're gonna have an episode
upcoming uh that goes way more into
depth on some of that hashish and some
of the traditions and some of the
travels and how that all worked and even
just I mean just how difficult it was to
even get over there uh and and trip
around uh it wasn't in the 60s and 70s
it was not easy uh to get to that part
of the world
uh and to move around it's far it's you
know different issues today so yeah far
more dangerous a lot more dangerous yeah
we've um sadly America's been at war in
that part of the region for quite some
time so people's opinions of us have
changed a bit and it's certainly a
little sketchier uh with the Taliban and
some of the other various aspects that
go on in Afghanistan and Pakistan but
you know that region is one of the few
regions as well where there's still a
lot of traditional farming going on of
cannabis yeah um so it's good in the
sense that it's a resource it's sad that
it's hard to get to for us but at least
it's still there and there are some
people that are traveling around there
that are uh starting to ship some seeds
back to Europe and to America from those
regions and maybe people will find some
cool stuff in this more recent wave of
you know heirloom cushes or heirloom
Afghans and stuff like that that are
getting bred over there so we'll see
all right so we need to do some
housekeeping
uh for calebs anybody who's interested
in grabbing Caleb seeds I've seen a lot
of comments about that you can find them
on Speakeasy you can find them on his
website he has a lot of other retailers
what's your website Caleb
uh
humboldtcsi.com effect there you go so
if you're interested Humboldt csi.com I
know speakeasy's got a bunch of great
stuff
um is there anything else we wanted to
get to
I don't know how long have we been
talking it's pretty wide-ranging
discussion hour and a half hour and a
half
probably pretty good we probably are
pretty good yeah I mean you know we
always as as always uh uh Matt and I
will look over the questions and stuff
don't feel bad there's always too many
questions uh to get to if your question
didn't get answered maybe it'll get
answered in the future podcast uh maybe
even it'll be the seed that starts the
whole episode idea
um yeah so keep your questions coming
you know and all that uh you know
feedback
we have our patreon you can join our
discard chords via patreon and we go in
there chat uh I think we're doing movie
night tonight where we [ __ ] sit and
watch movies together or TV shows just
dick around but we also talk about
cannabis stuff extensively and put a lot
of my catalogs online and a lot of my uh
collection of historical stuff so pretty
much anybody can access the part of our
patreon and I'm putting up nudes of
Caleb in the same folder oh my gosh and
then two things real quick just because
I see questions I see multiple questions
about it
um I gave my my headband cut to Caleb to
breed with he's already released a few
lines off of it it's it's not very well
spread out in the community yet and so
since he's so prolific at breeding and
he has such a customer base my main goal
was to get it out there so he's done
some chemd he's done some TK uh there's
you know there's potential more work
that he's going to do with it as long as
it ends up being worthwhile and he likes
it
um and so that's that and then someone
asked him some questions about Mexico uh
you know Mexico is super close uh
unfortunately the Mexican uh the Mexican
weed is controlled a lot by cartels and
there's a lot of violence associated
with it so it's not so much like the 70s
anymore where you can kind of go down
there and like hang out with regular
farmers and maybe get seeds it's a
little bit more sketched than that the
violence has been quite extreme for the
last 10 years
and so while Mexico does have a large
and diverse population of cannabis down
there and we hope that some more of it
comes our way it's not as simple as it
was decades ago to go down there despite
how close it is and poke around and get
access to it I think there's anything
really worth
um getting in Mexico anymore just with
the influx of uh you know European
genetics
I hardly doubt it man cartel would have
been trying to increase production at
some point you know what I mean like
they're not they're not stupid that's
their main export other than meth so so
that might so that might be something
just real quick that will end it on is
that uh sadly one of the you know I I
talked about how it's very difficult for
us to penetrate Afghanistan and Pakistan
these days that might be a benefit
um because it's keeping their lines a
bit more pure uh some of the European
lines have infested Jamaica
Morocco and some of these other regions
yeah even Colombians
especially Colombia some of these
regions have been you know have you know
some of these you know Morocco
especially because it's close to Europe
you know uh they used to have a lot of
traditional cannabis they have a lot of
DNA they have a lot of different
European seed banks got Super Lemon Haze
now yeah stuff like that that they bring
down there and breed
um so there's a lot of regions of origin
that have been polluted for better for
worse uh by these other things and
you're not going to go to Jamaica and
find some 25-week Lamb's bread anymore
you're not gonna it's not as easy to
find stuff in Morocco it's not as easy
to find stuff in Mexico
um that's part of the issue is that the
you know global trade has good and bad
parts and in the 60s and 70s a lot of
these regions were untouched and they
just had what they had from their region
and now there's been a lot of
cross-contamination
um and so yeah you know no one's going
to Morocco looking for Super Lemon Haze
but sadly that's what they might find
you know or they might find some LA
Confidential or whatever over there you
know
um
those Farmers just want to make money
yeah so
um you know I think uh you know we could
answer a lot more questions and we could
talk for hours but I think we're coming
to a good place to close uh thank you
everybody everybody that gives us a bit
of time on their Friday it's always
appreciated absolutely you know we're
gonna keep this thing flowing we're
gonna try to keep topics of interest on
breeding and different things like that
going so
um thank you everyone oh wbd wbd hit up
um Speak Easy get them your address you
received a free shirt for having the
most upvotes on your question
so yeah get a hold of them yeah and so
everyone thank you very much I hope you
found it informative everybody have a
great day thank you Caleb for joining us
thanks for coming to you all soon
everybody have a wonderful afternoon
cheers