all right how's everyone doing I think
we're live now
I think we are live I'm trying to get
this all set up so people can actually
see
what we're talking about during
everything
so how's everyone doing tonight see I
see there's questions
um
let's see how many people we got only
yeah we got quite a few people
registered let's see how many people pop
on
I can see the registrations I can't see
how many people are in here live
so if you guys can feel free to shout it
out
yeah maybe I'll give them a few minutes
I'll give everyone a few minutes since
it's a different kind of process than
Instagram people got to go check their
email to get the link and all that crap
naza's on the way
so yeah this is uh we're gonna talk
about the history of of cannabis e banks
as we know them right
um a lot of people are familiar with
seed banks as far as the attitude uh
more modern type seed banks but this
goes this is a an industry that goes
back a long way and uh yeah so that's
what we're going to be going over I'm
going to try to do most of the
illustrating from my end like the old
seed bank catalogs
um and not so is going to try to handle
most of the
the talking because I mean this is his
specialty right
let's see if there's any questions I can
answer real quick
any chance you could get CSI on I think
it would make one of the best podcasts
in Canada's history actually sent uh a
picture of that that comment to CSI so
so he can see it himself
uh let's see what else we got anything
else I can answer
hash plant to Neville
um I'm sure uh
not so remember that
it will be available to watch for a
short period of time if you missed the
live event hopefully we can record it
I have not watched the Tony avoc I've
been so busy with [ __ ] moving and
everything
what is the importance of triangle
cushion the Legacy Heritage Flowers you
know it's going to be it's going to be a
very relevant important
um God I mean OG Kush is the market
right
personal favorite clone or line to come
from devil's work I'll let not to answer
that
um
I I I mean in all five Hayes has the the
majority vote I would say but I'm a fan
of super skunk Ultra skin super skin
[Music]
someone asked hi there I've been I'm
very new to this all however I've been
creating my own for a couple years
Crossing hemp High CBD varieties with
canvas strains from my own personal use
is this a thing yes it's absolutely a
thing
yeah man I I came into it when um forums
were the source of knowledge and my God
my God how much has changed you know
there he is we are here how you doing
bud I'm good it finally worked sorry
sorry everyone for the technical
difficulties but it appears that I can
see my face can everybody hear me yeah I
think so can you guys hear them
fantastic
I can see your hands Matt yeah I I um I
mounted this so I can I can illustrate
as you talk through certain things you
know with the Seedbank catalogs the
Scentsy catalogs sssc we got here we got
even the original sacred packs as you
talk about any of it so let's just start
rolling man
all right so uh this is the first
edition of our new thing so obviously
like we've never done this before
hopefully it works a little smoother
than live
um and uh we'll be able to do a couple
more cooler things we should be able to
see people's questions yeah uh all that
so uh hopefully bear with us with some
technical difficulties if they occur but
hopefully we'll be able to chat a bunch
of a bunch of cool [ __ ] and it'll work a
little easier we'll be able to see your
comments a little easier than we were on
live
so this is sort of like the new thing
we're gonna try
um for lack of a better way to go about
it
so
um we'll just try to
[ __ ] for a while and get uh where we
can on some of this stuff so
I don't know where we want to begin I
thought maybe this thing would be good
to talk about like some some seed bank
history yeah the you know obviously like
now uh there's a lot of stuff that's
kind of coming out of the woodwork where
people are talking about a lot of famous
old cuts from the 80s and 90s seed lines
and all that and I thought that like
there was a bunch of people that didn't
uh maybe didn't know some of the history
behind all how all that occurred uh and
so obviously since it's weed history
it's not entirely exact but this is
everything we're going to talk about is
the best that we know it right so uh
there could be some different
information not everything could be
entirely correct but we're going to give
it our best shot to give you uh what we
think and what we know and all that
right
that is correct
so that's the word so the reason why we
wanted to start with um like sort of
Neville and sort of Holland history uh
is it's that's not where like seed
history started obviously like there was
stuff going on in California there was
sacred there was plenty of private
breeders but
um in Holland that was sort of the first
place where you could literally be a
nobody and just send them money and get
seeds
right yeah like kind of in California at
least from my knowledge and experience
you kind of had to know somebody you
kind of had to be connected a little bit
um you know you had to be within certain
circles uh for instance you know I grew
up in the Midwest
and there was no access to seeds there
was no culture or anything like that so
the only places that we knew how to get
weed were dead shows and Holland
um and so you could mail order from
Holland you could uh you could fly out
there and buy them direct and kind of
try to bring them back yourself so
to me that's kind of where like modern
weed history as far as like most
people's access to it begins yeah if you
were in certain circles if you were in
the Pacific Northwest I mean you know
obviously it starts before that but
um Neville put an ad in High Times and
84 or so and that started what Matt's
holding up right now is his 85 catalog
um and because Holland's
because Holland's laws had changed then
they were sort of the first place that
could like really make seeds available
to everybody
right
so as a result of that like that's where
a lot of people got
most of their seed stock
um it wasn't from connections it wasn't
from friends that those were small
groups uh you know Neville uh sssc
um you know a couple other small places
they allowed everybody people from
Florida people from Chicago people from
New York people from North Carolina
Virginia wherever to just if they had
the balls to go there they had the balls
to order it they could get it
right and so that's where
that's where kind of like our modern
story starts and that's where like a lot
of uh a lot of seed strains and a lot of
lines that became famous to everybody
like Hayes Northern Lights skunk one G13
Maple Leaf all these things we talk
about now that'll become kind of
legendary
it's really where like 99 of the
population really first started getting
access to it right
um and so Neville is kind of unique in
cannabis history in that he had the
balls to start it and he sort of got to
as as you know by the mid-80s
persecution in California and America in
general had really kind of ramped up it
was the Reagan years uh drug laws had
gotten intense and so a lot of a lot of
breeders and a lot of Growers and a lot
of guys were seed they sort of took what
they had and they fled uh to Amsterdam
right and so Amsterdam basically got
famous because it was able to collect a
lot of stuff that was going on in
America and not so much stuff it was it
had itself
but really stuff that was going on in
America
um they did do some trips it's certainly
true that uh Neville
um the dronkers from Scentsy other
people you know some people went to
Afghanistan there was [ __ ] that they
called obviously the hippie hashish
Trail where people started going to the
Far East and poking around looking for
seed stock and stuff and uh but Holland
is really where it Consolidated like
Matt's holding it up right now if you
look on the left page that he has up
there's like an order form right and you
could literally write down what amount
you wanted of what strains and you could
send them [ __ ] money and they would
send you seats and uh that was pretty
revolutionary I think because that had
never happened before you couldn't just
ask a stranger for a bunch of a bunch of
illegal marijuana beans and get a hold
of them back then
right and so we thought maybe it would
be good to start like on a historical
basis because most of the stuff that we
grow today in some way there's a lot you
could trace a lot of it back to that
first five or ten years in Amsterdam say
like 85 to 95 right yeah I think Matt
would agree absolutely the vast majority
of today's modern cannabis you can at
least tie some of it back to that era
most of it definitely yeah you know and
so Neville did two things right Neville
had the balls to start
and then secondly he was kind of able to
collect a bunch of people's previous
work
um like for instance Mel Frank uh Jim
Ortega uh Seattle Greg from the NL crew
um you know uh Sam Skunk Man various
groups like that and then his own
travels and so he kind of became the
first person to be able to blend all
those things together like before him
nobody was crossing skunk in Northern
Lights because the skunk crew and the
Northern Lights crew didn't know each
other
nobody was crossing nl5 you know with
Haze because those that crew didn't know
each other yes in a way he got lucky
because I mean like imagine today for
instance
you could collect nobody knew about Kush
nobody knew about cookies nobody knew
about Sour nobody knew about all these
things that are famous in America and
imagine you got to be the person that
Blended them together first
and then sold and then resold them to
people so like that's kind of like what
um that's kind of what Neville got to do
in a sense right is yeah he got to be
first
you know and a bunch of people copied
him and a bunch of people came along and
added their own thing and obviously like
just like every other breeder
nobody started [ __ ] right everybody
happens on the shoulders of who came
before him so you all pick up you know
the breeding projects and the clones and
the seeds as you get into weed as you
come around and then you know you kind
of add your own kick to it and that's
what every breeder has done you know
from the beginning
um in some cases the first breeders in
say like America uh were taking all the
import lead like the Colombian and the
Panamanian and the Thai and the Mexican
and all that and all that stuff came in
uh from seed you know seeded weed
so literally every time you bought weed
you got free seeds
um and so most most breeding in America
was a bunch of sativas
right because that's all there was was
sativas like if you got Hash Hash was
Afghans but you didn't find any seeds
for the most part in hash
I think this this is a really super
important part too because most people
that are around today don't realize that
the the influx of modern afghanis and
stuff happened more in the 80s late 70s
early 80s as opposed to have always been
existing and always a part of the
culture yeah it it changed I mean most I
would say for instance that like most
most things that people were growing in
the 70s was a blend of sativas yeah
because that's what that's what
everybody had access to right so you
know it'd be Mexican Colombians it'd be
Mexican Colombians and ties it'd be all
these type of things and Afghans were
super [ __ ] rare like really rare
um because somebody had to go to
Afghanistan or Pakistan or one of those
regions get seeds and they had to go in
the 60s and 70s when travel took a long
time right they had to go they had to
collect them and they had to smuggle
them back into America either mailing
them or on their person somehow right so
but there was literal tons and tons and
tons of Mexican and Colombian and Thai
and Panamanian and all these different
Jamaican that was coming in and you know
in bricks and stuff to America and it
was all seated
so you know uh that was kind of like the
and so as a result of that most American
breeding was like in core groups right
it was just little groups of people
friend groups extended friend groups
that type of thing
you know uh and you know so that's kind
of how it started and it really I mean
it really wasn't until Holland that most
of America got access to like a what a
lot of little groups of people were up
to doing
you know
um obviously like prohibition was pretty
heavy so you know you just there was no
way for you to know what what Seattle
Greg and the NL crew was doing in the
Pacific Northwest they were trying to
avoid getting busted yeah and they were
they and Greg's commented several times
that it was just like watching dominoes
fall constantly watching their friends
get popped it was sketchy and so as a
result of it being sketchy and you
trying to be underground right
that meant that most people didn't have
access to what you were doing because
they didn't want most people to know
what they were doing they had to in
order to be successful you know there
was there was you know some stuff going
on in Mendocino County and Humboldt
County and you know Santa Cruz and the
Central Coast Area that was mountainous
um and you know people were getting away
with pretty good sized things and
breeding and stuff but unless you were
connected to those Crews if you lived in
Nebraska if you lived in Florida if you
lived in you know Chicago like where I
was born or anything like that you had
zero access to those people
you had no idea whatsoever what was
going on you just had you know if you
were lucky you got some imports so
the reason why we thought uh starting
with Neville and starting with the seed
banks is because Neville was really
Neville was probably one of the biggest
reasons why we're all here
uh he sold between he had when he
started the seed bank
um you know he sold millions of dollars
worth of seed millions of dollars yeah
all over America all over and so what he
did is he gave thousands and thousands
and thousands of people the ability to
grow their own
and the ability to get some of the best
American genetics that were happening
that people didn't have access to before
um so you know in a way
um you know he kind of took a lot of
very famous weed characters and he made
their stuff famous
you know is really kind of what happened
he made it famous yeah that's he made
some rock stars you know so I was
talking about it before and if anybody
was listening to like uh you know the
first breeder Syndicate uh interview uh
Matt Matt and Kanza got to interview
um uh Seattle Greg and one of the things
that Seattle Greg said in that interview
was that
you know he sent uh Neville a whole
bunch of NL seed because he saw that
advertisement that Neville put in that
in High Times
uh he literally you know reached out to
Neville and
um you know he sent Neville Northern
Lights
um and you know within five or six years
of that time uh everybody in the
northern light crew has gotten busted
um and it would have been lost a time
and nobody would have known anything
about it other than some Legends
um but he had gotten it to Holland
before they all got busted and lost it
right so
um
you know there's a there's a thing when
people are asking questions I haven't
gotten to the questions yet because I
just been kind of rapping about stuff
but
there's a button where you can people
can go and they can ask questions and
we'll try to get some of those questions
answered a little bit later after we
roll through some of this [ __ ]
and so
you know I'm I'm in my mid-40s so
you know literally like I said before I
knew how to get seeds I knew how to get
good weed from Grateful Dead shows and
Holland and uh I went to Holland in 1994
and uh you know I was able just as an 18
year old nobody to just walk into
various places and buy seed stock
you know I didn't know anything about I
knew barely anything about growing weed
I literally got my first seeds that I
had access to because I could buy a
plane ticket and I could fly to
Amsterdam as a kid and I could buy seeds
and I could bring them back to my spot
and we could pop them
and uh we could see what's up was it
still super expensive for the time like
you know like modern times comparatively
how were the seed prices back then when
you first flew over did you have to save
forever or
so the funny part about it is is that
um seed prices like when you look in
those old catalogs yes check it out in
all honesty you know you see a lot of
stuff for 50 bucks 80 bucks 150 bucks
200 bucks ever
you have to realize the way money works
right now
um
like I'll just give you guys for an
example of inflation in 1994 when I
turned 18
20 back then would be worth 38 today
foreign
ly stable over the decade
they really haven't jumped because if
you think about it most if you were
selling seeds at what Neville was
selling seeds for most seed packs should
be between two to four hundred dollars
yeah yeah
um just just even to equate how much
actual money Neville was getting for
selling those seats right
and so you know they've stayed pretty
stable I mean obviously there's some
people there's some there's cookies uh
there's some uh when Skittles came out
there's some people that
really profited off people's
availability
um
and uh you know they've charged you know
500 800 a thousand dollars a pack for
certain beans but
um you know seed prices for most things
like if you buy stuff from CSI or you
buy stuff from uh Riot or you you know
other good breeders that uh you know we
like like Shaw and different people
um they're amazingly competitively
priced uh you know to today so
um that's kind of like the that was kind
of a long-winded way to basically say
this hour or some chin change or however
long we decide to shoot the [ __ ] is
basically about like maybe giving some
people some information about how
Neville got started and how he collected
things and then how he started blending
things and then how those things sort of
became like the Bedrock of modern
cannabis
right
um because he's the guy that really took
it from very few hands relatively
speaking
um to crowdsourcing it if you will to
use a modern term where all of a sudden
a ton of people had access to it
right and I don't think that would have
happened
um without Neville and some others and
Holland and all that so
um
maybe that's sort of the uh that's sort
of the beginning
you know
um and we can kind of walk it through so
Matt right now is holding up the first
actual real Seed Catalog which has a
bunch of cool pictures of Neville's
Afghanistan trip
um you know he's holding a bunch of his
sheesh he's hanging out with people in
the tribal regions of Afghanistan and
um you know so basically when when
Neville first started
uh
he didn't know [ __ ] of what he had right
there it is yeah he really didn't he
didn't know anything that he had he was
just collecting stuff from people right
and he was starting to blend to those
things and I would say it probably took
him about three years or so of [ __ ]
around
um 85 84 85 86 going into 87 before he
really started to figure out like what
he had and favorites of what he had and
then kind of like 88 89 90
um that really when like the blend
started happening that ever that got
made really famous like if you look in
um if you look in the book the very
first book
you know in the Northern Lights
Greg and those guys sent him like
Northern Lights labeled one through
eight
but he you weren't able to buy nl1 from
him you couldn't buy nl2 you couldn't
buy NL anything you bought a random
assortment of NL that he had because he
hadn't had time to like you know he
inbred those things line by line but it
took him a few years to really figure
out what he had or then Grow rooms of
the stuff and even see what was in there
you got to realize too that like to him
these are just names that are coming in
from these different Growers
um you know we have a lot of knowledge
about what these things are supposed to
be now but he didn't have any
so in the first couple years there was a
bunch of there was a bunch of stuff in
there that's weird uh in for lack of a
better term you know there's random
Nepalese by skunks you know Colombians
by this Africans
yeah you know there there was just a
bunch of stuff because he was sort of
reselling
uh everything you know everything that
he had and he didn't really have uh he
didn't really have a way to
differentiate that you know so he was
just experimenting so you'll see a lot
of weird things in there like there's a
page
um you know yeah he's got some some Tie
by uh by uh Afghani you know New Mexico
Afghani yeah he had stuff that you'd
never see again like skunk one by by nl9
I think or nl8
um he had Mazar Missouri that he got
from his travels to Afghanistan he had
Nepalese
Rooter Alice it was kind of just a grab
bag in the beginning of
just whatever whatever you know he's
kind of collecting from all these
different breeders right and um
so uh
you know they um you know and you know
and and also just to go back for a
second just to give people an idea so he
was collecting all that
uh Greg Greg Seattle Greg sent him uh I
believe NL one through eight
uh according to Neville
um and Greg and uh you know who keep
David Watson who people call Sam's skunk
man he had gotten in trouble a couple of
times and so he took a bunch of seed
stock from himself uh and then some from
some other breeders and he brought that
to Holland and he ended up selling it to
uh Neville uh he ended up selling it to
uh the owner of positronics
um
the owner of positronics Bernard
um he ended up just basically you know
he had a couple kids or whatever he was
kind of brokish
um and he ended up going out there and
he gave Neville skunk one and Hayes from
himself and then he was friends with Mel
Frank and Mel Frank had given him
Afghani one and Durbin poison
um and then another breeder in the Bay
who we don't know his name had given
um some some other afghans
and stuff like that and so 85 86 Neville
was basically just reselling a bunch of
stuff that he was collecting a bunch of
different breeders that he had gotten in
touch with you know people who had flown
out from America to Holland or had
reached out to him through his
advertisement like Greg did and started
making connections right
uh so that's kind of like the that's
kind of the um
that's kind of the beginning
really
um so I don't know I've been talking for
a while I don't know if Matt if you want
to throw in uh any comments onto that or
we want to start back and forth on some
stuff but well
um let's let's start going over some of
the baselines that came out of the the
seed bank area some of the bass lines
that we see in a lot of modern cannabis
lines today
all right so maybe we'll start maybe
we'll start with uh something simple
like Northern Lights yeah but like I
said if you look in the 85 catalog and
you look in the 86th Vlog I'm not sure
maybe even the 87 but my memory fails me
slightly I think you really can just buy
Northern Lights yeah this one says
cannabis Indica Northern Lights in the
86 and in 87 it just says cannabis
Indica Northern Lights as well just as
Northern Lights so he got it in 80 he
placed that ad in 84. he got the seeds
sometime in 84. it's not we're not
exactly sure when yeah
he kept he started growing them out and
he started keeping the lines separate
and interbreeding them right and so if
you guys listen to the podcast with Greg
McAllister uh Seattle Greg as we like to
call him and um
you know he basically said that like you
know the nl1 and the nl2 and the nl3
um those were all pretty predominantly
Afghan they were rated by height and
length of flowering time and then most
of the other most of the other NLS were
those couple Afghans either one or two
blended with basically every sativa they
could get their hands on Hawaiians
um you know uh Colombians ties
Mexicans so it was really a hodgepodge
and
Greg has mentioned that they were really
scared to keep notes uh and they were
really scared to like lay out exactly
what they were doing so a lot of those
lines are kind of lost to time in terms
of what their exact makeup is uh because
those guys didn't even want to keep
track they were just trying to find good
weed right so yeah some of them is a
mystery but if you look in those first
few catalogs like I said before you can
find
you know uh skunk one by NL nl9 you can
um you know five by eight if you will uh
you can find a bunch of different things
and he started reading them together and
combining them
you know in various in various different
ways and even in the beginning right
like
um everybody's familiar most people are
familiar with what he ended up using
which is one of the things that became
pretty famous which is nl5 by nl2
um but the first year he offered it he
reversed it and he and he and it was nl2
by nl5 uh because he hadn't really
decided yet on like what you know what
worked for him
so after a few years of [ __ ] around
with NL he basically realized that
um nl1 bred pretty true to itself it was
pretty close to what we call Steve
Murphy Afghan uh which is basically The
Afghani that sort of got the NL line on
its way he got these Afghan seeds from
this guy named Steve Murphy uh who wrote
a couple cannabis books in the mid 70s
and this was sort of a wide leafed short
squat kind of bubble-like
um lowland Afghan
leafy Frosty resinous
short uh quick flowering thick dense
that type of thing and then the nl2 was
um you know more of a cush type it had
thinner leaves uh one thing that people
should know is like Afghanistan has an
enormous amount of height variation
depending on where you grow so some of
the stuff like the mazars and some of
the regions might only be like one or
two thousand feet above sea level but
then when you get up into like the Hindu
Kush region the Hindu Kush region is the
second highest mountain range next to
the Himalayas and a bunch of those
Afghan farmers were growing at like six
thousand eight thousand feet these big
tall valleys in the middle of nowhere
and so those leaves were kind of much
skinnier much thinner think about like
everybody's pretty familiar probably
with like the way that like what modern
Kush looks like and it's like that
skinny three leaf
um you know with different nugs
um where like the lowland Afghans were
sort of like thick feathery
um denser looser more more leafy nugs
like Matt's holding up in the picture
right there right yep so
I think it's 89 is it 89 the first
catalog mat where all of a sudden he had
figured out which NLS really worked for
him
which ones were stable which ones gave
him good breeding work and after getting
all those NLS all the NLS pretty much
disappeared okay from Neville's catalogs
except for
he offered nl1 F3
he offered nl2
okay
and then he found
he grew up a bunch of five and since
five is so famous maybe we'll chat about
that there's this dude named Kirby who
uh
um who took uh Steve Murphy's Afghan and
he crossed that to a Hawaiian which he
said was a Colombian by Mexican right
and
um you know and he gave that to Greg and
Greg sent that seed line out as one of
the one through eight well never Neville
grew a bunch of that out and obviously
if you're growing a bunch of Afghan by
Colombian by Mexican you're going to get
a bunch of uh a variety and Chaos okay
so he found this one maybe if you want
to show that one an L5 pick again yeah
let me find it
within the first few years
he grew up a bunch of this nl5 and most
of it was a chaotic mess uh Afghani
sativa blend all over the place but that
picture that you guys are seeing on the
left you found this one he called it
like a throwback plant right and he
found this one plant that was almost
pure Afghan super Frosty super resinous
didn't taste like much super low Terps
um but it uh it had great structure it
had a great Buzz
and uh he loved it and so I think by 88
89 90 the only thing that Neville was
really breeding with was you could buy
nl1
you could buy nl2 and he had one cut
that Matt just showed of the nl5
right yeah you gotta realize for a
second that
in America right guys they didn't have
Neville's nl5 cut
they sent Neville a cut of their
favorite but theirs was a hybrid theirs
was that blend it was an F1 hybrid of
Steve Murphy Afghan by Colombian and
Mexican right
and so you know there was there's a lot
of confusion about nl5 and we have this
thing that we call pre-pre
where a lot of people like to like to
talk about how they have seeds or they
have Cuts like from the earliest
possible time you could have the cut
but people need to people need to
understand that there was always
um there was a North American cut of nl5
that was an Afghani hybrid of with
sativa and there was a cut that Neville
found amongst the seed line that is that
picture right there that looks super
Afghan and super Frosty right and so
um by 88 89
almost all the NL you're gonna get is he
used nl1 and nl2 as males
and nl5 was always the this the female
and that was pretty much it after three
four years of breeding with NL he had
decided that most of the sativa most of
the hybrids that were with sativa that
Greg had sent were a [ __ ] mess and
hard to breed with and didn't breed
consistently right and you got to
realize too that back then during the
high prohibition times people wanted
consistent producers yeah that's
important he used the joke that if he
gave you some kind of white hot fire but
it yielded 10 percent less you'd be
pissed
yeah right and so most he found that
like most pure Afghans didn't cross very
well together
um they like being crossed with that was
one of the he was one of the first
people that really realized that when
you start Crossing things you start
getting really neat stuff when you start
Crossing things that are totally
unrelated to one another
ah so
the NL that everybody became famous with
people should realize there never was an
nl5 line that was ever released pure
that's super important as well because
we see that all the time people popping
up with nl5 saying they have the nl5 cut
or nl5 seeds so
you know the nl5 cut that was made
famous because people were buying
millions of dollars worth of hybrids of
it really
that was in Europe
you know and you know Greg has stated
that by the late 80s they had all gotten
busted and lost all their [ __ ]
right and they didn't really share very
much Greg told us that they had shared
the eight a cut of the eight a cut of
the nine and with a few friends they had
shared the five cut but that wasn't the
super Afghani five cup Neville shows in
those pictures that was the F1 hybrid
that was Colombian Mexican and Afghan
right so
um everything that never sold
was an nl5 hybrid
you had nl5 by nl2 he had no five by uh
skunk one he had nl5 by Haze uh can you
think of any more Matt
um as far as nl5 crosses final five Haze
nl5 by two I think that what was the
other one in all five one
those are three most common right yeah
yes you know a lot of people are talking
about having pure nl5 well that'd be
really [ __ ] hard
because Greg says that they lost it all
by the late 80s and then Neville never
sold pure nl5 uh there and and by pure
uh to be clear he grew out a lot of the
seeds that Greg sent him and most of the
nl5 line was a mess and he found this
one Afghani plant he liked a lot and
that's the one he used
so
uh you know you see a lot of stuff you
know I see some comments you know uh
talking about Bodhi stuff and all that
and it's tough because I'm not here to
like you know call anybody out or
anything like that or obviously there's
a lot of people making a lot of claims
um but you know that's part of the issue
and that's part of the reason why we
wanted to do these podcasts and these
talks is because most of the history is
oral
right it's not written down very well
um even the people that were there
disagree exactly on what happened yeah
right there's some consensus but there's
also uh there's also some disagreement
and some of these Old-Timers they don't
like each other
yeah just flat out and they have beefs
and they have disagree I mean it's not
very different than today right there's
breeders today that don't like each
other and they have beaches
20 years from now there'll be legends
about both right and they'll be like Oh
I thought Matt Ryan was a piece of [ __ ]
he's a [ __ ] this and that I don't
believe him at all and then there'll be
other people who will be like well Matt
Ryan's story was consistent in this
other guy's story wasn't consistent
and most people aren't there right
and so what we're trying to do with this
is just kind of lay out some like basic
facts right and uh yeah and I can
actually comment on the Bodhi uh in all
five thing because I was we were talking
during that time a lot you know we've
been close friends for a long time and
in his goal with the nl5 knowing he knew
that nl5 was never released pure as a
seed line however we were trying to find
something closest that we could find and
he was like he was trying to find it and
and Consulting all his friends too
saying hey where do you think the best
nl5 seed line would be that would show
the best representation and at the time
there was like Dr Thomas Northern Lights
um which was a supposed claimant to the
nl5 you know uh lineage and then there
was BC seeds which was the more popular
one that had had been around probably
accepted as as closer to Northern Lights
than most that was available at the time
so that's what he went with and and I I
agree it was probably one of the better
options at the time but as far as a pure
NLP seed line when you break it down
it's that's really hard to find
because it never because the only people
that had it you know and by pure let's
be clear the initial nl5 seed line was
an unstabilized poly hybrid
yes it was a mixture of Mexican
Colombian and and Afghani right it was
never stabilized it was never pure it
never BR it never bred true right it was
a full-on polyhydrate
oh and that's right squirrel mentioned
the nl5 skunk one yeah that's correct
yeah no five I I mentioned I think
Neville sold nl5x2
NHL five by Skunk one yeah five by Haze
um and so but NL was always the NL was
always the mother plant
yeah I'm sure most people know this but
I'll say it anyway
just in case is that the way we talk
about seeds is the mother should always
come first
and the father should always come second
correct you talk about five by two he's
using the mother of nl5 and a dad of nl2
right uh some people get it flipped
around and that's hella confusing
because it is important to know what's
the mom and what's the dad it really
helps to have consistent terminology
when you're chatting about seeds
um what about the new cut so
you know there's things where it's like
I can't you know
when we're talking about kind of seed
history and stuff like that this is all
stuff that's going on in the 80s and the
early 90s
um and then you know these these things
get legendary status and then they pop
up in different generations and by
different people and different seed
companies in Holland different seed
companies and later in Canada they start
uh they start popping out and um
I can answer that one actually real
quick yeah so uh there's there's
somebody asked a question about nl5 seed
from Todd uh we know quite a bit about
that uh the basic story is that Greg
says okay that he found that that they
found some seed
from him that he didn't know existed for
decades uh after his sister had sadly
passed away
in her fridge in her freezer in her
freezer and he gave some of those to
Todd uh Matt got some of those as well
um and
um so those you know it's it's hard to
say uh you know Greg admitted that uh
Greg admitted that he lost everything
for decades and then he finds some seeds
in his sister and his deceased sisters
uh fridge uh that were labeled and so at
best you can say that the provenance of
them is uncertain
for sure you know it's just uncertain
there's just no way to tell if it is an
L5 then it would be
Steve Murphy Afghan by
Mexican Colombian which which originally
Greg referred to as a Hawaiian but later
on he said what the Hawaiian was that
was actually over there it's a Hawaiian
but you know I mean obviously Hawaii
doesn't have any native exactly weed so
most of Hawaiian was sativas from other
traditional regions brought to Hawaii
and grown
yeah right yeah and so how did BC Seed
Company obtain nl5 so this is kind of
jumping around for a minute but let's be
clear uh most of the seed companies in
Amsterdam
once they realized how profitable this
seed [ __ ] was
they would buy seed from whoever had the
seed in Holland rename it and resell it
yeah okay so
um you know a company bought Neville's
nl2 F3
and they renamed it Oasis
yeah uh which company is that Matt
remind me uh Dutch Passion Dutch Passion
so Dutch Passion you know uh when this
is jumping ahead a lot but you know
within a year of Shanti releasing white
widow or other things there was two or
three other competing seed companies in
Holland selling White Widow and they
would just take this they would just
lift the exact lineage from the people
that's that first sold the seed they'd
buy five or ten or Twenty or however
many packs of seed from that person grow
them out pick a male and a female and
start making and packaging their own
seed line because it was money
right
so
these things are just reworked you know
and
one thing that we should also know
is uh
seeds have always been Shady
and everybody involved in seeds has
always been shady and it's already
always been Underground
and it uh you know it's always been
somewhat persecuted and so you know a
lot of the characters to be perfectly
honest live
and it's hard to tell what they lie
about
you know
um yeah I mean the provenance of a
breeders only as good as
what they can prove you know and a lot
of people don't demand that proof they
don't know to demand that proof or or
have it even researched to demand yeah
well I saw something we'll get to some
questions here and just we'll go through
like a little question and answer
session
um you know shortly here or whatever and
we're not we won't get through it all
today but I just kind of like you guys
can see I mean I haven't even gotten I
haven't even talked yet about the most
famous hybrid of all time which is nl5
haze but there's a lot of depth to these
stories on how these people got started
um and you know and then other people
should also know that like you know
um some of these later seed companies uh
a lot of these people worked for Neville
right yeah uh Adam who was part of
starting THC seeds Tony who was first at
cerebral and then made his own sag
Martha seeds Simon who was also at
cerebral and then made serious seeds uh
they all were boom
right all of them and then within a year
of leaving working for Neville or
leaving working for Scentsy under
Neville to be more accurate they all had
their own Steed companies
so it's highly likely that at the very
least they took some stock uh some other
plants some fathers some whatever from
their previous job and rename stuff uh I
mean that's the game right uh it's
always been a meaning
it's always been
get something
right yeah it's never been
um you know but maybe I should take a
step back I'll talk for a few more
minutes and then we can answer some
questions
but the other part that's cool is that
one of the things that Neville did that
other people didn't
is that he actually went to America on
some even clone hunts
and uh there's a dude who is written
most people probably know exactly who
this is uh he's one of the people
through his books that taught me how to
grow weed there's this dude named Jorge
Cervantes
and uh Neville met up with Jorge
Cervantes on one of his trips back into
America and
um Jorge got had new breeders maybe
breeders is the wrong word they knew
Growers at the very least they knew
growers in the Pacific Northwest region
and Jorge hooked him up with the G13 cut
and what what became known as the
Pacific Northwest hash plant
that's right
um
and so
certain people gave Neville a bunch of
seed lines
but then there was things like the
Pacific Northwest hash plant the G13
um you know stuff like that that ended
up just being straight cuts that he
purchased uh and
um you know
yeah George wasn't somebody he used to
go buy a different pen name
um back in the day
uh but uh yeah he he hooked up Neville
with those two cuts and really all we
know is that Neville paid 500 for the
G13 cut and it came out of order
and he I don't know how much he paid for
the Pacific Northwest hash plant I'm not
sure but he paid for that and he sent
both those things back as cuts
right
so
um you know he kind of collected over
the first five or six years he was in
business through some travels uh to
Afghanistan from meeting up with
American breeders uh to going to to
going to America and buying cuts and
Seed lines
we haven't talked about that but there
was this uh very mysterious character
named Jim Ortega that gave him seed
lines that became Super Famous the
garlic Bud the Hawaiian Indica the
um the maple leaf Indica
um
and uh uh the Kush four
uh you know and those ended up a number
of those ended up in a bunch of Neville
projects
um so Neville kind of like Neville kind
of like was able to in that five-year
period you know our six year period
really 84 to 90. he was constantly
collecting stuff from breeders
collecting stuff from people blending it
together releasing stuff playing around
with stuff and seeing what the hell it
was is kind of how it got started in a
sense
uh you want to add any of that [ __ ] Matt
um actually this this is hearkening back
to people are asking about the BCC
company and their sourcing I actually
found something in reference to just
that real quickly is it the doctor
Atomic one so there's gonna be the hemp
BCC bank I believe and they don't really
give an exact
um anything on how they sourced it but
it does say uh this state-of-the-art
Indica as a result over 20 years of
selected inbreeding they pretty much
took levels uh description the buds have
extremely frosted then they actually
sold an nl5 Hawaiian Indica no5 Haze one
Hawaiian Haze but again it didn't see
anything about the sourcing of their no5
and they couldn't have possibly been
around for it
so that's a lot to digest and it kind of
gives you like a super General overview
of like what what Neville was up to and
you know some of the people he was
collecting from and some of the things
that he got
um maybe we'll pause for a second and
we'll hop over to the votes uh yes
people are and we'll answer some
questions yeah I'll read them off to you
so you don't have to read them no I got
them in front of me it's pretty easy uh
this app that I downloaded works pretty
well awesome
the first question that got a bunch of
votes is uh getting CSI on here
um CSI is I could probably safely say
he's a good friend of both mine and
Matt's
um we both uh chat with him uh fairly
often
um you know he uh we're all good friends
uh it's certainly possible that we could
convince them to come on one of these in
the future
um
he's not quite as talkative as Matt and
I am and he's lost
but he has done it in the past and it is
entirely possible that we could get him
to do it uh he's a wealth of knowledge
um people call him inspecta for a reason
uh he's got a really curious mind he
pokes and pokes and pokes and tries to
figure out knowledge kind of like
the rest of us everything I just said
um that I rambled on about for forever
uh that it's the result literally of
years of talking to people uh a year of
researching years of you know uh Matt
got to talk to Neville quite a bit in 09
uh 10 12 years ago
um or so got a bunch of emails and
various kinds of communication uh there
was a couple year period on uh Mr Nice
forums which is Shanti Baba's site where
Neville was actively posting and
answering a bunch of people's questions
uh there's friends of his that have
contributed uh there's enemies of his
that have their own various stories and
stuff and so
um all this stuff is not easy to find
it's not in any one location it's all
sort of a conglomeration of uh
you know it's a lot of a lot of work and
you know CSI
it crashed
he puts a lot of effort he cares about
history he cares about
um knowledge uh he cares about the oral
history
I can't say when but we can try to get
uh homie on here and see if he wants to
chat about various things
the next question is we have like I said
before we have no idea who passed the
Pacific Northwest hash plant to Neville
do you know that
jorgeous
yeah that's right Jorge did arrange that
that exchange for the pnw hash plan
right he did he did
your team
um so it's not public knowledge who gave
it to him we just know it came out of
the Oregon Washington state area uh
there was Growers that that Jorge knew
that he was able to hook up with Neville
and Neville bought them from them
um so uh their names are not known to my
knowledge uh whoever they were
and uh the Maui cut that I have
so the the third that question and the
next question what seeds did I buy in 94
and did I find anything decent and the
Maui cut are both related
so I was Dumb and I was 18 and in
retrospect I went there and I bought a
ton of seed
but sadly I only bought one or two packs
of like 15 different things
um and not realizing at the time that I
would have been better off buying say
two or three or four things like five or
six or seven packs of each
um and actually get like 20 or 30 or 40
females of each one instead you know I
bought a bunch of random [ __ ] I bought
stuff from Scentsy uh I bought some
stuff from
um
I'm trying to think now uh this the
easiest way to put it is uh I didn't
find anything that was worthwhile on
that trip except for
I was at the gray area coffee shop and I
was smoking a joint and we were young
and this old timer was sitting down next
to us and I mean old timer in the sense
he probably looks something like me
right now he was probably in his mid-40s
a little a little gray whatever and uh
we were smoking and we were young we
were all 18 I was there with some
friends of mine we were like all 18 to
20 or whatever and we were all hippies
deadhead this mission to buy seeds and
smuggle them back so we could grow I had
a I had I had a huge scene I had a two
lighter at the time so really major
major player and uh
um I was sitting down next to him this
this old guy smoking weed and we were
telling him our story and he told me
that he was from Hawaii
and he'd lived there since the mid 70s
and every few years he came out and
traded seeds with some of these guys in
Holland
um and brought him back and tried them
in Hawaii on Maui and it wasn't a very
long conversation we drank a cappuccino
I didn't ask him that many questions we
smoked a couple joints together and a
little hash or whatever and then at the
end of it he was like well I'm super
stoked you kids are out here trying to
find some weed and he's like why don't
you take why don't you try a little bit
of what I do and he put a handful of
seeds in my hand
um and one of those became the Maui cut
uh I stupidly didn't make any seeds
uh that era I wasn't even attempting to
breed yet I was just trying to find a
good female to fill my two lighter so uh
I didn't ask him any intelligent
questions about it and so I called the
Maui
because that's the island it came from
and that's the only thing I know about
it
so it's gorgeous though yeah so really
uh the first time I went to Amsterdam I
went to Amsterdam probably two or three
times between 94 and 03 probably two or
three times a year I went to like three
cannabis cups in that time
um and I would go mostly I would go in
summer
um but I would go I'd try to go a couple
times a year and buy different seeds
talk to breeders talk to various people
learn as much as I could you've got to
realize back then there was no forums
everything was just in books information
was pretty hard to come by
um you know information was rudimentary
really uh the the way the information
flows now I wish that I could have
listened to somebody like this to shoot
the [ __ ] about weed but it was pretty
hard to come across so
um
the only thing I found on my 94 trip and
I kept for the gift
everything I bought was I don't want to
say it was bunk uh but my 18 my 18 year
old knowledge I didn't keep any of it
so
um I still have that cut it's still
grown in Mendocino County by others it's
a great outdoor plant it has a bunch of
it might be in some popular strains that
are around nowadays
it is definitely in some popular streams
um and all that and uh you know so yeah
I got
um the first the first trip the only
thing I found that was useful was a gift
from a man I don't even know his name I
smoked a couple joints with him I'd
probably spend a total of 20 minutes
with him drank a cappuccino got a
handful of seeds in my palm
boggled it back called it the Maui and
uh that cut is
27 years old this year that's so wild so
it's uh it's certainly my longest held
cut I've had it my entire adult life
uh it uh paid a lot of bills I brought
it with me when I moved from Chicago to
Mendocino County in 1998 I spread it out
a little bit there
um and it's uh
it's been in a number of different
things
um I bred with it quite a bit
um you know I gave some hybrids that I
had made uh of Superdog which is another
story that we've talked about before but
super dog by Maui I gave a bunch of that
to mandelbrot
mandelbrot uh found afino in that that
he called the truth
and then he bred with it and some of his
own lines and stuff and so she exists in
various she still exists pure with me
and some friends but she also exists in
some other people's work she might exist
in some pretty famous things at this
particular time but that's kind of how
cannabis is you know so
um how long have we been talking Matt
it's right about an hour um I got an
idea I was gonna do a giveaway tonight I
think probably since we're touching on
the pnw hash plant I'll give away some
of the seeds to the person who asked the
question that got the most upvotes so
whoever Billy is send me a Instagram
message some of the pnw hash plant
crossed the blue bonnet
um so there's a couple more questions I
could answer for sure
um
and uh we'll uh I can chat a few things
so uh our friend uh flanville he said
what's my personal favorite clone or
line to come from Neville's work
you know
the line is easy uh I I personally think
the most famous uh hybrid ever made in
the most successful cannabis hybrid
that's ever been sold is Northwest 5 by
Hayes
um I think it's uh
yeah I don't think there's another
there's another line that's more famous
um if you're looking at
um at the catalogs right there right up
there on top in the 1990 catalog
that picture of nl5 haze do we know
which one it was eight it's A2 it's A5
A52 852 yep there it is that's the
mother of Neville's hate that picture
right there that's the mother of
Neville's Hayes
um that cut is still alive uh it's both
in Europe and it's floating around with
the select few people in America
um
it's you know it was found in 89 or
something like that so it's super old
um and look at all that leaf resin damn
so yeah basically
um you know he got you know it's kind of
long but he got haze from uh Sam's Dave
Dave Watson's Sam Skunk Man and he ended
up Crossing it with some of his indicas
um Maple Leaf Indica uh called that
silver haze he crossed it with G13 and
he had G13 Hayes he crossed it with nl5
that became and the nl5 uh I actually
don't think there's another line as well
as me thinking that it's the most famous
and well-known line I don't think
there's another line that has as many
named Elites that still exist as that
line
yeah it'd be hard you'd be hard-pressed
to find one there's probably four to six
at least famous named Cuts in Europe uh
that are nl5 Haze the pith the heights
Haze the Cuban black Haze the dog [ __ ]
the church uh all those are all nl5
hazinos and they all come from 88 to 95.
here's another picture from Scentsy
though
um it is
uh it's probably the most it's probably
the most famous line that anyone has
ever made and there's literally 8 to 10
to 12 cuts of it that are all have
different names they're all Elites
they're all still hoarded
uh and exist on both in Europe and in
America so I think it's by far the most
famous cannabis hybrid ever made
um since you have this beautiful one
yeah that's super skunk since you see
today is sadly probably bunk
um yeah Neville worked for them that's a
whole story in itself but Neville worked
for them after he got busted and got
they bailed him out of jail and they
gave him a great deal of if we bail you
out of jail you have to sell us your
company
oh uh he spent like he spent a good
chunk of time in jail and they bailed
him out and Scentsy seeds ended up
absorbing uh the seed bank from Neville
and the entire Neville as their top
breeder so Neville went from owning the
biggest most successful Seed Company to
having the DEA after him spending about
eight or nine months in jail and then
having to go from being an owner to
being the head breeder for different
people
and uh that's another story but they
ended up renaming a bunch of his stuff
um and so Scentsy for the first five
years in the 90s for the most part
um that was where Neville resided and
made most of his themes and probably
from 95 to 2000 they still had the vast
majority of the original uh lines that
they were working with
uh seed laws changed in 99 and 2000 in
Holland and most of the original
breeders got raided and busted uh Ben
and Alan dronkers are
um Dutch businessmen for lack of a
better term they will never admit that
they lost a single plant from The
Originals you can't get a word out of
them that anything is different than uh
it's ever been but most likely they lost
a bunch of stuff and if I'm correct I
think they farmed out most of their work
to Spain
they haven't made traditional versions
of their seeds and in the the timeline I
always go by is roughly 2005 2006 is
going to be the last times you want to
buy stuff from the majority of the Dutch
seed banks because by then Nirvana
[ __ ] all of them Greenhouse uh
Scentsy they were all farming out to
Buddha seeds and eventually telemota
so basically yeah um
then see sadly since he had about a a 10
to 15 year run of having lit a lot of
legitimate stuff I do think that there
could be some things in Scentsy that are
still real
you have no idea what to know what and
we do know
um that they lost uh quite a few mother
plants and breeding plants over the
years but they'll never admit that so
sadly
it's no longer what they were in the 90s
which was an excellent place to get a
bunch of beans
um
and I will say uh see if if people want
to see what original Haze is like
seedsman still has original Haze that
they sell I believe uh it's all it's all
purchased from Watson if I'm correct but
if you know people talk about you know I
might have a cutting of original Haze
and stuff it's still around it's still
around in seed form
um
you know so yeah there's I don't know
there's
we could talk endlessly
um
uh
there's a couple things on here that are
that are easy to talk about somebody
said that skunk VA head dog use your
headband cut uh yes and no I have two
headband cuts
um one of them we call the LA he does
not have that one but there's another
headband cut that's extremely nice uh
that both him and
um ICC uh uh uh both have and
um Mr Bob Hemphill and some other people
have it's much more of a cush-based
headband and that's the headband that
that he uses it's a great cut super
potential that's the one that I use as
well from Elite cannabis
yeah and then
um
let's see
uh you mentioned the nl5 seed line was
composed of Afghani Colombian and
Mexican what makes this different than
skunk one
um that's a good point skunk one is
Afghani Mexican and Colombian just
totally different types of parents
totally different lines yeah I mean it's
it's like saying somebody's Italian
Irish and Chinese you know it's not the
same parents uh it's just the same
region of origin
um certainly Sam Skunk Man was not using
the NL Cruz Afghans in his lines
um and it's very unlikely that the
Mexican or the Colombians are related
um but it just goes to show how
different blends you know from different
parents can lead to very different
things
yeah
vastly different
vastly different you know
um let's see somebody asked about I
don't know I mean I've been talking the
whole time and Matt has been unusually
quiet while I [ __ ] so I I learn I
still learn when we talk there's certain
things that you said tonight that I
couldn't [ __ ] remember
um even even from being the one who
talked to Greg a bunch I still couldn't
remember some of that stuff so I'm just
learning
um so uh which which do you know which
uh cut of headband Caleb's using let me
let me ask this there was a guy that was
talking about where can one find real
old school strains and genetics
why are all these pollen Chuckers with
watered-down Herm genetics and trash
gear getting the most attention
all right so there's a couple comments
on that uh for one thing
um and this is common this isn't just
for weed but
um you know some people are really good
at marketing
right uh for lack of a better turn you
know yeah
you know there's a lot a lot of breeders
um let's all throw it out there again
right so if we get CSI on here in my
opinion CSI is one of the absolute best
breeders that's alive today and working
hands down I think he the amount of
breeding he does the amount that he
shows his own work the amount that he
constantly cracks entire rooms of seed
that he has made and shows people what's
in the seed lines themselves almost
Nobody Does that yeah right almost
nobody shows as much of his own work in
pictures and you can just watch him grow
after grow after grow after grow after
grow after grow on IG for years just
posting tons and tons of pics of you
know most readers don't test their own
work at this particular time it's very
rare testing your own work is time
consuming the best way to make money as
a breeder is to make the cross give it a
killer name make some amazing Patrick
packaging and then be like Masonic or
something like that and like pump pump
pump on IG and try to get a bunch of
hype going
um and growing it out and testing it
takes time money energy space
power bills you know all this different
stuff and so
um
no but the reason why I mentioned CSI is
because he is absolutely terrible at
promoting himself
he is a phenomenal breed
that doesn't really self-promote the way
other people do you know and so you got
to separate marketing from Talent right
the other thing I should say about that
is that when people talk about term
genetics people act like herbs are a bad
thing right and so and they're not
you know I said this on the live when
Matt and I were chatting before anybody
that thinks that Herms are bad is
tripping
yeah right perms are inconvenient in
today's Marketplace
um obviously having seeds and stuff like
that isn't the greatest so you know uh
Herms are just a genetic trait that
enable a plant to create seed in the
event that something weird happens and
they don't get pollinated in order to
continue the species right from a
breeding perspective
um they're quite convenient to the
marijuana plant
um from a seedless perspective where
we're trying to grow since Amelia or
whatever you know however you want to
call it seedless they're inconvenient
um but but the marijuana plant did not
develop with the idea that it was going
to be seedless to it seedless is a
failure yeah right a straight failure
okay so you know it's trying to just
like all other life it's trying to
reproduce and survive
right and
you know just to be clear too there is a
lot of the best cannabis out there
that's bag seat
okay straight back seat it's really
humbling as a breeder that some of the
best on the planet is accidents it sure
is the chem dog came from a bag of weed
bought at a dead show without seeds in
that bag of weed we don't have chem dog
sour was a multi-term accident
okay the super skunk that everybody's
hunting after and everybody wants and
everybody's claiming to have rks and
there's rks coming out of the woodwork
and everybody wants to claim like they
got skunk skunk skunk that plant permed
like a mofo it harmed like crazy
but because it harmed like crazy if it
didn't hurt there would be no sour
diesel
right there would be Sour Diesel is is
from accidental harms right the reason
why people have Kush the reason why cush
came to La is because in Florida
somebody's room hermed and they sold
seeded weed and people found that seeded
weed and they grew up some seed and they
got what we known as Kush
Sour Diesel cookies
okay uh chem dog you name it they're bag
seeds
and so you know a lot of people like you
know jump on Herms and obviously you
don't want to buy a bunch of gear that
has tons of Herms because it's
inconvenient but Herms are a genetic
trait like anything else and they exist
and breeders do the best they can to
reduce the incidence of Herms but if
you're breeding something okay nobody
you know nobody cared that Sour Diesel
hermed a little bit
it was Fireweed yeah right tasted great
got you super [ __ ] high lasted a long
time burned great it's a Herm
you know Kush came from a Herm cookies
came from a herb multiple Hermits so a
lot of the backbone cannabis and a lot
of the absolute most famous lines were
not created intentionally at all they
were accidents that happened in people's
rooms and so that doesn't mean that like
you want to get a bunch of hermy gear
that sucks and makes your life crappy
right obviously Herms are inconvenient
and breeders can do the best they can to
reduce her hermaphroditism traits but
there's I mean Matt can speak to this
there's populations like Thai and other
things where perms are like prevalent
yeah I mean it really depends on which
line you're running and it vastly
depends on the room that the the parents
were acclimated in that made the seeds
if if you're if you're popping seeds
from a grower that only predominantly
makes seeds indoors and you want to run
them all Outdoors probably not the best
idea you know it's it's acclimation
climate all that goes into it but
intersex traits are here people have
right against them for ever since people
have been breeding cannabis first and
vanilla right but they're still here and
there's they're not going anywhere it's
a part of the the genome and you know
man there's there's a there's a uh
there's a lot of there's a lot of
questions I'll try to answer a couple
more before we before we leave the last
question is Caleb using the other
headband cut
um Caleb is CSI uh and uh CSI has both
of my headband Cuts Like I said he's a
real good friend of mine I trust him
with my whole Library he can have
anything he wants for me basically
um I love his breeding work uh you know
nobody put the Mendo perps which I got
lucky enough to crack nobody put more
genetics out there of the Mendo perps
and made it a permanent part of the gene
pool more than CSI so he has both of my
headband cuts
um my La cut is a sort of a diesel type
it's much more of a blend
you know uh the other one is much more
of a Kush varietal they're both super
potent they're both in my kind of top
five or ten cuts that I possess
um so he has both he hasn't had them
forever but he has started using them in
various work and you can buy some of
that work as we speak
um
Mr Nice I'll ignore that one just
because it's a super long subject but
the short version is that after Neville
left Scentsy he started working with
Shanti Baba and they made they bread
together for a while and the result of
that breeding was super silver haze
mango Haze Neville's Haze some other
things and Neville was hurting for money
and uh he sold
County for a good chunk of loot uh a
quarter of a million dollars or
something
um most of his seed collection from the
seed bank era uh in the 80s unreleased
stuff various lines and things like that
so Mr Nice
um like a lot of people there's some
people that believe that shanti's full
of [ __ ] there's some people they believe
he's a shady character that he's a liar
but it's indisputable
that
Neville gave him a lot of real parents
and Neville gave him uh or sold him his
seed collection
um so there's not very many people that
have indisputable evidence that they
have a bunch of access to the old things
and he's one of them that being said
there's no way to verify what he has and
what he doesn't have and so there's a
lot of debate on what he has and there's
disagreement and some people think he's
full of it some people think he's got
all the white hot fire
the truth is probably somewhere in
between I'm sure he has some of
Neville's old work I'm sure he has a
bunch of Neville's old seed it's hard to
say exactly
um what he currently has and what he
doesn't but his provenance in being able
to access it I don't think is in dispute
would you agree with that Matt oh yeah
for sure I mean Neville Neville uh I
mean at the very end it's not talked
about a lot but um he he felt like
Shanti Baba might owe him some more
money even though it wasn't in the
agreement because he had done so well
with Neville's line so Neville obviously
felt that his lines were being used
correctly and making tons of money with
them
there's another thing about Australian
bastard cannabis at CSI I'll just say
that real quick I don't know that much
about it
um you know CSI is a true breeder
um he's really interested in freaks he's
really interested in genetic uh Oddities
and if nothing else ABC is extremely odd
uh in the way that its leaves form and
stuff like that and you know a lot of
stuff right now is really bottlenecked
people use the same 30 40 50 Cuts over
and over and over again and so at the
very least
when you buy ADC work you're getting
something that is genetically unique so
far
and he's certainly widening the gene
pool of available cannabis
Yeah by making it by making it available
to the public
um it is probably one of the first lines
in a long time that's totally unique
from what came before and it's valuable
just for that and it's an ongoing
project that he's putting a bunch of
time into and I'm sure over the next
three or four or five years we'll see a
bunch more work from it uh Matt can
comment on this too but he's really just
been getting started with his own work
on it yeah yeah
um I see so many people get so mad every
time he posts pictures of people
actually genuinely get hurt feelings
when they see this plant and they're
like oh my God what is that piece of
[ __ ] you know it's it's surprising to me
because a lot of them claim to be
breeders or or our seed makers and have
companies but they don't see the genetic
novelty in bringing in something
completely new that hasn't really
touched cannabis you know as far as
modern lines
yeah I mean there's there's a lot of um
there's a lot of uh
there's a lot like I said there's a lot
of sameness I'll say this quickly too
the way the breeding is gone the last 20
years as soon as something becomes
famous everybody crosses it to
everything else
yeah so the amount of [ __ ] right now
that has cookie in it cushion it Sour
Diesel in it Skittles in it
um you know you name it in it
um stuff gets bread and bread and bread
and bread and bread and bread to die
um so to take say cookies and across it
with uh ABC is crossing it to a vastly
different gene pool than anybody else is
using and so who knows what might come
of that that's the best part you don't
know who knows in a few years where that
might lead that might lead to Unique
highs that might open up the gene pool
and make things pop out you're not
expecting genetics
and so people get on them about it
because it's so weird
um but he's really just in the infancy
of playing around with it but you've
seen that he is
um you know he's been posting a bunch of
pictures this last week of some of his
work with the ABC
um
and I don't know we probably how long
we've been talking
um we're at about hour and a half
hour and a half
um so I don't know I mean maybe you know
I don't know you guys could like this is
probably odd because I've been talking
98 of the time for an hour and a half
it's all good I can hear it in my throat
um but we kind of wanted to do this
thing and maybe we'll do it like you
know semi often or whatever we had this
thought of kind of going through the
seed banks and it's such a big subject
um we really only touched on a little
bit of the history we didn't really
touch on Haze or skunk or Durbin or
anything from Jim Ortega very much but
those can be for future things
so
um I don't know you know I don't know if
this is where we want to leave it Matt
yeah this is perfect dude
so maybe this is perfect but you know if
that's the case I hope everybody enjoyed
it uh you know I don't want to make it a
forever thing
um but we could do this pretty often I
can certainly look through the questions
and maybe maybe if your question doesn't
get answered don't despair maybe it'll
give us an idea for a topic that we'll
talk about on the next one so just if we
didn't get to your question or you
didn't see it happen doesn't mean it
won't happen you can always ask it again
or who knows you might even hear us
talking about it on the next one because
it was a good question and it just
didn't pop up on the flow of things and
there's also the patreon you can go to
read your Syndicate patreon where me and
not so always shoot the [ __ ] with a
bunch of people that are a part of it
you can ask questions all the time and
whenever we have time we go in there and
pick at them and and try to break it
down that's really true too
um the uh it's on Discord uh and uh we
have a we have a server there
um you know and yeah you can you can
directly message me on there I generally
answer sometimes it takes me a minute
because you know I do do things and get
busy or whatever but Matt and I are both
pretty active on there and we do
[ __ ] a bunch and it's a lot easier
to ask away and get responses on there
so feel free to join that
um and really what all Matt and I are
trying to do at this point is just get
chunks of history and chunks of
knowledge out there to the larger public
uh this is kind of our this weed life
this is what we like to do is what we'd
like to talk about you know and
pontificate on or whatever so I hope
everybody enjoyed it
and learned a couple things and I hope
it continues
and all that so uh yeah I think that's
it I think we should cut it and we'll go
from there yeah sounds good thank you
everyone for showing up whoever Billy is
who asked that question that got the
most up votes send me a message and I'll
send you some pnw hash plant uh blue
Bond if it's unreleased you guys thanks
so much natto good time