yeah there's really good questions right
now
all right
good evening everyone welcome to Burrito
Syndicate I'm here with uh our other
host natto I don't even like calling you
a co-host because you're you're really
just the other host yeah the other host
indeed
all right so so today we're going to
cover
um uh cannabis Brewing as it was back in
the Dutch era mostly in pre-datch Era
and a little bit after and why it
matters today and how we apply that to
what we're working with today and to
start with that we're going to have to
go over some very basic breeding
um terminology just so you can
understand when we move on move forward
some of the people who haven't quite
gotten there yet can understand what
we're going to be talking about
so yeah let's kick it off dude all right
so uh we'll kick it off with you know
just to just to go over what Matt said
again we're gonna try to take you
through like some early days of reading
kind of up to what we've already done so
far which is like the the 80s Holland
era and that style and then we'll move
forward onto different stuff later
um but as far as terms go probably one
of the more
misused terms is F1 right we'll just
start there so start with F1 because
this has a lot of this is used
incorrectly in the Cannabis World daily
even by myself like I mean there's not
really another term to switch it out
with as we use it so sadly uh there's
almost no F ones
um yeah and the reason being is that
like what an F1 means is when you take
two parents that are pretty much true
breeding okay and you cross them
together
right
um let's you know that would result in
what was called an F1 where basically
all the dominant genes from both parents
will be dominant right and so you'll get
what's called hybrid Vigor because
you're not going to get any weird
recessives you're not going to get
anything like that you basically end up
with
um whatever the dominant genes are on
both sides that's what pops yeah right
so you know an example of that for
instance would be you know say something
like you know for our purposes like
skunk one by Haze or something like that
like or or skunk one by an NL or
something something along those lines
part of the reason why they use skunk
one so much was simply because it was it
was an easy way to F1 something right
well even even technically you want to
get more basic if you're doing F ones
it's like Afghani cross to tie right
sure because it has to be the definition
is two Crossing two parental line lines
with distinctively different genotypes
the most importantly which makes it more
rare so it's one of the most incorrect
terms
um because a lot of times it's used just
to say this is the first time someone's
crossed these two things and my
cushman's by Skittles F1 yeah right and
that and that and that's not right
because no those aren't like parental
stock from region of origin you know
um type of thing so F2 would be if you
take that F1 seed and you grow up males
than females and you cross them together
that's when with a line you should see
all the dominance all the recessives all
the various permutations of what's in
that line can pop up so instead of
getting like all the dominant traits
combined
you get every trait imaginable combining
in every way imaginable and most
importantly you'll see stuff that you
would not see in the F1 line stuff
cannot show up there are things that
will never show up in the F1 line that
will only show up F2 and absolutely yeah
to give it to give a really easy example
for people like in humans
um brown eyes is a dominant gene and so
in order to have blue eyes gray eyes
green eyes hazel eyes both parents have
to have that Gene and they have to line
up the two recessives
right so if one parent doesn't have the
gene it'll never pop
if that you know so exactly so anyway so
that's that's F1 F2 S1 is is a
relatively modern thing uh in terms of
people being able to do it but that's
basically it's a self one
um either through hermaphrodism
naturally or something human induced
from some kind of spray that's used in
modern terms you S1 the line it used to
be sort of frowned upon
but in uh in recent years because we
have a lot of cuts that we don't have
the line anymore we just have the
specific cut it might be the only way to
look through genetics in that line
besides
you know besides an outcross or a hybrid
of it right so it's not as good as as
doing uh because you'll get a lot of
weirdness when you end breed you could
get some undesirable things but at the
very least it gives you an idea to like
look through something like chemd or you
know Trinity or you know something
that's old that's an elite clone only
right yeah
um and then there's a thing called and
also in adding on to it was looked down
on it was only looked down on in the
Cannabis sphere in normal agriculture
selfing is the normal way to breed
uniform crops that's how they do it they
don't use filial Generations they go
through solving yes yes so that's so is
it cannabis kind of uh old wives tale as
it were and one of the one of the things
that happens with cannabis too is that
you know in modern agriculture when
you're developing a seed line you might
want a whole bunch of like butter
lettuce for instance that comes out
extremely similar and you might want a
bunch of seeds of whatever cucumbers or
zucchini or what what have you that
comes out extremely dependable and so
they will S1 that until they get you
know a very dependable very narrow
breeding uniform uniform not a lot to
look not you know that's part of the
reason why like you know and so IBL
maybe we'll shift it yeah this segues
into it because IBL is another like
super misused terms and it stands
essentially for inbred line yeah um but
and hold on hold on let me add this in
because this is the the point where most
people lose it
because it says inbred lying it does not
mean that if you line breed that you
have an IBL it is a very specific term
and it is a basically don't look at it
like okay well I crossed this F1 made
f2s that's IBL right it's line bread
it's inbred line it it basically what it
means is uniformity in a line and that's
it it's not something that can always be
achieved at F6 or f8 it only means when
you're popping those seeds you have a
homogeneous line meaning uniform like
clones so for us
um for you know for like large-scale
agriculture something like that might be
useful for cannabis it's not that useful
for the most part unless you get
something amazing because what you see
is what you get if you breed with an IBL
it'll throw what you see
it's very valuable in hemp Farms I I
know that that's one place where they're
liking seeing uniformity in self-blinds
because they just it's it's more
vigorous it's faster they can pop all
those seeds and if they come out uniform
that's even more that you it takes the
the cloning out of the you know out of
the picture and stuff so in in hemp I
can see that being more useful but in
modern cannabis people want to find that
that keeper
yeah they want they want a little bit of
variety so there's New Paths if for a
breeder for somebody like you know um
for a breeder or anything like that and
uh all that
getting something where like there's
nowhere to go within the gene pool
itself because it's an IBL and it
already is what it is the traits you see
are the traits you get yeah unless you
really want to add those traits to
another line specifically there's not a
lot of room for places to go
yeah because it's already been all that
variety has been bred out of it yeah so
that that's another thing with breeding
where it's like a lot of breeding
depends on what your goals are yeah you
know um depends on goals some people
might want consistency some people might
want like the same three to six phenos
to regularly pop some people might want
to breed an IBL some people might want
to do an open pollination or an F2 and
have the widest possible
gene pool to hunt through depending on
what your what your goals are you're
trying to find like a random Elite
cutting to hold on to are you trying to
actually breed a line like Matt was
saying where you could like put it in a
hemp field and start thousands of seeds
and get the same consistent you know
size Bush type of thing
so that's kind of the thing
um so uh we have is in Cross incross is
the last one we have left so in Cross is
the last one so can this is another
weird term because uh in um we call it a
BX
right yes
um but in most other breeding they call
it a BC a back cross is actually like
the technical term that you would use
but for for most cannabis people they're
mostly familiar with a BX and a BX is
simply
you take a cut
um you know and you use an outside
pollen donor uh to make a male line of
it and then you take the children of
that and you back cross it onto the
original female so we've talked about on
the previous on the previous podcast we
talked about how
um you know uh you know Neville used
um Seattle Greg's nl1
and uh you know would use that as a
pollen donor and would back cross to
make a pure hash plant to make a pure
big bud to make a pure nor uh Hawaiian
Indica that type of thing uh JJ from Top
Dog you know he took uh an Afghani one
and used that to cross into
um chemd and did that a few times and
made double dog and Trace dog and so on
and so forth so that's basically what a
BX is is you find a pollen donor and you
cross it to a clone only for the most
part and then you back crop you keep
back Crossing so on and so forth so
those are kind of like the lockdown
single traits when it's back Crossing
and then IX is going to be similar to a
BX but going further down the line and
Crossing back to a previous generation
so like maybe an F6 cross to an F1 of
the same line that would be an in Cross
because you're Crossing in between the
same line
but sure yeah so that it is essentially
still a back cross though so those yeah
those things are and and it's only it's
only a BX or a BC if you back cross it
to the exact same parent exactly that's
super important cutting like if you for
instance had like a line of chemd for
instance and you and you crossed your
children of that to a different chemd
parent it wouldn't be a BX yeah it has
to go directly back to the original
genetic
stock that started the process otherwise
it's it's not a BX so
um those are some basic terms I think
that covers like most yeah cannabis
people deal with and so we we thought
about like
um I don't know exactly you know how
much time we'll spend on each specific
topic but we thought about like it might
be interesting to
um
we thought it might be interesting to
talk about how we got here as far as
breeding techniques yeah I see in the
comments you know where we're going we
have to know where we came from I think
yeah exactly so
um you know the the easiest way you know
we won't we could spend an enormous
amount of time on how cannabis moved
around places
um but you know the basic premise is
that for most of the like what we
consider to be like the land race
regions right when people were starting
to get Imports into America they were
coming from Mexico
uh Colombia Panama Jamaica uh Thailand
Cambodia Laos
um you know those type of places uh and
they were importing seeded weed right
and so how do those Farmers how did
those farmers get to the point where
they were growing tons of cannabis and
exporting it to our region right
well basically it's at some point in the
past we don't need to spend a super
amount of time on this but you know
somewhere humans figured out that THC
had cool effects yeah they get [ __ ] up
you know by by a lot of by a lot of
people you know um you know humans
started interacting with plants and the
nature around them they started figuring
out which ones were good to eat which
ones were good for health which ones did
this which ones did that and so on a
certain level there was a point where
um people figured out that you know
marijuana that you know the wild
marijuana strains had some effects
whether it was like hand rubbed Shiraz
uh making hashish by rubbing Buds and
then getting it on their hands and then
rubbing it off and smoking it or
consuming it or various aspects like
that people started to sort out that
this was a useful plant
right yeah and so like just every other
kind of useful plant from corn to
watermelons to anything else people
started messing with it to get more of
what they wanted yeah right and so we
what we think is is we think as as you
go from Wild populations right that um
that uh started that humans started
interacting with to planted populations
of cannabis by humans what we assume is
the traditional method is that people
would go out into these fields and they
would pick uh females that they like the
smell they like the structure they liked
whatever it was about it maybe they
liked it it had increased THC compared
to its neighbors sure and they would
keep those plants and then therefore
next year they would plant a bunch of
seeds from their favorite females yeah
right and so then over time year after
year generation after generation humans
started slowly improving their local
gene pool
and breeding it towards things they
wanted yeah maybe it was Terps back then
although they obviously wouldn't have
called it that Aromas effects weight you
know finished who knows different
Farmers I'm sure had vastly different
things but sure you know Farmers back
then seed collecting was part of the the
way they grew everything so you picked
your favorite plants they were seeded
and you grew that next year and then
over time uh humans started having a
massive impact on what kind of you know
what kind of plants were being grown
because they'd done this selection over
time over time over time and that pretty
much I think happened
um virtually everywhere uh anywhere that
cannabis was endemic sure yeah I mean
it's it's kind of not well known but
just really quickly they think that
cannabis sort of started in the Highland
areas around China Tibetan Plateau
um you know that kind of region it went
down into India it went down into
Pakistan and Afghanistan and about 2 700
years ago we have verifiable evidence
that the scythians who were like Central
Steppy people were using it in their
culture that it was being used in the
very Northern parts of Afghanistan and
in certain parts of the caucus mountains
and that also we've they found THC
burned in temples about 60 miles south
of Jerusalem about 2700 years ago
so right so there's so there's a
situation where obviously like we have
we don't know how long ago it started
but China and uh Tibet and the caucus
mountains and where Israel is right now
are obviously pretty far far apart from
each other especially from the way that
people got around at the time which was
you know camels horses donkeys Etc right
so it is so smoking and consuming either
hash or cannabis is at least 3 000 years
old documented in multiple spots yeah
probably goes back uh significantly
farther than that we just haven't found
absolute evidence that it occurred
sure um and so you know then you have
then you have a scenario in which
um so that's kind of how it starts start
starts up in Tibet and China area it
comes down into Pakistan India
Afghanistan it starts going into Iran
and the Middle East then it goes down
into uh into Africa
right yeah
um in Russia it turns into what becomes
known as ruderalis uh and um
so so then so then there's uh you know
the the weird part is the Americas right
is how it got to America uh it seems
like
um although this isn't 100 verified but
it seems like that most of the stuff
that ended up in America came along with
the Conquistadors and then later the
slave trade
uh it seems like a bunch of hemp hemp
was obviously used for most rope most
sales uh it was Sailors brought it with
them
um everywhere because it was like if you
got Shipwrecked or something you might
need to grow a crop of hemp to turn it
into sales or rope again so you could
get off your island or wherever you were
um so you know uh hemp was hemp was
critical to that era's
um trade and so it was kind of brought
everywhere so it seems like uh to Brazil
to the Caribbean to Mexico when they um
when they start talking about that kind
of thing genetically most cannabis from
those regions ties back to some kind of
African yeah right another weird thing
and uh there's there's not a lot of
evidence to back this up but the strange
thing is is when
they did genetic work on Panamanian and
Colombian
that has to tie back to uh
um to Southeast Asia
yeah okay which is weird and so I only
have like one little tidbit on that and
it has nothing to do with cannabis
necessarily but obviously at some point
um if that if it's true in the genetics
of Panama and Colombia tie back to more
southeast Asia region then somehow it
had to get from there to to from
Southeast Asia to the Western half of
South America right yeah and so there's
essentially two options either it
happened once the Spanish and others
started trading with the East uh after
the conquests or there's another
interesting thing where there's Pacific
Islanders
and some others that they've done
genetic testing on in Southeast Asia and
some of these islands where they have
discovered pre-columbian
um Indian people's DNA
uh in these Pacific Islanders from about
11 or 1200 A.D oh wow so we know for a
fact because they interbred they had
babies with them they implanted some of
their DNA from
pre-columbian peoples into Pacific
Islanders and so we know for a fact that
hundreds of years three four hundred
years perhaps before uh Columbus sailed
and discovered and rediscovered uh the
Caribbean and Americas
um there was some kind of trade or at
least inner relationships between the
Pacific Islanders and the Panamanian and
Colombian peoples
um and we know if people are [ __ ]
they're probably smoking yeah and and
since we know that that happens was
absolutely was absolutely required for
sailing uh it makes sense that it
theoretically could have been required
for sailing
um back then and they they traded some
of these pre-columbian indigenous
peoples that were sailing out to the
Pacific Islands
um they traded them some seeds and the
seeds would be necessary on both ports
if they're going both places and so
that's not proof we have guaranteed
proof that they were interbreeding an
1100 A.D because the way DNA and
genetics works so we know that there was
trade ongoing
um we don't know exactly when but it
does seem like Colombian and Panamanian
tie in somehow to the southeast Asia
portion of the gene pool not the African
where Mexican Jamaican the island weed
uh the stuff that's on the Eastern side
of South America that all seems to come
from African origins search makes sense
because there wasn't just a mammoth
amount of trade both slave and otherwise
coming over from all portions of Africa
over to the new world yeah right and so
we know some of it was introduced then
it's entirely possible that that some of
it was introduced earlier I mean you
know some of this some of this stuff is
not poorly poorly you know documents
poorly documented for lack of a better
term uh you know the Conquistadors
burned most of the writings of the
Mayans and the Aztecs and the other
peoples because they thought they were
devil works so most of their knowledge
was sort of lost so who knows maybe they
even had it down uh and we just don't
know so you fast forward again and you
have these various people in these
various regions that are improving their
own genetic stock the people in Thailand
the people in Lao the people in Mexico
the people in Colombia they're growing
their stock they are working with what
them and other local farmers in their
area have access to right and they're
breeding it every year and that's where
all of these varietals kind of came from
obviously it was all seeded weed
um you know there was uh you know and
there was two distinct cultures going on
too right maybe we should mention this
so in the North Indian Pakistan and
Afghanistan regions it was primarily a
hashish culture so they viewed the plant
as essentially I don't want to say the
beater it's garbage but they viewed it
as a way to get a hold of the trichomes
yeah whether they did hand rub like I
was talking about or whether they did
dry sift or whatever method they used to
extract it
they thought that the proper use of
cannabis was to turn it into hash yeah
um you know and so but then you go to
Lao or Cambodia or Thailand or Mexico or
Colombia these kind of places they
smoked flour
so you had some groups breeding for
specific basically hash plants right and
then you had some groups breeding for
smokable flower
yeah
right and those were the kind of those
were the kind of selections that people
were making back then right
and then you know uh obviously like
America's founded on capitalistic
principles right and so if there's a
demand somewhere and there's a supply
somewhere else Adam Smith says that the
Invisible Hand should come along and get
the supply from where it is to where the
demand is right so you have all these
regions that we've talked about have
been probably improving their crops a
year to year they're saving their best
seed like they do with their food crops
they're slowly improving their genetic
lines but there's really not a lot of
interaction between them and other
groups they're kind of growing what's
available in their area except except
for the one thing we we had talked about
I believe it's referenced in Rob Clark's
hashish book except in Afghanistan where
they were importing they had learned the
trade of uh of of hand rubbing and hash
collecting via the route from India so
most of the stuff during that time they
were importing Indian uh more sativity
tight narrow Leaf varieties to
Afghanistan because that's what the
Indians were using to make their hash
and they weren't using their afghanis in
their fields yet they they weren't using
those to get the trichomes collect and
make the hash they were actually using
Indian sativas during that time and it
wasn't until more modern uh the past
1950 when they started using and
collecting their own varieties so maybe
a better way to more accurate way to
State it would just say that like we
can't discount that there was some
Regional trading going on sure right
between say you know India Pakistan
Afghanistan they're all connected to one
another you can kind of go back and
forth
there could be Panamanian and Colombian
going back and forth there could be some
Caribbean exchanges but in general there
wasn't Caribbean trading with Thailand
yeah with Afghanistan there wasn't like
different regions of the world the
regions themselves mixed a bit you know
it's obviously not written down so it's
really hard to determine with any kind
of factual basis how it exactly occurred
um but you have all these over all
hundreds of years by the time that like
America gets involved you have all these
uh weed cultures
that have developed around the world
some of them are hash cultures some of
them are smokeable flower cultures so
obviously they made different decisions
on their strains based on
uh you know whether they wanted to smoke
flour or whether they wanted to to
create a hash plant sure um and you know
prohibition was was fully going on in
America and
um you know invisible hand comes in and
there's a bunch of people in America
that want to smoke pot
musicians jazz artists
um hippies uh counterculture beatnix
various various types of people get
introduced to it most likely Mota uh
probably most people's first experiences
with it were probably Mexican
coming into the country
there was a lot of you know back and
flow over the Border uh with Mexican
like you know Farm working and stuff
like that they probably brought it with
them there's definitely records of of
famous jazz people smoking it in the 20s
and 30s looking at jazz cabbage yeah you
know I mean obviously it was it was a
big enough issue that uh they decided to
do some crazy Prohibition in the late
1930s
um up till that point and uh so
so then you have a situation where you
start hitting like what matters to most
people I think uh with with this way
that we've kind of brought ourselves to
here is that various entrepreneurs
decided to start sourcing weed from
various countries that grow weed and
figure out a way to get it into America
and sell it for a high dollar to
American people and the difference in
profit between buying it from a Thai
farmer to selling it to a guy that lives
in Venice Beach was extremely high yeah
so there was a lot of economic incentive
for these people to start figuring out
ways to smuggle it into the country and
and feed the demand
right yes and so uh sadly uh one thing
that was so we start getting Imports
right we start getting
we start getting Imports and we start
getting things from uh Panama people
start smuggling from Panama and Colombia
people certainly start smuggling from
Jamaica and other Caribbean islands
Mexico Hawaii
[Music]
um you know Asia there's some pretty
famous Smugglers that were working in
Thailand and Cambodia and Lao in the 60s
and they start you know all the famous
stuff you've heard about uh Colombian
gold Panama Red Thai sticks every every
um I'm sure Matt can think of some
others there's a bunch of them
Jamaican Lambs bread uh you know Holly
from from you know Mexican
um you know Mexican stuff was generally
named by region you had Michoacan you
had oaxacan you had this you had Baron
yeah you had various things and that's
kind of like those were the first names
that you would get
um you know the very first names of weed
was like where it's from
and maybe some nickname like maybe maybe
then maybe they dried Colombian gold
into a brownish gold color and then
there was Panamanian red and it had red
hair or there was this and you know they
wrapped they wrapped in Thailand they
wrapped the loose buds around sticks to
make it like a more these go from like a
super leafy hermaphroditic loose flowers
and they'd pack them tight to make it
into something and you get Thai stick
and so all the original names they're
not really strain names they're like
this is where it's from
and this is its nickname that we gave to
it from where it's from possibly a color
or smell or some other attribute yeah
yeah you know or rhyme
yeah right Maui Wowie yeah exactly they
guaranteed picked it because it rhymed
yep that was that's the reason right and
so you know
um and so that's when so that's when
like the the breeding that everybody is
familiar with kind of starts
yeah right you've got all this seeded
weed coming into America from all these
regions I named southeast Asia the
Caribbean uh Mexico America uh you know
South America that type of thing and as
you know I mean for the younger cats out
there you know I used to sit there with
my head down and a tray at an angle and
you would break your weed up here
right and then that allowed all the
seeds to roll down the tray and collect
at the bottom lip of the tray as you
broke up all your herb right and then
you'd have a bunch of fluffed up herb
for a bowl or a bong or rolling a joint
or something along those lines right
um and so everybody got free seeds
right free seeds we weren't really too
much we weren't really too much of a
hash culture and that's part of the
reason why and then also hash is is
trichomes separated from the flower and
and the such so everything that was
coming into America at first was various
kinds of sativas yes
because the sativas were the buds you
know yeah and if you were getting
imported Afghan Afghani Indica hash you
were getting blocks of hash yeah you
weren't getting Afghani Bud like that
important yeah it didn't come with free
seats yeah yeah there's no seats no
there was sometimes the random seed
didn't break a half stamp there the
random button I mean there's a famous
actually uh there's some serious debate
in Europe over uh over there's two camps
basically on the on the White Widow Camp
there's uh you know uh just so and the
only reason why I bring that up is
because there's a guy over there ingmar
uh and one of the one of the stories
about how white widow happened is like
the founding part of white widow is he
was breaking up a block of imported hash
and some seeds fell out yeah and he got
an original Afghan from some region out
of that block of seats yeah so it was
rare
um
you know there was some hash being
imported into America but like I said
you know it uh it didn't come with free
seats yeah where um there was no
seedless in any of these other regions
so all the sativas that we were
importing came with 3C
yes and that free seed is the start of
every famous breeder you ever heard of
Journey yes for the most for the most
yeah it really is yeah it is so people
start smoking weed right people start
liking the weed
and then some people have get the idea I
have these seeds I wonder what would
happen if I started growing my own weed
right and then there's places uh some of
them are pretty famous the Emerald
Triangle Trinity County Humboldt County
Mendocino County where I live
um the Central Coast San Francisco uh
Santa Cruz area of Bakersfield yeah of
California
legendarily you know basically anywhere
where it was mountainous smoked
people weren't going to find it
and the climate was cool I'm not saying
people weren't doing it in other parts
of the country because of course they
were but
uh you know wherever people could start
to get away with it with their with
their Imports they start growing it yeah
and meccas were built and Mecca's will
build and then the only reason why I
brought up those regions is because
enough people in those regions all
decided to start doing it that it
started the beginnings of American
growing culture sure right if you're
growing in Upstate New York or Oklahoma
or Florida or some [ __ ]
um you're probably trying to keep it
pretty small yeah you know there was
definitely some stuff with hippies and
Santa Cruz and Mendocino County and
Central Coast and different areas that
um they were a little bit more open with
each other uh and so there was a little
bit more trading going on and a little
bit more of a culture started to develop
whereas some of the other more harsh
police state regions of the United
States uh that were a lot more populated
it was a lot more secretive and you know
circles were even smaller right sure so
you know people start growing seed
probably with varying success and
they start discovering stuff
right they start discovering that when
you grow Thai and you grow Colombian boy
is it hard to finish in America yeah
very you know the stuff wants to go till
December or January or whether it
doesn't go that long
people start having issues with getting
you know because if you could grow weed
from the seed then you could get free
weed yeah and you wouldn't have to be
buying it what does this free weed look
like when it hasn't been compressed and
bailed and shipped from you know
International locations what would it be
like if you got it fresh so yeah the
initial success for people was
um you know people people could get the
Mexicans to finish
because the Mexicans typically were
farther away from the equator and they
were a little shorter right and they had
significant struggles getting the
Colombian and the Panama and the and the
ties and the different stuff like that
to finish right yeah so this this is
where people start to get the idea of
like I got some Thai stick or I got some
Colombian gold and I got some oaxacan
right and what happens if I grow them up
and I cross them
yeah that's that's basically the start
of American breeding that's the that's
the the honest to God that's the start
of how everybody in America started
breeding things right and I'm not going
to say America is unique but it is rare
in the sense that America is the plate
or one of the places where for the first
time in hundreds of years people started
Crossing these wildly different Gene
pools from these different regions
together
yes
right um I think I think the way you put
it the other night and I wrote it down
because it was it was worded very well
whoever and wherever the weed was
becoming imported the most that's where
the weed was Blended together the first
time right and that's that's well put
and so you know
um and so there's so so yeah so
basically
um you know there's uh you know there's
some pretty famous stuff that started
happening then
um people started getting these
different these different things they
started breeding them together
um they started experimenting with stuff
um in the San Francisco Bay area and in
Santa Cruz and stuff like what became
known as Hayes started which according
to Sam and others was essentially
Colombian by Colombian
um
you know and uh but you needed a
greenhouse
you needed you they figured with some of
these some of these land races you
needed to grow it in a mild climate
which the central coast and uh the Bay
Area definitely had and you needed you
needed some way to protect it from the
weather and give it maybe some heat or
some whatever and and
finish it right so they start Crossing
things yeah one of the famous people
that started Crossing things is a guy
named Rob Clark right yes uh Rob has
some very famous stuff that he did he
started Crossing Colombians and Mexicans
uh because Mexicans finished quite
faster and so he was trying to get the
qualities of the two and get something
that would finish in California
yeah right
and so they start breeding obviously Sam
Skunk Man is breeding obviously there's
other various people that are popping
and doing all kinds of stuff a lot of
the the oldest and most legendary names
that we know
are from this era
sure from this like pioneer take some
Thai take some Cambodian cross them
together cross it with some Colombian
cross it with some Mexican cross it with
some this cross some Jamaican buy this
you know trade some seeds with your
friend
um and you know uh so that's kind of
like the start of like uh cannabis
growing in America
yes on any kind of scale and so even
when I started in the early 90s
um I still have them some over there
there's I got like three books that I
bought uh knowledge was extremely
limited there was no internet there was
no forums there was no forums to confuse
you yeah no and so and so even for me in
the 90s think about how difficult it
must have been
um for the people in the 70s that had
even less knowledge oh I'm sure because
one of the things I'll hold it up right
now one of the things that taught me
breeding
was this
the Bible this is the Bible uh Rob Clark
took his experience with growing a bunch
of weed and breeding a bunch of weed and
he figured out how marijuana grows how
it breeds how it triggers how all the
different traits the different traits
and he wrote this I mean that's right he
wrote sort of a Bible yeah right he
wrote a basic Bible so when I started
out I was able to buy this Bible
when I got interested in weed and I was
able to read this book over and over and
over again and it taught me a ton about
how to grow cannabis yeah I'm sure Matt
had the same experience most readers
most breeders that get curious about
breeding
um you've read Rob Clark's book yeah if
you hear a seed maker and you actually
are passionate and want to learn and
make things better you almost everyone
eventually runs into Rob Clark's work
and eventually I think with the breeder
Syndicate thing one of the plans is to
do for patreon a course based on uh
cannabis Evolution and ethnobotany uh
Rob Clark gave us his permission to use
that for a course so I thought that
would be pretty cool to do yeah and so
he I mean I don't need to go through all
of it but he started talking about the
differences in latitude and you know
finish times and the differences in the
various kinds of cannabis and regions
and what to expect from them how to make
seed how to make seed mature like really
like and so you know he deserves an
enormous amount of credit sure uh
because I'm sure there was an enormous
amount of fuckups
yeah in order to learn reading when
breeding is 90 [ __ ] ups there was uh
there was a there was a but you know
they had to learn all that and they had
they had to put that down into some kind
of information base and I'm sure his
journey to learn was significantly
harder
uh than the people that came after it oh
I'm sure because there was no books for
him to buy exactly right I mean I don't
think there was any cannabis books in
the 60s and you know um there was not
breeding I mean in the 70s it sort of
exploded a little bit
um Steve Murphy uh who we've talked
about Murphy Stevens Murphy Stevens it
was his pen name but you know the
gentleman that gave the Afghani seeds to
uh Seattle uh Greg uh which he used to
to create what we know as Northern
Lights uh he wrote some I think like by
73 74-ish he had some books out uh Mel
Frank and Ed Rosenthal started
contributing some stuff uh there was uh
since Mella tips
um there was High Times
uh there was various other magazine
there's all kinds yeah there was all
kinds of things so people started the
70s is where all of a sudden there
starts to be like um information coming
out that people can access and they
don't have to like learn from scratch
or what their neighbor knows or what
their buddy that got them into it knows
yeah right and uh and so and so you know
Rob uh Rob did things like Rob crossed
Colombian and Mexican
right Robin and Sam scope man are
friends you know skunk one is
Afghan by Colombian Mexican yep you know
they start blending things
um longer things with shorter things
they start playing they start looking to
see can I get the traits of this Mexican
with the traits of this Colombian can I
get this tie to stop herming and not
take seven months yeah I uh can I this
it's a bad structure to the tie
different structure all that type of
stuff and so you know and then
um so people so people start
um
uh Crossing these things right and so
maybe this is a good time so that that's
what's really happening in the I don't
know exactly when it started happening
in the 60s
um but it definitely was happening in
the 60s to some degree it accelerated
greatly in the 70s one second I'm just
gonna chime in um Greg actually said I
studied Luther Burbank and then bought
all of Rob's books Burbank worked with
cannabis in California yeah so there you
go even even somebody like Greg who's I
consider to be in a very early Pioneer
oh yeah doing a lot of stuff uh Rob's
work helped him you know
um and so that's kind of and that's
that's also a theme that I'd like to say
uh you know right now is that and this
remains true no matter what episode
we're gonna chat about is that every
single breeder out there stands on the
shoulders of the people that came before
them whether it's whether it's the seeds
and the genetics they have access to
whether it's the forums or books or
Knowledge from older cats there was a
wave of pioneers that really figured it
out and that every generation after that
every Group after that they got to take
their work in genetics and improve it or
mess it up you know as the case maybe it
was it depending on your opinion right
yeah but they also got a bunch of
knowledge by the time a lot of you guys
on this that are listening got into it
there was probably forums you could go
there was breeding forums I mean you go
on the breeding Forum of overgrow and
there's Sam Skunk Man and Chimera and
people that have a lot of knowledge you
start reading that
um and you know the internet books
started putting the knowledge out there
in a way for people to really access
which really sped up the time it took
you know
um you know on uh I mean on a previous
interview uh that you know Greg's on
this when when Matt interviewed Greg I
mean Greg spoke about you know they got
some Afghan beans uh that were extremely
limited from uh Steve Murphy and they
crossed them to themselves and then they
basically crossed them with every sativa
they knew of yeah Hawaiians Colombians
ties you know lots of Mexicans lots of
Mexicans lots of this lots of that they
were just everybody was just playing
around with and that's the other part
that people need to know right is that
nobody knew what an Afghan by a Mexican
would look like
yeah it hadn't happened not yet we knew
what Colombian by Mexican would look
like because that hadn't happened either
so a lot of these Pioneers they're
taking you know Rob's like I wonder if I
took Colombian and Mexican and crossed
it what does that look like yeah you
know and then maybe later on when skunk
one is born Sam is like hey I got access
to some Afghans Let's cross this Afghan
into your skunk into your you know your
Colombian Mexican maybe that'll shorten
it up even earlier and it'll be done in
October
and this and I think this is a good
segue into talking about how breeding
for uh just to see what happens
um turned into breeding for traits as
they learn these traits as they as they
saw you know this one's purple this one
smells like watermelon this one smells
like cereal they started learning well
if we combine these traits you know
let's let's see if we can get this trait
to pop out if we cross this and this and
they started going and actually having a
purpose for breeding uh with cannabis
and finding out that there were these
traits that they could follow long
flowering short flowering colors smell
taste hi all of it and it went from
seeing what can happen to a real purpose
a real purpose yes and so I think
probably the two traits in the beginning
the people were after was I like the way
this weed tastes and smokes
it won't finish where I live yeah how do
I get it to finish where I live because
a lot of this stuff like Panamanian uh
Colombian the Southeast Asian stuff is
all very near the equator takes a long
time uh America is not particularly near
the equator
um you know so they had to figure out
how do I blend stuff to get the stuff I
like and be able to grow it in my region
yeah right and obviously there's a big
Financial incentive in that too right
because you don't have to import it it
doesn't have to come through customs and
that's kind of where green Bud was born
yes
right uh you know the way that most of
these traditional cultures they didn't
have air-conditioned dry rooms or
anything like that a lot of them dried
hanging in the woods a lot of them dried
in the Sun a lot of them dried it and
then
key load it right and then it begins to
ferment and it gets wrapped up in
plastic for weeks or months and then
shipped for some period of time you know
if you were lucky maybe you got some
green Mexican that was only lightly
compressed that they figured out some
way to get it across the border without
smushing it into a block that you could
cut with a knife uh yeah you could
actually like break it up into actual
buds instead of it just being like a a
flat Mass
um you know and so that's where you know
great Steve Murphy was breeding in the
70s uh Greg and his whole Pacific
Northwest crew
um the you know most people in
California were breeding either outdoor
or in greenhouses yes
uh the indoor wave was still and maybe
this is a good segue
um for a second I printed out this thing
and uh you can't really see it so I'm
just gonna read it because it's really
dark this is a this is a Seed Catalog
um
you know uh from 1981 it's tied into Sam
and his crew we assume
um but it lists uh strains in order of
of when they matured October November
and December and it lists like what so
it gives you a snapshot of what people
were actually working with right yeah
and uh
so I'll read it to you in October
you had Afghani one Afghani two Afghani
two purple skunk one skunk two
yep that's all they list five things
before that finished before Halloween
yeah the faster finishing right then you
have November right
Nepali Malawi Nepali Afghani Malawi
Nepali early Haze by Afghani yeah and
those are done hopefully by Thanksgiving
yep and then here comes the motherload
of everything and I'll say on this list
it says all of the above can be grown
outside in most years in the SF Bay Area
and that's the October and the November
stuff right and then below it it says
all below require a greenhouse to finish
in the San Francisco Bay Area yeah and
now you've got South Indian one two
three original Haze one to four burning
bush Nepali Hayes Hayes Nepali Nepali
hey South Indian early Haze South Indian
Haze South Indian Thai hey South Indian
South African Haze burning bush by
Nepali burning bush by South Hayes uh by
South Indian Hayes and then you even
have one category matures in January
extra late New Year's Haze yeah I bet so
maybe when people are listening to that
right yeah and uh you're uh you're
realizing that oh my God everything that
they're mentioning other than afghanian
skunk I've never had
yeah I don't have Afghan I don't I don't
I don't Malawi and Nepali and
Hayes Thai Nepali and this and that and
everything else
um
there's a bunch of um there's a bunch of
stuff like that so that gives you like a
snapshot of like these are what the
Breeders back then were crossing to each
other yep
right which is super different okay and
so you know
um maybe we can mention this even though
it kind of like it fits in but it kind
of doesn't but the reason why we're
talking about all this stuff is that
basically like every 10 years in my
opinion cannabis reinvents itself yes
absolutely and what was common becomes
uncommon or rare yeah and then you go 20
years from that point and what becomes
uncommon or rare becomes like impossible
yeah you know uh Matt and I were
recently looking at somebody's uh
freezer collection that they had been
gifted it was a big collection it was
super impressive it was really exciting
to look through and most of it was from
08 to 2012. yeah and I was electing
heavily during that time and that so
that was Matt's kind of era when he was
really collecting a ton and stuff and
and it's amazing that it's it's only 10
to 13 14 years later and 98 of that
stuff that's on the list you couldn't
buy today if you wanted to yeah and and
you'd be lucky to find a reproduction if
you were lucky you'd be lucky to find a
reproduction you know and there's some
famous people on there like you know a
bunch of stuff that people found Fire OG
Rascal work
um yeah tons of awesome [ __ ] back then
too and and nowadays like I I even still
look out for like white Urkel and white
master and a few things when I see them
in lists but they're they're not common
and he was selling tons of those packs
back then you know he was killing it
still probably is so all this stuff that
we're talking about right is that you
know
um what's common in this in the 60s and
70s becomes uncommon in the 80s almost
unheard of in the 90s a unicorn by by
today and that just keeps happening
right every every 10 or 15 years uh what
you used to be able to get easy access
to become super hard to find right sure
but then every generation those 10 or 15
years they're building on certain things
like I mentioned that list there's a
series of afghanis that made it over to
Neville and sssc there's this there's
hazes there's scums there's different
things that happened in that in that era
that survived sure right but most of the
stuff on that list you've never smoked
yeah I've never smoked you know I've
never smoked burning bush by Nepali by
salary bush is I don't I've never seen
it I've heard it was made I've heard
I've heard it was a pre-pre to Haze you
know it was an early you know but but
you know these names South Indian stuff
like that
um you know they they just didn't they
just that but that's what they were
growing
so all these guys what that shows you is
that all these guys
um
all these guys were basically breeding
sativas yeah
right that's the majority of that list
was some sativas there's a couple
afghanis even skunk one was 75 sativa
yeah it was a blend of Mexican Colombian
and a little bit of Afghan
so it was still even heavily influenced
right
um and so Sam Skunk Man became very
famous in that era that's where you know
he he says he started breeding his skunk
one in 1975.
um you know he bred it for eight or ten
years before he brought it to uh
California or brought it from California
to Amsterdam uh Mel Frank was working
with an afghan that got named Afghani
one that he got from another Bay Area
breeder uh who had gotten some Afghani
seeds
um he got some Durban Poison that he was
working in the 70s they were breeding
some other stuff like that Rob Clark was
obviously busy
um in uh you know Seattle Greg's neck of
the woods they had somehow come across
some Afghan and they were also blending
in
um some you know all the various sativas
that people had then
in Hawaii you know people call stuff
Hawaiian but there obviously is no
Hawaiian yeah uh 98 of the species uh on
Hawaii are not native
um because it's an island in the middle
of nowhere uh that created by a volcano
yeah but people started bringing
Colombian it's very tropical people
started bringing Thai and Colombian and
Afghans and Mexicans there and blending
them and growing them on the islands and
then they became known as Hawaiian
yep you know even though there are
there's no Hawaiian genetics there's a
blending of sativas
maybe with a touch Afghan right we're
about 55 minutes in so I'm going to do a
short intermission for a commercial real
quick quick plug for our uh everybody if
you're if you're enjoying it uh we have
our patreon shop up or we have our
merchandise shop up and we have our
patreon uh throughout the week we
discuss a lot of this stuff in Discord
what we're going to be talking about
we've got a lot of topics answer
questions there and we have a pretty
[ __ ] awesome Community for me there
so go to our patreon Brady Street or
Syndicate if you want to participate and
again merch we got hats hoodies shirts
You Name It We got it now it's all up in
the I don't know maybe someone can put
the link in here uh Morgan if you can
put the link in there for everyone to
see
um so we got the merch up we got the
patreon and I think that uh oh go check
out
yeah that's okay go check out Speak Easy
um uh most of us sell seeds on there uh
an amazing amazing group to work with
for me done we're
amazing stuff for me so yeah
um I think that's all the commercials
we've got
this has been you know it kind of like
uh took a while but yeah it kind of
walked people through sort of like and
now we're starting to enter this point
where
um we'll talk we'll talk a little bit
more about how the shift happened and
then we'll and then we'll answer some
questions
right because we got some good questions
this week so we might as well chat at
that so fast forward a bit people are
doing all the stuff in the 70s and
um you know in the uh in the late 70s uh
things were really blowing up people
were doing all kinds of stuff together
um in very in these various regions I
was talking about it was really
advancing uh then Carter loses the
election
Reagan gets uh Reagan gets involved and
the War on Drugs gets ramped up and the
world goes to [ __ ] for from the from
where it had been the penalties are yeah
they start putting more money into it
and uh they start flying
they start taking helicopters and they
start flying in Hawaii they start flying
in Mendocino County they start flying in
the Central Valley and some of this
stuff rep and so what that does is that
all of a sudden all these guys are
growing all this weed and they're
growing it in the mountain regions and
they're growing it in valleys and stuff
like that and they're not too concerned
because nobody's looking for them and
then also there's a helicopter flying
overhead sure and they got a big field
that nobody's ever bothered with before
and they get in trouble right so
pressure starts happening right
so you know they start hunting it uh
people start getting in trouble and then
this is when so we mentioned before
Steve Murphy's book
um and stuff like that but
people were on the What's called the
hippie hashish Trail where people were
traveling to Nepal people were traveling
to India people were traveling to the
Hindu Kush mountains they were meeting
up with tribal you know people and stuff
like that and so there was some small
amount of Afghan seeds and indicas that
started making its way into America yeah
mostly only to breeder circles certainly
not to Consumers the way every bag was
every sack of weed you bought had a
bunch of seeds in it for free but they
started trickling in smuggling style to
Trinity Humboldt Mendocino to the Bay
Area to various other places
um you know in in Steve Murphy's book
you see some broadleaf Afghans in 74. uh
obviously uh you know uh you know
Seattle Greg was working with some of
this stuff
um and so the the big advantage in the
beginning to people was that you start
Crossing these Afghans into some of
these sativas and now maybe you're
getting stuff that's finishing you know
the more heavy Afghan you select you're
finishing in September or October
sure and and one second I just want to
make sure everybody's really paying
close attention to this part because I
found one of the biggest uh myths in
cannabis is that afghanis existed in our
culture you know just as long as sativas
and as long as we've been smoking broad
or uh narrow Leafs you know people
didn't know that afghanis came as a late
entry so when you see a lot of these
people making claims about 60s afghanis
and 50s afghanis it's very easy to
Discount with history
so while seed of sativas like we said
before were getting imported by the
literal ton with every bag of weed you
bought you got seeds of seeds and the
the Indica stuff was being brought back
by Smugglers and what I would imagine
would be relatively small amounts uh you
know in his interview uh you know Greg
told you that he got a whopping four
Afghan seeds yeah whopping a whopping
four you know
um and the biggest problem that you know
you grow in Afghanistan and you and you
grow in the Hindu Kush mountains it's
obviously colder there and it's
extremely dry so people start growing
them in America
and they rot yeah the sativas were grown
in tropical much more humid regions they
had a lot of genetic resistance to rot
and so a lot of the things that people
were trying to figure out is they can
grow these Afghans and they're like oh
my God it's an amazing beautiful Frosty
crazy looking weed yeah and it's not
done and you get some weather and all of
a sudden it rots on and it has a totally
different High than a lot of people are
used to yeah people go from an up
energetic kind of Zippy High somewhat
psychedelic wow this that indicas come
with much more couch lock much more
heaviness much more limitations so a lot
of the early smokers didn't like indica
yeah it clashed so hard with what they
were used to as Buds and and the effect
they weren't super into it but from a
Grower's perspective since I read all
that stuff you know going from November
December Harvest to September October
Harvest when you have police pressure
becomes extremely important yeah
right
um
and so you know I maybe we should talk
very briefly
um because it's a pretty simple subject
but when I moved to Mendo in the late
90s people still mostly Grew From seed
outside
and the traditional way that you grew
from seed was that you would grow some
seed you would pick your males you would
take your males to like a kind of a
darker part of your Hill somewhere and
you would stash them away from your
females you would grow your females in
some patches right and then you'd
collect pollen and you'd go take this
pollen from all your males and you'd
brush it on some of the lower branches
of your favorite females from that year
yeah and I believe that's how the vast
majority of breeding occurred even when
you look at like Rob Clark's book he
talks about like putting like a paper
bag paper bags the paper bag with a with
a tie over specific branches and putting
one up on the bag you know even talks
about like gluing a strip of clear
plastic so that it gets some sun on it
while it's doing this yeah
all that type of stuff and so most most
70s breeding in America was pollinating
the bottoms of stuff you were intending
on selling
yeah
and then keeping it
yeah right and then you know with the
police pressure and stuff like that
that's really where modern modern
breeding starts yeah okay so
um 70s breeding not exclusively but
essentially was the vast majority was
seasonally they would pollinate their
best females with males they had kept
somewhere else yeah right with the
Advent of indoor lights and the Advent
of hydroponic stores and people like uh
and growing in the Pacific Northwest
like we've talked about multiple times
people started to do some of this
breeding inside yeah they started doing
it away from the helicopters
away from away from the lights away from
the ability to get caught and it also it
also enabled
um people to do more than one breeding a
year
yeah yeah I mean back
in the day you got like you got one shot
right yeah that's that's what you got
you all of a sudden you go indoor and
now as you know you can get four or five
shots if you want
yeah you know right and so that's when
that's when you know prohibition really
forced people to start going inside
and going inside is obviously how 99 of
modern breeding occurs yeah I would say
you know there's not I mean there are
some people that still breed Outdoor and
I would say most people breed Outdoor in
modern times because it's much more
cheap to make seeds that way I think the
ones that take it very seriously and are
doing actual selections do it indoors
but generally speaking let's do it
outdoor you know maybe I should rephrase
it most of the seeds that you guys have
access to that you can buy currently
were probably made indoor
no you know you don't think so no not at
all no not at all it's all done outdoor
in Greenhouse yeah 99 of it 99 of it
yeah
yeah even today even today most of the
seeds that people buy are going to be
coming from places big seed banks from
the UK maybe stuff like that so I the
way I was looking at it is most of this
most of the small and and Motors most of
the pipe breeders that people are
actually buying a bunch of packs of
these days they're you know
um they're mostly doing they were mostly
doing it in indoor scenes
um some of them were doing it in
greenhouses
um certainly he's correct in the sense
that like if I'm only talking about what
most people have access to obviously
when it comes to like all the Mexican
and all the traditional stuff and some
of the stuff that's going on in Europe
at a larger scale uh where legality is
different like Switzerland or Spain
they're still probably using greenhouses
that's like 95 of the market though
American American Boutique breeding is
still small Market
um and even then a lot of these guys are
doing it Outdoors making the seeds
outdoors and I don't know places like
Compton is crazy crazy places that you
can never imagine you can never imagine
so small small greenhouses tucked away
who make the most amount of seeds and
and that's I think for during the uh
oh
early to late
up to 2008 2009 a lot of the boutique
breeders were all doing it indoors in
indoors yes but so basically Galaxy that
was a poorly phrased way to say sure
that from the 80s 90s and the first 10
years of the 2000s for about a 30-year
period yeah prohibition had a lot of
breeding happening indoors exactly a lot
of your famous strains that you know of
uh whether they were from sssc or from
Neville or from smaller breeders in
America all the northern lights work all
that type of stuff the prohibition was
Heavy uh the legality was still not
spread out very much and so for three
decades
um the vast majority of of breeding that
we're aware of uh did did happen inside
yeah and now it's opened up again uh you
know in various ways in the last you
know 10 or 15 years and it's beginning
to shift yeah it took legalities
changing in the US though really I think
that's what changed it when people were
able to grow outdoor or and not get
popped for it they realize that the
amount of seeds you can make outdoor
versus indoors is Monumental but pollen
control is totally a different subject
control is hard
um not and no and pollen viability is
hard too I mean I know people that have
tried to throw off huge Greenhouse runs
and their Greenhouse is too moist and
pollen doesn't like heat light or water
and I've seen a bunch of people have a
bunch of failure uh because they weren't
able to control their humidity uh in
their greenhouse and they think oh I'm
gonna make 15 million seeds sure and
they make 80 000. yeah which is still a
lot but it's a far cry from 15 million
because they lost control of their
humidity so
um you know part of the so this is kind
of taking us up to like
people are getting busted I think bad
things are happening and a lot of these
American breeders okay and this is what
segues into what we've done the last few
shows a bunch of these American breeders
start fleeing
where it's hot and uncomfortable which
is Reagan America to where it's more
comfortable which is Europe Holland
right Rob yeah ends up in going into
Holland's Sam uh Jim all these guys are
bringing that's why Neville and all
these groups got access to it uh was not
because that all these guys wanted to
share it was because they were seeking a
new place to continue doing what they
were doing
yeah it got real plot it got real
problematic in the early in the early to
mid 80s late 80s
um I mean you know uh to bring up
Seattle Greg again he you know he
mentioned on on when you interviewed him
that by the late 80s a rolling series of
busts had pretty much taken out his
whole crew yep all the work that they
had done had been lost yeah to them you
know luckily he shared it with people in
Holland
um you know uh Sam skunkman and Rob and
Mel and Ed and uh these different names
that shared things with groups they did
so because it was getting uncomfortably
hot to do it where they lived
right yeah and they were trying to they
were trying to figure out where to do it
and so that kind of segues us into
what we what we talked about which is
kind of where we were at of this is how
breeding got
and then with sssc and with Neville and
with other groups and that whole era not
only because Holland has you know
um not the greatest weather uh but also
for clandestine reasons and simplicity
and everything like that most of the
breeding in the 80s and 90s uh at least
by the mid 80s uh through the 90s uh was
indoor yes you know the famous strains
uh you know Sour Diesel was made inside
a lot of the famous Pops that happened
uh that came about 90s weed was coming
from indoor right that was where people
could get away with it
um people were able to grow in the 60s
and 70s for a while freely and then the
cops found out what they were doing and
they started looking for it and it
became much more difficult to get away
with it
and uh and so then people responded to
that police pressure
by hiding it yep
and then we went from sort of like
yearly breeding outside and in
greenhouses to much more cracks at the
same thing you could breed you could set
up different rooms it's probably very
unlikely that somebody like Neville or
somebody like the super sativa seed Club
group would have been able to offer as
many strains as they did
oh yeah without your individual rooms
yeah uh the amount you know Matt and I
were joking about the amount of pollen
contamination that could have been
possible back then yeah you know but
certainly if you were trying to do it
outside in the greenhouse you're limited
to one you know one set of pollen
yeah otherwise it's just gonna be you're
just going to have pollen grains flying
around and who the hell knows what is
happening playing who's your daddy with
seeds like a lot of these guys do now
yeah right you know so indoor gardening
also allowed people to uh you know
it allowed people to do multiple
different lines you could offer skunk
one and Durbin and nl5 Haze and nl5
skunk one and you could have
you know I don't exactly know the size
of these people's rooms but that's
probably not that much different than it
was today some bedrooms yeah closets
some garages you know some converted
spaces yeah and that's kind of like that
kind of like brings us from like where
we were
importing you know uh indigenous
people's weed to like how people first
bred in the 70s to how it changed and
police pressure kind of led us to like
where we're at today yep um you know
that's kind of that's that's kind of the
arc and that kind of leads us right into
what we talked about at length the last
two episodes of how Neville was doing
all his work
yeah um they were uh
you know they moved it inside
you know so I don't know maybe we can
pause since we're how long in now an
hour and ten minutes hour and 20. yeah
maybe we can pause and we can start I
don't know can you see questions because
yeah I can see questions this time yeah
so maybe we should uh maybe we should
start an order on the votes aspect yep
uh all right
there I go uh what are each of your guys
daily driver strains right now and what
do you like about the strains to use
them every day go ahead
uh what's your what's your normal daily
driver like uh not necessarily today but
your normal one that you you would grab
if you had it every time so I like you
know I think it's pretty obvious to
people I like uh sour diesels and chems
and headbands
um you know I like strains that have a
potent and unique High uh and I also
like strains that I can smoke every day
and they get me high yeah there's a lot
of strains out there that get you pretty
high the first number of days you smoke
them and then you kind of plateau on
them and they don't take you to where
you need to be yeah on a daily basis so
I like strains that have lasting power
and the ability to like get me high the
way I like every day
uh and there is no I mean the chem 91
makes me feel like I'm a stone teenager
about to watch a comedy eating popcorn
and making it's a warm fuzzy comforting
buzz you know uh nl5 hazes can make me
feel up energetic maybe a little
paranoid
um you know different types of things to
be honest there are certain things that
are quite famous that I find have a
boring High
you know so
um chems headbands sour diesels
uh you know sativas that type of thing
uh you know it depends on my mood
obviously I don't want to smoke uh you
know a high-end sativa like dog [ __ ]
like at 11 30 at night right before bed
because I might like set my mind off
till 1am
but uh yeah chems headbands diesels
that's what I like what do you like Matt
um I'm pretty uh obvious with mine like
I'm a blueberry thing and I like them
different ties they seemed afghanis were
where most afghanis generally speaking
broadly if afghanis tend to relax people
and and you know ease them in that [ __ ]
me up that [ __ ] makes me stay in my head
it's like living in your [ __ ] head
and hating life so I tend to like the
ties that are really light I like
lighter high so if I have to punch
someone I can still I don't like to be
disabled you know but yeah that's
typically what I like and one point that
we should make is that uh you know we
have some really good friends where some
of my favorite strains they dislike they
don't dislike them they breed with them
but they don't like their High very much
and so there is you know everybody
thinks what happens to me is normal
um but with weed it's not normal uh
people can have different effects I know
people you know there might be people
that have a little add that they smoke a
a racy sativa and they feel calm and
relaxed and melt yeah where they smoke
an Afghan and it makes them want to jump
out of their skin and climb up a wall
yeah where an Afghan for me makes me
want to like lean back and eat some
popcorn and mellow out and laugh yeah an
Afghan makes me want it like would make
me like think about chopping down my
grow you know like paranoia yeah so so
it's kind of it is very individual
it's it doesn't affect people the same
the next question is what in your
opinion was the most prominent strain to
come out of Holland in the 90s other
than chem NL Haze and skunk
boy
well I mean that was a big one for me
one of my one that I was really
interested in was purple star and that
was a uh a Dutch purple Afghani of some
sort
um you know this is kind of cheating
because I kind of think it's like modern
skunk but certainly in the 90s uh you
know Sour Diesel in America
um became you know it's it's a it's
possibly a blend of Kevin skunk so maybe
that's not the same but it is it is
different it's not either one of those
things that's its own thing and it
became one of the most popular strains
in America during that time frame
um you know it's hard because when you
say NL Haze and skunk
there's a lot of things that have at
least one of those components in them
yeah you know very hard not to name one
yeah it's very hard not to name
something that doesn't happen yeah uh
you know but but if you're gonna name
some of that stuff you could probably
throw in uh the white family that came
out of Holland you know I mean in the
mid 90s the White Widow the great white
shark the White Russian uh that whole
line it doesn't have any NL hazer skunk
that we're aware of
um
you know it was completely it was
different genetics uh it was extremely
popular it was all over High Times it
was winning cups yeah it was getting
blended into all kinds of stuff
um when I first started growing White
Widow and white rhino were the ones you
know like that's what people were
talking about yeah
um you know another thing is uh this
this kind of I think this angers DJ but
um you know DJ gave uh DJ gave Tony from
sag Martha a bunch of blueberry lines
and sag Martha started selling blueberry
and probably for most people that was
their first ability to actually purchase
those lines yeah um he didn't you know
if he was giving it to friends or people
in his small Network it certainly wasn't
as prevalent as giving it to Sag Martha
yeah later uh later later on in the 90s
after he had soured on sag Martha I
believe Dutch Passion uh took over some
of his blueberry work and stuff like
that and so whether or not he is
appreciative of that or not certainly
sag Martha and Dutch Passion and their
breadth of sales put blueberry and those
lines on the map they did gave people
access to them it gave people the
ability to buy them you know it made
them it made him essentially Forum
famous when cannabis world and overgrow
were happening because all of a sudden
you could get these like these cool
sounding strains with these pretty
colors all that kind of stuff was going
on so
um those were those were pretty famous
you'd have to say they certainly caught
Americans attention
um and they're also not NL chem Haze or
skunk yep but for the most part most
famous things
you know he's the building these are the
building block strains so it's hard to
get away from them this one is all matte
okay with me what was Hobbes breath
creating or was Hog's Breath created
using SSC genetics yes uh the only thing
I know for sure pretty sure is uh that
Jimbo used uh Williams Wonder now
whether it was Williams Wonder crosstalk
random NL Williams Wonder cross two and
Afghani Williams Wonder it hard to say
hard to say
um his story did change based on who we
told but that was intentional he did not
want people recreating it
um that that cut was kept very tight
until uh several years after his passing
and it is now
out there
um his sister has the Hog's Breath
company and her husband they're doing an
awesome job with it uh awesome awesome
clothes I'm still getting all my Hogs
gear and Jim Jim was a major influence
on me for those that don't know
um so yeah Hogs one of my favorite
all-time strains I believe crd
underscore SD is going to be doing some
stuff with the Hogs breath family to
bring it back again all right uh can you
guys talk about the 88g13 hash plant
that Indian worked with not bread please
Bodhi uses it as a male and I believe
Haze man or someone else even though
they weren't supposed to be released
pure yeah um the the G13 hash plant was
selected uh from supposedly bought 1988
via Sensi which was not the case
um and
and that was by swampy who was an old
overgrown member Indian was his friend
uh Indian gets his name attached a lot
of stuff but what ends up happening is
he asks other breeders to send in
precedes he distributes them without the
breeder's name and it get his name about
stuck with it again like the ADHD 13
hashplan
um but it is it is the G13 hash plant
aka Mr Nice that seed bank or was this
seed bank distributed
there's a couple things with this yeah
I'll throw in uh one is that there is no
88 G13 hash plant in the seed bank it
comes out in 89. yeah
um so you know what's a year uh anyway
but and
um from my understanding uh it had been
sort of bred to F4 before Bodhi got it
and Bodhi cracked him and did some he
didn't realize it had been bred to F4
and bottlenecked a bit so he got it and
he bred it and he bred it a few times
and he realized that all the breeding
work that he had done with it was kind
of bunk and his best work with it which
is what he crossed everything to and
everybody has access to was actually the
initial seed pop
you did better with the initial batch of
seeds that he got because they'd already
been heavily selected for than him
trying to work within the narrow pool
post that he thought he was going F you
know F1 to F3 maybe yeah and he was
really going like F5 to f8 yeah and
that's a big difference right that is
amazing so I think most of what you're
getting when you get stuff from Bodhi is
the initial batch of seeds that he had
got that had already been narrowed down
and I don't know when they came from
they didn't come from 1988
um they were sold in 89 and in 90. they
were not sold by Scentsy
um and I don't think until uh Mr Nice I
believe until they named it Mr Nice and
Matt and I discovered that that didn't
pop up in a Scentsy catalog until almost
1999. yeah it was a long time so it was
available for two years from Neville's
seed bank in 89 and 90. I believe that's
probably where they come from uh it was
probably a pack or two that the guy bred
with yeah know honestly and so that's
not that big of a selection pool uh and
that's the it's obviously you know I
mean bodies had some great success
breeding with some of that uh it's also
probably one of those ones where there's
not a bunch of places to go with it
yep it kind of is what it is the breed's
very dominant
um it's pretty purple
smaller butted uh some are some are
large yielding but I I believe the one
that the male that buddy uses imparts
purple traits the deadly Gmail I think
he calls it and also uh for those that
don't know swampy who originally put out
those G13 hash plant seeds he also did a
cross called free Leonard and that was
the G13 hash plant butterscotch wine I
believe the butterscotch wine was a
female
yeah
um and that was phenomenal phenomenal
um who was it was it Oren that worked
with it I think uh yeah Oren worked with
it for a little bit and has done some
cool [ __ ] with it
um it made his caramel line and a lot of
people have since used the caramel line
and and you know yeah that's about all I
can do that one the next question will
go over very quickly because I think
Matt and I will both kind of want to
punt on it but we'll see
did Barney's Farm ever have their own
in-house breeders have they always been
a bulk seed reseller uh I don't think
matter I had a super high opinion of
Barney's
um I think they've always kind of been a
serious seller I think they came in very
late to the game when the Dutch scene
had already been significantly reduced
from its golden and even silver era they
kind of came in at the at the tail end
of all that uh I don't know anybody that
has actually bred for them doesn't mean
that they didn't have a little bit of
their own house stuff doesn't mean you
couldn't have found good stuff uh but
certainly most of the Dutch seed banks
in the last 10 years have have certainly
fallen off from what they were previous
to that in terms of what people find
from them so uh next question
longitivity on seeds and pollen uh one
is quite easy if you put seeds in the
fridge and or the freezer
um you can extend their life ex you know
by quite a bit and that's pretty
standard just about every breeder I know
that wants the longevity on his seeds
um they uh
you know they put them in the freezer or
the fridge
right yeah I'm just trying to read the
other questions the pollen the pollen um
Matt can speak to this I'm sure pollen
is a lot more delicate than seeds it has
a lot more limited shelf life
and Rob Spurs book they talk about you
know baking some flour in the in the
oven you know and then mixing that flour
either 10 or 100 to one and then
freezing that
um you know uh pollen is a lot iffier
heat light water all kills it
um it's a lot less viable than a hard
seed to keep alive so uh you know
um that's all I'll say about that any
any way you want to store pollen that's
not fresh there's various ways to go
about it if they're all iffy people have
some greater success than others
next couple questions ignore ignore a
few of these because there's nothing
yeah I can't I'm not gonna you know T
tkogee Urkel Sour Diesel those are all
their own longer things anyway uh do you
think Mendo purp is possibly related to
the purple skunk it was only available
in the original 85 catalog and it being
inbred for eight years and the sativa
effects of the purple Hindu Kush type
plant with those purple flower sounds
similar
you know
um like a lot of 90s stuff that you get
uh the lineage and the back story that
you would prefer to come along with it
uh is not there
um the only information that I have that
I think is factual about the Mendo perps
is that the guy that I got it from grew
it in the late 70s in kovalo which is a
remote Valley in Mendocino County I
don't know anything other about it
besides that I don't know purple isn't
there I mean there you know there was
it's sort of a pipeline you know and
part of the reason why part of the I
should say this too is that a lot of
land race stuff that we were talking
about a lot of it tested between seven
and fifteen percent THC and it was
really the blending of these various
land races and Afghans and these
hybridizations that really started
bumping us up into the higher teens
lower 20s mid-20s type of thing and so
the Mendo perps while it has amazing
qualities
um it has very low THC it's probably
somewhere between 8 and 12 percent if
they're not bumping it up which actually
kind of lends it lends to its truth that
it could be an original land race
brought over
um but I don't have a regional origin uh
the only thing I've ever smelled in my
entire life that smelled like the Mendo
perps was The Nepalese Temple balls that
I got from hash smugglers in Amsterdam
absolutely I've thought that it might be
Nepalese because of that but I have
absolutely zero evidence pointing one
way or the other other than the fact
that it's purple
I don't think it's purple skunk simply
because Matt and I have grown tons of
skunks various kinds it doesn't really
have any other skunk characteristics I
think Urkel is purple skunk I really
genuinely do I know uh CSI probably I
think he's uh more akin to something x18
or ptk something like that I think it's
purple skunk one Urkel but I do not
think Mendo purposes purpose kind of
corn
um okay so here's some funny ones what's
my favorite color in weed
uh you know uh
okay here's the thing I do think that
purple is extremely physically
attractive to look at I do think that
the cookies and that the stuff from DJ
Short and his son JD can be extremely
beautiful the lavenders the pinks the
blues
um I think the Mendo perps is beautiful
do I think that those kinds of weed uh
are as potent and as strong as the green
weed
no
no no
so if you like very light to moderate
potency it could be your thing but
literally every potent strain that I
hold and care for
um is some shade of green yeah I I want
to see purples I need that oh my god um
I would love people I would love people
to breed an extremely high potent
potency purple I haven't seen it I've
seen a few the the purple unicorn was
the chemd Blackberry Widow from JoJo
Rizo it was the first time I got candy
potency in a just Stark purple plant
yeah I'm sure it could exist I'm just
saying as far as most purple things
you're aware of it's not common no they
tend to be they tend to be lighter yeah
uh this is a good one the the Golden Age
of Canada I like that question quite a
bit
I'm gonna you know I'll I'll talk about
this one for a minute because this one's
kind of dear to my heart and maybe it's
just because I was young but I think the
90s was the Golden Age of cannabis
um you know I still think that we could
go into another golden age I don't think
it's like it's it's unachievable but the
reason I think it was the golden age is
because it was like the first poly
hybrid era
right things were less inbred
um you know there was a lot more f1s and
various poly hybrids coming out that
were quite potent and the you know the
chems the sour diesels the nl5 hazes
like most of our Fame like very
extremely famous the the cushes they all
originate from that era and people are
still using a lot of 90s cuts
um in their breed work
they're some of the most common cuts to
use they're sort of the backbone of our
modern industry is 90s cuts and the
other thing I think that makes 90s Cuts
different is that 90s was the last era
before the The Name Game
and then Matt can speak to this
extensively but one of the downsides to
the name game is that every time a
famous name or a famous craze happens
with cannabis so many cool unique things
that were easy to sell
before get pushed to the Wayside because
as soon as something becomes not easy to
sell
the amount of people that are willing to
hold on to it becomes tiny
so
you know
um I'll give you guys a perfect example
you know I live in Mendocino County when
the when the purple craze hit in o40506
and everybody wanted to grow Grape Ape
Urkel lavender uh you know so on and so
forth there was all these Hill people
that had been growing all these killer
strains for a long time and easily
selling them and then they couldn't sell
them and their neighbor was like hey
you grow this Urkel I'll sell as many of
them as you can get every gram every
gram will go give me your Urkel and so
all these strains start to get dropped
and so a lot a lot of the reasons why we
still breed with 90s work is because
that's when the that's before the
bottlenecking happened
and now if you look at what people are
selling now all these Boutique breeders
every famous thing gets crossed to every
famous thing yeah so sour got crossed to
everything Kush got crossed to
everything cookies got crossed to
everything Skittles
you name it then they start getting
crossed to each other from both sides
again yeah Schmitz by this by this you
know Cherry Pie by cushman's by wedding
cake by and it's all the same blend of
the same
30 Cuts unintentional inbreeding
unintentional inbreeding because and
that's and I don't mean to call out
breeders because that's what the public
wants yeah yeah two
um Soma definitely all in Soma
definitely had some worthwhile offerings
um his lavender stuff was worthwhile
declining Buddha his reclining Buddha he
got he got some G13 by Haze a from
Neville that he used as a male in some
of his sativa lines and a lot of that
came out to produce a lot of the CBD
lines later on that G13 Hayes Mill yeah
so uh you know when I used to go to
Amsterdam uh you could buy his his Bud
from the dam cring which was one of the
nicer coffee shops in Amsterdam he grew
good weed
um some of his weed was quite popular it
was a little different
um that's because he kicked it first
you know I try to be nice to people but
he was he was a little notorious for
potentially running his YouTube Tumblr
for two or three minutes before he put
it in the bag to sell different things
so he could collect the Keith that's for
real uh who is a legitimate source for
nl1 NL seeds the problem when I
mentioned earlier on the podcast which
is like every five or ten years we'd
reinvents itself you can go look at
almost all of these catalogs from the
90s and it is almost impossible to find
the vast majority of these lines in seed
form
yeah unhybridized pure skunk you know I
mean it just is it's it sucks to say it
but
um every 10 years stuff becomes rare
that's the 90s now that's you know 25
years ago plus
um most of the stuff that was available
in the 90s is no longer available today
you can't get it
um it exists in various hybrids I have I
have a tendency to think that Bubba Kush
is has heavy nl1 influence
um you know so I think some of this
stuff exists in different names
um but that's the sad part if you don't
buy it and store it uh you might want it
later on and you can't get it yep
history of the 1979 Christmas tree I'm
gonna skip that one maybe I don't know
it maybe if CSI comes on at some point
um
uh aspiring breeders
um oh I'll uh skip that one too not
because not because it's a bad question
but it's kind of complicated yeah I
haven't heard of any bud called UFO in
Florida nope
um
I don't know anything about freeze
drying cannabis I know there's companies
out there you know uh there's there's
companies that are that are claiming
that freeze drying is amazing uh I have
specific methods of drying and it
certainly doesn't involve freeze drying
uh here's a good one when and who
started making feminized seeds Dutch
Passion off uh gives themselves credit
for it but it was actually a man named
Mohan RAM and I can't remember something
set as ett that we're first doing the
the scientific experiment experiments on
plant reversal using Cobalt colloidal
SDS and several other methods
um
okay so here's something that's
interesting
um I uh we'll skip a couple of these not
because they're not nice questions but I
don't know anything about the New York
recreational uh rules or anything like
that I don't know anything about the new
uh uh attorney general for our state yet
um you know
uh
Central American cannabis what's the
importance of it I mean it's very
important
um Mexican is is Central America
uh and Mexican has been bred into all
kinds of stuff
um that we use uh the other essential
American countries not so much
um it does exist but it certainly didn't
have the impact in terms of breeders
working with it there's certainly
Honduran and El Salvadorian and you know
that kind of thing Panama's also is also
technically Central
um is also technically Central America
so uh the two famous ones from Central
America that have a lot of influence and
have been bred into a bunch are Mexican
and Panamanian yeah
um
let's see cubing cubing is sort of bxing
in a way it's kind of [ __ ] concept
but
yeah cubing is is great if you have a
true F1
and you want to isolate a single one or
two traits that that that's effective
and then you Cube then you then you
cross forward that's that's generally
how it works
um however I always give this example
every time uh people tend to think of
c99 when they hear cubing because it was
back crossed three or four times
um can't remember what the claim was
from Seoul but it was all [ __ ]
anyways but in a sense it's in a sense
you don't want to take a line that has
[ __ ] a thousand phinos and try to
cube it you're not going to get anywhere
in four steps back
to isolate all the trades like that and
a lot of people confuse that cubing
isolate a few traits Crossing forward
isolate multiple traits that's that's
really the the best way I can describe
it
um that kind of ends most of the
questions I think for this week There's
a few we didn't get to Urkel is potent
no
I don't think Urkel is super potentially
but other people might think so I
definitely think it's one of them I
think it's one of the more potent
purples but I would not put it up
against the more I would not even
remotely it wouldn't be in my top 10 or
even 20 uh most potent strains that I've
tried
it's one of the top ten that will
instantly get me paranoia anytime I mean
you know
see it's just the way it goes with my
brain yeah there's a guy there's a
there's a gentleman asking about do you
think land race seeds are still good at
the source
um you know if I don't know anything
about those guys but I certainly support
people going around in Afghanistan and
Pakistan
is he talking about a specific company
or is he talking about I think there is
a company called land race seeds that
bring stuff over from Afghanistan and
Pakistan
um it's not that easy for white people
to go there and collect things right now
I mean when we went to war with them for
a couple decades and so it's a little
sketchy at the Taliban and stuff and so
the fact that you have people that are
going to collect and send seeds I don't
know what will come of it but it's
definitely an access point
um and we'll go from there uh you know
and uh
the difference in early Colombian Haze
I think the difference in early
Colombian Haze and why it was better was
it was just raw crosses and less inbred
I think there was a lot of mistakes made
in the 70s on accident as people learned
they didn't use large enough population
sizes I think it's been documented that
a lot of the best females that the haze
guys liked started disappearing in the
mid to late 70s because they made some
some poor choices with selections and
they weren't sure what they were doing
um you know the South Indian stuff has
kind of been debunked now Sam is saying
that it was always Colo by Colo which is
Colombian by Colombian he's saying that
the this four-way blend is a bunch of
bunk and it's not true
um so uh I can't I can't speak to that
um so I don't know you know I mean here
we are as that's basically the end of
the questions there's you know there's a
guy that said that Mexico is North
America
uh I'm aware that uh that uh that they
don't consider Central America continent
but since the question was asked about
what came from Central America that was
beneficial
you know if people are talking about
Central America it's pretty much Panama
Mexico
um I realize it's all either North or
South America as the way that uh
geography would work I was just trying
to answer the question
the Durbin stuff we're going to ignore
simply yeah we have some stuff coming up
that I think will shed a lot more light
on the Durbin thing next week and so I
don't want to chat on that two weeks two
weeks something like something
relatively close there'll be some really
good new information
I think we could talk about it now since
it's most of it's in the can um is that
okay you want to talk about it real
quick just plug it yeah we could plug it
really quick so
um you know we uh we we were blessed and
we have been able to interview
um the the founder of super sativa seed
club uh and
um as part of our like 80s breeding
program Neville's obviously passed so we
weren't able to interview him but you
know Neville and super sativa seed Club
were the two largest ones and we have a
quite long interview coming that we're
going to be giving some context to where
we ask him a bunch of questions about
some very famous trains what it was like
back then
a lot of cool stuff a lot of stuff that
surprised even Matt and myself uh new
information he was super engaging and
cool I'm really excited about it we
gotta edit it a little bit in various
ways just for uh you know but
um there's a lot of myths busted there's
a lot of there's a lot of stuff that's
gonna come out that's super neat there's
a lot of stuff that's going to come out
that uh you know might make lips that
might make people sad or flip some
stories that have been kind of accepted
on their head
um you know I think uh the Durbin thing
is interesting you know
um you know and and so we'll we'll sort
of save that that for that but uh the
Durbin story is a little wider than we
once thought
we do have that interview coming it
should be great he was super cool to
chat with us uh he'll really flesh out
what life was like back then and what
breeding was like and he was one of the
two biggest uh seed banks in the world
in the 80s so we're really excited to be
able to bring that stuff to you guys in
the near future
um
you know and uh you know so I don't know
that kind of like that kind of takes us
to uh
um that kind of takes us to sort of the
end of like our Arc here we answered a
bunch of questions
yeah but uh again if you want to want to
be a part of this you want to be a part
of some of the research we're doing if
you want to see a lot of the like I I a
lot of people know I collect a lot of
old stuff you know like old cannabis
memorabilia
um I post a lot of the shots from those
books in there like as I come across
them cool [ __ ] that that adds to the
history of cannabis uh we have a a
depository we're working on with a lot
of old catalogs a lot of old magazines a
lot of old books that are inaccessible
to most people
um
we also have the merch shop again you
can click buy Syndicate merch um right
under one of our heads and uh it should
take you there and you can buy a hat
shirt anything that helps support us
this [ __ ] costs money to do and we're
actually like I just bought a new mic
that I couldn't use this time and a few
other things so it does cost money the
more you support the more we can do and
the more we're appreciative and we can
do more giveaways and cool [ __ ] so yeah
let's throw some one basic plug is that
uh you know if you guys can't figure out
how to join you can always send a a DM
to matter myself on IG or breeders or
breeder Syndicate we'll share the link
uh that'll take you right to where you
need to be uh you know we have our own
like we have our own chat in there where
you can ask us questions all the time
and we we chop it up with people on a
much more regular basis uh our point to
all this is to get information out there
and talk about the stuff that interests
us so
um yeah if you can't find it for some
reason give mad or myself a shout and
we'll send you a link and point you in
the right direction and I hope everybody
enjoyed listening to a longer
a longer thing and just hit us up and
we'll see you guys there
um as someone said not so accept my
follow or have three years bad luck d uh
D DM me on on IG I have I have like over
a thousand uh I have over a thousand
people waiting it's not intentional
um but if you hit me up personally and I
can chat with you for a second I'll
accept you and we'll go from there
there's a link at the bottom that uh
breeders said to get just put up there's
the thing to pledge at if you can't uh
if you want to send us a lit we'll send
you a link too and we're going to be
doing this all the time so we're gonna
have some shorts coming up we're gonna
have some cool interviews with some old
schoolers we're gonna have more lives
that are just like this so there's going
to be some variety and content coming
um some more interviews uh you know like
I said said some short topics some more
long-winded [ __ ] like this that's an
hour and 50 minutes long
um and so we're just gonna we're gonna
start adding adding to it over time and
trying to make it cooler and hopefully
everybody enjoyed listening while
they're what they're up to yeah um I
like the uh the idea of keeping us all
on an even playing field when it comes
to information some guys like to secret
scroll that [ __ ] others don't
um we want everyone on an even playing
field to be able to make the best weed
possible because every if everybody's
making good weed we can all build off
each other's [ __ ] so thank you guys for
showing up thank you very much for
showing up we really appreciate it we
all hope you have a great weekend uh
enjoy everyone have a great day oh my
gosh on that note bye everybody and uh
we're out of here
am I still alive just me he bailed and
left me here
you guys gotta look at my ugly ass I
guess I gotta figure out how to undo
this bye