foreign
hello bastards and bastardettets how we
doing
all right kind of getting settled in
here for the uh
yeah thingy today
the [ __ ] thingy
so
um as you saw I think we're gonna have
CSI Humboldt
come stop by
uh whenever I he may not show up at the
very beginning but he'll be here at some
point and we will go over what he saw in
the NL reproduction
and let me get not so in here
or do I have to do them both same time I
can't remember let's see
so we'll keep our eyes peeled for when
CSI pops up
you guys let me know
Wasabi I need to teach you how to use a
camera
use a camera as my own heads cut off
yeah this is a professional it could be
called headspace that you need to get
there you go this is a perfect I'm just
analyzing my [ __ ] you just super anal
dude I like logged in and like your [ __ ]
was like aiming at the wall I know I I
started I start off with a scenery of my
my ceiling
you do yeah because nobody wants to see
my [ __ ] face the first time they jump
in I want to traumatize anyone I want to
be I want it to be smooth
yeah
all right
so
um
trying to think of how to start this
uh well I don't know what you said
because I just popped up
we're hoping
uh managing technical difficulties and
whatnot that we might be able to get a
CSI on to chat about some stuff yeah
um and uh
this uh this Friday evening we kind of
decided that we were going to maybe sort
of merge uh something that's current uh
going on right now with some historical
[ __ ] yeah right and we had an excellent
opportunity to do that in the uh in the
nl5 project that Matt and and CSI have
been up to uh and nl5 probably needs uh
no introduction in the sense that it's
probably like one of the most famous
terms in all of cannabis yep uh but
there's a lot of Legend behind it and
there's a lot of misinformation behind
it and so we thought for this episode
maybe we could sort of like take you
guys through like how it started some of
the history to it and a lot of this
stuff has been chatted about in various
ways and shapes and forms but we thought
it might be interesting to sort of like
coalesce it all into one show yeah uh
and start from back then and sort of
bring it into the now
because modern times yeah because you
know so I mean I've done I've helped
with some like 90s stuff and uh it makes
me feel old but you know the 90s is like
30 plus years ago now uh and the 80s
when all this [ __ ] was happening was 40
plus years ago now so most people in
cannabis have heard about nl5 but it's
mostly just Legends and there's a lot of
misinformation and a lot of funny cuts
and a lot of odd stories and so we kind
of thought we'd just chat about those
kind of aspects a little bit and sort of
merge the history with a little bit of
the project that these guys are doing
um because they tie in together
and yeah I mean where do we want to
start
uh you know we can start with
um maybe I'll start maybe we can start
with just the generalization you know
and then we'll start with some history
so the reason why everybody knows what
nl5 is in my opinion is because of
Neville
right uh Neville uh popularized it he
picked a selection uh and he used the
nl5 and a bunch of famous crosses one of
which was probably the most famous line
of all time the nl5 hates yes uh and
then other groups and Canadian seed
banks and all these different things
started using the name nl5 and L5 right
and it just sort of became part of the
fabric of cannabis history yeah if you
will
right and there was a lot misunderstood
about it or whatever but it's probably
one of the most recognizable terms in
canvas yeah I think even people like my
parents uh my mom my dad was who he was
with weed but my mom had nothing to do
with it she wanted nothing to do with it
never learned it and even she has sort
of Northern Lights as a strict and
Northern Lights and Northern Lights five
and all that and so now what we've got
going on is is I've joked on previous
episodes or whatever that like when I
was trying to collect uh a lot of old
stuff it was almost impossible but now
we're kind of in this wave of you know
famous things from the 80s and 90s you
know or in any form they might exist in
has has got a Resurgence yeah of
popularity and interest and people want
to see what's up with you know what was
once common becomes legendary yeah
right it's really is kind of what it
boils down to and so for anyone that
came into the weed scene later when ml5
was already kind of a myth
um you know uh you know hopefully we can
like clear up a bunch of stuff because
there's a lot of there's a lot of people
that are talking about the name yeah
right yeah so uh
when we tell this tale let's go ahead
and start with there was a man named
Herbie
sure and Herbie uh went to a certain
hair hair salon where the Northern Light
crew hung out and he would go to they
would go to this hair salon and commune
and smoke weed and talk stuff well this
guy named Herbie came in and he was a
veteran and he
um wanted to be able to grow and make a
living for himself so they set him up
with some lights and some some of the
original Steve Murphy Afghani seeds and
he had some of his own
um different hybrids he was working with
mostly Colombian and Mexican I believe
that was the uh quote
um
yeah and and he he was the one who
selected this
nl5 clone from or from his own work with
the Steve Murphy Afghan and Hawaiian
so yeah I mean probably the the way that
a people can understand it the best is
that there was a loose Collective group
of friends you know you know
acquaintances whatever in the Pacific
Northwest area yeah um Herbie was one
there was a guy named some some people
call him the Indian uh was another one
um Steve Murphy was a different one
um there was uh you know a um there was
a number of different characters all
involved at various points and so it was
a mostly everyone has to remember that
in that time in the early 80s almost
everything in America was still sativa
and blends of different sativas because
all the all the weed that came into
America
was seeded Sativa weed
right so the core of everybody starting
to breed was you got three seeds with
your sativa weeds lots of them and the
rare [ __ ] was Indica because Indica made
hash hash didn't come with free seeds
and so Indica seeds were really hard to
acquire uh they came from people on the
hippie hashish Trail people like Sam
Skunk Man and Neville and others made
trips to Afghanistan which in that era
was extremely difficult to do
it's dangerous and they started bringing
back small amounts of seeds so unlike
sativa that was getting sativa seeds
spread out all over America in every
kilo that was sold Indica seeds were
hard to come by yeah so the NL story
starts with a very small handful of
seeds of pure Indica that came from this
dude named Steve Murphy yeah
right and then of course just like
anybody
um the group in on the Pacific Northwest
up there started making hybrids of this
stuff they crossed it to itself they
crossed it to everything else they had
and the the famous numbers of NL
basically
you know connotate like the lower the
number the more indica and the shorter
it was yeah so the one two three four
were you know predominantly Indica based
and smaller and you start getting into
five six seven eight nine ten eleven and
they start getting more and more sativa
now Matt's already interviewed one of
the main characters uh in the for in in
this thing and he basically stated that
they took that Steve Murphy Afghan and
they crossed it to every sativa they
could get their hands on
so Hawaiians Mexicans Colombians
you said Indians blends of those things
hybrids of those things all back and
forth right so
the nl5 they had this buddy named Herbie
who got involved and uh Herbie had a
Hawaiian okay and this Hawaiian was
um
you know he crossed he it got crossed to
the Steve Murphy Afghan and the it got
called nl5
uh for its position and the height and
the blend of sativa versus indica or
whatever
and they found afino that they really
really liked so nl5 initially was a seed
line created within that little crew
and then Herbie gave back to the NL crew
like this select Fino that he was super
excited about
and so the as best we can tell it's a
pure Afghan from Steve Murphy on the one
side
and a Mexican Colombian We Believe on
the other side
that was called a Hawaiian because it
was called a Hawaiian because it was
grown in Hawaii but there is no
indigenous Hawaiian weed yeah most
Hawaiian weed was Mexican Colombian a
blend of those two or a blend of those
two with Afghan right so
um you know and then as you know as the
story's been told uh this gentleman
um sent Neville uh a uh a whole bunch of
seeds all numbered
right yeah and uh I don't know if you
have any of those catalogs handy but
Neville's story is that Neville's story
is that he was
um
you know he did a lot of work with them
and a lot of them as we found out were a
mess because they were a blend of
indicas and and sativas yeah but in this
one seed of nl5 out of a bunch of Indica
sativa hybrids and a mess he found this
plant that was what he called the pure
Indica throwback that showed zero sativa
influence yeah it was short it was squat
it was leafy it was covered in Frost it
didn't have a lot of smell
um and so he started Crossing this to
things and it crossed amazingly well
with basically everything he threw on it
yeah so the legend of nl5 was born
because he crossed it to skunk one
and he crossed it to NL he crossed it to
Hayes
and he crossed it to ml2 and he crossed
it to a few other things uh it started
showing up in poly hybrids he made like
silver Pearl yeah and it just sort of
became one of the building blocks of his
genetic library and since he was one of
the first dudes that had a seed bank
anything that he had that he threw into
a bunch of crosses kind of went
everywhere yeah right and all these
things are winning High Times you know
stuff and it's getting big glossy
pictures and nl5 Hayes was the most
popular strain they sold so the legend
of it just took off
now
there's a debate here because what
what's indisputable is that he went to
the states and he got uh the Pacific
Northwest hash plant and the um and the
G13 through friends of uh another guy
who's pretty famous named Jorge
Cervantes some friends of his hooked him
up and he arranged for the cutting that
the guys in the Pacific Northwest were
growing as nl5 to be shipped over
right yeah and so they did this they did
this clever thing where they shipped
this plant over in a terrarium of other
plants and they took scissors and they
cut the serrations off the edges of each
of the pot leaves
so it didn't look like wheat that's sick
huh that's right they just shaved all
that off so it looked unusual
and if Neville is posted uh back when he
used to post on Mr Nice that he didn't
like that one as much because it wasn't
as consistent of a breeder as the one he
found amongst the seed line yeah and so
he didn't use it yeah so right there you
have this massive confusion where
everybody thinks nl5 is the same thing
where it is kind of the same thing but
there's a seed line that never got out
there's a clone that they selected from
that seed line that was popular in
Washington yeah and there's a clone that
that Neville found among seeds they sent
to him
and they all got called nl5 yes and
that's where a lot of the con the
confusion lies yeah so people think
they'll be like oh I've got the same
clone that Neville used and all of his
breeding but it never left the West
Coast yeah well no because Neville says
he found it in seat yeah
you know so there was there was two
select cuttings even early
um and you know most people don't
realize this but Neville says his was
like a total Afghan throwback and the
one that that uh the Seattle crew
describes had like two foot colas on it
right yeah that's a long running lime
green colas well yes and no yes and no
if I remember if I remember it was
stated that they combined different buds
to make it look like it had a massive
Cola for Neville oh Jesus yeah so that
there were some fun stuff going on there
was some Shenanigans perhaps yes
Shenanigans abound there was some
Shenanigans so there's a so yeah I mean
there's an aspect where
um
I'm sorry I'm looking down for a second
because Matt didn't have his catalog
handy I know I always do too but I do I
don't know if there's a bigger version
of this but if everyone wants to look
at that picture right there
that is a picture of the mother cut
taken in Amsterdam and put in the
Scentsy seeds catalog
taken when it won a cup in 1995 it was
printed in the 96 catalog that is a that
is one of the few existing pictures of
an actual growing nl5 that Neville used
and you can see it's short it's squat
it's leafy as [ __ ] you know it's got all
these things going on to it
um
and so
you know uh so nl5 Neville said that nl5
was prop nl5 Haze was probably the most
famous and best-selling thing in his
whole catalog both at his seed bank and
later at Scentsy yeah
um the nl5 skunk one got renamed it's I
don't know if it was renamed Shiva Shiva
skunk yeah I think it was renamed Shiva
skunk at Scentsy seeds but it was sold
the whole time
um so probably it was sold from 87 or 88
all the way through uh you know 1999 or
the early 2000s still probably to this
day but it's not the same [ __ ] yeah
um and nl5 Haze was sold consistently so
you know it just kind of entered into
the Lexicon everybody knows nl5 hits
yeah and it's gotten old enough now that
a bunch of people are like oh I have it
I have the original cutting I have the
this I have the that so
you know
um you know and uh and and you know it
it um someone's saying nothing about the
NL crew telling Neville that I mean
Neville you know Neville spoke about the
NL but he basically like has said that
he just got
um he just got these labeled seeds and
he made his own inferences about them
you know so yeah
you know he had he had to make it up
basically like he had to think what what
am I seeing yeah um and then you know
the guys back then it was in the 80s and
they were all scared of getting busted
so they didn't really take copious notes
no and then either that was stated
several times you know and we actually
know a bit more about the nl5 than we
know about a lot of the other NL numbers
because of what Herbie was working with
and what he said he crossed to the Steve
Murphy to get that nl5 yeah so it's like
a lot of things you know I mean a lot of
a lot of uh a lot of breedings are
collaborative
it's a small group of friends doing one
part at my garage and you do the next
part of yours and this and that and
everything else and who's responsible
for it there might be one or two people
that gets known for it but in reality
there's a whole little group that's
involved
yeah it was it was a kind of small group
yeah
right yep so you know uh and then you
know when it comes to ml5 Haze uh
Neville claims that right before he left
Scentsy about 95-ish uh they lost the
mother of nl5 dope
it died and it makes kind of sense
because if you like there's a bunch of
nl5 haze cuts that still are kept in amp
in America especially in the New York
Region and in Amsterdam and they all are
basically from 88 to 95. yeah
you know there's not really people
aren't really like oh I got this one in
uh but there was a lot of fire in those
seven or eight years that they were able
to marry those two plants together yeah
you know and then
you know uh Super Silver Haze and stuff
like that was kind of Neville's attempt
to blend the three most famous Amsterdam
lines together uh which was NL skunk and
Haze
and so you know now we have this whole
thing where
everything gets different names and
different nicknames and tons of [ __ ] has
NL or skunk or Haze blended into it yeah
but you might not know because it
doesn't have that name attached
yeah you know uh no someone said I
assumed it was phenos of one to nine no
it was different hybrids so nl1 was
almost pure Afghan
nl2 was another afghan that they
actually got like a Kush type Afghan
from the Indian and they Blended that to
Steve Murphy yeah three and four sort of
lost a time nobody has them but they
were also you know they started
increasing amounts of sativa and 5
through 11 were just the NL Crews
Crossing that Afghan to different
sativas yeah
and you know the more the higher the
number the taller the plant the more
sativa influenced yeah
right yep and so we know it so if you
look around uh at some of Neville's
early catalogs you can see him playing
around he uses the eight he uses the
five he uses the nine he's got the one
and the two you know all these different
things and then after three or four
years he decided basically that he was
only going to breed with the one the two
and the one cutting of the five that he
found yeah and so all these other
hybrids kind of go away
because probably because they were mixes
of extreme sativas with indicas and they
were probably a lot more of a pain in
the ass for a breeder to tame yeah and
he did have high high as far as his
Keepers he did use a uh
a rigorous selection so he didn't keep
he went through a lot of seeds to find
what he kept and the Indian I believe
the Indian was Native American but I
can't say that for sure but he was he
was Native American but he was he was
part of the Pacific Northwest crew yeah
uh and a lot of these guys aren't aren't
well known and don't want to be in the
well-known because in the 80s especially
in the late 80s there was a series of
rolling busts and they all got in
trouble yeah uh so it was a hard time to
be a cultivator
yeah yeah and all that it was there was
a lot of persecution back then there was
a lot of secrecy back then that's part
of why they didn't keep copious notes
because they didn't want them to be used
against them in a court of law later on
um and so you know but basically I say I
think it's fair to say that the reason
why everybody knows nl5 is because of
Neville that I think that's fair I think
everybody agrees with that too because
he and even like the Seattle guys will
say that if they hadn't sent it to
Neville it likely would have been lost
yeah because they went through a rolling
series of busts and had issues
yeah you know so it so it was sold at
Neville's seed bank for a number of
years and then it was sold at Scentsy
for a number of years after that uh
never pure
right uh always a hybrid skunk one Haze
nl2 silver Pearl other poly hybrids
Blended together but never really by
itself yeah
so there was a pure seed line of nl5 but
nobody got it it wasn't sold it didn't
make it to out of Amsterdam it was given
to like a couple people and even like
even great you know uh even like some of
the Seattle guys said that there was a
couple of cuts that got out the eight
the nine and maybe one of and maybe one
of the twos from the Indian but nothing
else yeah so the five survived because
it went to Amsterdam
basically yeah that it's that's the only
reason it survived that's the only
reason why it survived so if you listen
to the Seattle crew they had one version
of nl5 that they kept as a cutting and
and kind of cropped out uh Neville found
a breeder that he kept you know yeah and
you know it kind of It kind of went into
it kind of went into Legend
um you know and so
you know uh and so yeah I see all kinds
of people what's up with this person's
nl1 what's up with this nl5 what
happened is is because it became so
famous okay two things happened one is
that in Amsterdam anytime anything gets
famous people get seeds of it and they
white label it yeah right and they offer
up their own versions of it okay and
then on top of that when the Canadian
seed companies got involved they ended
up buying a bunch of stuff from
Amsterdam blending it to Canadian
strains and claiming that they had these
things for sales purposes yeah you know
so you get and and they all have sort of
dodgy history yeah when it comes to
provenance what I've what I've told you
so far is pretty much factually agreed
to by the people that sent it to Neville
and Neville yeah and people around
Neville yeah you know and then it gets
famous and there's a proliferation of
people and seed banks that claim to have
various stuff
but they weren't passing out this
cutting to other people no they weren't
sharing it just so other people in
different continents could like make
their own seeds with it it wasn't like
today where people were trading seeds
back and forth
you know and clones back and forth
especially to competitors you know the
Dutch are extremely business oriented
very they're not going to just like bro
out
[Music]
yeah that's why Matt's laughing because
they very are very much business
oriented if they have a cut and everyone
else wants it and they're breeding off
it and making money there's not really a
chance they're going to share that
[ __ ] thing and there's a definite
chance everybody's gonna say that they
have it yeah there's a definite chance
that everyone's gonna say they have it
and they're gonna use that any name that
becomes famous in cannabis
gets used yeah you know so someone asked
about you know and so
um that's kind of like that's kind of
where nl5 you know just got crossed to
some very famous things and Neville made
some very [ __ ] famous lines off it
and there wasn't that much weed strains
back then and the combination of that
and High Times being like the premiere
magazine in the 90s and you get all
these high quality glossy photos and all
the the Cannabis cups and there was only
one Cannabis Cup a year yeah so this
[ __ ] got hella famous
legendary
you know yeah and um yeah
what about another one
what's that what about in L1 oh denali's
question
oh I didn't see it I mean nl1 is is
probably the closest thing to Steve
Murphy Afghan
um it's it's it's got a little bit of
discrepancy between the guys involved as
to what exactly is in it yeah um but you
know it's that's kind of irrelevant
because what actually got sold is what
got sent to Neville and everybody should
know that Neville got it in in uh in
84-85 and spent two or three years
seeing what he had so if you bought
Northern Lights in 85 or 86 or even 87
from his catalog
it was a [ __ ] hodgepodge of any of
the lines
all Blended together yeah it wasn't
until about 88 that uh
um it wasn't about I'm gonna turn off my
light because people are bitching it
wasn't about until 88 that uh he started
coming out with nl1 nl2 and nl5 yeah
right
and uh you know and so and then so then
these numbers get attached I think
1989 late 88 is when nl5 Haze got
released yeah and nl5 skunk one and nl5
this and so no one nl2 you know when it
went to Scentsy
um you know they just called nl1
Northern Lights
yeah and they called nl2 Hindu Kush
uh and so lots of people got NL because
it was one of the most common things
sold
yeah so I had to screenshot something
this one no yeah it's hard I mean people
ask questions sometimes I'll get it
sometimes not it's really hard to like
Pat your head and rub your stomach at
the same time so like I try to chat
about something and sound like you know
fairly have a have some flow and then I
read a question and I think about it and
all of a sudden I'm not talking and I'm
just staring at the screen so forgive me
uh for all that you know if it's a
little ADHD yeah if I miss your question
I'm sorry it's just the way it works so
you know I've chatted about this a bunch
before on some of the previous podcasts
and a little bit more detail but that's
what got it famous
right that that is the story that is
that is that is the story and so now
anytime anything becomes famous you know
it's kind of like music or fashion or
something like that it gets [ __ ]
recycled
right like it becomes new and most
people don't know about it and then all
of a sudden people are like I've got
this ancient nl5 cut and I'm making
beans with it I've got this this this
you know
um you know and maybe maybe Matt you
could explain the boof cut or the the
new cut I I don't know I I've never
talked to Bodie about that one and I
keep meaning to ask him because people
ask it a lot but I don't know the the
history on that one
so I mean people you know and you know
people asked about Bob Hemphill and you
know uh and and Ella and stuff like that
and so people have been people you know
it's really hard when you get see when
you get seeds and lines that are that
are 25 30 years old Plus
uh provenance on it becomes difficult
right you know uh apparently you know uh
Hemphill used to work with uh the
coastal seeds Collective uh and
apparently you know he got it through
some friend of cogus
you know
um but nl1 was sold for you know what
probably 20 years yeah for a long time
for a long time it was it was sold it
was and there was never a specific cut I
mean Neville had some breeding males
that he used uh nl1 and nl2 and
Neville's thing was almost always males
yeah they were part of his breeding
males and so it wasn't like nl5 well
while never Neville just had one cutting
that had to be kept alive yeah nl1 was
kind of like a line yeah and so any like
Urban Poison or something right yeah so
anytime there's a line it's a lot harder
to lose the line
than it is when you're dependent on one
specific cut to stay alive and keep
going yeah
just because these these [ __ ] Dutch
guys are such businessmen when you're
not sharing a cut amongst your homies
and your good friends it exponentially
increases the chance that some kind of
disease or accident or drought or worker
error is going to kill your [ __ ] cut
that greed will get you and then you
haven't shared it so it gets lost
right yep uh you know and so uh Ben and
Alan dronkers aren't generous people
they were sharing they weren't sharing
[ __ ] with anybody
you know
um and uh you know so I don't know I
mean it it uh nl5 is super famous NL is
super famous that we went through
probably a 10-year period where nobody
gave a [ __ ]
uh probably starting right around the
Kush sour going into cookie era yeah uh
where old things were just old and
unpopular
right yeah it's just yeah things like
Northern Lights skunk one these were a
cheese things that that like people are
kind of looking at now like oh they got
the [ __ ] G they got like like if I
saw that in a store with tons of clones
and you know the early mid-2000s it's
like
huh give me some of that new [ __ ] nobody
was worried about that because it was so
abundant oh you know I mean we we had a
I can't remember who said it but it's
absolutely true you know 15 20 years ago
you you bought seeds from Nirvana Gypsy
Nirvana and you got free skunk one seeds
because he might as well because you had
so many of them and it was so common
it was you know you had to give them
away yeah because nobody wanted to buy
them yeah it was super abundant and so
there's a thing where everything's so
common why would anyone want it and
people's tastes and change you know
people's you know taste changes and then
it becomes rare
and then people want it again yeah but
most people in cannabis don't hold on to
anything unless it's currently
profitable
so what once becomes we've we've seen it
over and over and over and over again
um you know where something that was
once abundant yeah becomes Uber rare or
lost a Time
like I'll say it straight up if it you
know hopefully he pops on here this
evening but if it wasn't for CSI loving
the Urkel and breeding with it a ton
most people wouldn't have access to it
yeah his prolific breeding is probably
the reason why that genetic survived
yeah and I'm not saying he's the only
person that held it no but it but yeah
it got done I used to know I mean we're
not going to talk about purples very
long here tonight but like I used to
know dozens upon dozens of Growers 15
years ago that ran Urkel
and you and then Diesel and Kush gets
popular and like six people held onto it
yeah
literally yeah it's yeah that's how it
goes dude and it's not and and the
reason why I brought that up is because
that's how super skunk became almost
extinct that's how nobody can find the
the Dead Skunk Terps that's how all
these things become rare or hoarded or
extinct is they're so common nobody
thinks they need to care to preserve it
and then hippies and Growers start
looking around at who's got that old
school
and they can't [ __ ] find it and a lot
of times the name game happens it'll get
a different name or you know someone
makes seeds with it and it has a
different name that it carries on with
so people don't even know to look in
that direction for said one of these
bass lines yeah we've talked about that
before too where I love the counter
culture aspect of Americans giving weed
nicknames yeah but for lineage it's a
real pain in the ass no it's terrible
because we take whatever the name of the
actual thing is and it gets a nickname
and then it goes to a different crew and
they give it a different [ __ ]
nickname yeah and then it goes to this
other crew and they give it a spin on
that name yeah and then 20 years goes by
and you're trying to trace what the hell
it is yeah playing telephone you've got
to go through four or five nicknames
back and then you get to the core thing
and then you and then the trail goes dry
so you know I mean uh
so now after 10 or 15 years of nobody
giving a [ __ ] about Northern Lights
it's hot
yeah people want to try these ancient
things that they grew up when they were
kids reading about or these the first we
the first like true famous wheat yeah
you know they want to see what's up they
want to see what's up with it and uh you
know and so now because there's interest
now all of a sudden where there's
interest there's economy and people
start popping up with it yeah
all over the place and most people
probably don't know that there was two
completely distinct cuts that were used
one from America and one from haunt yeah
and there was a seed line but it was
given out to nobody and then you see
stuff where I've got nl5 Pure
well how yeah lots of that right how
yeah you know
you know I mean you can you can talk you
can you can know that that Neville had
it pure because the guy that made it
says I sent it to him pure along with
the rest of it yeah and Neville says I
got it pure from dude okay they both
agree
here's when I sent it it exists but did
you share with anybody no so everybody
has a bunch of hybrids or Canadians got
it and sold their [ __ ] and then people
get it and it's got a name attached and
they're like
you know
um
there it is yeah
you know and because we're cannabis and
because all of our stories are kind of
black market or underground or
prohibitioning it gets really difficult
to to sometimes it comes down to who you
choose to believe yeah and that's a lot
of the time with a lot of these strains
and so some people will get like NL and
they'll and the guy will be like I've
had this for 30 years and never left the
West Coast it's it's this yeah and
they're like great it's this that's all
the proof I need let's start breeding
with it and it's this
and now it's labels all over the place
and people are buying it and is it that
one thing one thing I also noticed was
that during the philos era a lot of
people would get said cologne that they
got with dubious
Heritage or whatever they submit it to
philos
and by doing so say that philos verified
their clone as legitimate you know God
yeah yeah that happened that started
happening a lot too and that was a real
problem because and as we learned
um
yeah philos couldn't
tell people any kind of plant relation
with any consistency
that maybe we should say this about CSI
is that it doesn't matter what it is but
CSI sent in fi this is how Matt myself
and CSI discovered that philos was
really really really full of it
um we had some evidence before but this
was kind of one of the big kickers was
that uh CSI had made a cross
uh and he sent in both parents and I
don't know if he wants this story out so
much no yeah well I'll shut up about it
then I didn't even mention what it was
but I'll just say this we we discovered
that their genetic sequencing wasn't as
strong as we would have hoped yeah yeah
it was it was definitely disappointing
with the consistency of it
you know and so people thought that
their genetic testing was like American
genetic testing
yeah where you can have 23 and me or
some [ __ ] and be like oh my God I'm five
percent Norwegian
and you know Grandpa was from Germany
and this guy and I'm like and I'm part
African or whatever yeah and we were
hoping that same kind of accuracy would
be transferred into wheat
yeah and I'm trying to move Caleb in
oh we'll see Caleb click the thing and
save request to join if you can if you
if you see how to do that
hit the request to join button so I can
uh add you in when you got time
all right go ahead
yeah so I mean it it um and you know in
order the other the other thing about it
is is for like talking about human
genetics is geneticists can go to like a
pure Norwegian or a pure Japanese or a
pure Chinese whatever and they can start
comparing DNA yeah and seeing these
different things and they know how to
sequence it it would be amazing if DNA
evidence had existed in Holland in the
80s yeah and Neville and and sssc and
and Scentsy in these early groups would
have been able to like put down markers
of what was what
yeah and then we could have seen their
descendants because you'd have something
to compare it to
yeah
but that's not always the case that's
not always the case so fortunately you
know uh so it remains a dream because
here he is
sir your lighting is terrible but if you
just you look like you look like you're
on 60 Minutes and you're one of those
like grayed out you know like guys under
the witness protection program it's too
bright in here it's too bright in there
yeah you can always see your face too
bright yeah yeah
I ain't trying to you know
oh you look beautiful I thank you thank
you so maybe I talk a lot so maybe I'll
do like an introduction uh not the ones
needed and then I'll shut up and get out
of the way so part of the reason why we
did we TR we decided to do this
selection tonight was because it Blends
uh something that's currently going on
with something that's extremely famous
and uh has a bunch of History to it so I
just spent a whole bunch of time
chatting about the history of it and the
simple and maybe like you know mellow
way to talk about it is that uh in in
our search of History we started getting
in contact with some of these uh
original Northern Lights crew people and
hearing their story and as part of that
uh we got we got some seats
mm-hmm uh Matt got some seeds and then
um Matt uh and and Caleb here uh decided
to collaborate on it uh and and Caleb
donated some space and some time and
some energy and they uh did a bunch of
stuff uh both growing out Fino's looking
within the line making hybrids and all
that and so uh I was I was involved as
much as listening to them talk about it
so I'll shut up and turn it over to them
because uh they are about to offer up
some seeds of what they have going on uh
and it might be you know some of the
first real NL to come on the market in a
while
um so Matt and Caleb why don't you chat
about what you found and what you saw
and what interested you and
well first things first you know I'm you
know when I posted up on IG you know
there's there's a few people who are
like you know what did what did Matt
have to do with any of this you know and
fair question I wouldn't even be growing
these seeds if Matt hadn't uh you know
had all that dialogue with you know
mystery man
and you know he he's the one who you
know put all that together he's the one
who sourced these seeds essentially so I
wouldn't be growing nothing without Matt
you know making that first step so yeah
maybe maybe I'll throw in one more thing
so everyone knows when you know breeders
like us get together it's super common
for some breeding to be a collaborative
process right right this guy's got some
seeds you know they both have an idea
this other person has some room that
they're willing to put towards the idea
or a greenhouse or some indoor space
they come up with a plan and you breed
together
of the transaction but but every but
everybody everybody you know lots lots
of friends who are breeders kind of
collaborate on little things like that
all the time
it's super common just so people just so
people know so you know
um
you know Matt had the seeds uh you know
CSI had the space and skill you know and
skill and you know and ability uh we all
have the interest and the history behind
it and really wanted to see what was in
there and so it you know the project
happened right and uh you know some
people know some people don't the very
first you know clone I ever grew came
from my dad and that was Northern Lights
back in 1994. you know so that's about
that one dude
I mean you know you can remember
I mean I rocked it on and off until
about 2002 when I lost it and uh it was
a Cola plant super Frosty a decent
density you know not not like rock hard
Girl Scout cookies or anything
I I describe the nose but I'm absolutely
horrible at scribing you know the smells
so when people ask I'm like it smells
good I don't know but that's not my
forte I I'm more of a visual you know oh
it looks like this you know similar to
this in the looks Department blah blah
blah you know other than you know it
smells great or whatever whatever if I'm
not the dude for for the sniffer yeah
um but yeah yeah okay I mean
when you lost it was it something you
kept looking for like when you when
you're picking up clones oh yeah oh yeah
yeah no it was one of the things that
you know uh family and friends you know
all had it and then you know I lost it
and I went looking and nobody had it
everybody lost it you know that's how it
goes yeah but some people are asking if
it purple
not the one I got from my dad
um I don't I don't really recall it even
remotely having any type of purple to it
at all yeah and and these these you know
nl5 seats that you know I just ran there
was very very little if any you know
actual purple to any of them so yeah you
know
um but then again uh sometimes when
you're making seed uh
you know the purple traits kind of kind
of tend to take a back seat yeah a lot
of a lot of purple things will be
halfway green you know or all the way
green you know
when they're making seeds so I mean
Mendo purple does that you know where
it's you know more green than purple
even under cool temperatures and
everything when it's full of seeds yeah
you know so
um but uh I think the plants have
different uh processes when they're
pregnanted versus not
right right you know they they do they
do very different things their their
goal is different at the time and and I
didn't even think about this but I'm I'm
feeding seeded out plants you know
nitrogen [ __ ] all the way through yeah
yeah I'm not trying to cut off their
Nitro Source you know early like it
would a flower so yeah the goal is is
healthy mature seeds not attractive
flour
is just the carrier for the seed so it's
very different it's a very different
feeding regimen to get where you want to
go and flower
which is why when you have a failed run
and a bunch of flour and no seed that
smoke ain't the best yeah right and he
already said it maybe maybe I should
mention something is that uh you know
CSI has actually you know he has some
pictures of some of these old Gardens
and stuff like that
um but unfortunately since it was all
prohibitiony back then
um they were on Polaroids and uh you
learn with Polaroids that they fade over
time
you know so uh they become the the
colors start to become washed out the
edges start to become less distinct yeah
so you know he cataloged some of it and
uh you know you can you can get a
general idea but it's not the sharpest
of picks right I I have thousands of
these Polaroids you know for you know
the better part of a decade and now
now they're uh
not much to look at yeah that's a bummer
dude that's such a bummer right right
it's just something you didn't know at
the time who knew that over 15 20 25
years Polaroids would would fade right a
regular picture developed at a you know
you know old school style will stay good
for a long time right yeah Polaroids
don't you know I should have scanned
them all while I had the chance
yeah I mean you know we all should have
done things differently when we were
younger yeah you know that's the common
theme right right your camera slowly but
surely burning out bro well you know so
the best thing is is I was having I was
having a conversation with with uh our
buddy pip uh who is gonna drop some
seeds soon and he might come on here and
chat with Matt and I but he didn't
really want to show his face so I'm
definitely going to show him this CSI
Tech yeah right here
because it's exactly what he's looking
for right a disembodied voice coming out
of coming out of the darkness isn't that
how they always used to do yeah right
this is Barry 60 Minutes in the 90s you
know
now I just need the voice Tech yeah you
need that voice Tech
yeah yeah
um tell us what you saw man tell it tell
us what you saw in that room okay so
yeah
the the the seeds that Wright and I have
available
um are basically an open pollination uh
from 47 plants 27 females 20 males just
open pollinated
and uh you know there was there was
definitely good Bad and the Ugly in
there
um there was one plant that was near
identical to the Northern Light I grew
you know from 94 on from my dad
um smelled like it looked extremely
similar to it you know all of that
um
and you know I I had a one of my good
old old buddies from you know
from that area you know uh
you know check checking things out with
me as it was progressing and he was like
yeah that's that's just like the plant
we we used to rock you know 25 years ago
so that's wild that that's definitely a
good sign
um there was a lot of variety in there
um one of my favorites of course uh was
this one that was super Frosty kind of a
popcorn nugget thing a really good
stretch
um and it was kind of bubble gummy
that's how I you know describe it but I
don't know maybe other people would you
know
just describe the smell different
um but it was really nice and we're
definitely saving that one and then the
one that was
um I just have written down a stinky as
[ __ ] but it it's it had like 10
different smells you know top middle
bottom and I I can't describe that kind
of stuff but you know there's there's
guys with noses who are like oh yeah
that's blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah you know and lift 20 different
smells on something but all I know is it
smelled amazing too
um yeah and that one uh that one's
definitely a keeper and then there were
some other ones that you know ranged uh
you know this way and that way and you
know might might end up being Keepers
might not definitely gonna give them a
couple few runs to decide on which ones
are going to kind of make the cut for
future projects you know
so that that's what I'm stoked about is
that we get to see them as clones not
just see seed moms you know but as
clones and they have clones of every
single one it's it's pretty expansive
and it was a it was a cool it was cool
fit and I know you know he he he credits
me with getting the seats and stuff but
it was it was really cool to be able to
to look inside
uh csi's mindset as he did these
selections what he was looking for how
he went about it how many clones he was
keeping of each I learned a lot I
learned a lot from dude during this so
um he put in the work no matter what he
says he put in the [ __ ] work on this
stuff right
yeah maybe maybe I should add something
in where Caleb and I chat a bunch about
like you know Fino's he's found in seed
lines before
um that didn't survive like you know the
the backup clone didn't survive and he
lost it and he's like well you know I
got x amount of these seeds I can find
it again
so uh maybe you know how excited were
you dude to find something that was
pretty close to the spitting image of
your lost plan
I was stoked on it
um
but you know uh I was all honestly more
excited with some of these other ones
that you know because you know back in
the the reality is you know
um it's just a traded clone you have no
idea you know where it came from how
many speeds it got selected from you
know anything about it you know and
that's the thing with traded clones is
you know it might be selected from one
or four or ten or a hundred you know
um I just like you know having the
opportunity to actually select from
better than one yeah for sure I think
too that like there are things for all
of us now that we're all older where
some of the strains that you grow first
and you build your first relationships
with as a grower right in your mind
because you're learning so much then and
this is your kind bud plant right right
you know and they really stick with you
those and you know you think back like
oh what could I have done uh with that
plant when I actually had some some
knowledge when I had that plant I was an
idiot you know I was 19 or something and
I Didn't Know Jack and now I'm like you
know what could I do if I had it now
right right
yeah yeah yeah yeah no I'm I'm a little
interested too and I know this is an NL
talk but are you do you want to talk
about any of the pinks and perf stuff
you're singing too since that's a big
project you have going on right now
oh we could touch on it just a little
bit yeah yeah you know uh um had me
amped yeah I'm definitely gonna uh you
know try to post up a little bit more on
that soon
just because uh there's there's some
interesting stuff in in there
um and uh yeah that one keeper I was
telling you about uh
it smells better than 99 of wheat I've
come across so that's wild you know
um definitely it's not a purple Fino
pure green you know no purple traits to
it whatsoever but man the smell is just
so overpowering uh I I think it could be
a passed around the keeper as long as
it's over five percent THC of course
yeah for sure
we should mention that some of the
terpiest things tend to be lower THC
right right there's a ratio there's a
there's a there's a ratio there that's
not fully understood but a lot of times
things that are extremely human
perception terpy don't tend to be the
most potent there are things out there
that have both but uh a lot of them
don't so we'll see and uh
have I told you much or anything about
this uh this pinks and purpose plant
uh uh I I heard it through your conver
you and Matt chatted about it and he
called me all excited yeah yeah because
it's rare that you sound not excited
yeah something that you found so he was
I'd never hear him overstate anything
about anything dude pops thousands of
seeds so when he tells me dude like this
is special like yeah I mean I think I
think homie told me something like he he
thinks it might be like the best Fino
he's found yeah which for someone like
you to say who pops literally like
thousands of seeds over a number of
years and searches through them that's
really something oh yeah you know
and it really is I I like to give to
give credit to you know uh what what
plants you know kind of produce these
kind of things yeah and uh
uh this particular plant you know it has
Mendo purple in its background but
there's no purple traits to this plant
at all but Mendo purple has this strong
uh mango
um trait that pops up in the ones and
this thing is that mango times a hundred
you know it's it's just the strongest
mango I've ever smelled wow you know as
you know and a bunch more fruit too but
uh you know I know it gets that mango
you know at least you know a portion of
it from from the Mendo perks so you know
could be cool as long as I don't lose
the Clone ganja boners yeah I mean one
one of the things that the Mendo P
certainly has is it's got pretty wide
genetic diversity so there's a lot of
Terps in there right right and so then
you throw it on something else that's
also terpy and maybe wide and you can
get these unusual things that have a
potential to pop up right I mean that's
kind of like people should know this too
and maybe I should say it right now
where it's like if you cross something
to like that uh you know to but to I
don't know to deep chunk
you're going to get a lot of deep chunk
and it's going to be really consistent
you know and there's certain things you
throw certain things on cookies and it
looks very cooky right and so people get
frustrated when you cross two very wide
things because you can get a bunch of
junk and you can get a bunch of this and
that and it's all like unpredictable oh
yeah but then every once in a while
amongst all that stuff there's this gem
because it's so wide and unpredictable
and you're like oh whoa
what is that thing right right so
sometimes the frustration and the effort
pays off
because a really wide base of things to
look through and maybe I should say this
too is when you know when Caleb was
referencing when he did the open
pollination that there was some gems
some mids some junk
that's 90s wheat if you have a wide
genetic base you're gonna get
amazing mid Z junk they're all in combo
and also uh on that pinks and perps one
uh you know I I was I was I always
forget this but
um
I I grew up when I I made those and
found that one I was growing out 180 of
those things so there was only one like
it out of 180 yeah you know so I wonder
how it's gonna breed because it was such
an outlier
right were there other other fenos that
were more consistent and like popping up
more often oh yeah the the the the
purple ones were predominant you know to
find an actual green one in in this
hybrid was actually the Rarity you know
most most everything was you know some
form of light pink or lavender you know
all the way through you know purple to
almost black yeah you know but uh yeah
the the green ones were were rare you
know and and I I probably kept out of
the 180 I probably kept about 20 or so
of the of the darker purple ones and
just the real terpier ones the you know
but they're all I don't think I I have
any other uh green ones out of the whole
all all the purples and the blacks
that's wild man yeah that it was so
consistently that and then this one pops
up right so and so maybe I should throw
this out there just real quick before we
totally lose the thread on it is on some
of these ones that you found that that
the one that's super Frosty and smells
to you like bubble gum and the one that
kind of reminds you strongly of your dad
dad's dad's NL and such
um you're probably planning on doing
some more breeding with those select
females correct oh yeah I'm already
working on that too uh so the the first
round of course was the open pollination
and now
um I have uh a room that's a couple few
weeks into flower and that's all the
keeper females and my keeper male my
favorite male out of the whole bunch
which is
um I don't know it's like almost a milk
chocolatey smelling male and he's super
pungent and he almost looks like a
bigger uh version of purple indica
you know that was that's a throwback
from the same you know Washington areas
these seeds came from you know so you
know there's there's something to that
and uh like I've told uh
um told Matt I'm not sure if I I told
you not so but uh
um when the the Northern Lights I used
to have
um you know occasionally I'd throw a
late Nana or whatever whatever and I
grew out a bunch of S1 seeds well I gave
you know some of these s1s to my buddy
you know uh clones of the S ones anyway
and uh
um he uh accidentally crossed it to
train wreck and
when that stuff was grown out it had
that same chocolateiness that I'm
smelling in this thing you know when
grown Outdoors so
I don't know if it's just coincidence or
or what but you know it it could just be
same same similar genetics the power of
accidents
the power of accidents so maybe I should
throw this in there too so if with with
the these seeds that uh Matt and Caleb
are offering up this open pollination uh
what that's going to give you is you
know that's going to give you your own
ability to hunt through the line and
it's going to be very wide
you know but you could find gems just
like he found yeah uh you could you
could absolutely perhaps find one you
wouldn't know that it looked you know
there could be bubble gum smelling ones
there could be this ones there could be
there's a reasonably good chance that
somewhere in there those phenos pop up
again
and then give them x amount of months to
do some more breeding and we'll get the
chance to see if some of these selected
females breed true for the traits that
he liked because those will be on offer
too so that's kind of like for people
that don't know that's kind of like when
you get old seeds or seeds that you want
to preserve one of the best things to do
to keep the genetic diversity of the
line is just to open pollinate
everything right and then you know you
can set aside you know some seeds from
selected phinos and you can keep certain
phenols and start breeding with them and
intentionally
and seeing where it takes you so that's
kind of like the that's one of the
processes of
um taking old seeds and trying to both
preserve the line but then take it in
certain directions
and you've done that a number of times
with like various heirloom strains that
you've come across you know always open
pollinate step one and then you know you
can do whatever you want past that you
know directional this way that way or
the other
you know and everybody else can too as
long as you know you share the seed and
all that you know yeah
are there any other projects you're
super stoked about past that like any
Femme projects coming up that you're
you're you're pumped about
oh I got that patient zero common
patient zero is on its way
uh I don't know that that one's gonna be
interesting
um I'm not sure how that one's gonna
turn out but you know we'll see it could
be cool maybe you could explain for
people because you have so many names uh
because you're so prolific about things
what is patient zero oh patient zero is
a you know uh
um basically it's the just the Urkel
across the Pakistani Central Kush and I
grew out a hundred and something of
those years ago and my absolute favorite
plan of that one was a was the one I
named patient zero
um and you know it's it's kind of as
long as you like a little turpinelian on
your diet is pretty all right
and so maybe I'll add that to it too
where it's like a lot of modern breeding
today is one-offs where people hybridize
something and then just toss it out to
the public
um what he just described is what's
known as like multi-stage breeding where
he made a cross he grew out a bunch of
phenos he picked one that he liked and
now he's doing further work with that
Fino itself probably Crossing it to
itself and Crossing it to other uh
cuttings that he has in the stable that
he thinks might blend well with it right
um one of my favorites I actually have
uh flowering right now
um is uh uh the Mendo purple number 54
selection from you know growing out that
last hundred and something of those
the Urkel 103 you know S1 and then you
know those you know
um I reversed the 103 slapped it on the
Mendo man those are uniform I mean as
uniform as you can get really yeah
that's cool interestingly uh the Mendo
is extremely dominant on it uh really
yeah they're all they look more like
Mendo purple plants than you can barely
see any Urkle to them and both of those
selections were made out of that room
that I came and visited you and saw
before you uh the s1s of Urkel and the
s1's amendo P yeah yeah uh-huh yeah yep
but uh yeah yeah
um definitely interesting though
I don't know yeah I was excited too like
about I don't know if you want to talk
about any of the purple punch stuff or
if that's you know what I mean like the
the findings in that that you're kind of
seeing that are unique yeah yeah
um
the we we've talked and the most
surprising thing about breeding with
purple punch is how [ __ ] stable it is
I mean absolutely right when you're
working with you know it doesn't matter
what you know ogs diesels chem dogs Girl
Scouts you know and then all the popular
stuff based off all those yeah you're
gonna find a nice portion of you know uh
hermaphrodism you know more so if you
know your your environment's not a you
know perfect but you know even if you
have a perfect environment there's
always going to be a percentage of those
um
but the purple punches have almost the
lowest uh levels of hermaphrodism I've
seen in any hybrids so I mean that's
that's useful that's something people
look for and I think like the fact that
it popped up in an OG GDP was kind of
shocking you know yeah yeah
and you know I I was I was the I wasn't
a huge fan of purple punch I didn't even
you know start growing it until a couple
of years ago yeah I I kind of ignored it
and was like I got plenty of my own
Urkle hybrids I don't need another one
yeah but uh you know it has traits that
it put puts forward and you really can't
argue with it you know yeah I was the
same way you know we both just kind of
dodged hype for a while with like the
[ __ ] the the gorilla glue and that
and then end up at the end like [ __ ]
that shit's kind of good yeah right last
one with the party that's an interesting
that's an interesting aspect that people
maybe should hear about is sometimes you
can have an amazing cut that checks a
bunch of boxes and it breeds like [ __ ]
right it's right all over the place that
throws a bunch of junk and it does the
quality inherent in the cut itself
doesn't seem to translate to its
children very well and then other times
you can take something like purple punch
that they're just talking about that has
a lot of nice traits but kind of Lacks
High or whatever else and you don't
think that much of it
and then you cross it to things and it's
children come out incredibly amazing
with a bunch of traits that you like
right so sometimes a breeding parent can
actually be kind of a crappy
crappy plant in some ways like uh Caleb
likes a lot of the s1s of my Mendo P
quite a bit more than the mama
oh yeah you know the Mama's amazing for
breeding but as an actual plant itself
there's some aspects to it that are
unpredictable and and it's low THC right
right
um but some of its children and some of
the things that it throws and when you
breed
um and sometimes you might take
something like purple punch that people
make fun of and you breed with it and
you're like wow this thing is amazing
it throws all these traits consistently
that are useful right
I mean like you could talk for a minute
about how stable that bubble gum cut you
have is and why you use it in so many
different things because it throws like
rock you know it it doesn't rot very
easily it's got incredible structure it
it densens things up right right right
well I don't know about
it's really not the densest cut out
there but it's it's uh it's definitely a
um you know as as rot resistant as you
can you can get a plant you know
um on on my worst year year ever
outdoors I think I was aiming for like
700 pounds or something and
then we had six inches of rain the last
week of September you know first week of
October and I lost 50 to 60 percent of
that Garden to mold
and the only thing that came through
that garden with probably less than one
percent rot ratio was that bubble gum
cut that's winning
you know yeah so you know tons of people
are like you know what's your best you
know mold resistant you know blah blah
blah well right there you know
so that outdoor Queen yeah so someone
sometimes those traits like they were
just talking about like you know uh
Caleb does an enormous amount of
breeding so for him to say that the
purple punch is some of the most
non-intersex stable thing he's ever
worked with is saying something
right you know when he says that like
this plant is almost immune to mold and
it's the most mold resistant plant I've
ever seen and it passes that trait to
some progeny that's useful information
right right you know I see a lot of
people commenting on the purple punch
strength and like when
breeding has changed
um from where it was maybe 10 years ago
on what we would select for potency wise
but we wouldn't use what we would use
certain one of us you know
um purple punch all I'd ever heard about
was how weak it was so I just never I
never got into it however
it is a is a very extract Centric
Community now and with extracts pretty
much everything's [ __ ] strong
um so so a lot of things are are more
terp-based now where people are are
checking out what kind of Terps are
being passed how they breed and uh yeah
I mean some people won't want to won't
want to [ __ ] with anything that doesn't
lay them out me I I like all kinds of
ranges of different highs and I don't
like being laid out so for me purple
punch is [ __ ] perfect oh yeah
yeah and you know weed weed affects
humans in different ways
um some of my favorite strains to smoke
on a regular basis the other two guys
that were CH you know they don't like it
that much on a they they agree it's it's
a super quality cut
but it's not something with their body
chemistry that really adapts all that
well yeah I have friends that only like
incredibly potent indicas because they
want to be hammered down
and a sativa makes them crawl up the
wall yeah right I have other friends
that smoke a sativa and they relax
right that would be me so yeah so
cannabis and cannabis and individual
strains uh don't think that the way it
affects you is the way it affects
everyone
there's a range there yeah
that's why I like keeping so many
different you know cultivars because you
know I I like the whole spectrum of
different things and I know other people
too you know like different things so
you can't always breed for yourself
definitely not does the purple punch
reverse
uh yeah yeah it reverse is fine
interesting so it reverses easily but
won't ever throw intersex traits yeah
yeah that was kind of odd in itself
right the the S one I got grown now I
don't think I found a single ball
or or nanor on any of them
which was almost unheard of oh yeah yeah
you're usually going to get at least 10
to 20 percent you know and I I say 10 to
20 and that could just be one ball down
low or one you know a late Nana or
something but there's always going to be
like 10 to 20 percent yeah
and then there's certain things that um
perm but reverse
right right you know I mean we've talked
before about we're not going to get into
it too much but you know they uh you
know the old sour cuts are famous for
not reversing oh yeah or getting a
handful of seed but they're also famous
for the wrong conditions and they they
throw nanners that can see create seed
in your room for flower production yeah
it's really easy to grow it boofy I had
a I had some Sour some sourdies in a in
a fully seeded out room just recently
and uh
um
you know completely full of seed and
about week four it just starts balling
up just hanging all kinds of Sour Diesel
balls and even though it's fully seeded
so the whole room was completely seated
so it didn't have any risk of
pollinating anything but you know it
still felt the need to you know throw
out just a ton of balls Mike what are
you doing with this you know
I didn't see any pollen off of them but
you know
yeah yeah I mean the you know the um
like the what I consider to be the
original but you know it's the one I got
the chemd cut uh is pretty famous for
throwing a bunch of manners at week
three four uh but they're sterile
you know they don't really They Don't
Really uh you know uh you know they
don't really make seat yeah and that Kim
D or just chemds in general it seems
yeah they they throw bananas like
they're going out of style yeah and it's
a trait that goes there and so I've had
any number of friends or helpers or
whatever on a light depth Greenhouse
come to me panicked
because half the greenhouse has bananas
popping out all over right and I'm like
oh calm down calm down it's it's the D
we're gonna be fine you know and we're
fine you know you can find a bean yeah
um but you know you do that with cherry
pie or something and you have beans
everywhere right
[Laughter]
so certain things certain things are
different different risky you know
there's different levels of risk yeah
yeah yeah right so I mean maybe we
should maybe we should chat about this
maybe we should reel it back in for a
second
um part of the reason why we did this
nl5 chat uh both starting in the 80s and
going through some of the history and
then bringing Caleb on was to talk about
the project that that him and Matt have
going and uh they they just dropped the
seeds I believe
yes or we're about to or just did yeah
no they're dropped uh calebs Caleb's
site is
humboldtsi.com correct Caleb yeah there
you can buy them on there or I'll write
seedco.com yeah and so it's a it's a
it's a riot and uh and Caleb collab
um and it's a big open pollination of
genetics from
um one of the people that was intimately
involved in the old NL crew uh so the
the provenance is excellent as far as
like who it comes from
um and you know but then on top of that
too the proof is in the pudding so you
know
um it uh it's a chance for people to
maybe hunt around if you have if you're
a little adventurous and look through
something old
and something famous you know uh and you
know Caleb found a few things in it that
he was super excited about and so
hopefully you you guys will too
uh and one of the ways that we're gonna
make sure that not everything is
Skittles OG cookie
cushman's whatever is by people taking
effort and Reviving some of these old
things and making fresh bats of batches
of seed that are more viable and then
getting them into people's hands so the
gene pool stays wider yeah yeah so not
only is it a cool old project to
something that's extremely famous uh and
there's potential in it
um but you can better believe that most
modern breeding uh with a few exceptions
is the same 30 or 40 Cuts Blended in a
bunch of different ways over the last 10
years
and this Harkens back to a much older
time so there's a possibility there that
when you out cross things to something
that aren't like each other if you take
these nl5s and you start throwing it on
different stuff you have you might get
some unusual stuff you're not expecting
that's good
right
you know brayden's [ __ ] with me sorry
guys no it's like because that's because
that's the thing is a lot of breeders
say that like sometimes you know
Crossing two very distinct things
together
is where you really get quality yeah
you know and you're certainly
introducing something older in the gene
pool that was very common 20 30 years
ago but now is many generations in her
bread
and so uh by these guys doing this
project we're it's kind of getting
thrown out there again where it can get
bred into a lot of modern stuff
and people get to see what happens so
you know you'll you'll get more
opportunities to see what CSI is doing
with the work uh in future breeding
projects that seem like they're already
engaged
um and hopefully people are going to buy
a bunch of this stuff and start posting
and trying them out themselves
and it's one of the ways you can keep
cannabis history alive right and making
the encourage with the stuff yeah yeah
you know mixing it with modern things
and seeing what happens
right right so what do you guys think
would be the best
you know available
uh plant line whatever out there too
across to the nl5s
you know
I I personally I want to see the Hogs
breath in all five I think that would be
cool if if we could track that down and
do that again it's been out of my hands
for a while but I think that would be
interesting just because of the terms
how about you not so
you know I actually think that
um it might cross well with something
like the dog [ __ ]
okay okay you know kind of a potentially
almost a back cross potentially almost I
mean a back cross has to use the the
technically the same cut to go back to
but maybe something that is very NL
because one thing I'll say about that
dog [ __ ] grown indoor is boy does it
look like 90s weed like lime green with
bright orange hairs and it just has that
like NL type of like like look I was
gonna say Hydro but uh Caleb is purely
organic so I don't want to insult them
it's just that like that like big sack
of hydro and NL that you would get you
know that's just super Frosty and stuff
like that and so
um you know but it might give it some
stretch and some Vigor and it might kind
of like and that's kind of like what I
like one of the things that I get
interested about is crossing two
different things that you think have
similar parentage behind them yes and
then you see if you get some throwbacks
because both parents have it yeah I I do
have the dog [ __ ] in uh my latest round
but
so you know but it's it's getting across
to that that chocolatey
um
nl5 mail and honestly uh I think there
were better uh there are males that
kind of looked more similar to dog [ __ ]
but uh
um I you know I I didn't use them
personally for this round
um because I liked that you know
particular you know chocolatey one and
if I was gonna throw out one more
recommendation and combine the old with
the new
um one of Neville's most classic
combinations was uh nl5 and skunk
and I kind of view uh the diesel family
as cert what we have is surviving modern
skunk not that there's not cheese and a
couple other things like that but I kind
of view like sours as American skunk
right or very very skunkish so it would
be kind of cool to see like what we have
now is skunk and what we have now is NL
Blended back together
right
um because that was one of the most
classic best-selling and they combined
super well yeah
um I definitely have cheese in there too
so you know
are you talking skunk one or skunk
I mean I that's cheese is fine that's
obviously pure skunk one that's very old
I was just thinking of certain diesels
just because I consider I consider
certain diesels uh modern that to me
that even though it doesn't have the
name I consider a diesel to be like a
skunk skunk skunkoid type plant right
right it's tall it's rangy you know it's
it's got that kind of skunk type growth
to it it's got these very I basically
think of like gas and Diesel as it's not
like roadkill but it is on that skunk
Spectrum
it's like different angles of the same
Terps yeah you know yeah that's kind of
how I see it so you know
um
but yeah and then the other thing too is
that you know he you know you cross it
to things you hope are gonna cross well
and then you cross it to some things
that are just random and sometimes those
random ones end up being the best ones
because you really don't know and you
really don't know what genes are gonna
pop right right and you really don't
know what recessives are in there
true true right like so to take it back
to humans unless both parents have the
gene you can't have kids with blue eyes
or green eyes you know you if if one
parent has the recessive the other
parent has the dominant it won't combine
right blonde hair is the same way both
parents have to have the blonde hair
gene or the red hair gene or it won't
pop
and so sometimes if you take two things
that you think might have similar genes
you might get some recessives that pop
and all of a sudden something unusual
comes out you know
yeah yeah
so
yeah well I promise to to not hold Caleb
too long I know he's got some [ __ ] to do
tonight too so I I'm thankful for you
coming and talking about the Northern
Lights I know everybody's super stoked
to be able to hear about it firsthand
um but yeah is there anything else you
want to talk about before we all balance
uh I think I'm good I gotta go Wrangle a
five-year-old beast at least yeah we
know you know uh Friday night isn't the
easiest night for you so we super
appreciate you coming on and shooting
the [ __ ] and all that you know and uh
you know I briefly saw your face in the
shadows there for a minute before the
pitch black kicked in
um but yeah you know
um that's that's kind of it we wanted to
chat about NL we wanted to chat about
the history we wanted to clear up some
misconceptions and we wanted people to
hear about some of the specifics of what
was available How It Was Made what you
what we saw in it
um and let people go from there
so as always everyone thank you for
giving us part of your Friday night you
know Caleb uh where do you where where
can people find your seats again
uh Humboldt
csi.com there you go yeah humboldtsi.com
we'll grab the nl5 please
experience it make sure you let them
know about yours too yeah I got it too
but but you know support the man
yeah so you know both both guys have it
you can get them both off each of their
individual websites
um they were communicating a bunch
during the during the grow they were
talking about what he was seeing sharing
pictures and just you know and all that
and so
um you know it's how a lot of people
tell a lot of passion projects get made
today is with uh uh people that have
similar interests collaborating and
making it work so support it if you can
if you you know it'd be great
uh and it would spread out some old
genetics and it would keep them alive
and you could do your little part to
make sure that the gene pool stays wider
and hopefully find some fire
yeah so you know everybody enjoy their
Friday night uh as always there's a
million questions we didn't get to
um but you can always hit us up on our
Discord matters
patreon yeah Matt and I chat up there a
whole bunch we're pretty responsive to
questions and all that and so you know
every every Friday night we'll try to
bring you something new and pertinent
and interesting and bring on various
friends we have uh and all that and uh
kind of just push the history and the
info forward
and at the very least you'll get seen
not so naked all right thanks everyone
thank you enjoy everyone you have a
great night good night cheers