so we're just going to assume that we're
here what's up everybody how's everybody
doing welcome to uh breed of Syndicate
today we're going to go and talk about
the sequel to what we were discussing
last uh episode which was the early
years of the deaf seed banks
yep so I mean kind of last year we uh or
last last time so to speak we chatted a
lot about how they got started we
chatted about Neville and all that and
we kind of
um we kind of took us took everybody
through like the first three or four
years
um you know I see that there's a bunch
of cool questions this week that have
already popped up so we'll get to that
in a little bit but we're going to kind
of start on
um we're gonna kind of start and take
you guys through like
um the last say like 10 years or so of
uh
of Neville's influence and kind of his
history so uh you know we got a bunch of
notes and things like that we'll hold up
some stuff on occasion to give you guys
some ideas all that all that type of
stuff so
um you know uh probably the easiest way
to start is to say that in uh in 1990 in
um that was kind of when Neville had
been in business like three years or so
and that's when he kind of started to
sort out like favorites among amongst
what's he what he had he had had to uh
he'd collected a number of cuttings from
America by then he dealt with a bunch of
breeders by then he had
um bread with a number of these things
for three or four years in some cases at
this point and that's where his uh
collection started to go from sort of a
a hodgepodge grab bag of things to more
of the famous stuff that we all became
familiar with when we started getting
into weed history uh Northern Lights one
Northern Lights two uh G13 you know hash
plant NL you know NL hazes and stuff
like that so
um 88 to 90 is kind of really when
um people are probably like more
familiar with that stuff yeah because he
you know he's he'd sort of settled on
what worked for him yeah right where
before he'd been just kind of playing
around with everything he really didn't
know what he'd had people had sent him
stuff people had he'd bought things off
various folks and he you know but these
are just names to him to us you get NL
you get Maple Leaf you get Haze that all
means something because there's a lot of
history behind it but probably to him
there was just a lot of they were just
literally names from dudes well early on
he was sourcing a lot of seeds and later
on and over those three years he became
a breeder as opposed to just sourcing
and passing on genetics he actually
started working lines which is which is
where these amazing lines come from yeah
and he he and he had done a bunch of
breeding and he sort of figured out what
was an inconsistent pain in the ass for
lack of a better term and what was
consistent
um you know Neville was always
um he was always sensitive to what
people wanted uh you know he wanted to
sell seeds he wanted to make people
happy and so uh people weren't happy a
lot of times with incredibly variable
stuff that didn't perform well and so he
uh you know he had started to figure out
what males were good to use repeatedly
um what females were Champs and bred
well with lots of different stuff and so
we're gonna we're gonna start kind of
you know walking through some of that
type of thing okay which one do you want
to start with first
um
maybe we should start with we kind of
talked a lot about uh Northern Lights
last time that was probably one of the
things that we expounded upon the most
yeah so maybe we could chat about
because 1988 is when things dramatically
changed yeah uh in that regard from 85
to 87 he just sort of sold a variety of
Weird Hybrids of Northern Lights and you
kind of got you just bought straight NL
Northern Lights it was a grab bag of all
the different types yeah well by by 88
he had decided that there was two lines
that really made the most sense nl1 and
nl2 yeah nl1 was sort of like a
broadleafed Afghan
um possibly you could call it a Bubba
type you know wisely Frosty golf ball
type uh you know nugs almost maybe
slightly yellowish
and that was probably one of his most
consistent lines he had because he took
all the northern lights and he bred them
together yeah right uh independently and
so in 88 he offered what was called nl1
F3
yes and nl2 F3 I wish I could put these
up on the screen but I can't because I
don't have the controls yeah we'll just
have to read it we'll just have to read
it so so basically
um you know those two things they became
and we'll talk about a little bit more
later but these kind of became like
Mainstays in cannabis for quite some
time they became permanent editions
right yeah as well as that as well as
offering them pure so let's figure he
gets them at 80 84. he starts messing
around with them in 85-ish by 88 he'd
had you know three years of having them
he'd taken them to F3 right and he was
releasing them as a more consistent
variety yeah and so that's the for 88 is
the first is the first year that those
two things pop up right and it's also
the first year that you start seeing so
in addition to offering both of those
strains as straight itself you start
seeing nl2 and nl1 being used as
breeding males in all kinds of stuff
that he had
right
um nl1 there's probably nothing that he
used as much as a breeding male as nl1
is that the the biggest one biggest
focus on the company is a male overall
looking back yeah I would say so I mean
you can you can look at stuff and
um you know he a lot of the you know a
lot of the stuff that he had you know
that he got his cuttings for instance
um like hash plant
um hash plant he first offered his hash
plant by no one yeah he gets big butt as
a cutting he offers it as big bud by nl1
yeah
um you know he gets uh he gets a variety
of things and he starts Crossing it by
nl1 88 is interesting too because you
know he had gotten these old Haze seeds
from Sam Skunk Man
and uh in addition to some other people
in Holland and 88 is the first year that
any kind of haze hybrid pops up and it's
one that maybe a lot of people haven't
heard of right yeah uh it's very weird
it's Haze by nl1
uh and so it was only offered for one
year
but what's unique about it is that all
the other Haze hybrids he offered used
Haze as a male yeah this actually was a
female that he found that he called
Hayes B yes right so there's this one
year where all of a sudden you could get
Haze B by nl1 and of all things it was
nl1 Rooter always yeah
so uh that's the first time that Haze
pops up that I'm aware of in a catalog
in Holland
okay I think so yeah you know that's
that's I do think you're right
um and it was because he hadn't settled
on he had you know he he was still
experimenting a little bit but he'd
figured out some things yeah right it
also
um he'd gone to America
and he had acquired through Jorge
cervantes's Connections in the Pacific
Northwest uh in the Oregon uh Washington
area uh Jorge had hooked him up with
some unknown uh Growers and those
unknown Growers gave him G13 and what
became known as the Pacific Northwest
hash plant
uh both of those things ended up getting
used pretty extensively in future years
yeah right
so
um
you know he he also I don't know if I
don't know if Matt can show it or not
but
he the 87 update I don't know I can't do
it I don't know you don't you can't do
it so he offered this 87 update one of
the things that was cool about novel is
that he he gave a lot more data on what
the hell he was doing versus most other
breeders it was just extensive
especially in that 87 update that's
really like more of data than most
Growers back then would have even given
a [ __ ] oh yeah I'm glad he did he he
lays it out right so yeah
um you know he uh he starts talking
about it and he talks about basically
both the hash plant and the big bud that
he crossed to nl1 yes and then he took
that and he back crossed it uh males of
that back to the original and so that's
how he became that's how big bud and
hash plant actually got offered as as
separate strains yeah is he used nl1
um to be reacts them for uh you know he
so so they're actually
um you know he never had seed lines of
those
right so and he lays out in like
extensive detail I can't show it to you
on the screen right now but he kind of
lays out like his like step by step how
he figured it out yeah what kind of he
knows we're going to be in it what you
could look for
um all that type of stuff and so that's
when 88 is when a lot of uh
that's when a lot of the famous stuff
that we all know of really pops up the
G13 hash plant I think pops up that year
I think it you know it does and then you
know he you know it he found some of
these some of these Indica strains these
you know he
um some of these Indica strains were a
lot more consistent than what he was
working with and so once you find
consistency you start Crossing them to
different things and
um you start
you know you start getting these various
hybrids sure of such so uh
you know I don't know
um and then 89.90 is really when like he
solidified
the sort of the lineup as it were and
that lineup ended up staying pretty
consistent
um
in in in the seed bank catalog and even
going into Scentsy
um a lot of that stuff ended up gets
getting ported over yeah so you could
kind of look at it and if you're
thinking about it in that way I would
say probably by the late 80s
probably the three most consistent
females that he used were
um
nl5
G13 yep and hash plant
yep those those were sort of the three
most common indicas that he would use as
as standard females the hash plant this
is the pnw hash plant cutting
still looks very similar yeah
after all these years they still looks
similar kind of ugly very ugly to be out
to be perfectly honest about it not the
by modern standards not particularly
pretty
and then as far as males go
by 89.90
you would say that the the most common
males he used was like I said before was
certainly nl1 he also used nl2 a bunch
yep
um you know and you know he you had
um Northern Lights five by Northern
Lights two you had G13 by nl2
yep um had Northern you had all kinds of
stuff by nl1 yeah
Hawaiian Indica was by nl1 Big Bud was
by nl1 hash plant was by nl1 uh that
Haze I spoke about was by nl1 Hawaiian
yeah all that stuff I'll answer one
quick question I see it coming on the
thing people talk about the Airborne and
the Pacific G13 Cuts uh those are a
little hazy but
um it's most likely they're not pure G13
they're most likely a G13 by nl2 like
that like that would be uh Fino popping
out of the seeds the Airborne popped
from Pacifica is a lot different
um that one that one is a lot has a lot
more of a cloudy history we know the
Breeders that offered it and stuff but
it never quite panned out the same as
Airborne as far as uh producing quality
and and stuff similar to G13
so yeah so and then
um aside from nl1 and nl2 uh the other
probably two most common males that he
used by you know 89.90 would have been
the haze mail uh and skunk one which
Hazel
um he you know the haze story it's
probably we could probably talk about it
a little bit yeah if you could brush up
on it brush on it we could brush on it
so
um so uh Sam Skunk Man uh flees America
and he comes over to your he comes over
to Europe and he's trying to get set up
and he has
um skunk one and Haze seeds and then
from Mel Frank he has Durban Poison and
Afghani one seeds and he has a couple
other uh seed lines that he'd collected
from the orange right California Orange
I think that was from Rob Clark oh was
that for Rob okay I believe so um he had
a number of things
um Paul uh Paul you know he had a number
of things from Rob Rob followed him out
later early Pearl early girl yeah the
Early Girl the
um you know the Pearl stuff early Pearl
uh some of the Mexicans that that
Neville offered uh those were from Sam
initially yeah but they were from
um
but they were from Rob yeah you know so
Sam ended up coming over
Sam ended up coming over to
um to Europe first in New York he kind
of brought a hodgepodge of various uh
collectors and and people's lines right
yeah um
and so uh
so you know there's there's a there's a
debate between
um well it's not a debate anymore
because Neville's passed unfortunately
but there was a long debate that was
likely never to be solved where
um Sam has a number of stories about the
early Haze and how it happened Neville
has his own stories that could be an
entire podcast in itself but suffice to
say that when Sam came over to uh Europe
he sold some Haze seeds to Neville
uh he sold some Haze seeds to uh the
founder of sssc
um he gave some to the owner of uh
positronics
um and maybe someone else maybe um there
was a few people at least at least three
people are documented to have gotten
um stuff from some from Sam right when
he came over right yeah I think that's
been pretty well done with the haze yeah
with the haze so uh Sam so Neville
Neville Neville's story just real quick
is there were a bunch of old seeds he
cracked a bunch of them uh most of them
did not pop uh and he the first female
he got he unfortunately killed because
it never finished flowering it took
forever it was a huge pain in the ass he
got another female which is the bee
which I spoke about
um
which I spoke about earlier as being the
first actual release and what really
became famous is he got two males which
he called A and C
right
um and sadly
and your audio's clipping a little bit
it is
yeah yeah I think so
my back
yeah yeah you're there but I mean it's
like it's hitting high points clipping
it should be good okay so
um he got two males uh A and C they both
ended up uh becoming kind of famous see
much more so and he he he crossed he
crossed the a to basically everything
every good Indica he had uh and he made
a mistake with his workers in 89 and he
lost the mail early so yeah ever he
never sold he never sold any commercial
uh he never sold any commercial seed of
a so everybody everybody that
um that gets nl5 Haze or any of that
other kind of haze crosses silver haze
all that it's all using the sea mail
because that's the one that survived
yeah right uh and strangely
um it seems like Neville had more
success finding fire in the haze seeds
that he got than other people did
yeah that's what it sounds like that's
what it sounds like I mean and it sounds
like he had 10 seeds total is what it
sounds like so he so there's debate in
that and there's yeah camp that believes
that he got similar things to everyone
else yeah and he just had better indicas
to cross them to than anybody else yeah
there's another camp that thinks that um
Neville claimed that Sam sold him old
seeds
that he said would have a low
germination rate that we're from 69 to
70. and maybe Sam and that maybe Sam
when he first got there sold some
original stuff before he did his open
pollinations in Holland and the people
that got a hold of that original first
batch of haze that he brought over with
him got better quality Haze than people
did later on yeah
uh it's not really a debate that we can
solve being that it's two dudes from
1984 1985. yeah right and they disagree
um you know but we do have you know all
three guys that he that well Neville and
the you know the guy from SSC and the
positronics gentleman they all agreed
that they got
Hayes seed from Sam at the same time at
the same time same year same time same
bag everything all that kind of stuff
and so we know you know we have we have
we have documentation from others that
that it certainly happened yeah
right and so that's when
um by 80 by 89.90 that's when all the
famous stuff you start hearing about
which is nl5 by Skunk one and a five by
two G13 by nl2
um you know nl5 by I think nl5 by Hayes
was actually released via catalog not
until 1880 990. here's a pretty picture
and I was just looking earlier and it's
nl5 it's a I think it's a much prettier
picture than on the back of a lot of the
catalogs that they show where it's just
like
a jumbled up close shot of some kind of
Frosty leaves this one is a much better
I think it gives a much better picture
of the bud structure overall growth
patterns and whatnot
so that's really interesting uh because
that's the famous nl5 cutting yeah
um a uh I'll answer a quick question
just because I was talking about it
somebody just asked where's Tom Hill's
Haze fits in yes and uh you know I would
say that uh Matt knows a bit more about
that than I but I believe that Tom Hill
got his hay stock from positronics yeah
it's the old positronics Haze I don't
know if I think it's the old positronics
Haze 19 based on all that so that that's
where
um Tom Hill's Hayes comes from one of
the uh you know one of the one of the
first people that gave and gave Hayes to
um positronics um
and
let's see here so lost my train of
thought for a second answering that
question but the nl5 that he was just
holding up maybe we can talk about that
for a second because that's true
interesting so Neville there's we were
talking about on the previous podcast
how there was always two famous cuttings
of ml5
um on the interview that Matt did with
uh Greg Seattle Greg of Northern Lights
Fame he said that he got a cutting of
nl5 and it was from his friend Herbie
who at Steve Murphy's Afghan and crossed
it to a Colombian Mexican yeah and that
was the cutting that he sent Neville
Neville claims he got that cut and he
didn't like it very much compared to the
cut that he found Neville story is that
he popped a bunch of nl5 seed lines
because that's one of the lines he got
from Greg and most of it was an Indica
sativa hybrid mess yeah it wasn't
particularly useful but he got this one
plan attempts that was what he called
the throwback plant that looked pure
Afghan and had no influence of sativa
whatsoever and as you see this short
stocky dense butted Frosty yeah that
picture
I would say leads up to
um to nebels you know Neville's story
being correct yeah
um and probably having some truth to it
because I would look at that thing and I
would not say it had any Colombian or
Mexican influence yes I would instantly
say that looks pure Afghani it would
look like a pure Afghan yeah to me at
least so
um
you know and uh so yeah I mean that
right there that's the famous nl5 Haze
that's the famous cutting that got
crossed the haze that got crossed the
skunk one that got crossed in Northern
Lights to
um and it's really you know we mentioned
it before but there was never a pure
seed line of nl5 offered there was one
hybrids correct
right there was only hybrids offered so
um
you know uh that's the cutting
there we go let's discuss the nl5 do you
want to go into
Maple Leaf Indica the big bud stuff like
that did we cover that I don't think we
covered that too too much so
um we won a second I gotta do something
with Murray go ahead and start talking
the uh
um
so the so basically once he once he
found that nl5 cutting
um like I said before that's when he
started Crossing it it became one of his
standards yeah you know in in the in the
situation
um and you know he had you know like he
crossed it to skunk one that became an
extremely famous strain uh Amplified by
Skunk one nl5 Haze is probably the most
famous line he did yeah I know five by
two is also Super Famous and uh so you
know he nl5 G13 hash plant those became
sort of his standard indicates yeah his
his best producing females uh skunk one
Haze
nl2 and nl1 became his most common
um
males yeah that he used and he offered
obviously he never offered a pure nl5
line or a pure uh Haze line but he did
offer pure nl1 pure nl2 pure skunk one
um you know that type of thing I you
know I never got to ask him why
the why of that why didn't you ever
offer Ace peer or nl5 pure
you know I think I think part of the
reason why he never offered uh Hayes
pure is because he's he's screwed up
early on and he lost too much of it yeah
he talked about later on wishing that he
could
um that he could cross the uh that he
would have been able to cross the B to
the a yeah
and he you know but he he lost the B
early
um because he didn't realize what he had
he lost the A on an accident and so he
sort of ended up with uh he sort of
ended up with not very much that he
knows he was like his most consistent
yeah what do you have what he had left
yeah
um you know and then strangely it seems
like for whatever reason all the other
people that got A's nothing much came of
yeah no matter how much breeding or
crossing they did nothing became famous
like the later Neville hazes so like
when I was going to when I was going to
coffee shops uh coffee shops were
um you know they were full of of C5
which is
uh nl5 AC 85 which is nl5 haze a uh
ag-13 which is G13 Hayes a they also
they also had a G13 hey c yeah they were
full of Neville work yep um they didn't
really carry much posi work they didn't
carry any Sam work they didn't carry any
of those things
um you know even though they were easily
accessible yeah those were standard
people in Holland so uh there must have
been a significant quality difference
yeah yeah it had to have been
um and you know I think even today
is there is there a famous Sam cut
is there a famous pot you know it's all
the stuff that they do is not really
all the stuff that they do is is all the
stuff that's hoarded over there yeah is
um you know is uh Whatchamacallit
Neville Cuts yeah and and right now I
just want to take the time if any of you
older gentlemen are watching this and
have all these cuts
give me a give me a ring I'd love to
just to be able to chat about them and
get and get further Histories on a lot
of these yeah I mean a lot of this stuff
you know one thing that should be
mentioned about this is uh all this
stuff happened on a different continent
and you know what uh the story sounds
pretty straightforward and simple right
now but the amount of talking and time
and energy and interviewing people and
trying to make sure that like it's not
just one person's opinion and we can get
other people to back up opinions on this
stuff takes a long time yeah
I mean me and you have been working
steady on this for I want to say three
years now just me and you together and
we've done our work on our own obviously
but like we have been pushing hard on
this so it's taken a long time to even
get up to this point to be able to say
any of these things positively yeah and
I mean when we say them positively uh
most of what we're saying is generally
accepted generally accepted fact for now
like you said if there's some Old-Timers
or whatever with some secret information
out there that's not well known most of
this history is oral some of these old
guys have beefs with one another some of
them don't like one another very much
yeah have their own Egos and their own
versions of of history and events
um and so uh see there's a guy right
there that just said it's his 70 year
old neighbor has had nl2 since 93.
um if that's the case uh possible we
would love to talk to you yeah yeah all
right
because there could be pockets of these
things that survive
yeah the hard part now is that for a
long time nobody gave a [ __ ] about these
uh about these strains and so the
information was a little bit more
verifiable because there wasn't anybody
trying to claim rep or trying to claim
we have this joke we call it pre-pre
um where now ancient old whatever has
come out of the woodwork so it gets a
lot harder to weed through who has what
yeah and like I I was talking with
another gentleman that we're we're
starting an interview with
um and he was very important in the
Dutch C team and he was talking about
some of his old lines possibly popping
up in the U.S
and this is something that happens every
few years someone says I've got this
stash of XYZ I've kept you know mason
jars full of every single one and done
reproductions since 80 something and
it's it's hard unless you have extensive
knowledge about these old lines and it
have run some how are you ever going to
tell him no that's not correct it's it's
a hard situation
yeah I mean there's a guy saying you you
know there's some old school Growers
um there's pockets in America that
aren't on Instagram that sure aren't on
on some of these they've never done on
the forums that live in police states
that have kept their circles quite tight
um they don't they might not even know
how rare or how cool
some of the stuff that's been within
their little circle that they've just
been growing and smoking on might be you
know so we still have hope every time a
[ __ ] artist comes up I'll freely
admit that there's a small part of me
that wishes it was true yeah yeah I just
want it to be true I want all the
stories to be true I want every ancient
rare being imaginable
to be accessible yeah cuts and stuff
like yeah to pop up and be
um you know and be available to people
sure um sadly there's a lot of people
out there that are just trying to make a
quick buck
uh and when you sell beans I mean think
about how many people have been selling
beans of uh roadkill skunk for the last
two or three years now right yep
um but I haven't seen any roadkill skunk
flower yeah it's hard it's hard to get
finished flour with roadkill Terps
everybody's figuring that out you know
and you can sell beans for quite some
time before nobody you know and exactly
and take a while before they realize
that you're not finding roadkill skunk
exactly and sell a lot of beans and
there's people that have dropped
thousands of dollars of you know hopes
and dreams and spent months hunting and
they get some floral Citrus skunk ones
Citrus skunk one resold them skunk one
it's like you know slight Funk slight
whatever not roadkill not clear skunk
Terps
um so you know it's uh it's sad in that
way
um you know people were asking some
other stuff and you know we got a lot to
cover so we'll we'll move on a bit but
to say
89.90 is when Neville really established
most of the strains that kind of became
famous yes yes that's when they all
started popping up that's when they all
started popping up that's when he sort
of figured out what he had what was
consistent to breed with what made sense
what lines people liked uh you know he's
had this running joke that people would
ask for the highest level of quality
imaginable and if he sold them an
awesome Indica that was a hybrid of two
pure indicas and it yielded like [ __ ]
they'd [ __ ] and [ __ ] and moan and
whine and complain because they wanted
the best possible and they also wanted
to crush yields yes so that's always
been a difficulty in in cannabis
um you know people want the best people
want the greatest Terps uh there's lots
of people out there in commercial world
that don't want to grow anything that
takes longer than nine or ten weeks yeah
they don't be a pain to trim wanted to
be larfy they don't want it the finicky
or low Peter massive yielding Frosty the
highest amount of chirps yeah
everybody's 20 THC I want the strongest
most potent weed you can possibly
imagine with crazy herbs and I want
donkey dick Buds and I want it done in
50 days yeah send it
yeah but you know rarely does that occur
yeah same package sadly yeah you know a
lot of the a lot of the famous strains
that we all smoke
um from a production standpoint are
annoying yeah very much especially at
the last decade or so it's gotten worse
nobody would ever pick to grow cookies
no nobody would ever pick to grow Kush
where it's like dink dink dink dink dink
yeah nugs here and there they don't hold
themselves up I mean if you were like a
commercial farmer in the real world
um you know they'd be looking for some
kind of like green crack blue dream
type structure
top to bottom buds easy to grow fairly
fast finishing you know that's what from
a production standpoint uh and a
happiness standpoint that's what you
want yeah but you know
um even Sour Diesel you know that yields
pretty well takes a long time kind of
feathery makes a lot of debugs if you
mess up it can be really larfy
um you know super tasty and it works
really good it burns really nice but
it's not blue dream no it's not
it's not you know Barry White or
something like that it's not something
that that's just covered in Nubs
and so
um so yeah so uh the uh uh maybe we
should talk about so he created all this
stuff Neville was the largest there was
really only two you know there's other
people that will claim to have seed
banks yeah Scentsy seeds had a tiny seed
bank positronics had a small seed bank
or was other seed banks in Holland but
there was really only two seats and this
is really why we're spending so much
time talking about it is in the 80s
there was really only two seed banks
that were selling a lot of seafood
America in in Amsterdam in it's selling
to America correct and they were the
first two seed banks that really offered
worldwide sales to anybody that was
willing to come to Holland and buy them
or fill out their their mail order sheet
and send them an envelope with some
money and a list yep and that was super
sativa seed Club
uh and the seed bank which was Neville
yes 50 seed club uh started a little bit
after Neville
um it had similar things to him it had
some of their own stuff but Neville was
the he was the elephant he was the big
dog he was yeah he was the he was the
one selling the vast majority of stuff
that people in America were buying from
Holland was Neville's yes and that
really that's really what makes them so
important because
the uh the seed game is super
Diversified now
right he basically almost had a monopoly
yeah and it's why all these strains that
are around today usually have something
of Neville's in it if not both sides
yeah and so that there's a lot of
there's a lot of Neville work in a lot
of modern trains yeah
um simply because he was the only game
and he was one of the only games in town
and tons and tons of people got his
stuff and then they bred his stuff into
stuff they already had in America yeah
and so his stuff got Blended in
and you know his stuff got super famous
obviously the nl5 haze became a
phenomenon in New York
it started being it started being sold
you know they call it the heist Haze you
know the pith the church the this the
that whatever
a massive thing
um and the super skunk uh you know
became Super Famous uh as well
um he's talked about how super skunk and
nl5 Hayes were his two top selling
varieties
yeah
you know and so enormous amounts of
those seeds got sold right yeah and
that's sort of what uh maybe we can talk
so the 90 catalog is the final catalog
of Neville's ownership of the seed bank
yeah I don't think I have that one here
um and that there's a couple there's
there's the most famous thing that came
out of the 90 catalog was who released
um super skunk yes uh Super Skunk was
you know when sadly
uh Sam did not like skunk
he didn't well you gotta say he Sam
liked skunk one he did not like skunk
smells he didn't like skunk Aroma yeah
Aroma he took skunk one
and he tried to breed the skunk out of
it that is by his own quote right
yes he did he has his own quote he was
going for more of the Citrus grapes
sweet floral he liked those Aromas he
was going for bud structure and other
things yeah he didn't like the rank
skunk he tried to
uh this so I'll answer another question
the silver Pearl came out as a single
strain I think in the last two years of
the seed bank uh 88 89 and 90. yeah he
offered silver Pearl and I
quote me on the on Silver polich
I think it's I think it's early Pearl it
might be nl5 early Pearl skunk one
something along those lines something
like that yeah yeah yeah uh let's see I
only see early Pearl improved in this
one and it doesn't list anything but
yeah it's something like that it's
something like that and he also released
uh silver Pearl by Hayes in those couple
years which was called Silver Haze
uh at the time uh he called it he called
it
silver Pearl by Haze yeah um I got
shortened the silver silver haze at
Scentsy so he um
you know there was a guy named Jim
Ortega that we'll talk about real
briefly and
um Jim Ortega he traded with Jim gave
him kush for garlic Bud
um
uh Maple Leaf indica and Hawaiian Indica
yeah he offered Hawaiian Indica by nl1
in the last couple years of his catalog
maybe three years of his catalogs he
offered a maple leaf
um a pure
yes called it
a Afghan breeder packs I think where you
could literally buy some of the Original
Seed stock that Jim Ortega gave him you
know how amazing would that have been
yeah I mean and he
um and he offered garlic Bud as a pure
strain uh the only thing that never
really got offered is a pierced that
never really got messed with too much
was kush four yeah there is a thing he
sold called Kush by Kush
Push by Kush which he said he crossed
his two best pushes to um
you know uh to each other and his two
best coaches were cush four and nl2
do you know what year that one's in I
was trying to show it but I can't find
it
I'm gonna say that one's in here that
one might be an 87. here's at least one
of them in the 89 talking about it I
don't know how clear it is
and he also offered skunk Kush which was
and so that's that's you know and then
uh
um
so maybe
we're getting pretty in depth here but
yeah maybe maybe we should talk about
um his Fame led to issues right yes
let's get into that he's selling
millions of dollars in seed to America
yeah right it's the Reagan Era and then
the George Bush era it's the height of
the War on Drugs large penalties weeds
totally illegal everywhere
um and there was a situation in which a
um a hydro store got rated
um from whatever reason some kind some
kind of action and they discovered that
this guy was supplying a bunch of
Growers and in that they found money and
Neville's catalogs
and they realized that uh
they realized that he was selling up the
dollars in seed
um to America and you notice in some of
these back catalogs it always says that
it shipped from the US or like in the
High Times uh ads for Neville's things
it would always say ship from U.S
well what's interesting about that is
this isn't factual but I believe it to
be true that Neville I think had
partners that he smuggled seeds into
America yeah
and then you would send Neville money
and then he would communicate what you
needed and they watched the seeds from
within the U.S yeah I think he was
pretty
um he was transparent about that when it
was going on
and so as a result of that that meant
that every seed batch didn't have to go
through customs yes you just had to get
it through customs occasionally
and then he could sell it within the
United States
uh the DEA and the government at the
time took a pretty uh poor view of that
aspect yeah right
and so
um operation green Merchant happens
where they decide to raid
um everyone every Growth Store in the
united for the most part they raided the
grow stores in the United States they
did a big push right and uh Neville gets
caught I believe in Australia yep and he
gets busted
okay uh and he ends up spending a good
amount of time in jail
better part of the year yeah
um and so that you know we're not gonna
this this this particular episode we're
not going to talk very much about sssc
because we're going to save that for a
different time
um but what that did is that sort of uh
um
led to a domino effect of sorts it had a
domino effect of sorts uh uh super
sativa seed Club decided to stop
um because they saw what was going on
with Neville and it was pretty serious
Neville was already in was obviously in
jail
and uh this gave an opportunity for
others yeah who had seen how how Neville
and the super sativa seed Club were
doing right it left a void in Amsterdam
uh in Holland it was still it was legal
at that time obviously to produce seed
for
um
to produce seed yeah the only places in
in the world where it was totally legal
to produce cannabis seed yeah
so uh Neville was sitting in jail
um he was fighting extradition
they didn't want an extradite Neville to
America because
um they wanted to put him in jail for
life in prison yeah
and Australia and Holland which he was a
citizen of both didn't agree with that
yeah so he was stuck in jail
uh and he
um
you know there was all of a sudden there
was no seed banks yeah there was no Key
Banks left it caused a bunch it caused a
bunch of Ripple effects uh a whole bunch
of growers in America got busted
um to their relationships with various
uh hydro stores and stuff like that
um you know uh Greg Seattle Greg talked
in his interview with Matt about how by
the late 80s and that era they had
basically lost everything because of a
series of rolling busts yeah uh there
were heavy presence they were really
going after people electricity all this
kind of stuff and so
um
Scentsy which was founded by Ben and
Alan dronkers they saw an opportunity
and they offered to bail Neville out of
jail
and uh give them money to help him fight
his situation as long as he sold them
their company yes
and that was the invention of Scentsy so
crazy that was the death of the seed
bank feed Bank yeah and Scentsy uh since
he absorbed him
and all of a sudden went from a nobody
to the biggest game in town that's right
um and they bought uh they they bought
his feedback
right yeah so sudden they start offering
um you know and we actually the Sensei
91 seed bank catalog is one of the
rarest catalogs
um because it only was out for his
office building out for one year and it
shows the merger of the seed bank with
Scentsy
and they have a much much more limited
catalog than what they offered in the
future and a much more limited one than
Neville was currently offering but by
the time he split so
um yeah and so as a result of that uh
sadly for Neville Neville went from
being the owner of the largest most
successful seed bank in the world to the
Head breeder
of Scentsy yeah he lost his company
he lost his self-control
uh the government hated him yeah uh and
he was trapped in Holland for a long
time
because the the America wanted to come
steal him yeah got him to America and
have him face charges of life in prison
for seed sales yes Holland refused to
extradite him because since seed sales
were legal and he was a citizen of
Holland they were not going to extradite
one of their citizens for doing
something that was legal in their own
country yes then we go to life in prison
in some other country in some other
country he is not a citizen yeah and
some other countries not a citizen so he
had his freedom
but he was stuck in Holland
the DEA in Interpol was after his ass
yeah and he lost the biggest most most
uh famous seed company and had to give
it to Ben and Allen drunkers and work
for them yeah any didn't he lose the
castle as well at that point yeah he
lost the castle
um
there was a number of projects He had
that when he was in jail
never saw the light of day yeah he was
planning on releasing a uh nl5 seed line
in 1991 yep um he had taken the nl5
cutting that Matt showed earlier and he
had bxed it like eight times yeah
um he used nl1 like I said with
everything uh he bxed it eight times and
he was planning on releasing it in
um 1991 and it disappeared yeah that
project disappeared it never got
released again
and so there was some things uh
somebody asked if they could see it
again which one you know five the nl5
yep yeah
here we go
so yeah so
so obviously that sucked for Neville
uh spending a good 10 months jail is no
fun jail Foods no fun being in in you
know concrete jungles no fun
losing your company's no fun yeah your
companies know I mean yeah it's like
basically they were like hey we'll do
you a solid we'll get you out of jail
and we'll get you back to Holland but we
want your [ __ ] Yeah by a minor
competitor at that someone that wasn't
even close to the level he since he
wasn't even close to where super sativa
seed club or the exactly they were a
nobody compared to that and so you're
sitting in jail and your options are
keep sitting in jail
or have these sort of uh greasy Dutch
businessmen uh offer to get you out and
get you home and give you some money and
buy your company yeah it sounds real
good at the time sure you know he chose
the get out of jail yeah
you know uh card
but then he lost control
yeah
so
um you know that was sort of the start
of you know by the time that uh Matt
Matt can speak to this a little bit he
got to communicate quite a bit with
Neville I I got to meet in it a few
times uh I've chatted with him a number
of times Matt had a much longer back and
forth with him uh much later in his
career that sounded super dirty and well
I just mean that you know no I know what
you mean they communicated a lot more
over a lot more months a lot more
directly yeah than you know I met him
through other people I used to go to
Holland quite a bit to get seeds and I
ended up meeting him a few times I was a
young guy guy it's not like I had some
kind of uh you know massive uh
information dump from Neville to myself
yeah I wasn't interviewing him in or
anything like that I was a little
shell-shocked uh yeah meeting somebody
like that so
um but you know Matt can attest that uh
that was sort of the start of Neville's
bitterness
yeah yeah uh you know uh things Neville
paid more of a price than most yeah he
did or uh spreading seeds for
overgrowing the government for that kind
of thing
um and if you felt like he was owed the
most for doing this and so you know he
felt like most people lived off the back
of his work yeah and and it's not
necessarily incorrect
yeah he never got
um he never he never got to reap the
benefits as much
of his work as other people did
um his life got burned down on any
number of different occasions yeah that
should be said you know this is kind of
a personal part and not
um not uh
it's not the greatest thing to talk
about with Neville but he was a heretic
yeah that's actually the reason why he
went from Australia to Holland was uh
you know you know he was getting he was
uh heavily addicted in the early 80s he
was getting treatment
um and so I'm sure
um that some of his life issues were
certainly self-inflicted sure because
when you struggle with addiction like
that your life is
um
I mean your life is tough tell me about
it
you have ups and downs sure uh you have
issues you know you you probably wasn't
the easiest person to deal with he
probably had moods major mood swing sure
change your mood swings you know better
days than others better months than
others type of thing
um you know and then on top of that like
you know a lot of times really talented
people
um sometimes they're pain in the ass
yeah
talented people can be very hard to
communicate with sure
um but what I will say about Neville
that was different than most people is
that most Dutch which is some which is
different than a little bit in America
certainly there's lots of people in
America that are just like this yeah but
um in
he was probably one of the only Dutch
that really loved the plant
and really did things as far as the
famous Dutch I'm not like making some
big general statement about everybody
but of course as far as like the you
know the Dutch are pretty famous for
being extremely business oriented
correct they'll tell you the truth as
much as it helps their bottom line yeah
and if it doesn't help their bottom line
they could give a [ __ ] yeah so Neville
was extremely open about lines and
strains and what he used and how he did
it what he did it with and where he got
it from yeah there's nobody in the Dutch
scene that we know more about who he got
strains from
and what he did to create strains all
everything yeah a lot of other seed
banks in Holland it's a mystery they
have zero interest in telling you yeah
they've had decades to tell you they
don't care yeah there are a few that
might be popping up that that uh are are
pretty interesting that's why I wanted
to make a qualifier because he's by no
means is the only one yeah but there are
plenty of you know and that's the sad
thing is that
um you know Ben uh the drunkers are
still alive correct yeah but they're a
terrible interview yeah and they don't
care about history no that's not their
interest at all they will tell you to
this day that they have every original
plant known to man they lead with all
the same plants they still make their
own seeds they still make their own
seeds even been verified by any number
of different sources that they Outsource
to Spain sometime yeah yeah and that
they lost a lot of plants
um but you can't get actual history out
of them correct yeah
they don't care it's hard Neville
Neville cared while he had the seed bank
he gave a bunch of information he was
honest about when he lost certain
strains popped up on Mr Nice a long time
later in like 09 uh 10 11 era he asked a
lot of questions pretty directly yeah
um the dronkers and Scentsy are a black
hole Yeah they don't tell you [ __ ] major
black hole they don't care and I don't
know that they even know [ __ ] to tell um
obviously they do and they were part of
but I don't know that they would have
any kind of knowledge about any of the
breeding going on at Scentsy
and so you know this is um so so that's
kind of I guess we kind of segued into
Scentsy yeah
so we're headed into Senti we're headed
into Scentsy so Neville you know Neville
had the seed bank most famous seed bank
created a lot of the most famous strains
gets busted spends much time in jail
gets bailed out loses his company now
he's head breeder at something yeah
um and so it took some time to
transition
yeah so Matt and I have spent a bunch of
time analyzing this
and um
I don't know the best way to put it but
Scentsy there were certain famous things
like nl5 Haze and uh Super Skunk that
they left alone because the aim already
had such great
uh
that's that uh
it had already been marketed under that
name and was already so successful if
they didn't have a need to change
there's actually some pretty good
comments happening I'll get to them in a
minute maybe we can even [ __ ] you can't
see stuff so
um so anyway well
this is this is super long-winded but it
is pretty important and the reason why
it's so important is that the a lot a
lot a lot of our famous strains and our
named Elite cuts from the 90s and a lot
of the things that went into the Famous
Cuts that we all worked with today came
directly from Neville's work yeah
because he was the biggest game in town
um probably from 1985 to the late 90s he
was the biggest Force
in cannabis
and so as a result of that the tons of
people in America were getting in seeds
and
um
okay so there's there's stuff coming in
that people are saying that's actually
pretty cool so we'll start chatting
about that so uh so Scentsy buys the
seed bank
and they in my opinion they wanted to
obscure
exactly how much of the seed bank they
had taken yeah and they wanted to trade
so like I said super skunk nl5 Haze some
of the stuff that was super famous
already they left alone
but they were the first company to start
trademarking names in cannabis which
still goes on today and sucks yeah
there's still battles going on about
about that and so uh
uh I see some stuff people are talking
about early Shiva Shanty had garlic bud
in it anyone remember the early Shiva
Shanty that threw garlic thinos
uh that type I have one of the catalogs
it actually talks about that
specifically that very first catalog
remember I was just reading it to you
yeah so that's pretty funny in the sense
that my opinion is is that Shiva Shanti
is garlic Bud yeah one of them is one of
them at one point was garlic butter
and so I'll try not to get too deep into
it because it's kind of a it's it's kind
of a nerdy subject but if you look at
the seed bank catalogs and you look at
the Scentsy catalogs
um
since he ended up using a lot of
Neville's stock photos yes a lot of his
verbiage and his descriptions
just much shorter versions of them in
his catalog
um so uh they she garlic Bud disappears
yes but it becomes Shiva Shanti Shiva
Shanty one and it sounds like a hybrid
of becomes Shiva Shanti too right and so
they use the same they use a lot of the
same verbiage in describing Shiva Shanti
as Neville's descriptions of garlic bud
and the same picture they use the exact
same photo okay
um another one that we could talk about
is nl5 skunk one
becomes uh Shiva skunk yep
and that's actually the only one that
they change the name that in the Scentsy
description they actually say it's
actually nl5 skunk one yeah but they
still leave that in the description it's
literally in the description they took
it from nl5 skunk one they called it
Shiva they called it Shiva yeah this is
something that people will probably find
extremely interesting
um or maybe maybe not but uh Neville's
nl2 F3
he always referred to going back early
as the nl2 any description you can find
in the seed bank catalog of any hybrids
he made not only does he call it nl2 but
he always calls it a Hindu Kush type
yeah
so when Northern Lights gets ported over
from the seed bank Northern Lights
one F3 be completely Northern Lights
yeah right
um and you can actually tell because
they ins in the Scentsy catalog they
list Northern Lights as a three-time
Indica winner yep 88 89 90 and you can
look it up and nl1 was the Indica winner
in 88 89 90. yep
nl2 becomes Hindu Kush
yes
so since he changed the name and
and
nl2 use the same picture they use
similar descriptions you can go back
um even even straight up in certain
stuff like they they sold a skunk cush
yeah and they called it skunk one by
their best Hindu Kush yeah
Neville sells the skunk Kush at the seed
bank and he calls it nl2 by Skunk one
yeah
they call it the same name they have the
same description except for they just
call it Hindu Kush yeah right so nl2
doesn't disappear
it just gets a different name yeah it's
absorbed differently is that there was
another seed company that stole nl2 and
they sold nl2 it was Dutch Passion and
they saw nl2 under the name Oasis
and then
um Adam dumb I think his name is he sold
one is closet queen that was also in nl2
purana so nl2 sort of drops off as a
name
but it lives on in other names and
that's sort of start of uh
that's sort of the start of
um the rename game yeah this is all the
real early rename game so I'll just read
off some renames he had the renames uh I
gotta look away at the camera so I can
actually like see this little chart I
got going on but okay Neville called it
silver Pearl by Hayes
uh since he calls it silver haze yeah
um garlic Bud becomes Shiva Shanti
uh like I just said and all one becomes
Northern Lights and L2 becomes Hindu
Kush big skunk which was Big Bud by
Skunk one at the scene simply become
Scentsy skunk that's right hash plant by
nl1 by swazi becomes African queen
that's my other nickname that a lot of
people call me African queen big bud by
nl1 simply becomes big bud
Hawaiian Indica by nl1 simply becomes
Hawaiian Indica yep
um it was really only a few of the most
famous like skunk one
uh you know nl5 Haze Super Skunk that uh
that kept the name yeah they changed
everything else but they left us Clues
because they were [ __ ] lazy yeah out
of laziness pure laziness they use the
same pictures and they use a lot of the
same verbiage yeah and they even kept
the same yields and harvest Harvest
times and other data that Neville
included yeah
um so they made it
so they made it uh and then they
trademarked those things yes
so then all of a sudden they own the
trademarks yep
right
um
let's see where
where is a good segue from that
um
I can't even bring up my notes no fine
you know you're right so Shiva like I
said Shiva Shanti it is garlic Bud yeah
it uses the same verbiage in the
description it uses the exact same photo
from Neville catalogs it is
it is the Garlic but I had that pulled
out earlier just to show too the the
tube side by side but I can't remember
where I put it it's yeah we don't I mean
it's it's yeah it's we could we could uh
we could go we could go in depth I'm
trying to keep it relatively brief but
the point is is that since he was trying
to obscure just how much they went from
a little company that had barely
anything yeah do the biggest company
um
the biggest company in Holland and
the timeline we're talking right now
this is 1991. yeah
uh this is this is early to mid 90s Mr
Nice is I'm just answering a question Mr
Nice is way way later we probably won't
even get to that part of cannabis today
because that didn't start early 2000s
yeah so
Neville's working as the head breeder
for um
for Scentsy and we're not going to talk
about these companies very much but it's
probably good to mention that Neville
not only spawned Scentsy seeds
but everybody working for Neville
got their own ideas and he spawned a lot
yeah
so I don't know if uh
um well yeah somebody just posted Shiva
Shanti as not garlic now uh it was sweet
we'll get to why things aren't the way
they are anymore yeah but
Adam Dunn from th seeds
um uh is that how you pronounce his last
name
Adam Adam from th seeds uh Simon who is
famous for serious seeds yeah Tony who
ended up making sag Martha they all
worked at Scentsy under Neville
yeah and they after leaving uh Tony and
Simon started cerebral seeds in 1994 for
one year and then split Tony made sag
Martha uh Simon made
um Sirius and um
you know and uh uh let's see and Adam
like I said made THC yeah so
um you know so Neville working with
Neville you know uh Neville sort of put
all four of those companies on the map
yep those companies would have existed
if they hadn't been able to work either
for Neville under Neville uh since he
bought Neville
um so you know and I think that for most
of Neville's time it's Scentsy he was
breeding and doing a bunch of projects
but uh you look at the catalogs that
come out from those 90s in those early
to mid 90s period and
it's basically the seed bank catalog
yeah
basically you know there was a few
things that Neville got rid of in at the
later era of the seed bank like he
didn't really like Afghani one yeah he
sold it for the first few years of the
seed bank and then he and then he
eliminated it since he brought it back
um there was a couple other strains that
uh that popped up here and there but for
the most part
um Scentsy was the seed bank continued
and uh they they absorbed all of his
history
you know they started claiming her from
85 they started oh yeah the originator
of all these various strains they sort
of like you know since they bought it
they bought all the history too
um
and all that
and so Neville was working for some uh
some Dutch businessmen that he didn't
really like yeah
that's how it ends up
yeah so
um so he worked for Scentsy and we can
since nothing much changed from the seed
bank to Scentsy
um we don't really have to talk a bunch
about that except for uh you know I
started going to Amsterdam in uh 1994.
there's some very famous people on IG
and stuff that started going in the
early 90s and mid 90s and stuff and
since he was one of the primary places
where we got things yeah
so you know
um Sensei was really Neville yeah it was
all his stuff he was their head breeder
still
um and uh you know and so you know
Neville from
you know 85 to 90 at the seed bank and
then from 91 to 95 at Scentsy
um you know a massive amount of super
skunk and nl5 Haze all the nl5 haze you
know of the Cuban black the pith the
heights Haze the various the Miami that
all came from that era yeah of uh you
know nl5 Haze seed
um and he uh you know they lost the G13
cutting by Neville's own admission and
about 93 was one of the ones that got
sick and died early yeah lost the nl5
haze cutting
um they're 94.95
it's one of the reasons why all the best
Finos of nl5 hey
and um and in uh uh America were found
sort of between 89 and 95. yeah
um and then once the once the mom was
lost people didn't really find the same
quality I don't think I think all the
name deletes of nl5 haze of which
there's probably eight or twelve yeah
they all come from that six year period
yeah
I don't think there's any that come
later
I doubt it and I haven't seen any good
in on five phase cuttings in a long time
in that era and so
um
you know uh so well maybe we'll tie a
bow on the Scentsy thing because we've
kind of covered most of it yeah by the
uh the last famous thing that never
Neville did there was he was working on
this hybrid
um which was nl5 Haze uh or people call
it C5 now it's still alive he had this
he had a very famous mother cut that was
sold in all the coffee shops it was one
of the two of his two favorite C5
cuttings
um and he was trying to play around and
make a poly hybrid and he was playing
with Crossing it to skunk Hayes yeah and
he wasn't really happy with where it was
yet
but Ben and Alan dronkers being uh uh
businessmen they had spent a bunch of
money and they were sponsoring the 95
Cannabis Cup and the Cannabis Cup was
all about Jack herrer and it was all
about his life and his history and his
contributions to cannabis and so Ben
went to Neville and said hey
we want to release a Jack Herer yep I
have something that we drop at the
Cannabis Cup wouldn't that be a great
marketing tool yeah he's the number one
sponsor of this cup we're spending a
bunch of money it's all about Jack how
about we release [ __ ]
yeah so what ready
um as far as Neville was concerned but
he released nl5 Haze by Skunk Haze and
they called it Jack Herer yeah I doubt
we need to spend very much time talking
about Jack herrer uh because it's
super fast yeah it's Jack Jack
it led to Cindy 99 you know it led to a
whole bunch it was big yielding it was
fast it was chunky it was a tremor's
dream uh it was it smelled like uh
terpenoline uh it's people have a a love
and hate a lot of people have dislike
for that Aroma the Jack Aroma became
Infamous for uh
you know being something that repelled
people yep you know
and stuff like Jack Terps and someone
was saying yep Jack Terps Jack yeah
people not genuinely know what genuinely
speaking know what uh or generally
speaking no what Jack Terps are I I
think the first time that people ever
heard about the word terpenoline long
before that terp was identified yeah
called it Jack Terps yep Jack Terps Jack
Jack was a super high yielding uh you
know strain a lot of people grew it and
that was People's First experience with
extremes terpenoline
um and it it bred dominant very Matt can
talk about trying to get interesting
phenos out of terpenoline dominant
strains that don't give you terpenoline
it's pretty tough it is very tough to to
breed with serpentaling anything and try
to infuse that into your life Jack Terps
train wreck derps a lot of breeders have
have thrown their hat in the ring and
tried to breed with the lot because it's
such a vigorous powerful high-yielding
fun plant yeah and it's real hard to
find a not terpenaline dominant Fino
that works I think um in in modern times
though people are finding out that
terpinoline is actually really good in
extracts it makes them very flavorful so
there's been a little bit of a
Renaissance for the terpenolene Queens
out there
so maybe
um maybe since you can't see anything
maybe we'll pause you want to answer
some questions yeah you go ahead and
figure out what uh questions we need to
answer and let's do it so the number one
voted thing and we talked about it a
little was why was Sam's never able to
produce a haze to rival Nevels what was
the outstanding difference
that's the number one biggest question
yeah I think I think you you you've uh
answered this before when I was talking
with you about it so go ahead
um I actually think I mentioned it
mostly a little earlier in the program
but
um
we don't know why Sam you know Sam sold
Haze to positronics if you bought haze
from The Flying Dutchman that was Sam's
Haze he sold the clothes of wholesale
seed to any number of brokers in Holland
and then they sold it through their seed
banks and for whatever reason
uh everybody in Holland wanted Neville's
Haze hybrids
and nobody found anything that rivaled
what Neville was able to find
um you know and a lot of times uh Caleb
uh CSI myself Matt others we always talk
about like the proof is in the plants
yeah you know people lie plants don't uh
and for whatever reason maybe it was
sheer luck uh maybe it was Neville's
story is true and he did get an earlier
Haze than than Sam produced later maybe
has been open
which is something that I found
um
which is I found uh uh
hard to believe to be honest as a
breeder is he loves Haze and uh he never
ever made any selections
and he just he just said all I did was
open pollinate it to keep it as wide as
possible for 30 years yeah he didn't do
any selection work any Line work on it I
as a as a breeder never ever playing
around with your favorite phenos from
your favorite line
seems really unusual to me yeah yeah it
is uh it's like me never [ __ ] with
blueberry
you know yeah but but that's what Sam
says yeah and it's also possible so we
could talk about this for a second
sometimes when you open pollinate that's
great because you open it up wider but
that means it might be a hell of a lot
more effort to take more effort stuff
that you want and so and by repeatedly
open pollinating it and never making any
selections
um he might have open pollinated his way
into jungle weed or hemp or he might
have lost a bunch of the quality that
led people to love Hazel in the first
place
well you look at um like Tom Hill's
Hayes
um he would even say you need at least
10 packs you know 100 seeds to find a
single keeper so the the the repeatedly
oping probably didn't help anything
because obviously there's so many
phenotypes even in positronics Haze
that's been worked there's so many
phenotypes that you need to pop a
hundred to find a single one yeah I mean
Sam has claimed that everyone got the
exact same Haze and no one got any
different yeah I find that a bit hard to
believe because there's lots of people
that bought Flying Dutchman Haze there's
lots of people that bought posi Haze
there's tons of people that bought uh
Tom Hill Hayes uh Hayes has been sold
for decades in a wide variety of places
and
all the elites that people hoard
come from Neville's stuff yeah
for whatever reason yeah and you would
think that we have a lot of quality
Afghans out there and you'd be able to
cross some pure Haze to some other good
Afghans and get all the results to
Neville
um but the G13 Haze and the nl5 haze and
so on and so forth no one's been able to
replicate yep those ones are better and
they did also have the theory that he
talked about much later on that he only
believed in breeding with Haze males
that that was the key to finding the the
the Holy Grail Haze was through Hayes
males breeding and not using them as
females
you know some of that might be that he
lost the two best phenos of females in
the 80s
that's what he ended up doing I would
also say too that collecting pollen from
some 18 or 20 week Haze mail and then
dusting it on other plants when
appropriate is probably a lot easier of
a breeder uh aspect than trying to wait
for a 18 or 20 week female to be the
appropriate time to pollinate it that's
a good point so there's something to be
said for the fact that you could collect
a bunch of pollen and then dump it on
stuff later and it's probably much
harder to breed with the girls
yeah so
um there's another question Mean Gene
recently mentioned that you and he have
been doing some research and it looked
like we do Kush could most likely be a
renamed NL I think we chatted about that
already at length yep I I definitely
believe that the Hindu Kush that was
sold at Scentsy is just nl2
yeah
um
have I had any dealings with Gypsy nope
I'm not I almost did and um and it was
just a really bad proposal for me to
front a bunch of seeds he said that he
would sit on the money for I want to say
six months to a year
at which point he would pay you out
mostly in credit store credit
so you would wait like almost a year to
be able to use anything from anything it
was stupid it was no way in [ __ ] hell
well we'll have podcasts that deal with
gypsy's era of seas at some other time
maybe not necessarily a ton of him
specifically but he's from a different
era than we're discussing today sure
sure
um outside of the work that Neville
brought to the world who outside the
original big names contributed most new
strains worth something to the culture
early on
that's a pretty good question see yeah
it is I've mentioned some of it before
um I'll just associate some names with
strains uh Sam Skunk Man brought uh
Hayes and skunk one to Europe uh which
were popularized it to people uh Jim
Ortega who's a very mysterious character
brought Hawaiian Indica garlic Bud uh
Maple Leaf indica and kush for King
Neville those are all used extensively
in projects and so became very famous
building blocks
uh Mel Frank uh who's still quite well
known he contributed The Afghani one and
the Durbin poison
two things
uh I don't know if Jorge Cervantes uh
I don't think he directly contributed
anything but he did make the links he he
certainly connected Neville
um uh growers in Oregon and Washington
that led to the hash plant and G13 which
obviously entered into the pretty
legendary status
um Rob Clark who wrote marijuana botany
uh hashish and some other really
important cannabis books he contributed
a bunch of
um you know California Orange
um various Mexicans various sativa
crosses uh he certainly brought Early
Girl early Pearl yeah that type of stuff
that's all credited to him
um
I'm trying to think of
you know that's sort of those that those
names right there are sort of the
backbone
and the NL guys yeah
the Seattle Greg certainly yeah NL and
the NL group from the Pacific Northwest
they contributed obviously all the NL
lines and so
um there's a number of people we don't
know who they are but those guys are
sort of the foundational
um people that brought a lot of stuff
that ended up not only getting brought
over there but ended up getting used a
lot yeah into a lot and Don Downs for
nl2
specifically I believe that was his yeah
yeah I mean there was a guy named Herbie
that contributed the nl5
um you know I'm sure behind all these
famous names are just like a lot of
things there's probably a group of
people uh or good friends and stuff that
contributed various things that their
names have been lost to time yeah you
know
if I've not so dog and Matt Could Turn
Back Time what hack would you buy
well
you know uh
I would buy everything from the seed
bank
everything literally everything you
could I would buy hundreds of seeds of
everything that I could all the Durban
all the skunk one and all the nl5 haze
the app the maple leaf mix
um a lot of these things we talk about
um but you know Neville was one of the
few people that got to run through
hundreds or thousands of even of these
seeds and really see what was in there
we talk about the famous phenos but
um you know
uh we were really young when these
things were out there I was like six
something I'm a little older than you
but even still like I said I was I was
only 18 in 1994 when I started going so
I was even sort of catching the tail end
of certain things yeah
let's see there the next question was
Afghan T what's known about it the
strains it was used in
geographically what part of Afghanistan
did it come from via who et cetera Etc
so we don't know where it came I'm gonna
preface this I'm gonna preface this all
these people
all these people talking about roadkill
skunk and all the other stuff I
sincerely believe and and just from the
work with uh even the heirloom Afghani
the uh later sours the [ __ ] super
skunk and jesel all that I sincerely
believe that's the direction to learn
and all these people chasing different
directions I think it's fair to to put
it out there so everybody's on it even
playing field that's probably the
direction I'd look
so
um
you know uh the maple leaf we don't we
don't know anything about Jim Ortega we
don't know where any of the strains that
he got came from
hero documented anything about he's
still alive yeah so it's possible that
he could
um come out and tell some stuff but it
is a mystery we know we'd love to have
them on we know we know the story of his
work basically as soon as he started
trading the Neville yeah that's when he
pops up and you know the
um we can talk a little bit about the
maple leaf so the maple leaf Nevels
talked about extensively
uh when he first started growing it out
he started getting some sweet big bud
types
um and then he started growing more of
it out and then he found some more like
hash plant types some dark hashy thick
types he called those types Ortega uh
and then he started growing more out and
then he eventually found what he
considered two skunk archetypes which he
called Afghan T and Afghan s and and
it's important again because when most
people hear skunk they think skunk one
he wasn't referring to skunk one types
in this Afghani no he was just kind of a
little bit of the structure a little bit
of the nose a little bit of the look
that type of thing and what he said
about it is that so obviously the the
maple leaf was kind of a a hodgepodge of
different phenos that popped out of
Indica but what he found is if you took
a big bud type and you bred with it the
maple leaf big bud type bread big bud
like yeah you took an Ortega type the
hash plant type and you bred with it it
sort of ended up being hash plant so
they kind of bread true to type yeah
when they popped up if you bred with the
Afghan tea or Afghan s it also bleeded
true so the t is pretty famous
uh in the sense that it is the mom of
super skunk
uh he claims it's what put the funk in
it's what Crossing it back to it's
asking you know to an Afghan the Afghan
T brought out the the rank yeah it took
uh it took a kind of a sweet floral
skunk and made it reek yeah
and so uh Afghan T is incredibly famous
um but it's the probably the least
well-known thing we're going to talk
about tonight as well as being
incredibly famous it's the least well
known but it's the mother of one of the
most famous strains out there
the reason why that stream was so hunted
nowadays
yeah Super Skunk is probably one of the
most well-known cannabis strains in the
world
uh and he says that that's what made it
super
yep reading to Afghan T
um Afghan tea also crossed well with
Haze and there's a thing called Afghan
Haze
um Mr Knight
um
and uh that's supposed to be a uh uh a
half a maple leaf by AC
hard to verify obviously if that's the
case but uh we have documentation from
Neville that made super Stunt and it
crossed great with hazy yeah
um so that's kind of that
um there's some other stuff
that I just answered the Jim Ortega
question on a different one there's some
Mendo perp stuff
I don't know if it's pretty wide ranging
um we discussed garlic Bud pretty good
we discussed Hindu Kush the Friesland
and Scentsy star and stuff like that
we'll get to on a different episode uh
we'll certainly talk about those a
little bit more
um
you know uh where they like to have been
coming from the Seattle Greg's group uh
all that was there a Scentsy nl5 line in
89 there was not no uh That Never Was A
Sensei didn't have nl5 because in 89 the
seed bank was still owned by Neville
uh and there was never a Pure nl5 Line
offered as far as I know and there also
was never a 1988 Scentsy seeds G13 hash
plant
no uh do you can use the melvanics
garlic Fino of nl5 I'll let Matt take
that one if you want to just answered it
okay so no on that
um do we know if Neville's kids have
knowledge on his father's work yeah his
son has some knowledge of it and I know
his son and Neville's sister are
currently doing something
any info on what cush4 is
um not really
uh like I said Jim Ortega's still alive
he could maybe one day expound upon that
if he likes yeah a lot of rumor about it
there's rumor that the Clone might exist
there's rumor that the Clone is uh is
not it and it's uh it's ignite pure kush
it's a cure a pure kush variant yeah a
Bubba yeah nl2 type area RJ on that
level
um
I got this guy said I got to try a maple
leaf from an old timer in Georgia
unbelievable flavor almost like Dr
Pepper means Roadkill
that sounds good yeah that sounds
delicious
um when did the silver Pearl that pip
Works come out
um I think we talked here earlier the
silver Pearl started being offered by
Neville at the seed bank around 88.89 uh
it was offered 88 89.90
it was one of the strains that got
offered at Scentsy later on as well
so it popped up
um
is Steve Hagar just as guilty as Sam the
skunk man as AKA Dave Watson from
operation green Merchant who's Steve
Hagar he's the uh guy he's the one of
the the big head honchos oh hi friends
yeah that's a whole subject could be a
whole podcast in itself so to speak with
all the rumors and accusations and
there's a lot of people that believe one
way there's a lot of people that believe
another way
um that's a pretty in-depth one yeah as
far as Sam goes a lot of people do say
that there is something to do with
Federal informants and stuff I've looked
up extensively I've never seen a damn
thing come to life for any proof of any
of that but I will say Neville told me
specifically that he said yes everybody
knew Sam and everybody knew his DEA
Handler that walked around with them but
Neville also
during that time Neville was telling me
that him and Sam were [ __ ] making
video games back and forth at each other
so I don't know how uh reliable that
information is yeah uh Sam and Neville
had famous beef coming from Neville's
bust those Kung Fu dub over video memes
that they would send back and forth at
each other in 2009 2010 they were I wish
someone still had them they were [ __ ]
hilarious
um so uh you know there was um
there was a
uh yeah
um so there's a friend of ours that
mentioned black domino we can touch on
that real quick sure
um so black domino was something that
you know in in Neville's Neville's seed
bank era the vast majority of the stuff
that we were talking about in the 80s
and and this is kind of this is kind of
the same with the supersedeva seed Club
is they were basically all F ones or
very simple hybrids yeah uh that's kind
of what they were doing they were they
were crossing pure strains together they
were releasing lines of pure strains
they had gotten and they were taking
these pure strains like skunk and
Northern Lights or Haze and skunk or you
know and Northern Lights and Haze and
they were crossing them yeah in the 90s
uh but the poly hybrid terms started to
pop
where you started getting more complex
breeding coming in so black domino was a
cross of four indicas
uh that Neville that they released that
Neville bred while he was at Scentsy and
the mother was consistent the mother was
a one of his favorite cuts it was uh nl1
by hash plant
by nl1 to say it correctly actually
because uh the no one was the dad that
was the mom
and released three versions of it
um depending on the year and one of the
dads was
um
I believe Afghani won by nl2
there was another dad that was uh
Afghani won by Ortega which is maple
leaf and there was the third and final
dad which I believe was the vast
majority of the seeds but it's kind of
hard to say people wanted uh with all
these pure indicas being crossed
together people wanted a larger yielding
thing and so he crossed that hash plant
by nl1 to a garlic Bud by nl2
um so black domino
uh had three versions yeah many forms
yeah three forms uh mom was always the
same uh dad varied as they played around
with what to do yeah it was just a
really good name so they just [ __ ]
went with it yeah it's a great name I I
will say that um of all my trips to
Europe uh I lost it sadly but a black
Dominic uh Fino I found was one of the
best things I ever got uh out of Europe
um I had a great great variety of it it
tasted peppery it was extremely Frosty
yielded pretty nicely uh it was dark uh
dark Afghan not too leafy really fast
too it was pretty fast yeah it was a
great cut I wish I still had it it's one
of my like super regrets uh we have some
good friends
um that there was a rare 12-week Fino
um that was likely a recessive garlic
Bud type uh that people really like they
called the lady Fino uh there was a lot
of good black domino black dump popped
um it was probably one of the best later
things that Neville did yeah
uh and uh so
I don't know we can um
so we've probably been talking for a
long time I don't know how long it's
been going but we'll we'll hour and a
half we'll tie it off with
um we'll tie off Neville at least with
sort of um the last phase of what he did
and why that's important maybe and then
we'll call it good uh we didn't get to
everybody's questions it'll be hard to
get to everybody's questions but some of
your questions might lead to more uh you
know more podcasts in the future we
might dive into some of these things in
different ones real quick I got to do a
giveaway
um so whoever okay now last time y'all
[ __ ] I said whoever had the
best question right
gets the giveaway I'm gonna do that
again but please don't have four people
message me saying that they were that
person it really it does get confusing
so we'll do a giveaway um what should I
give away something that's referencing
something from tonight let's do the uh
the G13 nl2 bluebonnets let's give away
a pack of that so whoever had that top
question
uh message me
I will mention real quick the the
there's a tie for the two highest
questions tonight okay so both of them
win and one person said can you describe
the different growth structures flower
times yields flavor effects pros and
cons of the different chem Cuts chemd
chem 91 chem CIS chem 4. uh we'll do a
chem Dog episode I won't touch that one
tonight uh we have a long history with
chem uh I got blessed and I got to be
one of the earlier people that got a
hold of the chem 91. I've had the chem D
since 06. I've had the chem 4 for a long
time I have a lot of experience with
them we could do a long talk about that
I promise you you'll hear more about the
chem the most political episode we will
ever do probably of that one I mean
there's there's other ones I think that
could cost him fire but yeah but we will
I promise you we will we will talk
extensively about chem uh we'll be
popping out these episodes pretty often
so uh you'll hear about it in the future
sure so to tie off the Neville bit after
answering questions is
Neville was ticked off about uh working
under Ben and Allen dronkers he wasn't
into it uh anymore and so he left in
95-96. and he partnered with a younger
cat named Shanti uh Shanti Baba we won't
talk about him extensively but he came
to Europe in the early 90s and he
popularized White Widow a great white
shark White Rhino things of that nature
he was also from Australia he's a bit
younger than Shanti he sort of
um and so when Neville left
Scentsy uh Shanti Neville and this
gentleman named Arjun partnered at the
greenhouse uh coffee shop which should
be pretty familiar to everybody that has
even a rudimentary knowledge of that
um usually the first seeds everyone buys
post 2005 yeah they they they had a very
successful seed bank and they had a very
successful series of coffee shops in
Holland
um I went to a bunch yeah and so
um basically at that point in Neville's
career he wasn't as interested in
breeding with a bunch of Afghans and
stuff anymore but he was really
interested in is continuing his Haze
work because that's that's what
interested him so like I said earlier
about the jack herrer
um Neville didn't consider that line
finished he just released it under
pressure from Ben and Alan dronkers to
coincide with the seat with the uh the
Cannabis Cup
so after he left Scentsy him and Shanti
partnered together and they started
taking they already knew what strains
they had they had two nl5 hazes one of
them was caught one of them we call C5
which has been spreading around a little
bit in America now and there's some
people that are selling seed hybrids of
it and stuff it's finally popped out on
our side of the of the world and another
one was called the the 122 or the mango
right and they were trying to work out a
poly hybrid using skunk Haze that would
reflect the qualities of both so they
were parallel brief and basically what
they were doing is old school breeding
that's a huge pain in the ass in which
they were taking different skunk cases
and they were crossing it to these
things and they were growing out the
kids and seeing if the dad threw the
traits they wanted yeah
so uh most people don't do that anymore
as Matt gonna test it that's a super
time consuming pain in the ass the
market doesn't let you have a strain in
six years later release it you know what
I mean like you can't do it it doesn't
it doesn't work in today's world but
they
he had been working on that for a number
of years he kept working on it and
eventually they found a skunk Haze dad
that meet their criteria Neville
preferred the line that you see five is
the mom and that line became known as
super silver haze uh won three cups in
the late 90s probably everybody knows
about it it's very famous yeah jonty
preferred the skunk Hayes dad crossed to
the 122 or the mango my preference that
one got named the mango Haze that's also
my preference I would actually the the
122 is sadly not in America yet it is
the nicest nl5 Haze i've smoked yeah I'd
love to smoke that my personal favorite
out of the a5s the c5s whatever not that
I'm an expert on all of them or anything
but I have in coffee shops and getting
to know people over there smoked most of
it that one's amazing
bit and I wish I had it uh mango Haze is
dang but it lives and you can buy it
from Shanti still
um as the 122. he it's it's 122 by Skunk
Hayes it's called mango Haze and then he
also released something that was the
start of his holy grail project His Holy
Grail project was trying to recapture
the magic of haze in an actual line and
not F1 uh Neville talked extensively
about how he didn't like most of the
poly hybrid hazes nearly as much as the
f1s yeah so he was trying to figure out
a way to do that and so what he did is
he took A5
A52 which is on the cover I don't know
if Matt wants to show it but the A52 is
on the cover of the seed bank 89 and 90
catalog both
he took the A52 this ugly beast
he took the A5 to that one and he
crossed it to Haze C
and which is the famous dad that was
used in almost all the releases so
um that was the first time that the a
dad and the C dad was crossed in the
same line so it was 75 percent Haze and
25 percent Northern Lights and they
initially crossed it just to be a
personal breeding project as their Haze
Grail but they found so much killer
stuff in it they decided to release it
Neville's Haze
there is still a cut of that first find
in Holland it is the strongest sativa I
know of
it's almost like a
uh
maybe the best way to put it is all
those old school stories of psychedelic
trippy hold on to your seats sativas
that make you see tracers in the corner
of your vision and making like
something's talking to you
um I kind of believe that was [ __ ]
and then I smoked Neville's Haze uh that
Fino that they found that became famous
and it literally felt like the top of my
head blew off
I'm dead serious I shared a joint I did
I I at that point I had I had the chem
91 I had Super Skunk I had a whole bunch
of pretty potent nice quality stuff I
felt like the stuff we had in America
was mostly Superior to what Europe had
to offer I went over there I met a
gentleman uh who used to work with
Neville became friends I smoked a small
joint with two friends of the Neville's
Haze
and
it blew my head off I mean it literally
felt like like air was rushing over the
top of my skull yeah I remember holding
on to the railing as I walked down the
steps of the dude's house
I remember feeling anxious
stoned Trace rushing uh definitely
feelings that I'm not used to in
cannabis yeah and so at that point I
realized that some of those old sativa
stories had the were true that some
people did get a psychedelic energetic
almost disassociative type of potent
feeling I don't care how useful you are
to smoking whatever Afghans you're used
to yeah have a tolerance to Neville's
Haze and you smoke some you'll probably
get knocked off your feet
you know there is a person in the U.S
and and me and this guy don't
necessarily get along the bass now but
um in all reality the best novels Hayes
I've ever smoked has come from snow high
he had an amazing selection of it and I
think he used it in some breeding work
but it was uh every spice you could
imagine in a kitchen cabinet all in one
and it was just it was just so Speedy it
was crazy [ __ ] it was really good though
it was unique I don't recommend this but
if you smoke too much Neville's Haze
it feels kind of like psychedelic
cocaine oh let's just go do it it feels
I mean but some people some people feel
like uncomfortable yeah out of your skin
yeah in a corner
um you know I get that from afghanis
which is really weird a lot of them oh
it really it really uh it really has a
strange feeling
um
I looked for that Fino and Neville's
Haze I bought quite a bit of seeds I
never found it
um luckily that Fino still exists it's
still sold in coffee shops over there
there's still people that hold it and on
that side of the pond
um yeah panic attacks uh it it was uh
certain people don't like it yeah I
[ __ ] hate roller coaster weed that
[ __ ] don't but it is
it's it's very tasty it's extremely
potent it hits you extremely differently
than most things and it certainly was
factual and I'm like okay some of these
people that are making these stories
about ties and Colombians and how it
made them feel a long time ago
um are true yeah because that that that
cut has it in Spades yeah uh it's 75
Haze 25 Northern Lights it's the first
thing that crosses both Haze dads A and
C in the same line it's nuts uh I've
been it's one of my white rabbits uh
I've been searching for it since the
late 90s I know where it exists I
haven't gotten it yet I hope I get it
hopefully after this we'll have I don't
know nine or ten companies making
crosses with it from the US
yeah I mean now that we've mentioned it
everybody's gonna have it all sudden so
here's the quick right is that thing
takes like 16 weeks yeah so it's a super
long Runner but it literally yields like
three and a half pounds of light
yeah that's insane so even if even if
you even if you were to take that 16
weeks and turn it into eight weeks
basically like growing an eight week
pound and a half a light strain yeah but
it takes twice as long yeah
um
you know I I saw I saw a room in Holland
uh I'll tell this story uh before it
gets too late but sure I walked into a
room I saw a room in Holland that was
all uh nl5 Haze and Neville's Hayes and
it was one of the craziest things I've
ever seen they were growing on a slanted
floor with drains they were growing in
Rockwell croutons yeah rock wool is very
popular in Europe yeah um they were
growing in one gallon pots
there was thick thick stems growing out
of these one gallon pots they were they
were on constant drip slow drip right
draining out onto the floor and these
stems went trimmed up about six I'm six
foot three they went up over my head The
netting was about six and a half feet
tall
three feet from about six and a half
feet to about nine or ten feet there was
a mass Jungle of buds everywhere and
then 600s all over the place yeah it was
one of the more unusual Grow rooms I've
ever seen was it all like vertical bulbs
hanging in there no they were just way
up high oh okay got you but it's like so
you look at the ground and there's these
tiny little one gallons of Rockwell
croutons with these big thick stems
coming out of the base that went up
thicker than me and then right above my
head it just branched into crazy sativa
arms at my bed everywhere and after they
threw it for the coffee shops
um
so
that these last two episodes we
basically sort of walked you through
Neville's main breeding era which was 85
to 97 98
that super silver haze won three
cannabis cups in a row
uh 97 98 99 most people have heard of
Neville's Haze Super Silver Haze mango
Haze and sort of the last major breeding
that Neville not that Neville stopped
breeding but he did some much smaller
projects and some collabs more with
other people
um it was a bit more about that than I
do but
um you know Neville probably had a
17-year run
yeah it's a good run in this industry
cannabis yeah it went through the seed
bank it went through Scentsy it went
through the greenhouse uh you know he
sold a bunch of we were not going to
talk about that uh this episode but he
sold a bunch of his stuff and gave a
bunch of his cuts to Shanti and then it
continued at Mr Nice seeds in
Switzerland
um and so that's kind of Neville's as
far as his breeding work that's kind of
his Arc yeah for lack of a better way to
put it
um and uh you know I don't know that's
probably
close to a good stopping point yeah um
so everyone if you want to get involved
in these conversations I mean there
might be people in the chat room right
now that are actually a part of our
patreon that go into the Discord and we
discuss all this stuff a lot of these
episodes that we are recording we do a
lot of those discussions publicly with
uh with each other
um and in that chat room so if you if
you're a [ __ ] straight up straight
nerd come join our patreon you'll enjoy
it um a lot of those other guys can
testify to that
um we also are going to start working on
doing some old cannabis Publications
making those accessible for people not
like High Time [ __ ] but uh stuff that's
off the radar you know what I mean it
has a lot of old strain info a lot of
old pictures a lot of old growing info
and all that's available through our
breather Syndicate patreon so join up be
sure to uh do that make sure and and
uh we put up the crowdcast links in the
bio on breeder Syndicate for each new
one be sure to sign up for each one it
doesn't send notifications every time
unless you sign up for it so that's uh
that's the housekeeping details I think
um I mean the other thing we could say
is we say this every time we have a
Discord server that's breeder Syndicate
um you can ask Matt and I questions
we're pretty responsive on there uh you
know we pop in fairly often we're gonna
also be doing some shorts soon not every
subject requires an hour and a half or
something like that to discuss
we're going to be doing a series of
shorts coming up 5 10 15 minutes about
various topics so sometimes your
question might not get talked about but
it might lead to a 10 or 15 minute short
where we talk about things uh we
hopefully have some pretty cool old
school breeders that we're going to be
bringing on uh in in the future we're
going to be doing this on a regular
basis both the shorts and the long and
the long Factor it won't just be me and
Matt uh some breeders are shy some are
busy some are both we're going to do our
best to add in some extra people and get
you know pretty historical so for all
that you can reach us on a patron you
can reach us on this the Breeders is a
damn tequila patreon patreon yeah so
um all that there's various ways you can
get a hold of us we want to keep this
kind of thing rolling I hope it was
interesting to everybody I promise in
the future Matt will talk more
yeah so um but you know I thank
everybody for listening I hope you find
it I hope you thought it was cool I hope
you learned some things and uh everybody
thank you very much for signing up and
listening for everybody that stuck with
us
you have a great day peace everybody