foreign
Mr Murray here like oh dang he's gonna
lock it up with Murray
see if we can get this
it's pretty dark in here there we go
anyway let's get to some real questions
uh
something worthwhile something worth
putting out there
we go all right hit me with some
questions fellas
oh here we go here we go here's JJ New
York let's bring him in
foreign
still says connecting hasn't connected
yet
hey JJ
hey what's up
oh your your phone has a lag with the
audio
try again
let me see if I can move into a better
spot you're a little better
you got better yeah what's up brother
yeah
get by an internet connection always
works the best
what's going on not much just dealing
with the normal [ __ ]
you know how it goes
so um yeah there's a couple things I
wanted to talk to you about
um let's do it one being
one being the diesel diesel uh the usual
is super scum
right you you stated it was super skunk
I think uh it could be a super skunk
cast one we don't know because there's
no camd coming out of the progeny at all
in any of the S1
um
that came out of a chemd uh mother
though the MD flower I was told I was
told by Greg that it came out of the
super skunk flower that the cam D heard
uh I thought I I was uh told the
opposite but maybe either one of us
either one of us could be wrong Greg
didn't keep good notes as we know
right right and that's correct from
those guys you know him and Louise will
go if you could ask the same question
twice and get two different answers
right
but
um but uh have you grown the the my
super skunk no I have never grown
Matthew for skunk never never had it
okay
because uh you know with the speculation
that the mass Super Skunk is with the
sour diesel and I kind of have uh a
couple discrepancies about that because
the mass Super Skunk if you ever grown
it it grows kind of medium height and
it's it's a single Cola with a very
thick stem
and so like the
theory that it would be part of the the
chem dog
um with the cam dog making a sour diesel
uh the growth the growth structure is
just is way off
yeah you know what I'm saying
um like if you ever if you've grown
cabin 91 next to Sour Diesel like this
the the growth that the sativa growth on
the shower diesel is just
I don't know if you've grown it I don't
have to yeah yeah it's night day from
cam 91 sure
right so so if the theory of the the
super skunk went into it then where does
all that sativa growth come from you
know I mean unless it's a recessive
trait but I kind of uh disagree with
that because uh I've I've grown the DNL
that that I think that uh is part of the
uh Sour Diesel and it grows exactly the
same just that really stretchiest
achieve uh you have to top it off and
just Branch it out and everything all
right
so that that's just my my yeah I agree
some of your ddnl and I saw a lot of
sour traits in it as well
I would agree with you right and I
thought and I was going to ask you that
because I thought a while back that you
had uh grown some of those uh DNL
crosses and I wanted to get yours
love that [ __ ]
yeah I still sitting on some beans I I
haven't uh brought them out in a long
time but uh I got so many different
things I've been working on that uh I
don't know I got to try to get into it
soon especially with all this uh with
all this skunk uh controversies that is
going on
and then speaking of controversies over
uh
this whole thing with uh [ __ ] giraffe
and that dick Nick yeah
yeah I mean you know if I was skunk VA I
would have just ripped his head off
right there on the side I'm surprised he
didn't
uh yeah that dude is just like a mellow
dude and he's the kind of dude that once
she snaps like
I mean he's got he's got his arms are
the size of my thighs
it's like Popeye he's like a wrestler
he's like a shoe I mean like I couldn't
believe what joint a joint breath told
him to suck his dick or something online
uh yeah but there was he went up to his
booth and they had some kind of uh
conversation and then he came outside
and I was in a circle with uh
the swamp boys and uh Bronson was there
and he just like [ __ ] lost his mind
you know I mean I thought I was gonna
have to fight him at first but then but
then I became like his therapist I mean
I kind of had like a shred of Sympathy
for the guy he was Sandy and went to
jail and yeah
everyone hates him and how he wants to
be accepted and and all this other
[ __ ] you know you were the voice of
reason usually you're swinging on people
listening stopped fronting I was like
you know you're he he's handing us a jar
of skunk around and I'm like yo you
think that's real roadkill I told him
I'd give him you know some kind of skunk
one or something like that like but when
you smell it I mean it kind of has that
smell to it but the bud structure itself
is like very kind of
um leafy and sativa like and then smoke
it just it tastes like straight up hay
and I'm not saying that to be a hater no
no I'm giving you my best opinion and I
told the mother Hey listen if you had
something that great I would
congratulate yeah for sure
everyone's saying [ __ ] to be a hater I'm
giving you my honest opinion and
everyone I talked to that was in that
Expo that's all that stuff was just like
yeah he brought it to Emerald cup too
and it was uh and the people that
touched the underside of the jar got
some orange [ __ ] on their fingers that
smelled like real skunk
bro I didn't he didn't have any of that
going on but
poor fella you know
he's shorting in dangerous territories
[ __ ] around with Duke and skunk yeah
either one of those dudes man they're
like
we'll see what happens at the next yeah
right
let it boil over a little bit
but you know but you know in there and
then there's all these other guys that
you know were you know say they have the
the road killing and I had the original
Super Skunk back in like 1995 and let me
tell you when you just cracked that Joy
or just permeated
you know and then I had gotten to cut
years later it was just it just wasn't
the same it didn't give out those same
kind of toys or whatever I don't know
there's a different cut or that you know
you know Cuts just dud out after they do
yeah
and it's starting to happen with the
sour diesel because everyone asked me oh
where's that where's that Sour Diesel at
you know with that old-time Sour Diesel
in you got to figure it that's like 25
years that's how how long that uh that
cut is now so and it's just been given
you know from person to person from room
to room and I think you know uh Cuts
adapt to the room that they're in so you
know your shower diesel is going to come
out different than my Sour Diesel now if
you start giving out cuts and I start
giving out touch you know after a while
I think there could be you know some
type of genetic drift that you know
might happen not anything drastic
believe but you know there's this seems
to be these three small subtle things
that seem to be missing from the from
the sour uh nowadays sure yeah I mean
acclimates from room to room to room to
room and that thing's so [ __ ] old
yeah
right but I've had we had you know the
original Underdog which was super skunk
NL times a 91. it just went bad on us I
mean we had the cut and then after a
while it just it only showed glimmers of
itself you know when it was really
really good and it was start you know
the um
went down it was harder to clone and
everything and then after a while my
phone was like he gave to me I did a
little bit of work with it and my phone
was like listen I'm just going to let it
go
and
I remember just buying from buying weed
there was this stuff called the
wheelchair the the wheelchair and back
in the day
that [ __ ] you know was was given me bomb
and then the same thing after a while
you just could not get the same batches
just from buying it after a while and
the same people were growing it and
everything but what's the wheelchair
I'm not sure it was just some type of
um local
um strain that was sold in New York City
you know back then we didn't really have
uh you know names weren't really another
thing that they are now so
uh yeah I have no idea what it was so
let's talk about I-95
yeah I think I've seen so or I think
I've seen some stuff referenced like as
the wheelchair or the crippler or
something like that and I'm gonna have
to uh really find out a you know where
that really came from but I think that
you know those that stuff came from the
Amsterdam back back in the day sure did
yeah
let's talk about I-95 that's you that's
that's yeah and that was the other one
that I wanted to do let's talk about the
history of it all of it
you know uh that's a Money Mike strain
and originally he bred that back in like
2014 we brought it to the Denver CO yeah
the last Denver cup was 2014.
and we and we brought that it was
um
it was uh Legend star dog male times uh
the triangle kush yeah
so he bred that we brought that out
um and we were friends with Tara Rojo
and we went over to mine full and he
gave us a tour and you know and so we
gave him some seeds I gave him some
store dog seeds he got some I-95 seeds
and
you know we you know we're just trying
you know to help the guy yeah let's be
nice not right not knowing well
you know going further back he had
invited us to uh share his booth in one
of the first few Denver cups it might
have been 2011.
you know what I mean so
um you know we you know I always you
know respected Phil and you know uh
thank him for you know helping us and
everything and so sure
he used to you know to play with and
stuff and um
so you know he grew those seeds out and
then see this is where it starts getting
kind of fudgy because
when I confronted him you know he says
you know that he had started the seeds
and left mindful or I'm not really sure
but
we gave a seeds to fill I mean and then
before we know it uh one of his workers
uh Matt Ross
um started a seed company basically with
the seeds that we gave Phil correct yeah
Phil
claims that he he stole them for mindful
took him out and started playing with
him at his house and all but
um you know we held us feel responsible
for that
and he claims that but you know he uh
like he hired the same guy to run uh
some kind of you know get some kind of
job in Chicago yeah yeah
so to me I think that you know he kind
of set him up to kind of be the bad guy
and where I'll feel
spread those genetics all through his
his
um
this you know his dealings with eight
yeah
and so he's got the egrets thing and he
does you know other smaller stuff on on
the side yeah I mean like I know you
know he got some stuff in Baltimore and
Maryland
Pennsylvania and I don't know if those
are acreage uh related or not but I do
know they're running the I-95 chemd yeah
that those I've made
and um and then you know so you know
they they did that and then we had uh
Elite the elite guys which those guys
are friends of ours yeah they're good
friends of mine too
and you know they you know they took a
pack on I-95 and did you know they did
the same thing I mean they bought them I
mean but then you know they saw what uh
what these guys did with it and they and
they started doing the same crosses that
they but they didn't sell it
they didn't sell them but they were
giving them away but just even doing
giving them away you're trying to like
make a name for yourself you know I mean
in the way that I look at it is if you
know if you buy if you're given a pack
of I-95 can be you think you're ever
ever gonna buy one from me
yeah I mean the chances did you guys
ever release the I-95 camdier the I-95
publicly
oh yeah I'm selling them oh I didn't
know that because
yeah so I'm selling them now so
everybody go grab your I-95 camd from JJ
Top Dog seeds right here
well basically I took
um yeah I took f2s from them guys and
then I I mean not well they gave me f1s
and I made f2s with them but then I
started
um
Crossing into some of the different
other strains and then Money Mike also
uh did a remake of his uh
uh I-95 into the chem D and made the
chem chem uh the d95s so as money mics
take on it yeah and my circus on is just
an F2 on it actually so I took there
yeah and then I took the original that
um Ken Deli uh
um
it's MD reading uh she and I was the one
that I F2 that that I had gotten but I
had they had I mean and I went over
there with with those and when after
Phil left and uh in in uh Matt and his
brother uh Jax and both gave gave me
seeds gaming budge tell me told me how
much they loved me you know all the
whole thing and then and then he went
around and did that yeah I mean and then
wave gem did the same exact thing they
came up to our booth in in Boston and
told us how much they loved us and blah
blah blah and Money Mike wanted to punch
the guy out because he was playing
around with with you know he was he was
getting into dangerous uh territory at
that time and I told him yo you better
just back off and you know I mean you're
getting a little bit too close yeah I
mean and then he got all stupid did and
did the same thing yeah I mean so
everyone tells you that they love you
how much they respect you this and that
come and kiss your ass they get your
gear and they want to be like you and
they just go and just you know just try
to copy all the work that you've done
yeah
so you know it just seems to be a
you know common trait you know I mean
and you know on Instagram now yeah it's
a different world at least on the forums
like people would get called out all the
time by a lot of people you know what I
mean
yeah but you know now you know it's just
as easy to you know just block someone
no one really you know has the you know
respect or
with decency anymore you know back in
the day it was a lot different
it was a lot different than now I I've
never heard of that wave gen is that a
new company
uh just some some guys I think they were
some kid that was out of Road on Rhode
Island and he's up there
um in Maine now
all right I'll keep mine
yeah waved wait uh yeah wave gem or gem
wave gem genetics or um he's changed his
name a few times he's gotten deleted you
know and then you got Green Point
another one here I mean
man he he took the I-95 he took the star
dog he did the same thing yeah you know
this guy right here
wave genetics all right yeah someone put
it up waves in that X that's that's the
guy so hey I got a question for you
um a lot of people don't know what DNL
is in the first place can you go over it
for people
well as far as I know the DNL originally
uh originated was the RFK skunk which
the the
um the weasel mic and Gabby went down to
a a dead show at RFK and scored a bag of
uh kind bud and found I don't know like
eight or ten seeds or whatever so
um they both agreed to split the seeds
and when they did it they actually put
all the seeds out on the table and they
they each one by one I picked this one I
picked that one I picked this one I
picked that one and
um when the weasel uh
and he wound up um getting I don't know
like three different phenos and and
that's when I first met him in Central
Park he was sounds drunk one skunk two
skunk three yeah that's what he called
him and then
um a friend to his uh
wound up getting like some type of um
some NL seeds and some Hawaiian seeds
that you wind up having no seeds and he
gave him uh one of some of those uh RFK
clones and so he made his own strain uh
combining the three and he just called
it the NL but you know it might have had
some NL in it but it was mostly sachiva
dominant in instruction
and you know and the Hawaiian it kind of
had these tropical like
tropical skunky tones a little bit yeah
I mean kind of you get you get little
bits
you know you could taste in the sour
sometimes you know what I mean
um so you know so that was a strain that
he grew exclusively and I think that he
gave it back to uh the weasel to grow
and you know that's what what I just
suspect was in the room when uh you know
those uh seeds were made originally well
what weren't made but were found
originally I mean in the 91 because I
mean I you know I used to sell weed for
the weasel he grew it I sold it but he
had he had vondo and there were a few
other people that were that would weasel
in and try to uh to buy to buy it
because it was it was like a race
because I would you know he would only
get like a couple pounds so it was like
you know you just had to grab everything
that he had at the time just cash him
out and this way you had control of of
all of that because you know back in the
day people would just come in and just
want to buy it all I mean and I'd be
like I can't sell it to you all because
you know I I like to spread it out and I
would sell to other people that did me
favors you know I mean so you know
didn't go when I get something and you
know I'll hit you off you can make some
money just do me a favor you know get me
you know you save me you know this or
that and so you could use it as a
bordering tool to you know get other
favors from people sure
yeah
what do you know if the RFK is still
around or is that long gone
no it's been long gone yeah and then
really recently they lost the DNL within
the last like two years or so off so I
mean that's why I was thinking about
trying to
you know fall back on some of those uh
seeds I've made yeah dude let's see if I
can pull anything out that's like the
original that would be real cool real
cool
because really I wanted to try to
reverse that into the 91 and see what
would happen yeah I mean because when I
first started growing uh in like 99
you know I you know I you know I had
been selling weed for a long time and
anytime I had some anything that was
super kill and I found seeds I would
save them I mean yeah and then and then
at one time I had a you know really
badass collection from the 80s and and
all that and the cops took it I got
busted a bunch of cakes
wound up taking it so I wound up
starting a new one and then so I started
that one and when I started getting the
chem dog you know uh you know every once
in a while you might find a
a seed or two in there so I would save
them and so when I started
um I popped a few of those seeds and
really back then there was no really
such thing as the sour yeah but you know
but you know looking back I had found
some stuff that was very sour like very
sourish you know I mean and I remember I
had um
I had
something happened I think that we were
we were we had to close down to grow
whatever and I had just pop these seeds
and I sex them and I screamed him and
and I gave the Clone to my friend and I
was like listen I was like I said the
only thing I know that this is like you
know came from out of chem dog and just
female and I gave it to him and he grew
it out and that became uh the the guava
but not the guava of today I got you and
he so he called that cut the guava but
it was kind of very sourish and all yeah
and he and he ran it and then eventually
lost it you know I mean and then
um years later
um I wound up doing the star dog and I
had gifted my friends some seeds to give
to Andre Grossman uh the photographer of
High Times okay
and he
um
he grew him out and he found afino
that was today's guava so what happened
was
um somehow while he well what happened
they they like that cut so much uh and
at the time uh they had uh at High Times
they had their uh the Kyle Cushman
Strawberry Cough yeah and they actually
had they had a plant they had a plant in
the in the office
and like anyone that that went into the
office if they liked you enough they
would cut you all cut you a couple
clones right off the plant in the office
and let you go home with them so So
eventually the same thing happened with
the guava
and uh both the guava and the Strawberry
Cough became the the office strains
so years later like I was saying the
same guy that named the guava tells me
that he got the guava he got the guava
back
so
um
we've eventually find out that it comes
full circle back from The High Times
guys
and so like
um that was how you know that the guava
uh kind of got its name of today though
uh but it was originally uh some type of
rush hour can something the original cup
but I remember it and it was very soured
usually but I don't think well I didn't
get to ever finish it out actually well
one of them I did and then another one I
didn't yeah or I mean I did get to
finish one out
but then I had popped another seed and
that was the seed that I gave my friend
but it came from the same batch though
of seeds now
was the stardog guava similar in Terps
or anything to the other lava
and not really I mean the guava of today
is more comfort-ish
what am I think we'll have to come
forward
where uh the other one was more
more kind of 91-ish yeah
a little more fuel easier a little more
fuel salary fuel the original one was
do you still have any of those old uh
the purple afghan cross I think you did
a purple star dog with it
um
with a purple store dog with what I
think it was British Empire's purple
afghan yeah I did I never really
um I never popped any of those seeds I
do I'm sitting on them and I think I did
some into the chem D also oh wow
and I think I did some into the original
Haze too those all could be real that
Afghan original Haze could be [ __ ]
real interesting I I wound up
um
flowering out some of that stuff and
some of it was green and some of it was
purple just by yes you know
and I wound up using a male and you know
I [ __ ] up and never made f2s out of
that you know
uh but I do have that just just the
crosses into the star dog in in the
chemd yeah that would be fascinating to
see Pop back up
yeah but uh the purple star dog that I
uh that I made you know the purple came
from the tree dog male
and and the purple probably came from
the Afghan yeah it was a uh since he
seed uh Afghan
field after anyone
Afghan one yeah and I think you know
looking back into that that wasn't
really like a true uh
uh cultivar as in one string I think it
was a mix of their best afghanis or
something like that
and then even like looking back into
um the the the the maple leaf I think
even like the maple leaf really wasn't
really uh
really like one stable string I think
they were were a variety of different
phenos in there because uh if you if you
look back into the the seed the seed
bank catalog they actually offer that at
like a 50 pack or something like that
and it's more of like a breeders you
know I mean they don't really I mean but
it sounded like you know there was you
know a lot of different different
varieties in there but the one guy that
they talk about uh Maple Leaf uh whoever
they called one guy Maple Leaf yeah it
was
of uh you know the fenos that he was
growling at the time so I guess all that
was Beast off his stuff you know I've
always um found that a lot of the stuff
that was listed is maple leaf Indica
like it was used tend to look like The
Afghani won so I don't know if they have
a similar parentage that way back up
I think you know because I look back and
I think you know if you look into the
catalogs on The Afghani one it says it's
like a mix of their three or four best
afghanis or what or whatever you know
but when I grew it
it kind of it grew
um very fat stemmed uh single coal uh
kind of short medium height
and
um
it didn't really have a really uh
the Terps on it weren't really super
strong it was kind of subtle yeah and so
that's why I figured it would be a good
out process to go yeah yeah out across
into the county because it wouldn't be
dominant you know because you kind of
had like a kind of a madisony a little
madisony thing onto it you know it was
decent I mean I I smoked the flour but
you know it wasn't anything uh that
would compare the chem dog but the
structure you know that you know
definitely added you know because it
gave you that really thick stem yeah
you know and and all the all the
um the calyx the bud ratio you know
there wasn't much leaf on that so you
were you know you're one of the first
guys I saw from not necessarily the
modern era but um
prior to the modern era that was
actually using like the Northern Lights
the super skunks The Afghani one [ __ ]
like that and that always inspired me to
go in that direction for those bass
lines so I appreciate that yeah well I
was always a big sense you see fan back
in the day yeah I mean their genetics
are not the same unfortunately
yeah but you know but if you looking
back most of that stuff they got from
Neville yeah yeah I mean our stuff was
seed bank stuff that you know where
Neville was in jail and you know they
bailed him out and
you know they gave them money or
whatever so
I'm pretty sure that that was the story
behind that yeah some of the best stuff
there is as far as bass lines go I think
if people don't grow that stuff they
won't have an idea of a lot of the
traits and modern stuff like they're
they're they don't have a good base
knowledge
and and looking back like I know people
you know that I've talked to the
drunkers and they've admitted that
they've lost all their mother yeah
but you know someone like Adam Don he
was working you know wisdom back in the
90s and so he you know knows firsthand a
lot of that stuff that went on uh
but you know he uh he you know he
laughed after he left that's real you
know
and then uh I don't know who else was
doing it but I don't know who else was
doing her breathing
um back in the 90s I'm not sure
but you know what because you used to be
able to get the cellophane uh cord packs
yeah and then they upgraded to the box
with the bubble yeah
and beating up a little leading up until
today because my friend he had bought a
pack of Jack Herrera like you know the
year it won the cup or whatever
and um you know he grew it out you know
I was selling the weed and after a while
uh they need this kind of people got
sick of it you know I mean they started
doing okay told him to stop doing it
he's like oh don't worry I'll kill it I
still have the whole pack left you know
years later I said hey why don't you
look for that pack well I lost it yeah I
mean so then I was able to grab a pack
of the boxes
and I gave him a pack of the Jack
Carrera and he grew it out and
this way it just wasn't it wasn't the
same yeah
yeah I mean it was a really it was junk
and you know I think really by then
that's when a lot of people started
Outsourcing to uh yeah
a lot of that stuff comes back you know
it's kind of like
but it's you know it grows very
sativa-like but it you know it's kind of
wispy and like I don't know I just call
it like generic answers yeah
yeah and like even like Adam says you
know like that the the Jack itself is
like I don't know like a 12-way you know
12 Way Cross or something I mean just
four things that just crossed back into
each other and after a while just
becomes like uh you know it's genetic
like messing yes where it just comes
it's just very generic and
in what it's producing becomes a muddled
mess
right it looks like we got a minute left
anything else you want to get in my man
well we got into pretty much everything
I'm surprised we're able to squeeze it I
know dude well hey it's a pleasure
having you on uh
you're one of the best thank you very
much man I appreciate it I'm glad we
were able to go over these things and
just you know iron out some of the
confusion that might have been out yeah
sure man
appreciate it talk soon brother
peace out