ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
what's up fudge
oh man working working i took two weeks
off so you just have to come home and do
all the stuff you didn't do for the last
two years in two weeks so yeah that
sucks dude
yeah no rest for the wicked man how's it
going with you i'm doing okay hey dude
what do you got growing in there
um
i've got some
that whole back row
that's all gmo
nice
it's kind of stretched on me
doesn't it it's [ __ ] yeah that's
about
seven feet um
this is
from
big red gross
it is melon aid to dosey dose
i think he calls it pistachio
um this is
some kush cake
this is ice cream cake to mint julep
mint julep is
a lambo mike's uh
uh mint chocolate chip cookie the dna
kosher
there's
one
three nice heads on it they're just
about 25 days i'm in
five gallon bags
nice here's another one nice and open
you know
it's got a nice open structure
yeah i i love it you know
it's across the table on all of them
there's another one there
yeah another one there that's the
raspberry doula
uh yeah
ice cream cake i've been rocking those
out small hops for
six months
just trying to find the ones you know
you know i mean nothing yeah dude
nothing's ever easy you know and if you
say you're gonna do it it never works
out that way so
you know you just kind of
wallow through it you know i compared
you know trying to work a line is like
being the kid that has to practice the
trumpet you know while the other kids
are out you know
going ape [ __ ] out you know
[ __ ] playing in the summer and you're
kind of stuck moving in one direction
and it's you know that's tedious but you
know it's it's rewarding at a point you
know
yeah yeah it's it's something i mean
like it used to be the standard but yeah
right not for much anymore you know not
so much anymore you know i mean the way
the market moves and and the attention
spans and
and what not a kids it's just you know
it moves through it so fast you know i
have a buddy doing a wreck and you know
he said he's he's flipping uh you know
trains out you know every two to three
runs they're just two to three and done
you know
you know that fast so it's really
tough to do what we do in this industry
if you want to
you know you want to play with that hype
stuff or you know you want to stick to
your guns and and wait till you know if
you're not in that hot zone wait till
what you're doing comes
back you know
back in basically yeah
it's like it used to be at least like
for me five six years seven years before
something would come back around that i
made that wasn't popular
and then everybody'd want it and it
would be old seeds or i would just be
i've already given them all out for free
you know at some point because they
didn't sell
exactly exactly exactly and i mean
that's that's the tough one is nowadays
i think a lot of breeders just kind of
they throw those filler plants in that
you know they're not going to be the
main you know
bangers out of what they're dropping but
they're going to be plants that just you
know
kind of make money and i think you know
a lot of plants are thrown in in guys
menus as
options rather than choices you know
like yeah
you know i get thousand plants you know
i can get you know i can get 4 000 bucks
off that plant you know or or whatever
you know and they're they're pushing big
plants and just pollinate the [ __ ] out
of them and you know moving on to the
next one on and on and on you
something i've been covering lately a
lot just like trying to explain to
people the difference between
how we used to do it and now where the
market is pushing everyone to go like it
that like testing was a given and if
someone didn't test like we always would
give them [ __ ] it's like yeah [ __ ] you
ain't even testing that [ __ ] now
they got the [ __ ] advantage bro they
got the yeah yeah there was always
almost one guy to come in you know hey
uh i assume this is untested you know
and then you know all the hype boys be
like shut up you know oh you know aliens
genetics 2012 you know
we all saw that go down and and
that became our our new norm you know
yeah it did it did it [ __ ] sucks it
really sucks
because waiting
like i mean if you're going like if
you're hitting it hard running as fast
as you can
with a brand new line you're you're
making a cross and testing it you're at
least 18 months in if you're doing it
right like and actually seeing if
anything's good running it all the way
out you know and yeah
and that is not a um time span that
works for the current market
and there you know you see a lot of
people and they're you know claiming
they work just to f6 or you know bat
cross five or something and you you you
you go back on their feed and it's just
the arithmetic just doesn't lie you know
it's like dude you know you you
obviously just pulled the two best
looking plants you had and set them
aside and bred those together you know
there was no
there was no full look at it you know
you were you're you're gambling you know
absolutely gambling you know yeah it's
always a gamble but i think like what
guys i want i won't name any names but
there's a lot of guys who have figured
out the plan that
if they sell seeds that the majority of
the market
is not going to grow out those seeds for
at least a year year and a half maybe
sometimes longer so a lot of the
negative feedback they've got like two
years in to to [ __ ] just put a bunch
of [ __ ] out and run and that's
that's that's the the time span for it
yeah yeah there's a lot of guys that
have came and gone in the last two years
you know and you know probably popped up
with someone else you know you know you
don't have to be
you know fly by night
people there is in this industry period
you know yeah
so
sucks man it was it was a lot different
back in the day man you know you there
wasn't access to you know all these cuts
and whatnot and you knew when you got
something it was real you know because
people just weren't like that you know
and you know hearing you talk about
provenance you know for for the last you
know couple years has been really cool
because
a lot of people don't understand that
you know and they yeah you know i see
descriptions of cuts on people's clone
banks and whatnot and they're like well
you know
it's you know it's strawberry this or
that and then you know when it goes down
to the description they're like well
it's great in extracts and it's like
oh
come on now you know if yeah if it's
strawberry you know it should be
dripping off your skin when you leave
the room you know exactly
yeah you know so the you know the the
cover-ups you know there's i think
there's a lot of that with with the
banana too you know
just a pet peeve of mine you know it's
just
you know
there's a few big clone guys out there
and that you know that's their
explanation on why their banana isn't
bananas because you know you need to go
make oil out of it you know yeah
that's not right you know it made it it
made it halfway through flower over here
and
and uh
oh you just cut out there you are
yeah you know nothing just no banana
what the [ __ ] you know banana is banana
that stuff should be poppin you know the
the second you have trichromes you know
and if you know it you know you you know
what you're looking for you know what
the smell is you know what your stems
are going to smell like and you know i
will say this dude you got everybody can
rank on stem rubbers all they [ __ ]
want but i will masturbate a [ __ ]
stem you know it's not so much as
looking for a a particular smell i mean
it's it's looking for a familiar smell
you know everybody knows what a cam
smells like a million
or whatnot and you you know if you can't
you know you you can rub that damn stand
dude and at least tell you if you're in
the neighborhood
if you know what you're talking about if
you if you've rubbed that girl down
before many times i mean it's it's no
different than grandma's cookies you
should just you should just know that
essence it's putting off period you know
no different than grandma's vagina i
agree you should know what that smells
like
there it is
so let's let's talk about your your
starts dude like um what were some of
the first lines that you you that got
you into wanting to make seats in the
first place
first
you know the first seeds i ever made
were a uh from a
old university of
washington uh hash plant
that yeah you know came came to me
through some people from normal and you
know we
you know with that and the coffee bubba
you know in the 90s i mean we we wore
those [ __ ] like a damn placard on our
chest that was our family crest you know
if yeah you know you were in our
neighborhood you you knew it by by you
know the city and people called by the
city and they're like oh yeah you know
you must you know know so and so and you
would kind of get to know people but you
know you would never really know what
you had or whatnot because people just
weren't open but but uh i i did rotalyze
some uh
some hash plant seeds and
in the 90s i just wanted to continue on
i read up on the process and i went wow
okay well you know i guess i'm going to
flower these things 17 weeks and just
hope for the best and you know i ended
up with a lot of really nice seeds out
of it and
you know
everybody
was kind of affiliated with some just
small time air airports and whatnot
their mechanics and you know they were
flying around and whatnot and uh
uh they had all lost their cuts you know
and i kind of just
uh you know redistributed an s1 you know
amongst the buddies you know and
everybody thought it was so cool and i
thought wow man i i'd really like to do
this more and then and then you know
years went by and you know i mean i grew
always and you know i never
you know i never got to really level up
you know i'm a working shoes kids and
and you know some you know the truck
breaks whatever you know yeah
something you know i never
really got ahead you know and and i
ended up after medical caught on here uh
uh
getting
hooked up with my buddy from
construction who opened up grow shop and
uh i got hooked up with old exotic mike
uh
yep
we were guys that just kind of you know
shopped at the same place and whatnot
and you know he he was a damn good
[ __ ] grower man you know and and uh
what he was working with was a lot of
tga gear and whatnot
and uh i was more
man i you know i found a guy on
craigslist who had
who he had cuts the whole nirvana
catalog uh you know he had a lot of this
old uh
uh you know that the iced uh
oh yeah
you know a lot of paradise seeds and you
know i was
at that time you know i was more about
you know the thunder [ __ ]
and uh
uh you know that this the stuff that was
coming from europe you know we were
still
you know in the 2000s and and though you
know we saw some great california weeds
show up in the fall you know it was
you know unless you had the balls to run
the i5 corridor there just wasn't a lot
of it you know later on
towards seven and eight you know hell
people were just flying up and down that
thing and then you guys actually just
flooded our freaking market out you know
at a point
during those years like yeah 2006 2007
like
amsterdam if people don't know amsterdam
amsterdam was that those seed companies
were still dominating the american seed
companies they were small there were
very few big ones i think at that time
me and subcool were the only ones on the
attitude which had just taken the market
over the attitude it just started and
taking the market over so yeah i mean
that's why that's why guys in the u.s
were getting our seeds from amsterdam
because that's what you did that was
what was in demand
and you know it was it was a long time
it could be four or five months before
you got your seeds back then you know
and i mean people don't realize that it
was like you know there was no there was
no tracking you know you just you just
went to wherever you were having those
things set and just looked every day or
called is it there is the birthday card
there is it there yet you know
it's it's not like today where you can
just you know press a button and you
know if your bank's on point you know 72
hours later you know you have you have
seeds in the in
in the dirt you know yeah yeah
but uh but you know i started working
with mike and and
you know at the time you know like the
the ogres and banana kush
and uh you know grape ape and granddaddy
were just absolutely just murderizing us
as far as all what what you know we were
still all growing the dutch stuff you
know and
and it's like wow you know how can we
get a hold of this california action you
know you know we actually sat on a uh
you know once we were building a room
over here my buddy financed it and you
know mike helped pay for it and we uh
you know we got growing over here and we
were putting the walls up you know it
was like you know what what can we do
and at the time you know mike had made
seeds but
he wasn't like actively pushing them or
anything you know
really modest about it and and i know
right
yeah you know it's a long time ago and
you know it's like you know how how can
we beat these damn california genetics
you know
how you compete
the first answer was was sub cool seats
because you know he was in every
dispensary on you know every corner here
in washington you know so every every
magazine you could pick up with subco at
the time sure oh yeah and he had just
absolutely saturated the market with
those you know fifty dollar freaking
forty dollar packs you know they were
everywhere
and uh you know so mike had a few slave
crosses and whatnot and uh you know we
we started kind of pushing them on this
uh this thing called the northwest green
thumb
which was our our medical forums and it
actually you know became pretty big and
there was a lot of michigan guys on
there and you know a lot of guys that
poke in there just just for fun and
whatnot because sure there's so much
[ __ ] talking it was just ridiculous but
uh uh
the the guy who made the green thumbs
uncle actually was the founder of silk
road so
you know i i think they scared a lot of
people off once they started you know
trying to push bitcoin you know for oh
yeah
you know
you know back then you know this is
still 2011 or so so
yeah you know we we pushed the uh
you know the flav stuff and and you know
got our feet wet with that and then you
know of course the you know the infamous
star fighter pack was bought off alien
because you know uh my kid paid logic
for those those auctions right after the
the alien auctions right i remember
watching yeah yeah those that that
option was pretty well known because it
went for so [ __ ] much money
oh yeah yeah what was do you remember
how much it was
uh there was one pack that you know
apparently went for 4 500 bucks and
didn't get paid for and then mike
had bought that pack for uh 2100
and
the the seeds never showed up go figure
you know
logic said hey uh you know can you just
get a hold of alien and aliens sent them
30 seeds actually and uh
you know i believe it was the 29 and the
30 that actually made the f2s you know
with the uh
you know the uh yeah so you know
you know who knows what would have
happened if logic would have sent seeds
you know yeah right
you know you know that's where those
those those strong alien kush dom uh
plants came from you know
you know i mean by god you know i mean
if you go look into opposite pictures of
alien kush and then you know start you
know looking at you know mike star
fighter it was like wow okay yeah you
can see where we're going with this and
then you know i i did get a chance you
know over time to smoke ops is you know
a cherry alien dog and you know some
other personal ops ops cuts and it's
like wow
starfighter is a direct kino of these
plants directly
it looks like any anytime i see
starfighter stuff or anything descended
from it
you can always tell that it has the
alien technology like [ __ ] resin
rails the type of resin
it breathes very true for all that stuff
yeah exactly and his mail you know i
mean i gotta say kudos man i mean he
he picked a solid male and that thing
was just like a freaking car wash man it
would just you could you could put an
average plan in there and it would just
shine it you know i mean it had great
it had great traits as far as that went
the only downfall and i think what moved
him away was you know one he didn't want
to be a one-trick pony you know and and
number two is you know if you look at
the numbers i mean it has high thca
but
the rest of the categories are zeros you
know i mean
there's there's not much else other than
that dhca in there you know
so you know i mean it kind of you know
it kind of hit its ceiling and i think
you know that's what kind of it led to
its demise it's
you know
people were were expanding on on that
stuff and and you know that new bar of
26 percent thc you know in in 12 or 13
you know and you know went from like 17
up into the 20s it was like wow okay you
know [ __ ] got steamed here you know and
and you know kind of screwed us you know
out of a lot of great traits and
compounds i'm like oh yeah dude
you know which which kind of leads me
back to where i started was with
um was with the ultimate chem 08 you
know uh
you know i was lucky enough to
have some friends back in the early 90s
you know i'm not not going to say 91 you
know
i'm not trying to you know tell a story
or whatnot
you know you know i mean you hear some
of these these big ones out there you
know and it's just like okay yeah okay
so you were sitting next to skunk va and
you [ __ ] dropped your hot dog on his
leg okay you know yeah you know we
basically
had some friends that you know from
seattle that traveled around and they
would follow the dead and you know have
this contest every year you know they
would pick up weed and when the dead
took a break they'd come home and you
know we'd get the
the sweet blueberry and oh you know
some of it the skunk and the you know
the kgb the killer green bud that was
you know that we thought was lost in
like you know the mid to late 80s you
know some of that stuff you know
would come back around you know and and
it was like wow you know i i got to
smoke some
actually okay man all all [ __ ] aside
here uh
i was on a forum
uh called canada kinetics okay and it
was oh yeah everybody was popping and
you know bodhi was over on kinetics and
you know relentless and you know uh i
was over there mike was over a ton of
[ __ ] people were over there you know
oh my god so surfer had some
some starfighter f1b
yeah and uh
this was after alien and surfer have
their fallout when
surfer was kind of trying to pimp aliens
cuts out i guess you know
that and uh
so surfer was selling
packs of starfighter f1 and
you know i'm the new guy over at
kinetics mike and i you know and and you
know our reps aren't built okay whatever
you know i hit him up i'm like hey bro
you know i'd love to get some of those
starfighter f1s and he says
you know you know i i gave my list
because it was all about the list over
there yeah of course yeah everybody
reflects their list and of course jaws
won every time you know that guy is such
a [ __ ] dork
oh my god the biggest poser to ever hit
our scene oh [ __ ] next to osa
and you know he he did well you know
trading his own beings for other uh
other people's beings man i mean yeah
his blessing is [ __ ] huge you know
any letter you say there's just you know
40 or 50 strains there
and you know you we all know those peach
peach-colored walls with the blankets
over the windows you know yeah
yeah you know i i i was never on
kinetics because i i had been on the
precursor called pot pimp
and the owner
was a dude named rips and he literally
ripped everyone off and his moderators
were like
oh my god everybody got ripped off and
we got ripped up too let's start a new
site and they just started ripping
people off
yeah so i refused to be a part of it
wow that kind of goes into some stuff
that i've always wondered about because
that uh
okay let me ask you this man is rips
dead no do you think rips is still
walking this [ __ ] earth and stalking
people on on instagram yeah i'm sure on
a different name but sure yeah
yeah oh yeah yeah him and um mr djk
and
uh
i there was a few other dudes on there i
can't remember off the top of my head
but they were all part of that same crew
a dj i'm i'm friends with mr djk now
and i always have been but like you know
i mean that was his homie his tight
homie and he went and started a new site
it was suspicious not going to be
exactly so
so yeah we're at kinetics and i
basically got punk by surfer telling me
i only trade for top dog or elite
genetics gear and you know i mean this
is still you know 2012-ish i hadn't been
around on the internet man you know much
you know i'm an old-school dude and and
yeah you know so at that point i was
like
you know [ __ ] i know okay i know who top
dog is i need to find out who this
[ __ ] elite genetics guy is you know
and and i google them and i start seeing
this these this double dip banana and
and these names you know and i'm like
great names dude
i was like holy [ __ ] it's like a big
soda fountain i was like wow this guy
you know the twisted purple the lemon
larry you know
like well i was just like wow this this
just sounds like the dude i need to get
down with well you know i didn't read
far enough you know
[Laughter]
but you know uh uh you know i just made
it kind of my point
to
get as much elite genetics gear as i
could in a short period of time yeah so
someday i could throw that [ __ ] back in
that dude's face you know right
so yeah you know i started there you
know you were at you know we've talked
about before you're bidding on the same
pack of 08s yeah it's night late at
night and and that's where my journey
began you know i popped those those
seeds and
you know
not knowing what it was because you know
i mean back in the day man 90s 80s i
mean there's nothing had names you know
i mean it was
you know it was the kills it was
whatever the chronic where's the [ __ ]
weed whatever you know whatever you
called it and and
and it was like holy [ __ ] you know i
smoked this ultimate cannon it's like
wow grandma's cookies you know i've been
before you know and
you know i started you know
you know expanding because of the the
forums and whatnot and you know got to
smoke some d and some four and and you
know
uh some stuff lemonhoco was growing you
know he's yeah he's kind of the like the
old master splinter for all the breeders
here i don't i don't care what they say
you know he was he was the guy doing it
long before any of us and and you know
using predator mites and and doing
things that you know or you know
everyday practices now but you know 10
years ago we're like this guy's a
[ __ ] freak dude you know but
yeah
you know you think about all the people
that came out of that little northwest
green thumb you know it's you know
exotic me
uh you know pacific northwest roots kaya
uh dvg you know eric yeah uh dungeon
ball you know you know he was pushing
the granddaddy perps label at the time
but you know yeah
you know doing his own thing now and
[ __ ] you know he [ __ ] i can totally
vouch that he was doing ken's breeding
you know yeah
you know there is no [ __ ] to that
one
everybody in the room is confused so
lemon larry is different than larry og
you guys in atlanta larry og was going
big time but lemon larry was less
less so at the time lemon larry became
popular on forums for a while but it was
a lemon thai larry og not just larry og
that happened to be lemon so for the
people in the in the audience reading on
and talking go ahead
no sweat
yeah dvg was cool man but yeah he was
doing all kin stuff and i remember
back then i i was always [ __ ]
trolling ken because he was such a lamer
and he would always be super cool to me
even though he was on the dooba ken
account
and you know he's
he's got a quick fuse man but you know
if you sat down in that guy's living
room man you get nothing but [ __ ]
love you know yeah yeah he's cool
you know yeah he's got a quick [ __ ]
fuse man i i've seen it you know i've
seen it
yeah
yeah but uh you know yeah i mean i
started with the ultimate cam and and
you know that the 08 and
you know i i
ended up getting the
sauer larry cut from uh
from dr frost that was from zoolander
and dr frost you mean mr this is dr
frost you mean lacy frost yes exactly
yes yes so lacey frost uh
you know did a lot of animal cookie
stuff
and uh fire og
and he uh took a bunch of people's money
and went bought some boobs and then just
kind of disappeared dude that was that's
probably the smartest idea i wish i
would have done the same because
that's killer idea
killer idea
so yeah you know i ended up
you know he he kept on pushing on it you
know you need to do this you need to do
a bad cross and blah blah blah and i was
just like man
i'm still old school i don't want to
send you you know because he i was going
to send him uh some pollen and uh you
know cuts to my
ultimate camo wake females and just like
you know i just found these and where
i'm from we don't share dude you know
yeah so uh you know i had a tough time
with it mike was finally like man just
you know this guy says he has alien cush
yada yada yada yada yada you know
and uh he's like just you know be nice
to him you know i want to get some of
the seeds and
uh
so you know i ended up sending them the
ultimate cams and uh
you know four or five days later i get i
get this box
and
it was delivered to mike's shop and
no no it's delivered to my house i bring
it over to mike's shop and we open this
thing up and
there's water coming out the bottom
and
we crack this thing open immediately a
flyer comes out of it we're like oh [ __ ]
you know jesus this [ __ ] is hot you
know
uh you pull this thing just directly put
into a box
and
it was planted in the ground and yanked
out of the ground and it was in a
six-inch rock thank you
that was just [ __ ] it just wreaked
like avid and forbid and and all the bad
yes yeah yeah and it was like oh no you
know so
so i got that i actually i put it back
in the box and we left it outside for
two days in like february and i was like
[ __ ] that [ __ ] that guy you know i hit
him up said dude you were you're a dick
blah blah blah blah blah and then i got
thinking about it i was like wow okay
you need to hit a civilian up that
doesn't grow that can't get any
collateral damage and pay them you know
to nurse that thing back to hell so
yeah i went and bought a light and and
you know bought bought some azmax and
i bought some you know one step uh
oh god i can't remember that one-step
food you know just basic blue yeah uh
you know i i gave a dude two ounces to
to give it to me clean and and you know
it's like three months later i got this
plant back that was just you know
thoroughly shellacked and barely alive
it was so locked out and
you know the the process begun you know
it was my 08 mail and and uh
you know man it's i compare you know all
breeding man is just just like building
a house man or a car or anything man you
know you you start with the best
foundation you can and you just you just
build up from there man and
you know you just take your time and do
it right man you know and
you could see there for you know about
four years man a lot of people were just
having it you know breeders were having
terrible luck with with with intersexing
and whatnot and i mean it's become a lot
more
you know accepted and what not on a
small
you know a smaller level but you know
people weren't looking at their males
and and they were just throwing anything
in and it is it really showed it really
[ __ ] up a lot of good gene pools you
know and and
you know i i
i just try to start the best plants and
then you know as many as i can like you
know
like we both know you know if you if you
say you're gonna do something you know
and yet you put 20 down to get a you
know a a mission done and get some seeds
made you know i mean
[ __ ] it's going to take 40 you know and
when you don't expect it you get exactly
what you want so yeah exactly
i'm kind of at the point where i just i
just pop seeds i want to pop and i hope
for the best and i realize that you know
you know you can't make it happen until
it's there and
you know
you just don't force it you know we
don't you know this industry doesn't
need any more four seats you know and
you know i tell a lot of people do keep
your [ __ ] day job you know because
you know there's always that dude that
hits you up and they're gonna be then
they're like man i'm gonna be the next
seed junkie and you're like yeah yeah
right on bro man you know good luck to
you test your [ __ ] just don't quit your
day job you know yeah and
you know i
i think if a lot of people did this just
for fun or whatever you know then and
game would be a lot cooler you know the
the the people that don't smoke pot and
breed you know and and can't even give
descriptions of what the hell they're
working with or what they have or or
what to expect man you know i mean at
least you know you're gonna apply
somebody with a with a prediction you
know and and you know a lot of people
say that you know a good breeder just
can predict the outcome to an extent of
what you're going to find in his packs
you know and yeah
we all should be able to do that man
that's just taking responsibility for
what you're making you know yeah that's
just knowing what you're working with in
the first place like you don't just pop
and make you have to know what you're
working with to see if it's worth
breeding within the first place yeah
right
there it is and the other one is guys
that are picking up other guys's f3s and
and
you know making f4s first of all you
know we know these aren't actual f gens
yeah about correct well we'll call them
industry afghans because i i test that
for my pack but i'll just let you guys
know i don't know what an actual filial
jam is but
we'll stop there but guys that are
taking these packs they've they've never
never ran any of these northern lights
they've never ran great baby for these
granddads
and they're making [ __ ] the next
generation of seeds with them and it's
like dude you
you've never smoked real gdp in your
whole life and you're you're
you're making granddaddy hurt things
right now yeah
for one pack off ten seats you know
sometimes even less you know and
you know some of that needs to just go
away you know but but
back to you know the 08 you know i i
tested everything i beat the [ __ ] out of
everything
out crossed it to a few more things and
then eventually made the f2s and it was
actually
fit almost
seven
years for me to make the f3s you know i
mean i grew a lot of them and i i
thought it was just like one of the
coolest crosses i had ever grown but i
couldn't figure out where
to take it
and then i kind of realized man there's
no need to really take anything anywhere
you know and so i'm i'm kind of an
anti-bottleneck guy now you know i'm
more issue
you know i'm more into
four males and
two females all on the same gene
frequency you know a micro population of
similar plants where
you know i can call some stuff i don't
want out you know more more suspense
features or or whatnot you know but you
know if i'm aiming for a an indica i
mean i shouldn't be really necessarily
looking at some plants in in my pool of
plants i have to use you know you know
you know i call the whole time and you
know try to get myself down to a decent
sized micro pool
you know out of a larger population and
then throw those flower them do what i
need to do and then take those clones
then i can actually you know make a
generation of seeds and feel confident
about
what i'm putting on the table what
everything has to offer what i've seen
what to expect you know just just you
know i don't i don't have a big tester
truth you know so yeah
you know for me it's just you know
sometimes easier to do it myself and
that's kind of what slowed me down this
year i really haven't done any paper
drops just because i've just been been
finding the plants i want to work with
man stuff that inspires me versus just
you know currency man you know i don't
you know i
i do okay enough that i don't
need to make seats for a living and i'm
[ __ ] there's nothing wrong with that
man a lot of everybody's good enough to
do it and there's a ton of guys doing it
and [ __ ] props to everybody this this
is a part-time thing for me and and i
realized at a point that it kind of
became about the money for a split
second and i i kind of
realized that you know it was great
because every breeder boy you get your
first drop in and it's just like
i don't even know how to describe it
it's just like a
[ __ ]
three bulls eyes or a [ __ ] running a
table a nine ball it's like you know you
get adrenaline pump just like wow you
know people paid for my [ __ ] you know
i'm right i'm somebody you know
yeah i know that's for real
and
that that can turn you man i could turn
you quick you know and and
so i just i just kind of slowed down and
i'm just trying to kind of just trying
to just
i'm trying to find the one you know i
would love
to
hit a male to 20 plants you know but if
i don't have that male and i don't have
that 20 plants man i'm i'm in idle so
you know i guess you can say i got
writer's block at the moment you know
i'm just i'm just going through
everything
trying to find the right plants to do
what i need to do you know i can
sympathize with the writer's block thing
that shit's for real
right you know the [ __ ] runs came
around dude
is worthless to me man yeah i don't have
anything
and it's just like dude man this is this
is like not even practice sweet i
wouldn't even smoke this just just to
practice smoking weed you know
yeah so yeah man that was kind of an
uninspiring year
as far as that went i just i didn't you
know i i i thought you know i did a
slice cream cake which was you know sour
lariat ice cream cake and and you know
that was as far into gelato as i i
wanted
to be you know ice cream cake you know
the the cut that i had was was great it
put up huge numbers man it was like 38
percent
you know with everything and you know
the washington state standards you know
uh uh
but it still
goes back to that starfighter thing
where it's hollow you know yeah i like
the chems i like the diesels i like the
ogs and the the the crosses of all three
because they they get you in the gut you
know it's like yeah it's like getting a
ride in a fast car the torque you know
that that
feeling of helplessness you know i i can
smoke some good cam
and
just get up and move around and i don't
even have to think i don't have to
[ __ ] move my legs they just walk
themselves you know and
you know
yeah
that's what i like you know i don't
want to have to you know like i said go
through and and especially with me
having hyperemesis uh you know i can't
smoke a large quantity of [ __ ] pot
you know it's you know from the from one
episode when i start throwing up and it
stops
i usually wait 10 days before i start
smoking again it should probably be two
months but you know i'm right on the
clock again for it happening again so
that sucks you know my tolerance is low
so [ __ ] i can get through the day with a
[ __ ] gram dude i'm a flower and i'm
like [ __ ] set you know like
ready for bad [ __ ] bloodshot eyes but
you know that that day
i was [ __ ] high all day i didn't have
to [ __ ] move my legs to take a step i
was [ __ ] moving you know
you know i i
i really got into the sour larry stuff
because it you know it it it
had a high level of mercy and humulin in
it and uh
you know it was it did great as far as
medically you know so it was it was it
just it was a win-win you know and that
was my last
you know big male you know the big the
big one i worked and you know probably
across to 15 females probably close to
you know and and
i just kind of at a point when elite was
out that last time and just kind of
bugging me i just felt like dude i i
want to completely remove myself from
anything to do with you dude and every
every time he got out and said you know
okay can i get some she can i get a
package and then it was one it's two and
he just he he just never just he never
quit you know so
yeah life
well the thing with this [ __ ] too like
if we're being real like all this early
[ __ ] like none of it was consistent you
could buy two packs with one name on it
be completely different but because he
was using like bubba and og early on
like most of it was pretty decent
compared to what other people were
putting out but trying to figure out
what [ __ ] really was in your packs was
[ __ ] impossible
exactly dude i told them that at a point
it's like you know he he'd hit me up and
say stuff like oh dude you must be rich
from using my stuff in your gear you
know and i was like oh my god
it's like dude for real dude you know
and and yeah it just you know he got
weird and there's always late night
messages and it's just like man this
dude's [ __ ] out but he's [ __ ]
gonna be back in soon and oh yeah you
know i just i just finally told him it's
just like [ __ ] dude weird so what is it
this isn't
and i just i just needed to remove
myself from his gear basically so you
know i ended up making the cami [ __ ]
sours and that was
pretty much my you know equivalent to
the the oats you know i'm i'm done with
those it's out of my hair i won't be
making more but you know i can at least
have
a platform of the same genetics but
actual cam cuts with what
provenance yeah right
you know because it was you know i used
skunk uh va dog patch he said it was
okay and you know there it is man i've
got you know my equivalent to the 08
probably a little more
indica you know there was a lot of a lot
of you know 10 and 11 weeks stuff in in
elites 08 you know and i'm noticing in
these candy [ __ ] sours you know it's
you know eight and a half nine and a
half and you're you know you're out
you're done you know so
you know it's just it's a better place
for me you know so
you know i know i just you know i'm just
trying to kind of go through right now
and just
you know make make another batch of as
many crosses as i can you know i have
that over my dog named like a large
a large bag of pretty much everything i
i had for myself and my sons to carry on
all vacuum sealed up and you know it was
uh
it's
i couldn't put a price on that bag
i had a bag that if i ever needed to
leave town in five minutes that was the
bag i was grabbing yeah
you know i had some of the old uh the
lemon bubba crosses you know that i
would elise lemon bubba or moda slim and
bubba whoever made it you know they
argue about it but you know it's
it is what it is who are you going to
believe ron or jesse you know yeah god
only knows
hey so people are asking about your mr
whitey does that sound familiar yeah man
oh
back in the day
i uh
who did i originally get them from um i
got some
got some bubba ogres some bubba oak
seeds
in a tree
okay i remember when that was made
um the bubba oh um you know i want to
say i got them from
is it seeds of compassion maybe yeah
could have been
when he like a uk guy and didn't kind of
work with fire stacks for a sec
i can't remember on that
god but you know he's an older guy
been around and he uh you know he traded
mike a bunch of exotic he might create a
bunch of exotic gear and i you know went
through the list and picked some stuff
out and i i got a bunch of these these
bubba ogres and uh
you know ended up getting a male in
there you know and and
you know the first thing was i hit csi
because you know at the time you know he
was that you know he was the new
femme guy on the block and whatnot it
was like okay
there's anybody to talk to here it's you
you know and he says he says nope
nope no possible way not gonna happen
you know it's contamination you know
yeah uh yeah [ __ ] them those aren't
white bubba ogres and blah blah blah
blah blah blah you know
you know i ended up running into him in
a cup you know and
actually like blazing past uh archives
like like hey nice to meet you blah blah
blah yeah yeah whatever you know and
running over the [ __ ] inspector you
know yeah dude off but uh whatever
and and you know i i mean i've been
reading up you know there is a one in a
million it does happen you know and and
you know it's possible you know and yeah
you know
he
he couldn't argue it you know at a point
you know and i threw a ton of them out
because i was really
really
wondering about it because of the fact
you know you you just don't have all the
goods there to make a mail you know and
and
we grew up a population of 100 of them
out
over here at this house
and uh
that was actually where a male came from
that mike used
in some of his crosses
um
i think he
he released like eight strains with that
male but it was an absolute white dom
bubba ogres i i ended up i crossed the
uh bubba ogre mail to the white
uh forum cut cookies
because it was right around
so okay yeah
i was rocking the forum cut predator
paint
blackberry kush
and uh
you know i did we uh
have a guy out here 210 beans he helped
me a little bit a while back and uh he
had gotten this cut of blackberry kush
down in pendleton oregon uh which you
know pendleton oregon has no relation to
work and kid at all you know by yeah you
know by you know what i know about ken
and where he grew up and whatnot but
uh
it was oregon kids blackberry kush you
know and there's no disputing it you
know it was the it was the small [ __ ]
that liked to grow out sideways and
throw those three bladed leaves down low
and you know it would it would put on
some nice purple color and it had great
frost but
same starfighter complex where it just
didn't it wasn't a any kind of full
spectrum high or anything yeah yeah
you want to smoke more in 20 minutes you
know
it's you know it's that type of wheat
you know
so
yeah you know i messed around with those
for a long time and i you know i grew
them out i grew out multiples and you
know i think i ended up sending an
inspector back a bunch of pictures i'm
not sure but you know i talked about
with a bunch of you know other breeders
and sending them pictures all my
findings and you know they're like you
know
fine you know you're dude you have white
dawn plants in there you have bubba dome
plants in there and then you have that
classic
ogre sativa plant you know big bush with
you know nine and 11 bladed you know uh
leaves on it everything slumped over and
if you go back to icymag
uh somebody had a couple of pictures of
the s1s and then the actual
ogres cut over there you know and uh
you know you you would see that as well
you know i more so than anything
actually there was more you know classic
ogres in there
than anything you know
uh
so
you know yeah i brought those out for a
while made a few crosses i i know one
cut was in colorado and did 35
thc back about
oh [ __ ] probably six years ago or
something but you know that's
just one that got eight eaten by the
dogs
that was one that i probably had 30 of
those left
i i always try to
if i'm fond of something i want to give
the time it deserves so i i hoard a lot
of seeds that i make because
it's just not the time you know
i really want to work these but it's
just i've got other [ __ ] on the plate
and if i can't you know give it 150
percent
i can't [ __ ] with this and
i had a lot of stuff that whole bag was
stuffed like that and they ate the whole
bag and oh no
a pack of you know starfighter f2s which
i had a thousand dollar offer for oh
there was old rascal gear in there and
it was it was a big bag of seeds was
this recently
uh this was last
last
halloween yeah i kind of remember when
all this happened because i remember you
busting out rascal gear and i was like
oh [ __ ] yeah oh yeah yeah yeah just just
all of it just wasted and then you know
that gave me a big pile of uh
just floor hash seeds and i did end up
sending all those to speak easy and you
know
we might have to find a few definite
plants out of there you know there's i
had a sour larry to uh
uh
zeus cut to
some
of the
ultimate sfb cam that uh yeah
karma had given me a bunch of packs back
in the day to run through
and uh uh he gave me the ultimate sfv
cam which is a completely different plan
you know the i'd say the kimo 8 you know
was a nice sour cam and and the uh
the uh the sfv cam has a lot of uh
he he said he put uh
swerves
sfvbx in there that was crossed to
supposedly an appy bx
you know and uh
i do get a lot of
really short
stubby leafs
the afghani traits and those those would
be the sweet plants that are in the
bunch and they're they're actually
really cool because
you you get some of the sfv too and it
kind of
it kind of equates to like a almost like
a piney
like a piney cam you get i get tiny cams
out of there too where there's you know
it
it it was really cool man uh you know i
really wish i would have made more
more seeds of it but i you know i had
two females out of the packs
and they both mattered late and it just
it's just
that the late flowering manners are so
just unappealing to me man yeah
they can ruin whole [ __ ] crops and a
bunch of preemie seed that [ __ ] sucks
yeah it's just you know just just just
looking at it you know i just you know i
hey i love some candies you know but
don't get me wrong i i've seen that you
know nine or late or whatever but
you know compared to back in the day
when we had some uh i remember mike had
this apollo 13 from sub cool
and
this thing
threw down you know
would throw down a pound of plant easily
by itself in a five gallon pot you know
with just pro mix in it and uh
it would be covered top to bottom and
freaking little sterile manners and it
was just like oh my god
i kind of look at it i hated the smoke
it was terrible all that you know i
i hate to say it but you know a lot of
that space queen dom some cool gear just
was not in my wheelhouse you know yeah
you know that's that was the biggest
complaint from everyone was all the
space green stuff [ __ ] room rooms
and there it is you know i i i was i've
always been a camo g guy you know yeah
that that's that's what i like that's
that's where my my palate is that's
where the the effect that i desire in
crosses is and
you know it's just it everything works
out the best you know i have a few lines
that i work in the mid juleps you know
or whatnot you know at least has the
kosher in it and impacts the punch and
and you know has good frost with the uh
you know
the starfighter in there deep down uh
but uh you know the kosher still gives
it legs man you know so i enjoy
smoking it's good daytime smoke but you
know you know for the most part i'm a
indica guy 100
man you know i want to i want to smoke
and feel the effect and relax and calm
the [ __ ] down you know that's my thing
you know
so with the with the um talking about
the reversed males so me and inspector
have gone back and forth on that ever
since we've known each other like i said
we're stupid friends because i've seen
what looks like males appear from pure
s1 lines where i know they weren't
contaminated
in the end
what what we kind of came to the
conclusion of
when these things were tested sex tested
they would test females but they were
expressing all male
it's a rare occurrence
but it definitely can happen you know i
know what you're saying you know i i
i've read about it i haven't really got
to see it yet yeah but yes i i have
heard of them
expressing or you know masking or
whatnot yeah it's with with with
cannabis plants like it's really easy to
see with with uh reversal spray because
i mean you could you could
reverse a femme line that is most that
is all female reverse it and make it
turn male so manipulating any kind of
hormones can make something express a
hundred percent male even if there's not
male chromosomes if that makes sense
yes yes yeah now now it's a trip
now how could i get true males
from across to the white then if i if i
i crossed that
that bubba ogres yeah
and then those offspring
had males in them yeah i mean it it
shouldn't be more than maybe one or two
males per 100 um
but it would just be
females expressing male as opposed to
just being
genetically male it would just look like
males but genetically they're female if
that makes sense
cannabis is a weird [ __ ] plant and
and a lot of times people put like human
like think about human type genetics on
it like where things are definitely male
definitely female etc you can have
something with all like all female
chromosomes express male which is it's
rare but it happens and it can happen
for thousands of different reasons you
know
and they can follow
now
long term though will will progeny of
that
false male
contain males
yes usually what for some for whatever
reason yes yeah and and the longer it's
worked back
it will
slowly gain more males in its population
yeah and that that's that's that's the
other hard part that we've never figured
out scientifically why that happens
right it's been the longest process like
just from when i first started reversing
plants and noticed that males were
popping up and of course people are like
no no no pollen contamination i'm like
but this is like one in a thousand how
am i getting one into that well pollen
contamination you know so i fought it
for a long time trying to figure it out
tighten up rooms figure it out and it is
complicated it's way more complicated
than just exactly but but
most of the people who sell packs
that are like half male half female and
from a reverse pack that that's pawn
contamination
yeah i've done it myself on accident
thinking that i knew what i was talking
about and uh sold paul and contamination
but
oddly enough it looked like both the
parents which always [ __ ] me up you
know
yeah
yeah it was crazy man i i ran through a
ton of those mr white
um a few you know
a few runs of the blackberry bubba ogres
um you know it's hard to get any kind of
scientific evaluation or anything using
cookies in anything
yeah i bet
yeah right i couldn't you know give any
good info on that but yeah it was really
bizarre seeing seeing males and and like
i said you know chopping it up with with
uh
with caleb and just you know just
walking away stupider than i was you
know before the conversation
you didn't have
yeah
you know so
yeah man that was that was about 2013
man
i would love to go back into those i do
have some mystery like ultimate
oh sorry i'm picking lee
so mr white's ultimate kid i think i
still have mr white to
the white
uh that's cool
yeah yeah a few of them you know
they didn't get every pack but i'd be
damned you know there there were certain
breeders they just liked the packaging
on uh green team they loved his labels
but they didn't eat any of the packs so
it's like i had like 10 tore up dream
team packs and then you know they didn't
get into the seed containers at all it's
like oh nice you know there's
there's a hundred seats down the drain
you know
so
yeah
that's a it was a rough one
so where are you at now what what what's
your newest muse are you just kind of
like you said stuck on um
writer's block
i'm uh i'm back into these uh
i have a towering inferno i made with
the uh norcal fire og the ultimate sfp
cam
uh
i have made f2s
released a few packs i made f3s
but uh just a just a small just you know
you know personal pack type of thing and
i'm i'm going through those and i would
like to make the next gen of those and
uh
you know i'm down to like these you know
like i said in those ultimate sfv chems
uh
that you know about one and uh i'd say
two and ten
i'm getting these uh these short little
appy plants and and you know the rest of
the population is is a really you know
stretchy camog headband plant you know
yeah
they grow fast they grow vigorous they
grow you know straight up and as long as
you know you clean the bottoms you just
keep pushing and you look next to it and
here's this little you know 150 yard
marker that's you know a foot call with
these you know
a few little branches coming off the
meristem and you know that's what it
wants to be so yeah
you know i'm trying to eliminate that
you know and and
you know like i said if i can just keep
working these
you know micro populations on these same
frequencies you know these you know if i
can use you know six plants that you
know all have that you know soapy smell
the beginning of flower and then you
know by the end i'm getting you know
classic you know tennis ball og and
and some you know volatile cam turks in
there you know i mean that's that's what
i'm expecting you know so yeah you know
i'm not there yet uh that that's the one
and uh
also i have uh i used relentless's 818
sfb cut that he you know worked back in
the day
i hit that uh same ultimate sfv cam and
uh
i'm
working the f2s right now i've got some
really you know that that relentless cut
was just straight
gasoline just like classic
gasoline no ethanol in it just classic
gasoline but it
it was really short and just really just
a
terrible grower it put off terrible
flowers you know really small just you
know thumbnail size flowers and it's
like wow this thing's either you know
it's either drifting or degenerating or
something so
before she uh
got tossed i hit her to the o uh the 08
and the ultimate sfv chem as well i hit
him to both
parents because at the time i was into
this
okay work these lines parallel hit the
white
to both the open sf
and the 08 and then you can
have two cam white chem lines and you
tweak it either way depending on what
you find in these these two lines here i
was kind of you know trying to shoot out
you know six six oh g's all in the same
path and you know working into the best
camo gi to it you know by
you know manipulating what was there so
you know i that's just kind of what i'm
doing now is is
playing with those those eight one
eights
uh
both both of them the uh the sfv one and
then the eight winning owings
going through those pretty heavily and
uh
you know just just trying to just keep
furthering the lines you know i mean
yeah i don't want to go too overboard
and and
you know like that you know working that
sour larry from you know bx1 bx2 bx2
f2 bx2 ix you know it was
this is a lot of [ __ ] time and i i
get why guys don't want to
you know you know they want to keep it
moving and keep different flavors coming
in and whatnot because i mean dude
that's a pain in the ass not every
plant's a [ __ ] rainbow man and yeah
a lot of times you know especially in
the early days with it i mean it was it
was like classic [ __ ] gold mining you
know you were you were [ __ ] sifting
through rocks to find gold nuggets more
so than you know
you know now you know i think everybody
has stepped their game up and
you know they're there's a lot of good
good strains out there you know where
guys are pulling good numbers five out
of you know
five out of 10 females or whatever you
know approved and you know people are
finding keepers and whatnot not
not long-term keepers i'm noticing yeah
well i i think i think that the
definition of keepers has changed so
much
that
i don't know that they're finding
keepers that we would have considered
back in the day
but they are instagram appropriate and
more resinous therefore
they're easier to label keepers if that
makes sense
oh yeah yeah cause it's not the keepers
are chosen on instagram by pictures not
necessarily by by the quality of the
smoke the complexion yeah
yeah exactly
dude
give me green weed any day
[Laughter]
you know i mean i liked animal cookies i
thought for a cookies cross that was
that was a good one you know i've had a
few
but for the most part man that i i still
like anything free cookies you know what
with the exception man i i can't dog on
it too hard but you know we smoked a lot
of northern lights here you know yeah
that's just one
one i i
wouldn't care if i ever saw it again
dude i mean
yeah people got tired of nl up there
yeah oh do you either smoke you either
smoke
weed or you smoke nl there for a while
you know yeah you had two choices and in
the fall you know this was around
[ __ ] late 90s man you're either smoking
you're either smoking lights for your
smoking you know that we call the
canadian bacon
and we could still get the uh every fall
from you know cali we get the christmas
bud up here you know yeah and only in
small amounts you know and we literally
just knew somebody that brought enough
to take care of like 10 friends you know
and it you you put your order in on like
the fourth of july and you know had your
fingers crossed you know yeah but uh
yeah it's it's changed you know these
you know it used to be hard to get cuts
and seeds and
[ __ ] you know it's it's a whole new
world you know
ballpark for all of us yeah dude
but uh i still believe there's plenty of
[ __ ] you know legendary giants and
all those old seeds man and
you know uh uh i i think a lot of people
need to just step back and
you know
work on resurrecting something that you
you know and like and and can work with
and call your own and whatnot and you
know put the pedal to the metal with it
you know cross it to 20 different things
you know we don't need 10 guys all
making the same crosses and
yeah that's getting old yeah
it's terrible it's like oh you know we
see it you know everybody went orange
for a minute then yeah you know
everybody was trying to go you know you
know cookies and then all of a sudden
everybody was going sour and then you
know it's it you know it's just you know
i understand it you know i mean the
wheel
is never gonna stop turning but
you know we don't
we can at least try to reinvent some
things
yeah
what do you have on your plate what are
you working with
um we're doing the nl projects right now
with csi we have some other stuff that
we're going to start a company with uh
mutant stuff
and i'm i have some some blue skittles
some um
i did pop some of the blue max just to
take the light a little bit forward and
then the punchy booster which is the uh
it's all blue bonnet stuff mostly just
because i loved it so much you know
is there anything else you want to talk
about before we before we wrap it up
no man
it's been a privilege dude like i said
man back in the day dude i [ __ ]
looked up to you and [ __ ] a lot of
other dudes man so i appreciate you
having me on and [ __ ] appreciate your
time it's great meeting you down here
and [ __ ] dude and uh yeah [ __ ] and
then also love little boys
yeah i know so green loves
us agreed loves little boys that's right
it's my pleasure you've always been
super super [ __ ] cool and i
appreciate you brother and and thank you
for coming on like what it's
right on all right
take care
all right
thanks again to thunderfudge for
stopping by he really is a [ __ ] cool
dude really really cool dude uh i've
i've had the privilege of hanging out
with him smoking with him [ __ ]
shooting the [ __ ] in person
and uh yeah all right y'all lots of love
cheers thanks for stopping by
[Music]
you