ready go
[Music]
so
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Music]
yeah i don't know how to do this [ __ ]
you got it
does that work yep that's perfect dude
cool
all right how are you doing today
pretty good oh itself uh good they had
some good questions at first um do you
know about any of the history of trinity
the cut that's going around
uh just that it came out of eugene
really um
i don't really know anything else other
than that the one that i've seen
recently
uh does not remind me of what i used to
buy out of eugene that's interesting
it's a lot then the more recent thing is
more a lot more modern
sweet smelling yeah and i just remember
that all the trinity that i ever saw
even though like different um
phenos uh
or whatever you know whatever jars of
weed that were coming around like were
called trinity it always was burnt
rubber yeah it was
roadkill it was burnt rubber so
yeah the newest trinity um a lot of them
have like dud branches and i ended up
with one of the [ __ ] dud branches and
it uh
yeah it spreads pretty quick
so yeah that uh
especially if you're not um
keeping the [ __ ] uh
um
the dunning likes to proliferate in low
light yeah
so absolutely dude and fungus gnats seem
to be a vector
yeah yeah i've heard that in uh aphids
and thrips
yeah pretty much anything that like
chews on your uh
shoes on your plants is probably going
to be a pretty good vector for it and
particular shoes on your roots also yeah
it's it's one of those has like the
[ __ ] rubbery stems with no texture
three flowers everywhere you know
yeah totally ugly [ __ ] things all
right
here's a good question who's your
favorite breeder dude
um
i don't know i mean
for me it's it's just there's good
varieties that you know my favorite
breeder is accidental herming how about
that
yeah did you have a breeder you looked
up to when you first started though
um
no in particular i was just a seed buyer
i wasn't like
i don't um
i don't idolize people that much you
know so it wasn't really like about the
person so much to me as it was just uh
the product that came out of it that was
it yeah a lot of the people that i got
into i immediately regretted once i met
him you know like like dj short and some
other people like they just don't want
to talk about [ __ ]
yeah and i had the benefit of having
like met a lot of those people early in
my career or have run across them uh
with the seattle hemp fest stuff and all
that kind of [ __ ] so um
you know
what's that saying about like not
meeting your heroes because they might
not
stand up to the standard you have in
your mind or whatever you know
so for me it to me it wasn't so much
about the person it was what kind of
work you're doing and what are the
results from it that's it yeah i think
that's that's a pretty smart answer too
because a lot of people are dicks that
do good work
right and you know i'm here for the
genetics i don't really care about
who you are it it really has nothing to
do with it for me personally yeah
what are you what are your thoughts on
the whole filos thing going down where
what did you think
at all does it matter
i mean i think a lot of people are have
miss uh
misguided attention
right
um
you know they don't really have that
much data you know they have short
sequence genome testing right
and if you lift listen to kevin's [ __ ]
he you know he's much more
um knowledgeable about the whole type
hold the science behind it than anything
so
um
for me it was just like uh
you know what are they really gonna be
able to do with it anyways and
they
like a bunch of my stuff is in their
galaxy that i didn't send in because
they were they're able to just go
purchase the product oh yeah um and put
it in that so like how you know
what are you really gonna do right not
not
not only can you not send them the
product and all these other things but
you can't have your product on the shelf
somewhere because they can just buy it
put the [ __ ] stem in and then send do
their short sequence analysis so
what um
you know
what are you gonna do to stop it even if
there were even if they even if they
were
legitimate about it or weren't
what difference is it going to make they
can still acquire all the data that they
want anyways so the short sequence data
yeah i think kevin said it best dude
like when you it broke it down explain
how it works
uh kevin from um medicinal genomics when
he broke it down and explained how it
works that like he ran uh their data
through his software and it just dumped
everything out as invalid um
sure yeah i think people
are missing the main main points yeah
they lied we all get that they didn't
yeah that's the only thing but so so
does 95 of everybody else that exists in
this space too yeah you know that's
that's why i call out so many people is
because there's
blatant evidence it's not even me just
like
making [ __ ] up there's high times
articles where they [ __ ] admit to
this [ __ ] yeah it's like what else
you know what are you gonna
what do you expect
what else you guys got
let's get some good uh strain history
questions
oh i got one for you i got one for you
so we can put to rest some [ __ ]
purple
mad farmer's family or not
i haven't really read into it but i find
it highly
uh unlikely
[Laughter]
yeah i mean it's it's probably the same
odds as crippy coming from kawaii yeah
and making ode exactly you know
or what other
20 different [ __ ] up stories that
someone has made up in the last 10 years
that is obvious [ __ ] that some
for some reason people perpetuate i
don't even know yeah i have no idea the
same reason we still hear [ __ ] og
kush is what kim [ __ ] lemon thai
yeah the ocean grown story it's like how
many times do like
how many people have to say how shity
that person is for people to stop
believing
all right here we go uh what do you know
about the organ funk and or blue dots do
you have any experience with them
blue dot like i said last time was a a
cut down the bay area and um
uh
what was the other one um uh working
funk
i never saw oregon funk yeah
how do you feel about the josh d story
i mean every
person that i know that got og back then
it all leads back to josh yeah so
it's you know
from my perspective it's as legitimate
as it comes
everybody traces back to him yeah
yep
i think that's the one of the only few
people that actually can has everybody
traced back to him that wasn't 100 full
of [ __ ]
and i i saw
pictures uh like the na the film
negatives
from josh of him and matt and then the
next picture in the film negatives is
og kush right it's it's i mean the plant
is really easy to identify once you know
and so it's it's pretty obvious to me
that um
they got more evidence of having it back
in the late 90s than anybody else i've
ever met yep
what do you feel was your most left on
release
um
i don't know i mean
you know certain stuff you just expect
to move slow because it doesn't have a
brand name i mean dog [ __ ] crosses even
as popular as it was back in
the northwest back in the day
i guess the name doesn't translate well
yeah yeah i could see that dude the cat
piss crosses also same thing
uh it's not really that popular but uh
um
the name was always really popular man
the san diego cactus is a [ __ ] legend
though like like being from san diego
and [ __ ] like that was the bomb
you know i can't believe that doesn't
sell better than it does
yeah it's you know you just don't have
people rapping about it i guess there
you go maybe maybe if it had been called
cheetah piss we'd all it'd all be fun
cheetah cookie piss
yeah lion piss my bad
bobcat piss
let's see what we got
um
albert walker across the face off is it
coming back
i never released it you never released
it
yeah that never got sold i just had uh
the albert walker manic line
um
that was the number 32 line yeah
that sounds cool
what can you what can you tell us about
the manic
that came from shroomie
uh it was there was a female and a male
that came from he said they came from
some family in the humble they had ibled
it um
no one had known that i knew had a
um
[Music]
used the mail yet so i just i have two
and then made hybrids with it
okay what's your uh man the manic female
was like purple urkel without the purple
smell oh really
yeah like same growth pattern um
[Music]
a real similar bud structure it got it
would turn purple on the tops um and it
just had that like sw really sweet
skunky smell that that uh
um
that uh urkel has but just without that
like purple lavender kind of top end
yeah i always thought that was
interesting with urquell is it as it as
it grows like when it's first in bloom
it's really skunky and you wouldn't
expect it to turn grapey at the end
yeah if you grow it right um
it can finish pretty skunky too wow
erkel and manic both
here's one golden coast brotherhood of
eternal love afghan anyone ran it
i have no idea yeah i i actually have
i've run it
it's uh it's it's a good afghan but it's
not skunky it's not anything uh it
wasn't what i was looking for
what's yeah what's your rules on
breeding with your gear
oh i mean it's not about my year or
their year or whatever it's just put in
some work so that we have
differentiation between
people's selections in their lines so if
you're not putting any selections and
then what are you really doing you're
just
putting more of the same thing into the
gene pool yeah
and poor and poorly selected that if you
didn't do any um
uh
didn't do any selection work yeah if
it's just popping the pack of seeds and
picking the first female yeah
right you could get really lucky or you
could just be proliferating a bunch of
garbage under the same name and now it's
either diluting the original work
or
maybe it maybe makes it better in
certain cases but in most cases it
doesn't
yeah
is it true lumpa farms split up
who cares um
let's see what we got uh it's got to be
better questions than that
wasn't alien the breeder of fruity
pebbles og
yeah i'm pretty sure alien genetics was
what else we got
did you ever find anything worth
worthwhile in the dutch flower stuff
uh nope
all right what was your first uh strain
that you sold man
uh probably the 32 line yeah 32 what's
that yeah the albert walker manic line
cros albert walker manic male crossed
with
uh sauerkush um
i don't think i sold any albert walker
bx ones but
uh sauerkush original diesel
uh master kush
um
a couple other things can't remember did
you are you pretty good about keeping
back stock and stuff and and preserving
you're like preserving your own lines
and holding back stock of it
yeah i have everything wow
that's something i have every seed of
everything that's ever been made i have
thousands of seeds of everything that's
ever made
really
that that i made yeah i'm gonna have to
blow you for something then all right uh
and then i just um
i just popped pretty much all the old
seeds that i have from 15 years ago and
that's it that's awesome
and so all i have left is just seeds
that i've made
see
archive has very gassy chirps what other
flavor profiles do you feel you have
dialed in aside from gassy
that's pretty much what i breed for
skunky i mean you know every every other
flavor out there
um but has to be skunky you know yeah
what's your fastest finishing release
um
probably a shark bite but i don't think
i've put any of that in
a while
let's get some strain history questions
come on y'all
super dangerous this guy keeps asking
about super dave genetics i don't even
know what that is to you
uh he's just a dude up here in
washington i don't i don't know
i i don't know a whole lot about him or
haven't seen a lot of his work yeah it's
hard to comment on [ __ ] like that
why do i think the bland [ __ ] becomes
popular
it's because people because the whole
world is turning into a
consumed by visual
market marketing right so if it looks
good
it sell it people want to buy it you
know
even though the vast majority of really
really tasty strains
don't look the best because you're
selecting for terpenes and flavor not
for
visual appeal
and and when no one was taking pictures
of the bag a week because they didn't
want to get busted
uh
the best selling point was what it
smelled like when it opened up yep
when you opened up a bag
did we cover albert walker last time
where it originated from i don't think
we did um
maybe i'm not sure
yes uh i don't think we did maybe
yeah
i got it from
my buddy uh cannabis reverend up here
and uh he um
got it from this other kid who got it
from the old timer
and that dude lived like an hour and a
half away we were just uh
buying the herb back then
uh canvas reverend happened to get a cut
one time uh i think he took it down to
oregon lost it
uh and then reacquired it again um this
is like 2003
probably
yeah 2003
and uh
like 10 years later
the the guy that we got the cut from he
hit me uh or like i guess it was like
2013 or yeah like 10 years
he hit me up as the medical scene
started uh coming on was like i'm the
one that gave that to your buddy right
um and he knew all the same people so
it's obviously him and we sat down and
had some beers and uh he said that it
came from a uh electrician plumber dude
that was uh i think it was in the
portland area or like vancouver
washington
and he had moved out from iowa or
something like that
and uh when the old timer up here he uh
got the club he got the clone when he
got his electricity and his plumbing
done for his grow room like you know 15
20 or 20 years ago like mid 90s late 90s
yeah
um
and uh that's where he had got it from
and then i had another guy come up to me
at uh
uh
emerald cup
and
he said that uh he was the one that
popped the seed in iowa
and
he was telling me that he had given it
to like three or four people he only
grew it for like six months or a year or
something like that
and he gave it to a few people and one
of those guys moved to
vancouver washington i think it was
right
so the story's kind of lined up and i i
hadn't given him any information about
what i knew about it um and he said that
he had received the seeds
uh from the base player of culture right
the reggae band
and that he had popped him and that's
that's what it was
well he but he didn't know what the
actual origin of the seeds were like
with the baseline
old
yeah yeah
that's pretty [ __ ] round though that
it came back so like that
yeah well i mean one of the very few
companies that's working with it right
and is known for for that one and i mean
you know we entered it into the
can of bible with jason king
um
so uh
yeah anyways they uh
those guy i mean you know how much of
it's true i don't know exactly i mean
the guy that we got it from i believe
his story because he had nothing to gain
from making anything up and then the guy
that came up that just happened to match
up with the rest of the story so yeah
that's pretty fun bad man
yeah sometimes it works out and you know
our walkers are pretty unique
name so it's uh
it's easy to know if you you are or not
what what you're talking about yeah
absolutely there's a lot of fake albert
walker going around uh
that i remember from san diego
yeah well that was that eight cut from
when uh yeah he got given it and it got
mixed up and then sold it with the wrong
name and you know that's the one that's
that uh
that cuts equally also good i suppose
because it's been winning stuff down
there yeah called albert walker yeah
that's not bad the [ __ ] walker it's not
bad
it's just totally not albert walker
right
let's see what else we've got do you
have any other passion strains beside
the skunk or terps besides the skunk
anything like any any like
terps that you're passionate about like
i have my strawberry and blueberry that
i always seem to [ __ ] navigate to do
you have anything
no no just not real
well no it just has to have a long
lasting after flavor and that typically
tends to be the stuff that's
either really skunky or really
incense-y one or the other
yeah makes sense
what else we got here
i need to put on my [ __ ] old lady
glasses so i can [ __ ] see
the ape cut yeah i think apes doing
stuff again now
he seems to have his farm back up are
you still talking who's that
oh ape yeah what's that you still talk
to him i never talked to him i never
knew him oh really yeah i knew him yeah
i didn't give him the clone it came from
wick oh [ __ ] wick [ __ ] wicked
probably in here [ __ ] wick
yeah i didn't get i didn't give him i
never met him didn't give him anything
someone said bring back the the 32 line
please
yeah that would be pretty cool
yeah i mean
you know
him and three other people
interested in all that kind of stuff
history of skywalker og
i mean million different stories yeah i
think they're confusing the blueberry
mazar skywalker with skywalker og
nope
that was the jedi og was the blueberry
one
the uh skywalker the earliest i ever
heard about it was a buddy of mine in
southern oregon was a
growing ghost og
he used to uh the guy from i i remember
this because i used to i took him
actually my
omega gardens when i was done running
him
because he wanted to run him and uh
he used to take all zerg down to the guy
that owns calm and malibu right yeah
and they already have it like ghost og
on the shelf right so they just called
it skywalker og because the star wars
films were coming out you remember it
was like
2004 2005 when uh
the star wars films like re came out
yeah right yeah and uh
that that was it was like good marketing
you know it was like the same reason
with the blue ivy og when jay-z had his
kid and like you know they always do
that in l.a whenever when when whitney
houston died
there was a whitney houston og you know
i remember yeah
[ __ ] stupid
right
so which cuts which and
you know
and
after that then there actually became
like a differentiated
uh skywalker og club right
that like went around la and whether or
not that's an s1 or some who knows right
now yeah
since when have you been washing your
own genetics
i don't know what now that's not a good
one well do you know much about the a5
and c5
uh the males
the a5 hayes and the c5 haze
kind of i guess but there's there are
females of it yeah
no yeah i don't know anything i'm not
from amsterdam
uh there was a there was a good one just
a few seconds ago see um coma como your
yields will only go up if you wear socks
yeah when you do it yeah socks and [ __ ]
and that's it
archive had them sour grapes right
do you have a sour grapes
no i didn't think so
stony girl how about bull rider what do
you know about bull rider
nothing nothing yeah no
that's a real hard strain to track down
like the original i see afghani bull
rider all the time but not the original
bull rider
yeah the only bull rider ever saw came
from danimal and then it had to be fake
because it sucked and it's the animal
exactly
so [ __ ]
we did the uh the purple indica last
time so you can go watch that lenny john
face off we also did last time i believe
like
the barbecue yeah
yeah face-off uh back seats from casus
yeah
any old long-lost varieties from your
past you wish were still around
yeah there's definitely some good ones
um
i never saw much of it but the freezing
orange that was up here i've seen buds
of it that people say is it since but
my buddies that i trust up here they say
it used to be awesome um
there was this strain uh
called coral reef that was at um that
was in northern california yeah it was
like a skittles type thing just weird a
crazy incredible different smell
um tasted just like it smelled
uh what else was gold humboldt gold was
pretty good that uh
reefer man had or
something gold that they had
uh that that was [ __ ] was pretty good
what was it uh is it the kodiak gold or
is it no it wasn't it wasn't the alaskan
one it was something else it's like
humble or mendocino something gold oh
interesting
um
yeah
if you could change one thing about
docidos what would it be
uh
i mean there's nothing
no there's good there's good uh
phenotypes and all this in all that
but there's definitely some hermes and
dosito i mean it's like if you've ever
grown ogkb
uh it throws balls on the bottoms it
throws bananas out the tops and it'll
throw clusters inside the colas you know
so
um
just trying to reduce that
uh to as little of an occurrence as
possible is like
put some of the hardest work
so i wish it didn't have that trait so i
didn't have to spend so much time trying
to get that yeah for sure
i get plenty of strong flavor in the
dosey though just the norcal cut that
goes around is kind of a in between for
everything i it's not even a cut i keep
personally really
there's one dude a smell book had a
[ __ ] killer cut of your dose it was
beautiful beautiful [ __ ] yeah there's a
lot better stuff in the seeds than the
clones that go around but that's a true
with
anything there's probably better wedding
cake seed phenos that go around probably
better of everything because
most of that [ __ ] is um
[Music]
small uh
small population selection so you just
gotta you know
absolutely especially from that first
release
how many people yeah and you know
there's it's i mean i've grown so many
[ __ ] seeds over the last 15 years and
there's been hermes in almost every pack
of seeds i've ever grown and the ones
that didn't ever have hermes had super
swag [ __ ] weed yeah so
what you know like what are you gonna
deal with
yeah i don't know i think when people
are good growers they don't really focus
so much on that they just deal with it
you know what i mean like when it comes
to [ __ ] herms and [ __ ]
just handle it
yeah well i mean what do you want swag
weed or or no herms you can't breed for
everything all at once right
i mean what you are trying to do is
reduce the occurrences but it doesn't
matter if you're talking about chem 91
chem 4
uh ogkb cookies sherbet
gelatos
skittles there if you
stress the original mother plant it'll
hurt right so
how are you going to uh
are you gonna expect anything else
here's a good one um can you talk about
the amnesia cut you use
it's uh the amnesia haze cut from uh
um
uh from amsterdam or was it that yeah
what is it whatever the core cut yeah
exactly
it's i mean i've seen people call the
same cut it's super lemon haze also yeah
yeah
so what else we got guys
are we ignoring the face-off question or
just not saying no we answered it in the
in the last time me and him did a live
feed that's up on youtube
tyler
how many weeks should sourdy go
10 for sure yeah
as many as you like it where you like it
yeah at least 10. yep ever heard of
ultra i mean that's like the very
earliest you could get it for sure
ever heard of ultraviolet we talked
about that last time
uh yeah that was the purple indigo yeah
face-off cross
any of any collabs with other breeders
not really my thing yeah
they're already collabing with me
anyways half the time yeah using your
stuff yeah
so it's cool
cool works either way yep
see what else we got give me some good
uh strain history questions you guys got
is there any strange that you want to
run the history on that you'd like to
like that has some misinformation out
there
um there's got to be so many
yeah probably pretty much everything
yeah
yeah i don't know
nothing's coming to mind right now
columbian gold crossed with uh
federation seeds romulan
1972 colombian gold
big sur holy weed history i know dude
there's a lot of uh
stories behind that
do you are you familiar with any of them
not i mean i don't have any first-hand
experience you know i really only talk
on the stuff that i was actually there
for you know or have first-hand
experience if it's so and so said so and
so all i can do is tell you what the
story was like the monk from monk named
paul
story like every the same one everybody
else knows yeah exactly
phds did not make strong
oh [ __ ] done made strong uh are you
gonna cross runs is that is that in your
future run stuff
for sure
favorite og cut a favorite og other than
face off
just the original cut if you know
people weren't feminizing [ __ ] back in
the 90s so they
they're not
directly related so if you just take the
oldest cut and feminize it you're going
to get every other clone yep
here's a good one what's the story with
scott's og
uh i gave him a bunch of clones and
that's what he made with it
here you go
are you thinking about collaborating
with ethos anytime soon
i don't even barely know him i met him
like twice
some of these questions kill me um what
is train wreck bread in a cardboard box
to get those cardboard chirps
if you think train wrecks uh it smells
like cardboard then you should just stop
growing all right right now yeah if you
grew trainwreck and it smelled like
cardboard you suck at drawing period
your cure game is [ __ ]
because train wreck reeks train wreck
reaps train wreck's a beautiful [ __ ]
strain man trainer it's a great train
it's one of my favorites and it raped
yeah
uh history of banana og that's easy
enough to look up
uh someone uh rob carney carney for puck
if you want to look it up he's on
facebook hit him up ask him about [ __ ]
he'll talk to you do you like gmo terps
i mean it just reminds me of old hash
plant it's not anything new there you go
do you ever breed some stuff for
yourself that you don't release hey
stuff old lines etc
tons of it
what's up tell us about one of them
just choose one uh like i've been doing
a lot of hawaiian stuff lately
so i have the
my uh
buddy from hana that gave me seeds he
had a lemon strain i grew that out
picked one
that one what he used to call the maui
rain smell it's like a really hazy um
like real tropical
really
cool smell it's just unique right
uh that my buddy's uh hawaii web denica
uh molokai frost cross that i've
selected a pheno of that's in the new
strain that i'm making too
and uh
uh what else did we
pollinate recently
still trying to work the walker into
something better than it but yeah it's
hard that would be i think it's more
than working yeah
um yeah for the old purple indica same
deal you have to hunt through a lot of
them to find improvements really
favorite cut you have right now
i don't know if that'd be easy to answer
i mean that that's why i have so many
cuts is because i don't have a favorite
but i i gotta admit the skittles the way
that thing [ __ ] smells now i mean the
first time i saw that um
you know it uh i thought the smell was
fake you know
i remember i i went to the first time i
smelled it was at uh sebastian's place
in in oregon and he pulled some out of
the freezer some fresh frozen and opened
it up and i was like what the [ __ ] did
you get because it did smell right yeah
it's it's it's special definitely yeah
the only other thing i i've smelled that
was that fake was some uh herb we bought
from my buddy's dad when we're in high
school and it smelled like dryer sheets
but it was like uh it wasn't didn't have
dryer sheets it wasn't actual dryer
sheet weed which was common back then
also
but it was like some locally grown stuff
it was really like
real
um
like a perfumey smelling
let's see here's one um what do you
think uh skittles is just by looking at
it
uh i have no idea i mean it's probably
got some kind of uh
kind of has like a cherry pie-ish look
to it a little bit yep
uh does fletch have any old land race
heirloom beans if so what
did you have a favorite old heirloom
line that you that you have
uh all that hawaiian shit's pretty
um
pretty special
uh
the malawi gold that i don't have
anymore but the malawian haze cross yeah
um
what else do i have the purple indica is
pretty old school i mean a lot of that
stuff is um the milli is either land
race or land race hybrids they're not
very
well developed varieties but that way
um history on irene i know there's been
a few histories going around you what's
your recollection of the actual history
i just know it came from grow hard ruboy
right
that's it i mean that's
i don't really ever have anything of it
beyond that
yeah
i think he's back out too which is cool
come on
get some good questions any highland tie
available
do you work with highland tie
no i had a tie that chris gave me i
think we talked about it yeah
um
that's that was the only real tie i had
i mean i grew a bunch of thai crosses
the derby thai high flyer
um
what other thai stuff did i try
i tried a bunch of cambodian stuff from
canada at one point
uh
i can't remember any other thai stuff
the thai stuff i remember growing it and
it was just so
um
so swag most the time you know it's just
yeah
like it um
just like nose not much smell really
hairy not much resin and herbies so it
was like it's hard to find a good
[ __ ] timeline i've had people send
back bunches and bunches and bunches and
spend a lot of time on a lot of bad time
on shitty thai it's it's yeah it is hard
to come across a good tie
yeah yeah i'm not saying ty's bad it's
just everything that i ran i mean that's
that's what people have to keep in mind
with every variety too is like you tried
one version from one person that who
knows how reputable so it's like
sometimes you got to go through
a bunch of [ __ ] to find what you're
looking for
this should be hey i i still don't think
that's out there i still think it's the
um
uh
the puss kush that's going around and i
even found an old post from you remember
el gato yeah yeah
even made a post where he's like
this uh pure kush that's going around
it's not the la pure which is the og
type right
it's uh
but and he's like it's not the same as
um
uh
suggs cut and he was one of the main
purveyors of passing out that cut
10 years ago you know
and that that post was like from like
2010 or 2012 or something
see um
how did you get the name the doctor who
who chose it
i when i skateboard when i was a kid i i
would get bloody all the time i didn't
ever break bones so i'd bring around
uh
um gauze and and uh
that's pretty rad
pretty rad i didn't know that yeah i've
been stand up i i never broke bones all
my bodies broke break bones we have to
go to the hospital and i just end up you
know
bleeding everywhere so i just got the
got the right [ __ ] for it and clean
yourself up
let's see
ever heard of the pkg cut of og
uh no no
anything i like that i like the i like
the ghost one pure kush recently though
that's a good one
[ __ ] a clone that the guy that it's
named after never had yeah that's
it's gotta be legit dude yeah gotta
gotta it's gotta be legit you know how
many people [ __ ] tell me i'm wrong
about that too it's
mind-blowing
i it's it's it's painful nowadays to
even try to correct people or correct
even just misinformation i'm trying to
correct them yeah you're trying to
correct misinformation from being
being spread it's like you would think
that
the misinformation 20 years ago would
have been um
worse because there was the exchange of
information was really
poor right yeah
now it's people are overflowed with so
much information that
it's too hard it's like finding needle
on the haystack finding the real
information
yeah it's it's it's a pain in the
[ __ ] oh that that's what pkg means
that's sort of pure kush ghost
yeah that's what that's what i thought
that's why i'm together
i thought i thought someone had a
remembered seeing someone trying to call
it that and i was like yeah that's just
that's even dumber than calling it ghost
one kirkush
you're gonna um bring out any more
bazooka joe
um
problem well maybe maybe that was a hit
that was a hit it was good it was good
for out really good for outdoor
our greenhouse are trinity and humbled
snow related you know any
they didn't they don't smell related to
me yeah
the snow is like that
incense-y kind of smell
and trinity was uh
um
that burnt rubber
how about sage have you ever found a
good sage
i've never found a sage that's as good
as the big sir holy weed cut yeah i
would agree with that
i believe adam said he did say that uh
big sur holy weed wasn't sage right
that's what it's supposed to be yeah
yeah it smells like it yeah
i mean whether or not it's the same cut
or whatever who knows but it's it
definitely smells very similar
what are you smoking on right now
uh docido 18 fresh frozen rosin
sounds delicious
yeah
do you ever ban land raisins land races
i have all the time yeah or as close as
we can really get to it nowadays you
know yeah
i mean uh the d the dog [ __ ] is pretty
close to land race it's not pure but
like when i have worked and grown pure
land races like we're talking about with
the uh
like the ties they're so bad it's like
it's
it's too hard to work with and even the
purple indica is the same thing
is the same issue right it's so
unhybridized yeah that anytime you cross
something into it you gotta like
search through
a few hundred of them to find an
improvement
um because it's it likes to those genes
like to dominate the hybrids
yeah yeah people don't understand what
they're getting into when they want like
newer growers want to run land like real
land races legit land races you're going
to get a lot of herms you're going to
get a lot of [ __ ]
resinless [ __ ] you know you've got to
comb through it all you have to
hybridize it you have to work it for the
most part
well everybody expects that like just
because it's a land race it's going to
be more stable or something and i've had
the exact opposite experience growing
yeah especially if you're growing land
races indoor and that's another thing
people have to keep in mind is like when
people make selections outdoor
or in different environments
so if if you make your selections
outdoor in a greenhouse right
if that plant does not hermaphrodite at
all in those conditions right
is that a true female or is that a
hermaphrodite if it hermes when you take
it inside is that a true female or is it
a herme right yeah because once you
change the environment change the
wavelength of the of the
light source and everything else
if you may be inducing the
hermaphroditic tendencies but in its
natural environment which is
outside under the sun
it's a clean female so so what is the
sex of that individual is it is it
actually female or is it a hermaphrodite
because it hermes indoors but not
outdoors
i would think you'd have to apply it to
outdoor status you know what i mean like
because that's its natural environment
everything needs to acclimate to some
degree but yeah that's that's that's a
big difference trying to bring something
indoor to outdoor or outdoor to indoor
well every cannabis plant is outdoor to
indoor right
even if it's been hybridized indoors
still
carries the same genes of every other
plant that grows outside yeah and
i mean
another thing people have to keep in
mind like a thousand watt hps at least
historically i don't i don't know about
the des but i know it's not that uh
it's probably not that considerably
different
uh
the
uh thousand watt hps bulb six inches
from the bulb is one tenth of the
strength of
of the sun
in like the middle of summer right
so when you are selecting for a plant
that performs well indoors
essentially the first criteria that
you're so unknowingly selecting for is
the plant's ability to
uh
turn light into energy right through
photosynthesis
right well there's a if
if a plant does not convert that super
efficiently it won't grow well indoors
period because it needs the intensity of
the sun to process the light right yeah
and
if as soon as you go indoor with it
you're already selecting away 90 of the
plants that don't perform well
um
without a full light source right and
that's why you have lots of varieties
that when you take them outside they
actually perform way better again right
they may be kind of poor growers are
kind of weak stemmed or some
you know mediocre growth pattern indoors
same plant outsides a beast right
and that has nothing to do with like
quality genetics or
anything other than the plant's ability
to process light and how effective how
efficiently it can do that and whether
or not i could even do it with a
fraction of the light available in its
natural and
evolved environment yeah absolutely
acclimation's so [ __ ] important
so important right
uh so it's just it's just about whether
or not it can
and uh it can convert that light energy
yeah i don't i don't do any breeding for
outdoors like i don't i don't take my
plants out acclimate them outdoors see
how they perform outdoors because i just
don't have outdoor space
but i think that's ideal
especially because uh
a lot of people during certain seasons
are only buying for outdoor
right yeah cool
what is the true og kush chirp profile
how would you best describe it
um i always thought it kind of smelled
tasted like chlorine yeah i get i guess
like soapy
cleaner yeah yeah
yeah yeah it almost smells like a pool
and uh
like salt water and real like skunky
type of smell um
mainly that like the whole lemon pine
thing i didn't really ever get that out
of it i don't pick up i mean it's like
kind of like that but only because like
lemon and pine are also cleaner type
smells as well right
so yeah i i tend to think that a lot of
people pick up more lemon from og
because they associate that with cleaner
like lemon pine salt and stuff like that
right yeah yeah exactly
uh can you talk about cleaning clones
with ionized water
i don't know i think i mean ionized
water isn't anything special yeah i
don't know anything about that uh
is there any real milk chocolate tasting
weed
um
[Music]
some old bubba old old bubba
yeah or old purple indica
oxidized weed taste chocolatey in
general
why do you think it was chocolate thai
yeah exactly
it wasn't because it was fresh
uh what else casper og talk
it's just ken's og that came from uh
from josh there you go
i mean that that cross with the face
offline
yeah it won't extract without ionized
water
i know i know blonde had a good question
here somewhere
blonde hit it
any opinions on meduse or wood horse
heroine do you have any interactions
with chris
no yeah i don't i personally i'm all my
interactions with him he's been a dick
but i think he just he openly says he
doesn't really like americans so that
that's my
only interaction i wouldn't be chasing
down marijuana personally
um
biggest i mean i saw the best the best
heroin i ever saw
was um
from uh
uh the heroin og that used to go around
la yeah right and i i don't know if he's
claiming that he bred heroin but heroin
is a steve tuck thing yeah you know
so
yeah which most people forget about that
guy even though he had a big impact on
a lot of people forget where all this
[ __ ] came from there wasn't that many
people
yeah i'm surprised when people when
people talk about heroin you never hear
tough's name brought up but
no even though he's
super [ __ ] known for it and
15 years ago he was like the only source
for it yeah
i think he made it i think they made it
and called it that yeah that's that's
that's the that's what he says yeah
yeah like i don't remember ever hearing
it other than with his name attached to
it
is he still around yeah he does videos
if you go on uh youtube he does strain
history videos that are
probably some of the most grown groan
worthy [ __ ] strain history videos
i've ever seen
he took credit for og kush i did see
that
yeah
him and 14 other people yeah
right
uh best cross with moonbow from the
newest drop in your opinion
what do you like um
i've been liking the moonbow 75 femmes
so
that's
i'm stoked to see you putting out fans
dude that's awesome
well it's a little easier to select your
uh
pollen donor when you can actually smoke
it yeah right
yeah i mean that's the hard part about
picking a male is like
you know if i'm picking one out of
uh 300 females is the one that i want to
keep picking one out of 300 males and
figuring that out with just
reversing it
and picking for structure yeah you know
you still are
your odds are significantly decreased
absolutely
by 99 percent
how many um dosey f1 packs were released
less than 20 less than 20 packs
there you go
frank gee gap story you can find that
elsewhere uh yeah i was the one that
debunked that whole thing being related
to anything yeah because i found i was
the one that found all his [ __ ] old
the
where he got um
they they ended up having him on that
show and they didn't ask him the one
question that was most important of
everything right which was
when they busted
frank right it wasn't frank like his
brother his brother and some other
people yeah and there was three brothers
and if you read the news articles there
was three brothers that were younger
right
between like 24 and 26 and those kids
were supposedly brought in
because they knew
how to grow yeah right
that they had experience growing
no one ever asked anything about those
three kids and they were from
uh lake tahoe or somewhere around there
and this was this was in the news
articles
uh that's what they were describing
so
um
what where are those three dudes
you know if you really wanted to know it
sounded like they were the ones growing
the [ __ ] yeah yeah um i i went to dinner
with christy right before that
and talked to frank on the phone and he
laughed he laughed at the og kush story
he's like dude we were growing like how
it was like big bud nl4 and something
else something stupid he's like yeah
that's not possible but he didn't he
didn't really sound that much into
growing he was more interested in uh
telling his bunker stories but not about
the growing aspect
right totally yeah
yeah they were more interested in
selling the look too
right exactly
all right we did a full [ __ ] hour
dude
i appreciate it
yeah dude [ __ ]
part two
later all right thanks for thanks for
coming on dude always a pleasure
and he's gone just like that just like
that thank you everyone for coming in
sorry if i didn't get your questions in
i was trying trying to keep the
the best questions coming flowing as
best i could stuff i knew that he he
wanted to answer stuff i knew he had
info about you know so i appreciate all
of you thanks for coming on
check you guys later
[Music]
you