we're going to start the day off with
captain martin and kathleen martin as
you all know is uh the niece of people
and
it was many barney kills
uh on top of their abduction that kind
of served the whole thing on that earth
and then of course we've got our roswell
people here too you know of course
roswell started a big thing you know
community
and so anyhow i'm going to be we've got
a lot of great guest speakers coming in
today so
you're going to enjoy yourself and
you're going to learn a lot too
and uh but anyhow i'm not going to take
up your time but um
let me introduce you kathy pardon okay
kevin
i hope everyone had a good night's sleep
after that terrific meal last night
and i just
this is captured preventing barn hill
ufo experience
many people have asked me why i decided
to
research and investigate my aunt and
uncle's ufo sighting and why i decided
to write a book about it
when
other books had been written about it
the interrupted journey primarily but
there had been it had been mentioned in
other books and my reply to that is
in 1988
i watched a television series
called cosmos
carl sagan was on it
and carl presented the story of the
betting barney hill
ufo experience
and
it showed betty and barney
riding down the highway very very dark
night
torrential downpours the windshield
wipers were swishing back and forth the
radio was on
there was a lot of static and betty was
turning the knob as she was nervously
looking up at the sky
and barney was saying don't worry betty
it's only a plane or a satellite or
something
and
all of that
was false
if
i
actually contacted steve markle who is
the chief meteorologist at the mount
washington weather station in new
hampshire
and i asked him to look into his
archival records
i wanted to know exactly what the
weather conditions were that night
so i did all of the research from myself
although other researchers had done and
i didn't want to believe anything anyone
said
well steve markle told me
that it was a light bright night
atop the the rock is what he called
mount washington
and the visibility was 130 miles
there were high
cirrus clouds covering about 60 percent
of the sky but they were the type of
clouds that you can see through
so you could see the stars through
there was a waxing gibbous moon it would
be full in six days
so it was not raining
there was not an inversion a temperature
inversion that night that would make
distant objects appear closer than they
were it was a great night for observing
this
and betty told me that the radio was not
on
so all of that was false
then i believe it was march 4 1993
i had already started investigating this
but carl sagan again
published an article in parade magazine
that was read by thousands and thousands
of people
and in that article he wrote that betty
and barney were driving through the
desolate area in the white mountains at
night
that
benny
cited a star-like object
and that it seemed to be following him
nervous they turned off the main highway
onto narrow winding mountain roads
home later than anticipated
and then two weeks later she had a dream
about
being abducted and convinced barney that
they had both been abducted
that was also a lie
well
stan friedman who went to the university
of chicago he was a classmate of carl
sagan they were adversaries and
about ufos
carl sent a review copy of this article
to stamp
and stan
wrote back single-spaced
a 12-page letter
pointing out all of the mistakes that
carl had made
well
this was two months before the article
was published
and
paul changed only one thing
and that was he said that betty and
barney were a childless couple
and barney had two sons by a previous
marriage and that he had adopted her
first husband's three children
he changed that he didn't change any of
the rest of his misinformation
and even though he was an astronomer he
played amateur psychologist in this and
if you attended my lecture yesterday you
learned about hypnagogic sleep states
hip and sleep states slim paralysis
and that sort of thing
carl was completely wrong when he was
talking about the idea that this
a hallucination that a hallucination
could actually explain ufo abduction
because we know that it's internally
generated if there's absolutely no
physical evidence in a hallucination
and in a hallucination it it is very
short
you don't have a complex narrative in a
hallucination that's a delusion
so
let us begin
like to introduce you to my aunt and
uncle betty and barney hill
betty was born on june 28 1919
she was the oldest child of florence and
raymond barrett
she grew up in south kingston new
hampshire and
there were five children in the family
my mother was betty's younger sister
betty was a very bright child at a time
when very few people went on to college
betty did go to college
she graduated from college with a degree
in social work she worked for the state
of new hampshire as a social worker and
a child welfare worker and eventually
was promoted to the position of
supervisor
she died in october of 2004
from lung cancer it was the third cancer
independent cancer not related that she
had
starting in the 1990s
the last one did metastasize the others
did not
barney was the youngest in his family he
was born on july 20th 1922.
he grew he was born in newport news
virginia and grew up in virginia and on
family farm and also in
philadelphia he
became very discouraged in high school
he had an iq of 140 very bright student
he wanted to become a civil engineer he
was advised that because he was
african-american
there was no work for him in that field
he would never be hired
he became discouraged he dropped out of
high school and went into the army just
before the outbreak of world war ii
he later went back and did earn his high
school diploma
but during world war ii he served
honorably he was a truck driver and a
marksman
he was wounded during the war discharged
in fair condition and his military
records state that he was an excellent
character he worked for the post office
married and had two children
he and his first wife divorced he met
benny they were both
activists in the civil rights movement
although they never intended to
fall in love and get married it was
pretty difficult during that time and
certainly in the state of virginia where
he grew up there were anti-miscegenation
laws so it was against the law for them
to even enter that state as a married
couple
along the 17 other states
but they were married
and they had a very good marriage
this is the dog dalcy who is along on
the trip
delsie also experienced some physical
physiological problems after the
encounter with the ufo she developed a
fungus infection and she had what seemed
to be nightmares and these were new
she would woof
while she was sleeping and her little
legs would run and betty said that this
was not characteristic behavior for dels
well betty and barney left for niagara
falls on september 17 1961
they hadn't had a
great honeymoon they got married in new
jersey and then traveled to betty's home
in portsmouth new hampshire
barney wanted to surprise betty she had
a week's vacation from the welfare
department
and he asked for a few days off from his
job post office
and
surprised her with this trip
i think that they probably went because
uh i had gone to niagara falls about a
month before that and i enjoyed it so
much
i was showing betty and barney my
photographs and talking about it betty
had never been to niagara falls so i
think that's what gave barney the idea
and i also like to show this photograph
of myself because the debunkers all say
that i was only three years old when all
of this happened you couldn't possibly
remember what i'm talking about and you
can obviously see that i was not three i
was thirteen
well this is the route that betty and
barney took on that group they first
went to niagara falls then they drove up
spent the night in the thousand islands
area and went on to montreal the next
day on the 19th they thought they'd
spend the night in montreal but uh the
road signs were in french
everyone was speaking for it when barney
went to ask for directions when he was
lost
they showed him the men's room so he and
he didn't have a good map of the suit
so he decided to just drive to the
outskirts and drive on and if they
retired that they would stop on their
way home somewhere along the line they
did hear that there was a hurricane
coming up the post and thought it would
be a good idea if they did travel to
portsmouth that night
but and barney was accustomed to staying
up all night long he worked graveyard
shift in the post office
this is the road that they took
they took from montreal down from new
hampshire northern new hampshire
they went to montreal to coast
on route 112 and then from poetical they
took 141
down to route 3 to colburn new hampshire
this is co-adco
if you read uh or have heard anything
that the bunkers will tell you they have
said that
barney uh
was
so upset
beep by because he was confronted by
woodlands when he was in canada and that
they harassed him because he was a big
white woman and that this caused him so
much emotional distress that when he was
looking up at that alleged ufo that was
actually a conventional aircraft he
hallucinated hoodlums looking back down
well all of that of course is false as
well
betty and barney did go into a
restaurant in koat cook
he
did see young men in there there were
two young men who had what he called
duck bill haircuts he associated that
with hoodlums
and
uh went on guard momentarily but then he
discovered that there were very nice
young men they were dressed in
conventional clothing they ate they used
the rest of their canadian money and
they moved on and had a very pleasant
time at that restaurant
barney was a little upset with himself
because he realized that he had
stereotyped them and he really
had a problem with people stereotyping
in
well they were driving home along the
way they they traveled over a gravel
road was a very nice gravel road between
coattack and northern new hampshire as
dr simon
uh
asked barney what kind of mood he was in
he was looking for any distress and i
want to play for you now the first
recording of barney's answer to dr simon
[Music]
okay it's not really clear these are the
original hypnosis tapes i did have them
put onto a cd but
they were not clear to begin with but
barney was stating that he was in good
spirits he was in high spirits he had a
delightful dick
and he felt he could drive on down to
new hampshire without a problem
so they passed through us customs
in canaan vermont
and this is the route that they took
through
the northern and central part of new
hampshire here we have colebrook here's
lancaster and his twin mountain
in colebrook they stopped for another
step
this was going to be their last
opportunity to have a cup of coffee
before they traveled on to new hampshire
they were about two to three hours
actually it was about three hours away
from their home in portsmouth i've
driven this route over and over again
measuring distance and time driving at
the rate of speed that barney reported
that he was driving and stopping
at the stops that he reportedly stopped
at in in order to attempt to become lost
or in order to attempt to have missing
time
and i couldn't do
so they stopped at howard's restaurant
had a snack
they left the restaurant at 10 o'clock
they checked their watches
and they went on to lancaster
and they're driving along and just south
of lancaster was about 10 50 when they
arrived there so a little later than
that
uh benny noticed a new light in the sky
a month later she reported this to
walter webb from 9cap and i told you
about walter webb yesterday
about his background he was miss connor
he worked in the hayden planetarium in
boston
and he interviewed betty and barney
separate and together for six hours
and what they told him is that betty's
eyes were drawn to this new light in the
sky
the couple initially thought they were
observing a fallen star only it moved
upward a plane or a satellite
so though that is a quote
of what walter wrote in his original
confidential report
well
they continued to watch this as barney
drove along
watching the road and it was coming
closer and closer and it really spurred
her interest
and she told barney she wanted to stop
so that she could get a better look at
this through binoculars
he really didn't want to he wanted to
drive on he was a confirmed skeptic he
didn't believe that ufos were real but
she told him that delsi was restless and
chelsea needed to go for a walk
so he did stop he found a roadside stop
at the mount cleveland picnic area south
of twin mountain it was about 11 20 when
they arrived there on my calculations
and they got out of the car
and i'm going to play for you
what betty saw
[Music]
i saw
it travel across the whole face
and it was flashing all different
colored lights
robert schaefer will tell you that this
was
the plan of jupiter
that betty saw
and benny wrote to him is that you know
confident planet jupiter
crossed in front of the face of the moon
flashing multi-colored lights
and he
replied in a very very nasty letter he
kind of a nasty guy too bad
and all and continues to tell the same
story
after all of these years
so barney got out of the car he had
walked dowsing he went to the trunk of
the car and removed a pistol the reason
he did that is because they were in a
picnic area there were bears in the area
and he was afraid that the bears would
come out of the woods and
he was a city person and he was afraid
of bears so he he took the gun out for
protection against the bears initially
um
what he did is he took the binoculars
from betty and watched this craft as it
traveled toward vermont
in a northwest direction and then
without turning
it suddenly shot back at him so rapidly
that he could see the windows in it at
that point
it was unconventional it was silent and
it did not have conventional lighting
next they entered franconia this was
four miles south of the mountain
cleveland picnic area
this is franconia notch in the fall it's
a beautiful tourist area
as they passed by cannon mountain
betty noticed the tower on top of cannon
mountain the craft passed over the top
of the tower and the steady light on the
tower blinked out as the craft passed
over
they decided to stop again
they stopped by the old man of the
mountain which is on the backside of
cannon mountain and that this base fell
as a stone granite profile it fell in
may of 2003 it was our state symbol
unfortunately and we no longer have it
but uh if the important part here
is that between
the old man's forehead
and chin was 48 feet
and that is important because they said
that the crap came around and stopped by
the old man's profile and it was at
least one and a half times the length of
the old man's profile
they have stopped they've gotten out of
the vehicle what you're seeing here is
profile lake it's just underneath the
old man's profile and actually he fell
into part of him fell into the lake in
2003 and i'm going to play for you now
barney's description of what he saw when
he got out of the car on the second stop
it was about
a thousand feet i guess
all right
i
know this is not a peppercorn
it was too fast
it moved
before the west
and without
looking as if it turned it would come
straight back
it would go back up
straight up and come straight back
without a circle
and i think only a jet could fly that
fast
so we returned to the car barney was
driving very slowly at this point to
prank honey a notch while betty was
watching the craft as it traveled along
the top of the mountains sometimes
coming down in front of the mountain
sometimes behind the mountain
it
was traveling sometimes in a sphere step
pattern and she was very intrigued by
what she was seeing
they came out of frank honey a notch at
indian head this is indian head and
right across the street from indian head
are some cabins the indian county resort
is there now it's a beautiful resort i
highly recommend that you go there and
stay there if you go to new hampshire
they are currently
uh erecting a monument to betty and
barney hill and they will have a travel
guide
so that you can actually
if you stay there get their travel guide
and follow this route yourself
so i'm pretty excited about the fact
that there will be a monument for betty
and barney there
but getting back to what happened next
barney stated to dr simon when he saw
these cabins that he
felt
safe and less of the barren hostility of
the wooded area he said i've been there
before and i feel comforted that i see a
familiar place
betty was becoming excited and barney
said benny rarely became excited over
anything
so he thought maybe he'd find a place
where he could pull over again and he's
driving around and looking then he saw
nature land which was a little tourist
area
and
couldn't pull over there but as he was
driving along he was forced to stop
the craft had shifted ahead and stopped
just to the right of u.s highway route
3. and this is the off-season there were
not other vehicles
on the road then if you go there now
it's pretty heavily populated it's very
different you'll see cars
but at that time of night
on that night
betty and barney did not see another
vehicle and it's a good thing because
barney stopped that car right in the
middle of the highway straddling the
center strip center line and got out to
look at this craft and while betty sat
in the car watching it
and
he said it continued to have a forward
look facing me as if it swung and did
not move from its position but just
swung from position with the front still
facing me and it moved to my left and i
continued to look and
walking across the highway that's why he
told walter webb in the confidential
report in october 1961
he also told walter the figures were
dressed in shiny black uniforms and
black cats with bills they reminded
barney the cold precision of german
officers the leader of the window held a
special attraction for
he could almost feel the leader's
intense concentration to carry out a
plane
was questioned about this event several
times by dr simon and what i'm going to
play for you now
is the tape of bonnie's first hypnotic
regression
uh with dr simon so that you can
actually hear the intensity of emotion
in his voice as he relived this
experience this is the point where he
experienced just after this a mental
block
[Music]
i know
all right
oh
this
before
[Music]
because
everybody who
everyone was standing there looking at
me
but everybody moved
to these zebras or in the back or they
[Music]
shiny jacket
in the sky
you can see you can hear the intensity
of emotion
uh in barney's response to what he saw
on board that crap he had a conscious
recollection
of encountering a non-human being
and he in his original report on in
october of 1961
described what he saw to walter west
he simply could not remember their
facial features at that point there was
something about them that terrified him
and caused him to have a mental block
now i'm going to play
the same kind of rendition
but this is
a later hypnotic regression and barney
has uh calmed down he's undergone his
reaction and catharsis and now he is
more rational about his experience
i
noticed with my monaco's that there were
about 11 minutes
now
i thought
looking down at me
and they suddenly made a
turn
to what i thought was a panel
and i could see their arms going up
and there was one that kept looking down
and i kept going closer
and
i could see two red lights coming out
from the tip
of this thing that did not look like a
plane at all or a helicopter
and
i could see
a long something coming down from the
center
and
i kept going closer and closer
and i thought oh my god
what is this thing
and
i
felt myself being told to come closer
and i was greatly confused and i built
my eyes and i thought this can't be real
and i shook my head and turned it away
and looked back and i thought oh god
it's there what is this thing and i put
my hand towards my gun and i could not
put my hand there and i could not
understand why my hands kept going up
with the binoculars and i was told to
keep the binoculars up and keep looking
up and keep coming closer no problem
will come to me and that's when i opened
my hands and the binoculars fell around
my neck and i ran
screaming back to the car
that they were going to capture us and
yet i could not understand what they
wanted to capture us for and i thought i
should report this to the police if ever
i could find a car box or anything or a
restaurant open because this was very
unusual for something to do that and i
thought of the military and i thought
since they had on black jack the one
looking at me having a black jacket he
must have been
a military officer and yet i could not
quite understand why they were doing
what they were doing and there was no
sound coming from this thing
okay
barney did run back to the vehicle
thinking that he was
in danger of being captured and he
stated that as he entered his car
the craft moved overhead
and
when it did he started speeding down the
highway
and i'm going to play for you now what
betty described because as that craft
hovered over their vehicle
they've heard a series of beeping what
they call beeping sounds code like
mechanical beeping sounds what barney
called buzzing sounds in
different words to describe the same
thing
[Music]
i don't know
it is that's all i can think of is some
sort of electrical signal
somebody's just just you know with busy
business and i thought well i want to oh
god why didn't i go to the lobster
because maybe this is the most problem i
don't know
and i thought
a winter coat
this is the shot you get if you don't
like it so i put my hair up in the
middle of the track
and i kept feeling this feeling and i
didn't feel any uh shock electric shock
but the hotel was vibrating
the whole car was vibrating and that
vibration
caused a tingling sensation to pass
through betty's and barney's bodies
when that happened they stopped speaking
to each other and they didn't speak
again
until they were 35 miles down the
highway and it seemed that only an
instant had passed
as i listen to their separate hypnosis
tapes
they suddenly find themselves on a new
robe that they haven't been on before
and there are tall trees all around
betty attempted to find a rational
explanation and just thought they must
have been continuing to drive down u.s
highway route 3 and then made a
left-hand turn onto route 175
which runs parallel to root three but
there's no evidence of that on the
hypnosis tapes
so somehow
they got from group three over to route
175 to a new area
it was a long pause after these
beeping and buzzing sounds and suddenly
they're in a new location perhaps that
craft picked their car up
it's been note they have been known to
pick up other cars
so let's take a look
at their
timeline is the first stop at 10 50
south of twin mountain here's the old
man of the mountain the second stop at
about 11 50. actually betty said that
as they passed cannon mountain she
glanced at her watch and it was 11 20.
so i'm going to have been a little too
liberal but i wanted to make sure that i
added time
uh to this
to
try to
find a rational or mundane explanation
for what happened to them so
i may be off there
here's the encounter field the third
stop that was about 12 15 by my
calculation and down here
is the capture site
the hills remember to roadblock and they
remembered men in the road they didn't
know when or where it occurred this is
part of their conscious recollection
they remembered a fiery oar
and i'm going to play for you now
what barney
told dr simon about that fiery lord
how can
the moon be on the highway
in that kind of position
and i can never seem to find any
uh terrain up there that would fit what
i sort of definitely remember that they
were sitting there like and i kept
remembering you just writing it down
and then i
don't remember
and now i
remember
see this was after the hypnosis
he always had these shadowy memories of
a roadblock
he and betty consciously recalled his
fiery orb
they attempted to rationalize that
perhaps it was the moon setting
but it didn't fit the characteristics
of a setting moon
and
barney realized that
this object was moving but he was not
moving
well then they drove on they passed
through plymouth new hampshire
and they heard their second series of
code line beeping or buzzing sounds this
brought them back to full consciousness
this is when
barney stopped the car he shifted from
side to side on the road he attempted to
create this type of sound and wasn't
able to do that betty said to him well
now you believe in flying saucers and he
said don't be ridiculous there's no such
thing
and
then they
drove down here's plymouth ashland
this is actually a 1960 road map of new
hampshire in north field they recalled
seeing a sign that said 17 miles to
concord here's concord the state capitol
and then they
made a beeline over here to portsmouth
new hampshire thinking that they would
arrive at 3 00 a.m at the latest
but
it was 5 15.
they checked their watches and their
watches had both stopped but finding way
into the kitchen and check the clock
well betty walked delsie the dog
barney felt a strange sensation in his
groin he checked his groin went into the
bathroom didn't see anything then but a
couple of months later 21 three-quarter
inch groves had grown in a concentric
circle on his groin they were later
removed they became inflamed while he
was undergoing hypnosis with dr sun
the lab report confirmed that they were
not venereal warts
and betty felt planted as if they'd been
contaminated and they really did worry
about contamination
and there the watches that had stopped
never worked again
and his binocular strap was broken the
tops of his shoes were scraped not just
scuffed
but scraped and he was a meticulous
dress after that he had to wear these
shoes for yard work
they sat down in separate rooms and
betty sketched the
practice she recalled seeing it see it
from her position in the car
and this is barney's sketch he had uh
he had seen it from next to the car and
also from the field
and so he said this is how it looked
when it was about 200 feet high that was
when it was beside the highway on the
right side of the west side of their
vehicle
and then it descended to within about
100 feet of their vehicle and there was
a little red light on each side there
and this is how it uh looked when it
shifted over the highway descending to
about 100 feet over the field
and these little thin like structures
appear to come out with a red light on
each end and you can see the little
figures that he drew
the day he arrived home so if anyone
tells you that all of this was recovered
under hypnosis you have proof now that
they had full conscious recollection of
everything except for the abduction
itself
well faith took off her dress and when
she did she noticed that the zipper was
torn at the top
there was an inch
one and a half inch tier on one side
uh an inch tear on the other side there
was a tear in the zipper fabric and in
the stitching this was a new dress how
did this happen to a woman
riding as a passenger in a vehicle down
the highway
uh the lining was torn from waist to
hemlock
the ham was torn down on one side of her
dress
she folded him and placed it in her
closet knowing that she'd have to repair
it but the next time she took it out
there was a pink powdery substance on
that dress
she hung it out on the clothesline the
pink powder blew away but she noticed
that the dress was permanently stained
she decided to throw it away but that
unsecond thought
she thought that it might hold a clue to
what happened to her on that night so
she saved that dress and it has
undergone laboratory analysis five
separate times
no one has ever been able to identify
what that pink powdery substance is
i'm looking for a phd botanist who might
be able to look at it to see if it's
some kind of fungus or mold
um but if you go online to the black
vault encyclopedia
phyllis buzzinger his report is on there
it's at youtube uto
and i just want to point out
you can see here the blue
this is the blue color of the dress you
can see the discoloration
and something that betty told phyllis
had told me as well
is that the areas where they actually
touched her are the areas that were most
saturated by that pink powdery substance
they grabbed her with their very long
narrow hands
around her armpits
you can see on the hem where it dropped
onto the floor and also this
discoloration up in that zipper area
this is phyllis bunninger
uh she has a master's degree in
chemistry she's a research scientist
she's retired now she works as a
consultant sometimes and she has her own
laboratory
she worked for pe amaco
which was formerly standard oil for 35
years so specialized
in petroleum chemical and polymer
analysis using spectroscopic techniques
and
i have such a high degree of respect for
her
she did the most thorough chemical
analysis of anybody
i write about it in the book or you can
go online for the full 47-page
report that she wrote
there was
an oil-type substance on the exterior of
that dress that did not belong to them
this was externally deposited there by
something else
uh so quite interesting
phyllis
ended up
this is an i'm going to phone her she
wrote this to me
her conclusion was i am convinced that
the event did happen as determined by
the chemical analysis i did on betty
hill's dress
well
betty then phoned my mother
bonnie said that uh they should never
tell anybody about this no good could
possibly come out telling anyone about
this event so many then went to the
telephone and immediately called my
mother
her sister
and uh and had to talk to her
it uh
because betty was so concerned
that they might be contaminated and we
had a neighbor who was a physicist
my mother called the neighbor and he
suggested for some reason and i'll never
understand this but he suggested that
betty take a compass if she had one and
go out to the car and
to see how the needle on the compass
would react now we know it's going to
fluctuate when you put it over the
engine and put it over the battery but
she's sorry i'm going to let her tell
you
postmortem
shiny
and
it had been raining
that day
and uh the cow was all wet stole that
and
i thought well
i started
on the side of the calf
to see what would happen and i kept
going
closer and closer to the trunk
and then it was when i started to go to
the trunk of the compass but i noticed
the
shiny spots on the trunk
that they were
the very very shiny spots
about the
the hulk cluster album
about the size of
you know half dollars or
salvador something like that
and most of them
twelve or eight noodles several for
overdosing i would say
all around this spot and very shiny
and
when i just kept a couple of anywhere
near
the league temple kepler spinning around
and around and around
and
i at this like
i got more
well the debunkers will tell you that
barney went out and experimented with
the compass and the compass behaved
normally it didn't spin and betty was
making all of this up
but let's hear from barney
what happened
i said how can you not know if it isn't
anything and then i put the compass
close to it
and the compass
was bent
and spin
and i could move the compass a few
inches to a spot
that did not connect to a
carbon
on the trunk that did not have a spot
and the compass
would drop down
and so you can see again that the
debunkers are lying
while those bombs were in the exact
location where the hills said they heard
the beeping or buzzing sound that caused
their vehicle to vibrate and their
bodies to tinkle
i actually saw these spots as did the
other members of my family we were at
betty's house within a day or two of the
time was occurred
eddie washed and waxed her vehicle
uh that fall but the spots would not rub
out
but they faded away over the winter of
1961 and 1962
and in my book captured
i do have
included a letter that betty
wrote to walter webb
about a meeting that she had with
several air force officers about those
spots and their opinions on what they
might be
uh
a number of people have speculated that
they might be just weather spots weather
spots are caused when it rains and
pollutants drop down from environmental
pollutants drop down and deposit on the
trunk of the car and then the sun comes
out and bakes those environmental
pollutants off
you have to actually buy a chemical
compound and rub those out you can't get
them out
but that is not what was on betty and
barney's car
that's not what they looked like
it had been raining but the sun didn't
come out
it was continuing to rain that afternoon
that evening
and they had not been there the day
before
this is what they looked like
not this
well
betty was excited she called my mother
back
and the chief of police of newton who
was actually the former chief of police
at that point he had
shortly before that but he was my
father's best friend and he came to the
house every night and had a cup of
coffee on his way home from work
and
he told betty that she should report
this to the air force that the police
departments and all received
instructions from pease air force base
to for people to call them to report
their ufo science so that's what she and
barney did
and you can see the original report it's
in the appendix of my book this is the
original hand written report right here
and
already there's a cover-up going on it
says there was a strong inversion in the
lincoln-new hampshire area now we
already know from what i've told you
from
the
chief meteorologist from mount
washington weather station that there
was not a strong inversion that night
when they passed through the inversions
set up in some of the lower valleys the
following morning after they had already
arrived home
and the original report up here you'll
see that it's hand checked that
it was picked up on air intercept radar
and ground visual radar
uh and this is the radar report
every other report after this does not
have
air intercept radar checked off
dr james mcdonald said that he had
actually seen the pilot's report that's
what he told that
[Music]
that disappeared from the files it has
never been seen again
this is just the second page and there
are several pages of the air
intelligence report
uh it's only a description of what you
have already seen on my slides
approximately 10 days after this
experience betty had five disturbing
nightmares or dreams they occurred early
in the morning as
just before she woke up barney was not
sleeping with her because he was working
nights at the post office
they included her conscious memories of
ufo sighting
but sandwiched in between these events
was a ufo abduction in these streams she
rearranged she wrote them down she
rearranged them and in november of
1961 she wrote a five-page paper
about what she had dreamed this has
always created a lot of controversy
because
dr simon for one and this is dr simon
hypothesized that perhaps
betty had only repeated her dreams under
hypnosis and that barney had created a
fantasy and confabulated the information
under hypnosis about an abduction he was
really startled at how similar betty's
and barney's stories were
just couldn't believe that they were so
similar and that had to come from
someplace because of course ufos were
not real and no one had ever been
abducted so he was looking for another
explanation
but i told you yesterday about dr
simon's credentials he was very
outstanding a psychiatrist neurologist
he had set up the psychiatric unit at
the mason general hospital on long
island in new york it's a 3 000 bed unit
he was the the chief of psychiatry there
uh
had a tremendous amount of success in
treating post-traumatic stress disorder
he was a lieutenant colonel in the army
he was awarded the army commendation
medal the american campaign medal the
victory medal he taught at yale and he
lectured at harvard and he was skilled
in deep trans hypnosis to resolve trump
amnesia
barney was referring to him because
he was not able to resolve some
physiological problems he was
experiencing he was hospitalized with
bleeding ulcers
he was experiencing stress
and
he was not responding to traditional
medical treatment so he was referred to
another psychiatrist dr duncan stevens
and one day when he was in dr steven's
office he mentioned that he and betty
had traveled to the white mountains the
previous weekend to try to job their
memories about this ufo experience that
they had and the missing time and dr
stevens thought that barney was very
well adjusted he couldn't understand why
he was experiencing these problems
because there was nothing else in his
life that should have caused that he did
miss his sons who were in philadelphia
but he saw them during vacations
uh he thought there was something more
bothering barney so he made the referral
to dr simon
and betty went with him
they met with dr simon for the first
time on
december it was december 14th i believe
they started hypnosis in january they
underwent a period of conditioning and
then on february 22nd
barney underwent his first hypnotic
regression session
and uh what he said and what betty said
as well
and i did a comparative analysis in 1996
betty turned all of the hypnosis tapes
over to me i transcribed all of them for
comparative analysis
my background is in social science uh
and i am now a hypnotherapist i was not
them
um i was a social worker i majored in
psychiatric social work is what they
called it back then in college and
so i did this comparative analysis and i
told you betty and barney suddenly found
themselves on a new road and there were
tall trees all around
and barney said i kept driving and
driving and i made a turn and i never
knew this i don't know why i had to make
that turn and that's when he saw that
fiery orb in the road
they then saw figures in the road and
i'm going to play for you
betty's description of what she saw
that day
then i thought well you know are they in
the car and the car broke again or
what are we doing there
and
i'm going to stop
and then
they
they separated
they came up with two groups
and when they started to do that
i was real scared
open
i
thought i saw a cluster
of
six men
because
they came to me
and three
midnight
i
didn't think of the man
in the
he said he did not think of the man in
the sky at that time he did think about
going for his gun
but you can see
bobby said the three men went to his
door he saw a cluster of six men
three went to betty's door that's not in
their dream material where did that come
from
unless it happened
then um
they were taken out of the car arnie
stated under hypnosis that he could feel
the tops of his feet bumping against the
stones then he stated not under hypnosis
but you don't
report everything that happens when
you're hypnotized you remember
your experiences but you don't report
every single little detail
betty remembered struggling with her
captors as they attempted to take her
onto the craft and she said that this is
the point where she tore
the hem on her dress and the lining
because she was fighting for her life
and she kicked one of these guys as hard
as she could
but at that point they took control of
her again and she lost consciousness
they took her into the craft and this is
barney's uh diagram of the interior of
the craft
here's the ramp
this is the side with the windows this
was a darkened hallway
barney was taken into this room there
was a table and there was a cabinet here
betty was taken into this room there was
a table chair and cabinet here
so this is
barney's diagram
now
this
is
my composite of the aliens that betty
described in her dreams i want to make
that clear
this is her dream alien
they looked pretty human maybe southern
european
dark hair big hair dark eyebrows
blue lips but they had lips they looked
a lot like jimmy durante they had large
long noses they would rest in
uh cadet type uniforms
and they were about five feet to five to
four inches tall they were very human in
appearance
let's compare that to what betty and
barney described after hypnosis
very different
scary
this is the leader
he had large chest cavity and spindly
legs
before they ever underwent hypnosis
barney recalled the roadblock and he
mentioned their spindly legs and how
they were oddly jointed and how as they
approached the car they were sort of
shifting side to side
very different from a human gate
they described a membrane inside the
mouth that flooded when they spoke to
each other in their own kind of sort of
mumbling or a humming type of language
betty told me once that it reminded her
of the low drone of a beehive
or a hornet's nest
they had large slanted eyes that they
said were square had square corners
they had a vertical cat-like pupil and
the artist who actually drew this
drew it more human-looking than benny
said they actually were now betty and
barney described uh
an iris that filled up most of the white
area of the eye only a very tiny bit of
white was showing and that was yellowish
in color so this uh this painting is not
completely accurate
this one was the leader was about five
feet tall
they understood him in english
although she did not see his mouth move
barney also understood him in english
although he did not see is not moved
that is not in
betty's dreams or recall
this is the examiner the original
examiner painting was stolen from
betty's house i commissioned patrick
richard from new mexico to
do this painting of the examiner
and the examiner held a weaker chin
betty thought perhaps this was female
but didn't know for sure
he was about four and a half feet tall
very much like the the leader they had
these long narrow
palms of their hands and they had
probably three long fingers and one that
was shorter from what betty could recall
this is a side view
drawn by the original artist david baker
from new hampshire and there was one
that they didn't talk about
the scientists working with them asked
not to disclose this information because
they wanted to know if other people had
had this experience as well and if they
had they might mention another group on
board this craft this one was only about
three and a half feet tall i call him
the supervisor because he stood in the
darkened hallway and he was incredibly
frightening to betty she kept her eyes
closed a lot because she couldn't stand
to look at him he had larger eyes and a
larger head in proportion to his body
than the leader and the examiner
well
from
what i could
discover by listening to and
transcribing the hypnosis tapes it
appears
that these alien beings were interested
in the human skeletal structure they
examined base and barney's hands and
feet and joints their eyes their skin
their mouth their reproductive systems
and many specimens were taken from their
bodies skin scrapings
um perhaps ova from betty
there was a sperm test sample taken from
barney
uh just about every order was open in
their body
bodies were entered
as separate betty's underwear did remain
on
uh here's betty
she underwent
a needle in the navel test this is
before we had amniosa
and i'm going to play for you now
betty's description of what she
experienced
on my back
and the excitement
has a long needle
in his hand
i could kill him
every day
reader
he does overstay
put his son
around this time
from your eyes
and he says i'll be all right
i won't feel it
come on
get all the page all the way
[Music]
this was all seven betty's dream
material the difference between this and
betty's dreams is that
she experienced so much trauma as she
was going through reliving this
experience that dr simon actually had to
end the session early
we don't know for sure if this actually
happened because we can't i was not able
to verify beyond a reasonable doubt
anything that happened individually to
betty and barney on board the craft only
there's their statements of what
happened when they were together
so there's a good chance it did but i
don't have what i would call scientific
evidence that it did
well stan friedman may have talked about
the star map to you uh if he hasn't yet
i'm sure he will so i'm going to
go over this rather quickly this is his
area of expertise he was the first one
to publish on the star map and he wrote
the chapter on the start out in captured
by betty said to the leader
after the examiner had left to work on
barney i know you're not from around
here where are you from
and so he produced a star map that was
three-dimensional it was like a
holographic image
from the wall
and
dr simon gave betty the post-hypnotic
suggestion
that she would be able to draw this when
she went home if and only if she could
remember it accurately and it didn't
cause her too much distress
some of the stars she did go home and do
this and some of the stars were
pinpoints and others were as big as a
nickel these solid lines represented
trade routes so you can see trade routes
here here's the sun up here
um so you can see solid lines and then
the dotted lines represented expeditions
his margarine fish was stan friedman
this is back in the 70s i believe
marjorie was the school teacher from
ohio she was also a member of mensah
she was unmarried and
had plenty of time on her hands to
express her interest and to research the
start out she reasoned that if it really
existed she would be able to find this
place in our galaxy perhaps so she
started building three-dimensional
models using
silk
string and
beads
in all she built 26 models before she
was able to find a match
it took her four years to find the match
the hard part wasn't getting the
accurate distance data because you can't
just
order these catalogs she had to go to
the university to the astronomy
department ohio state university and
copy and copy the information
from those catalogs
and uh
a lot of the astronomy departments that
she attempted didn't even have this
information libraries didn't have so she
had a difficult time getting it but
finally a new catalog was released and
she found a match in 1972 she completed
her work when the last three stars were
found
and this is a photograph of one of her
models
and this is her identification
now she was having difficulty finding
scientists to
better work
for accuracy
stan friedman was called in by coral
lorenzen from afro and asked if he would
assist marjorie in this he went to
marjorie's house he was impressed by her
work and by her intelligence and he
actually did find a number of scientists
who were willing to back her work and it
was accurate
so
what she found is here's zeta
reticuli zeta 1 zeta 2. now you can see
that these lines are shorter they're
closer together
than what betty actually drew the
difference for this
and and marjorie reasoned this out with
the astronomers and they did accept her
explanation as being reasonable is
because betty
observed this as a three-dimensional map
yet she put it on paper as a
two-dimensional map and she was looking
at it from a certain angle and from a
certain uh distance so when they did the
math they found out that
what
library has here
represented what betty described see and
then through
so if you're a sun
it is now 39.
well 39.2 it says here but i think the
updated one is 39.3
light years away from the sun
uh zeta 1 and zeta 2 are 1 8 of a light
year apart
but
they
are
able to support planets
if they have plans in a stable orbit
they're not so close that they wouldn't
have stable orbs
some
all interesting facts
pattern stars are sunlight stars the
only five percent of the thousand stars
in our local galactic neighborhood out
54 light years are sunlight and all the
sunlight stars in the volume of space on
the mouth are in the pattern
the bay stars are at least a billion
years older than the sun and can support
planets in stable orbit
they are all on a plane like pepperoni
on a pizza rather than like raisins in a
loaf of raisin bread so it would be
easier to travel from one to the other
instead of jumping all over the gallons
well betty reported also that she saw a
book on board this craft
and in
2000 the year 2000 august of 2000 i
asked her if she could reproduce for me
on paper the symbols in that book some
of them she her memory had faded at that
point she had difficulty with this this
may not be an accurate representation of
what she saw but she did this for me
they were arranged uh in six columns
she said the book seemed to be
constructed of thin shiny plastic it was
approximately an inch thick and the text
was embedded in the plastic
she asked the leader she could take this
as her hope that she this experience
actually occurred he initially said yes
then that nasty little supervisor saw
that she had it and took it away from
her she
remained behind
on the crap arguing for this book
now if you heard my lecture yesterday
uh i told you in my comparative analysis
i discovered that under in betty's dream
account of what happened she said that
the hills that she and barney were
returned at the same time and that they
stood outside the car and watched the
vehicle the spacecraft leave
that's not what they stated
independently under hypnosis
what they stated under hypnosis was that
barney was returned to the car first
barney stated he sat on his gun
when he was put back into the car he
then saw betty coming down the path his
bedding
he didn't report seeing the leader but
then he said the leader was with her and
then dropped her off at a certain point
and she walked toward the car she opened
the door
she picked up the dog delcy and said
barney let's get out and look at uh this
thing leave
this is even so different from betty's
dreams that they were standing in a
different location under hypnosis than
they were in benny's dreams this leads
me to believe that this was a real
experience that both of them told dr
simon about as they relived it under
regression from a hypnotic regression
well on dr simon said if this really had
occurred they'd be able to find the
location and they did on labor day 1965
uh
they did find
the induction spot you can see here's
route 175
is melbourne road this is where the men
were in the road there's a path through
the woods the craft landed right here in
this sandy soil area they remember the
sandy soil and it is the only area in
that air part of new hampshire that has
these physical characteristics and they
looked and looked they could never find
a place until they were driving along
we'd go up there
and spend weekends different members of
the family would go
uh and camp out and then go look for
this
on this particular day
arnie just seemed to remember he was
driving along he made the right turns he
stopped the car they got out they walked
in the woods
and found this area i was asleep in the
back seat of the car
they said oh kathy you have to see this
i was too tired i didn't get up i said
i'll see it the next time
but as years went on i saw it dozens and
dozens of times
if you go there today it's impossible
there is a housing development there the
road has been paved
and
there are side roads there are houses
everywhere it looks nothing like this
but this is betty standing on the
capture site
so this is the another map of their trip
home
they heard the second series of beeps
right here around the ashland area it
was 37 miles to concord 17 miles from
from northfield to concord and then 47
miles back to portsmouth
if they they were in thornton at 12 45
a.m
they would have arrived in ashland at
about 3 30.
well
if they stayed on route 3 it was only 16
miles
if they turned off under 175
it was only 21 miles
my husband and i drove this group over
and over again and tried to get lost we
took every side road we could
we could never get lost for more than 45
minutes
nope after the hypnosis sessions were
over barney was feeling better
um he
and betty once again turned to this
political activities this civil rights
activities full force all of this was to
remain confidential information never to
be released
we the three of us were invited to
lyndon johnson's inauguration and
attended that here's barney with u.s
senator tom mcintyre from the state of
new hampshire
on
january 19 1965
and they were active in the civil rights
movement
barney was appointed to the new
hampshire state advisory committee for
the u.s civil rights commission on may
4th
1965 he was also appointed to the office
of economic opportunity he was the
executive director
of the
chairman of the executive committee for
the rockingham county community action
program that he and betty have found in
the state of uh in portsmouth new
hampshire for rockingham county so they
were very well known around the state of
new hampshire very politically involved
and the worst thing that could ever
happen to them would take
for this information to be made public
they'd lose their credibility
they feared that they would probably
lose their jobs as a result right
they were contacted by a newspaper
reporter from boston in august of 1965.
john littrell
he had heard through gossip
[Music]
from a person who was supposed to
maintain confidentiality who had
listened to
some of the hypnosis tapes and had
information that she repeated to this
newspaper report as a violation of
confidentiality barney said he asked to
meet with betty and barney because he
wanted to publish this story they said
absolutely not
this has to remain confidential
so what happened
by october 25th
1965 it was a regular day they got up
and they went to work and all of a
sudden
the media was all over them
outside their offices wanting to come
into their offices
john letrell had published this on the
front page of the boston traveler it ran
for five days
it was a horrible experience for my
family
betty and barney were panicking
they came to my grandparents house i
looked across the street from my
grandparents
we met as a family to
attempt to
determine what we were going to do about
this
and
betty and barney at that point
decided that
maybe they would tell the real story
about what happened to them uh they also
spent one night with uh
an officer on pease air force base ben
swett
and you'll read about him in my book he
retired as a full colonel from the
pentagon
they decided after this in early
november november 3rd i believe it was
1965 to speak publicly for the first
time
they had spoken about their experience
to their church members at one time and
they can't
without being on the agenda stood up
briefly at the two-state study group in
quincy massachusetts
in early november of 1963
and talked about their signing
but that was it
it was done confidentially
they thought
well they did uh john 4 was at that
first time that they spoke they were the
universe the unitarian church in dover
new hampshire spoke to a packed crowd
the the church was filled the basement
of the church was filled with people
it was cold and rainy and there were
people standing outside the church they
had to set up speakers everywhere
and
john fuller was in the audience
they were introduced by the public
information officer from pease air force
base
and they did not talk about their
abduction they only talked about their
sighting
ben swept introduced john fuller to
betty and barney
john 4
talked to them about the possibility of
writing their story in a book and
eventually they did agree
and dr simon agreed to join them
and
the interrupted journey was published in
the fall of 1966
well
two of the original investigators that i
haven't mentioned if you know the story
at all were robert homan and c.d jackson
they worked for ibm wrote with robert
holman was a writer
c.d jackson was a senior engineer
they
were in contact with betty and barney
again and convinced betty to participate
in psychophysics experiments with them
in order to vector in the craft i have
all of the letters that robert holman
wrote to betty about this they went up
they visited betting barney they went
back to the site they actually scripted
betty and some of this script is in the
appendix of this book i've devoted two
chapters to the experiments that they
did
they um
were attempting to obtain hardware for
ibm
according to what i can gather from the
letters that robert coleman wrote
they were not able to do that but the
strange thing is this experiment was
confidential
so when i was a teenager i wasn't aware
of why these ufos were landing on my
grandparents farm
but i think it might have had something
to do
with this experiment and in fact i know
that it had
i
i can't prove scientifically they landed
there because of the experiment but
there was physical trace evidence they
were observed there was one i write
about it in the book observed by a
commercial pilot who was a neighbor of
ours who saw it come in at night it woke
up my grandparents as it shared up the
tops of some trees it woke up my brother
who was sleeping
and the physical trace evidence was on
the ground
the trees
were burned
it was investigated
one
afternoon i was an amateur astronomer i
was standing outside setting up my
telescope i looked across the street
over my grandparents barn and there's a
ufo
it was close enough that i could see the
windows in it i was excited i'm jumping
up and down
ufo ufo i'm yelling my mother comes
running out she takes one look she grabs
me by the arm she takes me back into the
house and says stay away from the
windows
well after barney died
the experiments with homan and jackson
ended
but betty continued to look for ufos in
fact
she was a little credulous in
some of this she
got to the point where sometimes she
wasn't able to differentiate between
conventional aircraft the ufos
but between
80 and
95 depending upon what report you're
reading the statistical analysis you're
reading
of ufo sightings are conventional
aircraft anyway and when betty
saw finally that they were conventional
she identified them as conventional but
what you see here is one of her better
photographs of something i can't say
that this is a flying saucer you can't
say it's an extra terrestrial craft but
i thought it was interesting because it
is saucer-shaped she said it hovered
over her car and in the original slide
of this you can see someone standing
right here in this window so i thought
that was rather interesting there was
another one too a fiery orb that betty
photographed
and
this all culminated
40 years of files uh betty's files the
hypnosis tapes all of her memoirs went
in to this book and culminated and
captured the betty and barney hill ufo
experience with by stanton freeman and
myself
and
i want to thank you very much for coming
today
[Music]
the story has
been being told for some time since the
late 60s
it's not a new story
we have done a lot of research that puts
information out that hasn't been put out
before the new book captured
but it's an important story
for
on several different levels
there's a first abduction experience to
get any serious attention wasn't the
first abduction
first when they get attention
and john fuller's book the interrupted
journey
now
it got attention in spite of the efforts
of betty and barney
because they were very much concerned
about what the impact would be on their
lives
if this story got out
betty was a social worker
a supervisor in the welfare department
state of new hampshire
barney worked for the post office was
very active in civil rights
uh the last thing they needed
was public attention about the strangest
story you can imagine
bad enough to see a flying saucer people
have been seeing them for years
many years
even seeing crash flying saucers as you
heard in the previous talk
but now we're not talking about
dead bodies we're talking about live
ones
we're not talking about wreckage we're
talking about a craft that comes down
does its thing and leaves
takes them on board against their will
this is a crazy story
so they made every effort to keep the
story from getting out in the public
because they were honestly and sincerely
concerned about what it would mean to
their lives
their jobs
[Music]
as you may have noticed this is an
interracial couple
this is 1961 in new hampshire
such couples were not very common
very special people
and i surprised some people by pointing
out that even though you noticed barney
died in
1969 february
i met him
ian betty and i had dinner in pittsburgh
pennsylvania
in 1968 november
and it was it was interesting because i
got a call from
the local the big radio station big
television station kdka
and i had done i got started in public
involvement on ufos because i did a
program on kdka
called surprisingly enough contact it
was a call-in show
and i had asked frank edwards who had a
best-selling book about flying saucers
uh i said i want to go public frank i
had met frank
i've been active for several years and
finding out about saucers give me some
names frank you know everybody he was a
newsman in indianapolis
uh he gave me some names in pittsburgh
where i was living and working for
westinghouse
and one of them was a producer of this
show contact
and i called them and gave them a spiel
and usually being a nuclear physicist
working for westinghouse were
gold-plated credentials in pittsburgh
you know you want to buy a house how
much do you want to borrow that kind of
thing
but their response was pretty much don't
call us we'll call you
well less than a month later they called
me at 6 30 at night could i please be on
their show at seven o'clock
somebody had canceled at the last minute
and lord knows how many people they
called before they got somebody like me
who was willing to go on the show
so i did the show
i wasn't as good at handling the noisy
negative as then as i am now
but somebody at work at westinghouse
heard me asked me to talk to her book
review club which was looking at frank's
book i gave my first lecture in her
living room
i did the show many times over the next
couple of years
and
finally
after i'd done several shows for them
i got a call
betty and barney hill are coming to town
we thought you might like to know
now normally stations won't do that
they protect their guests
so they called me told me what hotel
they were staying at
i called them went down we had dinner
together
i was very favorably impressed by that i
mean i'd read the look magazine article
in john fuller's book and so forth
so i can truthfully say i had a chance
to interact with the both of them i've
seen betty many times since
at her home we did television shows at
tomorrow show
other shows
my movie ufos are real there's some
copies outside
interview done at betty's
house so
a very special
twosome here
and if you look at the dates
you'll see betty lived a much longer
time than barney
so these are the protagonists in this
interesting story
but
people with excellent reputations in
their community who did not seek out
publicity talk to a lawyer about keeping
the story from coming out he said
there's nothing you can do
the reporter got a hold of it who wanted
to interview them
from a
boston newspaper and it was the last
thing they wanted but
you want to interview dr simon the
psychiatrist
he wasn't having any either
so
it's an interesting saga this was second
marriages
well
they both have been married before
and a very special couple let's look at
the next slide
and another character in this drama was
stelsi their dog who was with them on
the trip
and whose behavior indicated great
concern at some time hiding under the
seat as i recall it
uh
but she's not the little critter we want
to talk about the most tonight
let's look at the next slide
uh
now
you'll hear all kinds of crazy stories
one of the things about important
stories like roswell and the hill case
is that the nasty noisy negativists
really work overtime
trying to put out garbage
and you'll see every aspect of each case
being attacked by somebody who doesn't
know what he's talking about or if he
does is intentionally lying and i'm not
going to pass judgment on that
you know why they went on a trip betty
had a week's vacation coming barney
wanted to do something they were fairly
newly married
celebrating a special way
betty had never been to niagara falls
barney got time off from work well she
had a vacation
and they decided to go to niagara falls
everybody's romantic objective if you
this is sort of like a honeymoon forum
and you may not recognize this person
but she's standing right here
this is kathleen
and
at the time
she was 13 years old
should i say that yeah you're not
supposed to tell a woman's age but
that's right this was a girl's age was
13.
she had been at niagara falls
uh
and so she had told them about her her
trip
and that helped them understand you know
why it was worth going
there and so forth
uh
the
objective here is to drive to niagara
falls come back through montreal
come on back home they'd have a great
weekend
you know a break in the activities
but kathy was around at the time and
there are some people who will tell you
she was only three years old at the time
how did she know what was going on they
left off that little one 13 and three
are not the same in case you hadn't
noticed excellent
so they were following a
route they'd gone over to niagara falls
which is
from thousand islands
they came up through montreal had a
great time in montreal
and headed east
from montreal to koatikook
i got it i think i pronounced it
properly
close enough
down through colebrook there's a border
between canada and the united states
here
this is lovely farmland dairy farms i've
been on that road
uh a rural area
montreal isn't rural believe me
the countryside is
and things were going as one might
expect them to go they thought they
might stay over in montreal barney got
lost
all the signs were in french and he
didn't speak french
and so after they got through the town
they decided oh what the heck he felt he
was feeling great he we could drive on
home to
portsmouth new hampshire
these are not busy roads
once you get past montreal
it was that night he was accustomed to
working at night
uh so away we go
next one
here's quite a cook and it's kathleen's
turn to say something
betty and barney stopped for dinner in
koat cook they decided to use up the
remainder of their canadian money
and you might have heard that barney was
very upset
during this trip because he had
encountered some hoodlums who gave him a
rough time about being married to a
white woman
that is false what actually happened
is that betty and barney went into a
restaurant there were two young men in
there who had what barney described as
duck bill haircuts and it reminded him
of the haircuts that hoodum types were
wearing
at that time frame
but
they were conventionally dressed and
barney stated that they were very nice
young men
they had a nice dinner in the restaurant
and then they left
after they left
they traveled
through the canadian countryside toward
vermont and then on to new hampshire
this is one of the attractive farms that
they passed along the way
and during the hypnosis during this time
frame dr simon was asking barney how he
felt what his emotional state was and i
want to play for you now barney in
barney's own words how he felt
[Applause]
i hope that you could hear that it was
he what he uh stated is written up there
on the
screen well then they drove on and they
passed through customs and canaan
vermont without any problems
and this is the route that they took
here's colebrook this would have been
their first stop after they left canada
they got gasoline there and stopped at a
restaurant again for a cup of coffee
then they went on to lancaster the next
city down along route 3 the major route
that ran through northern new hampshire
it still is the only major route in that
part of northern new hampshire
and then on to twin mountain
this is the town of colebrook
they stopped at a restaurant their
howard's restaurant
and
just had a cup of coffee they knew it
was the last opportunity they'd have
probably to have a cup of coffee that
night before they went home
and as they were leaving the restaurant
they noticed it was about 10 o'clock
p.m
things are quieting down in new
hampshire
uh
they drove along to lancaster now you
see cars here
and you think oh it's pretty busy
there was nobody out it was late
10 50 is late at night in rural new
hampshire
this is off season this is before the
leaves turn beautiful
there's nothing much going on
no traffic
very little very few things open of a
commercial nature any place along this
route it's country
pure and simple country
so don't be fooled by the cars no
traffic okay
and then
the driving south
betty on the right in the passenger seat
of course
saw a strange new light in the sky she
was watching the sky the skies are clear
and beautiful down there this is not
smogsville country at all and as you'll
see the weather was great
and they saw this new light in the sky
except it was sort of like a meteor
except it was going up
next slide they were going from north to
south as you can see there
okay this
the first interview that was done at any
length with them
after they made an initial report to
peace at the local police and peace air
force base
was done by walter webb
he was a wheel at the planetarium in
boston
the lecturer
when he finished i guess he was
assistant directors
uh
he was an investigator for the national
investigations committee on aerial
phenomena nightcap one of the two major
groups at that time apro and nikop very
phenomenal research organization
national investigations committee on
aerial phenomena
now after the event we'll be talking
about uh betty went to the library got a
book out by major donald kehoe who had
pretty much founded nightcap and was
director
and it had an address to which you could
write to report a sighting and they
requested that sightings be reported
and so she wrote a letter
uh
detailing what happened during this
experience as far as she knew at the
time anyway
and they in turn passed this on to
walter webb nycap was in washington dc
we're talking about
new hampshire nearest big city boston of
course
walter webb was
their big shot investigator in boston
they passed betty's letter
naturally typed she was a social worker
she was a supervisor welfare department
of new state of new hampshire he was
accustomed to writing reports
uh
and it was detailed
so walter called them
within a couple of days after getting
the letter from nycap
and arranged to meet them
and so we have a copy of that report
he's still around incidentally
little older as most of us are now
and there's a quote here the couple
initially thought they were observing a
falling star only it moved upward a
plane or a satellite next slide
uh
there were bright
you can see that up there the first stop
was near twin mountain now
now we're getting up to 11 20 p.m even
quieter
nothing going on peaceful countryside
no hoodlums
there were bright colors like bright
orange light almost a reddish beam and
there were like a blue light on a police
cruiser
they were just a flash flash of
different colors
and i'd never seen anything like it
before it was moving quite fast
now she's watching barney's driving
when i saw it go in front of the moon i
was sort of fascinated and i kept
watching now note that
a later explanation is that this was
jupiter
now i can't remember the last time
jupiter went in front of the moon
it's half a billion miles out there
the moon's a quarter of a million miles
out there
but let's look at the next sign
she was intrigued in other words and
she's telling barney incidentally
about this
she's seeing a ufo and he's betty there
are no ufos
he was poo pooing and he was driving
south she's watching this thing and
reporting to him
they went through franconia notch which
is now we say mountains in new hampshire
when you're on the east coast and you
say mountains you don't mean the rockies
the highest point east of the
mississippi is in new hampshire mount
washington or one of the highest points
to
gather with north carolina
but you do have rolling country
and some sharp hills so you get this
franconian notch they call it you can
see why
it's sharp
notch
not slowly rolling down kind of thing
uh this was taken a little later time in
the year and they get gorgeous color up
there but normally in october
not september and then you'll have
busloads full of tourists looking at the
color
but not
september 20th next slide
then we see cannon mountain there is a
well you can you can see it there
there's a
a tramway
you know it goes up and down runs most
of the year
ski lift if you want to call it that not
at this time of year of course
they do have skiing there
no it's a beautiful local area well
known and some people have suggested
that what they saw was the light at the
top of the mountain there
and as you will hear about all the
things this crazy light did you realize
it couldn't have been
that lights at top of the mountain stay
in the same place normally they don't
move around they don't fly in front of
the moon and you know
so let's look at the next slide
is that yours
uh
now
i get a real kick out of the
explanations about point sources jupiter
uh
they also watched it go past one of the
real
emblems of new hampshire the old man of
the mountain until it fell
uh
when we went by where it was we were up
there doing a television show but
this shape
as you can see first seen in 1805 by a
white man looks like an old man of the
mountain
they saw the ufo
alongside it
now it's 48 feet from
chin to brow
it was about one and a half times
the height
that's not a point of light in other
words
yeah i better show you up here
you see the idea here's the old man of
the mountain this now fell into a lake
and you can't see it but
the saucer was next to it
uh
but
people want to explain it away and
ignore this part of the testimony
if it was 48 feet one and a half times
would be 72 feet
that's hardly a point source of light
and so many of the so-called
explanations disappear
okay
they then made a second stop and got out
of the car to look at this object in the
sky
betty had told barney that it was moving
erratically and they both speculated
that perhaps it was the movement of the
car
and betty was looking at this through
binoculars as she was riding along
and so they decided to stop
to see if it actually was moving
erratically or if it was only an object
that was moving smoothly in the sky
and so i want to play for you now
barney's description of what they saw
about
a thousand feet i guess
i
know it is not a pepper cup
it was too fast
it moved too fast
it would go
up and
down
it couldn't go back so fast
it could go away and come back
go toward the west
and without
looking as if it turned it would come
straight back it would go like a
uh
i think of a pedal
and a ball with a
you rubber
the ball
and the ball goes straight out and comes
straight back
without a circle
and i think only a jet could fly that
fast
so he thinks only a jet could fly that
fast the only problem is it was
completely silent
and it had unconventional lighting
and they could see the windows in it
there were no red lights at that time
there was only a row of white lights and
it appeared to be rotating
whoops here we go
they then returned to their car
and drove south
the next area that they would have come
to is known as indian head this is the
area where the
spend the night there were cottages
there at the time and there were also
some tourist attractions
what you see here is indian head
the indian head resort is there
in 1961 there were only cabins today it
has grown into a big beautiful resort
and i did want to mention that in
september of 2011
the indian head resort is going to host
a 50th anniversary event
uh to commemorate betty and barney
hill's experience and they are going to
dedicate a memorial to betty and barney
and there will be guided tours of the
close encounter route i will be giving
those and also lecturing so i hope that
you will consider coming to that
as betty and barney pass those cabins
betty saw someone standing in one of the
windows it was a man standing in a
window and she thought to herself well
i could end all of this right now
if we just stopped and spent the night
at this cabin
but then she thought she was so curious
she wanted to see more of this
and barney having left this very
desolate area told dr simon and i quote
i feel safe and less in the barren
hostility of the wooded area i've been
here before and i feel comforted that i
see a familiar place
now barney started to talk to dr simon
about betty's reaction
dr simon had asked him and he said betty
is becoming excited about this thing
and betty rarely becomes excited about
anything
so something is going on here that is
unusual
and i think that i want to stop and get
a better look at this thing
so as he was driving himself he was
looking for another place where he could
pull over to the side of the road and
stop
but
before he had the opportunity to find a
spot
this craft shifted ahead of them
and stopped directly over the top of
their vehicle and then descended toward
them causing barney to have to stop the
car directly in the middle of the road
now we're at 12 15 a.m now he stopped in
the middle of the road and you might
think well that was not a very bright
thing to do but there was nobody around
there was no
traffic he says it continued to have a
forward look facing me as if it swung
and did not move from its position
but just swung around with the front
still facing me
and it moved to my left and i continued
to look and began walking across the
highway
from the car got out of the car
going across the highway there's a field
over there
and
okay
barney
walked toward the craft holding the
binoculars up to his eyes
and what i want to do now is to play for
you two tape recordings of barney's
statements about what he saw the first
recording is his first session with dr
simon
and dr simon uh brought on this
tremendous release of emotion in barney
at this point
this is the place where barney's mental
block set in he recalled
the a close encounter with this craft he
recalled observing non-human entities on
board the craft in fact his statement to
walter webb in the initial report was
that they were somehow not human
in betty's letter written september 25th
to nycap
she reported that barney had observed
figures on board this craft and there
was something about their appearance
that had frightened him so badly that he
had developed a mental block and would
they were considering finding a
competent psychiatrist who would use
hypnosis to help barney
understand what it was that caused this
mental block
so the first tape i'm going to play for
you
is this first session
keep
[Applause]
just looking
looking and stay there
and just keep looking
yes keep looking
could you hear each other oh i gotta
pull these binoculars away from my eyes
because if i thought i'll just keep
standing there
could you hear me tell you this oh god
he didn't say it he felt he said it i
know
you know he just there yeah
just stay there he's saying to me
[Applause]
all right
[Music]
oh
[Applause]
how could you be sure he was telling you
this
[Music]
[Applause]
nice
[Music]
how did you know the other one was the
leader because
everybody moved
everyone was standing there looking at
me
but everybody moved
to these levers or in the back or they
went to this
big
board they looked like it looked like a
board
[Music]
and only this one with the black
black shiny jacket
in the scarf
stayed at the window
there's some real terror there you might
have noticed
now i'm going to play the excerpt from
the second hypnosis session where barney
was reliving the same experience with
left's emotion and was able to give dr
simon a little more detail about what he
observed
i noticed with my binoculars that there
were
about 11 men
now
i thought
looking down at me
and they suddenly made a
turn to what i thought was a panel
and i could see their arms going up
and there was one that kept looking down
and
i kept going closer
i could see two red lights coming out
from the tip
of this thing that did not look like a
plane at all or a helicopter
and
i could see
a long something coming down from the
center
and
i kept going closer and closer
and i thought oh my god
what is this thing
and
i felt myself being told to come closer
and i was greatly confused and i blinked
my eyes and i thought this can't be real
and i shook my head and turned it away
and looked back and i thought oh god
it's there what is this thing and i put
my hand toward my gun and i could not
put my hand there and i could not
understand why my hands kept going up
with the binoculars and i was told to
keep the binoculars up and keep looking
up and keep coming closer no harm would
come to me and that's when i opened my
hands and the binoculars fell around my
neck and i ran
screaming back to the car
that they were going to capture us and
yet i could not understand what they
wanted to capture us for and i thought i
should report this to the police if ever
i could find a call box or anything or a
restaurant open because this was very
unusual for something to do that and i
thought of the military and i thought
since they had on black jack the one
looking at me had on a black jacket he
must have been a military officer and
yet i could not quite understand why
they were doing what they were doing and
there was no sound coming from this
thing
barney then finally managed to pull
those binoculars down and when he
arrived home the strap the leather strap
on the binoculars was broken
and this must have been the point where
he broke that strap where he pulled them
down so violently
in order to overcome this this thought
that he was getting from the leader on
this craft to keep them up at his eyes
uh he pulled it down and ran back to the
car
screaming to betty that they had to get
out of there they were going to be
captured betty was seated in the car all
of this time the door was cracked open i
imagine the interior light in the car
was on
and she was calling for barney after a
few minutes
and when he didn't come back she was
becoming very upset
and she
felt that if he hadn't come back when he
did she was going to get out of the car
and go into that field and look for him
as barney was returning to the car
running back he noticed that the craft
had shifted overhead above the vehicle
whoa
and
he told betty to
look up and see if she could see the
craft so she rolled down the window and
she looked up
and she couldn't see it
all she could see is blackness she
couldn't see the stars
she couldn't see the sky
she saw her only blackness and i'm going
to play for you now her description of
what happened next
she's inside the car looking up
out the window
no even buddy said
what's happened yeah what's that noise
and i said
i don't know it sounds all i could think
of with some kind of electrical signal
somebody's you know it's really big and
i thought well i wonder why did i learn
the most code because maybe this is the
mouse code and i don't know it
and i thought well maybe it's electrical
it's the shock get it you know i could
so i put my hand on the metal of the car
[Applause]
and i kept feeling the feeling and i
didn't feel any uh shock no electric
shack
but the hotel was vibrating
the car was vibrating and there was a
tingling sensation that passed through
betty's and barney's bodies and caused
them to feel a little numb
the next thing they were new
they were 35 miles south of the fields
they hadn't spoken another word to each
other
you would think that betty would have
asked barney what he had observed in the
field
you would think that they would be
discussing this thing
they didn't they didn't speak for 35
miles as far as they could remember they
know from the signs on the road how many
miles to some place you see
okay this is a map
okay this is twin mountain their first
stop was at the mount cleveland picnic
area here just south of twin mountain at
about 10 50 p.m it might have been a
little earlier than that when they
arrived but when i was driving through
uh reenacting
their trip for myself i had to drive
more slowly than betty and barney were
driving back then it's more heavily
populated now
barney was driving along at a fairly
rapid clip 50 55 miles an hour according
to his testimony we had to slow down
as we were passing through
here's the old man of the mountain
that's the second stop
i estimated it was about 11.50 but when
betty passed by cannon mountain she told
dr simon that she looked at her watch
and she thought it was about 11 20 at
that time so i again may be off
this is the third stop
at the close encounter field
they thought it was about midnight then
i arrived it would have been about 12
15.
and then
later on they found out that there was a
capture site that they didn't recall
initially until hypnosis and this is
where that was located
now a point that needs to be made when
we were there to do a movie and i won't
talk about the movie
but
uh
when you're standing at that location
where barney was looking with his
glasses
and you realize that very shortly after
that he gets off the main road onto a
secondary road and then onto a dirt road
there is no possible way he would have
done that on his own
makes absolutely no sense
he was being directed
to a rather unique spot in the whole
area it's a heavy heavily wooded part of
the country as you can see the trees are
tall this is not new mexico desert
this is wooded new hampshire
and yet they wind up on this very narrow
road
no lights no traffic no people no
buildings
why would anybody go there you know
and they see a roadblock and beings
meant in the road
they couldn't make any sense out of this
what was going on here is there an
accident there's no traffic there's not
no reason for there to be anybody there
so let's look at the next slide i just
wanted to mention that in their
conscious recollection
there was a roadblock
they just didn't know when or where it
occurred that was a mystery
and
they saw this
you can call it a fiery orb a bright
light some source of light ahead of them
in the road
it was moving but they weren't moving
i thought it might be the moon but
obviously the moon isn't down on road
level
uh
it couldn't have been the moon
so they're totally puzzled about this
situation what's going on what's
happening let's look at that and i'd
like to play for you barney's statement
about that experience
this was part
the moon be on the highway
in that kind of position
and i could never seem to find any
uh terrain up there that would fit what
i sort of dimly remembered
uh this thing was sitting there like and
i kept remembering these men flagging me
down
and then i sort of don't remember
and now i
remember
okay
next thing they remember is this gap
they see this orb whatever it is in the
road they see men
beings around it
and then it's like everything fades out
the next thing they remember is a number
another set of these
buzzing beeping sounds the car shaking
maybe
and they're 35 miles down the road
and now they're back in full
consciousness
except that it's it's seamless
they've been alert and awake now they're
alert and awake and in between
nothing
how do you drive a car without knowing
what you're doing you know
so let's look at the next one
and so they kept on about their business
uh coming down this way heading
portsmouth is on the coast
on the atlantic coast
concord's the capital and so many of the
signs said how far it was to concord
that's your measuring label
here
and
they expected to get home about three in
the morning
uh but that's not what happened
they arrived home
at 5 15 a.m
they checked their watches when they
arrived home but they were no longer
working
they wound them
those watches never worked again they
went into the house
barney went into the house first he
looked at the clock it was about 5 15 am
he said
arrived a little bit later than i
anticipated
betty stayed outside walking the dog
delsie and she talked about how she
could hear the birds chirping
it was already daylight
this is september mind you september
20th
the birds shouldn't be chirping at three
in the morning
barney sensed a strange sensation in his
groin a little itchiness and he went
into the bathroom and checked himself to
see what was wrong he didn't see
anything then
but not long after that 21
three-quarter inch growths
appeared in a perfect concentric circle
on his groin
later
under hypnosis he would tell dr simon
that he could feel a cup-like device
being placed over his groin in that
exact location
those growths
became infected
inflamed when barney was undergoing
hypnosis with dr simon and he had to
have them surgically removed at that
time this is two years after the event
mind you
but the growth appeared shortly there
after the event yeah okay but the
inflammation was later yes it was later
so
i do want to uh stress the point that
the lab report
stated that they were not venereal warts
the debunkers tend to say that that's
what they were they were not
uh he and betty felt clammy as if they
had been contaminated by something more
than anyone would feel just from driving
to monitor from not montreal to new
hampshire
and there uh as i said the what the
binocular strap was broken and their
watches had stopped and never worked
again
the tops of barney's shoes were scraped
he was a meticulous dresser
he had to wear those shoes for yard work
after that he had no explanation
logical explanation for how this had
happened they weren't just slightly
scuffed they were scraped his words were
they were scraped
they went into separate rooms
and they drew sketches of what they had
observed standard practice
you do it with your kids they both say
they saw something well you sit down
here and draw what you saw and you sit
down here and draw what you saw so they
each
drew what they could recall
this is without hypnosis at this point
in time
and
two drawings pretty darn similar
it should be noted that these kind of
wings or whatever you want to call them
slid out from the side
so
red light then gradually as it came
closer to the ground and there were
windows with beings being seen on the
other side
neither one of these two was a great
artist you understand
but
uh close enough
to say that they were drawing the same
thing this was a temporary apparently
appendage
i call it a wing but that's probably not
a good name for it
okay
and i just did want to mention that
barney drew figures behind the windows
whereas betty did not
that's because barney observed those
figures when he was in the field and had
the binoculars and betty was in the car
so she was drawing what she saw
initially in the car before
the craft shifted over the field and
barney walked toward it
now betty had put on a fairly new dress
the morning of the trip from montreal to
portsmouth
and when she arrived home
the zipper was torn at the top of the
zipper there was a two inch tear on one
side and a one inch tear on the other
side
no mundane explanation for that all she
did is
ride in the car she got out a few times
she ate a couple of restaurants
no explanation for this
the
lining was torn from waste to hemline
and the ham was torn down on one side
she knew it had to be repaired so she
folded it up and she placed it in her
closet
the next time she went to her closet
to retrieve the dress it was covered
with a pink powdery substance that
degraded the fabric and destroyed the
dress
she hung the dress up on the clothesline
the pink powder blew away but it had
discolored the dress permanently
and this is the dress here
you can see that part of it
this area right here
is still blue that was the original blue
color of the dress
but there are areas
where it was completely saturated with
this pink powdery substance
and these were the areas where betty
later told dr simon
that these alien beings who had abducted
her had wrapped their hands around her
shoulders
there's another view of the dress you
can see that some swaths have been cut
out of the dress those were for the
chemical analyses that the dress
underwent
they underwent four chemical analyses
and uh i have written about that and
captured and they also uh
were used in a seed growth experiment
this is phyllis buttinger
she has a master's degree in chemistry
she did the most extensive chemical
analysis on the dress she was a research
scientist for bp amico previously
standard oil for 35 years she
specialized in
petroleum chemical and polymer analyses
using spectroscopic techniques
and currently she is the technical
director of frontier analysis limited
laboratory in chagrin falls ohio
a quite respectable chemist
you can read more about it in captured
but her conclusion at the end of this
analysis was and i quote i am convinced
that the event did happen as determined
by the chemical analysis i did on betty
hill's dress
well
my mother was the first person that
betty called when she arrived home
barney had advised her that they should
forget about the entire event that no
good could possibly come of it
but betty and my mother were very close
and lived 20 miles apart
and
so when she called my mother
my mother suggested that she would call
a neighbor of ours who was a physicist
and see what the physicist
had to say about this whole thing betty
was worried about contamination
uh what might have happened to them and
the physicist told my mother to advise
betty that if she had a compass she
should take it out to the car to see how
the needle of the compass would react
she did find a compass and she took it
out and
when she went out there she noticed
there were some new very shiny spots on
the trunk of the vehicle that hadn't
been there the day before there were 12
to 18 of them and they were very shiny
and i'm going to play for you both
betty's and barney's descriptions of
what those spots looked like i also saw
these spots this is a facsimile because
none of us thought to take a photograph
of those spots
but this is based upon betty's and
barney's descriptions and upon my memory
of what i observed
there was nothing about an abduction up
to this point in their minds
so the significance wasn't yet known of
this whole experience it was like a
whacker
put on over the color and even when i
waxed the car
the shot and the spot still was shiny
and
it had been raining
that day
and uh the car was all wet still left
and
i thought well
i started
on the side of the calf
to see what would happen and i kept
going
closer and closer to the trunk
and then it was when i started to go to
the trunk of the compass that i noticed
the
shiny spots on the trunk
that they were
these very very shiny spots
about
the whole cluster album
about the size of
i don't know half dollars or
clover dollar something like that
and there must have been
oh twelve or eight billion several
twelve a dozen i would say
all around the spot and very shiny
and
when i've just got the compass anywhere
it's near them
the compass kept spinning around and
around and around
and
i at this i panicked
i got more upset at this one spot than i
did
at any
thing she said now let's listen to what
barney said
and i said how can you not know
if it isn't anything and then i put the
compass close to it
and the compass
would spin
and spin
and i could move the compass a few
inches
to a spot
that did not connect to a
caught in on the trunk that did not have
a spot
and the compass
would drop down
and i
so you can see that betty and barney's
description of those spots and how the
compass needle reacted were consistent
nobody understands why that would happen
you understand
the spots were located in the exact uh
location where the hills said they heard
beeping or buzzing sounds that caused
the vehicle to vibrate and that
vibration to cause their bodies to
tingle
betty washed and waxed the vehicle but
the spots wouldn't rub out but they
faded away over the winter of 1961-1962
we i do have a letter in the book uh
quotes from a letter of a meeting that
betty and barney had with air force
officers
at their church
rectory
where they discussed the spots on the
trunk of the car and speculated about
what might have caused this this wasn't
part of the official blue book record
it was a meeting
brought together by betty and barney
could never understand why these
officers came to this meeting it was
supposed to be to listen to poetry
written by one of the officers but after
he read his poems the officers asked
betty and barney to stay and they had a
conversation about the spots on the
trunk of the vehicle barney knew people
at the base
because of his work with civil rights
you see so there was a connection with
the base peace air force base
just outside port portsmouth
now there has been some speculation that
they might have just been weather spots
weather spots uh develop when
it rains
uh atmospheric pollutants drop down in
the rain
they deposit on the vehicle
then the sun comes out and bakes those
spots on the car
and you have to use a chemical solution
to get them off they don't rub off very
easily
this is what weather marks look like and
you can see here that this is not what
betty's and barney's marks looked like
does not fit the description
and then here is the facsimile again
just so that you can see the difference
they
called the local police
they advised them to call nearby peace
air force base
they did they made a report they were
treated
fairly decently a record was kept
here's the official project blue book
air intelligence information report
it would
was taken seriously
uh the report also included the
interesting
where's the comment about the
radar there what is that
oh on this one
i can't read it though
can you read it
um
there was a radar report it was a radar
report uh it says it was revealed that a
strange incident occurred at 211 local
on the 20th of september no importance
was attached to the incidence incident
at the time
subsequent interrogation failed to bring
out any information in addition to the
that of the extract of the daily uh
controller
and there was also a report on another
radar installation up in uh where are we
in normal concord vermont yep yes
blue book tried to push this aside and
there have been a number of instances
noted where they've changed files and
records and so forth
but what i'm saying is there's a
definite record of something happening
at the right time and place and so forth
they were taken seriously
uh
let's look at the next but
i want to mention that this is the
original handwritten report
and in the original report
the air force said that there was a
strong inversion in that in the lincoln
new hampshire area that night
and an uh temperature inversion will
cause a distant object to appear much
closer than it is and one of their
favorite theories was that this might
explain ufo sightings that people had
it was a favorite for the washington
national airport sightings
the only trouble is when you check the
weather records uh there wasn't any
temperature conversion
and this is from the mount mount
washington is the tallest point in new
hampshire tallest point on the east
coast
the official weather station archival
records looking back on our records for
the dates in question it appears that
the 19th and 20th were both beautiful
late summer days atop the rock pile
mount washington was the rock pile they
had some of the strongest winds in the
country on average
terrible winters
rugged kind of place
the evening and nighttime
conditions for the 19th were quite
tranquil winds were from the west at
around 25 miles per hour
visibility was 130 miles throughout the
night
but dropped to 75 miles during the
morning hours of the 20th
uh there was a movie well we'll talk
about that but in which the windshield
wipers are shown going like mad
it wasn't raining when you got 130 miles
of visibility
it's not bad weather
some critics have also stated that the
weather people at the top of mount
washington would have observed the craft
if it had really been there on that
night
uh there was a letter written to the
weathermen up there and they said that
due to uh their job the type of job they
had they only went outside of the
building at night in order to check the
temperature gauges outside and then they
returned to the building they would not
have observed anything in the sky that
night
they're not looking around are there any
flying saucers folks no
the chief meteorologist said it is
possible a weak inversion set up in the
valleys overnight
as the valley locations are more prone
to the diurnal day night effects of the
sun but i think that the cloud cover
would have prevented any radiational
cooling in the valley so there wasn't
any inversion
that's what the chief meteorologist said
and
uh
as
things went on and we haven't mentioned
that but we did mention you'd gone down
there yes seen the car witnessed it so
personal experience etc
ten days later about betty began to have
nightmares had five of them
they included a conscious memory of a
close encounter with a ufo
she also dreamed of an abduction by the
crafts occupants
i think you're all aware that sometimes
the events of our daytime life show up
in our dreams
so something was going on here but betty
being betty she recorded the dreams
she kept a record of them now remember
barney work nights
betty work days
let's look at the next
okay now
the event took place in 1961 september
okay
barney developed some ulcers some
problems
health problems went to a doctor
uh you know got to take care of the the
ulcer problem
got blood pressure problems
and the doctor told barney that uh look
i've done all i can for you with
conventional medicine something else is
going on here
he recommended that they see a
psychiatrist
because remember back then ulcers were
thought to be caused by mental stress
and if you could control the stresses
you could take care of the ulcers to
some extent to make a long story short
he wound up in the office of doctor they
wound up dr benjamin simon
now benjamin simon didn't know a darn
thing about ufos but
he was a world-class expert
on helping people
uncover
hidden memories if you will
uh
is specifically dealing with world war
ii shall shock war veterans that's what
they used to call it today it's
post-traumatic stress disorder
well you know
your body's head gets blown off next to
you
it's a little hard to integrate that
into your
life you know why me not or him not me
and how do i live with that and
you know these are dif people are coming
back from iraq and afghanistan with
these things
uh
and so
dr simon actually ran a hospital with 3
000 beds
for shell shock war veterans
yeah the greatest success of any of the
psychiatrists it's never 100 percent i'd
better add not everybody is able to get
back to a normal life
but he even stars
in a movie let there be light that the
army made
showing his techniques that he had
developed using regressive hypnosis
somebody who was blind was able to see
again
we're not talking mythical stories here
the army wanted these people to get back
to living again
and dr simon was the best equipped
probably of anybody around
who could have had the chore of trying
to uncover what happened he was not in
boston
and he conducted his sessions each
separately
not together
and in induced
amnesia at the end of each session
two purposes
they couldn't remember it themselves and
they couldn't talk to the other one
about it
he was taping all these sessions
and eventually
played back the tapes to them together
and his whole purpose was to get
the feelings out to have them relive
these experiences
so we could show them they're okay now
they can live with it
the truth shall set you free something i
don't know who said that i don't know
who said that but it doesn't matter
so ben simon was
not an expert on flying saucers and
listening to the tapes sometimes you get
the feeling why didn't he ask of this
that or the other thing well he wasn't
interested in the saucer part of the
story
he was interested in helping two
obviously sensible sensitive intelligent
people
get their lives back
after what was clearly a strange
experience that was disturbing to them
so it wasn't the next week the next
month it wasn't carl sagan did an
article which made it sound like there
was one hypnosis session where they came
up with this and bull story
nonsense
and as a matter of fact
we have it in writing that the emotional
intensity in one session each
was greater than that in the voices of
any of the military guys that dr simon
had worked with
he had to stop those sessions
he was afraid they couldn't handle it
the terror is quite clear
and i mentioned this because you'll hear
people saying
what was it class said
that he
didn't get excited it was like she was
taking a stroll in the supermarket
it sure doesn't come across that way
when you listen to the tape
barney
is terror stricken
and remember
there had been no
abduction cases that had been publicized
there's nothing to draw upon about what
happened here if you're being abducted
by somebody are you going to get back
what's going to happen to you
is your life going down the drain while
these guys get when they get finished
with you they throw you away but you
know
so there's an inate terror aside from
their having you under their control
and doing physical examinations and
other stuff which none of us are
nobody wants to be a specimen
which is how they were treated
for fair enough statement yes
so he was quite a remarkable guy
and
it's important to recognize that this
was a real expert
not in flying saucers
but in helping people get through
difficult experiences
and as they're reliving this experience
they realize that
remember that business about the orb
they saw this light in the road and some
men around it and stuff that they
remembered that consciously not very
clearly
now they're going over it
and when you're up in that country the
uh
the trees are tall the
road is narrow no lights
oops
i kept driving and driving and i made a
turn and i never knew this i don't know
why i had to make that turn
as i say when you stand at the spot
where he first sees the leader through
the binoculars
you get the very strong feeling that he
was
being directed
where to go
and the place they wound up
was the only place in the area where you
could sit down a large saucer
empty
lot i'll call it sandy area this is very
heavily forested land and at night it's
dark out there i'll tell you that
the sand is kind of whitish
so
he was there because they wanted him
there
and from the air of course you could see
where could you set down a saucer where
could you bring a car in and so forth
and so on
there's the comment
when betty was talking about her dreams
i saw eight to eleven men standing in
the middle of the road the men
surrounded the car we sat motionless
that's what she said
let's listen to
the description
then i thought well you know are they in
a car and the car broken down or
so what are they doing there
and
bonnie first had to stop
and then
he
he stopped the car
and we
decided to
come up to the car
they
they separated
they came up in two groups
and when they started to do that
i i get real scared
yeah
the the cowboy died the cast off
and
when they started coming up the body
tried to stop the car
he tried to start it
you know how a road of a cow just turned
over 125.
i just had to count it like that and
we're gonna collect it
and i think well
i can't get away from the vegas if i get
the car down look like you're running
the woods inside
and
i'm thinking that i just put my hair out
candle and open it
and just add the make them up and they
open it for me
and they open the card door
and then
why did i put his hand out
i don't know what happened
did that sound like a trip to the
grocery store to you
the emotional level of a trip to the
grocery store
for a woman who's normally
very even
toned this is not an excitable woman
now in betty's dreams remember she
dreamed that there were eight to 11 men
they surrounded the car and she and
barney sat motionless you just saw that
under hypnosis that's not what happened
there were three who came to her door
let's see what barney
described
i
thought i saw a cluster
of
six men
because
they came to me
and three
did not
i
didn't think of the man
said he didn't think of the man in the
sky
at that time
well
as you can see
barney said that three approached him as
well
that's not what betty had in her dreams
there's evidence there that
what happened might have been a real
event
they both made the state same statements
correlating data under hypnosis
that was not in betty's dream material
the point is some people said there was
no event it was just betty's dream that
was the whole story
that what came out under hypnosis was
just betty's dreams and barney picked it
up from betty and we got no problem here
it's just you know wishful thinking
the reality comes out quite different
from that
and barney could as they each one was
grabbed by three people three beings
and barney could feel the top of his
feet bumping against the stones
that's where that scuffed shoes came
from
this is the sandy area they're being
transported in quotes separately
three with barney three with betty
his eyes were pretty much closed
they were under control
you want to keep your specimens from
fighting back in other words nobody
stuck a needle in them they wanted them
conscious presumably so they could do
what they were told to do when they were
being tested
uh but that's where the
shoe
problem seems to have come from
you know think of them sort of hanging a
little bit and being dragged
with his feet behind them on the ground
barney stated that he felt as if he were
floating somehow that his arms were
extended outward
and that he could just feel the toes of
his shoes bumping along those rocks and
then sliding along a smooth surface and
bumping over a surface at the top
smooth surface
we'll call it a ramp anyway
betty was feisty
she was trying to kick these people she
wasn't going to be taking willingness
willingly into whatever it was they
wanted to do with her but so three guys
on each of them managed to get them up
this ramp
over a kind of
lintel i'll call it a doorway kind of
base
and they were taken into separate rooms
uh
this is a clear area here the only space
in the area we could put down this darn
saucer
right next to this
narrow road where they were grabbed
somebody was paying attention and
planning
and when betty struggled at the bottom
of this ramp it's probably the point at
which she tore out the
lining of her dress and tore down her
hem
much more sensible and she's sitting in
the car and suddenly these things happen
barney later
uh drew this picture of what things look
like on board he had a compass
uh
you know he was
up this way
into a room it was a table and cabinet
this was a circular craft with pie
shaped room wedges you know going around
it they were not in the same rooms for
their
neither one was witness to what was
going on with the other one
some people have said that betty
recalled aliens who look very different
from the ones that barney recalled
they're getting betty's dreams confused
with betty's hypnotic recall this is
what the beings looked like in betty's
dreams
they looked a lot like jimmy durante
southern european looking dark thick
hair dark eyebrows human ears
human eyes large noses
lips that had a bluish tint
and a kind of a grayish skin
and they were dressed in blue cadet type
uniforms in her dreams
but this is what betty and barney
described and remembered
during the hypnosis sessions that they
had with dr simon
and this is a drawing done by new
hampshire artist uh
david baker he actually painted this in
watercolors and this was the rendition
of the leader now david baker
did his drawings based upon his
knowledge of human anatomy so they might
be slightly different from what betty
and barney observed betty and barney
said though that they had large chest
cavities they it was almost as if they
had barrel chest completely round rather
than being wider this way and thinner
this way
there was a membrane that covered their
mouths and this membrane fluttered when
they spoke to each other in this kind of
humming or buzzing sound
but betty and barney
understood them in english although they
never saw their mouths move when they
were communicating with betty and barney
telepathy to me anyway
they had large slanted eyes which betty
and barney said we had uh sort of square
sides
and
betty thought they had a vertical
cat-like
uh slit for a pupil and they both said
that the iris almost completely filled
up the eye
and there was a little bit of yellow
around the edges so uh what you see in
and david baker's painting is a little
bit different from what betty and barney
actually described in their written
accounts
the the leader was approximately five
feet tall
and
let's take a look now at the examiner
this is more what betty and barney
actually described this painting was
done by
new mexico artist patrick richard and he
was actually a friend of betty when he
lived in new hampshire the examiner
looked about the same as the leader only
they said he or she had a weaker chin
they weren't sure if it would this was a
male or female
it was approximately four and a half
feet tall
communicated in english again
they were all dressed in black
tight-fitting shiny clothing and in
barney's original reports
to
walter webb
back in october of 1961
he described shiny black uniforms
they betty later described long narrow
palms and very long fingers maybe four
or five she wasn't sure which
this is
a side view
a sketch by david baker
and there was a being on board that
betty and barney
didn't reveal to the public
they were asked not to talk about this
particular one by the scientists who
were studying their case
this is the one i call the supervisor
because this little being stood out in
the dark hallway looking in at betty as
she was being examined and frightened
her terribly he was about three and a
half feet tall
he resembled the others in a in a sense
but he was different
at the same time his head was larger in
proportion to the size of his body than
the leader and the examiner and he had
this very dark
irises
in his eyes
he had a broad flat nose and a wide thin
mouth and he was very hostile and
threatening
at the end this was the one that took
the book away from betty if you're
familiar with the story there was a book
that she wanted to keep
uh that she found on the craft it wasn't
didn't look like our books but it was
like a book and he was the one who saw
it and she told me that he was almost
screaming when he saw that she had that
book
and then
it was taken away from her she had asked
for something to take with early on to
prove that this event had happened
and she saw the book grabbed it and
she's getting ready to leave
and this blankety blank is telling me no
you can't take it with you
i'll remember you won't remember
it was a nasty scene there
well betty and barney said that their
physical examinations involved
an examination of their skeletal
structures these beings seem to be very
interested in the difference between
humans skeletons and their own whatever
that might be betty and barney noted
that they seemed oddly jointed and when
they walked they walked very differently
from us it was almost as if they were
gliding or stumbling along
or almost skating
it's really hard to describe
they examined betty's and barney's hands
their feet they took their shoes off
they examined their joints to see how
human joints moved they looked into
their eyes
they scraped their skin
they looked into their mouths
there were reproductive
experiments done
probably a needle was placed in betty's
navel
and the cup was placed over barney's
groin
many specimens were taken
from all of the
orifices in their bodies
and this is betty on the examining table
uh painting done by patrick richard
again
and the needle in the navel experiment
and i want to play for you now
betty's description under hypnosis
they rolled me over
on my back
[Applause]
and the examiner
had a long needle
in his hand
and i see the needle
and it's
this bigger than any needle i've ever
seen
and
i asked him what he's going to do with
it
and he said just as simple
and i asked him what
and he said he just wanted to put it in
my
[Applause]
you know
he goes over and he
puts his hand
right his hand in front of my eyes
and he says i'll be all right
i won't feel it
[Applause]
and all the pain goes away
just a simple walk in the supermarket
you can tell that
this is a session in which dr simon had
to end the session early due to the
emotional intensity he didn't want to
cause betty to relive any further trauma
during that session
and by the way that was before the
development of amniocentesis
they did say it was a pregnancy test
which didn't make any sense at the time
my wife has had amniocentesis the needle
in the navel routine
nobody was doing it at this time
now
uh i have another tape that i want to
play before stan
talks to you again
so
let's play this
[Applause]
he went
over
across the room
to the head of the table
and
though he he did something
he opened up up
and wasn't like a draw
he said i did something in the metal or
the wall
there was an opening
and
he pulled out a map
he asked me
had i ever seen a map like this before
and i walked
across the room
and i leaned against the table and i
looked at it
and it was a map of
it was an oblong map
the rhythm square
it was a lot wider than it was long
and
there were always
dots so much
and they were together all over at some
level
[Applause]
just pin points and others were
as big as a nickel
and there were lines
[Applause]
there were
on some of the
dots that there were
[Applause]
curved lines going from
one dot to another
and
there was
one big circle
and
it had
a lot of lines coming out from it
a lot of lines going to
another circle
quite close
but not as big
and
these were
heavy lines
and i asked him
what they meant
and he said that
the heavy lines were trade routes
[Applause]
and then
the other ones
the other one is that the solid lines
[Applause]
were
places they went occasionally
he said that
[Applause]
the birthing lines
were expeditions
[Applause]
so i asked him
where he
what
where was his home port
and
he said
where are you on this map
and
[Applause]
i reluctant i laughed and i said i don't
know
so he said well then
if you don't know
where you were
there wouldn't be any point
of my telling you where i am
wise guy alien is all i can say this was
preceded by betty asking him where they
were from
and saying i know you're not from around
here the understatement of the month
and that's when he showed her this this
map
and so this was followed by
dr simon is listening to this under
hypnosis this is reliving it's not
retelling
and he asked betty i mean you can
imagine how dr simon felt there he's got
a sensible person telling him a story
about trade routes and occasional
expeditions and
you know where is this all coming from
and so he asked but if she can remember
what the map looks like she says yes and
he gives her a post-hypnotic suggestion
if and only if she can remember it
accurately please draw it later on
and she does she goes home and she draws
it
and
there it is
base stars and you know trade routes and
occasional expeditions
how the heck are you going to make any
sense out of that
i mean a galaxy has a 100 200 billion
stars in it we have no points of
reference it might suggest that the
earth was on there or the sun was on
here somewhere because they're here
but beyond that we'll never know so it
seemed
until a brilliant woman named marjorie
fish did something nobody else had ever
done
she built 26 different three-dimensional
models of our local galactic
neighborhood that's marjorie that's
really me i did have black hair a long
time ago this is in the early 70s
she was a school teacher
she built these models
her whole point was to see if she could
she had visited betty and gotten more
information
to see if she could find a
three-dimensional pattern
that matched the two-dimensional drawing
that betty had drawn
she thought she'd find many matches
at first she didn't find any
now her models were limited by
information on how the distance to the
stars and how many you can put in a
model
out about 50 light years was the most
you could get in a cube kind of thing
she expected to find many matches she
didn't find any
using all the stars
then she started cutting back on which
stars she showed getting to the kind
that scientists then said were the ones
that ought to have planets in life maybe
not all stars would be expected they
might be too old too new to have another
star too close all kinds of restrictions
finally
when she got some good distance data the
astronomers aren't going anywhere so
they don't care how far away the stars
are
you need two
two angles to find a star
and whether it's 20 light years away or
40 light years away doesn't matter
but if you're trying to get a
three-dimensional pattern of where
things come from
it the distances matter entirely
and when a new catalog came out that
finally wilhelm gleese new catalog of
nearby star distances you heard the word
gliese
three weeks ago there was talk about a
planet 581 g gliese 581g
that's the same gliese
the star is 581
the g refers to the fifth plan i guess
it's fifth or sixth planet around that
star
and this may be in the goldilocks zone
and may have planets in life and all
this may have life
uh anyway
she finally found one and only one
pattern that matched
angle for line angle line length for
line length what betty had drawn it was
a big moment this is one of her models
each of those beads stands for a
particular star in its proper
three-dimensional location
and she had help from the staff at ohio
state university astronomy department dr
mitchell he's in my movie ufos are real
saying how accurate her work was she was
a school teacher she was a member of
mensah
brilliant objective person marjorie was
and
this is the identity of those stars the
distances then aren't quite accurate
the hipparcos satellite has made
millions of measurements of better
distances
finally uh the sun is up here that's the
important thing our star
the base stars
zeta 1 and zeta 2 reticuli
that's the constellation of reticulum
which means the net
you can't see it from here you've got to
go down to the southern hemisphere to
see it
these two stars are very special they're
the closest to each other pair of
sun-like stars in our entire local
neighborhood
our star the sun
is out in the boondocks next star over
4.3 light years away these two stars
from each other are only an eighth of a
light year apart
that's 30 times closer to each other
than we are to the next star over we're
out in the boonies these guys got
next-door neighbors
and those two stars are at least a
billion years older than the sun
a billion years now the fact that
they're so close means from a planet
around one looking at the other it's
visible all day long
and with that billion years and that
short distances is plenty of time and
more incentive to develop interstellar
travel a long time ago you got a
next-door neighbor and you can tell
because you're so close
that there's life of some kind around
the other star
around the planets around the other
stars
so it's a very exciting discovery
now the city people will tell you we
listened to those stars and we didn't
get a signal
seti really stands for silly effort to
investigate
uh to suggest that aliens are stuck at
our level of radio communication
technology we've had for about a hundred
years
is pretty silly
i don't use a slide rule anymore
uh i doubt if aliens are using our
communication technology now
but this is your target if you want to
go someplace they're only 39.3 light
years away from here
so that's in the local neighborhood now
several special things
all the stars connected by lines are
sun-like stars it's only true of five
percent of the stars in our neighborhood
is between a thousand and two thousand
stars within 55 light years we keep
finding new small stars
that's the first thing all the pattern
stars are sun-like even though five only
five percent of the stars in the
neighborhood are sunlight
and all the sun-like stars
in that very well
described hunk of space are part of the
pattern
the chance of that being a coincidence
are one in ten thousand to one in a
million
they're all in a plane the stars
connected by lines like slices of
pepperoni on a pizza big flat pizza
as opposed to raisins in a big fat loaf
of raisin bread that makes transport a
lot easier when you're in a plane the
planets in the solar system are in a
plane
amazingly
so
there you go it's a very exciting
challenging work i'm very proud to have
been the first to publish about it
i was asked to help marjorie by the head
of the aerial phenomena research
organization that's how i got involved i
met with her a couple of times three
times anyway
uh
very exciting piece of work and she's
one of the most objective people i've
ever met
now here's that question about the book
that we mentioned earlier
about the nasty supervisor
taking it away from her
here's what betty said the book seemed
to be constructed of thin stiff shiny
plastic maybe an inch thick tuck seemed
to be embedded in the plastic it was in
about six columns going down
with symbols what those symbols mean i
don't know can we decode them i doubt it
we don't have this is one of those
places where you wish dr simon had asked
for more information please you know
but he didn't
but it was something different anyway
let's get back to the comparative
analysis i did on the hypnosis tapes
where i transcribed betty's and barney's
statements and lined them up
and compared them to betty's statements
in her dream and although i have several
examples in the book
this i'm using only two examples here
due to our time constraint
but uh in betty's dream she said that
she and barney returned to the car at
the same time they stood by the side of
the car and they watched the ufo leave
then they entered the vehicle
and they
took off
well
let's go back
uh
that's not what happened on the hypnosis
tapes
in on the hypnosis tapes barney was
escorted to the car first
he was placed in the driver's seat when
he and he sat on his gun
he was sitting there wondering where
betty was and he saw her coming down the
path
betty had actually been back on the
craft arguing because she wanted to keep
that book
and she was furious
that she it had been taken away from her
she was feisty
and then the leader took her down the
path and she entered the car she picked
up her dog the leader had told her that
she could stop she could stand by the
side of the car and watch the craft
leave uh he thought it would be safe for
them to do that so then
she asked bonnie to get out of the car
and watch the craft leave which they did
so this was completely different from
the information that betty had recorded
in her dreams uh indicating that it
might have been a real experience and
not that betty had simply repeated her
dreams under hypnosis and that barney
had somehow absorbed the information in
betty's dream osmosis
and repeated it
and so after many attempts to find the
location dr simon had given a suggestion
that they would find the location
they did find it
in this area this is an aerial view
this is a dark at night
lonely road no lights
and there's now a house here
uh there wasn't then
and it's sandy and they recalled the
soil being sandy and it's the only place
around that's like this
so they're satisfied the people who live
in the house didn't know about this
being the place where this experience
had taken place incidentally
but
when you're out here as we were at night
in the dark
uh
it's a closed-in sort of place
i mean the trees are tall
they're not little scrubby things
and so
it's a unique location you can see
looking around there there aren't any
other places in the woods
uh this is not a place for spectators in
other words the guys who ran the show
knew what they were doing
this is betty standing on the site
before the house was built obviously
they went on home
you can see the distances on the map
here 37 miles to concord
from here at 17 47 miles to portsmouth
and people have said oh they got lost on
mountain roads
there aren't many roads
uh around the area there's no way
kathy tried to get lost she didn't
succeed
if they had traveled along route 3 it
would have been only 16 miles
from the field the close encounter field
to plymouth new hampshire if they had
traveled on route 175
it would have been 21 miles
there's no way to account for that two
hours of missing time
they were uh give you an idea of their
involvement in the community barney was
on the governor's civil rights
commission
uh very active in politics betty was
active in politics
they got invited to the inauguration of
lyndon johnson
january 20th 1965.
and kathy here went with them she got an
invitation too
so what the point of this is is not to
brag about that we're talking about
upstanding citizens of the community
these are not people who were looking
how can we make up a story and have a
crummy book put out and make a lot of
money this is not what we're talking
about here
these were people who had everything to
lose and nothing to gain by going public
against their will
there's barney with senator mcintyre of
new hampshire
at the inauguration
there's he's appointed to the new
hampshire state advisory committee on
civil rights commission
this is respectability
and remember those were difficult days
in the civil rights movement you may
remember the early 60s there was a lot
of
foment a lot of stuff going on
this is them in 1965 with that first
newspaper article
which started the whole ball rolling
unfortunately or not whatever you want
to say
through a violation of confidentiality
and against their will
the story is told in the book in great
detail but
there they are with delsi in 1966
they had at that point agreed to tell
the full story
and uh
john fuller had asked if he could write
the book unknown
well-known author sharp guy i've looked
at the comments there was an agreement
that dr simon would have final say on
everything
and boy was he rough on fuller the
papers are at boston university archives
in the original manuscript and
simon's comments on the manuscript
and boy he made him toe the line
well in the book i also wrote two
chapters on the psycho physics
experiments that betty agreed to
participate in with robert homan and c.d
jackson who were two employees
at ibm
robert homan was a writer and c.d
jackson was a senior engineer
and betty had agreed to do psycho psycho
physics experiments call them in
try to call them in with with some
limited success you will see
betty also went out she was trying to
vector in craft
this was
photograph taken years later after
barney's death in 1969
and we don't really know what this is
but betty found it interesting you can
see the shape here it hovered above her
vehicle this photograph is enlarged
on the original slide there appears to
be someone standing in this window
that doesn't show up well here
she also took this photograph of a fiery
orb we
don't know what that is either
and now we've come to the end and this
is our book captured the betty and
barney hill ufo