ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
hey what's up hey
yeah so oh oh
[ __ ] uh instagram blocked me because
someone's been reporting me i wonder who
i mean uh you're popular
i yeah yeah it could be any one of my my
loyal adoring fans so you know so we can
uh
yeah i mean it it's hard to to uh
um
it's definitely got the potential for
abuse
yeah i mean if
if you want to tell history you're going
to be pissing people off no matter what
you do no matter what you're talking
about no matter which subject it is
because there's always someone making
money off the subject you know
oh yeah there's people that are make
there's people that like
uh what is it the more mystery less
history
yes yes
that's like relationship advice but i
guess it comes into play with cannabis
you know it does it does i was thinking
like
even in ufos dude people go [ __ ] nuts
on each other when they don't
necessarily believe the same exact you
know thing
and and they report each other and they
get real nasty and like dox each other
and swat each other i mean everybody
likes science until it challenges their
assumptions
yeah there you go i mean it is you know
and it's rare
that
science is going to back you up on
everything that you believe
yeah yeah exactly oh wow we do have 80
people in here so that's a plus it is
like this account being much smaller
it's it's looks like it's popping up so
and it's only been a couple of minutes
so hopefully
uh more people pop on
and whatnot and i guess if if we're
interesting enough we'll have a podcast
on it or something too maybe so we'll
see yeah we'll see how it goes we'll see
how it goes
all right is there anything you wanted
to touch on early on
uh well i mean we kind of like uh we
were kind of going to have a grab bag of
things to chat about today we were going
to talk a little bit
since it kind of ties into what you and
csi have going on we were going to kind
of touch on
a little bit of hawaiian history and
what hawaiian means in general
in terms of cannabis you know yeah um
and uh you know and then we were gonna
then there was something that kind of
irritated both of us about terpenes and
some other stuff that we were gonna
[ __ ] about i think that's right i
printed this out too so so we can you
know so yeah you know um
so not too bad so maybe what we can do
we got 91 people in climbing so that's
pretty positive
yeah um so maybe what we can do is we'll
we'll keep off the the
semi-controversial stuff for a little
bit and we'll start on we'll start on
the on hawaiian right hawaii
hawaiian so uh so hawaiian is
interesting hawaii is a trippy place
because
i believe it's the farthest islands from
a continent
in the world
yeah
right
um of of one of the seven continents
it's the farthest it's the farthest
thing and so
um there are no
there's not much on hawaii that's native
yeah of any kind anything most things
are non-native to hawaii because it's
essentially a volcanic island chain in
the middle of nowhere right
um
but one of the interesting things about
hawaii hawaii is that
hawaii i believe is the only american
state that's actually in the tropics
oh yeah that would make sense so like
even even if you go down to like say um
florida like the very southern tip of
florida or the florida keys for instance
yeah those are still considered the
subtropics
yes not actual tropics yeah right what
about what about guam
you know guam is an estate
that's that's true yeah it's a territory
territory uh and i will admit that i'm
not familiar with all of america's
territories and where they may or may
not be located
yeah i only know that guam people are
called chamorin that's i learned that
because i had a friend that was from
guam and i said he was guamanian he got
real pissed but but i'll say this like
from the perspective that we're speaking
of
if you're doing something in the united
states and the 50 united states you
don't go through customs the same way as
if you're outside of it
yeah
so
um you know we've got this you know i i
don't have it but um they they're doing
some you know hawaiian lights and i have
a pretty old strain from hawaii and so
we thought we'd chat about what that
meant
so there is no wheat unlike most of what
we talk about where
mexican or colombian or panamanian or
thai or african or any of this [ __ ]
there really is no
record of marijuana in hawaii
um much before
you know
the 60s or something yeah you know um so
there's not like there wasn't really any
indigenous cultures cultivating it there
yeah right
and
so there's an aspect where
um
you know it's rumored uh and they
certainly were involved that the
brotherhood of eternal love
yeah that was one of the locations that
they used to grow cannabis um before
helicopters flew yeah and
so as a result of that a lot of the
common strains back then uh mexican
colombian that kind of thing could be
grown successfully out there yeah even
today in hawaii um most people if they
want to grow in hawaii they veg
indoors
or in greenhouses with artificial
lighting
because it's it's basically so close to
1212 there all the time that anything
that we normally grow in our in in our
stuff unless it's some kind of pure
equatorial sativa would flower
immediately upon going outside
oh wow i didn't know that
yeah i mean it's it's it's you know i
mean that's part of the reason why
equatorials take so long yeah is they
don't have any like wintertime pressure
where they have to create seed before
they die
yeah it's always kind of warm and nice
and there's not you know you take
afghanistan or hindu kush or something
like that where there's a pretty good
amount of difference between daytime and
nighttime versus summer and winter and
in the equatorial regions there's not a
big difference yeah it might be a couple
of hours
yeah right um and so you might be 12 12
or you might be 13 and 11 or you might
be 11 and 13 but you don't really vary
much beyond that little
aspect
yeah um
so hawaiian hawaiian it basically is a
catch-all term for anything
in hawaii
yeah
right yeah uh and what apparently what
used to be grown out there
was some combination of colombians
mexicans ties
and uh
um and then some of that stuff was mixed
with afghans
for structure and weight and this and
that you know and and all that type of
stuff so
um
you know when when for instance like
they were talking about you know the the
stuff that seattle greg and those guys
were getting in the 70s or 80s that they
were mixing with their afghans they were
getting hawaiian
right
but you know that was probably some
combination of colombian thai mexican uh
blended together
and or maybe mixed with afghan
yeah
is kind of is kind of that you know and
so
um hawaii used to be a pretty bomb place
to grow cannabis
uh and then the problem became is when
the helicopters started flying in the
early 80s and stuff um there's not very
much land mass in hawaii
yeah so it's not it it's not like
northern california or other areas where
they just have this vast area to search
through
yeah there's you know volcanic areas
that it's really easy to see if there's
a weed growing there's jungle areas that
are unsuitable there's only so many you
know human area human habitation areas
and so the area they have to cover is
pretty small
yeah it wouldn't be too hard to just
fly up a little bit and see there was a
big boom in the 60s and 70s of people
growing out there
and then as soon as the helicopters
started flying a lot of people got a lot
you know hawaii kind of ceased being an
export place
on any major level i'm not saying that
it wasn't some of it still didn't exist
but a lot of it moved into green houses
it moved on to the edge of jungles it
became really difficult to get off any
kind of large-scale stuff
yeah because the islands are so small so
when matt did his interview with with
greg i think was the very first breeder
syndicate interview
um
you know he talked about he thought that
the hawaiian that they were using in nl5
was some blend of
mexican and colombian
yeah
was his was his
take on it yeah that was his take some
kind of mexican colombian which would
have been uh pretty common because that
would have been two of the main imports
seeded weed imports that were coming
into america at the time
yeah
right
um and uh you know and so i have a small
tie to uh to hawaiian not that i lived
there or anything like that because i
never did but
um one of the strains that i still have
is we call it the maui
and of all places i met a guy from maui
in the in 94 in amsterdam who would come
out there to
trade seeds with some of the breeders
out there
and we shared a joint and stuff like
that and i was with some friends and he
gave us a small handful of seeds
and uh one of them became the mount
so they have truck stops in
hawaii is what you're saying
so or i mean amsterdam i mean so they uh
they i mean they have a whole district
district you know they don't even have
they don't even call it they just they
just it's very much more open there so
um and so being 19 or whatever the [ __ ]
i was i asked zero intelligent questions
of this man
uh i thought he was a super old timer
which he was probably about my age he
was probably mid-forties but to 19 year
old
yeah he seemed a grizzled veteran yeah
i'm sure you know
and that trip i spent thousands of
dollars on seeds uh and the only thing
that i ended up keeping was this female
from a handful of seeds that he gave me
when we shared a joint
wow
it was pretty good about the dutch stuff
out of all the dutch
that particular trip uh which was was
one it was my it was actually my first
trip to amsterdam believe it or not in
94. um that particular trip
um i didn't find anything that was a
keeper amongst the stuff that i bought
initially do you remember what you
bought i bought all kinds of [ __ ] yeah i
bought nlf i i went to scentsy
in 94 and i bought an l5 haze
i bought nl5 skunk one
uh i bought um
super skunk
yeah um
from them
um you know i bought some uh
you know i i
i think i bought some bubble gum that
year
yeah um i bought i bought a a random i
bought some stuff from maybe dutch
passion
anyway i was stupid um and instead of
buying well i was 19 right so instead of
buying like three or four things and
buying like you know 50 seeds of each
thing yeah i bought like 15 or 18 things
and like one or two packs of each yeah
right so then you like crack a pack and
it's 10 seeds and you get four females
and you don't like any of them yeah and
i was that wasn't at the era i was so
young then that wasn't at the era where
we were like keeping males or breeding
or anything like that right
um so that's the other thing too is i
got that maui and we tossed all the
males because they were [ __ ] useless
right what are we gonna do with those
you know um
but uh but so hawaiian hawaiian is
definitely
you know in that it's kind of it's in
the lexicon right and you know someone
just said oh maui wowie uh maui wowie
was is kind of like
madness [ __ ] or this or that or
whatever it's a catch-all term
it was
it was originally
made by a guy named fast eddie from the
brotherhood of eternal love so there
really was a maui wowie at one time
unlike madness [ __ ] we can't
trace it to one person but that one we
can but what has become maui wowie i
think most of what we see is maui wowie
are mostly afghan dominant types
um you know they used to uh they used to
ship
uh some of that stuff in macadamia nuts
oh wow they did they used to ship it to
the states they used to hide it in the
center of macadamia nut tins yeah that's
funny and stuff like that and so
you know hawaiian was sort of a was sort
of a catch-all phrase there is no
indigenous hawaiian
yeah right it was all basically
entrepreneurs
bringing other indigenous weed to hawaii
and trying to figure out how to get
worthwhile buds
is basically what it boiled down to
um and uh you know what's interesting
about like the the hawaiian that i have
the what we call them and the only
reason why we call it the maui
is because i was dumb and i didn't ask
any [ __ ] questions so
uh the only thing that we knew was the
dude was from maui
yeah
um but that's it right i met fast eddie
i doubt you met you met fast eddie um
because uh the fast daddy that you
probably met was a very famous dude from
dead tour
uh
who is part of the wrecking crew
uh maybe you met fast betty from the
brotherhood of eternal love but around
but yeah i've never been able to get a
hold of him i've tried a lot but the
fact the fast eddy that most people are
familiar with um is from the wrecking
crew he was he was a pretty famous uh
person on he goes yeah that guy it was
it was a pretty famous dude on deadlot
if you went to dead tour uh on any level
um you probably heard him be like dow
says he had the deepest voice dow says
he would scream at little kids and stuff
and they were all drunk and they were
just a mess but anyway
um
so there's an aspect where
uh you know so that's hawaiian hawaiian
is anything that got brought to hawaii
and got grown there
yeah basically right yeah um and then it
just gets the name hawaiian and just
like a lot of like we've talked about
this before but just like a lot of stuff
where it obscures like we give nicknames
to things and it obscures the origin of
where it came from yeah that's what
hawaiian did you know seattle grey got
hawaiian
which isn't very helpful
did he get pure mexican pure colombian a
blend a blend with afghan
he didn't know
yeah they they said they could tell was
after mexican colombian because that's
the best being hotel was mexican
colombia you know and so
you know um
and so that's what got blended in and
back then uh especially you know nobody
knew that all this stuff was gonna be
famous and lineage and all that was
gonna get poured over and be super
important right yeah and notes were a
bad thing
so it is like saying oh i got the
californian yeah there was a california
indica that made it around amsterdam i
got the california you know it's about
it like gives you an idea of where the
area was from
right
and so
um you know what's interesting is that
being that i'm not from hawaii and i
don't really have any ties there um
i do have we i do have some good friends
that grew up on the island on various
islands and grown there their whole life
yeah and when i showed them um pictures
and flowers of uh my maui cut they did
say that there was that wasn't that
uncommon of a phenotype that they had
seen in the past in hawaiian that they
had grown from the past
yeah you know um so hawaii is sort of
like a catch-all from people get stuff
you know i mean like like there was even
a thing we were talking about a couple
episodes ago during the chem dog episode
where
um there's a maui
yeah why is it called maui dog because
someone got a supposedly a dog bud seed
and took it to maui
yeah popped it on maui and now it's maui
dog you know so the interesting thing
there's some pictures of maui on my page
it's really interesting it's huge it's
chunky
uh it's pretty short it's got a bunch of
afghan influence but if you look at it
uh the leaves are incredibly skinny and
double serrated
yeah
there's that
uh
is my audio kicking out ooh
it's just on my back off from your
video
kinda i mean we can hear you but it's
just off from your speaking you look
like you're in a kung fu movie i look
like i'm on a kung fu is it better now
no but it'll work it'll work so sorry
that uh sorry that it's ad-libbed or
whatever like i'm i'm dubbed
uh hopefully that changes but um
but yeah so my maui
uh is you know csi is always looking to
um do things that match right and so in
addition to my headband you know i've
shared a bunch of stuff with him in the
hopes that he would breed it uh and it
would get out to a wider audience a bit
and um one of the things that's going to
get dropped with matt and and csi is
um
my maui by the hawaiian lights i think
it's i don't know if that one or maui by
nl5 it might be just be it might be maui
yeah but anyway he used it so
um you know and so there's an aspect too
where it's like
you know uh it's it's been out there
before there's a cut from uh mandelbrot
called the truth
which is uh maui by superdog that i made
20 plus years ago or something like that
um so it's percolated around and it's
kind of been a mendo it's been a
mendocino county classic
because it's uh probably not now with
the way the market is but for a long
time it was one of those cuts that you
could put outside reliably get four or
five pounds off it and it would be done
in the middle of october yeah
you know decent that's very decent and
it's pretty i remember i remember seeing
pictures of it i've never uh i don't
think i've ever smoked maui but i've
never seen pictures of it and thinking
it was absolutely gorgeous especially
for an outdoor plant yeah and it turns
purple in the cold you know and stuff
like that and it's obviously some kind
of sativa afghan blend because if you
look at the buds and the density and how
quick it finishes it's got a heavy
afghan you know but its leaves are like
that's i mean it's like super skinny
leaves they don't even fatten really
they're just like consistently skinny
the whole way down and they've got a
bunch of double serrations
what's it smell like
um
you know it smells kind of
it smell i mean it's one of those ones
where when i asked oh god let's not do
that yet because i'll get all irritated
uh it
it's one of those ones where i've asked
trimmers for years and years what it
smells like yeah
and you get ranges from my favorite is
uh you know wrigley uh wrigley fruity
gum
that's a good smell you know um it's got
a super distinctive smell and i will say
jokingly that it's uh i joke that it's
like my longest female relationship
because
we popped that seed in 1994
yeah and i still have it
so she's
uh
28 years this year
28. yeah [ __ ] old yeah that's really
old it's [ __ ] old and so i've had her
literally i
she was the next to the crystal chunk
um she was the second weed that i ever
really started religiously cropping
yeah um and if you're in indiana or
chicago or illinois area and you ever
smoked the maui it's very likely it's
the same cut
because that's where we cropped it first
and a bunch of friends um grew it out
there and probably still grow it here
and there you know yeah it's not elite
by today's standards in terms of like
the high but it's probably it's kind of
good high
but it's it's not up there with the best
of the best in my opinion you know but
yeah it's got a bunch of amazing
qualities and it it's um
you know it breeds really well for for
color and frost and structure and all
that type of stuff
um it's really consistent and
uh it'll probably be another show but it
is blended into some very famous stuff
you know that we won't dive into um
but
uh all i know is uh all i know is um
where it's from yeah that's the totality
that's how it goes it was from an old
dude on maui they've been growing there
for a long time and he basically said he
grew things and acclimated him there and
he came over to amsterdam to trade seeds
with friends
yeah and he would bring stuff back and
mix it into his lines and
so he said it was an afghan that
finished quick and yielded well and was
rot resistant and you could see the
you know you could see the the sativa in
it and so
i have pretty high hopes uh that csi
will blend into a few different things
um because it's such a stable breeder
and the other part about it that i
really like is that when any time you
get anything that's that old
its lineage ties to something completely
different than what's a mishmash of
today
yeah that's true anything from the mid
90s doesn't really have any of the most
famous 40 or 50 cuts that we usually
talk about that's in it
yeah so a lot of times when you're
breeding you get the best results when
you start breeding things that are kind
of unlike each other and not too related
um so it's not related to chem or kush
or this or that or da da da da da da da
you know and so it hasn't been overused
and over blended
um
you know and so there's uh matt sent me
a a thing this morning um about all the
um
i'm sorry i started reading stuff and
got distracted but you know we could one
day do i we have some good friends that
probably uh
would be a a lot better experts on like
hawaiian growing culture and famous
strains and stuff like that i don't
really feel
it's like my place to like lead a kind
of discussion like that it's not an area
where my knowledge goes hella deep
yeah i couldn't talk on molokai frost
like people are asking or quite electric
i couldn't talk on any of that yeah i
mean you know i've heard plenty of
stories secondhand i've had you know i
know a bunch of growers uh from over
there and stuff like that over the years
um
you know but you know that we could do a
whole episode
uh where people could ask questions
um you know but i we did think it was
worth mentioning we did think it was
cool to talk about because hawaiian is
sort of getting like brought back in
because of this interest in the nl and
the nl5 and what greg was doing and
and you know maybe maybe there's an
aspect of like talking about what
hawaiian was
yeah yeah was beneficial
so
you know hawaiian is is sort of and like
what hawaiian was
isn't what hawaiian is
that's correct yeah because what
hawaiian was back then might have been a
mix of colombian and mexican and some
afghans and stuff that the brotherhood
of eternal love was doing
but hawaii now
is just another place that clones get
sent
right so it's got cherry pie and it's
got skunks and it's got this and it's
got chems and da da da da and you know
so on and so on and whatnot um yeah it
is a cool place in the sense that
there's uh
you know it's super humid there
and um
it's a totally different environment
and so you have to find things that do
well in that environment
yeah you know what i that would be a
good idea maybe we could have pacololo
in paradise on and yeah that's why i
just want to talk about it we have some
resources and some friends that would be
far more educated uh because that's
their neck of the woods yeah to talk
about that kind of stuff than we would
be i just wanted to bring it up in the
sense that we've been getting a bunch of
questions about hawaiian
and hawaiian lights and
what's your maui and stuff like that and
you know maui is one of those ones where
i even lost it uh sadly for a number of
years due to some unfortunate
circumstances
um but because it was a classic grown by
old timers around my area in mendo
um it it lift
yeah because like i said you know there
was you know in in an era where like
weed was weed to some degree um
you know a four to six pound reliable
plant that was done in the middle of
october was pretty beneficial
yeah so it was kind of one of those
things i brought i brought it out
in 98 or whatever yeah and started
spreading it around
and it's kind of percolated around our
area off and on since then and it's
still around there yeah uh yeah i mean i
still have it i live here
uh there's a few friends that have it uh
it's certainly probably under pressure
with how few strains sell currently
you know and how rough the market has
become and how how low the market has
become recently
um but it definitely still exists
um i gave it to like i said i gave it to
csi
um
to breed with
you know
and preserve help preserve you know it's
always it's always risky
when you're trying to save things you
have to find people that have an
interest in stuff that were willing to
hold on to it yeah
right because there could be a fire
there could be an accident there could
be a bus there could be any number of
different things
um people are talking about what's aloha
white widow i don't really know much
about aloha
except for amsterdam except for it was
white widow from amsterdam popped on in
hawaii
aloha seeds was from amsterdam
from amsterdam yeah they were a dutch
company and they they made it
and they just called it aloha white
widow so everybody assumed it was you
know a hawaiian white widow
see there you go i even assumed yeah
yeah i just assumed that it was a it was
another one of those things where
you're in um
you know you're in it's it was just one
of those things where it's like oh it's
from hawaii let's add hawaii i actually
called aloha seed bank in amsterdam
god when i first heard about the
strength because i wanted to see if i
could still source it at the time um
yeah they wouldn't even talk about what
was in it or any of that but yeah it was
it was their their seed line they
weren't they just weren't interested in
selling it anymore so it's sort of one
of those things where uh soma decided to
call a line new york city diesel exactly
and it's not sour diesel but we'll call
it diesel because it was the first you
know
yeah um
so who knows who knows i was mistaken
right there i didn't actually know it's
back history i've never personally grown
it you know
um
so so
i think probably like 99 of people had
no clue that it was aloha seats
amsterdam um it's just it's just how
it's always gone everybody was a
aloha widow of course it would be and
that's that's one of the things that
matt and i always talk about where it's
like you can make misleading statements
and not outright lie
and then people will just assume
yeah
exactly
these genetics are authentic
by the way i i was super stoked a long
time ago i made a joke about how you
could rename blueberry or blue dream and
call it blueberry [ __ ] yum yum and
someone would probably buy it i just
today saw a string called blueberry yum
yum taken off oh man damn hot damn
called it
oh somebody's talking about ncga
rock 10 rock
you know so yeah i mean there's the the
the name game and then creating
assumptions based on that yeah um you
know i mean
20 years ago if something was
was named after some kind of smell or
aroma or whatever it probably had some
kind of distinctive
remembrance of that yeah uh now it's it
has no connection to it
you know is it a ludicrous song i call i
pull blueberry yum yum out my ass but
god damn it's hard being original
i wouldn't have known that it's very
hard being original
so
yeah i mean there's there's aspects
where
you know hawaiian um
uh you know it's probably going to
remain a mystery and when any time
anytime you have like a mystery right
that's hard to be proven
you're going to get people that are
going to claim that they have knowledge
yeah and they have facts behind the
rumor and it's like oh well you might
not have had the hawaiian that went to
greg but we did
yeah that was my uncle
yeah yeah
that was my dad that was my uncle that
was my that was my dad's best friend
that was my you know my aunt's you know
my my aunt's boyfriend whoever you know
because you can't really refute it and
that's really popular in cannabis
um is
being able to not refute things well i
mean you saw just just in this episode
just in this
20 minutes or whatever that we've been
live you saw one person come in here
ask for an opinion because they weren't
sure and then flip out because it was
counter to what they wanted to hear
i missed that part
i'm not very good at patting my head and
rubbing my stomach so i ignore a lot of
the comments not because they're not
valuable but because i i have a hard
time like
bullshitting
uh and reading at the same time yeah you
know my brain
my brain was in here repeatedly asking
about someone non-stop
and then asked about someone that
referred him to that person um someone
from virginia that dude so i was just
like dude stop yeah i mean i don't know
there's and there's aspects too where
it's like sometimes people make a really
good assumption that like this is old
enough and this is mysterious enough
that it'll never be outed oh yeah yeah i
think most of them that do it think that
i think that it's old enough and it's in
the past enough and it's i mean we even
saw when i won't even mention their name
but we did this that we outed somebody a
few years ago
um that consistently had he was a
younger cat and he consistently had
strains that were from one to two years
before they were ever released yeah and
you could just tell that they were just
hunting on the forums for early info
yeah and then they figured they'd they'd
ratchet it back for a week a year or two
and then they didn't realize that there
was people that were actually alive and
in cannabis then
yeah you know
um yeah yeah he didn't even that dude
didn't even go look at the catalogs to
see if he could get the you're right
he's just like [ __ ] it
we won't even talk about that but when i
first saw him on instagram i thought
that dude was like in his 50s
he would have had to have been and then
i figured and then i figured out he was
like 27 and i was like what in the [ __ ]
you know no yeah
so you know and yeah there's a thing i
mean there's multiple people that that
have claimed um you know that have
claimed connection to various seed banks
or various people or various this or
that and
you know uh one of the cool things about
the internet is that it's linked a bunch
of us
yeah and so you get a chance to you know
you get a chance to ask those people
and then they're like hell no
yeah
you know and uh
you know and so
you know there's uh yeah it's go hey
someone picked it up skunk 18 fam uncle
fester skunk 18. uh nature fraud
i noticed someone mentioned about the uh
seats being federally legal and i at
first i was like what
first that's from a source like a single
source and i'm not 100 sure on what they
posted but if if um cannabis seeds were
to be classified as hemp seeds you'd
still need a hemp license you need a
seed distribution license and you'd only
be distributing in your state so no i
think you can send it i think you can
send it out of state but i think the
issue is is that you can't just be like
i'm going to send my buddy in florida a
bunch of seeds and write
hemp and we're good no you have to have
there has to be legitimate companies in
both states
because
hemp is legally registered in the state
of california as a california hemp seed
company yes and you'd have to send it to
a registered i use is that how it works
you'd have to be in the market for them
to see
is hemp was put in the farm bill
yeah so it's um it's legal in all 50
states yes it's not a state it's not a
state by state thing and there's even
there's even hemp transports where you
can transport legal hemp clones from one
state to another
interesting but you
still to this day after working at the
hemp farm i know that they cannot buy
anything not licensed to be sold in
california by a hemp register sure that
might be a different so yes technically
it's legal but there's but
it's still like you have to have two
hemp businesses it has to be a
legitimate sale between hemp businesses
it's not like i'm gonna send a bunch of
hemp seeds legally
we haven't gotten to the point where
it's like tomato seeds or something like
that where it's just like enthusiasts
can just trade whatever the [ __ ] they
want yeah i mean i i just ran through
this and experienced it with uh the
california hemp laws and like register
trying to register to be a breeder of
hemp and stuff like you have to do go
through so many [ __ ] hoops maybe
that's just california too
but you have to go through so many hoops
to be able to grow
hemp in california for sure yeah i mean
i'm sure i'm sure states state by state
they can put their own regulations on it
yeah but i don't believe that any state
can make hempi legal because it's a
federally federally legal on the farm
bill it's just it's not illegal but it's
heavily regulated
and i think what happened is is that all
these people in all these different
states jumped into hemp and there wasn't
a pipeline
for that much cbd or cbg or
hemp products yet
yeah people are saying
that um like costco doesn't have a
license no but they're selling hemp
that's been treated with heat that's a
whole another different kind of license
everything else once it's been treated
with heat it's unviable so of course
they can sell that
yeah i mean that's that's been around
forever but yes it has
so i don't know i mean
there's uh but yeah there's there's been
i mean that's one of the one of the
reoccurring frauds
in cannabis is just
like you know since new people are in
every five or ten years you can recycle
the same garbage over and over again you
know
and then people get all mad and they
start coming on and defending themselves
and then the people that told the lie
first they start to change aspects of it
because they realize they've been outed
you know and they have to shift what it
is you know
um and it's just one of those it's just
one of those areas that's like right for
[ __ ] yeah you know
um and so maybe maybe i should
maybe i should do like i never do a plug
on here but maybe i should do like a
plug right yeah so
uh anytime you see
like
quote unquote my headband cut or like
when i just talked about the maui or
anything like that like
my entire intention for spreading
genetics is for people to have good weed
yeah so
um
you know i uh
i don't um
i don't
i'm not making anything off of uh
off of can't off off these things i'm
not profiting in any way i'm not trying
to jump into the seed game i've had a
bunch of friends trying me to
trying to get me to uh one of them is on
is your is on your screen right now
um but uh i've resisted you know um and
it's nothing it's nothing against people
that make seed for money or anything
like that because obviously i have a
bunch of friends that do so
um but
like part of passing out uh you know
clones and stuff like that to good
friends uh and especially csi is that
he's got enough of a matt and csi and
others have enough of a customer base
that you can get good stuff out there
that's different
yeah and one of the ways that like you
know i've said it before but um probably
the person that probably the person that
did the biggest
guarantee that my mendo perps will never
disappear from the community is caleb
yeah because he fell in love with it and
he
grew he crossed it to a [ __ ] ton
of different things and enough people
bought that that even if the mom was to
terribly get lost her children and
grandchildren are freaking everywhere
yeah and so that's really if you want to
talk about legacy with seeds um or
anything else you know anytime anything
gets popular like all of a sudden you
know caleb releases um some ella some
chem d and and l.a
and some and some tk in la right um that
he reversed and people are finding
amazing things in it and now for the
first time ever all of a sudden you
start to see clone sellers popping up
with the cut
you know
um and you start to see
freaking uh and you start to see
um
you know people popping up with with you
know crosses that have it you know
and all that different types of [ __ ] and
so
you know it's just one of the things
that goes along with popularity
yeah you could probably go back six
months and before or a year before i
started talking about it and nobody has
it yeah nobody was ever talking about
the la kush headband before
we started talking about it so nobody
was mentioning it nobody was mentioning
it i mean not that it hadn't existed
before and not that it didn't exist with
mandel brought seeds 15 years ago or
something like that but in the last five
or six years it was it was nowhere yeah
right and so and and now all of a sudden
and really it only got my name i didn't
even want it to have my name
um people were just trying to
differentiate like how what to call what
headband yeah and so they attached it to
it so it's like people always assume
that i'm getting some royalty or i'm
getting some kind of um you know aspect
or i'm getting cuts or you know payback
or whatever and or they're assuming also
sometimes that you verified said cut
yeah but i verified it and that's why it
has it and so
you know there's an aspect to it where
it's like the only reason why i passed
it out to a few good friends is just to
hopefully have people that uh get weed
that i like a whole bunch
yeah and get that into some hybrids
that's really it just so everybody knows
you know so if you start seeing you know
people pop up on clone traders and this
and that and everything else it's not
like i'm the only person on earth that
has it but it's very very small circle
and it's most likely a scam
yeah at this point you know if it
becomes incredibly popular like
everything else it'll probably leak
and there'll be some you know but
i mean it's really just oh somebody
somebody's finding a bunch of fire i
have that yeah you want it it's 400
bucks
oh i'm breeding with that i got seeds of
it already
i got that yep
and that's the seed name game you know
this is name game and that's it's as far
back as like as people in amsterdam not
wanting to give out lineage just so
their competitors would all copy that
lineage instantaneously yeah
so you know just for clarification on
that like it it it's not and there's
nothing wrong with selling seeds or this
or that or whatever else but it's like
my entire breeding has like not been
that's not been i bred for because i
like good weed
yeah
you know um and i think it makes some
people mad that they can't attack me for
[ __ ] them over or like or breeding
hermes [ __ ] or this or that whatever you
know and and really when it comes down
to it too is like you know a bunch of
our friends have been talking to talking
about it and it's like if this seed
crash leads to a financial crash for a
bunch of people
it might go back to a small handful of
enthusiasts making seats
and it will be i i really think it will
be yeah because 95 of the people has you
know have gotten into seed breeding in
the last five or six years
with the intention that it could be
another revenue stream and it could get
their name out there and it could get
this and that and
part of the reason why so much stuff
today comes from so few breeders from 20
years ago is because nobody bothered to
breed
yeah it wasn't all that common
yeah because it was there wasn't money
in it yeah there wasn't a lot of money
in it
people think there's a lot of money in
it now but there's only a few people
making a lot of money
yeah there's only a few people and
there's and you know and so there was a
minute there in ig where people could
sell seeds and make their own private
hybrids and like sell them to their
followers and all that and that seems to
be collapsing a little bit right now
yeah um so we'll see in two or three
years how many of those people really
love making seeds and care about
breeding and which ones it was just
another avenue
yeah for revenue
and not that there's anything wrong with
revenue you know nothing wrong i
i have seen a massive
the one thing i mean whether people hate
me are like me i haven't gone away and
i've seen a massive overturn since i've
gotten here and i'm i'm expecting a
super massive overturn because i mean
just in the past five years you know
thousands of people making seats trying
to sell it has popped up and that's
going to get a lot harder that's the
problem too is that since most people
started recently
you know they're grabbing what they have
available to them that's recent
so all this breeding is like all the
same five or six you know five or six
years of the most recent most famous
stuff
yeah and i uh i don't think that you're
going to find anything magically
different
crossing cherry pie and kush
no
i think that people have tried that
yeah over and over and over and over and
over
and you know and you're probably not
going to find anything new using
cushmits
no and i'm not even dissing those
strains don't get me wrong i'm not i'm
just saying nothing's unique
to today everybody sneak from it
you know yeah i mean there was there's a
guy commenting there was a bunch of
people that had
the surprising thing about about the
head my headband cut is not that it's
mine or whatever because i didn't make
it or anything but
that
most people won't hold on to anything
unless it's making them money right now
yeah
so there's an enormous amount of stuff
like uh you know 15 years ago i knew
dozens and dozens of growers that had
urkel and grape ape and gdp
and green crack even yeah and green
crack and then as soon as the market
changed
six people kept it
yeah there was a bunch of people that
had headband 15 years ago
you know or sours you know yeah i mean i
even had a friend call me the other day
uh who's lifelong resident of
southern humboldt
and they're looking for sour cuts
yeah because in the last two or three
years everybody
has been um
popping all you know working with all
this candy and all this dessert and all
this purple and all this stuff and now
people are starting to ask for it again
and nobody kept it
it's not like it doesn't exist they'll
be able to get it back again eventually
but maybe they don't get back the same
one
yeah that's that's that's a big deal
that's why a lot of people don't have
vertical like you said oracle was one of
the most grown things up there everybody
that had more than ten lights in mendo
was growing urkel or grape ape or
something like that mendopa they were
all growing purples yeah
you know um and uh you know and then you
know when sauer and kush came in
um
everybody dropped it yep when cookies
came in a bunch of people dropped sours
when this came in a bunch of people
dropped that
and i do think there's going to be a
renaissance of some of those strains
because they're better in my opinion
than a lot of the modern cuts
absolutely
they'll come back they taste better they
work better they're longer lasting they
have more unique eyes
you know that type of thing so i think
they will make a comeback
um you know uh but
you know there's i mean
the my sour that i have i've had this
sour since the very early 2000s i don't
know which one it is
yeah um but it's not most of the one
i've collected a whole bunch of them
um and it's not most of them
yeah i haven't found one i haven't found
one i kept hoping i'm like oh maybe it's
the choco maybe it's the amish maybe
it's the joe b maybe it's the
uh ecsd maybe it's the nycd maybe it's
the
you know
yeah um
and it's really hard is you really can't
tell diesels apart by pictures
no no no they all tend to look super
skunky you really have to grow them side
by side and you really have to kind of
smoke them if you want to pick out
differences yeah
you know
so um you know what i know about my sour
is that it's old and that we kept it
and that's about it you know the
headband got renamed sour by a bunch of
people um it got
and you know it got tossed around but it
was a little bit more finicky than
regular sour and it could freak out on
you sometimes so a lot of people got rid
of it because it wasn't as easy as the
other ones
yeah you know and and then people get
rid of their cut
and one thing that i've learned is that
if i would have lost my sour cut even
though i have six or seven other
different ones right now
um
it none of them are that one
yeah and there's a bunch of people that
always talk about you know i tried to
get back that thing that i had
and i can't find the sour diesel cut or
the blue dream cut or the gdp cut like
or the trinity i can't get it back
it's like this one's good
but it's not um but it's not it's not
what it is
i um dookie made a good comment he said
the skunk search should start in a sour
s1 and i i agree but i think
the places i saw it the most were when
you cross two
different expressions of super skunk was
where i was seeing it just constantly
pop up i thought that was but i think
that you can probably find that miss our
s1
it's just you can't make them the
problem is with sour s1s is that like it
fails or you get like 20 seats exactly
that's why that's why i even went with
crossing two super skunks that are that
are different expressions like a sour
and a diesel but i do agree with them i
think that
diesels are modern skunk
yes i think it's one of the most classic
examples of a modern skunk oi type plant
that we have
yeah
diesels are modern skunk and the good
thing about the diesels
is that unlike a lot of other things
where you could be like oh that one's
fake or whatever
most of the diesels are pretty [ __ ]
nice man
yeah they burn good they smoke good they
have you know they range in gassy to
more headband aromas stuff like that but
grown well taken long enough dried right
they they work you know um they work
they're good you know so it's one of my
favorite families
so you know there's probably like at
this point from my experimentation
there's at least 10 or 12 cuts that are
all different from each other that
circulate
yeah of course everyone wants to be like
oh mine's the oldest mine's the original
mine's the one you remember
that's why you should pay x amount for
it
yeah in clone form or in weed form
because it i can try it take take it
back right to 95. you don't know the
bros that i know
most of those people haven't been
growing since i mean whatever you know i
just i i know in the sense that that
it's like then it becomes
you know that's really what it becomes
it becomes a marketing gig uh but
luckily um
you know
uh they a lot of them still exist and
they're most of them are all good
there's only one or two that i didn't
like very much yeah i liked i liked
um uh your growth the amish i never
tried it before that oh that was that
those couple years that i brought it to
the party it was fire it was due to all
the diesels you grew were flavorful they
all had that mouth coating thing in
common but they were all super flavorful
outdoor i never really had much diesel
outdoor that was good and that year it
wasn't it wasn't straight outdoor it was
greenhouse so i had a little bit more
control
it was sun grown it was sunny downgraded
i'm an indoor grower so anything that's
not [ __ ] pure indoor to me is outdoor
i mean somebody mentioned somebody
mentioned i'll bring it up somebody
mentioned pips ecsd yeah um you know pip
gave me his ecsd to try
uh as one of my like which one of these
sours is my sour and it wasn't my sour
it's one that i liked a whole bunch and
when he came out to the party that year
um he was like dude i've only grown it
this good once or twice
yeah
you know and i mean some of that's
probably i did a nice job on the growing
it but uh you know sun's real nice light
yeah dude
i love the sun the sun is a great light
so if you get good weather with the sun
and you get warm nice days that go into
late october early november and you can
take that sour late
most people with sour the problem that
became was sour up here is that
as soon as it got the nose people would
cut it
yeah
and it probably needed another 10 days
to two weeks
and it's real easy for it to go from
being a good nose when you cut it to
turning complete boof once you try to
[ __ ]
cure it i've seen sour go bad so many
times just in the cure people are asking
what ajs is you know i i don't i mean i
know aj a little bit but
um
you know what aj's was what aj's was in
the late 90s and early 2000s
does not seem to be the same thing that
he has currently as aj's yeah
i'll say that
um and it's not you know and there's
even times where i people are talking
about like oh there's like like names
i've never heard of
yeah right like oh now there's the real
sour
now there's that albany sour yeah
yeah now now there's names that like
never even existed during the forum days
or anything like that but there's new
terms that are popping up the real deal
yeah and that people will be like i'm
convinced that this real deal sour is
your headband
yeah and i'm like i don't know how would
i know how the [ __ ] would you know how
would i how would you know you know like
how would you know
you could give it to me and i'll try it
i suppose or whatever but it's like it's
not i i can't tell you you know
um but like i said luckily
most of these cuts of diesel cuts are
real nice
yeah most of them get you nice and high
most of them burn well
um
you know uh
yeah i mean amherst sour diesel
right
[ __ ] i mean he's passed now but
mandelbrot made that up
yeah that was my sour diesel that i gave
to him that he crossed into a bunch of
stuff and he just decided that it was
from amherst and added amherst to it
because that's what he thought
i didn't get it from amherst
you know
so
but it gets sticks yeah albany real the
real sour
that's not a that's not a leading
statement right do you have to try to
convince people the origins which one is
it oh the real one the real one original
one
yeah the original original the real
original real
verified
you know actually sour diesel i'm still
actually
yeah and some of them you know it seems
like the choco cut is the same thing as
the ecsd yeah but these names are so
it's kind of like kush the names get so
interchangeable
that one piece one person's diablo og
could be another person's sfe
yeah
you know
um and and all that you know so
um
you know and and really like when i got
my sour cut uh it came helpfully labeled
sour d
yeah it didn't have any moniker on it
and then i never got i never got aj's or
reza's or choco or ecsd because i
already had the diesel what what is a
plant spanker sour i've never heard of
her never heard of her okay keep going
you know and so so yeah people people
get people get stuff that gets attached
to it
yeah you know whose is it oh it comes
from this dude so it's his who is it oh
it's this well you know amish got named
it because it came out of pennsylvania
and there's a bunch of amish
and that one was from shroomie and it's
also called shroomies diesel too so
called shroomies diesel yeah you know
um and so there's you know there's
there's a lot of stuff like that where
nicknames get added and subtracted i
don't know what the real deal sour is
i don't know what the albany sour is but
it's like as as more of the story comes
out i would assume that like albany is
just
trying to tie it to manny and
some of the original sour people
yeah and you know what's funny is like
we know the term from bondo that they
called the sour that they all prefer the
manny and we don't really mention that
much but i guarantee
that someone's gonna pop up with that
[ __ ] manny in two weeks or a
week
you know
you know yeah and i i mean there's
and you know and and so sometimes one of
those things just like
just just like the the dog isn't really
you know it's not really you know skunk
va's dog
yeah but he gets on the forums and he's
the first guy talking about it and which
cut is it oh it's the skunk vaca
yeah you know oh it's not so's headband
yeah because you're trying to figure out
some kind of language
to chat about it it's matt riot's
12-inch [ __ ] i get that all the time i
just just because i
was yeah that's just the difference
between our our measurements and metro
and metric you know
people getting inches inches and
centimeters you know totally confused
totally confused inches and centimeters
but
but yeah you know and no i mean someone
just said hey for the preservation i'm
not even dissing i've known uh skunk va
sin for 20 20 plus years i'm not dissing
him that's that's not my intention
whatsoever i'm just yeah he didn't
attach his name to it it was it was
actually uh caleb who attached his
attached skunky's name to it
because that was the source that it came
from yeah and it's like so you know
which head you know which headband
you know uh not so headband
you know uh
yeah i hate that one oh my god i don't
even use i don't even i don't even like
that word hate but i really despise the
murder and like the funny thing is like
the 56 day that's what it was told to me
when i got it no six but it's not 56
it's more like nine weeks or ten weeks
at least somebody just said sun
simulator had something to do with since
any later had nothing to do with the
creation of diesel but he did make some
nice diesel hybrids later on i do agree
with that he did a cool strawberry
diesel
yeah lumpa headband lumpa headband is
most likely a og kush s1 bag seed and in
that case luffa did name that
[ __ ] after himself and he did he
did have an ego boost and name it after
himself that was intentional but
sometimes it's not intentional skunk va
he didn't intend on it and actually kem
dog got a little hyphy about it
because it was like technically his gut
yeah all of a sudden people are calling
it skunk fiesta yeah you know i'm kind
of embarrassed about my you know not so
headband because
um you know i don't really attach myself
to stuff like that yeah
you know i didn't name it not so's mendo
perps
yeah you know or anything like that like
you know i guess you gotta have depends
on whether or not you want to have a an
ego attachment to it yeah you know but
really when it comes down to it when you
get back to breeding all the stupid
names all the attachments all the all
that everything else the only thing that
people are gonna remember is if it's
good weed
yeah
so you are my phone my phone's getting
down to like 10 so let's cover some of
that real quick
all right so there's this thing going
around right now that really irritates
the piss out of me and um there's uh
you know they've been pushing all this
stuff with the emerald cup judging
and all that and sc labs has come out
with this new classification
and they're trying to get rid of using
sativa and
indica which that's a different
discussion yeah i agree i agree
that we that there could be better terms
there could be better terminology
applied to that what they want to
replace it to
um is they and what they're using for
the emerald cup this year is the most
ridiculous [ __ ] i've ever seen yeah
and the reason why is because they have
six categories and i'll try to do them
off of memory
um but
it's
haze jack and hayes
yeah
and it's um this probably won't be an
order
og and gas
yep sweet dreams
sweets and dreams sweet and dreams
desserts
exotics
uh what's the final one tropical and
floral tropical and floral right which
are two different and so like that's the
most ridiculous smell and terpene
classifications i've ever heard in my
life exotics what is exactly what's
exotic
i mean do they go off the exotic mic
definition of exotics where runts isn't
exotic well i mean just exotic is like
exotic is something that's unusual to
you
yeah exactly that's all exotics i'd be
like like you know maybe some southeast
asians i would consider exotics or some
wild africans but if you live there it's
not exotic it's common exactly so how
cool this might be
over there what is sweets and dreams
sweets and dreams is the one that makes
them like no sense to me
and then you know like and then there's
an aspect of okay so you've got sweets
plus dreams
and then you've got
desserts
now i guess cookies has a marketing
campaign where everything they name is
dessert based yeah so they get their
whole so they have all these and they
have sherbet and they have flan and they
have [ __ ] this and that [ __ ] and
whatever
none of it tastes like the specific
dessert
exactly it's just they have a theme
yeah right uh i will say that cookies
the original thin mint uh which they
can't say anymore because uh girl scouts
sued them um but
it did have kind of a doughy flavor
yeah i don't get that from any of it all
i taste is og but i know people do do
get that from it so it's it's also like
how you smell how you taste yeah
different things i mean i can at least
okay it's got some kind of doughy type
aroma to it you know that some people
but what is exotics but it was neither
thin nor mint that's right
what is what is exotics what is
what is dessert weed what is dreams what
is dreams what does that even [ __ ]
like blue dream even jack and hayes okay
so jack and hayes in california
like
um
you know that it's mostly terpenoline
yeah but that's by no means the only
haze aromas in haze
in fact
i would put blue dream in the jackson
haze category more than i would like a
blueberry category but i certainly
wouldn't make a category for dreams
based off one strain but you know it's
like even if so even like all in back in
new york right uh where there's a bunch
of haze cuts that are still pretty
famous and kept
yeah you know they don't the the best
ones they have back there aren't
terpitally and they don't smell like
jack they smell like frankincense they
smell like church they smell there's a
variety of smells
so
hold on i'm going to respond to one
thing
someone said they are leaning into
genetics no they're not and chemovar
this is not based on chemovar which i
think is important and i appreciate the
effort and advancing discussion the
thing is this discussion was already
advanced past indica in sativa and
hybrid long ago
and it's it's only the people that
aren't very well read on the subject
that are still there
just so everyone knows that when you're
judging at the emerald cup all these
jars are labeled and no one has any
supposedly has any idea what they are
yeah
they're supposed to just just blind
smoke and gas and smell and and look and
share it doesn't come with oh this is
white runts from xmx farm
yeah it's just sample number 148.
yep you know and we're gonna name it
does this is this dessert to you
is this dreams do you feel dreamy when
you smoke this yeah is this dream that
that still blows my mind because i you
know even the even the even the og even
the og and gas it's like with nog
there's piney
there's earthy
there's so much depth in og itself and
you can't just combine
diesel and kush
into the same category as gas eogs what
yeah what about what about the the like
the irene ones that are more sweet
cereal oh geez
ones that are like lemony and pine soul
yeah and ones that are straight earthy
mouth coat
yeah um so really to me i'm not trying
to to diss them or whatever but it it
really is a step backwards and i really
don't want that kind of language to
start being used
um because you know what the [ __ ] is
dreams
yeah what the [ __ ] is a dream yeah the
thing my point was like i i agree in
advancing the conversation because i do
not think index indica and sativa and
hybrid are accurate however
someone already did that but like
someone pointed out merlin and and clark
came up with the broadleaf dominant
narrow leaf drug i'm sorry broadleaf
drug type narrow leaf drug type and um
from there i mean you you know you can
classify it any other way but those eld
and nld
yeah bld and nld is a great way to do it
because it doesn't talk about the high
type it just talks about this the
outward expression and maybe we should
you know we're planning on having uh our
buddy crybaby come on uh one of these
shows and we're gonna have like a
terpene and an aroma episode uh because
he can probably talk more intelligently
about those kind of things than we can
he's got a better language
but really what this is it's about
communication and language so
when we're talking about our eyes
it's really easy to be like this is
periwinkle or this is burgundy or this
is orange or this is and you can be like
yes that is we can both see it but when
it comes to to nose right
other than sour
bitter
dead
salty there's only like five or six
things that you actually taste
right yeah and then the rest is
impressions so people will be like oh
this smells like pencil shavings or a
fresh car
or it smells like you know something
common like oranges so you don't really
describe the smell
you describe something else that it
smells like
yeah but but that classification what
the [ __ ] does dream smell like
yeah that's
what is what is exactly what it smell
like
yeah you know what used to be exotic in
europe pepper
yeah that's true huh yeah
spices
from the far east they were exotic
you know you can have exhaus exotic
dragon fruit but if you live in hawaii
it's probably not exotic
at one point you know mangoes were
probably exotic
what is oh yeah yeah
have you had those before
i know i remember yeah fresh vinyl
linoleum you know new car smell
all that and so there's a whole bunch of
those things where it's like it's really
difficult to have the language to talk
about smells with people
and i'm bad at it and you know and i
always i always when trimmers and stuff
like that i always try to ask them away
from the rest of the trimmers what do
you smell when you smell this wheat yeah
and try to get a bunch of different
people's feedback and then do i see
things that people keep talking about
is there a commonality that you can pull
out of their impressions
because not everybody has the same
impression like for instance how would
europeans know roadkill
yeah right there is no roadkill in
europe
no no roadkill skunk no roadkill skunk
but that's what they mean when they talk
about roadkill yeah
roadkill skunk i should have been more
specific but it's like you're not
american there is no you've never
smelled a dead skunk on the side of the
road yeah unless you came here yeah um
so you know there's an aspect where it's
like i looked at all this stuff and
you've got all these judges this
[ __ ] don't understand the
concepts of monoterpenes try terpenes
sesquiterpene shut the [ __ ] up we don't
you obviously don't understand the
discussion
you can talk about terpenes and you can
talk about individual terpenes but like
the language around how those terpenes
blend into different aromas
yeah you know like just like there's
there's only so many primary colors
yeah and you know the terpenes you can
combine two different things and have
them smell the exact same way no matter
what terpenes you're using you know like
you there's certain ways to make
strawberry smells and there's other ways
to make strawberry smells that are very
similar that two people could smell as
strawberry but the problem is
it's not a terpene conversation in that
sense the level of the level of
education amongst people to discuss
aromas in cannabis is very limited even
amongst the educated yeah it's a limited
conversation and so i don't think it's
advanced by and they're all pushing oh
my god we're breaking barriers and
here's how we're judging stuff and we've
got different colored stickers to put on
jars whether it's dessert or whether
it's haze or whether it's exotic
yeah and i just think that's a joke
yeah i think the categories are not
related to reality
yeah
you know and it's not dissing them
you know no
it's not dissing them i mean if anything
it's probably dissing sc labs maybe
but it's just uh it's just another way
to try to talk about language and talk
about classifications
um
but it's not accurate it's not helpful
most weed before cookies nobody said
nobody was like oh my god all this weed
smells like desserts yeah i this is like
this is flan at my favorite mexican
restaurant to a tea
i just exhale flan
no yeah i just exhale strawberry
shortcake
yeah definitely not
yeah
you see but yeah yeah
yeah i think that'll be a good episode
with crybaby too yeah i mean he's way
worse we'll do it knowledgeable about
that
in the
language than i am
he's got a much deeper base of talking
about the language and the terpenes and
stuff like that you know
yeah
so we're gonna do matt's phone's gonna
die i got some stuff i gotta take care
of and whatnot so we're gonna do a
little bit shorter normally we try to
take it to like an hour and a half two
hours every friday we're gonna cut it a
little short uh today for a variety of
reasons um but we just kind of wanted to
do no matter what we wanted to kind of
bring people together on friday night
[ __ ] about different subjects with
cannabis give people things to talk and
think about
um and so matt if you want to do any
plugs
oh yeah um
go to
google type in breeder syndicate patreon
if you want to join the patreon we have
our discord where we talk about all this
stuff
incessantly because we're [ __ ] nerds
that's what we do and it's what we love
to do
um
uh we got our hawaiian life stuff
dropping and of course i did not take a
picture of all the hybrids like i was
going to and print out but there are
some really awesome hybrids that csi did
with the hawaiian light stuff and that's
going to be dropping probably this
weekend but expect to see some old rare
[ __ ] in there including the the bomb
threat bubba which hasn't been released
in ages in any hybrids no that's not
good
yeah that's a [ __ ]
i've grown that one myself it's a fun
it's a fun one
yeah um but anyway you know and you can
always reach out to us you can always
give us
you can always hit us up on instagram or
on discord and give us
ideas hey i'd love for you guys to talk
about this i'd love for to learn more
about whatever we're super open about
that we just want to
[ __ ] on a weekly basis about
cannabis and keep people interested so
yeah thank you so much
uh right seedco.com hawaiian lights f2
open pollination is up right now and
tomorrow are the fights for those of you
on the discord we're going to get
together for the fights uh it's going to
be major awesome ones so yep cheers
everybody have a great night
[Music]
you