welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
welcome to Raiders Syndicate I'm Matthew
here with my co-host thousand fold and
today we're going to be joined by
Michael and Hamlet of C2 Custom
Creations someone we've been working
closely with lately and I really enjoy
their glass but they both have a lot of
history in the scene a lot more than
just glass so we wanted to take the time
to speak with them and bring them to you
thousand take
yeah um yeah thank you both so much for
coming on this is
man this is definitely the first episode
where we actually talk to people who
work with glass right it is it is and
something I've been wanting to do really
really bad because it's a it's an art
form I'm super interested in
all right yeah no just safe for myself
as well like being in New Zealand you
know I'm pretty sure what we get to see
is like cheap Chinese stuff
um or like you know Gatorade bottles
with um pipes jumped into them yeah so
sweet I actually have really really
enjoyed learning um a little bit more
about where the glass Tech has gone and
a little bit about the history
um
and uh I'll say as well that you know C2
Custom Creations um Yola based in Eugene
technically right is that is that
correct no no we're we're in California
I did know that I did know that but
Michael did you spend time in Eugene
earlier on yourself yeah born and raised
in Eugene ah you so you're you're the
one okay gotcha
all right well I think we start at the
start
and I want to ask you both and I'm aware
that the two of you have had maybe quite
different Journeys initially so maybe
you all can take turns but the first
question is how did you get into either
cannabis or glass you know depending on
which one came first
Okay so
cannabis
um
pretty normal I come from a you know
small town Eugene Oregon it's uh herb is
super prevalent there
uh grew up my family itself was real
conservative I never saw my parents
drink alcohol
um it was just never around but
about
I'm sure the dead had visited before but
they started a tour that came to Austin
Stadium
and that was the first time that
I had seen like that many hippies and
just like Counter Culture people
in the city ever
and uh I remember my parents had told me
do not go near the stadium for this
weekend
and so the first thing I did was I
jumped on my bike
my pass went straight to the stadium
got up got off my bike walked around
through Shakedown Street I looked up and
down the booths I saw the crazy plastic
bongs I had no idea what they were for
you know I knew it's definitely smelled
different than anything I had ever seen
before you know and uh I think that's
really how old were you
and I was
in probably in between 11 and 12 years
old
and that's when I definitely at least
started my interest
of what was going on something that I
had never seen before
fast forward a few years and I was in
high school a few of my friends have
been smoking weed and I hadn't
um
and I made a deal with one of them to
where they could give me just a little
bit and I'd bring it home and me and my
one of my little brothers would try it
and we tried to figure out how to get
the the Coke can to work and
uh yeah did our best to smoke it I have
no idea if it worked or not but
that's pretty much uh my first
experience with cannabis
did you just throw the Chunk on the just
a chunk of it on the can
I tried that's what I did it had been
snowing the night before there was a
little bit of snow on the ground I
remember we maybe got one or two hits
before that thing fell in the snow and
we were on our knees trying to find it
and couldn't think
you know
um
as far as getting into glass uh after
that first time of smoking I definitely
I was interested in it I continued to
smoke I was in Eugene so we were real
fortunate
um
we would go down to 13th Street which
was close to the university and there'd
always be hippies down there and you'd
walk by them and they'd whisper you know
nugs or this or that and if you had 40
bucks you can get a really nice sack of
weed even as a little kid a high school
kid
you know so I was real fortunate in that
it was easy to get
um so after high school I went to the
University of Oregon and I had ran into
a friend
from high school that had started
working at a glass shop
and uh he invited me over to the glass
shop to kind of see what was going on
and at that point I had made some pretty
good connections with with weed and I
was getting good weed regularly and I
guess the owner of that glass shop was
from California
and what he had done is moved to Eugene
and started a small shop
um I went in there I showed him some of
the weed I had he was real interested in
it and I made an agreement with him
where hey
I'd be willing to hook you up with this
weed when I get it regularly but I want
to learn how to make those pipes
because the pipes you know they were not
the coolest thing other than the wheat
itself that I had ever seen
yeah and uh so I made a deal with him
and I got into the shop that way and
they basically just started me out as an
apprentice on an apprentice program
and I took it from there
and I just within a year I had dropped
out of the University of Oregon
yeah we're not a real trade yeah went on
my Merry way with uh weed and cannabis
but that's like how you broker your way
into a trade though right like you have
to find ways to to get yourself into
different trades as a Young Man during
that era not everything was just laid
out for you as a not super rich kid you
know yeah absolutely not you had you had
to have something to offer to even get
in the door there and that was one of
the coolest things about that shop
because looking back
most of the kids in that shop were under
25 years old I think I was either 19 or
20. and every one of them brought
something different to the table as far
as weed goes and I could tell they all
got their jobs the same exact way I did
yeah it makes sense dude
um the reason why I mentioned Eugene
obviously in the introduction for those
of you who may not know is that it's
recognized as one of the places for
glass am I correct in saying that
or is yeah heralded like an era and all
right yeah that's where uh Bob snoggrass
kind of laid his flag and he's really
like the first fumed
glass pipe maker that was well known you
know I think he had been slinging pipes
on the Dead tours of the 70s maybe
earlier I'm not even sure but he's a
great guy and he was the one that
basically started the Glass Pipes and if
you wanted to learn how to make a glass
pipe in Oregon you needed to know
someone that had either learned from him
or one of his apprentices
and I think that's kind of we all
you know grow from the roots of that
tree
it's interesting that's great that's
that's some really cool uh
historical
um yeah signposting there
okay what about you Hamlet oh me it was
a little different I mean I remember I
was a 14 and I had a really stressful
day and my my circle of friends were
always older than me growing up so uh
one of my friends saw what I was going
through and it just passed me a joint
and I've never smoked before I mean I've
seen people smoke and stuff and I wasn't
about it but that day I was like you
know what I'm gonna give this a try and
when I did it it changed my life really
like I was like oh I could feel like
this instead of being you know all
[ __ ] up and stressed out of my mind
this is perfect
so you know in that token
um I don't know what kind of weed it was
or what strain or anything when I smoked
it um felt great
and I started looking more into it and I
realized that there's a whole scene with
like graphics and glass pieces being
made because of it and this and that and
I was like wait a minute my dad's been
to Glass floor for more always life even
before I was born oh wow yeah he was an
internationally known glass floor
um he worked in all kinds of different
projects nothing to do it nothing to do
with weed um yeah yeah scientifical
stuff a lot of Aerospace stuff satellite
dish
yeah and I just kind of grew up around
that and I never really
looked at it that way until that that
kind of week when I started looking more
into smoking and this I was like wait a
minute this is something here you know
so growing up I showed more and more
interested in the glass
um and when I was about 17 years old he
used to work at a company called scitec
class out of more Park
um
I think at the time they were actually
in a different city but yeah either way
and and he I got a summer job there one
time you know during break pool and I
learned a few things and um and it was a
short time job you know I a short period
I got out and started talking my dad I
was like well listen you know we could
we can do this we could make pipes and
like I'm learning and you can teach me
more and he was a little hesitant but he
wanted to you know he was tired of
working for somebody else for you know
most of his life yeah he made a good
living but then again working for
somebody else is not the same
so
um we opened 1994 I remember like
yesterday January 5th I was 17 years old
we opened up a shop but one laid in
there one torch small shop and he still
kept his job for about a year after that
going back and forth uh he was working
at night I was learning how to do prep
on glass during the day and he would
teach me things along the way and uh
this is how kind of started blowing
glass and wheat kind of like more and
more into it you know before that I was
just yeah just getting high you know
enjoying it and it's a it's a funny
story actually
um how wait Hannah before you go on can
I just ask
um were you already did you already know
how to work with glass
um before the program watch the 17th
most of my childhood I've seen it and I
didn't know until that summer job I had
um at the at the company that my my
father used to work at and that's kind
of where I picked up some things and uh
and my dad saw that I was picking up
pretty quick and it's in you can kind of
feel it if you're gonna like this or
you're gonna hate it sure think you know
like you pick it up a day or two you're
gonna know if you're gonna continue or
you're just gonna be done with it so and
I like it I enjoyed it you know I want
to learn more I want to learn more
techniques and how to do things and he
saw that so we went forward with that
for that reason and it just was you was
your dad like stoked that you were
getting into it yeah he was he was um he
was really happy about it and he was
excited that I was doing pretty good
with it and I was like he would show me
something and then the next day in the
daytime I would make it wrap it for him
he would come from after the job this
new business we have and he would see
all the parts that I made all the prep
work I he you know he was excited about
he was like oh my God this is great like
I can use this I don't have to mess with
it I don't have to change it you know
it's great so I'm picking up pretty
quick and you know a couple times he got
a little upset because I was doing other
[ __ ] trying to make my own pipe and this
is like no you're not ready you know you
got to do the steps yeah of course you
know like everybody else I'm trying to
jump ahead and do what I can do and make
a pipe for myself I can take away before
he even gets there you know yeah right
he he didn't like me smoking weed like
he was like oh you know you shouldn't
you're young this that uh you shouldn't
do it and your mom doesn't like it and I
in later on in life I realized it was
just mainly because my mom didn't like
it he would smoke weed on his own but we
kept it from each other yeah of course
of course right yeah like you know he
would smoke blunts and come home and
tell me
we don't want her pissed at me or him
right yeah so that yeah that's how that
went with that but um yeah and then we
just did more and more with the class
there was times along the years where I
did my own thing on the side but I
always but left my foot in there like
help them with the business and did
other things and try to progress and
give new ideas and like pressure because
he was older you know with all the crowd
to him it was basically like spliffs
really just tobacco and weed mixed
together and and you know with the
papers but um yeah I showed him like the
glass scene at what's available a lot of
the scientific stuff is coming out like
things are getting involved and it's
getting more intricate and nicer and we
kind of built on that together
um you know there was a lot of hard
times along the way but it it grew
faster than we thought and within like a
little bit short of a year he quit the
other job we're full time into this and
now we're working side by side so I was
learning more because when I made a
mistake he was right there on top of me
he was right there next to me telling me
Oh do this like this or you could do
this like that and from that putting it
together from what I'm learning and
putting my input into it and uh we kind
of just went with the scientific line
with it you know like just progressed
with that the class and um it's a funny
story from where the old shop was
actually there was a there's kind of
like a side story but there was a whole
race scene like import car racing that
was going on and we would work late
nights because it was just cooler and
temperatures were better and we would
always hear these cars racing right
outside of the shop on the street and I
guess one day cops pulled up and all
these race cars just flooded our parking
lot
you know and yeah my dad the crazy ass
that he was he jumped out there with his
rifle like a big ass milk and rifle
stood out there he was like I don't know
who these [ __ ] are but they're not
[ __ ] with me you know yeah no yeah
yeah and one of these guys was actually
[ __ ] Oregon kid Ken oh ken yeah yeah
you know that's the first yeah get him
and he he just kind of drove by and then
reversed and he was almost getting shot
because he was trying to reverse close
to the shop
I like glass he's like putting his pipe
out the window
I'm friendly with all this [ __ ] going on
yeah
um and my dad's like wait a minute like
you know maybe we'll talk to him for a
sec we'll give him a chance to see what
he's got to say before he [ __ ] kills
him yeah yeah and then uh yeah so he's
like no I like weed I like pipes like I
want to see what you guys have like I
know you guys are blowing Us in there I
saw the Torches driving by and this and
he was pretty ballsy for doing that but
it worked out and then we became really
close friends you know like really close
friends with the family uh with him with
us and he actually introduced me to Kush
and which I've never smoked before OG
kush yeah yeah when I smoked that I was
like what the [ __ ] is it like oh holy
[ __ ] there's this is a life-changing
weed the first time yeah I remember that
I got the OG Kush from him first time
Bubble Kush from him
um banana kush probably blackberry kush
too I don't recall that it wasn't
memorable yeah it's definitely not
memorable now that's what's stuck in my
head because when I smoked that and
inhaled it and exhaled and I felt that
flavor and the eye I was like what I've
been smoking [ __ ] mids all this time
you know yeah yeah the best [ __ ] weed
I've ever tasted so I had to become very
close friends with them and it was cool
you know we were cool like we went to a
couple of uh festivals together like you
know had some parties at his house at my
house we hung out
um what year was this roughly well I'm
sorry
what year was this roughly
oh my God uh 90
5 96 okay something like that uh and it
it it went on from there so I remember
the OG Kush was the first one and then
later on there was more of the flavors I
got from him and he's he actually pushed
a lot of our line and uh and the
features on our pipes because he would
come up like oh you know you should do
this or you should do that or you should
make a pipe that is this way maybe
you'll get more flavor or you know he
had a lot of input with it he was very
much involved in the whole thing
um and we would like you know hook them
up with pieces he would come by seconds
from us all the time and it was a good
relationship with him you know like he
and he would give me the I mean he would
give me the best weed I would trade for
glasses perfect for me oh yeah dude paid
money for it you know
um yeah that was a good time with that
um but yeah
kind of lost my Chain of Thought with
that no you're good I and I think
I think he was calling it OG Kush
back then but in reality I'm pretty sure
it was his Bubba
yeah yeah but that particular one was
his Bubba yeah that was dangerous that
was like it was the best way that I
smoked and I loved Bubba it's got me
more into it more interested with it
trying to do more different perks
different ideas uh different ways we
could cut the glass and and this was all
with like fuming and clear this is
before all these colors and array of
palette that we have now that's
available now we didn't have that back
then we don't have others who had you
know silver gold and then a blue came
out randomly yeah that was it for a good
long time so we didn't have much
variations but you know like taking the
techniques without my dad had with the
with the lab industry and incorporating
it with the scientific line and the the
glass picked up and we did well with it
I think you know
um I mean next January next year January
will be 30 years that we started
it wasn't Custom Creations oh this is
what I want to say this is how custom
patients can be
um during this time I had a smoke shop
right next to UCLA at the same time I
was doing this and this was actually in
the early 2000s I want to say
um it was called C2 smoke shop and the
C2 was at a partner at the time and my
friend we were like trying to see if it
was going to be the cottonmouth corner
or chronic Corner smoke shop and that's
where the C2 came from it was actually c
squared thinking it was right next to
UCLA people who get it but everybody was
calling it C2 but it was a big c with
the little two on the corner yeah yeah
where
like in the college kids there's C2 C2
C2 you know
and that was about a four-year crazy ass
run at the uh only only smoke shops
between the only bar and the sorority
run so I was open from 3 P.M to 3 A.M
that was some wild times in that smoke
shop yes dude you can imagine all the
trumpets and everyone coming through but
that was about a four year run and then
when I closed that off I was like and
sorry to backtrack a little bit when
we're at high-tech glass we didn't
really sell direct to stores and it was
kind of like shady back then selling it
wasn't like it is now open yeah it would
have to be low-key with it real real
calm like relaxed with it can't be too
much advertising too much of this so we
were working with Distributors so we
would make other people's lines for them
this is what we're called high tech and
it's not the high-tech you might have
heard of where they make the bottles
like the bottle looking one
um
and we decided I was like well no we did
I stopped a smoke shop I had more hours
and more time I was like let's just have
our own line and just let sell Direct
you know um yeah that was like okay how
can we already had the C2 Corporation
name I was like how can we incorporate
this with this and change it so we
changed high tech to Custom Creations
because it fit the c squared
and that's where
so um yeah
jump in the pipe dreams oh yeah I mean
I'm just going down
there was a time we had to stop making
pipes and we started making anything
that we can out of glass why is that and
well because the Ashcroft and pipe
dreams came down and that's right one
down and scared the [ __ ] out of everyone
yeah and we will just completed these
all our Distributors all our accounts
they stopped carrying glasses yeah so I
just want to I just want to interrupt
and and make it real clear operation
pipe dreams was an FBI operation a
Crackdown correct U.S Marshals yes
Marshalls certain attorney generals from
certain States uh Pennsylvania Iowa
um I can't remember the third it might
have been Indiana I was doing the Bush
Administration right after the chills
got busted too yeah but it was basically
a few attorney generals from the United
States were able to bring charges for
people out of state for shipping
something illegal into their state
illegal mini glass pipes yeah mainly
that's why and I imagine this was also a
time when the glass scene was like
burgeoning right like
it was starting to get big yeah like we
were starting to have big trade shows
exactly it was getting too big for their
comfort you know yeah Jerome Baker was
really big oh they hit him hard yeah
yeah Jerome Victor got hit hard um not a
big companies got hit hard and so our
Distributors yeah of course yeah yeah
and so we're like What do we do what do
we do
um you know jewelry like some mugs cups
it's not paying the bills you know like
well [ __ ] how about
dildos glass you know sex toys yeah all
right you know what's up and then uh uh
the company I'm working with they had
some stuff going on they came to this
organization they they contacted us like
yeah sure we can make those no problem
you know whatever you want what color is
the model
we did have some specific ones that came
with specific sizing and shapes and well
that's cool actually you know extra
large ones and yeah you got to fit every
other one we made for Belladonna that
was huge I mean it's like a tabletop
thing yeah like no kidding it was
[ __ ] incredible
people paid for these though like like
the big big monster ones people are like
yeah I need that one in my life that was
a special order from her porn company
yeah that was mainly for like the porn
industry you know what I mean wow and we
actually made a [ __ ] uh a chandelier
for Hugh Hefner that had like like
[ __ ] glass dicks like lined up on top
on top of the light bulb that's the
thing that's awesome it's yeah I mean we
had a few different um
taking this interview into the phallic
space I'm so glad he did that
they were in uh Playboy and
Hustler and everything yeah yeah Playboy
TV there was another company too that
was buying them from us as well yeah
remember yeah now this episode is
already like iconic yeah so when you
were when you got into this stage like
obviously there was a point when you're
like okay pipe dreams kind of is cooling
down maybe we can get back into box but
exactly did you drop the dicks
after that or do you just be like
this is good money we had to let that go
because China got involved in India and
in ports and all the [ __ ] was just like
no money in it left you know no yeah
Chinese were in the dicks yeah it was it
was a short thing I mean they say it was
quite a few years too no we got back
into Gaspar and Jack were making those
for like oh so like three years so half
the shop was still doing it for a little
bit and then we trickled back into pipes
and like tested the grounds on that to
make sure it's still safe and it's okay
you know like that that's how that went
in three three three years I think it
was gone after that what was funny is
we'd be at a party with like all of his
dad's friends and he'd make it real
clear to us you can mention that we make
pipes I don't tell anyone we're making
those sex toys
you know that look like dicks and tits
and all that like it was kind of funny
and turning into an old a whole part of
the thing but um but that's funny so
wait hold on I just wanted to double
check on one thing which is yeah sure uh
when did you two actually meet
and wait
when did you two actually meet um and
how did you meet Okay so
I actually met uh his father way before
I met him
um
we had the same distributor that would
sell our glass pipes
and uh when I first met his dad
he was pretty early with his English it
wasn't great back then yeah and so wait
this is this is pretty dildo
yes this is pretty dildo okay oh yeah
yeah yeah yeah this is pre-dildo
um and I would always see him and to be
honest coming from a small town I had no
idea what Armenian was I'd never heard
that term before and I'd never seen that
country on a map so like when I would
call my mom and talk to her and tell her
about people I'm meeting and different
things I'm seeing I'd be like man you
know there's a lot of these Russian guys
down here in Los Angeles
and uh
what it ended up came to be is that
there is a pretty healthy Armenian
population here and his father was a an
Armenian
and uh so we ran into each other at our
distributor one day and he's trying to
talk to me and I I don't understand he's
he's got a real thick accent you know
and I'm having a hard time understanding
what he's trying to say so he pulls
someone over one of his friends the next
time we were going to drop off product
because we did our drops on the same
days he had a friend come over that
spoke a little more English and what he
was trying to explain was hey
I'm a professional at this
you know a lot of people and have taught
a lot of people how to uh decorate the
glass but you're you're not a
professional glassblower you don't know
anything outside of the few things you
know how to do which was entirely true
um and he was explaining that let's team
up so that you can communicate for us
I'll make sure we're making the coolest
like best stuff that you can find and we
can be partners
and uh he actually he worked on me for a
good
six months to a year with that idea
before I finally was like you know what
let's just give it a try like I want to
know how the lathes work I all my
experiences in hand blown glass and uh
let's just let's give it a try and
that's how I met you at my at my
father's house yep I was I was stopping
by and I saw him
um with his wife at the time
and I was like oh who's this and they
introduced him this and that and and I
was at the time I was having a little uh
tiff with my with my dad like everyone
else you know like working it's not easy
working with your father yeah
I can imagine it was a tough guy to work
with and um so we're having back and
forth and this and that and I was really
short and I was kind of a dick to him
actually that's like I saw him I met him
I was like yeah I'm out bye you guys
have fun whatever you know but he he did
not be a great friend and a great guy
like that but that was the first time I
met him at my father's house through
through him and uh realized that they're
trying to start a venture together with
the business and uh incorporate things
and that's when I stepped back in I was
like okay we can do clear we can do
scientific we can do this we can do
different perks we can do different
sizes and shaping all this stuff and
kind of like but basically all three of
our minds together and uh progressed it
with the glass
nice
excellent okay so if we come back to
that um sorry I keep referring to it as
this but we come back to the post dildo
period the three and post dildo eras I
guess that's right
so we're getting you know you guys are
getting back into the pipes at this
point and yeah what happens from that
point uh between that point and where we
are now
in what way as far as how our glass has
grown how the industry has changed like
what maybe a bit yeah I I don't know it
could be both
um maybe like what stands out to you
um from that period on because what year
would that have been now I would say
probably 2005
to 2006 is when you really saw a
transition in water pipes from just
being a beaker or a colored work Bubble
at the end of a straight tube
uh
having like the percolation and the
function of the pieces be the most
important thing and not so much just the
uh the colors of the artwork yeah yeah I
do want to okay I do want to say this
here because
uh in my mind before I you know looked
looked a bit deeper into it yeah and
exactly what you're saying in my mind in
2023 a bong is something with a chamber
it's got a bowl and a mouthpiece and
that's all I knew and so kind of
finding out about perks ratchets
recyclers like all these things kind of
blew my mind honestly
um so yeah sorry but please yeah please
continue
yeah I think at that point there was
enough people that had
um left the scientific industry or had
been trained in scientific glassblowing
that they could add to what
um I'd say the minimal knowledge of like
uh the art glass Community had as far as
uh function and seals and some of that
sort of thing
is that the division between scientific
and and because I remember when that
started popping up on websites where you
could buy glass you know like I remember
oh there's a segment that says
scientific and I never to this day
probably until this conversation I never
even could grasp what that meant why is
this one scientific versus this one
recycler throughout the glass history
like scientific glass Force kind of
stayed away from the pipe scene like
yeah they acted like they're too good or
whatever you know sure they want to mess
with the pipes but that whole science
Industry got turned upside down when
everything started being imported Yeah
by being outsourced and you know these
guys that have all these factories and
and equipment and you know materials and
they can't use it because they can't
sell it to anyone nobody they can't
compete so all of a sudden you know okay
like we'll get into the pipe industry
they were like okay you know it was kind
of like that what my father too trying
to talk him into it yeah like he was he
even when we first opened up a shop he
was trying to pick up the science Market
but that was like a dying Market in
America
because again everything was being yeah
being outsourced so with that they kind
of merged like all these science guys
and these high technical glass floors
got into the scene with all these other
artists that they're doing the art
aspect of it and the colors and the
working of it of making it pretty and
and it's definitely pleasing but you
know the science guys came in like okay
we can make it look pretty aesthetic
with using and we can add our thing to
it and make it more percolation double
chamber triple chamber yeah right
functionality having different perks
different ideas and then bring and then
that's kind of how the chords thing came
into it too like when I started talking
about chords and making quartz Nails
people didn't know what the [ __ ] that
was we even got knocked off a couple
times and it was made out of borrow
silica glass which explodes if you try
to porch it and and and oh my god well
yeah because it's not made for those
yeah yeah temperature differences in you
know and it also titanium changing to
quartz and I was you know like we're
pushing all the scientific guys we're
pushing towards because they worked with
courts before and they've done a lot of
course things I mean hell we used to
um the the company I used to work out
they used to make big like four foot
five foot table size they were called
quartz bolts and wafer holders and they
had the satellite like the reflective
Wafers they will cook inside of these
things in a quartz lineup where it
doesn't give off anything and it's clean
and it will heat to a point so that that
knowledge was brought in mainly due to
uh economics really because people had
to make money people had to keep working
you know they kind of force themselves
like they had forced themselves to jump
into this and and and mold into the
wheat industry and try to progress the
pipes and make sense I'm so glad that we
mentioned this because
um I watched a little documentary called
degenerate art on on the glass pipe
scene and one thing that I was wondering
about because most of the work that was
featured in that was very very
sculptural
um uh kind of that I imagine that's what
you were referring to as art glass
um Michael
um and so I I was particularly
interested in this turning point so I'm
really glad that you guys have um
expanded on that yeah and I'm trying to
remember back to like the first
companies that were really pushing like
the new scientific stuff before we did
those was drawing well roar started
using the glass on glass stuff but I
remember Toro being like the first place
I saw the tree place no there was a
couple ones before was it yeah yeah
there was a couple of ones before we
even we used to oh I forgot about this
we used to make um the liquid Chamber Of
Glass before like uh illadelph or any
other companies are doing it back in the
day and you know we would mix food
coloring and not go certain time alcohol
yeah freezing when we're shipping it
over to states that are you know cold
um and I remember actually making one of
the first hand pipes and it made it onto
Michael Douglas's the game I don't know
if you guys ever seen that movie oh yeah
yeah for sure I've seen when they're
trying to where they're trying to frame
him and they show the bathroom that
there's like a teal looking pipe there
and some crack and some other [ __ ] or
whatever yeah and I made that pipe and I
saw it I was like oh my God this is
[ __ ] great that's awesome that's a
great movie that thing I I just you know
I it's there it's right there in the
movie I never got credit for anything
but you know it was one piece I made
that from nothing I made it the first
liquid-filled Empire which was a little
piece and then we used to Cork it and
and seal it with uh
um what was it epoxy and it lasted for a
good while you know until we got knocked
off and everybody else started making it
that was that that's a crazy story too
because I used to go to smoke shops to
get business and then that was one of
the worst things I did walking into a
smoke shop that I didn't know is
affiliated with a bunch of glass blowers
and they're like oh yeah we like these
pieces took one of everything and then
next you know hey they're trying to
they're trying to make their version of
it you know oh man oh yeah you know but
yeah that's scientific and uh and the
artistic kind of merged there but also
when you say art class there is also a
soft class form I don't know if you guys
are aware of this no no what's that yeah
that's like truly yeah like really
artistic colorful you know bigger pieces
like vases and
um like if you've been was it the win
the chandelier I think it's obaja oh the
Bellagio has a giant like Chandelier on
top I don't know if you guys ever been
to Vegas
there's a few well-known artists that
have been doing that for years stemming
from Italy like doing that old school
where they take the stick and they you
dip it in the glass pull it out and um
form it where our glass everything
starts with like a tube we get a
scientific tube and we form from that so
it it it's a different type of glass
that one is soft glass this is borrow
silicate so the art industry is kind of
like
merged between that and the Boro
it just everything kind of stacked up
and the timing was right for everything
to go that direction you know to get all
those pipes and pieces and the companies
popping out
I did one to also signpost here for um
people like me who didn't really know
about some of this tick uh previously
and just to kind of like generalize a
bit on the engineering side
um I imagine most of these advancements
had to do with how the flow of smoke and
Air
was being mediated in in the glass
research and development
yeah yes every single one of them
[ __ ] you know
that's the thing like I think each one
of the companies that have been able to
survive that make
um this kind what I I call is like a
scientific art glass
um have their own own way of doing
things I think for C2
we have been really on top of fast flow
easy function with coming up with
percolators that don't cost hundreds
upon hundreds of dollars to produce and
that that's kind of where we yeah I
always had like the end user in mind too
like we don't want to overcharge because
you know we made something new and
nobody has this like we could have went
a different route and charged so much
more and sold one or two pieces where me
I was like I want everyone to experience
this piece and everyone to feel what
it's like to smoke out of a piece that
percolates better that filters and easy
to clean easy to you know it's just it's
more functional it's better and I was
like let's just try to get it to
everyone instead of having a very small
niche market where only a few people can
afford it
and one thing I ideal that's kind of how
our pipes work it's getting the smoke
from point A to point B as quick as
possible yeah getting the pipes to you
know person to person as quick as
possible there's been many there's been
many many designs where we discontinued
we're just like oh this isn't working
out you know we try to change it up a
little bit this that happens exactly
very hard to clean or too much drag or
too flowy or Splash or any kind of
things that are not you know positive
and they don't work out the right way so
we just kind of get rid of it or just
change up the whole thing
one thing I observed when I was looking
at your catalog and gallery
um that I thought was really interesting
was that it seems like uh you know the
overall uh structure of your pieces uh
you know again like fairly scientific
but it's kind of within the chamber that
you guys kind of let some of that more
like Creative Juice like flow a bit or
like the art pops a bit more some of the
like in pieces are you talking about the
more like
um the sculpt there's sculpted pieces
they're sculpted inside that's right
okay
um yeah I mean that's just taking our
normal perks and letting you know
letting us kind of run with whatever we
can possibly do in that small space that
can add is that yeah go ahead
oh I'm just wondering like is that like
an interesting set of constraints to
work with when you uh
you know that tiny space that you have
to work with
yeah especially when you introduce so
many different colors because with glass
a lot of different colors
um
work and cooperate differently with each
other like some are not compatible with
the others and you know the temperature
differences you have to do minor
adjustments you have we have a lot more
braking and cracking issues when it
comes to having sculpted pieces and
having a finalized piece that's okay to
go uh versus clear where it's it's all
the same type of glass so it all works
closely and it's easier to use so yes it
does complicate a lot and um it changes
the Dynamics of like how what
temperatures we have to kill in it at
how many times we can kill the color
variations we can get from the different
temperatures we use and that affects the
outside shape too so it's like a good
balance we have to come up with
to to get those completed and done right
right and then but for the finished
piece we have an idea of what the the
end diameter and circumference is going
to be inside the tube so we kind of know
how much we have to work with and so
it's just about whether or not we can
fit what we want to within those
parameters and
okay let's go to the next side so here
we go from a 65 millimeter to a 80
millimeter or 110 millimeter now so okay
we made it part for 110 it doesn't fit
right we're going to figure out where
we're going to put it in you know so
we're below at the 110 and making it a
little bit bubbly shaped so it has more
circumference and room in it to put put
the art piece that we want inside
so it all kind of it's like it's like
you kind of do it and then just judge it
by then and trying to plan it as much as
you can but things change you know I
think what I like about it I mean of
course the whole thing is a piece of art
but the other way I can see it is that
like the clear pod is like the frame
almost or stage and then there's the
more sculpted bit kind of like uh
foregrounded uh or centered which is
yeah I call those like our captured
series because it's like capturing the
art in a dome kind of like old school
yeah like those you know creatures or a
hand or whatever in the jar had an idea
you know Frozen yeah that's cool it
reminds me of like a snow globe as well
in a way yeah
absolutely yeah
where the egg series was definitely was
definitely like that
for sure
yeah it must be interesting to try to
balance this kind of like aesthetic and
function at the same time like always
trying to find that balance
well I will say one thing most of the
custom pieces work great
but if it's pure function for me
personally I will always go with the
clear pieces
because I think they well the lines of
it have been having having like straight
smooth lines it makes the smoke travel
easier and faster and you can control
the chamber size better versus having an
interesting head where it takes up a lot
of the space and you're not exactly sure
how much room you have in there for
smoke where it's clear and it's straight
you could have this size on the inside
and the other side on the outside you
know exact volume of smoke and air is
coming through so you can really dial in
it that way but most of our like
artistic pieces first we dialed it in
with a pole in the scientific part and
then Incorporated the art part into it
yeah so make sure it works and functions
and then introduce the art and the other
way around will be a lot harder yeah I
think
uh that's yeah this is great this is
what I wanted to hear out of this
conversation like these are all the
things that like I just had no idea
about so yeah I didn't either much for
I've shot for glass for years and had no
like I just looked at color shape that
looks cool
why isn't that more discolored this
color I had no clue about any of this
stuff it's fascinating from the art
aspect yeah because I I think I was
saying this to you spindle in private
um being outside of the US you know
obviously like any other part of the
world we get a lot of American culture
but this is definitely not a part of
American culture that most of the world
has access to or has much insight into
so I think this episode is actually
going to be really cool for a lot of
people who are overseas even people in
America who may not know I think a lot
of people are really missing out because
there has been in the last 20 years some
absolutely incredible artwork made by
pipe makers oh yeah and I'm not saying
like Gallery either of us absolutely not
but there is some really impressive
stuff that um I mean I've seen a lot of
artwork as well and it doesn't get me as
excited as some of the glass pieces I've
seen reason why I think they didn't get
traction is because it's it's part of
the weed community and that's still
frowned upon in a lot of [ __ ] places
unfortunately and in the art community
as well yeah yeah definitely the first
person I met in the glass Community I
was at some random
um festival in San Diego like weed
festivals real random was Lacy lace face
oh yeah her pieces there amazing and I
was like I was mind blown like that this
person right here had just made this
beautiful glass like human beautiful
female form sculpture it's all the parts
and pieces yeah yeah he was insane yeah
it was really cool to see in person she
was a real cool chick too she's an
amazing artist for sure yeah
that's what I was saying if if she was
let's say part of the art scene and had
nothing to do with cannabis wheat or
smoking I think she would have been more
world uh yeah and more famous for what
she does yeah I would guess so which is
unfortunate but that's you know that's
the reality of it that's how that's
changing but then it is that is slowly
going you know the right direction but
it's very slow and it's been many many
years yeah
okay well if we take a little break from
this like deep dive into the glass which
[ __ ] I loved
um what if we come back to the timeline
um what's happened for you both in the
last I think where were we last talking
like uh mid-2000 like like 2005 2006.
what's happened in the last you know 15
years
oh wow uh well
um
after uh there was a period in there
where
um
his father and I were business partners
and then we split
and I moved out of state
and about that same time Hamlet
sold or closed his head shop and came
back to work with full-time yeah Dad
um
and then uh
a few years after that or no it wasn't
too long but I moved back to California
um to be with my family and
we decided Well basically Hamlet invited
me back to
so that we could all start working
together again
and uh that was when we really started I
think going crazy on new designs and
yeah really pushing it hard the perks
and doing the door seals and changing
our line and this happened to kind of
coexist with a time when
um a lot of the glass blowers were
starting to like double triple quadruple
their prices on the water pipes to where
they were getting like
I don't want to say ridiculous
but they were really expensive even for
clear glass it was getting really really
expensive and uh
I think we
I mean I remember us button heads a
little bit about the the whether to go
the color Direction the art direction or
to focus on scientific uh you know
obviously I was saying scientific he was
saying color and we were going back and
forth until we all of that kind of like
merged in and with both of us did what
we could but uh since then we just kind
of really been you know hustling glass
and pushing it and trying to do shows
and events and venues and anything we
can
coexist in the height of the the import
craze where if we designed something or
someone famous designed something it's
going to be knocked off overseas within
six months if you're lucky yeah oh
there's a time where they locked up they
knocked out for an entire logo and they
were putting it on shitty ass pipes yeah
so all of a sudden downtown has all
these C2 pipes that we never [ __ ]
seen before and they don't even function
they couldn't they didn't even
understand the process of smoking like
the perks didn't work you couldn't even
draw air through it it would just suck
water straight up it was like it would
work as a straw a lot of it you know
like the unusable pieces and has our
[ __ ] house and you you know can you
give us an insight into like what was
their process like to make this really
cheaply you know in comparison like how
were they doing this
well I think they used a lot of child
labor child labor no safety at all of
any kind uh cheap glass you know and uh
not actually worrying about the function
just because they were I'm assuming they
would look at a picture or video and
like okay I need to make this but they
don't they don't even know what the [ __ ]
it was for a lot of times
and the other person that's finishing
off the piece they don't know what's
what or what is it used for or how even
it's used and that's why a lot of those
pieces want to function yeah they didn't
have a lot of big smokers in China yeah
it makes sense their fingers cut off or
something like that exactly yeah right
you know and so at this point oh sorry
ego please I was just going to say I
think that's kind of one of the ways
that we really were able to say well
open for business when a lot of people
close we kept progressing was the fact
that we kept progressing creating new
designs and we've also done a good job
of creating stuff at the cheapest
possible price point that it could be
made in this country Yeah well yeah
because we're all hands on we we make
everything ourselves we [ __ ] sweat
and tears into it you know it's not like
oh yeah just tell this guy to do it
he'll take care of it all that no it's
like oh we're involved in the whole
thing yeah you know from the start to
finish to when the Box leaves the
[ __ ] uh Warehouse after it's packed
we'll throw out the whole process we're
involved there's no owner at the top
collecting a paycheck and not coming to
work like that's not a thing we have so
we were able to definitely avoid that as
well and that cuts a lot of the costs
and puts the you know labor fact down in
the labor costs down because we're doing
it ourselves so right and we don't live
like kings yeah
it's like what it takes to have a small
business in America today is stuff like
that like you can't just
you can't have a bunch of employees
anymore you can't you have to do
everything yourself and cut every cut
everything down and be doing it yourself
essentially because it's so hard
in in this industry anymore I don't know
of anything and well the cool thing
about about it is us being like involved
in the art and involved in the industry
when we do have employees work and we
they can't I mean not that they try to
but they can't really get one over on us
like other companies have or they're
just a boss running things they has no
idea how the glass works or how it's
made you know or if if my guy is working
and he's only making one of these pieces
where I'd be like dude I can sit there
and make three or four and you're only
making one you're [ __ ] me like you're
wasting my time you know and that helped
too with all the having the prices down
and having it affordable for everyone
and and smoke shops across the country
love this you know they love the fact
that they can get American-made stuff
that's made well that functions great
and and the price points is realistic to
most of their customers
and that helped out a lot and and
staying in business and and keep doing
what we do
and yeah realistically like I know we've
been to a lot of trade shows where
people think we're like a big Factory
company it is literally Hamlet eye and
yeah let me try really hard to make it
look that way
but you know you know we've had people
call us a big shop one of the big
production shops before and I'm always
like uh yeah it's literally three of us
like we're you know we're good at what
we do you know and so maybe it seems
that way but we work our asses off you
know
yeah every single one is a lie yeah yeah
every single one of the pieces was
designed or made by us you know like
we had to put we had to narrow it down
perfect it before it goes on to
production and production meaning we're
still part of it you know yeah so yeah
but it was a big front trying to like
you know stand up there with the big
guys and be like oh yeah it's our
company you know this is what we're
doing
so yeah
that's cool okay so we have this so we
have a point at which like you know is
the rise of Import Glass
what what's the next kind of thing that
y'all saw as being like a big thing like
uh it's been um Michael I know that we
mentioned Instagram at some point you
know
um emerging and and what that how that
affected your scene as well was there
anything else in between the Import
Glass and Instagram or you know that you
would consider significant
no I I really think
I think Instagram really changed
everything yeah I put in front of people
you know yeah y'all can dive into that
tell us about that
you know I I think the the whole
Instagram era of glass has been really
really interesting and it definitely it
can mimic in some ways the seed business
also because
um I think originally when I got into
glass blowing and in the Oregon scene it
was a somewhat of a small
it was still a small scene like the
headies.com guys were super famous for
making beautiful nice stuff and being at
the top of their game and with Instagram
you started seeing guys that I'd maybe
never heard of or had never seen at a
show
um really getting on the scene and
taking off and you start seeing these
guys that you know they're on Instagram
and they look very like the baller type
thing going on like the compound guys
you know in their jet setting and flying
all over the world and they must make
all this money in their glass blowers
you know and so I had never seen that
before I'd never you know as far as
glass blowers I was like I know some of
us make some money but I don't think
anyone's getting rich off of it you know
and so Instagram kind of changed that to
where you know people are like oh these
glass bars make so much money and you
know some of the really talented guys
would fall off a little and you wouldn't
see them as much and you'd see these
guys that maybe weren't making the
greatest glass in the world just Rising
like crazy and that was definitely a
change in the industry oh for sure yeah
social media did it for sure yeah I mean
Facebook just kicked this all out you
know they didn't want to do with it oh I
can't have that that's not that's not
enough I mean Instagram is starting too
they're they're you know the leading
accounts right left and yeah glass and
seeds Road the same wave that way I
think like like as when when
growing up we knew like there were some
Dutch breeders that were pretty rich but
the idea of an American breeder making
serious money was a joke like right it
was funny and then Instagram came around
and you got to see like guys like flash
and Rolexes and stuff and everybody
assumed that all of us made a bunch of
money and
no no rent farmers at best I think the
majority of the glassblowers that play
that game too it probably has more to do
with the family they come from than the
um
you're only going to sell so many
fifteen thousand dollar pipes a year and
you can really only make so many a year
yes
you know I think that's one of the big
things that Instagram changed with the
industry for sure yeah Instagram really
uh introduced me more in detail into uh
dabbing and uh what we can do with
dabbing tools and concentrates and
making pieces specifically for
concentrates and just condense them down
to smaller more effective little pieces
that are more like for flavor and not so
much for a volume of smoke or you know
the size of the piece that could be so
big and so many percolors we're having
one little perk that works perfect with
enough of a chamber where it saves all
the flavor of your concentrate and that
that was another part of the line we
introduced to when we started having
these variety of pieces that are smaller
and more Compact and uh just function
ideally for concentrates and that was
kind of an Instagram thing for me too
because I started seeing more and more
people getting into it and all the like
the BHO stuff came and you know the
rosin and all this sure coming out so I
remember the first time we went to Vegas
what was that little show was the age
the small one at the hotel
uh yeah age and it was the first time I
had seen dab Riggs because uh I just it
never been in my circle before and I
remember we walked into the smoking room
and these guys are smoking on those dab
rigs and I looked at Emma and I was like
oh my god dude I think there's people
freebasing in the corner over there I
was like no dude they're just dabbing
you know like I swear like it it tripped
me out it'll do that it'll do that it
looks it looks really weird at first
when you first see it like especially if
you've you've been around other worlds
and stuff and you see that you're like
yeah
I mean this is this would be a weird
tangent because I sort of asked you a
little bit about it but I thought maybe
y'all could actually do a bit of a like
glass tick in two 2023 101 like what is
a percolator
what does it do
it's gonna break the smoke up in the
water
so that
I guess there's more surface area of
smoke hitting water
would you say yeah that's why different
different perks work differently I think
because when you have a smaller more uh
concentrated perk you'll get small
little tiny bubbles of smoke going
through the water so essentially less
smoke hits more water
than having the big chuggy like both
book action where like the big big
bubbles come through and a lot of the
smoke doesn't even touch the surface of
the water because of the bubbles going
through are larger so that makes sense
yeah I mean was this was this piece of
tech something that just like
sort of came out of nowhere did it
emerge slowly over time or I'd say it
happened yeah using it just using it you
realize that you get a smoother hit or
you get a smoother smoke that it's not
choking you up it's not you know you
don't get that crazy cough afterwards or
you just by you how did
how did the idea even come about I guess
well
how did it come about I you know I'd say
research and development this this is a
really competitive industry like I'm
sure all Industries are but if you're
not constantly coming out with something
slightly different or new
um You're Gonna Lose sales
so we have we have two trade shows a
year sometimes a few more than six well
sometimes yeah yeah I'd like to not
remember those but yeah let's let's say
we have trade shows every year you need
to have something new to get people
excited about your product every time
you go and if you don't your company is
going to get stale and people are gonna
get bored so it's more a fact of hey how
can we approve improve on designs that
we already have how can we get this pipe
to hit better how can we make the people
that want a larger volume of smoke
happier how do we get the people that
want small volumes of smoke happier you
know that's very true because we have
pieces that have the same item code that
they did 10 years ago but I don't want
to say it looks completely different but
it has progressed and has grown into the
piece that is today but where it started
and put them next to each other and
you'll see that you know this is yeah
not the same thing but it just kind of
like grew into that
yeah yeah I mean like uh you know like
Michael was saying it's an extremely
competitive environment so everyone's
forced to evolve really fast right
absolutely
um
okay what's a ratchet
okay uh how would I describe that
ratchet
um is the perk that that it's like a
disc with cuts at the end think about
like a uh a ratcheting tool that has a
Sprocket in it when you know it clicks
when you try to tighten the bolt or a
nut and and that's the inner part of it
and that's what we called it a ratchet
because it was the actual uh the perk in
the piece kind of reminded me of the the
gear that's inside the ratchet uh I have
I have because of this uh site up on
here and I'm trying to find where on the
site I could show it ratchet oh you just
lost a bunch um I'm pretty sure
the color pieces in the beginning you
show even the artwork ones they have
ratchet perks where those all the whole
Top Line well except the one on the
right is ratchet parts all right yeah
when you go down you'll see the cuts
right there
when we look at it from the bottom or
the top it looks like a gear right yeah
so it's a specific kind of perk yes yeah
yeah
right that one's really really sick I
like that it's cool yeah
yeah y'all I think y'all have no idea
how many people are like will be
learning encountering this for the very
first time
which is more predominant in a lot of
different companies ratchet perks we
came up with it it's our thing and
there's a lot a few different companies
that make it now and um but yeah it was
our thing and we're Kings of ratchets
the ratchet Kings yeah I mean yeah like
as a strained strained person and like
when I got into weed I really like
narrowly focused my my experience and
view on what I really really really
wanted to learn about and glass has
always been something I'm interested in
but never really jumped into because one
it is so expensive and when I go into
collecting anything I go all in and I
never wanted to go all in there because
that's all you can you can spend upwards
of a hundred thousand dollars on one
piece yeah easy reasons out there you
know yeah so yeah so all this is still
new to me too and I think there's gonna
be a lot of people that that have been
around for a long time that use pieces
that don't know much about the actual
industry the form what's gone into it
the history and any of it so this is
really really cool go back to the top of
the page there's a gallery section if
you hit that
um
yeah or actually the catalogs are well
yeah you can see one of the ratchets
being made here that's the base being
blown out and you can see the ratchets
inside but if you go to a catalog a lot
of the clear pieces are in there as well
and you'll be able to see
um our production line from simple
beakers to simple ratchet and just gets
bigger and crazier and crazier
and those yeah Parts in those pieces
because they are clear
let's see I don't let me see if I can uh
get mine up here I think this is like
double ratchet five millimeter double
ratchet yeah yeah
that is Matt's custom logo
one of the luckiest places to get
affordable American glasses right
through the greater Syndicate patreon
right there
I'm sorry I didn't catch what you said
um thousand yeah go ahead that's okay
that's okay
um
what's a recycler is that something
that's relevant to what you guys make um
I think there's one right there you
passed it
right there no that's not recycled
um now you guys scroll more but it
recycles the water so the essentially
the the water that the smoke bubbles
through it it'll pull the bubbles it'll
pull the smoke and the water in a
certain chamber and it will separate the
smoke to go up to the mouthpiece and the
water will go back down into the bottom
of the piece so essentially the water
keeps circulating around the piece over
and over
and that that is the recycling action
and we introduced a recycler back in the
day it was an internal recycler and most
people didn't even know what the [ __ ]
was going on it just didn't take off
because of that because people didn't
understand it you know we didn't explain
it very well yeah we just made it
through it out there and a few people
were so [ __ ] stoked about it and most
people were like what's going on you
know like I don't understand what the
what the thing is but now recycles are
huge and every company has recyclers it
doesn't always pay to be first yeah in
the industry it doesn't sometimes
sometimes it'll be too early it's like
I'm and I'm not I'm not a Dabber but
um recyclers are one of the most
overrated things I think in glass as far
as glass water pipes I have no idea if
you're a carnosurer and you get really
into it it's like the way you hit a
recycler is different you kind of start
hitting it before you put your
concentrate on it you got to kind of get
the water circulating and doing its
thing before you put your introduce your
concentrate so it does so yeah it's very
you know like that's what I say yeah
okay that makes a lot more sense then I
I don't smoke concentrate okay I was one
of the people that used recyclers for
for a week because I thought they hit
smoother but you did kind of have to hit
like like it hit it like yeah yeah
there's a cinder way you got to smoke it
and it's like uh very unfortunate you
know but it is it's great it does you
know it does what it needs to do it does
cool a little bit better you can use
more water with the recycles tend to
have more water and this is why we only
kept one recircular in our line uh which
is the mini one and uh
it's small but because of the recycling
action we're able to put a lot more
water into it otherwise if you didn't
have the recycling chamber it would suck
up the water through the mouthpiece
right it was just like a straw so the
recycling chamber kind of lets you put
more water and it separates the water
and the smoke so you don't get that
splash of water in your mouth and the
water shoots back down
I was a big fan of recyclers for or
until I got this ratchet they're like a
double ratchet one and that I was done I
was like oh my god I've been leveled up
in your mind but we have ratchet
recyclers oh my God
but the thing is like these are easy to
clean too and that was like another big
part of it because it's like yeah like
you have mine always clean and all this
is very easy to clean even the ash
catcher and usually ash catchers are
paying the ass to claim
that's one of the things we keep in mind
both of us yeah we [ __ ] hate dirty
pieces so making it easy to clean is
part of the functionality for us yeah
yeah I'm so jealous Matt like I pray
that one day uh I will get magic one of
those no yeah yeah
okay um through the magic of TV
oh it didn't work
um that was a really really cool dive
into the tech
um and if we I don't know I was
wondering if we want to come back to
the timeline you know where what have
you all been doing in the last few years
like what was covet like you know what
was what if the last few years been like
for you guys well it's been kind of
crazy uh my father passed away uh seven
years ago he was diagnosed with lung
cancer and uh unfortunately he didn't
beat it and um
a lot of different things happened the
Dynamics of the shop changed the whole
vibe of the place changed because he was
a he was a very big presence in both of
our lives really
um and then um well the original spot we
were at we moved in on a handshake
didn't even really have information on
me until that landlord passed away
because so many years are going by and
people are getting older you know and
now a new company took it over they
wanted more rent they didn't want us
using propane I'm like if I can't use
propane I can't have fire if I can't
have fire I can't make anything so
you're kicking me out basically you know
and so we had to worry about moving to a
different place and dealing with all
kinds of things and the Dynamics of the
company changing and then covet hit and
it was crazy it was good for a little
while where everybody had the stimulus
money and they were spending it on this
and that the business was good but then
that all changed and died out and we had
to actually stay relevant as um because
we were essential we were essential
because there was a splitter that was
used for a a ventilator thing for the
hospital that we never actually got into
I tried but the logistics for that was
uh [ __ ] ridiculous but because of
that one thing we're able to stay
working when it was only essential
workers only
oh wow so yeah you know that kind of
helped us stay in business because we
otherwise we couldn't really go back and
forth from work
but yeah it was a crazy time man like a
lot of things changed and we just kind
of took it took it as a cane
in as far as living in Los Angeles and
this is for me personally I'm not
speaking for Hamlet but uh covet had to
be one of the best times of my life
because all of a sudden there was no
traffic
I was living in Eugene again I didn't
have to see anyone
um
it was quiet our business complex was
empty it was it reminded me of living in
the country again yeah it was a
beautiful time we had more orders than
you could possibly imagine
um we were still working with the same
people that we work with and get to hang
out with every day I'm a you know a
little somewhat anti-social so
it just basically I didn't have to deal
with all the crazy people and all the
traffic and everything about La that I
didn't like yeah we're both kind of like
hermit crabs we don't really like to do
much yeah no
yeah I don't blame you la does that to
people though too I mean it's a very
fast-paced City and you're everybody's
so around each other yeah making very
anti-social real fast yeah where I am
sitting it just looks like exhausting to
be out in an environment like that
it can't be it really can be you kind of
have to like find your piece you know
like yeah for sure and weed helps a lot
yeah
sorry man what were you going to say
about Bakersfield I know like we were
one of the few places where covet just
didn't change anything because nobody
you like
everybody here was like ah that didn't
happen this didn't exist yeah so nothing
changed like everybody was just out
shopping
if you wear a mask it was weird
in L.A everyone would be masked up and
like hardly anyone's leaving their house
and then we drove to Idaho for a trip in
like maybe an hour and a half we got the
bishop like an hour and a half out of La
we stopped at a store and it's like
covet never was happening this is like
yeah time and I was like Wow none of
these people are wearing masks like yeah
well San when I went out to Alaska I was
like what the hell is this is only on
the news over here you know it's a whole
different world yeah yeah we were like a
little island in California of that
it was weird it was like Twilight Zone
yeah crazy yeah did you wear a mask when
you went out yeah you got a lot of dirty
looks but yeah they did
yeah
yeah yeah it was a weird time for
everyone geez
yeah
it did affect some things like you know
delivery of liquid oxygen and propane
and uh regular deliveries of glass
coming in because you know our glass was
from Germany and it it broke her to a a
different company that that supplies us
and that was a lot of issues with like
the shipping and the back backlog of
ships and all that so there was a lot of
issues with trying to get everything
because luckily we had enough of a back
stock to
kind of just work through it and and
change up some designs and things to
meet uh the sizing and tubings that we
have instead of what we can get you know
and they did cancel those shows so that
was really nice too yeah yeah we had
like a whole year almost of no trade
shows it was amazing yeah trade shows
are brutal they are brutal brutal people
don't understand if you don't know to be
a certain kind of person we hate them we
don't we don't like doing the trade
shows we have to when we do do them but
we I I can't stand them yeah as a small
business owner you have to sell in order
to make money you have to be a Salesman
and just for certain people like for me
and I know you guys probably are the
same where it's just like you have to
force yourself to do things like that at
all like I can't sell [ __ ] and then
eight hours a day of it
so the trade shows like we you know we
don't fit in yeah I know I know that
feeling I know that feeling it must be a
really strange
must be a really strange performance
I mean sometimes you know
you know business sales and and just
like putting up a front that's annoying
yeah
okay well is there anything else that
y'all wanted to highlight about you know
your overall Journey especially recently
because otherwise we can actually segue
into like
more like open chat I know uh Michael
you had a few other kind of like stories
anecdotes about
um strains that you encountered maybe
but yes anything else you wanted to say
about you know recent years
I
I don't know
since you guys probably don't know a lot
about the well it seems like it would be
apparent to me but
um the early glass blowing scene in
Eugene I can talk a little bit about
that in uh where I was fortunate maybe
where I wasn't
um that first glass shop that I worked
at was called Advanced Glassworks it
turned into Cascade glass works and then
turned into
um
Cornerstone Glass Works where's like the
DFO and all that stuff takes place you
know so there were a lot of glass
blowers coming through
um I had left I think I only worked at
that shop for maybe about seven months
before
I basically figured out I had uh
basically my best friend little Chris
that grew up with me there in Eugene uh
we were both working there and uh we
looked at it and we were like hey you
know we could buy these torches on our
own and all these supplies and just do
this in our garage
and uh that's pretty much what we did we
went out on our own we had very limited
knowledge at the time
um we got really lucky though because we
ran into a handful of people
um there was a guy named Maddie that was
uh I was friends with through a couple
other glass blowers from that shop that
would teach us really cool different
techniques
um we went to a Hemp Fest at Bill
conde's place which is in Oregon it used
to be like a yearly Gathering and uh
that's where I met Marcel and I asked
him about teaching me techniques and he
was very generous with information
and uh it kind of leapfrogged me to
being able to support myself without
having to work for other people you know
and I I feel like I was really fortunate
because back then people really held the
information tight they didn't want to
share any techniques they didn't on
anyone stealing their Thunder and uh I
just I I've got real fortunate that
those those two groups of people
um
kind of taught me techniques that
carried me all the way to California and
being able to start a small company on
my own you know most of the guys that I
originally learned to blow glass with uh
stalled out and quit because we didn't
have the the education that Hamlet was
able to get through his dad and his dad
where he wanted to teach me everything
instead of trying to keep them when you
go to class or you take a glassblowing
studies or anything like that there's a
lot of information they don't pass along
because they don't want they don't want
it to pass like you said they don't want
it to get to other people's hands they
didn't want to leave them they want to
keep the art to themselves but with me I
was it was the other way around he
wanted to teach me everything he knew
you know and yeah I was fortunate in
that aspect of it
oh my God it's like it's like people
with clones in the in the weed world
like how in certain groups loans to some
but don't pass it to that guy yeah that
makes sense right and there'd be like
trade baiting type of things going on
where oh I'm sure you know I I'd run
into someone that would tell you how to
incorrectly do a technique so that they
could roll you off that path you know
similar to hey this is Kim D when wow
yeah it's so dirty it's so dirty it'd be
a simple little like you know tips and
tricks that are part of the trade you
know unless they tell you like you're
watching it you might not even catch it
because it's a Split Second
of what can happen that you didn't see
because very minute things in Glasgow
make a big difference
so you know it's just like that like you
said it
people kept the things to themselves
you know and uh thousand I know this may
be a little less to do with
um the glass but I wouldn't mind talking
about some of the herb that I saw go
through those shops between uh oh yeah
let's do it Baker design I think we're
ready for that yeah you know because
um obviously I've heard not so talk
about some of them and some of that
information he gets from guys that I
blew glass with and that were real close
friends of mine in Eugene you know
um there's so many strains from Eugene
bro
these glassblowing circles in Eugene
you know uh before the Bubba kushes and
the OG cushions I'd never seen those uh
in in Oregon at least at that point but
uh I do remember very early on
I'd say 96 97 we've started seeing a lot
of blueberries
um
not dj I know Matt might disagree with
this but they weren't DJ Short
blueberries it's very possible no I
don't disagree with that that it seems
to be there's stories of I've seen so
many seeds popped from DJ and I just
never saw the blueberry we were getting
past yeah you know it had a really
really distinct nose on it and it had a
spicy pure blueberry fruit Jam taste to
it it had real Crimson hairs and they
were that little round notes
you know
um the Trinity I remember the first time
that came through super early
um that's not the ones I wanted to hear
about yeah absolutely amazing I know not
so and I have different descriptions of
what we get from it but I think some of
that has to do with what we think a
skunk is I know he he's mentioned the
Trinity being really skunky to me that
wasn't really skunky that had more of
like a soft pillowy sour skunk
you get the to it whereas we used to get
a strain in Eugene called the Mudbud or
The Afghani Thai and it was long Spears
it was really really dark green with
orange hairs and it's smelled like dead
skunk for a long ways away oh wow and it
was the skunkiest thing we ever seen you
know I I don't know if it's the same
kind of Super Skunk the guys that had it
in Oregon were bikers
um but it was the skunkiest weed we had
ever seen I mean if it's an Afghani Tai
if they got that right it wouldn't be a
super skunk it sounds awesome though it
sounds like you know what I mean like
yeah I think there's skunky weed way
outside of Super Skunk I just think what
super skunk has is some of the best and
most accessible versions of it that we
have but there's got to be like a lot
more out there this pure afghanis and
different things and different hybrids
from different eras that are like that
and it's so hard if you haven't
experienced what you know for a hundred
percent is super skunk
it's hard to know yeah because yeah
always from where I'm sitting maybe I'd
see Super Stone can be like oh my God
that's even skunkier than that Afghan
yeah you know but from my experience
that was the skunkiest thing I had seen
um we used to get amazing AK-47 at that
shop just big pillowy pretty buds what
was that do you remember the scent on
the AK-47 you guys saw I thought it
smelled like Sandalwood okay so you guys
got the sandal what do you type I've
heard of that one there's a really
lovely spicy Woody
yeah
you know I I've never seen the Cherry
Jerry's nice guy and uh Maui Wowie and
[ __ ] white widow coming through
randomly back in the days and it was
like I don't know where it came from who
had it but it just ended up at the shop
you know how was it how did you like it
I loved it um the [ __ ] white widow
that I experienced back then it was
frostiest like just snow-covered looking
buds I've ever seen in my life and it
tasted amazing
um
yeah I don't know where or where it
originated or who had it what but like I
said ended up at the shop and the
chocolate tattoo that was random that
was from an old veteran buddy of mine
that I had he just randomly came up with
some chocolate ties like I know I know
you never smoked this before check this
out you know you know wow he just
busting out like Thai stick
and then I looked into it more and I was
more and more amazed by it yeah that's
awesome
um the Trinity I have to agree with you
like but there is questions about like
whether the Trinity cut that we have now
is the same as the old Trinity cut you
know but the one that we have now that
people say and they smell smell skunky
to me it doesn't smell skunky it smells
musty like that's about the best I can
get it's musty it's not sweet
and then I just leave it there because I
can't my nose can't develop it much more
but it's not skunky as I would qualify
it you know yeah I the one I remember
wasn't either I remember when the snow
first came into Eugene about that same
time that the Trinity did that one was
excellent
um we used to get a Korean skunk there
in Eugene and I can't remember if that
was from Amos
I don't remember if it was I think it
probably was he's the only person I've
ever seen have a Korean skunk ever yeah
it made its way through Eugene it was a
really spicy purple haired nice little
Frosty buds I would love to experience
that that was great
um it's like a backbone of a lot of his
lines my favorite out of all of them was
uh that quindy when that Quimby came
into the shop the first time it was one
of the most impressive strains I'd ever
seen the nose was just so unique and it
smelled so strong and it wasn't skunk
strong it was more of uh
just I don't know like some kind of
candied
um Candy dank I don't know how to
describe it
but
um some of those old school stuff that I
I can remember to this when when I get
something today and it's like oh it's
this or that I'm like I don't remember
it this way I don't remember and like it
smelled different to me it was you know
and I can never almost I can never find
it again
yeah
it's pretty common because like a lot of
people didn't keep those same old cuts
and you know they just didn't stay
popular and sometimes they get a second
wind and people just try to capitalize
on the name and don't have access to
those groups or those cuts they kept
them yeah so a few people do
yeah I feel like I just repeated a whole
not so statement right there
could have just inserted him
you know we used to get some really nice
Northern Lights that's uh not I mean we
would get Northern Lights number five
too also that was super boring but we
would get like a dank dark green
Northern Lights that was really really
nice
um
those are the strains that I really
remember like circulating heavily
in those shops like we would always have
access to one of those and they were
always good there's a few others I just
can't remember the name of anymore there
was a couple hash plants that had
special names Hench but that was when I
came to California yeah yeah
yeah you said Amos and I just realized
most people have no idea who you're
talking about or who we're talking about
you're referring to Soma Amos Washington
yeah
yeah and and what you're talking about
is the backbone I think to Lavender and
stuff like that
um did you have a lot of experience with
him there did you ever have run-ins
within there or any of that you gotta
remember
um
we were pretty young I'm trying to think
thanks for stopping man into him I was
probably 15 years old yeah and uh he was
well known for uh dry sifting his bag
but you got him so you could go and get
weed from Amos and uh you'd look at it
and it's still it was still good weed we
didn't really know any better to be
honest with you but what you could be
guaranteed is that Amos would [ __ ]
bong hit of about the best sift you
could ever imagine that you just paid
for yeah you know and the reason his
buds were always a very uniform
roundness to them in the same size yeah
so funny dude they look like bags of
like the little marbles yeah you know
but um but he did that story before yeah
he had great weed there was a you know
Eugene had a lot of those weird older
hippie characters in it that
every once in a while take advantage of
younger kids you know in one way or
another
I remember there was this guy I got
introduced to named Michael golden
and he swore up and down the eagle Bill
stole his design for the vaporizer at
the High Times Cannabis Cup
and would just gets so angry about it
you know and uh he was the first one I
saw with that heat gun and it was a real
vaporizer but
um what he had that really impressed me
Matt was he had about 20 packs of seeds
and this was
okay I was probably 17 at the time
so this had to be like 94 maybe 95
94. and uh he had these packs of seeds
that were from Corvallis Oregon with
this really cool Beaver logo on them and
he would tell me like each one of these
varieties and they were created
um early 80s and he's been holding on to
them forever and that was like the first
time I ever really saw packaged seeds
that were American and not Canadian
wow and who was this guy his name was
Michael golden
um the guys from uh
God it's not Pharmacy Factory uh what's
uh
the elephant logo
um honeysuckle Lotus
yeah those guys they're from uh
Mendocino well they're from Oregon but
they live in Mendocino they introduced
me to him
um I don't know if we were selling him
weed or we were buying weed from him I
can't remember but he was the guy that
swore up and down that eagle Bill stole
his design for the vaporizer and Eagle
Bill had won a Cannabis Cup with his
design
man so do you know a guy named Petrie
Joe Petrie Joe Petrie that's familiar he
had a book I think they called the king
of Nepal
I I can't recall the name okay it sounds
like a very similar character I was just
wondering yes it's very similar
character all right Fells it's been fun
but unfortunately I have to go um being
great having you dude we really
appreciate you being on thank you so
much Hamlet right on you guys have a
good one now you guys yeah you guys get
the full Michael now good luck foreign
yeah there were a couple of points
Michael that you wanted to touch on that
we discussed yesterday one was your
first year in California and the other
one was Josh d
which one we always do that oh you know
it was it was not necessarily just Josh
D it was my experience with uh getting
introduced to Californian weed because
um what a lot of my friends nowadays
have a hard time believing
is that uh this is kind of off topic
thousand I'm sorry but every once in a
while during harvest season in Oregon
guys would bring up weed from Humboldt
that was outdoor and it was so [ __ ]
good and everyone always had this thing
where oh Outdoors mids you know it's not
that great indoor is like the Holy Ghost
I remember getting outdoor weed that was
so good from some of those kids that it
rivaled any indoor I'd ever had
you know and uh even Hamlet I've had
this argue with them a million times
where he's like I've never seen good
outdoor weed I'm telling them it just
doesn't get here we don't know the right
people here it exists you know do you
disagree man I just didn't I don't know
I you know what but I don't have much
experience with it so I can't speak on
it you know what I mean like I want to
say I haven't seen it because I haven't
but I also didn't live in an epicenter
where like a bunch of outdoor was
shipped we had shitty brickweed growing
up and then we had everything else yeah
see I never saw a brick of weed till I
moved to California yeah see we had that
growing up and that's all we had so like
you know trying to call Outdoor shitty
compared to that is kind of hard
yeah yeah I could see that I just I
remember some of the outdoor beans so
good but um so right before Y2K
I got moved from Eugene Oregon uh down
to Los Angeles I've been in a situation
in Eugene where
um my glass shop was in my house and I
had come home from I don't remember I
might have been into girlfriends or out
hiking with my dogs but I pulled up to
my house and there was three undercover
cars and a bunch of cops in my house
and I pulled up and I asked uh one of
the officers I said what's going on this
is my house
and they tried to tell me that
um they had chased a suspect he had
jumped over the fence and they thought
he went into my house
and so um I walked in my house they're
all in my living room they're in my
little glass shop and I'm like hey
um so I'm assuming the guy is already
here and uh they start asking me all
sorts of questions like what's going in
the glass shop you know uh what's all
what are these gases for uh this isn't
for cooking meth right and I'm like no
no no I don't know anything about that
and uh
at the end they you know basically find
there's nothing there for them other
than you know some glass pipes which a
new Gene isn't a big deal and uh they
leave and I call the police department
and I start asking questions and they
tell me that they never had any officers
in my area that night
so the next day I go down to the Fifth
Street Market and I talk to a lawyer
that was always at The Hemp Fest
you know and I ask him to look into it
and he makes some calls like I gave him
like 200 retainer and uh he told me
um
at this point they're telling him that
this never happened that I'm imagining
that they never had any officers in the
area and his personal recommendation to
me would be to move somewhere else
you know wow I told him you know I I
don't really have too much illegal
involvement other than the glass blowing
and he just told me you know for my own
safety maybe it'd be better if I did
move
um I started talking to my distributor
down in California and they offered to
move me down there to start a glass
blowing company wow they would give me
the money and a place to live and set me
up
um the guy the guys that did that on a
chain of stores in Los Angeles called uh
dementia and at the time they owned Roar
and later that became uh heavy glass and
Sheldon black okay okay
so they moved me down and uh the guy
that is kind of coordinating all this is
the manager for all the head shops and
he's lived in the San Fernando Valley
his whole life he's real real connected
yeah so um I was fortunate in that way
because I was worried about coming down
to LA and not being able to get herb
this is before they had stores you know
yeah oh yeah
so I moved down to LA
and the first thing he does is he
introduces me to a guy named Joel OG
glass
who uh had grown up and Reseda so he was
real uh connected too and he was
probably one of maybe 10 glassblowers
that were known down here okay and so
what was really cool about that was he
was real connected with Oregon kid with
Josh D with all these guys so within the
first few months of me living in La I
was able to buy my first bag from Oregon
kid which was Bubba Kush for 450.
amazing oh yeah we hadn't I hadn't seen
anything with that particular smell and
taste in Oregon and I was really
expecting to come down to California and
think especially Los Angeles and think
they didn't have anything to offer me
yeah I had already lived in the Pinnacle
of marijuana yeah for sure that was
without knowing I had grown up in the
Pinnacle of berry marijuana yeah so
um
few weeks maybe after that Bubba Kush I
I uh got to go over to Josh D's house
with Joel
handed over 500 bucks for my first mason
jar of OG
with him I think at the time he was a
photographer
and uh
it was one of the most amazing things
I'd ever smelled I was just like holy
[ __ ] now I definitely haven't ever
smelled any weed like this before it had
a golden color it wasn't like a dark
green or anything it was like a nice
cured brownish gold and it was just
[ __ ] fantastic yeah I I have a hard
time recalling ever seeing OG growing or
looking and smelling that great as I did
from Josh
um that first month I also got
introduced to a couple guys in Hollywood
and that's where I first saw the
tangerine
and their big bud
um what they called
the NorCal big bud was uh not like the
Amsterdam big bud this was like a pure
sweet skunk big bud how interesting it
was really nice the buds weren't big I I
you know like they they weren't like
huge colas like I'd expect there's
another misnomer yielded huge she said
oh okay I gotcha that was the pull of
that big butt but his Tangerine was
again one of the most unique things I'd
ever smelled in weed what was that
Tangerine like
um
pure
pure Tangerine juice it's not what tangy
it's Tangy has nothing to do with that
tanji is gross in my opinion I think
it's gross that tangerine
was gifted to Oregon kid okay right
after my friend got busted and
um we basically all closed down shop
and didn't want to lose it it was it's
my favorite weed I've ever had it's been
that tangerine
and uh he got it and changed the name to
skunk tangerine
skunk Tangerine I'm trying to think of
what I have with that in it now you can
find it on um
certain
unreputable clone dealers menus I'm sure
Oregon kids shared it with them with the
promise that it wouldn't be let out
which of course this guy who you've had
running it running I'm sure now sells it
but um it's a 12 to 13 week
sativa that doesn't get too tall but it
yields great and it grows bats
like just huge arm length colas of some
of the most smelliest beautiful fruit
you know it puts Tangy to shame you know
yeah like I like a good orange I like a
good sweet orange myself like that
smells like sun-kissed orange juice like
that I do not like Tangy because it's
never smelled like that to me it's like
an orange rind or it's super muted yeah
so it's almost like maybe a descendant
or a bag seat from that original
Tangerine or something like that but
it's not the same I think I've seen Mean
Gene comment about him seeing it before
and it having huge bats but I know the
name was changed it was never skunk
Tangerine when yeah at it you know
as a little bit of a tangent but also
just to add some context
um
what do you like smoking these days
um and I wonder if you could actually
answer that for Hamlet as well if yet if
you knew
Hamlet loves Quimby
Quimby's an old Oregon strain
you know what's in it no idea
no idea
um when I lived in Eugene when the
dentist yeah okay when the dead tour
ended
there was like an influx of people that
left the the tour and moved to Eugene
and Quimby came around that same time
that all those hippies and the heroine
and all that stuff came to Eugene when
the tour ended yeah you know there was
positive the negatives when the tour
ended
you know
um a lot more drugs but a lot of new
strains Quimby was one of them
and uh it was just real real unique
I don't I don't know how else to
describe it
interesting
um I know not so has experience with it
yeah I think I think uh JD or one of
them used it or something
okay there you go Whittaker Blues there
you go that's why it's in my memory bank
yeah absolutely
um I haven't because I still smoke that
today he doesn't yeah no that's oh wow
okay it's not the pure Quimby something
that was
um
I think DJ had a Vanilla Kush any fan of
Luna okay so yeah a male from that was
used to pollinate the coinbee okay and
then Fino was found that's real real
close to that original
fascinating that's as best as I can get
for you how about you yourself what do
you like smoking these days
I really like not so sour I was really
surprised it didn't give me I I as I get
older
my likelihood of having panic attacks
smoking potent weed has gone through the
roof yeah sure yeah there's certain
things that um I joke about it but if I
smoke certain things I'm going to be in
the bathtub with my wife assuring me
that I'm gonna be okay for an hour yeah
dude just the reality of my situation
now Jewish I wish more more uh males our
age in our age group would talk about it
because I think it's way more common
than anybody realizes to have these like
[ __ ] major panic attacks even like
because I dab all day long and I smoke
flour interchangeably but there's times
when flower will just set me off in a
totally different direction and spin me
out and just give me a panic attack and
I don't know it didn't happen when I was
young but I don't know if hormonally as
we get older some of us it like just
affects us much get more different I I'm
almost 100 more things to worry about
it's hormonal yeah
things you worry about is adults too
you know I I think it's hormonal yeah I
feel like there are some strains like if
I am mad if I smoke Oracle I'm in the
bathtub yeah same to me dude yeah
there's even if it's just a little bit
I'll be in the bathtub yeah
um not so sour uh definitely relaxed me
made me feel a lot better
um the pineapple fields from Dynasty has
a real nice put me in a happy place
um
effect for me I guess
um I got some Riot Berry I'm getting
ready to try I'm hoping that that does
it too because yeah me too
make me feel real real good and I'm
hoping that I it's been so long since
I've had blueberry I'm hoping it can do
the same for me again I hope because
this mind descends from DJ's blue
blueberry so I hoped that
it just having the same scent expression
brings back some of those uh same I
don't know however they combine out of
the cannabinoids combine or you know
whatever because I know that anything
that typically has DJ's blueberry in it
whether it's a hybrid or full whether
it's blueberry scented or not usually
it's cool but usually if it has a
blueberry scent it's it's totally
anti-anxiety for me yeah so yeah it's
weird it sounds like you have a very
similar body chemistry or brain
chemistry to me when it comes to strains
it's it's weird it's ours you know some
people look at me really weird when I
talk about it like [ __ ] you know but
it's for real you know and I liked your
one suggestion I heard you say on one of
the shows where you were like I just
smoked so much so that my tolerance
doesn't get low enough to where it
affects me that way as much yeah that's
the only thing I can do I had a little
more free time where I could experiment
with that you know you know what really
helped me was with when I learned about
like dabbing and [ __ ] because dabbing
just doesn't hit me that way ever
because it's just for me it's always the
same effect it's real boring but it it
raised my tolerance for THC up so high
that usually I don't get that but still
even even you know dabbing diamonds all
day it'll happen it'll happen and it's
not
it's it's real weird I used to think it
was all THC related but if I'm flooding
myself with THC and it still happens
only with flour on odd occasions I I
just don't know what causes it it sucks
yeah and to be honest Urkel and Bubba
are the two biggest and it's funny
because I hear people say that [ __ ] is
not potent it doesn't get them high it
has low highs and then if I smoke Urkel
or bubble Bubba I'm running for the
hills yeah no and I don't know why I
don't think it's necessarily potent I
just think that it hits Us in such a
strange way and it's not not about
potency it's just about what the [ __ ]
you know yeah
the fear is there so
yeah but I think um I'll definitely be
getting to try a lot more things this
year you know now that we're lucky
enough to be able to have you know such
great freedoms in California where we
can have six whole plants
yeah I know right
experiment with trying some some of the
new stuff some of the old stuff you know
like right
what are you interested in
uh for herb
yeah like what what do you think you
might be interested in in running that
you haven't run before you know thousand
what I'm most interested in and excited
for is
popping beans that are made by people
that I can feel good about supporting
um hell yeah I think there's enough
people in this industry at this point
that can get lucky or pick a male to
pollinate a bunch of clones with that
there's a ton of good seeds and like at
this point it'd probably be hard to find
Bad Seeds unless you're buying from one
of the big companies I do get excited
about is being able to
participate in people that
I really know have a valid story and a
valid love of the plan and our breeding
for specific reasons you know like I
love Trace dog so I'm gonna cross it
with this other thing that I really love
and hopefully it passes on this instead
of just guys that say
um I've got grape gas I'm just going to
S1 it onto every single cookie stable
yeah you know and I'm sure all those
things they could have marvelous plants
in them yeah but I want to support guys
that are breeding
and on a mission
you know and kind of be able to follow
those
I don't know if I'd call them stories or
not but I want to follow their
theoretical ideas and see if they match
up and see if I can experience those
same things that they experience yeah
you know yeah I I think I
go ahead I think I just think that like
one important aspect of this is
connection and feeling like in growing
someone's work you are connected to
them their projects you know
um a wider Community my aspect
that's right
I got you with an aspect
you know I think that's one of the
really cool things it's one of the
really cool things about breeder
syndicate is
um
I can feel really good about throwing my
support
towards certain people
you know because uh
like back in the day Gypsy Nirvana I
don't want to throw my money at guys
that go overseas to have sex with little
girls like that is gross I don't want my
money going there my first name I ever
bought were from dark enemy and you know
yeah I grew some great NL skunk Mighty
might it was amazing the smells unique I
was happy but you know what I don't need
my money going into the pocket of some
[ __ ] crazy right-wing person yeah you
know like why am I gonna support that I
don't want to support guys that jet set
all over the world and wear big gold
necklaces and play these games when
I know back in Oregon the people that
actually know them know they've never
grown any [ __ ] places you can touch
the plants ever yeah it's very common
and then I meet people down here and I'm
like oh you know they have these
facilities down here I'm like wow what
are you doing in here oh we're making a
ton of seeds I was like what's your seed
company oh no we make it for this guy
yeah exactly and I'm like whoa that guy
that guy's I was like does he make the
choices yeah
yeah because this is my experience of a
lot of the industry especially before I
came to the breed of Syndicate like
everything's really like
uh faceless lifeless soulless uh
alienated isolated it's just like
um nothing seemed nothing felt real
um until I found you know some of some
of these guys here
yeah you know like I want to be excited
about genuine people that care about the
things that I care about
okay even if my garden is only six
plants
it's what brings me happiness at the end
of the day
you know it's it's not a freedom it's
just what they're allowing us basically
yeah but it's what brings me back to a
time in my life when I was super free
and I was
more concerned with myself yeah right
and more concerned with just happiness
yeah you know so if I can get in with
guys like h l and pack and Matt and God
I hope not so at some point you know and
follow their journeys of what they
experience and what their favorite
things are
I get to share a little piece of their
life and we can share it with each other
absolutely yeah for sure
yep
I feel that too even being all the way
out here it's been uh it's been a real
Joy yep I'm never gonna have to drag him
out one day all the way from whatever
he's from Australia or somewhere I don't
know
where the accent's from
so yeah to be more specific I look
forward to popping some high-end
Lonesome this year
um nice I just got done popping some
that I'm gonna pop some uh some goat
some goat farm
yeah high on lonesome's got a a new
Green Crack BX coming out real soon too
I saw that yeah I'm gonna go with the
stone ape no one else anyone else pop it
yeah
let's get some feedback on that puppy
yeah yeah I became to see that for sure
yeah I I generally
um I'm real narrow in my seat by at this
point in my life like oh wow isn't going
towards Matt or CSI yeah
high and Lonesome You Know It uh Dynasty
is the only one that I've really messed
with outside of that and I've been happy
with he's got good stuff too he's good
he's got a good eye for male sativas
he's got beautiful have you ever seen
his pictures yeah oh my God he's all but
he's always been that way dude like back
in the um three day days on the forums
yeah he's a photographer yeah but like
back I remember when sub cool used to
rip it up like of all the photographers
sub cool was just he was one of the best
when it came to taking pictures of
beautiful plants that no no one did it
better but I remember Dynasty got on his
site he was taking pictures and he him
and this dude oh cannabis well just
stepping It Up level after level and
yeah dude he's made a good name for
himself he's been around a long time and
he's kept his his strains unique and uh
his own identity and I appreciate that a
lot he's cool
and you know what Matt out of everything
I popped from him it's look like those
pictures yeah yeah that's and that's
another thing that's important right
like that you know you're getting what
he tells you you're gonna get absolutely
and that's that's a part of the art of
it I would say you know like when you
can deliver on something and say this
this thing that I haven't bought myself
I have I've worked with this enough that
I can predict how this is gonna the
outcome of this and it and I can show
you these pictures but I can ensure you
it's going to look like this that's
something special and a lot of that's
been missing for a long time
especially when it's not just uh you
know cushman's by whatever clone yeah
you're a big seed breeder but yeah
you're gonna know it's gonna look like
cushman's you know yeah yeah you know I
I like that unique stuff I I was doing
like I was I've been you know like doing
strain reviews lately and like looking
at the new strains because I don't know
[ __ ] about any strains and I probably
should because of the show so I was
looking up these different ones like
Blue Sushi and stuff and I didn't
realize this because because of their
names and obviously I should be
if you shouldn't shock me or anything
but there is no blueberry in it and
there's no there's nothing called Sushi
it was like a cushman's skittles yeah it
was a cushman's right like what like
what that Cushman Skittles has been done
for years you're they're still pushing
this but just gave it a new name again
yeah bro that's greater of the Year
magic magic magic magic magic
how they do it every time Magic
reader of the Year apples and bananas
baby it's all super unique yeah you know
it was funny is that um there's a dude
named dirt farmer genetics that had just
released in apples and bananas that year
too
yeah I got run over by uh compounds well
not even his release I don't I think I
know who made that but I don't want to
say because they probably don't want
people to know they made it for him so
yeah
no but he'll he'll happily take credit
and for sure extra uh necklace he'll
take that too yeah he will he likes them
Rolexes yep
so I could go on for hours an hour
well I mean we are we are coming up on
the two hour mark so you know is are
there any other things that you two
wanted to
touch on before we wrap this up
is anything specific you had
a thousand or me you
yeah
no I think I got a lot of that out there
um
wish I had more for you guys I mean are
you are you guys still in touch with Ken
today Oregon kid
it came down uh Last Christmas I think
it was last Christmas and hung out for a
few hours in the shop
um other than that
I'm I haven't talked to him except for a
few messages on Instagram yeah asking uh
you know
when can we hook back up and trade or
whatever
um it's just a fascinating part of the
OG story you know and it's always
interesting when people meet him early
on and have their Impressions and all
that
you know he he was a real sweet he well
no he still is yeah Thane was he hasn't
changed he's a sweet guy yeah he's
through a lot he's one of those guys
that was real early on yeah
um and in my eyes got taken advantage of
like crazy
yeah you know like he uh he had some
physical limitations but he should still
he's pretty talented with cannabis yeah
he is I don't know if you know this but
he's bred some really cool [ __ ] yeah oh
and he should still be you know in
everybody's mouth like doing cool [ __ ]
like a lot of these guys do and he's not
for whatever reason and I don't know if
that's personal choices he's made or
just the fact that
people are going to take advantage of
you if you put yourself in situations to
get taken advantage of take advantage I
I've attributed most of my like early
career to him and and kept him going
like that because I thought like because
I I did so much with the banana OG like
he was such an important part of what
people attributed to me and um even
Bubba because he played such a major
part with that you know and um yeah I
think he deserves a lot more credit than
he gets too and it's a shame because he
was an important part of all that for a
lot of us a lot of us and banana OG is
still being used out the wazoo could you
imagine if he hadn't paid that money for
the OG Kush clone from Josh what would
have happened with OG Kush I can't
imagine yeah it would have been locked
down so much further for longer
absolutely yeah you know like that thing
was hard to get he made that accessible
for everybody we should all be thankful
just like
um the chems yeah
yeah exactly they were made accessible
forever but they were and we were
fortunate to have them yeah yeah we are
we are
whether we like the guys that had them
or not exactly that doesn't quite matter
you know it doesn't matter the fact that
they're still available in uh
yeah even that Bubba Kush bro that thing
was [ __ ] amazing real amazing yeah
when he had it you know I never got the
coffee stuff from it mine was always
more lime
but it was beautiful there's a lot of
different ways you can grow Bubba and
it's one of those plants where like I I
can get it earthy coffee I can get it
almost chocolatey I can get it soapy
cushy you know you can get lime out of
it definitely you know
um there's a lot in Bubba depending on
how you grow it and the s1s there's a
lot of variation too there's there's all
lemon Finos in the s1s that show up yeah
I'm looking forward to someday popping
about it yeah I think I think CSI just
CSI just popped in another 100 or two
just to run through them to see what's
in there again
yeah yeah CSI
yeah
I wish I had that much space man
you know these guys are living our Dream
yeah he really is you know every once
while I'll get hit up you know by a
younger guy and they're just like oh bro
the glass thing is so awesome you know
and it's like uh
I got in the glass because I loved weed
roller coaster so that I can continue on
into weed you know because I've never
been great at being social yeah so I I
could do the glass blowing and get in
the circles I wanted to you know and it
turned out for me but I'd rather live uh
Caleb's dream than this dream you know
yeah I you know like I'm so fascinated
by different art like and I've done the
seed stuff for so long I'd be more into
the glass thing now I'd be like wow just
to learn a whole new trade as opposed to
more seeds
[Music]
more seeds but then again if I if I was
doing it at a csi's level it'd be a
different story though because like that
much space you can really really have
options run through some fantasies yeah
dude to be able to see things in that
large of populations always and and I
shouldn't say to be able to he has been
out of all out of everyone he's been the
most inclusive of anyone in in those big
projects with me like it's it's
I just don't take it for granted it's
one of those things where like a mentor
is showing you like how it's done like
it's crazy to be able to see that and to
get insight into each one of those and
then he spends time with that it's
really cool though and it really works
hard yeah I hope we'll be able to share
it again soon on the on the Bubba stuff
if he does another episode here soon so
yeah when Matt jeez we need to start
beating on his door hey dude everyone
yeah yeah everything
um
I just want to say that this has been
such a cool conversation like we got
such a such a neat overview as well on
like the glass scene yeah you know from
like Bob Snodgrass Eugene operation pipe
dreams science glass
um Import Glass like we basically got
all these lovely Milestones from YouTube
um and I think anyone from anywhere
wanting to learn about at least you know
uh get an idea of the history of of
glass pipes like this has been such a
great conversation
um yeah
yeah I think we could probably take it
you know if you ever wanted to because
we barely touched on each one of those
things in in brief segments so if
there's anything you want to expand on
and if anybody has any questions about
anything they heard in this episode let
us know give us feedback and we'd love
to have them back it's been a really fun
one and I mean I just sat here and
learned I kind of stayed shut up those
people were just like you know because
this is yeah informative for me I love
it I suspect that this is not the last
time we will see uh Michael AKA spindle
yeah hopefully not
yeah any anytime there's anything you
guys want to ask feel free if there's
anything you feel like I didn't cover
well enough and you have more questions
a thousand please
I don't know if I covered covered this
well enough uh this is some of the glass
yeah and realistically like
when we we met up and I tried it like no
[ __ ] these became my only pieces not
because like this had this thing even
been talked about or exist became my my
favorite pieces because of function and
that's why we even started talking and
you started talking to me because you
love [ __ ] strains and weed and we
just kind of dorked out together and
it's been really amazing and like I said
there's only a few times in life when
you get leveled up on on something that
you love and I felt like I got leveled
up in in smoking functionality with you
guys and and I appreciate that so thank
you very much
quickest from point A to B that's right
man it's all it takes you avoid veering
off into that [ __ ] sea yeah
you know
so
um I think if if you're trying to wrap
it up thousand there's a couple things I
wanted to go over for anybody that might
be younger in the audience I know how to
do it have some years ago number one
um do not this older generation of seed
makers these guys in their late 30s to
40s to 50s don't build them up into
something they're not they're just guys
don't
follow people blindly and fight for them
if you don't know what they're about
they're just guys making seeds enjoy
what they do enjoy their seeds but don't
build people up because they're going to
be constantly constantly torn down it's
going to bum you out yeah
um
two
glass bowling is one of the last
American handmade
Industries you know there's not a lot of
things that you can buy in America
anymore that is made by Americans and
glass is one of them it doesn't have to
be C2 support American Glass there's not
a big enough price difference to throw
your money at some Sweatshop that's not
taking care of its people yeah
and uh three for the younger generation
I know a lot of people are hurting
they're not going to have money to
travel around the world I was very
fortunate young I got to go to Europe
um there's a thing I found in France
called a bidet
younger generation
it's not that it's not manly
spray water on your ass it's the fact
that no one wants to shake hands with
someone
whose ass was only a small hand was only
a small tissue
between [ __ ] and your handshake yes
thank you get yourself a bidet
and smeared [ __ ] on your arm
would you be comfortable using a handful
of paper towels and just wiping that
clean and then going about your business
I don't think you've ever never
I don't think I've been lucky enough to
go to Japan a couple of times and I
gotta say I do love the bidet now yeah
absolutely it's a small upgrade for your
house you don't have to eat it's like 30
bucks 30 bucks on Amazon
you'll be clean the rest of your life do
it for everybody let's stop the next
pandemic yes see something [ __ ] related
it could be and it could be because
you're not using bidets absolutely and
it's really definitely feels much better
when you walk around absolutely you want
an itchy [ __ ] no nobody likes that
nobody likes that dude you know stinky
fingers suck no this is definitely how I
envisioned us concluding this episode
well you know one of the things I want
to leave something for the younger guys
I want to be able to share some of my
experiences yeah hygiene grooming tips
it's something important it was
life-changing
I feel like I'm not lying
don't idolize don't pedestal and also
clean your butt properly yeah they're
important by America and by American
glass yeah
yep all righty
That's it man hey I really appreciate
you guys we love you man
um yeah thank you so much dude and and
thank you to Hamlet as well yeah so I
guess uh that's it from reader Syndicate
be sure to check out our patreon um we
have our Discord where we all hang out
and chat and talk about
strains whatever daily life stuff
sometimes but it's a it's a nice
community of great people and uh yeah
check that out and I'll add one little
thing here yeah good which is that
people who have been asking about not so
you could join the Discord and you get
to talk to not so he's actually really
responsive on Discord and he's he hangs
out quite a lot right
right right so if you're missing him at
the moment and uh you know if we're not
at 10 000 subscribers yet you can jump
on the Discord and talk to him
and just for anyone that hasn't before
these guys make themselves so accessible
on that Discord I I can't believe it you
can message not so almost any time of
the day
and within an hour he will answer your
question and Matt's the same way high
and Lonesome uh goat farm
pack they all make themselves accessible
for everyone and it's [ __ ] awesome it
really is yeah we're all just mention
dork said like we'd be doing this anyway
you know what I mean like you just be
doing this anyway so we're not
I I think it's the greatest deal in the
industry you get to really get details
about the seeds you're buying from
people that bred them and grew them out
and tested them
you can get a 40 discount on
American-made glass that's right you
know and you get to basically commune
with a bunch of people that have the
same exact interest as you yeah so and
there's not there's not trolls like we
don't it's it's a really weird Community
it's not like Instagram or Twitter or
just people sniping at each other it
doesn't happen so
I have never had anyone be [ __ ] to me
on the Discord ever and if it happened
it would just be it's self-police you
know people take care of yourselves yeah
yep yeah so get in there before I
convince Matt to raise the the monthly
subscription [ __ ] yeah right
all right and uh oh yeah riotsseeds.com
for your spray and Seed needs and um
Glass by c2.com
is that correct
for all your glassware
and that's it thank you from everyone at
breeder syndicate
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate
check out our patreon and our link tree
or description below our merch site is
officially live we have all sorts of
shirts hoodies and goodies to sort you
out and shipping is super fast and most
importantly the quality is top notch
I've been saving old designs for years
for this purpose so please check it out
syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out