[Music]
I start it I it I got
put on my way to save the
world my way to save the world got a
brand new set words and the going bre
Che a questioning believe wor got it
done with shopping but
I
I my way to save the
world my way to save the
world so yeah I was I was thinking of
like where to go with this because
you've done other shows before but I
think like briefly not even briefly like
as as much as you want to go into on
your start obviously where your interest
started how you got specifically into
like a very Niche area of like the land
race heirloom older lines you know um
yeah yeah and we have questions from
people in our Discord and I want to talk
some of the lines obviously that you
carry so it can shine some light on some
of those too plus I'm interested in a
lot of them and I have a bunch so yeah
yeah yeah nice um yeah uh that's cool
that people have sent in questions
because it's always good to sort of yeah
answer that for people because often
often I sort of don't realize the extent
I mean I do I do people mention it but
you know when people come to the site
and they're a bit overwhelmed by the
sheer quantity of stuff on there and
things like that yeah um but yeah I mean
um for me it was uh
something
the getting into this sort of niche as
it were was more um
the growing up in the UK in the
90s yeah
um some of my well in fact all of my
first encounters with cannabis were
through uh stuff that friends of mine's
parents had you know so sort of boomer
generation
people who would still in that era go
and you know to Nepal and places and
bring back stuff to smoke and that kind
of thing and then the people who I was
talking to it about talking to about it
were also of that generation and would
sort of Regale me with anecdotes about
smuggling hashack from Afghanistan and
this type of thing you know so kind
triggered your interest um yeah I mean
that was my perspective on it was that
that was the real cache the real kind of
um you know um
mythologized stuff was that old old type
of old school cannabis you know that was
anyway what I was kind of raised the
context in which I grew up into cannabis
was one in which that was always had the
biggest sort of prestige attached to it
you know these were these old kind of
like um hippie type characters you know
like um there probably a
slightly I mean they definitely were
back in the 60s
but um those you know they were doing
the hippie trail and stuff and yeah
doing kind of scams like that and then
as teenagers we would
like you know I'm talking kind
of very early 90s and things would
obviously being so close to Amsterdam in
England anyway yeah you um do we were
seeing that um people were starting to
to grow but it wasn't the indoor indoor
kind of domestic production in the UK
didn't really take off in a big way
until the late 90s early 2000s and
suddenly in the space of a couple of
years imported cannabis just disappeared
from the UK completely so most Imports
anyway if you're in the UK unless you
knew someone were pretty [ __ ] [ __ ]
Moroccan hash to be honest throughout
that era but if you did know someone you
could get you know nice swasy red sort
of West
African
Nigerian and you could still get good
good Moroccan and you'd see Lebanese
you'd see very seldom see like really
good Afghan to get that you'd need to go
to Holland or someone somewhere to
actually find someone who could get the
real stuff because most of what most of
the Afghan Pakistani type hash by that
point that you'd see in the UK was bunk
even though people didn't seem to
realize you know yeah but um but uh
anyway
so but if we did if we did see like what
we would call skunk and that kind of
stuff in the early
90s we'd sit you know I'd sit with my
friends at around
their house and stuff and their parents
would just be like oh this stuff's
terrible why are you [ __ ] touching
all crap you know and they just give us
this kind of lecture about how awful it
is and stuff and um so that was kind of
my perception anyway and then also you
know friends of mine who are Australians
were basically had the same attitude
it's like if they came around and they
saw and this again older generation you
know if they saw us growing things it'
be like H these aren't pure sativas you
need like proper sativas and they'd Rave
about Tai and Indonesian and
papinian sativas and stuff you know so
always my perspective anywhere was that
so for me it was just that was the
natural thing to be interested in and
when I did start trying to grow for
myself I sort of had this realization
[ __ ] hell I know where all these
places are I want these seeds and I can
see online that all these other people
are wanting these seeds I know where to
go to go and get them and um so it's
just a kind of natural progression
really it just um you know
uh it all kind of fell into
place that takes that takes connections
like to to track down like legitimate
stuff and and you seem to be quite a
well- read historian of cannabis and um
yeah I can't imagine the links that
you've had to go to to to even to bring
out a lot of this old stuff and a lot of
the the land race stuff as
well um I would say it's partly
become possible because of spending
enough time in these places
that um you get to know people and they
trust you enough you know yeah abolutely
uh it it really varies though because
some some bits of some bits of the
um of Asia
anyway it's not really that you need
particularly to have connections you
just need to know where the places are
you know yeah so
um you know you can you can go to this
as long as you know where the places are
in a lot of in a lot of the more Central
Asian Parts it's actually quite a lot
easier because it's it's really the
tropics where it's more tricky because
there's no reason to have seeds in the
tropics other than to grow C you know
it's not like their food or something
like in Nepal some of the landr types
anyway as much as anything are
cultivated for the seeds you know yeah
so there are some areas where and and
the same actually is kind of true in in
even in um uh the Hindu Kush you know is
the seeds are a winter food source as
well so you could sh yeah yeah yeah
people this is a really overlooked thing
actually like even amongst the experts
people seem to realize
that cannabis is a multi-purpose crop in
all of the North areas like including
Afghanistan and the Hindu Kush the only
bit where it's not a multi-purpose crop
is in the tropical areas where where is
ganja which is s the semi sensy whatever
you want to call it that's the only
where it's a single purpose crop it is
only grown for producing the buds you
know guess that makes sense too with the
hash with the hash production and stuff
because they could still collect the
hash and harvest the seeds yeah yeah so
you know um sometimes like um I've read
people like David Watson Sam skunkman
saying you know we tried really hard to
um persuade the Afghans to like grow the
crop as since Amil and like they just
actually just weren interested and
there's a pretty good reason for that
which is that actually the seeds are are
very important winter food source
they're very high in you know important
fats and proteins as well and
particularly in the mountains that's
really necessary because obviously you
can't keep like huge her of animals very
easily in in the mountains you can have
a few cows and goats and stuff but it's
not like um there's a there's a there's
a huge demand for land and water and
everything in in any mountain area and
so you know if you
can have that extra source of protein
and fats it's it's pretty essential
actually you know I
would some of the Mid Eastern places
would be super hard to U make those
connection especially nowadays um I
remember hearing even Neville's story
back with
um I think Clive I think that's what he
goes by um when they went to I think it
was Afghanistan and one of them OD in a
hut and they were you know trying to
kick in their door and whatnot that
that's how the story went anyways so I
can only imagine how crazy it is to try
to get inroads in there nowadays with
the political
climate um I mean one thing one thing
I'd pick up on first is just in terms of
thinking about the geography of cannabis
um Afghanistan I think if you if you
want to have a kind of
clear just because I think it's really
helpful you know with with everything is
like context is everything and and for
cannabis it's really good to get the
geographical and cultural context kind
of on a basic kind of map in your mind
as it were and I would say Afghanistan
is best thought of it's like Southern
Central Asia so Central Asia rather than
the Middle East is how I would talk
about it in terms because it's um that's
the really Central you know in what we
call indicas in the sort of loose sense
colloquial sense are a Central Asian
domesticate basically and so Afghanistan
is really sort of the Southern edge of
Central Asia and um rather than the
Middle East I think if you is Middle
East is s more sort of
confusing confusing term yeah yeah
um because you know it connects
Afghanistan really sort of connects in a
cannabis sense with shinjang and places
like that which is eastern central Asia
yeah bukara is sort of really you know
Central Central Asia as it were and
those are all
historically very connected
important cannabis centers in terms of
the sort of Inda type yeah races um but
yeah going to those places um
yeah I mean it's been it's been
increasingly difficult
um especially with the uh Taliban being
allowed to kind of yeah retake the
entire place and stuff but um yeah and
you know there is also yeah the fact the
other definitely one thing I found going
to those bits of the world is that the
the culture of kind of opium and stuff
does um mix with the Cannabis culture
quite a lot and I definitely met
characters who were having problems with
things like you know
harder substances like
heroin yeah but
um
the yeah I mean it's there's there's
various ways to do these things I mean
some of the people who were helping us
for a while were were were stringers for
for media um and journalism in fact all
of the people I know
who I from these places who were were
were working as stringers and which
means sort of
helping
um you know journalists and media
companies who who want to make
Productions in those areas to to meet
the people find the right places doing
that kind of job and then they would um
just have a sideline in like helping
collect seeds for us basically you know
and then obviously once
the once the um the
the um Biden sort of pulled the plug on
air support for and tax support and
everything for the Afghan Army and it
just got overrun and most of them had to
then um spend the next sort of you know
half a year in like safe houses trying
not to get
executed
J yeah it's not great it gives you a
different perspective on these things
because everyone's sort of like I mean
you know
detour too far into politics but I
thought the whole that whole
um post 911 Adventure was just
completely misguided but it's like once
they've actually committed to it to then
just suddenly [ __ ] turn around and
say actually you know what [ __ ] that
we're just going to leave and not even
tell you yeah was just a just an
astonishing [ __ ] betrayal but
everyone was exping it so it's American
that's what they do it's it is between
extremes there's no sort of just seems
to be incapable of finding a kind of
sensible middle ground on foreign policy
to yeah always going one way or the
other too far it's like oh we don't want
nothing to do with it oh we're all in oh
we want nothing to do with it oh we're
all in it's like Jesus man just [ __ ]
you know this insane ISM that seems to
[ __ ] infect all the thinking about it
leaving all the caches of weapons and
whatnot too just to find their their
homes to wherever
fuing do something Ukraine the way it's
going so let just gift them the entire
[ __ ] um anyway but yeah um it's it's
it's um but yeah so yeah I mean that's
that's mostly what I've seen of it is
the the post 911 kind of version of the
hippie Trail so it is quite hard to
avoid the political aspects of it
because it absolutely the landscape so
transformed by the time I got to see
most of it like it you know the context
in which I saw people smoking a lot were
like um security guards and sort of yeah
you know sort of those kind of
characters like sitting around like with
like you
know guns and stuff outside places like
embassies and hotels and whatever you
know very publicly smoking hash and
things it's like there sort of there's a
whole um Marshal kind of militant not
mil you know
um Warfare type context of cannabis use
there and things that I started to
realiz yeah it's not just a sort of um
the the hippie Trail stereotypes of sort
of spiritual use and things are actually
just one side of the the culture of
cannabis there's whole ranges of of ways
it's used traditionally that aren't
necessarily part of the main Western
discourse of like Oriental cannabis
culture you know yeah that's that's part
of the story that fascinates me because
it's it's a lot of the stuff that even
as deep into cannabis history and stuff
as I am that's like not something I'm
really super familiar with so I don't
speak on it you know I don't know it but
you're the type of person that I can
speak to that has a lot more insight
into that and I think uh the more people
are able to see all these different
perspectives um different ways of
thinking about how it's been used maybe
ways they've never even considered you
know I think that's really important to
talk
about yeah I think it's like I think
everyone you know we all kind of want
to uh kind of know what the roots of the
plant are and where it's come from and
things um but there's definitely been a
tendency in in sort of the WR on in in a
lot of the writing about it to to favor
this idea that it's
um to to favor aspects of it that fitted
with the sort of historical moment of
the 60s when it really became a mass
phenomenon in the west you know which
was yeah mostly sort of the anti-war
anti-racist um anti sort of
countercultural aspects that were
emphasized although things like you know
the assassins and stuff did kind of
creep in there because that was already
talked about quite a lot in sort of
Orient myths of or Legends or whatever
so you know that and that
does go into the Marshal context of use
and stuff as
well when when thing I thought we should
go over early on too because uh I mean
the nomenclature is important and and
even even this far in like I don't feel
confident anymore like trying to say
what I think a land race is versus an
heirloom versus you know anything else
um I'd love to have your your actual
working definitions of some of these
things as we talk about it so people
understand what we're talking about when
we say land race and heirloom varieties
yeah was a good idea yeah just yeah
[ __ ] mindfield of like different
terms so so I mean land race is just a
really unfortunate word from my
perspective that was a translation that
was made in the sort of late 19th early
late 19th century from various European
languages into English from German terms
Danish terms whatever like l in German
it would be land rer that was translated
into English as land race
um whereas actually if you were to do
that translation these days land race
would be best translated as country
breed or something like that
oh yeah so it's a
defunct form of the word race that we
just don't use anymore it's completely
archaic now in English but it was race
did once in English have the meaning of
breed as in a created something that
someone has breed has created like a
crop or a
a breed of animal you know so so so land
races are
uh artificially selected they're
Creations by humans for products that we
want they're created in certain areas by
Farmers so they they have an element of
region being region specific and cultur
but they're culture specific and they're
absolutely creatures of human desire and
whatever so they they're things that
farmers have created for certain
products so all land races are product
specific so the um tropical land races
are specific
for and we're talking drug quote you
know air quotes drug cannabis here so
tropical land races from places like
India southeast Asia are all
specifically
for uh cam semii as in ganja is the
traditional term for this like it's the
seedless inflorescences or or you know
very lightly seeded yeah it should be
like that and then that product goes
back to at least the 15th century
perhaps as early as the 12th century in
India you can find Sanskrit literature
that describes that technique of roguing
out the males cutting down the males how
to maximize resin production by certain
cultivation techniques and so on so
Jesus what we call sativas
are you know there're those are what we
call sativas so the tropical land races
fled um high THC because they've got
this uh long history of individual plant
selection
that's enabled by keeping the seed
from batch of good ganja you know
because yeah in
practice uh Farmers
don't you know you can find uh genuinely
100% C
it is still around even these days in in
places like India and la and Thailand
and stuff but for the most part you if
you buy a batch
of any significant size of ganja you
will find one or two seeds in there if
you're in India you know it's can be
loads of seeds often you know but
um it shouldn't be like that and
historically it wasn't like that for the
most part you know it's amazing that it
goes back that far I didn't know that
that it went back to the 12 with
selections yeah yeah so with with um
cutting down um yeah and you know so the
the point the point is that individual
plant selection is is a strong selected
pressure and that is enabled by that
strong selected pressure is enabled by
the fact that you do often
find a seed or two in a batch of ganja
that you would buy you know abolutely so
consumers and officios and farmers are
all able to do that so consciously or
unconsciously you've got at least 500
years of individual plant selection
being a factor in the creation of
sativas which is why there's any kind of
fici knows they are the strongest forms
of land races
Thai Lao
burmes South Indian like
Kerala uh all these types of plants are
what went in to form the real kind of
original Haze yeah type sativas that
people know in the states and you know
back in the late 60s early 70s this was
literally
fetching multiples its weight in gold in
terms of price by the time it got from
from Thailand to the west coast of the
United States and it was the same in in
England so if you look at the custom
seizures records from the early ' 70s
for for for cannabis that was coming
from places like Ean in Thailand it was
like they were it was testing you know
with thin layer chromatography but which
is not hugely accurate but it was
testing kind of 177% THC yeah and that's
when they not gaming the tests and it's
probably sat in a warehouse in London or
for months never mind how long it took
to get to England in the first place you
know yeah so yeah I mean talking high
levels of potency so people aren't
making it up when they say that this
stuff could blow your head off you know
even in the 60s and 70s and doesn't you
don't need much more than 10% THC anyway
a lot of it's about the uh other stuff
that's in this in these uh the other
phyto chemicals that are in these plants
absolutely anyway to to stay focused so
there those are the sativas and then in
the north the main group is what people
call colloquially indicas which are the
you know I guess everyone knows what I'm
talking about broadly speaking but again
this is a type of land race that um you
know with the more semi- dwarf
morphology used for making hash so
product specific there's no culture of
CA in north of 30 degrees latitude so
once you've got to the north of Pakistan
there just is No in fact once you've
even got to the Punjab in India or the
Punjab in Pakistan it's bisected by
colonialism the um once you've got there
there's no culture of s by the time you
even get to the Punjab once you've gone
north of the Punjab towards the
foothills of the Hindu
Kush absolutely no sense culture at all
it's all hash and uh it's always been
that way so when you make hash you pull
the seeds yeah in the process of making
the hash so they just there not ever
been much in the way of any individual
plant selection on hash land Braes so
they bulk selected
crop that probably goes back Millennia
perhaps um that bulk selection which is
why on balance the the um the the
cannabinoid um uh characteristics of of
of of Inda land races do of lean
slightly towards THC dominant
um plants like type one plants as people
would call it but you do have in the
population a mix of type one type two
type three uh so you know High ratio of
THC to CBD is type one balanced THC and
CBD is type two and then type three is
sort of higher ratio of CBD to THC so
most hash land races will typically if
they're a pure land race we're talking
not a you know not Afghani number one or
something you can buy a
Dutch um seed bank um if they're a real
land race they tend to be like that they
do lean slightly towards type one
because they've had that history of bulk
selection it's you know more than random
more than random lean towards type one
but um uh yeah if you want to grow a
crop of Camila from from seed it's not
much
use uh to to to use a a real land race
you know they need to be worked to to
make them a cin cultiva you know so if
you were talking about the difference
between an heirloom and a land race
heirloom is not a technical term as far
as I know but it I would Define it in
the context of cannabis as uh a land
race that's been worked specifically for
in in a in a western or modern context
for since so x18 or deep chunk or
Afghani number one they're all in IND
indicia heirloom in a sense they're an
indicia land race that's been worked for
making sense yeah that's how Define it
that makes sense yeah
yeah and then you've got one other feral
varieties then like how how would you
define those in in terms of like land
race heirloom is it its own
type
um so
um
feral or kind of wild type is another
term you could use I think quite good um
they're
um you you don't find them much in the
tropics that as as a as a rule cannabis
doesn't
naturalize uh very well in the tropics
it's not uh a species that is well
adapted to that type of climate so if
you do find if you do find feral um
cannabis in the tropics it's because
you're you're you're at altitude
somewhere with a fairly
temperate
climate
um so for the most part if you if you're
in for example India you might find
weedy uh cannabis growing like anywhere
sort of north of the Ganges so we're
talking between in in in the sort of top
half of North India between the Ganges
and the Himalayas you know okay and then
as you go up towards the Himalayas
suddenly you'll find areas where it just
grows [ __ ] everywhere you
know just Seas of feral stuff especially
if you go up into Pakistan like Punjab
[ __ ]
everywhere um uh and then up into the
mountains around the rivers and
places anywhere where there's kind of
disturbed land but it's basically uh as
a species it's
uh it's a step species meaning it likes
kind of
windy um fairly dry places where there's
lots of disturbed land and uh to grow
along the sides of rivers where animals
to drink and [ __ ] and
stuff like high
nitrogen
uh decent amounts of water but not rainy
you know
um CBD dominant for stuff like
that um no um not necessarily so um
basically they're kind of um like nobody
knows where there's a pure nobody's ever
kind of satisfactory identified like a
pure wild like unaffected Ed by humans
pure wild cannabis plants has never been
found you know that makes sense so what
you actually have is like parallel
populations that have just been swapping
genes with whatever the local form of
cannabis is you know in the sense of
like humans domesticated at
least I don't know kind of say 8,000
years ago probably we started at least
you know unintentionally domesticating
cannabis yeah and um by just bringing it
back to hun gather like bringing it back
to places where they
were eating and stuff we like we're
unconsciously selecting for types that
we liked you know yeah and then quite
happy to grow around our campfires and
stuff because there was lots of [ __ ] and
discarded animal bones and stuff that
just are good for cannabis to so
um um basically if you're in somewhere
like the Punjab where it grows which is
north uh West
India where where where there's a lot of
wildr cannabis you can you can people do
like crop the
feral uh weedy stuff provided it's
somewhere clean that's not Dusty and
things you can just crop that and um use
it for making food and things you know
yeah so these are high high THC
um in in the sense of
uh they will get you stoned you it's
yeah it's not like in um places like I
don't know Wisconsin or somewhere in the
states where it's basically hemp that's
gone feral you know yeah the fiber h r
yeah I mean there are definitely like if
we're talking probably make things
confusing but anyway these are like in
in in in in those in all of sort of
Central and South South Asia where you
get feral populations it's pretty much
um drug drug type quotes cannabis yeah
and then in the Himalayas like uh people
do sometimes hand rub the the feral
populations for for Charis and it makes
what people sometimes call jungly Charis
as in like wild Charis but actually
there's a again this is one of those
kind of hippie Trail type
confusions there's been this assumption
that Himalayan cannabis is always feral
cannabis which is it which it isn't like
yeah
99% of the Charis that's produced in the
Himalayas every year is
From
domesticated intentionally
cultivated land races grown in fields by
a farmer you know yeah this that it's
the Himalayan cannabis is uh is all wild
and stuff is not not accurate like in
terms of the product is just very seldom
produced from the wild wedi stands you
can and people do but it's got way less
resin production than the the than the
actual land rces do you know
I'm yeah and and and it's useless for
making CSO it's not because it's all
going to be seeded anyway yeah you can't
use it for to smoke as bud it's just
it's I mean you do see sadu doing that I
have seen sadu like Yogi's wondering
kind of Yogi characters who've yeah gone
up to the Himalayas and picked picked a
whole load of feral
flowers and then they just sit and they
kind of pick out the seeds and mix it
with some tobacco and smoke it but it's
it's not like it's uh you know it's
not um designed for that yeah is why
people rub it for Chas because it it's
timec consuming to do but you end up
with a product that is actually going to
get you stoned yeah whereas smoking a
whole load of feral Bud like that mixed
with tobacco it's more just like a kind
of a maybe take the edge
off whatever physical discomfort you
experience as a as a wondering Yogi but
it's not going to like get you
particularly high I would thought unless
you really just happened to find an
unusually strong plant sure yeah you
know um one of the the interesting
things like from from the American
perspective at least for mine um is
trying like in my mind to Divi Define
Expressions between uh when people talk
about indicia types specifically or the
the broadleaf types um the differences
between like an Afghan type plant and a
Pakistani plant where the the overlap is
and you know like there's always talk of
Chinese um broadleaf types and I I've
never got my hands on any of those I
remember someone made the unan available
for a while but I never got to grow any
um I'd like to hear some of your Insight
on that and the the major differences
and I know it's kind of hard to
generally speak on expressions from
Whole regions you know depending on the
elevation but is there anything that
you've noticed between um say
Afghanistan and Pakistan in and how they
grow um scent Expressions anything like
that I mean it's it's particularly
difficult with um those Northern type
Central Asian you know Afghan Pakistani
yeah
uh populations because what you get if
you grow like a first generation of
direct from those places like seeds
directly from a farmer in Pakistan or
Afghanistan whatever there's a huge
amount of variation within the
population of one batch of seeds from
one farmer so the range of Aromas that
you're going to find in one field from
plant to plant just in one of those land
races it's extraordinarily diverse you
know one plant might be really kind of
like kind of candy shot sweet Tangy
Aromas the next one might smell like a
dog [ __ ]
yeah
whatever and and and so it's
particularly in those Northern
populations there's because they're bulk
selected they're not as genetically
narrow as tropical sativa populations
are so because they they haven't had
they haven't you know the the genome
hasn't been Stepped On by Farmers doing
much in the way of very consciously
intentionally directed
breeding there's a huge amount of
variation anyway and
then on top of that in terms of the
difficulty of generalizing you know
because the the Assumption amongst
afficianados is that Precision more
Precision in in your description means
more accuracy but actually if you get if
you get too precise on these things you
become less accurate you know yeah for
sure there's vast amounts of diversity
so particularly with cannabis because
it's so
phenotypically plastic so it because
like I was saying it's a
mountain uh species that's evolved um at
altitude um to adapt to the huge climate
shifts you get at altitude and that kind
of thing it can express itself very
differently depending on where it's
planted so if you were to plant the same
land race at sea level and then plant at
3 and half th000
M exactly the same batch of seeds from
the same
farmer uh you will see very different
plant looking plants morphologically
because you plant them up higher
altitude they're going to grow much
shorter broad more Broad Leaf they're
going to pump out way more resin yeah
probably going to have different
phytochemicals probably smell different
and everything you know so yeah and
likewise if you you can get that even
with tropical sativas if you grow them
on well they're going to be amazing if
you grow them incompetently they're not
going to smell so good you know yeah you
kind of have to go to point of origin to
to experience them as they
are uh yeah I mean it definitely makes a
vast difference even with the more
genetically narrow populations like
tropical steers if they're grown well by
someone who knows how to do it on the
right type of land with the right
irrigation timing the right Fe in timing
the right uh you know everything if you
overwater a tropical sativa late in flow
it's going to keep growing keep putting
out Buds and leaflets and it's going to
be [ __ ] yeah and no one and this is why
you get all this bollocks talk about 30
weeks ofas indoors and stuff it's just
people just [ __ ] watering it you know
so
stoper but anyway you know and if you
look at the Historical records it's
always it will tell you this like uh in
the um 19th century documentation of of
the ganja farms in Bengal and places
it's like yeah Farmers always say worst
thing that can happen is we get rains in
like January February and it'll [ __ ] up
our whole crop because it will start
shooting again yada yada yada yeah
anyway so it's all it's all there if you
if you want to look and stuff and I have
blogged about this on on the site as
well if people are wanting to go into
more depth and you can find all the
sources and stuff but um it's an amazing
blog by the way like it's I've learned a
lot reading through it over the years oh
that's good to know I I'm glad someone
reads it yeah I do I mean it's it's how
I how I um like came to know you without
speaking to you a bunch was through the
blog and seeing the passion and how you
write and how in-depth the detail was
and and over time learning how accurate
it was which is the most important you
know yeah well it's good to hear man
thanks I appreciate it I I've shifted
most of it now to the actual main
website blog rather than the sort of um
independent blog because uh it just
seems to make more sense so generally
I've been kind of moving everything over
to the main blog on the site now just
because uh it seems to make more sense
but I before I lose the thread of what
you were originally asking um so in
terms of Pakistan versus Afghanistan so
the thing to bear in mind is like um
seeds move around a lot seeds move
around with people in areas where people
use them as as a food and not just for
growing as well yeah plus
um uh you know these are artificial
political boundaries so there's no
cultural real boundary if in in in
meaningful terms cannabis wise between
uh the Hindu Kush in Pakistan and the
Hindu Kush in Afghanistan you know so I
want to try to kind of avoid being sort
of a [ __ ] as far as possible but
there's all this stuff I see on
Instagram with people talking about the
Duren line and stuff and like the dur
line there this it's just just [ __ ]
that's bizarre to me as well because I
think most of the kids who are doing
this are like Asian as well so it's like
the DAR line was just Dar was just some
[ __ ] from the UK who drew a pencil line
across the boundary between Pakistan and
Afghanistan you know the [ __ ] has that
got to do with anything you know
and and and
it's only in the last kind of 10 years
that um uh they've actually really
started policing that border and putting
fences up and things and even then it
doesn't make the blindest [ __ ] bit of
difference anyone who really wants to
get things across it can still do it but
in cannabis terms it's just [ __ ]
meaningless I mean and and and seeds
have been you know uh seeds have been
moved from Afghanistan down to places
like tra Valley in Pakistan you know
there's there's plenty of local stories
about the various kind of dervish like
kander Sufi type Saint characters who
are s of credited with bringing seeds
into TR and things and and and um which
T is one of the big cultivation valleys
in Pakistan and yeah this this whole
area is is seamless seamless with it's
the whole reason the politics and the
history is the way it is is because it's
impossible to police these mountain
borders you know oh I'm sure huge
smuggling between these places and then
uh chitra is another one of the famous
areas like yakun Valley and things up in
the Hindu Kush these all lead into
shinjang these are the trade routes that
you would take from shinjang which is
the Eastern Central Asian area that's
turkic area of of politically it's
inside what's now China and this was a
the biggest hash producing uh region in
in the world for oh wow for centuries oh
absolutely I mean this was the epicenter
of hash production so it wasn't
Afghanistan or Pakistan it was shinjang
was until the
19 late 1930s was the absolute [ __ ]
epicenter of world hash production I
mean thousands and thousands of tons of
hash were being moved from these places
across the mountain passes into the into
India because all the money was in
Northern India yeah and the demand for
these products was in Northern India in
these huge cities which even in the late
19th century places like laor and Delhi
had millions of well laor certainly had
in is the big Punjabi City had you know
seven eight nine 10 million people or
whatever even in the
1860s so these
were massively massive senses of demand
for these products and so they the the
production was all happening in eastern
central Asia so in shinjang and um you
know the British were trying to make
sure as much of what came into India was
being taxed effectively they didn't want
too much smuggling and um you know seeds
were moving around between these places
you can read about the people who were
responsible for uh a lot of the uh
initiation of like commercial production
in in um in shinjang for India were
often Indians or uh ethnically from
ethnic groups of of the mountains of
Pakistan you know
so there there's just not
um um much basis for assuming that
there's going to be
a you know there's there's a very
nuanced picture if you're talking about
the diff how how these land races in
these regions are differentiated from
each other yeah once you get into
Pakistan in the northern mountains there
probably is a certain degree of mixing
between kind of the more sativa type
um the further south you move away from
the southern edges of Central Asia the
further south you get away from the
Hindu
Kush there probably is
more prep there is a a higher likelihood
that you're going to have a degree of
intermixing with more Monson type
tropical type Punjabi type
populations uh so you know more
hybridization between sativa type
populations and indicia type populations
the further north you go
into I don't know into places like
shinjang there's a higher likelihood I
guess of it being a a sort of quotes
pure indicia type you know so if you
look at the plant that were brought back
from Shin Jang in the early 20th century
by people like Frank Meyer and stuff for
the USDA they definitely are very Inda
looking um plants and um uh yeah I mean
you know um you had some of those
pictures on your blog too correct yeah
yeah so yeah and and
um uh you know
they're there's no question that there
are these distinct types you know the
confusion of the confusion with the
discussion about are there such things
as indicas and sativas is
like yes there definitely are in terms
of if you're looking at pure land races
yeah real land
races um there are these clearly
distinct types there's also of course
some integrating between them even in
pure land races some some Landes are
likely to have Arisen through mixing of
these types uh but of course once you
move into the context of what you're
going to find at most dispensaries or
seed banks uh like cannabis
internet seat banks that is yeah most of
what you're going to find is is a
indicator sativa hybrid so this
terminology becomes meaningless in in
often most of the time in those contexts
you know
yeah important Point too like especially
uh from people that in in the US that
can go to collectives and stuff and
they're seeing indicia hybrid sativa and
they feel like they have a pretty good
working knowledge of what what each is
and um quite often I mean I don't really
see anything too narrow Leaf anywhere
you know or no not at all it's problem
because
um
um that's how cannabis goes extinct you
know biodiversity and cannabis primarily
disappears through hybridization you
know yeah so
uh this impulse that most people have to
like hybridize everything when they
because it is fun you know it's like see
what happens yeah actually the most
exciting thing you can do really these
days especially is to actually keep some
pristine lines going that you haven't
outcrossed because that's the
basis of uh everything really and once
we've got to a point where all we've got
a hybridized lines then it becomes
impossible to to do breeding that
doesn't have become impossible but you
can't make true F1 cult our yeah what
have you noticed or maybe haven't
noticed or uh as far as in those uh
regions of like Afghanistan and Pakistan
I've noticed there's a lot of people
popping up especially on Instagram as
Instagram became bigger especially for
cannabis and and seeds um yeah have you
noticed a lot more hybridization
involved like with modern lines T kind
of working their way into these lines
that are being declared Pure or you know
have you
noticed sort of
don't
um I generally try and like just ignore
most of the the sort of people doing
those things um but every every couple
of years I sort of maybe get curious
about what they might be saying and it's
always I mean the thing is I don't like
U I don't really know what they're up to
uh for the most part um it worries me
because I suspect most of them based on
what I heard um have been involved in
also bringing hybrid seed over to places
as well you know yep yeah I can't
substantiate that Beyond some Forum
things I saw in like 2018 when there was
suddenly there was a 2018 as there was
this sort of big yes realization among
some of these characters that um oh we
can get seeds from these places but at
the same time they were sort of wanting
to there was certainly some of them were
wanting to bring seeds up to places like
Parvati and Milana the sort of typical
Himalayan areas for for for for Charis
in India and
um yeah and then I saw these ridiculous
kind of excuses being made oh there's
some kind of wind wind uh climate type
micro climate to do with WIS that means
that any pollen from hybrids that we
bring up to Milano is is not going
to [ __ ] you can imagine and and it just
just after that I just I think I wrote a
kind of couple of sort of irritated
things back then on on the on the on
that old blog and about the amount of
[ __ ] that's spouted and and then
just thought [ __ ] it this is gonna put
me in a bad mood so I I I don't like
going on social media anyway much it
tends to put me in a negative
so I I just have chosen to ignore it and
do do my own thing really so I can't
give anyone an informed opinion about
what exactly is going on up to a point I
know certain outfits have like stolen
stuff from people who Supply me as in as
in like yeah they've supplied like I
know I know one outfit that one of the
guys who supplies me has sent seeds to
then they didn't pay him and they just
knocked off his strain and sold the
seeds and kept the money for themselves
yeah um so I know there's outfits that
are that shitty but that's that's like I
can only
um I only know that because it's in
intruded on my world as it were I
haven't proactively seeking out
knowledge of what they get up to because
it's just it's not it's not conducive to
being in a in a positive State of Mind
to involve yourself with [ __ ] but um
no I mean I mean to go back to the
plants and stuff like
um one thing I think is probably worth
clarifying for
people um Himalayan uh land races as in
we're talking between sort of you know
Napal and Kashmir are a distinct group
themselves right they're not indicas
they're not true tropical sativas
they're another kind of group within
land races that's very clearly distinct
you know they're much taller plants they
generally are triple use multi-purpose
plants so they're for seeds for fiber
and
for
um hashes Chas uh they're not um you
know they have a the canabo profile is
typically like a Central Asian you know
a field of them will break down into
like type one type two and type three
cannaboid profiles chemotypes
so they're a very distinct group and the
problem with people bringing Dutch
and um genetics up to Milan and stuff is
you can see it's just uh that around
that
area is very obviously not the same as
it was even when I first went there you
know yeah
it's uh very clear that there's
that skunky Dutch kind of effect as not
just not just a smell the sort of effect
it's yeah um uh I was I was there um one
time when this uh real kind of crazy
oldtime guy turned up who bought a bunch
of like tie brick weed with him in his
from from flown from Bangkok
to India like oh my goodness couple of
hundred gram like brick of
weird from like coang or somewhere Kang
and just a maniac you know but anyway he
had a bunch of it with him in this guest
house and it was very interesting like
smoking some of
that side by side with the the a lot of
what you could find in in manik Kuran
and places at that point yeah and this
is was at least 10 years ago and you
know the effect of the the stuff from
around that end of Parvati there had
been so much Dutch stuff brought in by
that point the smell of it was like that
real kind of skunky pissy Ur urinal
Aroma and then it was a very unup foric
Buzz compared to what I associate with
that area and then you smoked the Thai
stuff and it was really kind of up and
zingy and then the you
know yeah it's just really stood out
like similarly if you if you go to areas
of the Himalayas that haven't had that
um uh introduction of foreign hybrid
seed the effect is of the Charis in the
sort of unfashionable bits of the
Himalayas to go to is is the old school
real stuff that's not been obviously
[ __ ] up the effect of it is much nicer
you know it's like yeah much more
uplifting and
positive uh feeling you know it's uh
there's there's rarely something with
skunk one in it that I can smoke because
it always takes me to a very specific
like negative space in my head so
usually I can pick it out it's taking a
long time but I can pretty much like
yeah pick out anything that has skunk
one in it there's very few exceptions
that I find something I love you know
that has that in it at least you know
50% yeah and a lot of the anyway
the the the the the most of the
continuations of it have been selected
for the sort of heavy side of it as well
so yes it's uh most mostly in the UK if
if if you get something skunky it's
anywhere it's going to be like a Hindu
kusun Afghan skun whatever yeah anyway
so it's doubly like leaning that way
anyway but the thing the thing to bear
in mind as well is that like that's not
anyway the if you look in Afghan land
races themselves Hindu Kush land races
whatever that whole Zone they're not
necessarily like that they're not
necessarily sedative like some of them
clearly are predominantly like that but
there's such a wide uh range of uh
phytochemical you know CH type whatever
that in these populations that aren't
going to give you that type of uh effect
as well so there's no we're not kind of
stuck with this as long as we can keep
the some good representations of like
pristine uh uh land races in storage you
know they will always be the possibility
of creating new things that that
actually feel good which is you know
gets back to your original question of
like why did I get into this and like a
lot of people um the sort of standard
narrative is that you know in the UK the
standard narrative is oh around around
the year 2000 suddenly all this hybrid
stuff arrived and it was just too strong
and it's like not really I wouldn't say
it was too strong was the issue the
effect was just it wasn't very [ __ ]
nice you know a lot of it so a lot of
people didn't stop smoking because it
was too strong so much as it was just a
dysphoric effect from so much of it
compared to what they were used to from
the the traditional stuff you know yeah
so mostly what people people say oh yeah
it used to make me paranoid and stuff
and it's like the assumption is that
that's um because it's just too strong
but it's not necessarily that you can
have very strong tropical sativas that
um
primarily don't make you feel
particularly paranoid you know yeah by
absolutely yeah yeah that's a good point
yeah
um I don't think that's widely talked
about either that's a no it's
just it was it's it's just too strong
that's why I don't smoke it's like well
actually you can have a plenty of you
know
strong uh highs of cannabis that are
uh are really nice you know yeah they
don't evoke the paranoia and all that
other [ __ ] General kind of grebby dirty
feeling that you kind of yeah but I mean
it's not you know again I I'm always
very wary of talking myself into a
corner of being kind of anti-modern
stuff which I'm not at all I
just I I'm I'm just Pro kind of pro
diversity Pro um possibility which is
why I why I think it's worth preserving
as much as we can of what there is left
of of these
think so that there is that option in
the future of taking the plant down
different routes there's this this a
sort of default assumption that we've
already arrived at the Pinnacle of what
can be achieved in cannabis that was so
much a part of the last 10 years of
cannabis discourse this assumption it's
like yeah you know these Elite cuts and
stuff are like the best it's like
[Music]
no sure but sure as [ __ ] on like the all
there is to be to be achieved you know
yeah I try to explain to people a lot of
the quote unquote Elite Cuts in the US
like most of those were picked out of
two three seeds you know like in
someone's closet like in it's not I mean
Elites definitely uh it's very rare that
I find any of those old clones that have
been passed around that everyone
universally agrees that's [ __ ]
amazing it's so rare to ever find that
you know there's very few so yeah I the
clone Market in the US has been
completely taking over lately with that
spreading of hlv so a lot of like the
past few seasons of what I've been doing
is trying to explain to people the
necessity of seeds versus clones as well
in the US and I know that a bunch of the
Spanish SE or Spanish clones or stuff
from here that went over there has
murdered some of the libraries over
there of some of the Old Dutch stuff
that they had been keeping um right it's
not SL down it's not down anytime soon
and so that's very interesting I didn't
I wasn't aware that that this is the hot
lat thyroid yes so it's just basically
[ __ ] everything up oh already scenario
where we're paying the price of how
[ __ ]
homogeneous all of our stuff is already
yeah [ __ ] man
yeah about it but I hadn't realized it
it actually got to the point of like
trashing people's collections as well oh
yeah um with one of the bigger clone
nurseries that I know of and they'll
remain nameless but um they are pretty
content with 3% of clones going out with
hlv because it's so
inundated right just it's assumed that
3% is is the best that they can do not
0% but 3% is like when you are
constantly testing constantly because
they're still bringing stuff in because
everybody wants this cookies renamed
whatever the new name for cookie stuff
is today you know and and it's still
working on people obviously um the
education is out there but it's it's not
being accessed or maybe you know there
is a big difference between smokers and
Growers there's there's a wide pool that
just it's really hard to get through
because most people that I've
encountered here the attitude is why do
you care so much it's just weed you
know that's like a very standard British
attitude it's like it's all just weed
yeah it's like yeah
yeah like um Americans coming over to
the UK are just like H you know when
they see
what's available to someone who is just
uh randomly turning up in England it's
it's dismal you know even these days
unless you grow for yourself and or you
happen to be in a city that's
particularly like weed orientated it's
very very dismal you know but yeah I
mean I that's that's this this is what
I've always had in mind is that you know
there there is going to come a point and
I had run across the hlv issue but it's
not something that impacts me directly
with the way I'm operating so I haven't
been looking into it but I there always
just going to come a point where
something's going to come along that's
just going to [ __ ]
decimate um the the situation and people
are going to realize just how [ __ ]
homogeneous everything is and and yes
it's so based on such a small handful of
for the most part um you know uh Dutch
and
American lines you know this you could
probably count them on two hands I
expect the main contributors to the and
um and and and people
don't people especially sort of below
Generation X don't really have any sense
of that I think unless they're nerds you
know yeah they had deep
nerds yeah unless you grew up in the
sort of preh
hybrid era or happen to be interested in
the actual growing side of it there's no
reason why you necessarily realize you
know yeah it's one of the problems as
well um with the groups who are doing
collecting is a lot of them I can tell
are not from an age uh from a generation
where they're necessarily even going to
know what a pure land race looks like in
Thailand or Cambodia or whatever yeah
you know something that to me would be
so obvious that it's been hit with
something Dutch or American that
genuinely might not even realize how
that it I've had people contact me
saying hey I'm in you know cambod or
whatever I found these great plants and
it's like yeah they do look like pretty
cool plants but I can tell from just a
photo
that they're not um lacking in the
Afghan yeah for sure and uh people just
don't realize you know they're still
they're still worth collecting so it's
but it does it does matter the
difference between them and a
pristine population does matter you know
yeah um there's no reason like why they
that they're not like bad per se it's
just that they they are
introgressed they're they're down the
route of total homogenization they're
well down that route already and they're
not not even half as valuable as the
real thing you know
absolutely yeah that's well put yeah so
you have a lot of experience with
u maybe Southeast Asian is correct with
h tyan La I've I've heard you know some
of the stories
that uh it was leosan Farmers bringing
down stuff to Thailand is um is there
any veracity to that
or um it's more the um
the um I mean the the thing to bear in
mind is again like it's a really
important like really worth um bearing
in mind is that these political
boundaries yeah uh a very modern
Creations for the most part that don't
have any real seen in terms
of and the culture of the plant
so any way if you picture the if you
pict had the the meon kind of running
from up in of the east of Tibet down
into southeast Asia from you know
through the Golden Triangle and down
through Thailand and now down towards
Cambodia all along the Mong either side
of the Mong is is basically ethnic Lao
anyway once you get into Thailand and
and Lao
so uh large chunks of thailander like
isan where which is the famous the
famous ttic areas of of Thailand all
ethnic L anyway so it wasn't really a
question of people bringing seeds I
don't think it's just that the
culture um
existed yeah and um if you look at the
early historical uh
writing in so far as there is any in um
Thailand about
cannabis um I think there some from the
sort of 18th century or 19th I think
more 19th century some of the earliest
references that I've seen people find
found uh two Gano and cannabis in Thai
literature it the the the the Thai
writers are very much emphasizing that
this is a l thing so this was in the
context one of the really early
references is in the context of a kind
of historical
epic uh which is about the uh huge war
between the LA uh Kingdom and the ties
that happened um
basically it was 1830s maybe I got it I
don't quote me on the dates but not
super long ago but anyway
um the LA kingdoms got quite
expansionists uh under a guy called ja
onong I think it was they got ambitious
tried to sort of seize bits of LA and in
return the ties basically just
annihilated uh venan and all the big
cities of wow of L particularly like
literally raised it to the
ground moved all of population into isan
into Thailand across the Mong and
because they wanted to have more people
there because it was one of the big
problems the ties have always had is
that the population density was too low
for them to uh sort of uh tax Farm the
they they wanted more people there to
tax basically yeah that makes sense for
the state to to grow and um yeah so it
was a kind of um
the reason there's a very big L
population in isan is is partly
artificial basically so it's a lot of
people moved and
um the
um the culture from a very early all the
indications are is that the can cannabis
is associated in thae culture with uh
rural um
populations particularly ethnic La
populations and there's a very very
strong
uh status
Association in the in Tai culture is
very very status conscious like it's
worse than the English or any kind of
snobby
culture you can choose so all of the
politics of Thailand are all about the
big city Bangkok versus the the the
countryside basically and so this the
reason I'm giving all of this kind of
context is that
it's not surprising to me at all as
someone who knows these areas fairly
well it's not surprising to me that the
law has been changed back in Thailand
now to ban cannabis again oh is it did
they change it back yeah yeah so they're
gonna by sometime this I forget they've
got a few more months perhaps and then
they're going to just ban recreational
use again it's another question about
whether they'll actually be able to
enforce that but um at this stage but
the absolutely no surprise to me at all
whatsoever that the the consensus has
been that in in the Bangkok Elite that
this should not be allowed uh and
they're going to do what the British
have done they're going to basically
copy our model of like allowing some
medicinal industry that them and their
mates will get to cash in on so the kind
of industrialists and Elite will get to
make a killing out of the medicinal
industry but and everyone else can go
[ __ ] themselves and get a prescription
or go to jail you know
it's not much different than the US like
to be hon it really ended
up
yeah so it's the same it's the same sort
of whatever dialectic whatever you want
to say disc course it's
basically cannabis is a is a is a is a
peasant drug basically in to put it in
the bluntest terms in in Thailand
now that means that some people have a
some Elite establishment types have a
kind of affectionate attitude towards it
it's like oh it's the country bumpkin
kind of thing other people look down on
it disdain for it sure and there's the
definite hierarchy you know in terms of
things like amphetamin and and opiates
and stuff in Southeast Asia that's that
about Elite versus
rural Poor Man's drug rich man's drugs
and various in between yeah um and
cannabis is definitely the poor man's
drug you know
so wild yeah [ __ ] up we we assume it's
like oh it's part of the culture quote
unquote but it's from much more
complicated than that in Asia you need
to have a kind of sense of how
stratified and fractured all of these
countries are in terms of the culture
and the geography and how that relates
to to cannabis it's it's not
straightforward you know it's not
straightforward that they're going to
legalize in India by any means um and it
is very strongly connected to how the um
political establishment relate towards
the uh minorities and and
Village communities in terms of how they
see it and there's all kinds of
complicated ideas about smoking versus
eating it and which is smoking is
generally not okay and maybe eating it
is kind of okay and it's so it's so it's
not at all the question that it's like
um the shorthand that we in the West
tend to go for like uh the Americans
came and banned it and bl it's like yes
and but no not really there were moves
to ban these things long before the um
uh
American Germany or whatever was a thing
and and and a lot of the the the um
British involvement ironically was
strongly lent towards not making it
illegal because the British were there
to make money in in India and places and
the loudest voices who were pushing for
it to be made illegal were generally
Indians yeah of a certain establishment
type of in of mentality in India that
regarded this stuff as unacceptable you
know and that was nothing to do with uh
them being contaminated by puritanical
Western ideas these were like
locally
born ways of thinking about these
substances that
Associated them with undesirable groups
like cannabis was very strongly
associated with Muslim culture in India
for example uh particularly the smoking
hashish was associated with Muslims yeah
and then in far as it had any Hindu
connections it was Associated often with
Village forms of Hinduism that were seen
as being
um sort of folk versions of Hinduism
that were not sophisticated and or all
were contaminated with um
uh you know unorthodox forms of Hinduism
that were disapproved of you know so
there's all kinds of like nuances in
there in terms of it um you know it's
not it's pessimistic but I can't I'm not
like anticipating some glorious future
age of legalization there going to be
around the corner unfortunately there
was a while where I thought maybe maybe
because the money will decide it and
then I'm no it's not it's not going to I
don't think we're going to be like
living in some global legal situation
anytime soon basically yeah it just
seems like no matter what happens it's
always going to be putting the hand the
the money into the hands of the few so
maybe opening it up you know built this
Market but closing it back down puts it
back into the 1% type situation yeah
yeah it's it's pretty difficult once
yeah basically I think so and once it's
been once you've got a Prohibition
scenario like
extricating yourself from
that you know it's not straightforward
especially when there such a strong
plutocratic sort of oligarchical
tendency in in in our dysfunctional
democracies these days it's like when
you combine that with how difficult it
is to have a sensible discussion about
these types of topics in the in the
media these days it's uh it's yeah it's
very tricky you know yeah for sure yeah
I mean there's people in the USA that
you know applied for licenses and
because and didn't end up getting it for
whatever reason and then now they're on
paper and now they get raid like it's
yeah it's it's been wild to watch it
happen over the past you know however
many years and uh I can't imagine it's
going to get any better anywhere after
people have watched the rich sort of
take over the whole
industry yeah yes I mean I I don't know
like
um I I was very not optimistic but I was
kind of cautiously optimistic that like
even if it wasn't for the right reasons
we might end up with legalization sure
um
because you know and and the quirks of
the political system in the states where
you can have these sort of referenda and
stuff referendums in places like Oregon
or whatever
that we don't have anything like that in
the UK equivalent to that so I was sort
of watching somewhat enviously and
thinking yeah well it's only a matter of
time before you've got Federal
legalization I noticed Harris has been
saying she's going to do that and things
who knows you know I mean maybe they
will but it does require like some
courage on the part
of um people in power to actually do
what they know I mean talk to any of
these people they will know what they
should do and but they'll always do sort
of some sort of half-hearted fudge in
the end you know I mean you know the
chance of like having sensible laws
about actually kind of properly
dangerous drugs is is very unlikely
anytime soon and particularly given that
even the sort of more enlightened
discourse around these things is is so
um incapable of you know like I'm
thinking like you see all this talk
about psychedelics these days and
psychedelics this and psychics that and
it's like yeah okay but you know are we
going to just we're g to go we're going
go and legal these things legalize all
these things and then we're going to
leave like the actual [ __ ] like fentel
and heroin and mess or whatever that
right actually is really where you need
to change the law yeah if you were
actually concerned about not having all
these people dying and stuff uh but yeah
it's like uh you
know cannabis ex exceptionalism
psychedelic exceptionalism and all this
stuff it's like uh
is a whole is a whole other conversation
but um I don't see it's going to feature
anytime soon in the sort of any any any
any serious discussions basically you
know I I just recently learned that in
Oregon um because someone got busted
there um seeds seed cells and stuff is
is a serious felony if you you're not
like you know fully legal with paperwork
and everything and they yeah dude went
to jail still
yeah kind of blew my mind because when I
think of Oregon like when I visited um
it's it's very open cannabis wise much
more open than where I'm at in
California obviously like red are I'm
not up to speed but yeah like it it it
seemed pretty I don't know normalized
there but uh the seeds if you're not
legal you know you don't have all your
paperwork in it's a lot more serious
penalties uh
yeah yeah it's very tricky it's so sort
of So like um there's such a big gray
area with all of this stuff it's uh you
know in the UK itself totally
uncontrolled in terms of moving the
seeds in and out of the country yeah
it's not there's zero regulation on it
like literally none you know yeah it's
um as in to to leave the borders of the
UK and come into the UK you know sure
but it obviously for the destination
countries that's becomes infinitely more
complicated but absolutely it's it's so
um it's it's so uh it's so so sort of
surreal this is the thing though I mean
and I I tend to repeat myself so just
steer me onto something else if I'm
getting boring sure go ahead the weird
thing is with the the UK is it's not
historically actually been a country
that has tended to to prohibit stuff you
know yeah like Narco colonialism was one
of the most IAL aspects of our history
in terms of things like opium and and
all of that so yeah Colonial history
imperialist history of the UK was drugs
were a huge part of it the the elite
discourse of this establishment figures
you know sort of liberal old school
liberal kind of 19th century 18th
century liberals for the most part just
like in so far as they knew about these
things just didn't give a [ __ ] it was
like well that's something they do there
can we make money out of it yes y can we
tax it yes great you know yeah
subject you know and then um in in in
the UK itself like uh you know heroin
was available on prescription as late as
the the 19 19 late 1960s you know you
could still yeah yeah and and um it was
regarded as a as a opiate addiction was
a medical thing the notion that it
should even be considered criminal was
completely just anathema to the whole
way it was de with you know um
so you know people like William Burrows
and all these kind of beat type
characters would come to the UK and
stuff you know because it was so because
it was such a common sense culture
towards these things you know yeah but
then they obviously went like off the
rails dramatically by the 70s yeah and
um partly
for actually kind of historical reasons
not necessarily to do with America per
se but it was you know largely sort of
American let the the the move towards a
more aggressive Pro prohibitionist
stance yeah but it
um yeah I mean uh you know even though
sort of I think it's probably the same
in the States now like doesn't matter
how far right you go really most people
in in the
conservative politics in the UK would
would if you talk to them on a personal
basis even publicly not would be like
yeah of course it shouldn't be
criminalized you know should be yeah
legal you know everything you know but
um yeah that's wild so much different
than the US I mean I maybe maybe
politicians on the right would say that
privately but definitely not
publicly I don't know if it's a it's a
religious thing because our country
religious sorry sorry what was that I'm
not sure if it's a religious thing
because our country is so religious
based or or what the difference is
there I mean it definitely one of the
major
um dividing lines between the US and the
UK was the there was a strong
disapproval of of uh British imperialism
particularly in Asia yeah you know in
World War II the Americans were just
very openly like why the [ __ ] should we
even be helping you guys keep control of
your colonies you know ignoring the
hypocrisy the Philippines and whatever
but but um the attitude was that and and
and and and it was uh even before then
the League of Nations when the first
kind of international attempts of
prohibition happened we're talking kind
of 1920s and stuff um it was the
Americans and the Egyptians who led the
move to kind of include cannabis on all
of the um antopia laws which were the
real driver of the first attempt to like
internationally prohibit drugs through
the League of Nations preu type idea the
it was the Americans and Egyptians who
were really led the charge especially to
get cannabis included on the on the laws
and that ironically that was using data
from the um quotes lunatic asylums of of
Egypt that the British had actually put
together because they were kind of
doctors and stuff within the imperialist
Machinery who were focused on this idea
that cannabis caused insanity and that
it was Associated criminality and stuff
so it was partly British material like
the research that supported the idea was
was used to support the idea that
cannabis might somehow make you insane
or was associated with violence and
criminality yeah basically because the
British even though they didn't want to
ban these things in in India were were
still quite happy to use the association
between cannabis and like marginal
groups you know groups of men hanging
out on Street in in parks and in urban
centers like laborers and stuff smoking
cannabis or what are you doing uh you
know they were quite happy to kind of
police these groups
using um or you know to control these
groups using cannabis you know so some
kind of radical dervish gets conscripted
into some army unit and it's causing
problems in the Barrack so he smokes
hash he's insane put him in the lunatic
asylum you know what I mean so they were
still was still exploiting it to control
undesirable people you know yeah so
there was this kind of paper trail
associating cannabis with um mental
illness that was used as early as the
1920s to to kind of shoe horn cannabis
into the antiopi Opium
laws wild
yeah I could into this with you for ever
but I I definitely want to make sure
that we go over some of what you have in
stock because oh yeah yeah sure yeah
please yeah yeah yeah I mean yeah I'd
love to have you on you know whenever
you have more time too because like like
I said there each one of these topics
like you you could really open it up and
talk about it forever and this is uh
what fascinates me
uh I know least
about yeah far away like because it's
better if
give some questions so that I don't just
drift back onto stuff that some people
would have heard me talk about before so
so the um let's start with uh one of the
ones I had experience with was from uh
the Highland Thai Burmese I think it was
called when it was first released yeah
that one's I thought that was an amazing
like uh plant that could be done well
indoor I don't know how it would compare
to you know point of origin but it could
be done well in in the USA um what can
you tell me about that
line um so that
um has been through a couple of like
exitu maintenance grows now um
so it's gonna I and I haven't directly
been involved with that since I
originally collected the seeds so any
they may have been inevitably going of
some possible shifts in what it actually
is now just from the fact that you know
we can't do more than like double digits
in terms of plant numbers of maintaining
it realistically so
um I got it from uh in in mongon from a
guy who
um uh an exat guy who was based up sort
of you know very near the border with
Burma and they were Hill tribe groups
um uh who had got a hold of seeds and
yeah it's difficult to know like I I
hopefully we'll be finding out soon
based on genomics analysis of it what
exactly is in the mix but I suspect it
may have a bit of hybridization with
more like kind of East Asian hemp lines
in there not just a a pure
um it's not like a
simple kind of pristine ganja uh land
race um
I but there's taii like Shen is another
name for them kind of groups up in those
areas who definitely have a culture of
of growing cannabis for themselves
sometimes like it was a real problem for
uh this friend of mine or rather you
know not friend of mine but a guy I I
met who was um growing up there he he
would do these kind of Gorilla Grow
yeah with tropical you know really nice
like tropical lines like kind of a
carola hay and stuff and then they the
plants would get to like you know within
like a couple of days of just being just
right you know and he goes out to cut
them down and he just find some Shang
come and just taken the whole lot you
know like exactly when it's just like a
you know he's like [ __ ] that's so brutal
because they really know exactly how to
grow it themselves so they're like um
they're waiting for the the perfect
[Music]
moment the day before he goes out to to
get them take the whole [ __ ] look
that's always scared me about gorilla
grows is is yeah like here they say
plant one for you plant one for the cops
plant one for the thieves you know yeah
yeah yeah thieving is it's not great but
it's what it is just the the um but yeah
so so I think they were lahu the actual
guys he got the seed from that lahu kind
of like a Musa is another name for them
they're like kind of a minority group
who uh around those border regions a lot
there like you know Hill tribe would be
the kind of people would use they and
they move across the borders between
China and Burma and L places quite
readily uh and uh I think they were
growing and had got a hold of some seeds
but the thing is around there there's a
quite a lot of um cultivation of uh
fiber types land races as well in those
areas particularly because it's been
encouraged by the Thai government so
there's just quite a high chance that
there's been hybrid hybridization
between them like my experience of it
was it was not like a highly potent
compared to what you can have in land
races yeah and then the very tall plants
as well plus the hollow stem tendency
made me think like quite possibly
there's some hybridization
happened and there certainly other lines
where that's plausible that that's
happened because they are grown on the
same grow Cycles as the hemp hemp and
and and and gandja are growing on the
same grow Cycles quite often in those
areas so there's possibility of
pollen Crossing
between populations it's so and I was
just thinking about it like um
asking you to explain any of the scent
profiles and stuff like that but it
really doesn't translate like because
like you said it's a very
plastic um I wouldn't want to that in
the sense that like
um the Nuance is so hard to get right I
mean yeah
um when I saw them like he deliberately
had brought down like two the two kind
of main expressions of that that entire
land race that I mean it may be
something totally different from what
the Highland TI that goes around in
America under the same name by the way
probably I shouldn't have used that name
for it because it just adds to the
confusion but he brought down like a a
much more kind of light green and the
light green and the purple batch yeah of
the same land race and the purple batch
was much more kind of down the mango
Katey end of the smell smell types and
then the light green I much preferred
was more kind of like really hard to
describe but it was sort of citrus but
not like straightforwardly it was like
very kind of
musky
um uh it's very hard to describe smells
but it was a much more compelling smell
for me and I'm sure would be the
preference if I was working the line was
that that side of it sure
um uh but you know um the other thing
the reason I suspect some Chinese hemp
type East Asian hemp type is the the
leaves um could be very um broad not not
like not like with the the indicia shape
per se necessarily
although I need I need to actually look
at them again to see where the broadest
point is on them but the but they just
anyway look like something quite
distinct from the real kind of classic
La Ean Thai type um je pool you
know yeah so most of these uh questions
we've actually covered as a course of
just conversing um yeah there's one I
mean like almost all of them we covered
just bying but one one that I think will
be probably the most asked question you
probably when you get a lot is from CCC
and he asked how to keep pure well pure
relatively pure uh sativ as manageable
indoors do you have any advice on
that
um I mean one of the main
um tricks people do that I'm aware of is
um uh you can use pot size to just
control and and and and like because if
it's really like a pure straight from a
farmer type sativa it's it's they're
going to keep rooting even during
flowering you know yeah so
um you can just pot up in the kind of
second week of flour or so still and you
should find that the it will still root
into the new compost which can be good
as well because it can mean that you
don't make the mistake of like
overfeeding too much during flour
absolutely um and the other
thing uh with sativas endorses to try to
not overwater them like it's a really
important aspect of of traditional
farming of of gja you know C whatever is
the right irrigation schedule so
even these days um the good quality uh
production in places like LA and stuff
is in areas where they've got access to
lakes or ponds or streams to irrigate on
schedule rather than just allowing
rain fed um you know dict yeah so in
other words the the main good quality
crop is done from sort of sewing in mid
augusti is and then harvesting kind of
Fe February is so you um uh September is
or whatever to February marchish
basically six months over the starting
at the end of monsoon so you can have a
bit of rain whilst the plants are in veg
but really once you're into flower
you're looking to like have zero rain
ideally and just have irrigation and the
mistake people make endorses to over
water we've already kind of touched on
that but um the other thing is you can
if there are real land race you can
prune back pretty [ __ ] heavily if you
want and you can you can you
can um concentrate the uh Bud production
into exactly where you want if you prune
carefully and you can prune like quite
late on in the cycle of growth still
yeah um
uh yeah think of other things to be
honest with you I'm not like an expert
grower I just know from talking to
people and and stuff yeah for sure I I
don't have like a huge amount of
opportunities to grow because of the
amount of moving around I do you know
yeah yeah can imagine that makes it
hard
um anyway I yeah it's uh but yes sativas
they're not well adapted to in indoors
basically as the bottom bottom line
really want to be outside and they will
um you know the the the type of land
they want to be on is is a really
important consideration so in the Big G
growing areas of India um in the late 19
30 20th century there was quite a good
documentation done of that whole economy
because it was economically very
significant um and um the land along the
rivers along the Ganges Delta area that
was very lomy like light
Sandy loans yeah that don't hold water
too much but are very nutrient Rich were
really sought after by people who wanted
to to to get into commercial production
you know yeah and um there were
techniques which are still used of of
how you prepare the land so you know
still they'll do this still in in
Southeast Asia as you um create um uh
ridges you know like raised ra
beds like a kind of semi um Circle type
shape with between them for the water
and then you plant on top of those um
half circles as it were you know what I
mean so Cur curved the raised bed and so
that means that you the water runs off
the roots so the thing you're just
trying to avoid is for the to have the
brot sitting in water logged um water
logged uh land because that yeah
cannabis just does not [ __ ] like that
and it will get it'll get infected and
there are all kinds of parasites and
pathogens that were already very well
known back in the in that time which are
even can ofis specific forms of powdery
milu and stuff you know um and um you
know I these conversations sometimes
with people who are like using
these um what is it
natural um sort of what is it some kind
of like people based basically growing
in this like composting compost it's not
even properly compan natural farming
stuff yeah yeah yeah I get these kind of
emails from people sometimes and it's
like I try and like be as nice as I can
yeah yeah it's tough like I'm like on
principle I'm like all for kind of
permac culture and anything like that
it's like but Jesus man like cannabis
does not want to be in that kind of
[ __ ] situation this guy writing to me
like yeah I've created this amazing
system where like the soil is wet
247 like RAC love that yeah right no
cannabis wants to be
like okay with Hydroponics and stuff
maybe they've I mean I think in over the
last 50 60 years like cannabis in the
west has adapted to all kinds of Mal
treatment but sure absolutely has
ultimately yeah you don't want to be
growing a land race in like soggy
incredibly Rich
compost especially like especially not
with like stuff literally rotting on the
surface yeah this guy's like can you
send me like a photo and he sends you
thing there like [ __ ] cooch grass
like growing in in the same pot do they
do
that yeah I mean know each their own I
guess but yeah God bless them if
someone's asking opinion like I feel I
should just tell them like no yeah just
don't grow this
type take
abuse
yeah um is there any strange you want to
highlight that you currently have for
sale right now or any anything else you
want to talk about and get
in I mean I'm really interested like uh
and you can um I we collected a bunch of
stuff from orisa which is sort of just
south of of Bengal okay uh which I
suspect is
um uh quite um historically significant
um in terms of the development of um of
sativas like real tropical CA land races
uh you know we were talking about
there's that um book the kind of
alchemic it's an alchemical book
actually the an and theander is the name
of it um where they describe the sin
technique that's from around there kind
of Andres uh orisa area was where that
was probably
compiled and um I suspect those plants
are pretty
interesting uh to look at uh they seem
to be like probably more like five
months from seed to harvest uh the ones
we've got and um also
um yeah and and then um planning to have
some napoi um uh ganja land r R
available soon as well which I think
will be pretty interesting I mean just
in terms of product stuff like I'm a big
fan of Southeast Asians but the because
of the Aromas and stuff and I think
there's been a lot of hybridity
between possibly like independent
centers of domestication south of unan
with the the east
Indian uh sens of domestication I don't
know this is just a hunch but um anyway
I think these
uh actual South Asian land races like
from Arisa and Andre Pradesh and um the
terai regions of nepool are worth
checking out so we've got already uh
some like Dakin khi is the name of the
one from nepool that we've got that's
kind of
uh uh you could say like been
domesticated it definitely has been
domesticated for use as bud not just as
hash yeah and then the orisa one is very
much specifically for bud and um both of
them I think would be really interesting
to look at uh really nice Aromas from
them too as well you know um and types
of effect are really good like very
stimulating and
positive it sounds freaking awesome to
be honest yeah yeah I'm quite C to see
what the genomics work discovers about
them because my hunch is they're
probably that uh East India and Nepal
and East India are kind of where sativas
really
originate first we'll see yeah that's so
fascinating I can't wait to see that all
work out um where where should people go
to buy your seeds uh what's the
website um the real seed company.com and
then for the for the modern stuff is
quick seeds.com it's a stupid name but
it's like what I
originally yeah I'd originally planned
it as like a budget thing I was just
going to buy a bunch of like Cheapo
Dutch SE and sell it on there and [ __ ]
it I'm just don't want to get into big
business stuff and so it's kind of just
but um yeah that's where we've for the
time being anyway all the all the kind
of really interesting 90s material we've
got and some other um there's like some
later 90s things like uh Cinderella 99
Amnesia uh which is really good very
strong as well if you're looking for
like strong uh really strong stuff and
then some Colombian
um
um uh like a Colombian import that's
probably like a Northern Lights crossed
with a Colombian land race then crossed
with some like um um air Colombian and
Mexican things all kinds of things like
that you can find there and a whole
bunch of just like kind of fun hybrids
with things like uh Pakistan TR tral
Kush crossed with like some land races
which be great like for just making hash
and stuff and or for
Bud yeah and and very uh nice prices for
most of it yeah um yeah just yeah fun
stuff to play with if you've got the
space and things any any way uh you'd
prefer to be contacted to if people want
to reach out to you yeah sure I
generally um if you want a quick
response like uh the um Gmail re real
Seed Co at gmail is best uh you can
contact me on Instagram as well but I'm
sometimes I'm not on there like I I may
not get back to you as quickly and I
sometimes miss the um miss the uh
incoming messages you know yeah like
forget to check the request a bit
sometimes so yeah
always to to use this use the site
contact form or just email me directly
and and that I should get back to you
within like two three days max you know
awesome well I got to say i' love to
have you back sometime when time allows
you it's been an absolute
pleasure yeah I and and and um I've
really enjoyed it and it's very kind of
you to give me the space to just ramble
but I I'm slightly [ __ ] burned out
and a bit like sleep deprived oh was
seem to be when I do these podcasts but
um maybe when I'm back in theuk we do
another one at a more civilized well
it's kind of a civilized hour now but
I'm just not a civilized person so I've
not been getting out of bed before like
any anyway but uh yeah anyway it's been
it's been good though yeah thanks man
I've enjoyed it I I appreciate your time
my friend and um I'll talk to you soon
this is going to air Friday and uh yeah
people are gonna be stoked people are
really going to dig it I'll probably cut
it into two or three parts yeah yeah
nice one yeah yeah yeah right cool I'll
keep you posted on it and again thank
you for your time and um yeah it's an
honor I really appreciate it thank you
yeah all right brother I'll talk to you
soon yeah cool so that that's um that's
that is it like uh right yeah and send
me the um everything over like and I'll
as soon as you've got it all going oh
absolutely yeah and and it'll premere
live and there'll be people in chat
there's usually over 100 something
people that'll watch it live gets a few
thousand views in the first two days
awesome yeah yeah nice is okay yeah just
uh and and so it will go on YouTube and
everything yeah yep yeah okay yeah yes
I'll put it on the site as well and that
would be great I appreciate that nice
one all right my friend thank you so
much and thank you like seriously thank
you for your time I know it's hard to no
no it's pleasure I can I like I can talk
at length about this whenever
so yeah it's always I appreciate it nice
one man well have a have a lovely
evening and and I hope it's more been
over the last few
weeks that sounds fin a smooth
yeah well enjoy enjoy all right I'll
talk to you soon yeah nice one cheers
bye
bye want more Syndicate check out our
patreon in the description below thank
you for joining us on this journey we
are forever thankful that enough people
watch us to keep us going with that in
mind you can show your support for the
show by liking subscribing and sharing
the show we don't have advertised so we
need you also hit riot.com and
syndicate.com to show more support for
the show kick over the statues and bring
it back to the farmers
[Music]