welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the the corporate cannabis and
Seed posers are obus skating for their
own Financial benefit welcome to the
underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate so yeah I was TR I was
thinking of like where to go with this
because you've done other shows before
but I think like briefly not even
briefly like as as much as you want to
go into on your start obviously where
your interest started how you got
specifically into like a very Niche area
of like the land race heirloom older
lines you know um yeah yeah and we have
questions from people in our Discord and
I want to talk some of the lines
obviously that you carry so it can shine
some light on some of those too plus I'm
interested in a lot of them and I have a
bunch so yeah yeah yeah nice um yeah uh
that's cool that people have sent in
questions because it's always good to
sort of yeah answer that for people
because often often I sort of don't
realize the extent I mean I do I do
people mention it but you know when
people come to the site and they're a
bit overwhelmed by the sheer quantity of
stuff on there and things like that yeah
um but yeah I mean um for me it was uh
something
the getting into this sort of niche as
it were was more um
the growing up in the UK in the
90s yeah
um some of my well in fact all of my
first encounters with cannabis were
through uh stuff that friends of mine's
parents had you know so sort of boomer
generation people who would still in
that era go and you know to napol and
places and bring back stuff to smoke and
that kind of thing and then the people
who I was talking to it about talking to
about it were also of that generation
and would sort of regil me with
anecdotes about smuggling hashack from
Afghanistan and this type of thing you
know so kind of triggered your interest
um yeah I mean that was my perspective
on it was that that was the real cache
the real kind of um you know um
mythologized stuff was that old old type
of old school cannabis you know that was
anyway what I was kind of raised the
context in which I grew up into cannabis
was one in which that was always had the
biggest sort sort of prestige attached
to it you know these were these old kind
of like um hippie type characters you
know like um is probably a
slightly I mean they definitely were
back in the 60s
but um those you know they were doing
the hippie trail and stuff and yeah
doing kind of scams like that and then
as teenagers we would occasionally like
you know I'm talking kind
of very early 90s and things would
obviously being so close to Amsterdam in
England anyway you um do we were seeing
that um people were starting to to grow
but it wasn't the indoor indoor kind of
domestic production in the UK didn't
really take off in a big way until the
late 90s early 2000s and suddenly in the
space of a couple of years imported
cannabis just disappeared from the UK
completely so most Imports anyway if
you're in UK unless you knew someone
were pretty [ __ ] [ __ ] Moroccan hash
to be honest throughout that era but if
you did know someone you could get you
know nice swy red sort of West
African
Nigerian and you could still get good
good Moroccan and you'd see Lebanese
you'd see very seldom see like really
good Afghan to get that you'd need to go
to Holland or someone somewhere to
actually find someone who could get the
real stuff because most of what most of
the Afghan Pakistani type hash by that
point that you'd see in the UK was bunk
even though people didn't seem to
realize you know yeah but um but uh
anyway
so but if we did if we did see like what
we would call skunk and that kind of
stuff in the early
90s we'd sit you know I'd sit with my
friends around their house and stuff and
their parents would just be like oh this
stuff's terrible why are you [ __ ]
touching all crap you know and they just
give us this kind of lecture about how
awful it is and stuff and um so that was
kind of my perception anyway and then
also you know friends of mine who are
Australians would basically had the same
attitude it's like if they came around
and they saw and this again older
generation you know if they saw us
growing things it'd be like oh these
aren't pure sativas you need like proper
sativas and they'd Rave about Thai and
Indonesian and paping yugin and sativas
and stuff you know so always my
perspective anywhere that so for it was
just that was the natural thing to be
interested in and when I did start
trying to grow for myself I sort of had
this realization [ __ ] hell I know
where all these places are I want these
seeds and I can see online that all
these other people are wanting these
seeds I know where to go to go and get
them and um so it's just a kind of
natural progression really it just um
you
know uh it all kind of fell into
place that that takes connection like to
to track down like legitimate stuff and
and you seem to be quite a well read
historian of cannabis and um yeah I
can't imagine the links that you've had
to go to to to even to bring out a lot
of this old stuff and a lot of the the
land race stuff as
well um I would say it's sort of partly
become possible because of spending
enough time in these places that
um you get to know people and they trust
you enough you know yeah abely
of
uh it really varies though because some
some bits of some bits of the
um of Asia
anyway it's not really that you need
particularly to have connections you
just need to know where the places are
you know yeah so
um you know you can
you can go to this as long as you know
where the places are in a lot of in a
lot of the more Central Asian Parts it's
actually quite a lot easier because it's
it's really the tropics where it's more
tricky because there's no reason to have
seeds in the tropics other than to grow
C you know it's not like their food or
something like in napole some of the
landr types
anyway as much as anything are
cultivated for the seeds you know yeah
so there are some areas where and and
the same actually is kind of true in in
even in um the Hindu Kush you know is
the seeds are a winter food source as
well so you
could yeah yeah yeah people this is a
really overlooked thing actually like
even amongst the experts people seem to
realize
that cannabis is a multi-purpose crop in
all of the Northern areas like including
Afghanistan and the Hindu Kush the only
bit where it's not a multi-purpose crop
is in the tropical areas where where
it's ganja which is s the semi sensy
whatever you want to call it that's the
only where it's a single purpose crop it
is only grown for producing the buds you
know guess that makes sense too with the
hash with the hash production and stuff
because they could still collect the
hash and harvest the seeds yeah yeah so
you know um sometimes like um I've read
people like David Watson Sam skunkman
saying you know we tried really hard to
um persuade the Afghans to like grow the
crop as s am and like they just actually
just wer interested and there's a pretty
good reason for that which is that
actually the seeds are a very important
winter food source they're very high in
you know important fats and proteins as
well and particularly in the mountains
that's really necessary because
obviously you can't keep like huge herds
of animals very easily in in the
mountains you can have a few cows and
goats and stuff but it's not like um
there's a
there's a there's a huge demand for land
and water and everything in in any
mountain area and so you know if you
can have that extra source of protein
and fats it's it's pretty essential
actually you know I
would some of the Mid Eastern places
would be super hard to uh make those
connection especially nowadays um I
remember hearing even Neville's story
back with
um I think Clive I think that's what he
goes by
um when they went to I think it was
Afghanistan and one of them ODed in a
hut and they were you know trying to
kick in their door and whatnot that
that's how the story went anyways so I
can only imagine how crazy it is to try
to get inroads in their nowadays with
the political
climate um I mean one thing one thing
I'd pick up on first is just in terms of
thinking about the geography of cannabis
um Afghanistan I think if you if you
want to have a kind of
clear just because I think it's really
helpful you know with with everything is
like context is everything and and for
cannabis it's really good to get the
geographical and cultural context kind
of on a basic kind of map in your mind
as it were and I would say Afghanistan
is best sort of it's like Southern
Central Asia so Central Asia rather than
the Middle East is how I would talk
about it in terms because it's um that's
the really Central you know in what we
call indicas in the sort of loose sense
colloquial sense are a Central Asian
domesticate basically and uh so
Afghanistan is really sort of the
Southern edge of Central Asia and um
rather than the Middle East I think if
you is Middle East isly more sort of
confusing confusing term yeah yeah um
because you know it connects Afghanistan
really sort of connects in a cannabis
sense with shinjang and places like that
which is eastern central Asia yeah
bukara is sort of really you know
Central Central Asia as it were and
those are all
historically very connected
important cannabis centers in terms of
the sort of indicia type yeah land races
um but yeah going to those places
um yeah I mean it's been it's been
increasingly difficult
um especially with the uh
Taliban being allowed to kind of yeah
retake the entire place and stuff but um
yeah and you know there is also yeah the
fact the
other definitely one thing I found going
to those bits of the world is that the
the culture of kind of OPM and stuff
does um mix with the Cannabis culture
quite a lot and I definitely met
characters who were having problems with
things like you know harder
substances like heroin yeah but
um
the yeah I mean it's there's there's
various ways to do these things I mean
some of the people who were helping us
for a while were were were stringers for
for media um and journalism in fact all
of the people I know
who from these places who were were were
were working as stringers and uh which
means sort of helping um
um you know journalists and media
companies who who want to make
Productions in those areas to to meet
the people find the right places doing
that kind of job and then they would um
just have a sideline in like helping
collect seeds for us basically you know
and then obviously once
the once the
um the the um Biden sort of pulled the
plug on air support for and tech support
and everything for the Afghan Army and
it just got overrun and most of them had
to then um spend the next sort of you
know half a year in like safe houses
trying not to get
executed yeah it's not great it gives
you a different perspective on these
things because everyone's sort of like I
mean you
know detour too far into politics but I
I thought the whole that whole
um post 11 Adventure was just completely
misguided but it's like once they've
actually committed to it to then just
suddenly [ __ ] turn around and say
actually you know what [ __ ] that we're
just going to leave and not even tell
you yeah was just a just an astonishing
[ __ ] betrayal but everyone was
expecting it so it's American that's
what they do
it's is between extremes there's no sort
of just seems to be capable of finding a
kind of sensible middle ground on
foreign policy to
yeah always going one way or the other
too far it's like oh we don't want
nothing to do with it oh we're all in oh
we want nothing to do with it oh we're
all in it's like Jesus man just [ __ ]
you know this insane ISM that seems to
[ __ ] infect all the thinking about it
leaving all the caches of weapons and
whatnot too just to find their their
homes to
wherever do something Ukraine the way
it's going so just gift them the entire
[ __ ] um anyway but yeah um it's it's
it's um but yeah so yeah I mean that's
that's mostly what I've seen of it is
the the post 911 kind of version of the
hippie Trail so it is quite hard to
avoid the political aspects of it
because it absolutely the landscape so
transformed by the time I got to see
most of it like it you know the context
in which I saw people smoking a lot were
like um security guards and sort of yeah
you know sort of those kind of
characters like sitting around like with
like you
know guns and stuff outside places like
embassies and hotels and whatever you
know very publicly smoking hash and
things it's like there sort of there's a
whole um Marshal kind of militant not
militant you know
um Warfare type context of cannabis use
there and things that I started to as
young it's not just a sort of um the the
hippie Trail stereotypes of sort of
spiritual use and things are actually
just one side of the the culture of
cannabis there's whole ranges of of ways
it's used traditionally that aren't
necessarily part of the main Western
discourse of like Oriental cannabis
culture you know yeah that's that's part
of the story that fascinates me because
it's it's a lot of the stuff that even
as deep into cannabis history and stuff
as I am that's like not something I'm
really super familiar with so I don't
speak on it you know I don't know it but
you're the type of person that I can
speak to that has a lot more insight
into that and I think uh the more people
are able to see all these different
perspectives um different ways of
thinking about how it's been used maybe
ways they've never even considered you
know I think that's really important to
talk
about yeah I think it's like I think
everyone you know we all kind of want
to uh kind of know what the roots of the
plant are and where it's come from and
things um but there's definitely been a
tendency in in sort of the WR on in in a
lot of the writing about it to to favor
this idea that it's
um to to favor aspects of it that fitted
with the sort of historical moment of
the 60s when it really became a mass
phenomenon in the west you know which
was yeah most sort of the anti-war
anti-racist um an sort of
countercultural
uh aspects that were emphasized although
things like you know the assassins and
stuff did kind of creep in there because
that was already talked about quite a
lot in sort of
Orient myths of or Legends or whatever
so you know that and that
does go into the martial context of use
and stuff as
well one one thing I thought we should
go over early on too because uh I mean
the nomenclature is important and and
even even this far in like I don't feel
confident anymore like trying to say
what I think a land race is versus an
heirloom versus you know anything else
um I'd love to have your your actual
working definitions of some of these
things as we talk about it so people
understand what we're talking about when
we say land race and heirloom varieties
yeah yeah sure always a good idea yeah
it's just [ __ ] mindfield of like
different terms so so I mean land race
is just a really unfort forunate word
from my perspective that was a
translation that was made in the sort of
late 19th early late 19th century from
various European languages into English
from German terms Danish terms whatever
like l in German it would be land rasa
that was translated into English as land
race um whereas actually if you were to
do that translation these days land race
would be best translated as country
breed or something like that
oh yeah so it's a
defunct form of the word race that we
just don't use anymore it's completely
archaic now in English but it was race
did once in English have the meaning of
breed as in a created something that
someone has breed has created like a
crop or a breed of animal you know so so
so land races a uh
artificially selected they're Creations
by humans for products that we want
they're created in certain areas by
Farmers so they they have an element of
region being region specific and culture
but they're culture specific and they're
absolutely creatures of human desire and
whatever so they they're things that
farmers have created for certain
products so all land races are product
specific so the um tropical land races
are spefic specific
for and we're talking drug quote you
know air quotes drug cannabis here so
tropical land races from places like
India southeast Asia are all
specifically
for uh c/ semi Sensi as in ganja is the
traditional term for this like it's the
seedless inflorescences or or you know
very lightly seeded yeah should be like
that and then that product goes back to
at least the 15th century perhaps as
early as the 12th century in India you
can find Sanskrit literature that
describes that technique of roguing out
the males cutting down the males how to
maximize resin production by certain
cultivation techniques and so on so
Jesus what we call sativas
are you know there those are what we
call sativas so the tropical land races
narrowly
flitted um high THC because they've got
this uh long his history of individual
plant selection
that's enabled by keeping the seed
from batch of good ganja you know
because yeah in
practice uh Farmers
don't you know you can find uh genuinely
100%
C it is still around even these days in
in places like India and la and Thailand
and stuff but for the most part
you if you buy a batch
of any significant size of ganja you
will find one or two seeds in there if
you're in India you know it's can be
loads of seeds often you know but
um it shouldn't be like that and
historically it wasn't like that for the
most part you know it's amazing goes
back that far I didn't know that that it
went back to the with h
selections yeah yeah so with with um
cutting down um yeah and you know so the
the point the point is that individual
plant selection is a is a strong
selected pressure and that is enabled by
that strong seleced pressure is enabled
by the fact that you do often
find a seed or two in a batch of ganja
that you would buy you know absolutely
so consumers and afficionados and
farmers are all able to do that so
consciously or unconscious ly you've got
at least 500 years of individual plant
selection being a factor in the creation
of sativas which is why as any kind of
offici andado knows they are the
strongest forms of land races
Thai Lao
Burmese South Indian like
Kerala uh all these types of plants are
what went in to form the real kind of
original Haze yeah type sativas that
people know in the States and you know
back in the late 60s early' 70s this was
literally
fetching multiples its weight in gold in
terms of price by the time it got from
from Thailand to the west coast of the
United States and it was the same in in
England so if you look at the custom
seizures records from the early 70s for
for for cannabis that was coming from
places like Ean and Thailand it was like
they were it was testing you know with
thin layer chromatography but which is
not hugely accurate but it was testing
kind of 17% THC yeah and that's when
they're not gaming the tests and it's
probably sat in a warehouse in London or
for months never mind how long it took
to get to England in the first place you
know yeah so yeah I me we're talking
high levels of potency so people aren't
making it up when they say that this
stuff could blow your head off you know
even in the 7s and to doesn't you don't
need much more than 10% THC anyway a lot
of it's about the other stuff that's in
this in these the other phyto chemicals
that are in these PLS absolutely anyway
to to stay focused so there those are
the sativas and then in the north the
main group is what people call
colloquially indicas which are the you
know I guess everyone knows what I'm
talking about broadly speaking but again
this is a type of land race that um you
know with the more semi- dwarf
morphology used for making hash so
product specific there's no culture of
CA in north of 30 degrees latitude so
once you've got to the north of Pakistan
there just is no fact in fact once
you've even got to the Punjab in India
or the Punjab in Pakistan it's bisected
by colonialism the um once you've got
there there's no culture of s by the
time you even get to the Punjab once
you've gone north of the Punjab towards
the foothills of the Hindu
Kush absolutely no sense culture at all
it's all hash and uh it's always been
that way so when you make hash you pull
the seeds yeah in the process of making
the hash so there just there not ever re
been much in the way of any individual
plant selection on hash land races so
they bulk selected crop
that probably goes back Millennia
perhaps um that bulk selection which is
why on balance the the um the the
cannabinoid um uh characteristics of of
of of Inda land races do of lean
slightly towards THC
dominant um plants like type one plants
as people would call it but you do have
in the population a mix of
type one type two type three uh so you
know High ratio of THC to CBD is type
one balanced THC and CBD is type two and
then type three is sort of higher ratio
of CBD to THC so most hash land races
will typically if they're a pure land
race we're talking not a you know not
Afghani number one or something you can
buy off a
Dutch um seed bank um if they're a real
land race they tend to be like that they
do lean slightly W type one because
they've had that history of bulk
selection it's you know more than random
more than random lean towards type one
but um uh yeah if if you want to grow a
crop of cila from from seed it's not
much
use uh to to to use a a real land race
you know there need to be worked to to
make them a cin cultiva you know so if
you were talking about the difference
between an heirloom and a land race
heirloom is not a technical term as far
as I know but it I would Define it in
the context of cannabis as uh a land
race that's been worked specifically for
in in a in a western modern context for
cin so x18 or deep chunk or Afghani
number one they're all in indicia
indicia heirlooms in the sense they're
an indicia land race that's been worked
for making sense yeah that's how Define
it that makes sense yeah yeah
yeah uh and then you've got one other
feral varieties then like how how would
you define those in in terms of like
land race heirloom is it its own
type
um so
um
feral or kind of wild type is another
term you could use that I think is quite
good um there
um you you don't find them much in the
tropics that as as a as a rule cannabis
doesn't
naturalize uh very well in the tropics
it's not uh a species that is well
adapted to that type of climate so if
you do find if you do find feral um
cannabis in the tropics it's because
you're you're you're at altitude
somewhere with a fairly temperate
climate
um so for the most part if you if you're
in for example India
you might find
weedy uh cannabis growing like anywhere
sort of north of the Ganges so we're
talking between in in in the sort of top
half of North India between the Ganges
and the Himalayas you know okay and then
as you go up towards the Himalayas
suddenly you'll find areas where it just
grows [ __ ] everywhere you
know just Seas of feral stuff especially
if you go up into Pakistan like Punjab
[ __ ]
everywhere um uh and then up into the
mountains around the river and places it
anywhere where there's kind of disturbed
land but it's basically uh as a species
it's
uh it's a step species meaning it likes
kind of
windy um fairly dry places where there's
lots of disturbed land and uh to grow
along the sides of rivers where animals
come to drink and [ __ ] and
stuff like high
nitrogen uh
decent amounts of water but not rainy
you know
um CBD dominant for stuff like
that um no um not necessarily so um
basically they're kind of um like nobody
knows where there's a pure nobody's ever
kind of satisfactorily identified like a
pure wild like unaffected by humans pure
wild cannabis plants has never been
found you know that makes sense so what
you actually have is like parallel
populations that have just been swapping
genes with whatever the local form of
cannabis is you know in the sense of
like humans domesticated at
least I don't know kind of say 8,000
years ago probably we started at least
you know unintentionally domesticating
cannabis yeah and um by just bringing it
back to Hunter gather is like bringing
it back to places where they were eating
and stuff like were unconsciously
selecting for types that we liked you
know yeah and then quite happy to grow
around our campfires and stuff because
there was lots of [ __ ] and discarded
animal bones and stuff that just are
good for cannabis to so
um um basically if you're in somewhere
like the Punjab where it grows which is
north uh West
India where where where there's a lot of
wildr cannabis you can you can people do
like crop the
feral uh weedy stuff provided it's
somewhere clean that's not Dusty and
things you can just crop that and um use
it for making food and things you know
yeah so these are high high THC
um in in the sense of
uh they will get you stoned you know
it's yeah it's it's not like in um
places like I don't know Wisconsin or
somewhere in the states where it's
basically hemp that's gone feral you
know yeah the fiber h
r yeah I mean these are definitely like
if we're talking probably make things
confusing but anyway these are like in
in in in in those in all of sort of
Central and South South Asia where you
get feral populations it's pretty much
um drug drug type quotes cannabis yeah
and then in the Himalayas like uh people
do sometimes hand rub the the feral
populations for for Charis and it makes
what people sometimes call jungly chis
as in like wild chis but actually
there's a again this is one of those
kind of hippie Trail type
confusions there's been this assumption
that Himalayan cannabis is always feral
cannabis which is it which it isn't like
yeah
99% of the Charis that's produced in the
Himalayas every year is
From
domesticated intentionally cultivated at
land races grown in fields by a farmer
you know yeah this that it's the
Himalayan cannabis is uh is all wild and
stuff is not not accurate like in terms
of the product is is very seldom
produced from the wild wedi stands you
can and people do but it's got way less
resin production than the than the
actual land races do you know
I'm yeah and and and it's useless for
making Cino it's not it's all going to
be seeded anyway yeah you can't use it
for to smoke as butd it's just it's I
mean you do see sadu doing that I have
seen sadu like her Yogi's wondering kind
of Yogi characters whove yeah gone up to
the Himalayas and picked picked a whole
load of feral flowers and then they just
sit and they kind of pick out the seeds
and mix it with some tobacco and smoke
it but it's it's not like it's uh you
know it's
not um designed for that yeah is why
people graub it for Chas because it it's
timec consuming to do but you end up
with a product that is actually going to
get you stoned yeah whereas smoking a
whole load of feral Bud like that mixed
with tobacco it's more just like a kind
of maybe take the edge
off whatever physical discomfort you
experience as a as a wondering Yogi but
it's not going to like get you
particularly High I wouldn't have
thought unless you really just happen to
find an unusually strong plant sure yeah
you know um one of the the interesting
things like from from the American
perspective at least for mine um is
trying like in my mind to Divi Define
Expressions between uh when people talk
about indicia types specifically or the
the broadleaf types um the differences
between like an Afghan type plant and a
Pakistani plant where the the overlap is
and you know like there's always talk of
Chinese um broadleaf types and I I've
never got my hands on any of those I
remember someone made the unan available
for a while but I never got to grow any
um I'd like to hear some of your Insight
on that and the the major differences
and I know it's kind of hard to
generally speak on expressions from
Whole regions you know depending on the
elevation but is there anything that
you've noticed between um say
Afghanistan and Pak Pakistan in in how
they grow um scent Expressions anything
like
that I mean it's it's particularly
difficult with um those Northern type
Central Asian you know Afghan Pakistani
yeah
uh populations because what you get if
you grow like a first generation of
direct from those places like seeds
directly from a farmer in Pakistan or
Afghanistan whatever there's a huge
amount of variation within the
population of one batch of seeds from
one farmer so the range of Aromas that
you're going to find in one field from
plant to plant just in one of those land
races is extraordinarily diverse you
know one plant might be really kind of
like kind of candy shot sweet Tangy
Aromas the next one might smell like a
dog [ __ ] you know yeah whatever and and
and and so it's particularly in those
Northern populations there's because
they're bulk selected they're not as
genetically narrow as tropical sativa
populations are so because they they
haven't had they haven't you know the
the genome hasn't been Stepped On by
Farmers doing much in the way of very
consciously intentionally directed
breeding there's a huge amount of
variation anyway and
then on top of that in terms of the
difficulty of generalizing you know cuz
the the Assumption amongst afficionados
is that Precision more Precision in in
your description means more accuracy but
actually if you get if you get too
precise on these things you become less
accurate you know yeah for sure there's
vast amounts of diversity so
particularly with cannabis because it's
so
phenotypically plastic so it because
like I saying it's a mountain
uh species that's evolved um at
altitude um to adapt to the huge climate
shifts you get at altitude and that kind
of thing it can express itself very
differently depending on where it's
planted so if you were to plant the same
land race at sea level and then plant it
at three and a half th000
meters exactly the same batch of seeds
from the same fare
uh you will see very different plant
looking plants morphologically because
you plant them up higher altitude
they're going to grow much shorter broad
more broadly they're going to pump out
way more resin yeah probably going to
have different phytochemicals really
smell different and everything you know
so yeah and likewise if you you can get
that even with tropical sativas if you
grow them on well they're going to be
amazing if you grow them incompetently
they're not going to smell so good you
know yeah um
you kind of have to go to point of
origin to to experience them as they
are uh yeah I mean it definitely makes a
vast difference even with the more
genetically narrow populations like
tropical steas if they're grown well by
someone who knows how to do it on the
right type of land with the right
irrigation timing the right feeding
timing the right uh you know everything
if you overwater tropical late and
flower is going to keep growing keep
putting out Buds and leaflets and it's
going to be [ __ ] yeah and no one and
this is why you get all this Bullocks
talk about 30 weeks ativas indoors and
stuff it's just people just keep on
[ __ ] watering it you know so stoping
experience but anyway you know and if
you look at the Historical records it's
always it will tell you this like in the
um 19th century documentation of of the
ganja farms in um Bengal and places it's
like yeah Farmers always say the worst
thing that can happen is we get rains in
like January February and it'll [ __ ] up
our whole crop because it will start
shooting again yada yada yada yeah
anyway so it's all it's all there if if
you if you want to look and stuff and I
have blogged about this on on the site
as well if people are wanting to go into
more depth and you can find all the
sources and stuff but um it's amazing
blog by the way like it's I've learned a
lot reading through it over the years oh
that's good to know I I GL glad someone
reads it yeah I do I mean it's it's how
I how I um like came to know you without
speaking to you a bunch was through the
blog and seeing the passion and how you
write and how in-depth the detail was
and and over time learning how accurate
it was which is the most important you
know yeah yeah man thanks I appreciate
it I I've shifted most of it now to the
actual main website blog rather than the
sort of um independent blog because uh
it just seems to make more sense so
generally I've been kind of moving
everything over to the main blog on the
site now just because uh it seems to
make more sense but I before I lose the
thread of what you were originally
asking um so in terms of Pakistan versus
Afghanistan so the thing to bear in mind
is like um seeds move around a lot seeds
move around with people in areas where
people use them as as a food and not
just for growing as well
yeah plus
um uh you know these are artificial
political boundaries so there's no
cultural real boundary if in in in
meaningful terms cannabis wise
between the Hindu Kush in Pakistan and
the Hindu Kush in Afghanistan you know
yeah so I want to try to kind of avoid
being sort of [ __ ] as far as possible
but there's all this stuff I see on
Instagram with people talking about
Duren line and stuff and like the dur is
this it's just just [ __ ] that's
bizarre to me as well because I think
most of the kids who are doing this are
like Asian as well so it's like the DAR
line was just Dar was just some [ __ ]
from the UK who drew a pencil line
across the boundary between Pakistan and
Afghanistan you know the [ __ ] has that
got to do with anything you know
and and and it's only in the last kind
of 10 years the um uh they've actually
really started policing that border and
putting fences up and things and even
then it doesn't make the blindest
[ __ ] bit of difference anyone who
really wants to get things across it can
still do it but in cannabis terms it's
just [ __ ] meaningless I mean and and
and seeds have been you know uh seeds
have been moved from Afghanistan down to
places like tra Valley in Pakistan you
know there's there's plenty of local
stories about the various kind of
dervish like kander Sufi type Saint
characters who are s of credited with
bringing seeds into T and things and and
and um which T is one of the big
cultivation valleys in Pakistan and yeah
this this whole area is is seemless
seamless with it's the whole reason the
politics and the history is the way it
is is because it's impossible to police
these mountain borders you know oh I'm
sure huge smuggling between these places
and then uh chitral is another one of
the famous areas like yaku Valley and
things up in the Hindu Kush these all
lead into Shin Jang these are the trade
routes that you would take from shinjang
which is the Eastern Central Asian area
this turkic area of of politically it's
inside what's now China and this was a
the biggest hash producing uh region in
in the world for oh wow for centuries oh
absolutely I mean this was the epicenter
of hash production so it wasn't
Afghanistan or Pakistan it was shinjang
was until the
19 late 1930s was the absolute [ __ ]
epicenter of world hash production I
mean thousands and thousands of tons of
hash were being moved from these places
across the mountain passes into the into
India because all the money was in
Northern India yeah and the demand for
these products was in Northern India in
these huge cities which even in the late
19th century places like lore and Delhi
had millions of well lore certainly had
is the big kjab city had you know seven
eight 9 10 million people or whatever
even in the
1860s so these were
massively massive senses of demand for
these products and so they the the
production was all happening in eastern
central Asia so in shinjang and um you
know the British were trying to make
sure as much of what came into India was
being taxed effectively they didn't want
too much smuggling and um you know seeds
were moving around between these places
you can read about the people who were
responsible for uh a lot of the uh
initiation of like commercial production
in in um in shinjang for India were
often Indians or uh ethnically E from
ethnic groups of of the mountains of
Pakistan you know
so there there's just not
um um much basis for assuming that
there's going to be
a you know there's there's a very
nuanced picture if you're talking about
the diff how how these land races in
these regions are differentiated from
each other
yeah once you get into Pakistan in the
northern mountains there probably is a
certain degree of mixing between kind of
the more sativa type
um the further south you move away from
the southern edges of Central Asia the
further south you get away from the
Hindu
Kush there probably is
more prep there is a a higher likelihood
that you're going to have a degree of
intermixing with more Monsoon type
tropical type Punjabi type
populations uh so you know more
hybridization between sativa type
populations and indicia type populations
the further north you go
into I don't know into places like
shinjang there a higher likelihood I
guess of it being a a sort of quotes
pure indicia type you know so if you
look at the plants that were brought
back from Shin Jang in the early 20th
century by people like Frank Meyer and
stuff for the US DA they definitely are
very Inda
looking um plants and um uh yeah I mean
you know um you had some of those
pictures on your blog too correct yeah
yeah so yeah and and
um uh you know
they're there's no question that there
are these distinct types you know the
confusion the confusion with the
discussion about are there such things
as indicas and sativas is
like yes there definitely are in terms
of if you're looking at pure land races
yeah real land
races um there are these clearly
distinct types there's also of course
some integrating between them even in
pure land races some some Landes are
likely to have Arisen through mixing of
these types uh but of course once you
move into the context of what you're
going to find at most dispensaries or
seed banks uh like Canabis internet seat
banks that is yeah most of what you're
going to find is is a indic sativa
hybrid so this terminology becomes
meaningless in in often most of the time
in those contexts you know
yeah important Point too like especially
uh from people that in in the US that
can go to collectives and stuff and
they're seeing Inda hybrid sativa and
they feel like they have a pretty good
work working knowledge of what what each
is and um quite often I mean I don't
really see anything to narrow Lea
anywhere you know or no not at all it's
problem because
um
um that's how cannabis goes extinct you
know yeah biodiversity and cannabis
primarily disappears through
hybridization you know yeah
so uh this impulse that most people have
to like hybridize everything when they
CU it is fun you know like see what
happens yeah actually the most exciting
thing you can do really these days
especially is to actually keep some
pristine lines going that you haven't
outcrossed because that's the
basis of uh everything really and once
we've got to a point where all we've got
a hybridized lines then it becomes
impossible to to do breeding doesn't
become impossible but you can't make
true F1
cultiv yeah
[Music]
want more Syndicate check out our
patreon in the description below thank
you for joining us on this journey we
are forever thankful that enough people
watch us to keep us going with that in
mind you can show your support for the
show by liking subscribing and sharing
the show we don't advertise so we need
you also hit Riot seeds.com and
syndicate.com to show more support for
the show kick over the statues and bring
it back to the farmers
[Music]