[Music]
I start it I it I got
put on my way to save the
world my way to save the world got a
brand new set words and the going bre
Che a questioning believe wor got it
done with shopping but
what I
I my way to save the
world my way to save the
world um one of the other ones that like
visually like I don't know I'm very
visual uh when it comes to cannabis like
I was always into purple and um notar
because of the high or anything it's
just I like the color purple a lot and I
like to surrounded by you know aesthetic
beauty is the cool I don't how you
pronoun the Kumon how do you pronounce
that oh koni yeah Kumon what can you
tell me about that line I mean that's a
striking picture on the site oh yeah
yeah um so I mean the one thing to bear
in mind is like um purple color you know
it's very common in cannabis I think
precisely for the reasons you're saying
you like it people just do like the
color um and it's really quite uh
typical to find populations
that of one land raced where like you
know half of the population or whatever
is purple half is green so kamani is
defin and the same as with high and TI
so like kamani definitely like I don't
know actually what percentage it would
be but I mean I'm sure it's controlled
by some Ali or whatever yeah but of any
field of typical commanding uh field
there'll be like you know a percentage
of them will be per
plants uh sometimes that's temperature
related um and the kamani okay so that's
a very different type of plant from the
Highland High so kamani is like a a
kamani is a multi-purpose
Himalayan land race that's for fiber and
for culinary seed
and uh hand rubbed for hash you know
yeah it's not not intended for producing
s
there's no culture of that at all in in
the in the Himalayas in that area of the
Himalayas so
um uh it's going to again break down to
type one type two type three chemot
types I would expect if you actually
looked at the fields and so some plants
um will be useless for smoking as as bad
and then others you could begin a
breeding project with to bring them up
to being like strong type one if you
actually wanted to yeah um and uh I
think generally the males are what's
primarily used for for fiber
production um like they'll these days
like most people don't actually in the
village do the work of like reting the
hemp and like turning it into yeah um
cordage or whatever but it used to be
like 100 plus years ago that um most
people in the Himalayas would wear
clothes made out of hemp they'd make
shoes using hemp they'd tether all their
livestock using hemp um cordage so it
was a really crucial plant for them at
that point but again one of these sort
of status social status
considerations that comes into play
around cannabis is that having clothes
that were made from Himalayan hemp was a
marker of not being like a high class
person in the Himalayas you know oh
interesting yeah yeah so typical you
know kind of situation where you have
the original community of the Himalayas
that were doing all we using hemp as
their primary textile plant then you had
waves of immigration coming up from the
planes of kind of
Hindu um
Hindu brahin and stuff
and um then you have this kind of class
distinction that gets made between
people who wear cotton clothes and
people who wear H clothes and so even in
come on today like um you know there's a
if you look in the old 19th century
stuff there was a specific kind of
kown curse or or you know like sort of a
swearing type phrase that basically said
you know like I hope your I hope hemp
Grows All Around your house basically
you
know it's sort of like basically you
know it was it was a marker of being a
of a of a lower status group so that or
C would be the people who were
associated with growing him can still do
primarily do that people would call him
like Bahari or or whatever it would be
the mountain um local people who mostly
grow it and I've seen friends of mine up
there who are from the more kind of
landowner aristocratic type communities
who i' sometimes would like um have like
bags of seeds I collected whilst I was
staying at their gas houses and stuff
and would just kind of you know be
chucking them around the place on the
off chance they' germinate and they'd
always like make a point of like killing
any of of the seedlings because they
just it wasn't even a legal thing it's
just like they're too Posh to have this
grow around yeah it's like really you
know it's it's a nightmare but um uh and
yeah so comman is like that type of
plant essentially
uh I I don't know to what extent there
might be spiritual or kind of
sacramental use associ iated with it but
definitely if you go into some of the
Shiva temples you will see like people
in cound who will offer you know flowers
of cannabis to to Shiva and stuff along
with theur and these kind of things so
it's definitely a a thing about how old
it is I don't know you know a lot of
these areas would have been Buddhist if
you went way back you know before they
were Hindu and and some of them would
have been kind of animist like kind of
worshiping Sun God and stuff like
possibly kind of iranic syian type
connections oh yeah yeah yeah if you go
into the temples in kamam like uh you
can see the sun Gods often have like
these uh caral length kind of uh riding
boots you know yeah which you don't see
on any other kind of deities in uh in in
the Hindu Pantheon but the solar Gods
who definitely have a connection to
iranic kind of Central Asian cultures
uh uh have these uh riding boots you
know which could be a connection to cyan
culture yeah that's fascinating I love I
love uh learning about that specific
culture like Syrian saman all that yeah
cyan cyan sort of um cyan like uh
um uh you know it's the one ancient
culture where there's a very definite
undeniable h
cannabis connection you know like
obviously with Herodotus and and the
finds in the Pam and stuff of these and
the Alti which are all unequivocally
cyan like archaeology in the in the
burials and stuff uh the materials and
[Music]
um uh that's sort of 500 BC is and there
was a you know so it's these are a kind
of culture zone of deian really like
went all the way from the frontiers of
China all the way to the frontiers of
Europe um so you know you got the find
the the the the documentation from
Herodotus north of the Black Sea in
what's sort of Ukraine and Southern
Russia saying yeah these people are
fumigating with cannabis that's kind of
450 BC then you've got the very very
closely dated sort of 400 BC is 450 Bish
finds in paser and the AL as cidian
where they actually have the tripod type
kit exactly as described by Herodotus
even though it's like thousands of
kilometers east but it's again syan
syian territory then you've got um
that's in paser in the alai and then
just south from there a few thousand
kilometers you've got um the findes in
the Eastern pamier just near shinjang of
the
fumigation uh devices which again
definitely
cian uh based on the material in the
burials which have cannabis all over
them and then possibly you've got stavol
as well in which is Southern Russia just
north of Caucasus which again is syian
where you've got like cannabis and opium
on these uh drinking vessels is probably
what they are again 400 500 BC so you've
got four kind of fines which you can say
yeah these are definitely cyan and
they're spread right across the syian
culture Zone in the Iron Age and then
during that period to get it back to cam
during that period you had the expansion
of the aid Empire which was essentially
a syian project even though we call it
Persian yeah the expansion of the
accumulate Empire right up into the
Indus region of India and probably
across there and they installed all
these satraps like local govern
Governors who were cians and during that
same period talking 500 BC you have this
um fines of uh reting Lakes suddenly
becoming very active up in the in the
uh Gangi Source River Rivers up in Cal
and GW type area it's gell but it's the
same bit of the Himalayas you suddenly
have this massive increase in using of
these Lakes to rot uh cannabis to make
cordage or textiles
using uh cannabis fibers
so is it connected to the akid conquest
who [ __ ] knows but it seems highly
plausible and certainly Indian botanists
are inclined to think that it was cians
who or at least very at very least cians
were involved in the rise of cannabis to
become a widely cultivated crop in in in
the Himalayas because it it certainly
correlates in terms of the dates when
you start seeing it appearing you know
in similarly in napole it's the same
kind of period when you find
these uh indications of people moving
seeds around into the kig gandaki sort
of area which is the one of the main
routes you would take to go from Central
Asia through Tibet down into Nepal you
suddenly find these uh fires with clear
sort of what look like people eating
seeds and stuff yeah around 400 BC is so
um yeah maybe the cool thing is all this
is sort of speculation but there's going
to be a whole bunch of genomics work
coming out next year that
should be sufficiently granular to start
seeing how these populations fit
together you know was
it was was is are there independent
centers of domestication where you know
was was Cannabis domesticated in the
Himalayas independently or was it
introduced as I suspect yeah you know
was
it so anyway um but yeah there's
definitely like a PL plausible Central
Asian I mean the Himalayas in a cannabis
perspective is Central Asia but yeah um
it's plausibly kind of uh quite closely
tied to uh
Northern uh more Northern groups by
iranic kind of groups like The cians
that's
fascinating yeah um one one thing I I I
definitely want to ask you about is some
of the Greek accessions you have oh yeah
yeah I'm not familiar with Greek
cannabis at all um I do have some in the
freezer but I haven't I haven't ran any
um what can you tell me about some of
those um
so grece is another one it's funny kind
of like because it it links into what
we've been talking about with the cians
in the sense that I was thinking um yeah
they they documented the Herodotus
documented all that um s cannabis
culture way way back but in terms of
what you have with u land races that you
can find in Greece these days or or
could find um they're a much more recent
phenomenon I suspect although again this
is one of these things that you actually
need genomics to really establish what
their ultimate origin is but certainly
the historical evidence from the 19th
century is that there was a big
introduction of seeds to Greece by uh
these kind of smuggling networks that
operated out of Lebanon and Egypt and
places and turkey and so on who um when
um
let's like uh anyway there were seeds
were brought in to give to Farmers who
were taught how to grow and you know dry
C hash and stuff in order to supply the
market in Egypt because there was a huge
huge demand from Egypt like the big
centers of demand for for um uh for for
cannabis drugs were um northern India
and Egypt in terms of globally you know
these were the huge because these huge
cities like Alexandria and Cairo and
sure you know there was massive Urban
centers where there was this big demand
for for hash and things and um so there
was a ban imposed on Egypt in in Egypt
which meant that the production shifted
to Greece and they would just ship it
across from Greece to drop it on the
coast in in what's now places like Libya
and then just bring it in and um so the
types of plants were basically the types
of plants that the were being cultivated
in Lebanon and and places and Egypt and
so on so that you know they would just
bring the seed all the evidence suggests
that seeds were brought from places like
that to Egypt and certainly the plants
are very closely related they're like
kind of like
uh you know uh they're semi dwarf mostly
like uh you know so they sort of stay
under two meters yeah somewhere between
like sometimes you know some individuals
can be like less than a meter even if
you give them
space but uh you know not not more than
two meters would be normal and
um they're definitely the same broad
group as what you'd find in Egypt
Lebanon Syria turkey Morocco the thing
to bear in mind is that like
um the sea was the main way to move
stuff around you know so these things
did move around by land but as with um
thinking about tropical saas you know
the Bay of Bengal was this huge sort of
point of which all these genetics were
swirling around you know people were
importing uh cannabis from somatra to to
India in the 17th century and similarly
people were moving hash around this the
the Eastern Mediterranean a lot and
consequently people who were involved in
making money out of it were sometimes
moving the seeds around you know yeah so
was definitely this very very clear
there was an intentional introduction of
you know um levantine or whatever land
races to uh gree by these smuggling
networks and um they're kind of like
indicas basically in the sense that we
would think of an Inda but they tend to
be more narrow leafleted and effect wise
they're more
um they don't have such a strong
sedative tendency and so some officios
call them like compact sativas because
the leaflets tend to be on the narrow
side yeah um and the effect tends to be
more sort of typically tends to be more
euphoric but all that's that said you
know you can get very kind of funky
indic smells out of things like moloo
and stuff which is one of the ones we've
got um and the other big thing to bear
in mind with Greek Land races is that
they've had at least like probably
getting on for a century now of um being
used as bird rather than hash because
once the prohibition came in in the 19
late 1930s in
Greece uh really got enforced quite
heavily people had an incentive to use
the plants as Bud rather than hash so
once you've got that culture of using
the plants as bud you have a much
stronger selective pressure for potency
because you keep the seeds from the good
stuff yep so in general they're more
potent compared to Afghan land races so
you know they're good they're good for
that reason for Western Growers who are
wanting to grow since and then plus they
have another Advantage which is their
very early finishing so they finish much
earlier than Afghan stuff so real Afghan
real Afghan real Hindu Kush plants are
not as early as people tend to assume
like the reason we have all these
early uh Afghans is because people have
selected it for it actually if you you
grow a field of real Afghan land races
and a field of real Greek or Syrian or
lebanes whatever land races side by side
in you know 40 degrees north whatever
the Greek stuff will be finished by late
August early September whereas the
Afghans can be going right into late
October you know yeah so so
um they're good for that as well the
Greek plants and they're really
interesting like there's some indication
that they may have more complicated
Heritage than I've implied you know they
some of them could have been coming
through the Balkans from turkey and
places to Greece it's quite possible
that there's a much earlier lineage than
the um the hash
era you know when I talked about the
bringing seeds that was 1860s 1880s kind
of era whereas there's been Turkish um
um uh influence cannabis wise in Eastern
Europe you know going way back to the
15th century at least you know yeah
because there big kind of um association
between radical kind of Sufi dervish
type culture in cannabis that that that
goes way back to the ottoman era um you
know and the
Turkish conquest of of Istanbul
Constantinople whatever and yeah that um
beachi and the military units of the
Ottoman Empire were very very strongly
associated with cannabis and they were
feature in places like Albania going way
back you know so I'm pretty sure there
would have been cannabis grown back in
in Eastern Europe like Balkans bits of
Eastern Europe way back but we just
don't know much about it and again it's
one of those things that the G genomics
can piece together but if you look at
camata red is one of these Greek Str Nam
have yeah so I I don't know
about that one is I don't know about
how pristine that is necessarily but on
the sort of phos Galaxy they didn't have
anything else on their data base that is
very closely connected to it and um that
doesn't mean much necessarily because
it's not a comprehensive sure C of the
Cannabis genome but uh it's a yeah it's
another curious one I suspect it's more
modern creation but we've got moloo
we've got one from creit we've got an
one from the um Arcadian which is really
from the real kind of like m is from
really from the real kind of historic
hash producing areas of the 19th century
um yeah I recommend people check them
out you know like
um
they're much more suited to what most
people people are growing
for yeah yeah they sound fascinating um
yeah and of course like you know we've
talked a lot about the the land race and
and heirloom type varieties but um you
also have stuff like uh some of the
Dutch stuff that like the the 90s Master
Kush the Afghan was that a positronics
one or a different one or
oh like I made this decision way back to
put that extra a in there it's just it's
spelled in Dutch and that's how it was
written on the packet and um it was
designed to like emphasize that the
Afghan 90 was just designed to
emphasized that it's like a Dutch Afghan
you know rather than um but uh yeah so
it's a whole bunch of material that like
we we got like in the
um on like a trip sort of to the to
Amsterdam in like late 80s early 90s
like some of the people who I worked
with were over there in that era I I
don't think it's positronics like we
just don't know the thing to bear in
mind is like in that time in the in
Holland you could just go and just buy
like clones of the of someone on the
street you know yeah like literally the
people stand around at like festivals
like I've got video of it on one the
other site of like people just selling
skunk cuttings like Street and you could
just go into the coffee shops and like a
lot of the coffee shops back then were
just like a [ __ ] Caravan or something
like someone just parked up like a
trailer and just opened a coffee shop
and people were just sign up there who
were like working um on you know for
some of the seed companies or had their
own projects going and just selling
these under like
under I I genuinely like we nobody can
remember what the brand was that this
was sold as but it was like a very kind
of low low
budget um freelance selling guys you
know selling this stuff just in his like
homemade packs you know but they were
all what was going around in like' 8990
so it's like Master Kush skunk special
um we've got like a skunk ha all all
that stuff from that era like that you
would see on the menus in in the like
late 80s early 90s you know Durban yeah
Durban skunk skun you saw that yeah
we've got like other stuff there was
like a there was just like I know from
having been there from as like as like
92 93 I guess would be my first I'd have
been like 15 or something first time I
went there and uh 145 I can't remember
and and uh and there was like all the
things you would see on the menu back
then you know and some of them have been
like rebranded we tend to call them like
cushies and stuff now but you'd even see
like chatr chraa CH not CH but
like yeah would be one of the ones you'd
see yeah so yeah so you remember as well
yeah and it's like there's just a
certain staple of stuff and we've got
like a pretty good representation of all
of those it's just a question of like
how many of them we can get to germinate
now out of the packs you know so some of
them we'd have to had to do as feminized
just because we just didn't get males
and stuff you know but
still you got feminized now right like
you've been working a lot more femin
stuff uh I just made a category for it
because I was getting tired of people
writing to me asking like have we got
feminized seeds or do we do feminized
seeds yeah and um so I just made it like
specific category for it but some of it
is just because some of them like the PE
with freak Show and things made just
because people want them feminized and
like the Dutch stuff though we've had to
feminize them sometimes because we just
didn't get any males you know you get
like yeah yeah a handful of these to put
and uh it's like
what I think in future we'll make some
regular ones based on whatever we can
find that's as close as we can get
to the
uh like so for the Durban we we did
cross it with the the Nirvana Durban gun
because it just seemed that of all of
the ones available is actually truest to
the original
um uh stuff that was in Holland back
then you know yeah um but uh yeah you
know it's going to be interesting like
again I'm going to try and get like
genomics proper hardcore genomics work
done on all of those as well because it
could be quite a useful reference um
absolutely P um you know I mean the
original Dutch stuff we've got from the
90s because could be quite handy for
like mapping everything out if they
are it's super important to be like for
for any genomics database to have that
stuff because it's it is the backbone
ENT out yeah yeah yeah yeah like it
would be good to actually really get
that spelled out as clearly as possible
for some of the younger folks involved
because I just think so many people
don't so many people come into growing
with this sense that like all these
names correspond to some Botanical
reality when actually probably probably
there's about like 10 names that
actually have any meaningful
basis yeah especially as as the Spanish
got involved too with the uh white
labeling and that that yeah that changed
everything yeah and the thing the thing
is I mean I think the Spanish stuff is
good because it is just good to have
like as much diversity of different
people doing stuff yep but I get a
little frustrated with the fact that so
much of the ostensible land race stuff
that's going around in Spain is just
stuff that's been hit with like Northern
Lights or skunk
whatever um I get that you know it's
like some people justify that in terms
of meeting their customers halfway it's
like come on my customers aren't like
nerds you know just tell them it's but
it's like yeah kind of but also you know
there's an ecological issue going on
here which is like actually cannabis is
like no exception in terms of the
massive loss of biodiversity that's yep
probably going on and and certainly no
it is going on in terms of what's
cultivated and
um uh you
know I think you've got to actually take
a bit of responsibility with educating
your customer base absolutely in terms
like they you can't expect them to to
spend hours digging through the
literature like just tell them straight
up this is actually something we've
crossed out across Northern Lights and
whatever um that distinctions important
especially if it dominates it you know
yeah well I mean thing is a lot of it a
lot of it though like I've actually kind
of actually had discussions with it with
some of the Spanish guys and they've
been like yeah yeah but we've taken it
through like five generations since and
it's all like leans really heavily
towards the original land race like yeah
okay yeah that's great but still just
put it in the description yeah like how
hard is
that they they they used to but then
like there's a point where suddenly like
the land race became this really big
thing and they just like [ __ ] cut it
all out it's like guys come
on is there anything you wanted to
highlight specifically that you've been
working on lately or any of the the
stuff that you've put up recently or
anything yeah anything at all that you
want to highlight um I mean the one of
the really exciting things is that there
will be some papers coming out studies
coming out over the next sort of half a
year to a year of like really seriously
high quality genomics work
I I I sent in all of the material I've
got uh to these projects and they will
be producing like what should be the
first really good quality like Pang
genome for cannabis like the whole
species essentially that would be
amazing and um on the basis of that
we'll have some like
publicly
um uh it'll all be publicly available
data and and also some breeding tools
based on that that you can basically
send in you you can you can use to
really know like you can really start
establishing genuine
pedigrees and um this is ideally ideally
you know what will be achieved and then
ultimate strain nerd [ __ ] yeah yeah
essentially yeah so for just people who
have just a end as an end in itself The
Strain nerd stuff but also actually for
the serious breeding work you can use
these things well so you can really know
what you've got and really start like uh
catching up on like the seven eight last
decades that cannabis has had in in some
respects compared to other crops so um
yeah um there'll be some really good
uh uh tools available to let people you
know basically even even if you're you
know you can have like kind of the
equivalent this again ideally like
equivalent level of quality of
information about what you've got that
like [ __ ] Monsanto has even if you're
just like a a small business you know
you can you can access access this stuff
so it's hope going to like level the
playing field for for people who are
involved in in uh in uh in cannabis
breeding you know which is which is be
nice given how money has made the
playing Feld very not [ __ ] level um
already but um I would definitely say
that that your company caters to
breeders which is uh I wish more
companies would like that's that's
something that should be coveted you
know to to have actual breeders wanting
your stuff should you know I think that
lends a lot of credibility I I mean
ideally that would be what it is the
there is there are so many barriers
still um which
are which are which are in in the way in
terms of to have the you know even for
like projects which have got like big
money involved it's classic kind of
story is that a lot of germplasm I'm
talking other crops now as well has just
vanished over the years because there's
just sheer economics of actually
utilizing this material is really
[ __ ] challenging it's like if you've
got uh however many acres of land
available to you to be growing on how
much of that are you going to set aside
to actually like work a land race
absolutely you know and not just
outcross and stuff yep um so you know uh
there are shortcuts now you can take
like this kind of pre-breeding you know
where you where you try and kind of move
the useful ales from one land race into
like an established cultiva or from a
feral population into an established
cultiv like you try and basically take
some handy traits like drought
resistance or disease resistance like
powdery mil resistance or like whatever
smell or whatever you're looking to like
Aroma you're looking for whatever you
can shortcut you know from the land race
to the cultivar so that's that kind of
thing but it's very seldom you get
anyone actually kind of just like in
breeding with
one line to create an heirloom it's why
we've got so few kind of actual genuine
heirlooms now I mean as far as I know
x18 and deep chunk as far as We Know
um genuinely kind of inbred from one
land
race again just going to take genomics
to actually establish that but the
general consensus is I've never heard
anyone like contesting that idea but
there aren't many like pure genuine pure
sativas around you know even Hayes is is
a
hybrid sativas and then um most of the
sort of ostensible like Jamaican or
African things going around like in
Spain they've all been hit with
something I don't think many people
argue with that I mean you were asking
about the unan uh line yeah yeah I mean
that's a skunk um cross to something
from kind of Border Borderlands of yunan
it's not a land race yeah it's uh and
and um there's no uh to the best of my
knowledge there's no historic kind of
culture of growing cannabis as a drug in
that bit of southern China once you move
across the border into the kind of Thai
like tii Shan Tha Lao Thai areas sure
you get
a there's a kind of gja culture but in
you unan itself has no culture with
these things so you know a lot of What's
um passed around is is anyway just
hybridized stuff I think the most of the
notionally
Burmese uh lines in North America are
hybridized things they don't the B
doesn't look anything like the plants
we've got from Direct from Burma yeah
yeah there's a lot of the Canadian uh
Burmese stuff that I've seen that looks
just mostly Afghan yeah yeah I mean
Broad Leaf yeah and there's no there's
no there's no um you don't just you just
don't get plants in places plants like
that are just do
not naturally occur in the
tropics right not in a monsoon
area just any tropical area it's like
there's so many reasons why it's not
advantageous to have broad leaflets just
get [ __ ] up by the rain yeah pathogens
and Broad leaflets are so much easier
for insects to to to to work on oh yeah
yeah there's all kinds of reasons
why you don't get that in the tropical
population
um yeah so so yeah anyway that's the
most interesting thing I think is like
hopefully next year is going to be
really quite an exciting year in terms
of the science of cannabis um and uh
making life much more um easy for people
who are doing reading projects I'm
excited about it I can't wait to see
what you do with it yeah yeah well I
mean it's not it's it's just it's not me
doing the actual work it's I've just
submitted a whole bunch of uh well okay
I've done the work in terms of
collecting these things but I've just
donated a bunch of material to some
projects and um see what they actually
do in terms of making sense of it all
but as far as I understand they've got
like really really super high quality
like long sequences yeah that's
important phos didn't do that they did
the short SE yeah no this is like Mega
long like ultra high
quality and uh you know because the
problem with the genomics work to date I
mean aside from some sort of ethical
issues and stuff is that the reference
genomes that people have been using as
[ __ ] and and there all kinds of
different read depths and all kinds of
in congruities between the data sets
that just mean that you if you i' I know
two groups one mathematician and then
another more kind of cannabis Centric
group who've done work on the existing
data and just got these completely
like back to front [ __ ] results you
know it's like if you if this this Mass
guy is like I'm just going through all
this
Stu and um and he's like uh all the data
is saying that like the modern hybrids
are like more diverse than the land
races and it's like
yeah I don't it's you know it made the
meded retion is like well that's [ __ ]
what [ __ ] you know it's like no it's
just this [ __ ] data of [ __ ] mess
you know yeah and um and uh because
you're looking like if you comparable
kind of crops just a general point of
comparison like if you look at other
kind of land
race comparisons to Modern material
you're looking like at least like five
times more diversity in the land races
you know yeah and I would expect with
cannabis once you factor in like really
weedy populations it's way more [ __ ]
diversity in them compared to the modern
stuff but again the so much dodgy work
or just you know limited quality work
that's been done on on on up to done to
date so hopefully next year will be like
uh quite a big uh Leap Forward in terms
of making sense of all this stuff you
know I truly hope so there's a lot of us
that could use
that yeah there just like and there's so
much so much to be clarified you know
like just chatting with these groups as
they're going these people as they're
going through all the research it's
like um I think one of the first things
of my they looked at was like uh that
sudanes ession and they basically were
just like uh we're going to like
basically have to rewrite our entire
genome I don't think I don't know if it
was I think it was that one it was just
like yeah it's like the first one they
looked at and they're like yeah Cas is
like who we just got like completely off
the charts here and then they looked at
just even just the Milano and Parvati
accessions and that's not even really
like a pure land race and they're like
yeah we're finding whole new like sex
markers I think it is for sex expression
hav't even found before and then like
crazy examples of like monoi in in in uh
the southeast Asians and in the Afghan
and in one of the Greek ones they was
finding this
like um XY mono like normally you find
it on the anyway like males that were
like genetically male showing mono and
stuff which is like again super
interesting in terms of future breeding
possibilities and stuff because
monoicous stuff is a lot easier for many
reasons to breed with and work with and
stuff anyway there's all kinds of
possibilities and it's like so much uh
catching up to be
done uh with such an important crop
that's just been held back
massively um and uh yeah it should be
really
interesting yeah that sounds
fascinating yeah so I have I have a few
questions I want to go through just from
our our Discord that people wanted to
ask I try to go for the best ones
because there's quite a few um let's
see yeah so most of these uh questions
we've actually covered as a course of
just conversing um yeah there's one I
mean like almost all of them we covered
just by conversing but one one that I
think will be probably the most asked
question you probably when you get a lot
is from uh CCC and he asked how to keep
pure well pure relatively pure uh
sativas manageable indoors do you have
any advice on
that
um I mean one of the main
um tricks people do that I'm aware of is
um uh you can use pot size to just
control and and and and like because if
it's really like a pure straight from a
farmer type sativa it's it's they're
going to keep rooting even during
flowering you know yeah so
um you can just pot up in the kind of
second week of flour or so still and you
should find that the it will still root
into the new compost which can be good
as well because it can mean that you
don't make the mistake of like
overfeeding too much during flour
absolutely um and the other thing
uh with sativa endorses to try to not
overwater them like it's a really
important aspect of of traditional
farming of of gja you know s or whatever
is the right irrigation schedule
so even these days um the good quality
uh production in places like LA and
stuff is in areas where they've got
access to lakes or ponds or streams to
irrigate
on schedule rather than just allowing
rain fed um you
know yeah so in other words the the main
good quality crop is done from sort of
sewing in mid augusti is and then
harvesting kind of Fe February is so you
um uh September is or whatever to
February marchish basically six months
over the starting at the end of monsoon
so you can have a bit of rain whilst the
plants are in veg but really once you're
into flow you're looking to like have
zero rain ideally and just have
irrigation and the mistake people make
IND doors is to over water we've already
kind of touched on that but um the other
thing is you can if there're are real
land race you can prune back pretty
[ __ ] heavily if you want and you can
you can you
can um concentrate the uh Bud production
into the exactly where you want if you
prune carefully and you can prune like
quite late on in the cycle of growth
still yeah um
uh yeah I can't think of other things to
be honest with you I'm not like an
expert grower I just know from talking
to people and and stuff yeah for sure I
I don't have like a huge amount of
opportunities to grow because of the
amount of moving around I do you know
yeah yeah you can imagine that makes it
hard
I
um anyway I yeah it's uh but yes sativas
they're not well adapted to in indoors
basically as the bottom bottom line
really want to be outside and they will
um you know the the the type of land
they want to be on is is a really
important consideration so in the big
Gand growing areas of India um in the
late 19th 30 20th century there was
quite a good documentation done of that
whole economy because it was
economically very significant um and um
the land along the rivers along the
ganes Delta area that was very lomy like
light Sandy loomes yeah that don't hold
water too much but are very nutrient
Rich were really sought after by people
who wanted to to to get into commercial
production you know yeah and um there
were techniques which are still used of
of how you prepare the land so you know
still they'll do this still in in
Southeast Asia as you um create um uh
ridges you know like raised raised beds
like a kind of semi um Circle type shape
with between them for the water and then
you plant on top of those um half
circles as it were you know what I mean
so yeah Cur curved raised bed and so
that means that you the water runs off
the roots so the thing you're just
trying to avoid is for the to have the
root sitting in water logged um water
logged uh land because that yeah
cannabis just does not [ __ ] like that
and it will get it'll get infected and
there are all kinds of parasites and
pathogens that were already very well
known back in the in that time which are
even Cann ofis specific forms of powdery
milu and stuff you know
um and um you know these conversations
sometimes with people who are like using
these um what is it
natural um sort of what is it some kind
of like people basically growing in this
like composting compost it's not even
properly comp Korean natural farming
stuff yeah yeah yeah I get these kind of
emails from people sometimes and it's
like try and like be as nice as I can
yeah yeah it's tough like on principle
I'm like all for kind of permac culture
and anything like that it's like but
Jesus man like cannabis does not want to
be in that kind of [ __ ] situation
this guy writing to me like yeah I've
created this amazing system where like
the soil is wet
247 like RAC love that right no cannabis
wants to be like they okay with
Hydroponics and stuff maybe they've I
mean I think in over the last 50 60
years like cannabis in the west has
adapted to all kinds of Mal treatment
but sure absolutely has
ultimately yeah you don't want to be
growing a land race in like
soggy incredibly Rich
compost especially like especially not
with like stuff like literally rotting
on the
surface yeah this guys like can you send
me like a photo and he says your thing
there like [ __ ] cooch grass like
growing in in the same
pot yeah I mean each their own I guess
but yeah God bless them if someone's ask
opinion I feel I should just tell them
like no yeah just don't grow this
type take
abuse
yeah um is there any strange you want to
highlight that you current have for sale
right now or any anything else you want
to talk about and get
in I mean I'm really interested like uh
you can um I we collected a bunch of
stuff from orisa which is sort of just
south of of Bengal okay which I suspect
is
um uh quite um historically significant
um in terms of the development of um of
sativas like real tropical C land races
uh you know we were talking about
there's that um book the kind of
alchemic it's an alchemical book
actually the an and theander is the name
of it um where they describe the cinia
technique that's from around their kind
of andr PES uh barisa area was where
that was probably
compiled and um I suspect those plants
are pretty
interesting uh to look at uh they seem
to be like probably more like five
months from seed to harvest uh the ones
we' got and um also
um yeah and and then um planning to have
some napoi um uh ganja land races
available soon as well which I think
will be pretty interesting I mean just
in terms of product stuff like I'm a big
fan of the southeast Asians but the
because of the Aromas and stuff and I
think there's been a lot of hybridity
between
possibly like independent centers of
domestication south of unan with the the
east
Indian uh sens of domestication I don't
know this is just a hunch but um anyway
I think these uh actual South Asian land
races like from Arisa and Andra Pradesh
and um the terai regions of nepool are
worth checking out so we've got already
uh some like da and KH as the name of
the one from neple that we've got that's
kind
of uh you could say like been
domesticated it definitely has been
domesticated for use as bud not just as
hash yeah and then the orisa one is very
much specifically for bud and um both of
them I think would be really interesting
to look at uh really nice Aromas from
them too as well you know yeah and types
of effect are really good like very
stimulating and
positive um it sounds freaking awesome
to be honest yeah yeah I'm quite Kean to
see what the genomics work discovers
about them because my hunch is they're
probably the uh East India Nepal and
East India are kind of where saas really
originate first we'll see yeah that's so
fascinating I can't wait to see that all
work out um where where should people go
to buy your seeds uh what's the website
uh the real seed company.com and then
for the for the modern stuff is quick
seeds.com it's a stupid name but it's
like what I
originally yeah I'd originally planned
it as like a budget thing I was just
gonna buy a bunch of like Cheapo Dutch
seeds and sell it on there and [ __ ] it
I'm just don't want to get into like big
business stuff and so it's kind of just
but um yeah that's where we for the time
being anyway all the all the kind of
really interesting 90s material we've
got and some other um there's like some
later 90s things like Cinderella 99
Amnesia uh which is really good very
strong as well if you're looking for
like strong uh really strong stuff and
then some Colombian
um
um uh like a Colombian import that's
probably like a Northern Lights crossed
with a Colombian land race then crossed
with some like
um um Al Colombian and Mexican things
all kinds of things like that you can
find there and a whole bunch of just
like kind of fun hybrids with things
like uh Pakistan TR tral Kush cross with
like some land races which would be
great like for just making hash and
stuff and or for
Bud yeah and and very uh nice prices for
most of it yeah um yeah just yeah fun
stuff to play with if you've got the
space
any any way uh you'd prefer to be
contacted too if people want to reach
out to you yeah sure I generally um if
you want a quick response like uh the um
Gmail real Seed Co at gmail is best uh
you can contact me on Instagram as well
but I'm sometimes I'm not on there like
I I may not get back to you as quickly
and I sometimes miss the um miss the uh
incoming messages you know yeah like
forget to check the request bit
sometimes so yeah
always to to use this use the site
contact form or just email me directly
and and that I should get back to you
within like two three days max you know
awesome well I gotta say I'd love to
have you back sometime when time allows
you it's been an absolute
pleasure yeah I and and and um I've
really enjoyed it and it's very kind of
you to give me the space to just ramble
but I I'm slightly [ __ ] burned out
and a bit like sleep deprived always
seem to be when I do these podcasts but
um maybe when I'm back in theuk we do
another one at a more civilized well
it's kind of a civilized hour now but
I'm just not a civilized person so I've
not been getting out of bed before like
anyway but uh yeah so anyway it's been
it's been good though yeah thanks man
I've enjoyed it I I appreciate your time
my friend and um I'll talk to you soon
this is GNA air Friday and uh yeah
people going to be stoked people are
really going to dig it I'll probably cut
it into two or three parts
yeah yeah nice one yeah yeah yeah great
cool I'll keep you posted on it and
again thank you for your time and um
yeah it's an honor I really appreciate
it thank you yeah all right brother I'll
talk to you soon yeah cool so that's um
that's that is it like uh the r yeah and
send me the um everything over like and
I'll as soon as you've got it all going
oh absolutely yeah and and it'll premere
live and there'll be people chat there's
usually over aund something people
that'll watch it live gets a few
thousand views in the first two days
yeah yeah nice okay yeah just uh and and
so it will go on YouTube and everything
yeah yep yeah okay yeah yes I'll put it
on the site as well and that would be
great I appreciate that nice one all
right my friend thank you so much and
thank you like seriously thank you for
your time I know it's hard to no no it's
pleasure I can I like I can talk at
length about this whenever so it's yeah
it's always I appreciate it nice one man
well have a have a lovely evening and
and I hope it's more been over the last
few
weeks that sounds fin a Smooth Spot yeah
well enjoy enjoy all right I'll talk to
you soon yeah nice one cheers bye
bye want more Syndicate check out our
patreon in the description below thank
you for joining us on this journey we
are forever thankful that enough people
watch us to keep us going with that in
mind you can show your support for the
show by liking subscribing and sharing
the show we don't advertise so we need
you also hit Riot seeds.com and
syndicate.com to show more support for
the show kick over the statues and bring
it back to the farmers
[Music]