ready go
so
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
[Applause]
[Music]
hey what's going on
so in like 0.405
i was on cannabis world
um
and i got the green bubba the purple
bubba both from ken oregon kid and then
i had a shaw bud
who is 707 seed bank
his bubba kush cut they were all called
bubba
um
ken called the purple fino which was uh
supposedly an s1
uh
that some club owner in the in the
valley made um
it was really heavy yielding made like
club type nuggets with the rounded top
um the katsu uh
cut um
i as far as i know and i can't remember
specifically but i'm pretty sure that
was the cut that he sold to katsu right
and that was the green fino and then
shaw bud aka 707 seed bank
um his uh
his bubba cut was um
the pre-98 and so basically what
happened is i had all three cuts i need
to label them in my room so that i would
could tell the difference or you know so
i could
uh maintain mothers and know which ones
which
um and it just got the name pre-98
because shaw had
um
received the cutting in the in the
winter of 97 98 so at the time it's like
2003 i'm like well it had to have been
before 1998 because someone popped the
seeds and has a clone by now already
it's pre-98 right that's how it got the
name um and that was like 2004
and then it was like three or four years
later that swerve basically appropriated
the name for selling seeds yeah
so that's pretty much all there is to it
it wasn't anything special it wasn't
there wasn't anything crazy about it
what was the difference between shaw's
and like the katsu
they all pretty much smell the same the
purple was like a little bit more purple
smelling but still the bubba with the
incense and the like um
the smell in the air the same meaty
smell
um the katsu they they would all turn
purple depending on how you grew them
right so they're all phenotypically
variable based on environment um
it was the green pheno was the the katsu
which um
it just tended to be green more often
but if you over further it didn't veg it
very big whatever it put out little tiny
buds it turned purple at the end of
flower with cold temperatures no
not a major difference the pre-98 tended
to be a little chunkier more often but
still the same characteristics as the
other two cuts it would still um
uh
uh like basically what i call like big
stem small bud yeah
right where you've given it too much cal
mag or
it doesn't have a big enough root system
for the size of pot it's in whatever
right
um if you vet it look just like most
bubbas if you vet them out really big
they'll start actually producing pretty
good
that's [ __ ] awesome dude that was a
lot of [ __ ] i didn't even know about
bubba i'm glad you said that um people
were asking about the face-off story uh
that would be [ __ ] awesome to hear
like straight from the mouth
so the real og cushman the source
genetics chris
chris used to live up here in seattle in
2000 and um
i think he lives up here from like 02 to
06.
i met him in like 04 um
and he was growing the poison og at the
time which was his bad seed fino
um from bags that he had purchased in
socal the face-off was and i think he
had 12 seeds of face-off bag seeds the
face-off was never actually a clone that
was being grown it was just a moniker
given to
a certain batch of og that went through
the inland empire back in like 99 or
something like that
um i got six of the seeds i think four
or five of them popped if i remember
right the face off number four is the
cutting that i have right um i popped it
from c um
so
that's the only real face off really i i
mean i think there's like four or five
more seeds out there chris gave some to
cult classic seeds but i don't think he
ever popped them and i'd be surprised if
they even popped now being 20 years old
no and uh
i think chris might have a couple more
seeds of it but that's about it that's
pretty awesome so like though i i
thought the seeds it was the number four
fino the number one two and three the
number one was like uh
it like the leaves turned purple it had
more of like a in between bubba and
face-off kind of smell yeah um
the number two was like this really
short sativa um leaf looking thing but
it didn't stretch at all it was almost
like a dwarf plant but it had really
really thin blades
um the number three produced
like much larger bigger colas was a
little bit hermey
which was one of the main reasons i
didn't keep it and it pretty much
smelled like your typical og made with
like a little bit of a gummy bear funk
oh wow and then the number four
and and that the number three and the
number one kind of had that similar like
gummy bear in between og and bubba kind
of smell the number three was more og
dom the number one was like
it wasn't really bubba dum i would say
but it was just kind of
um
i would call it blander but you know
it it wasn't anything particularly
special and then the number four
was um
the uh
it based it's that it's that face-off
smell like that really long-lasting
lingering after flavor and a real cushy
flavor
um and the main reason i kept it too was
its potency it's always potent like the
first time i was smoking it i uh rolled
up a joint was driving to town to pick
up some hydro gear
this was like 2006 and i smoked that and
started getting like light-headed in the
car and i was like all right well this
thing's pretty potent probably um and
anybody that knows me knows i smoke a
lot of herbs so
um i i typically don't even comment on
potency at all because i'm smoking 20 or
50 different strains yeah a day
you know between all the different kinds
of hashes and whatever else so
that's fascinating dude i'm sure people
appreciated hearing all that now i have
a question something i'm interested in
that i don't know a lot about other than
uh probably jason king's uh cannonball
dude um the purple indica
told me it's the one clone that i don't
know that i don't want
yeah it's um
it's super hard to work with i mean it's
um
it's a really old strain from up here in
the northwest everybody that like if
you're around in the late 80s 90s and
2000 early 2000s smoking weed up here
you bought purple weed and it smelled
like the purple indica it's like this
really um
uh
really
not it well it's not i mean it's pungent
but it's like if you could think of what
the purp what purple smells like a color
this is everything that purple smells
like
um
and hold on a second i'm going to take a
token
um
and i i got the cut in 2003 it was the
very first cut that i got basically that
um it didn't come with a name either so
i got it from my friend who
had gotten a medical card at the time
which was uh pretty hard to get
and he had gotten the cut from some
organ growers
i had no idea what it was i was growing
some 97
dutch passion blueberry seeds at the
time and i also had some
some other blueberry seeds i can't
remember what they were
um i think they're from canada one of
the canadian blueberry crops like
yeah one of those you know um
i can't think of the company names but
you know [ __ ] out of cannabis culture
not like uh vcc depot but like
federation seeds all those guys i can't
remember who it was that had like the
blueberry the blueberry nl5 all that
kind of stuff i remember
do you ever try peak seeds
i do remember peak but i think this was
before peaks
um
i think this was uh
god i can't remember the name but it'll
come to me in a second
um
but basically i was growing blueberry at
the time and when when you cut up clones
of
the purple indica
it literally smells like berries kind of
right had a very berryish smell right
from the beginning which is kind of that
purple smell too
and um
so i would i didn't know what it was
right i just um i just knew that like it
kind of looked like the blueberry [ __ ]
so i kind of like was calling it
blueberry for a second i hadn't even
flowered it yet so i didn't even know i
was just like i don't know blueberry
something or other
by the time i finished the cut i knew
that it was one of the purple strains
from up here so we had the uw perp um
seattle perps tacoma perps ultraviolet
um these were all basically
the same phenos
or not the same phenos
they were either variations of the same
variety or hybrids of the same variety
right which was basically the old purple
from up here and it was like pretty
widespread and we knew that there was
multiple different cuts because
you could um
you could basically uh
like when you bought pounds of it you
you'd get some bags that all smelled
like the purple indica or like
ultraviolet or whatever
but uh if you got the perps like from
tacoma it'd have like big 20 gram colas
in it right
and whenever you grew like or whenever
you saw like ultraviolet nuggets
they didn't ever have uh big nuggets and
it was always small little ounce bags of
[ __ ] yeah and when i grew out the
blueberry or the unknown cut yeah um
uh
basically i start i grew it a few times
and i was like there's no way that this
is the tacoma cutting i don't know if
it's the ultraviolet i don't know if
it's the uw perp i don't really know
what cut it is because i don't have
anything to reference it by
in terms of other cuts so i called it
purple indica yeah that was how it got
its name right it got so it became pi
right
um
and
basically you know
there never really was a purple indica
up here as far as i know
it was just the perps
so
um and it's just a really really tight
it's not tiny it's not like a dwarf or
anything but it's a very tight internode
um afghani plant
um pretty much anybody i know that's
twice my age that's up here in
washington they immediately can identify
it as the old perp
um
from up here uh kindness cannabis he's
one of my buddies from back in the day
he remembers it really well too
um
and that's what the pi was and it's it's
lower potency um that you know 15 to 18
percent and pretty much whatever you
cross it to it reduces its potency okay
so uh [ __ ] plant though
yeah and it's just hard to work with
from from the perspective of trying to
um uh
it's trying to bring a new variety up to
modern day standards
it's you know it's
sometimes you cross stuff in and it like
like cookies for example you cross it
into stuff and it makes it really frosty
and purple which is what the market
likes yeah you cross the pi and it makes
it less frosty
dark purple
and not quite as potent but the the
funny thing is the potency is um
is so subjective yeah nowadays
that like back then the purple indica we
always called it shut up wheat because
anybody you load a bomb toke or whatever
for they'd immediately just sit there
and zone out
so even though it always tests
significantly
um lower potency than a lot of stuff
it um it definitely uh
would bring some people's bells sure
that makes sense dude
you know i've noticed a lot of these uh
lower potency strains are coming around
more now since since concentrates are
much more
in use and available it seems like
they've gotten a renewed life in them
yeah a little bit but i mean you know
lower potency means lower yields
as well right
so
um
i think a lot of people are just trying
to
get as much bang for their buck
especially from an economic perspective
oh sure
sure
so what are you working on now i think
that's what a lot of people like to know
about you what are you working on now
[ __ ] amazing [ __ ] yoshido that's
yours it's hard to top docie
i mean it's you know it's it's all
personal preference i
mean um i'm actually gonna pop all my
old seeds all everything from 10 or 15
years ago this next round right now i'm
remaking
um
all the stock right of stuff that's
already i've already gone through
um
and then uh i'm just gonna i'm gonna go
back to the drawing board i'm tired of
the [ __ ] i'm working on i can't wait to
[ __ ] see what you pull up from your
collection i can't even imagine
yeah um i mean [ __ ] gets boring you know
to me
um
and that's why people are like oh
someone else made your [ __ ] before you
could it's like dude i was working on
trying to find something new not
remaking
[ __ ] just because people are asking for
it so
it's all personal preference you know
and what your motivation is and it's all
about i mean anybody can make your [ __ ]
before you if they don't test it release
it right like yeah of course exactly if
you're not going to work it at all
i mean you can make it as fast as
someone can sell it basically yeah so
um you know docido took a while to make
in a remake because it's uh the ogkb is
like a type 4 hermes that thing hermes
every which way you can possibly get so
hybridizing into it you've got to at
least search through the population and
look for lower instances of those traits
and anybody that's not or even doesn't
even know about that obviously doesn't
even probably grow their own [ __ ]
seeds so
yeah
everybody's gonna be [ __ ] bombing you
about hurricane hear the story it's up
to you if you want to tell oh i mean
dude i so i can't make purple punch
cross with dozy though too i don't get
it
i agree
especially if it's a
half year line in the thing
right well i mean yeah exactly and it's
like well
you know if
if people are mad about the name or
whatever the the funniest [ __ ] is
they're the ones complaining about
patents on plants
but want trademark rights for naming
[ __ ]
it's you know
you can't you can't have your cake and
eat it too you got to be one or the
other because that's how patents and
trademarks work it's not
it's i mean you know i think
hypocrisy is the
the a lot of people's motives so
whatever it's fine i mean miseducation
leads to it and it's all right it's what
the world is nowadays yeah that's very
true
what else you guys got for him any other
questions that are [ __ ] you got him
sitting here don't ask [ __ ] lame ass
[ __ ]
yeah who wants to talk about purple
punch anyway exactly seriously
let's talk about some [ __ ] historical
[ __ ]
let's stop you know what yeah hp 13 uh
the most common uh misinformation about
it is that it's g13 hash plan i think
most people think that because of
[ __ ] retards and haven't looked up
anything can you tell us about the
experience with hp 13 it's not something
many people talk about
so i i got the cut i think from caleb um
i think he was the one that got it first
um but i had seen it earlier um for
example like uh in you're talking about
jason king's cannabis earlier so the can
of bible entry that was my herb
um the trinity crossed with u-dub that
was herb that i had purchased that i
showed to um
uh jason king at the 2002 seattle hemp
fest
um
the dog [ __ ] that's in there that was us
not the humble
outdoor pictures but the pictures of the
indoor that was my buddy cannabis
reverend yeah um through another
glassblower friend of ours that grew it
um
that was the dog [ __ ] entry that was in
there
um the purple indica entry that was mine
and then scott uh reach also reached out
to jason king and i think showed him
pictures of it but that cut came for me
i gave scott that back in the day
um
and uh
so
the first time i saw hp 13 was in 2004 i
went to stay with a friend of mine in
hana right and he's
he was a dude another dude that was on
cannabis world
and um
he uh he invited me to come out to this
party right now i won't tell too much
about the party even though they don't
throw it anymore but it was basically a
weed gathering party another another
couple buddies of mine that currently
live on maui and it was basically like
it was deep in the [ __ ] jungle it was
um off uh grid so there's there's no i
mean they had power because it's like a
multi-millionaire's home that was this
thing getting thrown at so they had
refrigerators and all the nines but it
was actually an off-grid home
and uh you know they had like cava leaf
blunts and [ __ ] homemade kombucha and
like homemade uh
beer and all kinds of [ __ ]
and um jason king also happened to be
there that was the first time i saw
mendo perps also
um that was like 2004 i believe
um yeah it was 2004. and uh
so
hp 13
i'd heard about it uh everybody had
talked about it i saw some jungle grown
hp 13 that was grown deep in the jungle
there and i thought it was swag it was
like but it was just poorly grown
um i thought it had a really unique
smell
but it had like no stickiness to the
resin
the smell i had to really mash it up
because it was that outdoor [ __ ] yeah
and um
but you could tell it had like a unique
smell to it
and then i eventually got the the cut
from csi humboldt
and i think that was probably around
2007 or eight was the first time i got
it
um from him
and uh
it's it was like it's a weird plant you
know it's um it's pretty leafy
um very columnar growth just like goes
straight up
didn't branch very much small yield and
definitely hermit on the bottoms
um and that's where like the p or the uh
the [ __ ] what did they call it
the the sour p which is the sour diesel
hp 13 cross
um that was all the same group of cats
that did this maui party um every year
back then
and uh
i still have some friends from those
parties that that live all over and you
know they they remember the stuff one of
the one of the most impressive examples
that i remembered was
the um
uh jasmine jack which came out of eugene
um and that was it was real hazy
smelling but at the time like uh in
seattle
uh hazy stuff was like where it was at
that's why the dog [ __ ] the malawi
northern lights haze that i made the nl
hayes f2s the pure malawi gold that we
had the super bill
um all that [ __ ] was um
was super uh that was like what was
popular like i remember when i first got
og up here from chris
nobody even gave a [ __ ] people were like
dude whatever that's just some indica
[ __ ] whatever
right they didn't even care couldn't yet
get anything more for it nobody really
even it was it was pointless
yeah i just was growing it because i
liked it right it wasn't you know like
an
030405 og wasn't really that popular or
known outside of los angeles yeah
that's so dude i i can't ever get
anybody knowledgeable to comp or comment
on hp 13 and it seems like everybody who
grows it or has run it has different
opinions on whether it's worth keeping
whether it's worth growing but uh that's
pretty fascinating dude i appreciate
that yeah the the people that i know it
came from the people that jason king saw
it from originally the people that put
it in the can of bible
those dudes were from new york it's from
new york right it is from new york then
for sure that's my understanding like i
i the the farthest back that i have any
experience with it and the people that
it came from
they had a new york connection and
that's where that cut came from wow okay
cool yeah i've always wondered because
you always see it in new york and maui
new york yeah that's why they had the
sauer d out there too right at the same
time that was all the same group of
people and um you know the scene was
really small 15 20 years ago especially
genetics scene back then because most
people all they gave a [ __ ] about was
just finding one good cut and running it
till the wheels fall off that was like
the deal
um
no one it didn't really matter what the
strain name was in those days because
everything's sold for great money oh
sure sure i've seen him [ __ ] growing
in maui growing [ __ ] plants and trees
and [ __ ]
[ __ ] gnarly out there
yeah that was how that hp 13 that i
first saw was grown and it was garbage
honestly it was pretty much garbage
i mean
i would be nice about it but it dude
ryan trying [ __ ] in the jungle is
impossible yeah exactly like i remember
i would ship out um a jar of weed like i
shipped out a jar of albert walker for
that party in 2004 and literally as soon
as i opened that jar my buddy's house
the weed got wet yeah you know it was
like cured perfectly and was like spongy
with the with the crack as soon as you
open the jar it's it turns into like
jungle weed yeah just drinking that
humidity
yeah the huma it's like 98 percent you
may are 100 humidity it's like raining
basically so
um as soon as you open the jar it just
takes it it takes it all on
[ __ ]
uh are you doing any more dog [ __ ] work
someone wants to know
um i i'm not doing any more ds work it's
just not popular enough it's longer
flowering um i'll play with it every
once in a while it's actually hard to
hybridize i saw rich in here earlier
also talking about
his dog walker
and uh
the scooby snacks [ __ ] that people like
to make a big deal out of yeah and like
every rich and i have
mutual friends
um i didn't do it as any intentional
thing i was living in l.a at the time
had no idea that there was i did i don't
even know this was 2012 so i don't even
know if rich had
made it or sold or given it to people or
whatever yeah um but literally i just
made cookies crossed with [ __ ] uh
um
cookies cross and face off and i called
it snoozy scooby snacks and honestly it
didn't even really sell very well and i
didn't expect
i had no idea until i moved back up to
seattle
um
and then started working with my buddy
in oregon
uh did i even know that there was a cut
out there called snoopy sacks so
i mean
is that what the dog walker cuts called
scooby snacks
no dog scooby snacks says dog walker and
forum cookies okay
right i didn't know that either
yeah yeah i mean i'm you know rich is
still in here
i'm sure he can uh
he can uh tell everybody but yeah the
dog walker which is our walker og i'm
not i'm not sure who made that side of
it um
and then that hybridized with chem 91 or
chem 4 i can't remember if rich found
out which one it is i think he ended up
saying chem 4 is what he was told yeah
yeah so i think it was supposed to be
cam 91 ended up being chem 4 i
personally prefer the flavor of chem 4
so yeah
it makes even more sense why
i like smoking dog walker here's my
favorite question
are you going to breed any more land
races
i mean why
are you gonna play a land race
yeah i i mean why would i even try i'm
gonna move to
antarctica and make the first antarctic
land race
there you go
[ __ ] hey
gotta ask the fun ones
yeah
what else you guys got you tired yet
fletch
you good well i mean if this means i
have to stop trying to um answer this
[ __ ]
with my fingers
uh that would be helpful
all right i mean i've tried you know
this matt i've tried for so many years
to try to just keep
the information correct
and it's just every year there's another
guy that heard something about the ocean
grown story from [ __ ] paradise seeds
mob john the biggest [ __ ] scammer
ever which can organ kid could come on
here and tell everybody about that's the
same [ __ ] dude dude that's kailua
yeah
that's him
right exactly it's all him every story
he ever told was a lie i got so many
stories about that guy because he lived
in portland and i [ __ ] knew him
personally you know
yeah i knew him in real life
yeah i want to say
uh man that dude would like i don't even
know if he had a wife really
you know it was a chick on meth that
used to [ __ ] smoke meth with him
that's what i know
dude he used to have like like stripper
hooker [ __ ] and [ __ ] around all the
time like he had a whole that dude it
was a problem you know i made him cry
once but he was he was how i ended up
meeting ken though right i believe that
yeah
because he was selling ken's seeds at
the time right
yep i believe that
uh west coast dog food as well is that
correct again west coast dog was that a
john creation
no that came from ken also oh
yeah west coast dog
so
so john used to uh basically find
medical patients
and get them to make seats for that
seeds for them
he'd take the seeds and not pay him
anything oh [ __ ] yeah so he had a couple
buddies that were down here in um
i do know ken who are not ken westfall
that's not who we're talking about but
ken
uh ken doe who's the guy that's posting
there he's also in our circle of friends
but not
huh
yeah i know kendo yeah he's old school
too but this this someone was asking if
it's kendo that i'm talking about and
the answer is no
this is totally different [ __ ] yeah and
uh
so john used to get these guys one of
the dude's name was diamond who's the
guy that's responsible for the u-dub cut
yeah that's on the long line it's not
you dub
first first of all
um there you go
it's it was a nice hash plant but it had
no smell of any udub i ever bought
buying pounds out of uw
um
there's many different strings that came
out uw but none of them i ever saw was
that one so there's diamond and his
buddy jim right and ken ken remembers
all these guys too
and uh so ken gave those dudes the cuts
and i got those cuts from them and that
was like the sour og the ogers
um the the cutting that ended up being
called the smelly it all that [ __ ]
i want to know personally about uh who
named banana og it was a cut of oh geez
right or ogres
ken named all that ken named and
selected all that okay um he he had
gotten
uh sagar martha's 60 40 seeds
um as freebies with [ __ ] that he had
ordered from gypsy nirvana
gotcha
and um
uh
he liked that and crossed it into the og
and that's banana og it was a freebie
packs from gypsy
um it was just bulk like basically skunk
number one hybrids um because that's
what i mean i think sam skunk man was
selling like millions of skunk one
hybrids back in those days to all the
seed distributor guys and they would all
just like package it up and sell it give
it away as freebies or whatever it was
you know
um
and uh
yeah it was just that you know it was
that cross with ogers and then ken grew
it so it was probably one of sam's uh
skunk one hybrid says the 60 40 based on
the smell and and like the way the plant
grows the fact that it washes well all
that stuff
um leads me to believe that it's
probably um
probably some skunk number one cross
just like pretty much everything else
that i've grown from that era from
amsterdam our buddy nick litus is asking
about um
norcal catfish that's a shaw bud one
right did it yeah that's shawba it's a
high school wheat from the early 90s
that's funny um and then the socal the
socal catfish is a cut that i got from
uh this dude that used to go by the name
philly he used to run a lot of weight up
here um there's a lot of local people up
in seattle that will know who i'm
talking about if they were around back
then and he brought me uh those cut i
did a bunch of work for him
um
and uh i actually heard that he was at
the glass show like uh last year down in
vegas um it was like a random connection
i might be actually have his phone
number i meant to hit him up but uh
you know i haven't i haven't talked to
the guy in a long time and he had some
uh
he had some issues let's just put it
that way with the uh with the law so i
you know and i was really i was always
really paranoid so
uh
so you know but but him and i philly and
i have some funny stories just like of
[ __ ] that [ __ ] that happened i got i
borrowed money from him to uh get
started in my first uh spot yeah when i
bought my first i had those omega
gardens that spin around the bulb and
[ __ ] yeah yeah
yeah so i had borrowed some money from
him to get going on that right and i
ended up with like three of those things
that's awesome
yeah but so anyways i did like some work
for them and moved some stuff and did
whatever and uh they brought me a couple
big mother plants straight from san
diego of that cut right
and i remember just like cutting up like
three there was two i never i've
still this day probably haven't seen
plants this healthy
um
they were just like six inch rockwool
blocks with mats of roots that were like
three feet long right yeah like they
were doing that um where you cover with
panda film over top of the uh the tray
yeah and male is just like perfect white
roots these things that just you know
been in the back seat and i probably
took like 350 cuts off of jesus those
two plants
you know they were like covered in
clones and anybody that's grown that san
diego catfish cut um yeah
we'll know how branchy that thing is i
mean it puts off cuts like crazy um
so
uh anyways that's how i got that cut
that's a legendary strain in san diego
along with the odds red p91 and the bull
rider do you ever come across the
original bull rider
i never saw any of those other ones man
i only ever saw the catfist right
it was like oh four that i got the cap
is from philly
and cannabis reverend the guy that uh
thought my dog [ __ ] buddy and our other
buddy um i don't know if he wants to be
caught
so i'll ask him in the future if he
wants everybody know who
brought our brought our crew
the dog [ __ ]
um but there's also the uh the the
farthest back that i know that the um
dog [ __ ] goes is
my buddy down in portland i um that owns
five zero trees
right they got it in 94. and supposedly
it came from like michigan i think
michigan or minnesota and it was
originally called electric boogaloo
that's um that's a story that my buddy
that owns five zero trees uh that those
group of stores down in portland they
were the first ones that uh
that got that cut
that that i know of and that's where
that's where they say it came from
and uh your thoughts on trinity
i only ever bought the herb from uh from
eugene i didn't ever see like the um i'd
never see the cut or know anybody that
had the cut correctly
all i ever remember about it was really
was that it had like a i saw a couple
different phenos of it so who knows what
the [ __ ] i actually saw right
uh but all of them were like very burnt
rubber smelling
um they weren't like skunked they were
like burnt rubber
like that burnt rubber cushy afghani
smell oh i i don't remember them tasting
it it was really well grown but it i
don't remember it tasting
um
better than uh
then it smelled i remember being the
opposite it's smelling really good and
not really having a ton of flavor
the trinity cut that i've been smoking
that uh
came through like the natsu dog and
those guys have and caleb that one that
one kind of tasted me like the old elvis
cut which is real interesting i'm not
sure if it is the old trinity or not but
i they're saying it is
yeah i haven't i haven't seen it so i
really don't know
um
the uh
like i said the trinity that i remember
all of them smelled like straight burnt
rubber
afghani punk and it was pretty strong
smelling but there was no sweetness at
all to it there was no fruitiness there
was no like
off smell it was just basically burnt
rubber i think if people confuse that
anything that's not sweet but that's
funky with skunk
uh i've been seeing that a lot lately
anything that's not fruity they call
skunk but
i think it also has to do with like i
know when i've stopped smoking for
periods of months and stuff
everything smells way skunkier yeah
like og smells like skunk ken sauer kush
that thing was [ __ ] super skunky i
mean like if you think gmo
has that bad breath whatever smell
abs ass ask about the original sour cush
cut
that um oregon kid can put out there
that thing was [ __ ]
ridiculous right i mean comparatively it
shits on gmo in terms of that wow raw
halitosis og
punk right yeah actually which is
totally different than the burnt rubber
i don't know i mean it is it's just
experience i think you have to have seen
it to know the difference absolutely
yeah
i think that's everything
we got
blue dot
707 seed bake he knows more about that
than anybody i mean that was like a club
cut that used to go through the third
floor at oakland that's all i remember
about it
um
i've seen some blue dot over the years
but whether or not it was like
um the blue dot that everybody talks
about i have no clue right the one that
i saw wasn't that impressive so it leads
me to believe that either
people are smoking bam or weed or i got
the wrong i saw the wrong [ __ ]
you never know yeah well i mean i've
been fooled before so yeah i think all
of us have at some point
yeah we're someone said something's
really awesome and then you see it
you're just kind of like oh never mind
yeah
uh let's see what else you guys got the
maui pog you familiar with it i don't
know anything about the pog yeah it's uh
hp 13. i want to say
their
maui dog or whatever it is that's all i
know about yeah i mean i've heard like a
bunch of different stuff but i've never
really seen enough um
about it the oregon pineapple someone
said
um
i don't remember a whole lot i just
remember buying that herb um i remember
seeing the pineapple ds i remember it
reminding me of the hawaiian indica [ __ ]
that was going around yeah and that's
what it rumored to be and i think that
you know that hawaiian indica line was
like pretty popular there for a few
years
uh one more quick one uh your collab the
tie with uh with uh with casas
yeah that was chris's brother's cut um
he lived in portland
chris gave me that cut uh when he
i think when he moved back or actually i
think i got it from his buddy up here a
couple years after he moved back to la
something like that
and i i had uh seeded it up with the
face off i never sold seeds of it yeah
um
but uh
i made seeds with it i have albert
walker face or albert walker manic cross
with uh that tie also
um
and i gave chris a handful of those
seeds and he's he's gonna work it just
partly in homage to his brother that tie
was really interesting it definitely
it was like um
it was like bubble gum and burnt onion
or not burnt onion but like uh like a
really strong cutting onion smell
and uh bubble gum and like a little bit
of the super silver haze yeah uh hazy
back end but not not really like when
you smell it you don't think haze it's
mostly that like
a tropical
uh cut onion
uh
type of smell it's pretty unique then oh
it's super unique and it was it was
stunk and i mean it did like the classic
uh little um bananas all up the calluses
yeah up the
on the top colas when it finished up
just like the milli two yep
what uh here's a good one and we can't
end with this this thing's almost over
um
what what project are you most proud of
like looking back on what you've done to
this point what are you most proud of
oh man i'm just one cog in the wheel
like i'm not
i just was preserving genetics because i
thought it was important and at the time
um
a lot of other people were getting rid
of everything because it was starting to
become like a marketing game right it
used to be able you could grow dog [ __ ]
and it'd still sell in fact it was the
most in demand product yeah ten years
later it was the opposite right nobody
wanted the long forex tivas people
didn't like smoking them anymore
um
it had become more of a marketing type
of cannabis market than it was before
right yeah and uh so for me as i i'm
just happy that i was in the right place
at the right time was able to get
a lot of these really good cuts and kind
of uh put them all in one place
and make sure that they they stuck
around i mean that's it
well
hey dude
we we actually did this thank you so
much for coming on and like educating
everyone and uh next time hopefully this
next time we can talk about like albert
walker and i know a lot of people want
that so
but i appreciate it and thank you so
much
and uh thanks for everyone for asking
awesome questions too
go later thanks fletch
[Music]
you