uh matthew riott let me explain
something to you
now matthew ryan is on is on youtube and
matthew i'm going to say this to you and
i want you to listen very carefully he's
going he's seeing hail satan
matthew what you have just done is
blasphemy what you have just done is
considered a mortal sin what you have
just done is sold your soul to the devil
my friend let me tell you something
matthew it's going to be one hell of a
hot place for you if god forbid if in
the next 30 seconds you decide god if if
god takes you
and you have to go to god face to face
and you are now in mortal sin because
you are hailing satan i will tell you
this right now you will lose your
salvation and where you're going brother
is a place where i wouldn't even want to
go where you're going i'm telling you
that crap is stupid
it is stupid
that's not it's not funny
it's not cute
it's dumb it is stupid ass to do that
oh good so matthew says oh my i take it
back let me tell you let me let me just
let me guys listen to the listen to me
carefully this is not a joke
when you're coming in there and hailing
satan and all this [ __ ] let me tell
you what's going to happen you're going
to lose your salvation do you understand
and i don't care if people like this or
not i don't care if it pisses people off
i'm telling you
this type of crap causes you to lose
your salvation this is a mortal sin
you are blaspheming god you might as
well just spit in god's face
because you want to be cute
because you won't want to let everybody
know how funny you are it's not funny
that's dumb
that's a dumb thing to do
well
believe me well i'm gonna i'm going to
delete you now matthew
because you obviously
have not heard a word i said
and the reason is it makes me mad is
because you're taking your salvation as
a joke
and i can only care as much as i
possibly can
but if you don't give a damn about your
own salvation then the only act i can do
is pray for you goodbye
well folks sorry but i had to um had to
block him and there we go i mean so
again folks it's just
some people i don't i don't get it i
don't understand
and um
yeah people are surprised oh my gosh he
bishop got mad of course i get mad i get
very mad when someone does something
like that
i get very angry because number one it's
offensive that you go into
uh a chat
and you start hailing satan it's not a
place for that you mean this is new
year's eve
this is new year's eve and you don't
have anything better to do than to go in
clergy's live show
hail satan yeah that's so funny
oh
my god
i don't understand i don't
um
all right uh someone's asking ikea is
asking about can you bring evil spirits
into your house from watching horror
movies or any