so i help that and of course i go to
people's homes and i bless their homes
and sometimes it's far away
and very expensive you gotta remember if
i have to fly to a place that's eight
eight hundred bucks or so maybe even
more and then i have to stay at a hotel
and as sometimes it could be up to a
week to two weeks
so and then rent a car so you're easily
looking at fifteen hundred two thousand
dollars and i do this all out of my own
pocket
i do not charge one penny for my
services not one penny
so i appreciate the gifts i do uh but if
you do want to um
uh to you can go to also cash app i
think that that cash app thing it's a
dollar sign bishop james long okay
astro beings um you know