welcome to reader Syndicate 3.0 the next
evolution of the look into
counterculture that is Canon my name is
Matthew owner of Riot seeds and this
started as a one-man mission for strain
history and breeding science over time
it's evolved into something bigger
better and more of a team effort we will
be joined by members of the can
Illuminati and other friends throughout
the seasons to hear their takes on grow
techniques breeding science strain
history and more our mission is to
combat the Nar the corporate cannabis
and Seed posers are obus skating for
their own Financial benefit welcome to
the underground We Are The
[Music]
Syndicate welcome to breeder Syndicate
I'm Matthew here with thousandfold and
we have a few friends with us that are
also Growers and uh we've been gone for
I guess what will now be a few weeks so
uh we will probably recap on that as
well at the beginning um real quick I
guess I'm just going to jump into that
and uh yeah
this so tell us what's happened in the
last couple of weeks yeah so for those
who don't know we did a few shows that
um we felt were really important uh for
a lot of the newer Growers or newer seed
buyers to understand what they were
going to be looking at when they first
came online to buy seeds um Based on
data and statistics and just what we see
around like we chose two different sites
that
being I I could say it because I can't
do anything the attitude and I love
growing MJ I don't want to say that now
um and uh yeah so we went through and we
showed like basically what red flags are
you know we didn't really go after with
the attitude we didn't go after the
attitude we went after not even specific
breeders just the biggest red flags we
saw of some of the more popular breeders
for new seed growers and um yeah they
just got flaged taken down um reported
for drug dealing which was just you know
I mean we're a a history and info show
that happens to be about cannabis so um
we ended up uploading those on Vimeo but
we did get strikes so that's uh
something so that's why we have been
down for a few weeks and uh yeah you
know I wanted to do a quick recap on it
as far as like letting you guys know
they're out there and we'll include the
links below um but they're important
episodes like just think about all the
money that we all spent as we got into
this and how much of like after having
some knowledge and learning how much
money was [ __ ] wasted with this
[ __ ] that that's meant to just
completely screw you um so yeah it's
important as it is and as as many
requests as we've got to do that we
tried and uh just didn't quite work so
maybe in the future we'll try again but
it's it's the whole idea was to show the
site and show proof of it evidence of it
as we're going through but that's really
where they got us is uh by showing their
websites so that's it thousand let's
talk about what we're going to talk
about
today yes so today we have kind of
similar to last season where we invited
on uh who was it spindle Big Ear local
to talk about what they've been growing
what they're looking for what they found
we have sha do I call you sha O2 Sean or
do I call you just Sean on the show uh
Sean works I'll just call me Sean Sean
we have scrw and scarecrow and we have
KT um so maybe to start us off why don't
you guys introduce yourselves a bit just
tell us a bit about what you know how
long you've been growing for what your
Growing Experience has been like and
maybe to tie it back a little bit to
what Matt was saying maybe just as a
bonus add in any anecdote about I don't
know early Seedbank experiences that you
may have had okay how about we start
with uh let's go with Sean since we just
talked to
Sean all right so my first experience um
growing was back I think in like 2008
2009 when I was just getting out of high
school um prices of everything were just
like we so [ __ ] good so um my
friend's dad he used to grow back in the
90s so he was like oh let's get in on
this and everything and and put kind of
me and and his son in charge of looking
up and finding seeds um we first started
with bag seeds that were coming from
some friends that were getting stuff
from either where they said Michigan or
C and so we kind of did that and then
when that was kind of going all right
and producing decent plants um he kind
of want us to look at seeds and I
remember first looking and I was on
attitude I think it was like looking at
Nirvana stuff and I remember looking
through the stuff that was kind of the
Cannabis Cup winning and I think there
was like cryistal
um there was like Snow White
blue mystic um
Blackjack what else um like a couple
others Northern bright Northern bright
um and a few others that we're like
looking at and then we ended up choosing
Northern bright um snow white blue
mystic Crystal
and couple others and we're they're
going good but he would always want to
cut him at like five weeks and then not
go through the actual like and then not
even try and let things dry and see
because he was like I gotta get
everything sold in six weeks and
everything like done five weeks sold in
six and then just like and I I didn't
know why but I mean he had a drug
addiction so he was trying to there you
go do that and he was yeah I mean he
ended up having us uh sell a bunch of
drugs for him after his son kind of like
blew up the spot because we ended up
renting this
big place this big nice house and we had
the whole basement that we were starting
up and his son of course like brought
people that weren't supposed to be over
and his dad was like [ __ ] this tore
everything down and then like then he
was just like oh here you want to have a
sell like uh you know roxies or whatever
that he's getting prescribed that turned
in just bad to just horrible decision
after decision and then I finally got
back into growing and 20 17 and was
looking around and I started um doing
some more research um I'd always kind of
pop in every here and there just kind of
reading things because I mean I always
wanted to really get into growing and
and that's just what I kind of just want
to do just have like you know whatever
job you know make some money and then
just be able to to grow and you know
maybe have like little auxiliary cash or
whatever but um yeah so I got back into
in like 201 2017 started growing some of
bie stuff I grew strawberry milk and
then Stevie
Wonder um which was that was a good one
both yeah both were good that's where I
first had my first introduction with
Appalachia with the strawberry milk um I
enoy wonder one of his first strains
ever is one of the F the earliest ones
too yeah I think Williams Wonder
something um yeah I can't can't remember
exactly uh what it was I know it was a
appal I know it's the Appalachian the
father and then um Stevie Wonder it was
like train wreck
blueberry um something else uh to the
snow Lotus
father um and all those were you know
really great um and then from there I
started getting some seeds from my
friend who you know I would help out a
little bit here and there and he would
show me a few different things and and
helped me learn about like a little bit
of soil building and and just different
things like that or tricks I just didn't
really think of and then I finally got
into um [ __ ] I guess when the blue
bonnet lines came out that's really when
I started getting some uh matte seeds
and grew I guess yeah when the first
drop of the the like pre-release of the
blistering came out I popped those yeah
those were those were phenomenal I had
like one that turned turned like blue um
but had like GMO structure and smell it
was it was like a perfect mixture of the
Bonnet and GMO where and then just like
the The Taste translated and it would
just coated your mouth and everything um
and then from there I I got onto blooper
skunks when they were released um I had
wrist surgery in between so when I had
wrist surgery I had a cast
on and my whole arm was up past the
elbow was immobilized so I couldn't
really do much for four months so I was
kind of just chilling and then got into
the blooper skunks um grew a bunch of
those was it your girlfriend hand yeah
unfortunately so I had to had to make
the other one stronger help me be idest
exactly
exactly yeah and then uh so then grew
out a few different things um in in
between there and now um the ones that
are most notable were Pock we're gonna
we're gonna get into like what like the
more detailed stuff about what you found
and like what you liked yeah so so I
kind of just been going on since uh
consistently since 2017 other than when
I had wrist surgery I had like the The
four-month Break um that
was
2020 like like right before the pandemic
happened so luckily that happened I was
in a cast and it wasn't like anything
wasn't a big deal but yeah that was uh
that's about it I
think pretty sweet thank you that's
awesome uh
Kristen uh yeah um well I try I tried to
grow when I was a
teenager and uh that didn't work out cuz
I know what to do and didn't have
anybody to show me or anything like that
uh but I started like actually
harvesting in
2011 and
uh I don't know I I wasted a bunch of
money on seeds from the
attitude
and what did you get what did you can
you I was I was buying those Greenhouse
when they were doing the the circles
with like five seeds in it and you poke
a little hole out of the back PL uh yeah
yeah the wax coated seeds were they any
of those ones yeah the colored one the
white and black packs and I got the
sativa lover pack or whatever [ __ ] yeah
bro yeah I I ended up going back to bag
seed um except like this time it was
from you know like decent weed yeah and
uh I don't know I had to take a Hiatus
for a little bit and so you you you end
up going to bag seed over the greenhouse
seat that you
bought yeah well not just Greenhouse but
Greenhouse was the ones I was banking on
I was like I'm going legit you know no
more of this because like I I started
realizing like man the problem is that
like I'm just popping like Mexican bag
seed I had no [ __ ] shot I didn't have
uh HID lights I was running off of those
giant CFLs the ones that like the size
of a pineapple like like that big yeah
yeah yeah I I had no shot uh at like
actually harvesting anything besides a
couple of Braes so I I thought well you
know it's probably my seeds it's
probably you know like I actually got a
book started reading got uh switchable
uh metal HED
HPS light and uh
bought what I thought were the most
legit seeds that I could get which was
Greenhouse [ __ ] yeah Cup winners bro Cup
winners every
time yeah they were just they were just
so I don't know they they looked okay I
guess they had great advertising dude
they they really did and still do yeah
and I like the shirts from the stealth
shipping from attitude right yeah yeah
you get those cool shirts yeah yeah but
I just went to like bag seed from uh I
was you know transferring some stuff
from uh a friend out in California and I
guess their spot seated out and pretty
much everything was seated for like a
year so I just started going through
that stuff and
uh yeah I didn't buy seeds again until
till I came back out of Hiatus cuz I was
just kind of helping friends grow since
I couldn't at the time yeah and uh I
popped up a finally was able to pop up a
2x4 and do every you know veg flour even
drying in it like I had to do everything
in that little 2x4 so I was just buying
fem seeds from uh um what's it called uh
the hot chick and her
dad humble humble seed how I mean I
assume that's who you mean
yeah yeah you know like cuz I I had some
CU I had still been collecting seeds and
stuff yeah
um and I I didn't want to because when
when I when I got caught up and had to
stop for a bit like
I I started learning that cloning isn't
just about multiplication of like plants
it's like actually oh hey this this one
was better than the rest there you go um
so I didn't want to pop anything like
that I thought would be super special
yeah with even those packs those were
[ __ ]
too and then uh yeah I don't know I no
offense
H well I found you know I don't know I
found the the podcast started listening
and um
yeah I got some triangle choke seeds
from a friend uh that he got from one of
those one of those uh shirt that's right
yeah yeah yeah we had the shirt giveaway
seed
thing yeah so I popped those found
something I loved and I haven't really
stopped popping Syndicate beans since
yeah excellent yeah and the rest is
history yeah we'll get into that we'll
be getting into that and that'll be fun
because yeah I know you know the other
reason why I picked the three of you is
because yeah all three of you are great
Growers you've been growing stuff from
the crew for a while and so look forward
to hearing more about that as we go
on before before Kyle starts that Avatar
is my I have to say second favorite but
that was one of my favorite dogs that
I've ever interacted with and that was
kind of like me and Kyle knew who each
other were before like you know but like
I think that's how we became friends
friends was through that dog and cool to
see him there yeah for sure well that's
why I picked it so yeah excuse so
yeah that's pretty wholesome yeah go k
uh well I mean I'm pretty much a newer
grer uh man maybe five years um well
like screw I I'm tried maybe when I was
a teenager but I was been raising kids
for you know that's basically what I've
been doing so but I've been wi I've been
around cannabis you know basically my
whole life uh I've had family grow in
meno Sonoma uh some out in Virginia um
so you know that's uh pretty much it but
my first SE Bank uh I don't really
didn't really to deal with seed banks I
have my first seeds were from snow high
so i' I've really only dealt with uh
kind of that type of SE Bank they're no
real Dutch type stuff or anything like
that
yeah yeah pretty much and any SE banks
are ones you know that were uh Matt was
helping out and that's how I got a lot
of Matt stuff is basically I was trying
he's helping people out and I always
thought that was a cool thing that Matt
always tries to do and uh yeah so you
know that's and through um through my
seeds uh through my growing I started
out with the Rev so I do all T yeah
that's that's how I found about snow
high and Matt and Instagram and all that
stuff the lives um yeah that's basically
it and actually when I was and actually
when I was a teenager surprisingly how
it worked out is um I uh used to use the
um uh the Rev likes to do use nutrient
spikes and Miracle Grow actually had
them and that was one of the things that
I actually did when I was a teenager
because I thought hey that makes sense
why why do I want to feed it all the
time when I can just put it into the
soil and then just water it yeah uh and
so once I found his philosophy uh it
just everything fit for me and I just
been doing that and yeah there's no
reason for me to change basically yeah
right yeah I was gonna just say that's
right now I remember yeah you're doing
um T cuz uh bumat from our Discord
Community has actually been talking to
me about like a broad Organics episode
and I just have been struggling to to
think of people to include so maybe I'll
I'll I'll be in touch with you about
that for sometime in the future yeah I
really enjoy it because uh I'm getting
as a you know I'm not younger anymore
and I do construction so the Rev it's
small containers uh you know it's it's
it's real easy it's not a lot of heavy
lifting type stuff um so that fits my me
because I do night gardening so you know
it's hard for me you know to do a lot of
stuff sometimes once I get home you know
especially once I you know I gu it's
another job on top of another job
sometimes and that that's never fun
because that's not why I do this I
definitely do it for a passion and it's
what I like to do
so
nice Okay well I've Loosely divided this
talk into like three parts so the first
part is kind of meant to be like what
you've grown in the past then the second
part's like what you found and the third
part's meant to be like what else you're
looking for so more of the future in
saying that I know it's obviously hard
to talk about what you've grown without
talking about what you're looking for
but you know we we'll do our best to to
see we can kind of focus in these you
know from these different
perspectives so we're going to start
from what you've grown and I know you
guys have already sort of touched on
that but we could bring it back to Sean
because Sean was about to tell us about
you know blue PR skunks and all that
what are some of the highlights Sean of
of the things that you've grown um and
yeah just just kick it off and and I
think at this point I also invite all of
you to ask questions if you have any to
each other good call yeah so I guess
some of my favorites that I have grown
so far have definitely been the
blistering um the blooper
skunk uh the Blue Sour the blue
resin the Santa Cruz wreck that that
stuff's phenomenal um I found like this
this blue um Bubble tape kind of
feno um and then there was like one that
popped out that was just like this weird
Savory meaty rancid meaty kind of thing
oh wow yeah I don't it it was just weird
I I don't really know how to explain it
my nose kind of sucks too so I'm
probably so how someone else would smell
it they would probably be like maybe
that's not necessarily what it is is or
they'd pick up other notes yeah um and
then also Paco's sour skunk dog um
that's right yeah that was one of my
favorites of the the sour hybrids I've
grown and I've grown out probably like
10 10 different ones um of just like the
sour and the diesel hybrids over the
past two or three years and really the
the Blue Sour the Appalachian Diesel and
the sour skunk dog would be my three
that I would kind of just look through
the to find something um I really love
the the appy diesel um I threw out four
plants um one was all right the other
three I they're just like two were
really close um just really really loud
um just I could bring it into a room and
and people would smell it and and
immediately and kind of just asked like
what the [ __ ] is that um yeah and it
would have this just burnt
rubber kind of just rotten mango Funk to
it that translate completely The Taste
with the the high that's just uh hits
you and and you know makes you kind of
kind of dumb a little bit but it like
keeps you awake and it kind of just gets
your mind off of things and numbs your
body a little bit and just kind of stays
up in the head and doesn't really uh
doesn't really burn you out too much um
which is great like you don't have like
like the crash um and then the app f3s
were good um they're a little bit slower
veg for me than I I prefer um but
flavor-wise
um just really great I got this one that
was like a mango chem um so it I guess
it was more kind of Trace dog with just
like the the little bit of green crack
on the back end that kind of gave it a
little extra taste and flavor to it you
know
um then what else the original can I ask
Sean actually just before you go on what
what led you to these particular packs
with strains what were um so like good
diesel representations yeah I kind of
was looking for so I I also grew out I
was looking for like banana tie because
I always kind of wanted to do like a
little bit of just growing some seeds
and throwing things together that that I
would like so I was kind of going
through through all like the Diesels and
and and sour and stuff like that trying
to find a couple lines you know that I
would really like that I could then go
back through and how I kind of go and
purchase would be um I something I think
would be like really good or should be I
may buy like a couple packs you know for
but initially I if I'm not too sure
about I'll buy a pack and then grow it
out if I like it then I'll I'll buy a
few more
so um all those I've I've ended up going
back and and buying buying more just
because I I want to end up using them
for making seeds for my own and and
trying
to um just make
something that I I could like you know
uh myself and just you know be happy
that I I made something that I enjoy and
and I have um I went and got I so the
banana tie I got some outdoor from Cody
Matt nose
Cody yeah I can't remember like
undefeated or can't remember whatever
his Instagram I can't remember yeah he
so he sent me some of the outdoor that
was just this like Juicy Fruit bubble
gum that reminded me of some wheat I had
when I was 17 uh yeah and like I skipped
school to go and get and everything and
um
and then the kid's dad comes home and
gets all pissed because we're like
smoking weed in his house and it's just
like this it I don't know it was fun
time so I wanted to kind of and then
that kind of brought the Nostalgia but
this banana tie had just like the most
amazing high it was just kind of just
really racy but not like anxiety
inducing yeah um which is is you know
what I really like and then just the
flavor and everything it was like this
juicy fruit bubble gum with a little bit
of a spiciness to it it and then he also
sent some shatter that was just all
Juicy Fruit Bubblegum and like this was
like
200 18 or 19 it was when your lives it
was when your lives I don't know when
your lives first started but it was
right before I guess it was like a year
2019 I
think when Cody was around yeah sometime
like 1819 yeah and so then I wanted to
you know I got a pack from you I think
the last pack of the F1 so I wanted to
you know try and find female to to keep
and then uh possibly use that or just
really just to have that so then I took
I didn't end up finding a female so I
ended up getting a male and I was like
all right let's just see what happen so
I ended up pollinating blue resin um
some apocal Sour skunk dog uh a
NATO La lemon tree um NATO La TK from
CSI what else did I get oh uh Cherry
Berry yeah yeah hit and and those and
then I also hit the like I said the blue
resin um feel like there's like a couple
other things in there I can't I can't
remember everything they just didn't
really interest me all that much um but
I've grown out the blue resin banana tie
and got some really nice like creamy
blue and blue blueberry lemon and I
ended up with some of the more Blueberry
Lemon ones I ended up making some hash
from some boy that was sitting around
for you know four months curing and the
hash came out blueberry lemon um awesome
made some bubble hash and I've been
enjoying that a lot um and then the
Cherry Berry banana tie came out um I
only grew out three females I did a
small pop just to see what it was
everything's like really nice dense very
resinous to of the three fenos were
um they're like a Cherry Lemon and just
like this kind of like light green
with more of like a yarn like a rust
colored hair I guess and those ones were
are just really nice um I've given some
to some friends and stuff to try out
other than myself and they all seem to
like them and then one was a purple feno
that uh kind
of was was more of like the Cherry Berry
um but it was purple so I'm guessing
that one was more um Cherry Berry
leaning super Frosty the high actually I
enjoyed more of that feno and ended up
smoking that one
first um so really most of what I've
bought and things like that I've kind of
wanted to to eventually find run through
things find things I I like and then
kind of mix them together um and enhance
the the the ones that I find so with the
banana tie doing that I was hoping to
pass on I was hoping the male would have
the you know the Juicy Fruit um tpine
profile and pass that along along with
the effects um so that was my goal I
haven't really
found the you know the juicy fruit
profile but and effect wise I couldn't
really tell you if it has passed on very
much but from what I've grown out I have
enjoyed it um I have you know seen the
nuances and and flavor profiles I I just
need to go back to those seats and grow
out more to to really see what's there
yeah um and everything but but like I
said you know I'm going from a male I
can't really if it was you know using
the female and going I would have a
better idea of what I'm trying to find
and this I was hoping you know it would
pass on certain things but and maybe the
other uh four things I have that I
haven't run yet something will pop out
of those um but we'll see about that um
yeah and then I guess so of my my top I
guess if I say the top three of of the
ones I have grown I definitely say
original sin that one's that one's yeah
everybody loves that one yeah I feel
like the crosses
uh it's Loompa loma's headband uh to
appy appy
F3 um and it's just like I haven't grown
out Loa headbands but I've seen it and
and seen what other people have said and
it's like a more
stocky and it's just like this pin
saww funk you know with a little bit of
like burnt rubber maybe in there and
there's some fenos that have that are
like a little bit of mango in there
instead of the the pinea and those ones
are just like really really good and all
the PO the potten and all of them um I
had four females all relatively close to
each other um and that's probably what I
or well not probably that is definitely
what I've been smoking on the most um
recently um and those I definitely want
to look through more and more but I mean
I found four that I was you know happy
with flavor-wise and effects with so um
I I know I didn't keep any because I I
have some work going on at the place I'm
at right now and keeping me from keeping
anything but then once the work's done
I'm going to go back to um the ones I've
really liked growing over the past you
know few years and then look into there
for Keepers to to then make some uh some
cool things with hopefully and then I
would also say I really love the appy
diesel and then the Cherry Berry the
Cherry Berry is really really good um
but man the blooper skunk and and
blistering too it's
just um the blooper skunk I got a lot of
like kind
of blue
like just buttery blue fenos and then
some that were like like really skunky
and then I got one that was like I don't
know how to how to describe it it was
kind of like a
blue like sweet tart kind of thing or
like an electric kind of blue thing that
ended up turning a little funky towards
the end um and I would just describe it
as best as like this is like electric
blue Funk and The Taste was just mouth
coating and T you know flavor just
translated and had this just really
really nice Mellow High um which I liked
about a lot of them I know I've seen
tests and stuff and a lot of people and
they test high but I mean I guess maybe
I I smoke a good amount but they didn't
like overpower me but they they did
everything I wanted it to do you know um
with wrist surgery my my wrist is
completely like pretty much destroyed I
can take my um Ola and move it up and
down still after
surgery so and I do you know manual
labor and stuff for a living so I need I
need stuff that's gonna know you know
fix with that uh not to mention just
other like torn lab Broms and other
injuries that I just what the hell did
you do to do all this oh work and
boulders and and you know moving those
around and one slipped and was about to
fall in and I grabbed it with my hand
and just like pulled my shoulder out of
socket Jesus you're happy so yeah so I
need stuff you know that's gonna not
necessarily you know put me down because
I like this smoke throughout the day as
well so I'm looking for things that will
cover you know the aches and
pains um and you know maybe help with my
focus because I have ADHD or not ADHD
but I have just bad attention you know
so I you
know yeah I'm like bouncing around half
the time so yeah it helps me you know
Focus down and nail down tasks and I
just you know I'm not trying to be but
then at night you know that's why like
you know maybe the original sin um that
that's kind of my go-to after work that
or yeah or the Appalachian diesel is
really nice um I do also really like the
the Cherry Berry um banana ties and then
I gur out the the blue tints from
Pico um those those were nice they all
came out like just really nice bag
appeal um really blueberry smelling I
had one that was kind of more uh
definitely looked more Kush mins um and
cookies and it was kind of like
um like a blueberry lemon muffin kind of
thing going on yeah and yeah I mean
those were those were good too I enjoyed
those um just those quick little testers
from the thing so I mean a lot of the
freebies and things that you give I'll
just you know give those a go and most
of those are great too um wait free from
where spell it out oh well not well no
no not necessarily oh well when you buy
packs and stuff from math you know yeah
yeah that's what I mean yeah yeah
exchanges for blood drops yeah yeah yeah
you know no no let me yeah I'll pause
you there Sean because we're still we're
still going to go into what you found
later on so you can like you know maybe
think about what else you found um for
the next part the other thing I've
noticed is no the other thing I've
noticed is that
um the three of you will have some
overlaps and what you grown and that's
going to be quite cool to talk about so
maybe Sean if I pause you there and move
us on to Kyle cuz you're going to get to
come back again anyway yep Kyle do you
want to speak to I know you've done some
banana Thai stuff as well am I Am I
Wrong uh no actually yeah no I have uh
yeah that's actually my uh the one thing
I'll make sure I never lose is the one
my number one from the
s1's uh yeah it's the juicy fruit or I
Fruit Stripe for you know uh old school
people I I always fruit strip gum yeah
the Fruit Stripe even though now it's
gone but I still that's how I refer to
it
yeah remember that
commercial so yeah that's it's uh it's a
three four hour high for me uh I can
smoke it's a no ceiling I can just keep
smoking get higher higher uh yeah yeah
it's just it's for me it's just i' I've
tested it pretty thoroughly I can't get
it to do Herm so it's pretty I want to
do work with it I've been trying I tried
my first reversal stuff uh I don't know
I don't think anything took but you know
that's how it goes and I only did one PL
so I I knew I knew failure was pretty uh
100% actually I figured I figured with
one PL but I figured I had one ready and
I just threw it in there uh to see what
would happen type of thing uh and I also
have another one I uh out of the pack I
I had got five and I got a pretty good
um Expressions especially from what Matt
has seen pictures of uh I end up getting
a cookies and cream one uh a few that
were kind of more of the dad uh from
what the pictures were that's on that
yeah that's the ones that you really
like as pictures yeah pictures are
beautiful yeah yeah yeah they definitely
the high it was okay uh wasn't there
what I wanted and and the turps it was
just kind of they the blend it when Once
stuff gets
muddled it's just it's kind of nothing
there's Bland ones inside that banana
tie and that's a thing like there
there's been um expressions in there
that I've definitely considered just
straight Bland like I don't know if it's
just the cookies that mutes it all but
it just goes Bland in some of them like
cardboard Bland but yeah we yeah yeah
yeah even though it's really they
smelled really good tropical mix like
there's nothing that was like banana or
anything they mix but then yeah once you
smoke it it was kind of yeah just
nothing no turpy wise but for me it's
always the effect I can I can get Beyond
tpps because I'm really old school so
i've smoked a lot of a lot of bad bad
stuff in my time because that's like
I've been smoking since uh uh basically
I was nine since paraquat bro yeah so
basically ear we're talking early 90s so
we're talking yeah I I definitely smoke
some bad stuff so it's like hey man go
get something to drink like if I really
have to yeah right you just get over but
uh yeah I just really like the banana
thae um yeah and I just plan on working
that and keeping it so yeah yeah what
what other stuff have you grown in the
past that you you know you want to
highlight uh well my first thing I ever
did before I actually didn't get the
snow High seats first cuz he took a
little bit cuz uh he was waiting on
whatever I actually had ordered so I
actually had got CSI and it was a sweet
Pig stink so that was my very first uh
grow line love that line yeah I did
three of those uh it was okay I just I
don't think I was the best obviously my
first Crow so looking back at the
pictures especially I'm like oh yeah
that's probably
why I didn't enjoy it so much but I I
still have half that pack uh but then I
did some perfect pearls those were
pretty good I enjoyed those and those
were ones of the few that actually my
wife she doesn't actually smoke but uh
she always smells Pine she's very
sensitive to anything Pine so basically
everything just smells weed Pine those
are ones she actually says and she
remembers was sugary sugary sweet so
those are ones so hard to describe Pearl
can you can you spell out what's perfect
Pearl who's it from oh so that's from a
souvenir uh SE
uh and that's the silver Pearl s1s and
these were his first release so uh you
know obviously I found out through Matt
obviously Instagram and you know I got
those as soon as they were available
actually I think that was through the
seed bank at the time and so I popped on
those really fast as soon as they came
up so yeah yeah that's one of my
favorite cuts that I've ever grown was
that silver Pearl cut that he used to
make the ones that's where I sourced it
same guy H uh yeah then uh see what else
uh everything else is kind of just a
random stuff I haven't really kept
anything uh too special there's some
people uh I've grown I'm not gonna
mention names um
yeah that yeah there's certain names I
just want like the certain seed banks I
just for me I just won't give them uh
this I just I just don't mention names
that's just you know it's just they're
not worth the time type of
thing let's see what else maybe one
thing I can ask you Kyle is uh did you
have a sense of what you were looking
for earlier on uh well for me uh I think
I was thinking recently that I think I
was searching for everything because uh
it was just this is such a passion for
me and I never grew that I G I have so
much now that I don't really know if I
ever have to buy anything anymore I need
to start kind of looking through what I
have yes um thanks mat and just Mak yeah
well I am making my own making my own
stuff because I know there's certain
stuff that people uh basically what I
look for is if everybody's doing one
thing I go the opposite so I know you
know right now everybody's kind of going
the blueberry in the Discord so right
now I probably wouldn't be glowing
blueberry type of thing so I start
looking in the opposite direction
because that's just that's just how
always how I've been for everything I
just kind of do the opposite of what
everybody's doing gotta keep it unique
bro well yeah and it's yeah it's kind of
you know but we're all going to see
pictures of blueberry and very very soon
and that's all we're gonna
[Laughter]
see like team team you know that the
team's doing this so oh yeah yeah well
Matt's gonna be very happy but you know
yeah
right yeah the other notable be right
now would be uh the sweet pee uh I did
get those seeds secondhand not not
actually through uh the person who uh
made them yeah I don't know if he wants
to be mentioned because I know he's not
an actual B yeah no that's fine oh yeah
I never know if he because I know he
doesn't actually uh uh no no yeah sell
like you know sell yeah one of the other
people I don't like to talk about either
like pretty much took credit for all
that [ __ ] because bitter doesn't say
anything but yeah as B p91 work with my
oh yeah yeah so I got that one um yeah
and that's uh same thing with the tie
I've already put that through pretty
much uh good the pace and it hasn't done
anything it's hard for me to get it to
be mad and so I plan I like to mix that
with the tie because uh people say that
there's the Menthol camper nutty thing I
don't get that from mine mine is kind of
more just what I describe as hashy which
is just Bland there's no real flavor
it's just to me resin uh which I think
would be good with the tie because it's
just going to get add I would think more
more resin because the Sweet Pea is
pretty resinous and that everybody likes
the pictures and uh maybe a little bit
of structure but that I'm not too too
worried about but I think the mix would
be good yeah and and then and then the
high I think it would be good I think it
could be more an intense
uh with the legs is what I what I would
think and that's what I would be
searching for
yeah nice thank you
scren uh
yeah so I uh I really like the what I
found in the triangle choke um and
what's that what's triangle
truck uh that's uh TK by gel and then
pollinated to the blue bonnet pollinated
by the blue bonnet yeah yeah and sorry
just to just to know obviously we all
know what these these strains are but
I'm making you guys spill it out for the
audience
yeah yeah um I mean I liked so I got the
five seed pack just the promo pack um
before they were sold just uh for my
buddy who got one of the shirts they
were did I ever sell on the site maybe I
did put them on the site eventually did
I yeah yeah that's right I did you did
at one point because you realized that
people were interested
yeah yeah uh and like that was just out
of two females so I bought two more
packs of those and then ER gave me two
packs of those that he got as a freebie
um that I'm going to be going through
here soon hell yeah
yeah there's good stuff in
it is that it what else have you been
growing oh sorry um the uh I really
liked the stone ape what we found in the
stone ape that uh my buddy actually
bought that pack um and popped him and
gave me clones so that I could help him
like keep it alive uh so I ran them
too and what we found in it was is so
[ __ ] good it's I mean three of the
four
females could easily have been kept just
depending on like preference yeah but uh
the one that we you know three of us
grew them so we kind of like passed
around jars and stuff like that
throughout our little friend group here
and
um yeah we all kind of picked the one
that was very much like a like rotten
mango and this was gorilla glue appal
yeah yeah
High extremely resinous um
potent and like a really good quality of
high not just you know like a one note
high if that makes sense very R Spectrum
High yeah ton and like the smoke was
really nice um it obviously it looked
really good uh probably because of the
Gorilla
Glue
um can I ask you SC I don't know if you
want to speak to this and we can like
clip this out if you don't but I know
that you've got like a little crew of
friends who actually like you guys kind
of do grows not grows together but like
you kind of um you guys are doing some
collaborative stuff right try some the
same things you want to talk to us about
some of that uh sure yeah um so like I
mean we're all just like you know mostly
we're all just dads like growing pot uh
on our own before and uh some people you
know I don't know I've been friends with
some people one dude I met actually on
The
Syndicate um and we all just kind
of pass out jars like from from our
Harvest to each other to so we can all
kind of like check out we you know what
other lines are like and stuff like that
and um one of my buddies uh grew and
chopped he's growing out the eie appy
and the eie by Blue Dream yeah that's
electric bugaloo right yes yeah that's
that's also known as dog [ __ ] for those
that don't
know
yes yeah and he's looking through those
hoping to find you know like
a good one out of each and then I'm
looking through the shoreline by appy
and Shoreline by Santa Cruz blue dream
so we can kind of cover more you know
bases yeah and find cool [ __ ] um I think
that's so cool like it's it's the it's
the kind of thing that like uh we dream
of more people doing I think in the
community just like Shar like pulling
your resources and time
essentially yeah well we have uh like a
little bit of like a geographic
Advantage just because our city is so
big you know like there's bound to be a
lot of people in it that are growing pot
you know
um yeah it was it was just kind of like
finding each other I
guess that the hard part yeah it's hard
to find people to trust in in any City
you know to that degree trusting with
your family and livelihood um yeah
want to sit at the table with The
Syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is
topnotch I've been saving old designs
for years for this purpose so please
check it out Syndicate gear.com we also
have an underground Syndicate Discord
where we get together and solve old
strain history together daily it's an
amazing community of learning away from
IG and it's an amazing resource for old
cataloges and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of readers and Growers come
check it out