welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
hey what's up everyone welcome to
breeder Syndicate reviews
um I've already done a review on this
product right when I got it and I did it
like maybe
15 minutes after having out of the box
and really not knowing what I had as a
product and not knowing what parts did
what and
I was trying something new but it really
sucked so I wanted to redo this reshoot
this and and since I actually understand
the product now I've cleaned it
taking it apart used it a bunch on
different stuff so I wanted to give it a
proper review
so this product is called the
now this part is going to be new to me
trying to get this in shot
a flower
the flower Mill
and this is the packaging for it and
again here's the stuff
and eventually there is a
if I can get the light not to uh
this is just terrible with this light
hold on
maybe I could turn down the lights on so
it just stops that
didn't really help much anyways there's
a QR code for it this is the flower Mill
and as it comes and it arrives it you
know what it comes with this is the
premium Flour Mill
from flowermo USA really nice it's heavy
you can
hurt someone with this thing if you
wanted to and uh when you get it you
open it up this is what it looks like it
has a it doesn't have teeth on it like
we are accustomed to seeing as you can
see from like this Edge
quite a bit different looking and inside
you'll see there's a uh
kind of perforated thingy and you can
unscrew it
and if you bought the um
upgraded screen package you can actually
change the size of these and we're going
to show you what each size does
and this right here now a lot of people
laughed at me because the last one I was
like what the hell is this green thing
in here you know
and uh sorry I have to slam it out it's
for the top
it sits in here and this is so when you
go to clean it
it's a rotor keycap and you just twist
it and Bam
this thing comes all the way off and you
can easily you know put an alcohol clean
it do whatever so it's actually pretty
freaking handy though I don't know where
to put the key in the meantime like when
you're using it there's not a good
storage place for the key like if you
don't want to put it in the bottom face
up so that your bud just hangs in all
these crevices right
um so I haven't found a good place to
put other than in the package and then
going and hunting it down when I need to
use it to clean it but anyway um what
I'm going to show you first is we're
going to start with
the screen that it comes with because
you know most people if you're if you
don't order the um if you order the
premium
uh Clower Mill
and
you don't order the extra screens I want
to show you what you'll get right so
this is it stock and what I'm going to
be what I'm going to be uh shredding
today is um
Santa Cruz blue dream
grown by my buddy pack from Santa Cruz
goat farm
so and I'm going to do that for all the
screen sizes the same stuff from the
same person so that you get an idea for
the same type of blood bud and density
and stuff what you're going to get and
even when I load these I'm just being
real picky about stems just because I am
though like the owner said because he he
wrote me after the first um
the first review and was like hey here's
my name here's my number if you ever
need to talk it's real friendly nice guy
um and like I said before this isn't a
sponsored video they're not paying me I
didn't get this for free I went and
bought it and um because I I saw it at
our can Illuminati party and I was like
you know I'm big warm broader I was like
dude what is that you know and I saw it
and in action it was cool and it worked
really well so when I got home I wanted
to check it out on more stuff you know
what I mean you don't really
okay I'll get to use a whole another
person's grinder for a whole long time
so anyway
so
as you can see let's see if I can get a
good picture maybe I'll put a little bit
more in
just because
there we go
so here we go
I'm Santa Cruz blue dream I really wish
this had like a better macro setting
you can see because I want to show you
how fine it grinds up now unlike
Grinders where you push real hard and
grind I am noticing you don't
necessarily have to do that like slower
is better
so when I'm doing it oh maybe I'll do it
from this angle Maybe
well because it'll just drop out the
sides you just do it real slow because
you're just Milling the flower you're
not grinding you're milling and you're
gently pushing it against that screen
and rubbing it up against that screen
and what it does is it gives the the
butter real super fluffy texture and
I don't know it seems to me and I can't
prove it like like what do I know right
but it seems to me like it's
not murdering the oils as much but maybe
I don't know
anyway let's see you can get this one
keeps coming unscrewed ever since the
last time I did it
okay see we got
so there's still stuff left up here
and this screen and this is this isn't
my favorite screen to use to be honest
with you because I've had a lot of
um stuff like this you know and the
sticks are supposed to stay up here but
like normal this isn't the most this
isn't like cookies density buds so the
fact that it just compressed it all kind
of was not a good sign
so I'll break it up some more
uncompress it and re-mill it
but yeah
this isn't this is not my favorite
screen I really feel like the the one
slightly finer does a better job when it
comes to stuff like this
and like I said I can't go back and
forth I can only go one way right now
because for whatever reason this thing
is
unscrewing as I go back and forth maybe
you're only supposed to go One Direction
though because like I kept seeing
ignorant stuff like that last time and
yeah see
there you go
this flag needed a little bit of
fluffing by me my fault
so here's the finished product and this
is what I mostly want you to see up
close
is the
texture
you see how it's kind of when you touch
it
it's still very marshmallowy
being just squish it
'll rise back up
yeah so
that's from the the screen that comes
with it and granted like I said I did I
did a crappy job try to grind it there
is a little bit left on top and that's
it
um let's see
so uh we're gonna put this somewhere
else
and then we will do the next screen size
so I can show you if you did get the
other screens which you can expect from
those
and luckily with this changing the
screens is very very very easy
so
okay that way we don't mix it up so you
can actually see the different
densities so this is the screen we were
using
there's basically a screw on the back
side you hold it twist it
and unscrew it battery Dome
and then
this is the next size down
what that was
anyway so now you just load it back up
let's put that on there you screw this
is the thing that kept coming unscrewed
when I would go both directions
but I haven't had that problem before so
maybe I'm just I am very very slow
so any complications please blame on me
not the product because really I've had
no problems with this thing it's been
pretty nice
it's been pretty freaking nice I will
say
um I don't remember the price point on
this but it is a plus 100 price point
for just the the um
the mill
without the additional screens alone
it's over a hundred
so it's not going to be something that
you're gonna like
you know get super cheap or it's it's a
newer type tech for this
um market so I don't even think there's
knockoffs or anything like that out
there I mean I don't know but um the
quality of this is pretty sound and like
the fact that I'm nobody and the owner
reached out and was like real cool even
though it wasn't the best review
it was cool of him so here's the next
size
and this is the neck size
um smaller on the screens and there's
one slightly smaller than that and I
believe two larger
all right let's see
and see the the top of this thing is
magnetic and and weighted too so it's
it's nice you don't have to push
it does it
bam see a little bit on top not much
and then
freaking not so dog blowing me up
ring her off not so we're busy anyway
here's the uh finished for this size I
don't know if with this camera if it
really will be able to show you any
like if you'll be able to tell any
difference you know
from the last size
come on get clarity there we go
the texture is slightly different with
this it's a little less fluffy a little
more fine
you know
the other stuff's a little more fluffy
and this is just a little more fine but
you don't have as much I don't know I
didn't ever have as much stuff left over
okay
so we're gonna go to the next uh let's
do
essentially what will be two sizes up
and after doing all this like a
barbarian I'm putting them all together
at the end right
that's slow all right
next size uh or two sizes up
so for comparison's sake we're going to
jump up to this size
wait hold on I think that was what we
started with make sure
yeah that's what we started with here we
go
this size up so we just use this one
we're going to go up to that size so you
guys can see what that one's like the
the monster site
so like I did before I just unscrew it
here there's a screw on the other side
pop it out
and I'm trying to show it in camera even
though I keep pulling it off because
like whenever I'm always trying to find
like a tutorial and then take it off
camera like the part one part I'm
looking for on how to do or undo
it sucks and that constantly happens
with almost everything I look for so
hopefully I don't do that to anyone here
if I do message me and let me know and I
will go back and
help somehow explain it somehow
because that is frustrating as hell all
right one last round of uh Blue Dream
here
so essentially one thing that you might
notice is that if you buy the premium
screens uh or if you buy the premium
Mill and you buy the additional screens
what's going to happen is you're going
to end up with two of the same size
screens because in that four screen set
it's an extra screen of one that it
comes with so just be aware of that
because I thought it would be like
additional screens as far as like
additional sizes so then I would have
five but realistically like you're gonna
find one that you work with best and
it's not necessarily going to be the one
that it comes with you know like I I saw
on the reviews a lot of people agree
with me that that small one is is not
the small list but the next to smallest
is
is the one that they like too so
and that one does not come with the uh
Mill that one is only with the
additional set it would be cool if
they'd like maybe what they should do is
like let you choose which one you get
you know as opposed to just giving you
if you can only have one maybe give you
the choice I think that would be a good
option
you know
that way you're not spending extra money
just to get the one that most people
like
that's kind of you know I mean nobody I
don't think anybody likes that kind of
business and I don't think that you know
they seem like good business people so
hopefully that suggestion helps
okay
stuff this one full because it's a big
in
got most of the sticks out I could
and again here you know this thing does
I in the last video I said that it's you
never have to clean it because I'm an
idiot and I don't know why I thought
that no one ever told me that it doesn't
say that anywhere but you do have to
clean it but it also like I cleaned it
super fast super super fast it comes
apart super fast it cleans super fast
because it's not like trying to get
between a whole bunch of teeth it's just
really easy scrubbing with the brush and
Bam you're done so Props on that
because that was a main point of biting
this grinder was um ease of use and I
really I kind of was sold on the fluffy
texture you know I kind of love that
like that fluffy texture I thought it
was like what I've ever seen me look
like this with this ground
so you know for people who like joint
stews it's just perfect but I smoke
bowls and it's it's
yeah it's Prime really good for ripping
and like vaping
most people know what ripping is but
yeah vaping
essentially and here's the final one
okay let's see if it will adjust ever
there we go
extra fluff watch
growing
it's growing
it's alive
it's fun right
now it's really cool though extra fluffy
um
it's a great grinder it's a lot of money
though at this day and age like
weed people don't have expendable money
like we used to
um believe it or not there was a
collapse in this industry so
um at the price point of like 150 bucks
for a grinder I don't know how many
people will actually buy this right like
um being realistic like that's a lot but
I don't know any other Grinders that
offer the same thing at the same time so
it's like
at this moment like if you want really
nice fluffy you know juicy tasty weed
it's a great option and um it's
available I believe the website is
flowermillusa.com and on Instagram
they're Flour Mill USA
um yeah
I like it I'm stoked on it
um
and you know I I don't know if it has a
lifetime guarantee and you'd go look
back but if it did I'd be even more
stoked because that would make it
definitely worth it if you didn't have
to buy another grinder or if something
went wrong with this one and they
replaced stuff that would be cool I'm
not saying they do so don't quote me I'm
just saying if they did that would be
cool because I know other places do that
uh for similar price points and yeah
that's uh
that's a review on this so hopefully you
liked it go check out riotsseeds.com for
all your femini seed spray and Seed
needs uh syndicategear.com if you want
to check out our breeder Syndicate
apparel merch stickers All That Jazz and
yeah usually every Saturday
1pm Pacific we usually have our shows
then so always pay attention to our
YouTube around that time cheers
want more Syndicate check out our
patreon in the description below
thank you for joining us on this journey
we are forever thankful that enough
people watch us to keep us going with
that in mind you can show your support
for the show by liking subscribing and
sharing the show we don't advertise so
we need you also hit righteats.com and
syndicatecare.com to show more support
for the show
kick over the statues and bring it back
to the farmers
[Music]