[Music]
where the [ __ ] is it
um
there we go
I just had to play this again I'm gonna
Force everyone to watch it because it's
real funny before I started
when I was in high school
I tried to activate Straight you know
play football
[Applause]
I remember the time at the football
party in high school
and jerk off in the same groom through
[ __ ] story I was there were you there
I was there I was there I was there I
was there I thought this is
I just
died
a bunch of dude
I'm at the same time jerking off at the
same time I guess that's pretty straight
[Applause]
anyway that [ __ ] was funny had to play
it
uh yeah that's a fe Black Beauty with um
custom pickups in it
sounds better
so oh yeah I need to bring a NATO let's
see
what's up what's up
did you get to hear the I just want to
fit in song again I did I did yeah I was
one of the people you forced to watch it
yeah yeah I know it's really good yeah I
mean you've always been fascinated by
male bonding rituals
you know
yeah
I wish I had more hands that's all I
mean it you know make friends that way
make better friends
oh damn it let's see we're gonna get my
trying to get my little skunky guy on oh
look at that yeah there he goes
all right
here we are here we are okay
um let's see what are we gonna start off
with what do we usually start off with I
mean we usually start off maybe with
like a general overview of like what
we're actually gonna chat about I
suppose okay you know so we thought
today we would we would talk about like
different parts of uh growing and flower
and like what it means for you so we'll
try to there'll be times where maybe
we'll get a little technical but we'll
try to make it topical and bring it back
to stuff that uh because there's a lot
of different ways of growing there's a
lot of different ways of uh you know
there's a lot of methods right yeah and
if there's anything in in weed that
leads people to religion it's the way
that I grow is the best way yeah and I
have the best pot because of this method
right and so it gets really hard to
debate any part about it because there's
so much
there's so much pride I guess yeah I
mean it's it's like art you know
everybody's got ego with their art and
if someone tells you that you know it
could be done a little bit better it
hurts something you know so yeah
definitely and you know there's there's
aspects of two of like you know one size
fits all
yeah sense of depending on what your
goals are and we'll talk about we'll
break it down into chunks whether you're
breeding or whether you're growing for
Pure heads or whether you're trying to
grow commercially on a bit larger of a
scale like there's different pros and
cons to your approach
they're not all the same so it's really
hard to be like oh I just need to learn
this one thing
and this method if I perfect it will
consistently do the best for me no
matter what I'm trying to do yep and
that's just not the case you know no
it's just really not the case you know
and then maybe we could talk a little
bit about like what those methods do to
the flower
sure and some misnomers maybe about how
and everybody thinks that like nutrition
is like the only thing
really that messes with it but there's
temperature and there's spectrum and
there's how you treat it afterwards and
all that that kind of goes into it yeah
you know
um you know and so as a result of that
there's like there's a lot of there's a
lot of people trying a lot of good good
ways to grow cannabis that they're not
putting all the pieces together yeah you
know I one of the most common questions
I get uh in relation to nutrients and in
feet is
um when people email me about a specific
strain they'll ask like Hey how do I
feed it what's it like and and I try to
explain to them the difference between
like you know it depends it all depends
I don't even know what expression you
know you're going for I don't know what
expression the plant's going to give in
the first place in your environment so
it's really hard to tell people how
you're going to feed because it's not
just strain dependent it's it's
individual plant and individual rooms
dependent and I think it'd be a good way
to illustrate it talking about matters
it's like trying to be like well this if
you just do this like you can pick up
any woman you want yeah you know this
this this dating method is just 100
effective yeah and doesn't take the
other human being into account you know
and I also thought like this is this is
a little esoteric but there's like a
there's this really cool book
um by this he writes the New York Times
or whatever and his name's Michael
Pollan uh and it's called the Botany of
Desire yeah yeah it's a great book and
documentary and it's a it's a um you
know it's like a plant's eye view from
the world so I thought maybe too like we
rarely talk about like what cannabis or
hemp or whatever wants yeah like what
it's trying to do and what it's going
for because in order for us to get what
we want
right we have to play with what it's
doing yeah to convince it to give us
what we're after yeah because what it
wants isn't necessarily what our end
product of smoking it is no and I mean
in some cases you know like I mean
basically it's most basic level uh the
plant wants to mate create seed continue
the progeny of itself
uh it has zero interest in creating good
smoke for us yeah that's not seedless
seedless is failure genetically to it
yeah
um and so there's a bunch of stuff that
that plays into that
you know and we just thought that you
know like we I I you know we we listen
to a lot of these things we hear a lot
of discussions and mostly what I see is
a bunch of people no offense I'm not
trying to piss anybody off but like
patting themselves on the back for what
method they've chose yeah and that's the
superior method and people aren't really
interested in hearing different opinions
about things too much yeah you know
there's yeah it's so it's it's very like
it's very cliquish it is very cliquish
whether you're assault farmer or you use
bottles yeah I mean right there like
bottle people or you know that's that's
kind of faux pas right now organically
you know like not only Organics but no
bottles organic yes no bottles no
bottles knf living soil you know full
salts synganic uh you know there's all
the I even you know all these different
things play into it and then like and I
you know I mean I think that there's I
think that there's a lot of
misunderstanding that goes into all of
it yeah right and so you hear all these
there's all these talks I'm not going to
sit here and say that I'm some you know
there's other more intelligent people
that can talk about like the Pure
Nutrition aspect of it I can give a
general overview that will probably work
but mostly what we're talking about is
like end results
and how to manipulate your plants to get
what you want yeah right and there's
different goals and it's not all the
same yeah I mean like like I've talked
about this a lot in the past uh choosing
for selection
um a lot of when I choose a plant for
selection or for Keepers I'm I'm
choosing a plant for Keepers for
breeding you know whereas someone
someone else's keeper may not
be that because they're looking for an
immediate production plan that has all
the traits they want right there I want
something that's going to have the
traits that it passes down as opposed to
what it's showing up in itself you know
yeah Neville and so the old timers used
to talk about that that sometimes the
breast the best breeders were not the
plant that they would put into
production from that same line oh yeah
yeah very different things there could
be there could there could be they could
be the same and they could also just end
up being different we end up breeding
with production plants yeah because
those are what survived yeah
for the most part you know uh you know
trying to you know it's not like there's
a bunch of even amongst Traders and
collectors like ourselves
we're not you're not trading old males
yeah right no no but you're not getting
like oh that's the 98 male of this and
this you know like no no that doesn't
you're lucky if you're lucky if like you
know you'd get a female from that long
ago yeah
yeah I don't I don't think I've ever
heard of anybody keeping old males like
that from uh the Dutch days
no I mean some people some of them do
but they're certainly never going to
trade them for you they view them as
like the Bedrock of their company oh so
much G13 Hayes Mill that's one that's
one that did make it out now that I
think about it yeah but yeah rare yeah
very rare rare you know one example now
with with STS and stuff like that it's
even become more rare because they've
eliminated the mail in a lot of cases
yeah so I don't know maybe we could give
it we could start because it is a little
rambly or whatever but uh we could we
could start maybe with like what's your
goal so like I was gonna break it down
basically into like three like big
chunks right yeah there's like growing
for you which is basically trying to
make it as heady as possible and usually
relatively small scale then there's
growing for seed
and then there's growing at a larger
scale for uh production yeah and there's
various obvious there's various grades
and levels of that and that's a lot of
what people are faced with today in
terms of like how
um How do you scale up headies yeah yeah
that's been a major major problem for
people yeah and people are realizing
that like oh like you know this this
method that I've done for 20 years it's
worked great in my two greenhouses yeah
well now I've got six 10 000 square foot
licenses and my weed's not as nice yeah
and I think a lot of people convince
themselves at the beginning of wrecked
that they were totally gonna be able to
scale up you know like it shouldn't be
hard you know right
anyway it just didn't work out that way
and not only not only from a difficulty
standpoint but also certain things that
might be perfectly economically feasible
at a certain scale you know inputs that
you might be using or whatever
um might not scale up yeah yeah right
and the amount of liquid you're going to
go through and the amount of this and
the amount of that and the amount of
Labor it might entail yeah uh you know
and so and and so all those things all
those things play into it right so
maybe we'll just start real General and
we'll talk about like the difference
between like growing good weed and
growing for seed okay
right okay so
you know if you're growing if you're
growing if you're trying to grow for
good weed these days that means seedless
so that means you're going to trick the
plant into constantly going waiting for
pollen That Never Comes yes right and so
what you're trying to do is you're
trying to give it you know enough
nitrogen enough Badger boost or whatever
and to get it to a certain size yet it's
a flower set and then grow good flour
Harvest it smoke it that's your gig yeah
right and so that requires a certain
kind of nutrition right where if you're
growing from seed
um you're planning on pollinating it
right and then since it's going to be
making babies like seeds inside itself
you'll probably give it a lot more
nitrogen and you'll give it a lot more
of a mix
um that is is very different than if
you'd smoke it yeah I I tend to uh feed
heavy nitrogen during uh flour for seeds
uh I feed it like tomatoes a very tomato
regimen is great for seeds keeping them
healthy and viable but
um I I flip out like if people feed
sinsamila like that because it just to
me it just ruins it you know when you
just flood it with nitrogen for the most
part I mean and so maybe there's an
aspect that people should realize here
so
one of the interesting things is there's
this I'll give a plug there's this
company called Canna okay uh which is a
Dutch company that designed nutrition
for cannabis right and the reason why
they're special is that for a super long
time when people were developing
nutrition
um they couldn't test it on cannabis
because it was illegal
yeah but cannot could so can uh
um you know they they were able actually
to grow different plants you know their
cannabis different ways and then test
how the plant actually uptook nutrient
right so they had this method of like
give it just enough and nothing more
yeah
right where like I would say American
companies are more super-sized me like
we'll sell the customer way more than
they need like Advanced the 32 product
[ __ ] sweet yeah or you know General
hydroponic you know I I just mean like
the usage rates it's like go heavy put a
bunch in there right and so what happens
with you know from a plant's perspective
right
um you know plants will sit there and
what they want to do is they have no
idea that there's like humans taking
care of them really right so they want
to soak up as much food as they possibly
can within themselves so that when the
food starts to run low
they have enough left inside themselves
to like carry on the process of making
seed yes right so like back in the day
you see a lot of people they're like oh
I want to pack on weight on my flower
right and they would like give boosters
or something heavy at the end yeah and
then you just you end up with unused
nutrient in your stuff and what can I
figured out is that if you gave it at
the at the like early mid part of flower
say like week three on a 10 week strain
right then the plant would have the next
month to use up that excess yeah and
grow all that flour and boost itself and
then it would still be running out
running low towards the end yeah because
what you want is since you're going to
trick the plant and you're never going
to seed it you don't want a bunch of
that excess stored inside the plant
itself no in general no right and so
that's what happens sometimes when
people like quote unquote pump it or
they ride a high EC or they have a lot
of organic nutrition that's like their
soil's hot the plant just soaks up a
bunch
and it and it's got a bunch in there
because it's trying to make sure when it
runs out it has enough to make seed yeah
it doesn't know you're gonna make
seedless yeah so you have to like plan
your nutrition around what you're trying
to do
yeah
if a plant knew that it was going to be
seedless it just it would probably not
put so much energy into making the
little hairs you know oh yeah and I mean
you know like our buddy uh you know CSI
who grows in beds in his rooms that he
makes seed I mean he puts enough
nutrition in there for six or seven
months yeah he mostly feeds water
because he's not concerned it's really
high nitrogen it's not something he
would ever do if he was growing for a
flower for Market yeah it's like a
completely different mix and that's why
it's so bunk uh you know when he talks
about like when it fails people act like
oh well then you just got a bunch of
good heavy weed yeah no and he's like no
I got a bunch of overly nitrogen you
know we're not gonna burn the right way
like it's not going to come out heads
because it was it was a mix for seeds
for seed creation yeah you know and for
to grow heads you kind of want to give
the plan everything that it needs and
then ideally let it use up its excess
before you're done yeah
it's also why it doesn't show a lot of
pictures of the actual seed process
making because it's not pretty like to
feed it correctly to uh to to have it
making healthy seeds it's not a visually
appealing plant you know some people and
the majority people wouldn't understand
that part they don't even know it's
doing a great job of making thick
healthy tiger striped seeds that are
that are going to be good for customers
but it's not going to look pretty where
if he has different rooms for instance
that he's grow he's using to do like
seed pops and experiments yeah he's
gonna like Fino hunt and see what they
are those soil beds will be mixed at a
different ratio yeah
you know it'll be a lot less nitrogen
you know it'll be a lot more scaled for
flour
yeah you know and then you know there's
and then there's an there's there's
other aspects too where it's like plants
really are like people
in the sense that you know you've got
your friends that can eat whatever they
want and like you know and they're and
they stay thin as a rail and you get
your plants that like look at a potato
chip and get intent gain 10 pounds
plants do that same thing they eat at
different rates yeah they have different
feeding requirements they have different
root systems they drink different
and so what becomes what becomes hard is
like you know I've always thought when I
was doing bigger [ __ ]
that you're trying to put plants that
drink the same
and eat the same
in the same area
yeah right because I've had situations
where I'm burning one plant or one line
and the other line wants more food yeah
right yeah anytime I have Urkle in the
room that's going on yeah or or you know
you're trying to grow something that
drinks a lot and really fast versus
something that like drinks slower like
Kush and you don't need to water that
thing as much so you end up over
watering it to compensate you know and
that's what makes like that's that's
honestly like people dis monocropping
but that's why a lot of people like to
Mono crop yeah because you can dial in
your nutrient regimen or how you're
feeding your plant or your style
right to fit that crop like we have a
good buddy pip uh souvenir Seed Cow or
whatever and he talks about
um you know he was at our party one year
remember he was he was blown away by how
good that diesel was yeah and he said
you know it was it was you know the cut
was from him at the time and you know he
was used to putting one or two in the
corner
and he couldn't feed it the way he'd
feed a whole room of sour yeah so it
would come out nice but not perfect yeah
you know because it's one of those
things where it it had different
requirements than the rest of the stuff
he was doing
yeah so it wouldn't come out as nice
yeah sour is also one of those where
it's like [ __ ] you miss it you miss
it yeah it's very easy to miss you know
it's finicky and so
you know there's an aspect to that where
people think that there's a
one-size-fits all there's a one method
they can they can take the method they
know and apply it to anything I mean you
start to see there's these like A5 and
C5 and the cough and pith and Cuban
black Haze are starting to gain in
popularity or even GMO right yeah if
you're gonna have a plant that takes 12
to 15 weeks
you're going to have to feed it
differently than a plant that takes
eight to ten yep
you're going you're going to have to
you're gonna have to veg it for longer
you're gonna have to give it a different
mix and just so people know it's not
like the mixed dictates what happens to
the plant
the plants trying to feed on what it
wants yeah and it's either there or it's
not
and I think that's a misconception like
maybe we could talk about that for a
second where like the plant absorbs
salts yes that's what it absorbs right
so if you're feeding GH or
you know I don't know uh you know eagle
or 20 20 or you know or yeah any kind of
salt or liquid chem nutrition you're
giving it like the 17 major and macro
elements like in like an IV basically
yeah right but if you if you're fully
organic you're still feeding it those
same salts it's just they're in longer
chains so you have to get various
bacteria and and fungi and stuff to
break it down yeah make it available
right and so
like people don't get that they're like
oh you you know the plant and if you
break it if you took a perfectly derived
organic salt and a salt that GH you're
cutting edge or somebody throws in their
mix you couldn't tell the difference
under a microscope
yeah I I don't even know like even if
you were a soil scientist you could
right no that doesn't mean they're the
same thing
that's not that's not true so it's like
because like basically like you know
chem is like you know our understanding
of what the plant needs
organic is more like if you get it
perfect it gives the plant everything
that it needs and then there's a bunch
of like relationships with the with the
soil itself that like it likes and we
don't really understand
you know I have a question I have a
question for you so I I am not worldly
or knowledgeable about organic feeding
I've always been like a house and garden
Canada type dude bottles sure and that's
just what I rocked with you know
um
so when you want to force the plant to
drink what you wanted when you're doing
Organics do you just do something to
lower the ph or raise the ph to no you
have to you basically when you're doing
Organics it was I mean there's different
approaches like there's bottles like for
instance like to use the same thing
Canna biocana if you buy organic bottles
you're essentially buying things where
like the company has taken the time to
sort of like cook it or ferment it or
Brew it or whatever method yeah and
those salts are more available than just
adding raw amendments to the Earth
okay yeah so like for instance we you
know if if you were if you're gonna be
that kind of guy where you're going to
get soil and you want to amend it a lot
of times you would get it and all you
want to do is raw amendments you'd
probably get it add your raw amendments
and let it cook for a month or two
before you'd even ever use it yeah you
know
um and then because what you're trying
to do is you're trying to like get all
those all that bacteria and fungi and
everything time to break down the
organic food in there
and make it available
right because that's the issue right so
the big difference is like when you feed
salt you can guarantee that the plant
the the availability is there
yeah if the temperature is right and the
pH is right and the mix is right and
your salt it's going to get all that
food
inorganics and hoping that food is there
but it has to be at a certain pH like it
a certain pH as nitrogen can't be
carried right certain certain pH chem or
organic the the plant has to have that
pH to absorb it through its roots yeah
and certain ones like nitrogen is more
available at certain pH and yeah there's
there's a rain there's like a chart and
that's kind of why people
um they give you that range for cannabis
yeah is because you know you get five
and a half versus 5.8 or something yeah
there's going to be certain things that
are more available than in the mid sixes
and vice versa right and it's usually uh
you start out lower and up higher right
yeah I mean if you want to do it that
way so you know it's it's it's one of
those things where like if you have a
well-buffered organic soil it's probably
something you don't have to think about
okay if you know uh but it also depends
like if you've got a great soil but your
water is ph9 coming out because it's
well water yeah you might need to treat
your water to not make the life of the
microbial life in your soil harder okay
right but yeah so there's an aspect to
it where it's like you know and I don't
think most people most people look at it
it's where it's like salts are sort of
like a cheat code
you know where Organics is like the pure
way to go right and I don't well I mean
there's an aspect to that I I do think
it's true but I also think that there's
some Organics that's dirtier
than Salt
you know people think that like salt is
made in some kind of crazy lab when
really it's like mined minerals that are
refined to a certain Purity and when
you're talking hydroponic Purity that's
like one step below like pharmaceutical
grade so it's really really clean and
it's designed to run through aerial Jets
sprayers drippers all kinds of [ __ ] not
clock yeah for the most part yeah you
know
um and all and all that and so you know
it's it's low in heavy metals uh the
good ones
um you know and that's another thing too
is like when people
people started uh you know and then you
go organic right and so organic is a
label but I don't think most people get
that a lot of the organic stuff that you
get is byproducts from other Industries
I didn't know that you didn't know that
so no if you get I'll give you a perfect
example right if you get bone meal or
blood meal yeah okay that's organic by
law
but it comes from major slaughterhouses
well that makes sense the cows aren't
organic yeah they weren't fed organic
food
you could be getting McDonald's
hamburger cows yeah and your bone and
blood meal Burger King Wendy's right
think about like the biggest meat buyers
and producers and that's all mixed
together and it's all it's all the same
and there's not actually a way to
differentiate unless you're really lucky
and you know an organic farm yeah but
it's all certified organic
right is one better than the other
though like realistically so bone meal
is Ground Up Bones from cows right okay
blood meal is the juice and the sluice
that comes off the slaughterhouse floor
and they collect it and like powderize
it delicious right feather meal is the
same [ __ ] it's a byproduct from the the
poultry industry
oh I didn't know that yeah that's better
sense okay you know pulled turkey uh
chickens you know uh all the parts that
they can't sell you yeah ground up and
turned into fertilizer okay right so you
have an aspect where it's like oh I'm
fully organic
and then you end up like in the I use
bone meal and blood meal and feather
meal and this and that and you're like
holy [ __ ] you know yeah because it's
it's it's legally organic it's got the
legal label Yeah by law but it doesn't
come from organic animals blood meal
smells like girls periods it's gross
well yeah it is and you know the issue
the issue used to become too where it's
like you know when we used to be gorilla
and stuff like that or whatever uh when
I first got to California you used blood
meal or something like that and all of a
sudden you get it wet and the the
vultures smell it yeah
and they start circling or the dogs want
to get into it or a bear comes and wants
to rip your [ __ ] up because it's not
you'd go put a bunch of awesome fish
Emulsion in your [ __ ] and then you get a
black bear yeah who thinks that there's
fish and starts digging for it yeah you
know and then you're and then you're
[ __ ] you know and so
there's an aspect where it's like people
think there's a free lunch and it's like
it takes even if you're using that stuff
it takes it a while for it to break down
some of it's available quick some of it
not so much and like fish Emulsion and
all that that's all from the you know
the seafood industry yeah it's all the
it's all the brewed bits of the nasty
parts that they can't sell you some of
the some people like build the soil or
whatever you know like some people have
stopped using uh bone meal because of
the issues with cows and mad cow and
just all the chem yeah and they're
selling you fish bone meal
okay because you know because it's it's
it's still bones and still calcium and
all that but it comes from the seafood
industry because it's not quite as toxic
yeah
even though it's organic so
you could have an organic style where
you could pick all these inputs where I
would rather use Canna or Cutting Edge
yeah I would think it would it would be
cleaner to me yeah you know even stuff
that's clean like bakuano or seabird
guano right where they don't they're not
there's obviously not like Factory back
one or factory seabird yeah you know you
are destroying Habitat to get it yeah
right there for bats they're going into
caves and for seabirds they're going to
a lot of habitat and they're scraping
the [ __ ] off it literally to send it to
you yeah and you know do you know why
that [ __ ] comes from like Indonesia and
Peru and all that not America
I I don't know because America has OSHA
and you can't send a 10 year old boy
with a bucket and a shovel into a cave
that's a good point I have watched him
collected one I'm dead seriously that
shit's [ __ ] up they do it where it's
super cheap and there's not a bunch of
labor law and they'll do an industrial
style and they'll have a bunch of people
with buckets and they'll have like a
bunch of bulldozers and they'll be
[ __ ] up some huge we have plenty of
bats in America yeah yeah it's just
cheaper to get it out of Peru or
Indonesia and ship it because they don't
have to obey labor laws yeah and kids
are great workers they're great yeah you
know and there's not child labor in
there so a kid with a bucket you know
and so it's good I'm not I believe me
I've used tons of back wano and
seaburguano and stuff so I'm not Disney
I'm just saying that that's the reality
of getting it yeah yeah it's a great
nutrient I love plants from I love
Brewing teas with it and stuff like that
it's like it's good stuff but uh it's
not exactly harvested environmentally
soundly and what happens to the people
isn't the greatest thing I remember the
first time I got sent home with tea from
the hydroponic store my very first trip
got sent home with compost tea and I
really sat there wondering if I was
supposed to drink this like if it was
some hippie Brew like that I was
supposed to drink I didn't understand it
was for the plants
yeah so you know I mean back you know
now we are really in a golden age of
teas and composts and inputs and
availability I'll I'll say that like I
mean I used to work in the hydro
industry and so I I got to know how they
sourced a bunch of amendments what the
difference is in quality were and why
sir why why certain companies were
cleaner and better
yeah versus other ones that were using
cheap inputs and covering it up yeah
right and now you have a situation that
goes on it's really a bummer but it's
like there's a lot of stuff that's from
the ocean that we used to consider super
heavy right but now that they test for
heavy metals it's dangerous yeah because
it's got too much lead or too much
arsenic or too much cadmium or whatever
in it yeah you know so you could you
could be like Oh I'm using fish Emulsion
and this and that and I've got all this
amazing stuff and I even have a hook and
you're putting all this stuff in there
and then your weed PAT test high for
heavy metals yeah I mean that's why they
tell like women you're only supposed to
eat so much tuna and so much big fish
when you're pregnant oh yeah because the
Mercury because the Mercury well that
stuff is in you know you want to get
some amazing crab or shrimp or whatever
yeah it's got it in it
because they live in a bath of it right
yeah and so in some cases it's like
people are like oh
you know salt to the evil bad choice
yeah and Organics is the smooth reliable
choice and I think that that there's you
know there's like it's more complex than
that yeah and you can grow good weed
with both
you know there's a lot of organic weed
that's grown that I don't consider
that's that nice
yeah
yeah you know oh yeah yeah I've seen
some knf [ __ ] be [ __ ] wild yeah and
so maybe maybe we should like get out of
the esoteric for a bit and I'll tell a
story that like like is pertinent to
people smoking right
so I used to go I used to go to the
Oregon Country Fair okay which is right
outside Eureka it's like a famous hippie
Festival it still goes on uh it got
delayed a little bit with covet or
whatever but so I I went up there and I
was I was from Chicago and I lived out
in Cali for a few years and all that but
so I was all salt back then
because where I grew up and where I came
up like growing weed you use salt I
lived in apartments like there wasn't
you weren't like grabbing soil you
weren't you didn't have a backyard you
know like you it was like so anyway but
you move out to Mendo and it's like a
lot more it's a lot more like back to
the Earth back to the land or whatever
so there's a lot of people out here that
grow dirt and I went up there and I had
all this salt weed okay and it was like
the super skunk and the chem 91 and the
Mendo perps and you know sour uh super
dog and stuff like that and they all
loved it
and they were all super prejudiced
against kenweed
yeah but they loved my camera right yeah
and then they all grew organic
and I never knew a bunch of cats that
grew organic like that yeah and so we
were like comparing each other's weed
all the time yeah you know and so we uh
you know we we ended up you know we
ended up teaching each other a bunch of
[ __ ]
yeah right and I ended up I ended up
going and working a little bit for John
jevins who's written a couple famous
books he lives up in Willits by me and
learning as much as I could about
Organics right yeah at a time when like
Organics was very very like do it
yourself
yeah not very many online didn't exist
really like you know it was basically
you were buying raw amendments and
everything you had to do you had to do
the work yourself yeah maybe there was
Earth there was Earth Juice
yeah Earth I remember earthquakes yeah
yeah still around there was very few
products there was very few inoculants
there was very few bacteria there was
very few it was very like Byron
ingredients and go for it yourself right
yeah so I did this project for
I don't know probably four years where I
grew my favorite strains in my in one of
my rooms and most of the room was
dedicated for flower for medical right
but yeah I had a section that side by
side and the same two lights I would
grow the best organic wheat I could and
I would grow the best salt weed I could
yeah of the same strains over and over
and over again right and then it was
just for head and so I would pass out a
bunch of joints to friends of mine and
stuff like that and it would all be
blind testing and they would just smoke
and tell me what's up yeah and that
started to shock me right because
sometimes with certain strains they
consistently preferred the salt yeah
right and then the salt was so much
easier I didn't have to put all that I
mean people should know back then it's
like we made the people that taught me
like we made our own soil in like
conquer in like those concrete tumblers
you know you'd buy one of those yeah no
you know you know you buy your own
concrete tumbler and you put all your
elements and you put everything in it
and you'd Stir It Up and then you pour
it out you're wearing a mask and I mean
I had multiple friends go to the
hospital for
um fungus infections in their lungs I
bet from breathing guano
yeah so it was actually kind of
dangerous you kind of had to like eye
and mask and glove up to be because
you're working with a bunch of [ __ ] and
a bunch of animal byproducts and all
this different stuff right yeah and so I
would try to make the headiest mix I
could
yeah and I learned that like some
strains consistently people like the
organic one better
and some strains people some
consistently like the salt without any
language
the the chems and the sours uh typically
like we're easier with salt yeah uh the
Mendo perps the super skunk a few
different ones would come out really
nice organic
yeah right
um and it's not like you couldn't it's
not like they weren't good it was just
like what you preferred back to back and
I think that's really important for
people I people have been asking me a
bunch because I've been making some
posts about various historical strains
yeah really the only way to have like an
effective comparison is for you to grow
it yourself
in your environment in your room same
time
okay I'm going to get these four sour
plants yeah and I'm gonna grow them at
the same time under the same environment
right I'm not going to get it from my
buddy who grows a totally different
style and his room's different
temperature yeah I'm gonna like it
doesn't you just have to be able to see
it in the same event right so and you
can see these plants all these plants
for three four years we're all treated
the same way every time
yeah you know and and uh you know it was
and it and and so you know and I have a
bunch of obviously you have a bunch of
friends that smoke weed so you're giving
out a b joints
yeah
right and um and and trying to get
feedback and I don't think most people
ever compare Styles they're doing one
style at a time
yeah right so how do you know what's
different
right and so we were trying to figure
out like me and a few friends we were
trying to figure out well what is better
yeah what is what is and it was
surprising in the sense that you know
and there's another aspect too where
it's like you start to realize once you
start to get a little bit more educated
about it but
um indoor organic is almost never like
outdoor organic
yeah I wouldn't know so well I mean I'll
give you a perfect example to make total
sense right so indoor organic is almost
100 organic
right it's like a mixture of peat moss
and perlite and you know or or cocoa or
different things where outside maybe
like 10 of the medium is organic yeah
and the rest of it is clay or or crushed
rocks minerals are like almost 45 of
most soils
so like that's why they talk about like
there's a six inch layer of topsoil
in a lot of places and that's like your
organic matter and then underneath that
it's a bunch of rock basically it might
be porous Rock but crushed rock but
that's what most Earth is so like most
People's Organic inside is like soilless
with added amendments yeah like you'd
never find like if you took say like
sunshine number four or something and
rice holes and other [ __ ] and you add
all your amendments and you make the
super heady mix
yeah it wouldn't exist in nature
anywhere
your mix yeah it's like a cannabis
specific mix basically for an indoor
garden yeah so you never actually really
like any kind of organic inside is like
a series of compromises
to begin with
because you're not like scraping up a
bunch of native Earth
yeah and then using that
yeah I mean it's not really organic is
it well I mean you can't call it organic
anyway organic is like a federal term
yeah that's what I mean it's like I
don't even think
I don't even think legal weed you're
allowed to use the term organic yet
interesting I don't think so because
because organic is actually you have to
you have to meet Federal criteria yeah
in order to to get the organic label and
not be lying right yeah but you can't
get Federal approval for cannabis
because they still think it's it's it's
funky
yeah you know people are saying we're
getting artificial light isn't organic
right so you know and then there's a
thing too where people talk about this
is like a big keyword and I'm by no
means am I trying to diss anybody but
what does living soil mean
right you know I always assumed it meant
there were [ __ ] worms and microbial
life a bunch of that [ __ ] right but
almost all organic if it's active has a
bunch of microbial life sure you know if
you if you take home a well-made tea
from your hydro store that they brewed
fresh or you make tea yourself
you're putting in trillions of living
organisms
into your soil it's alive
yeah no it typically means when people
talk about living soil they're basically
talking about usually like a some kind
of no-till method or some [ __ ] like that
right yeah but you know but even that is
like do you know why most people use
no-till
I have no clue to prevent erosion dude
there's a lot of because if you don't
till the Earth then when the rain comes
it's not going to wash away into the
riverbank
okay does that make sense no no okay so
imagine imagine like you're on a factory
farm in [ __ ] you know somewhere like
Iowa okay and you're telling the Earth
like a foot geek you're fluffing it up
and you're making it all light and loose
and then there's torrential rain that
comes in
okay and in that runoff a bunch of Earth
washes away into the Mississippi
yeah that makes sense right okay so
that's how that's where most of our top
soil went when they talk about the Dust
Bowl in uh in in Oklahoma yeah they
tilled up all the earth and the wind
came up and it blew all the [ __ ]
Earth away
it did there was like yeah because of
the Buffalo and [ __ ] there was like 10
feet of topsoil in Oklahoma yeah and
they didn't know what they were doing
with with farming and they got a drought
and they tilled it all up and then all
these huge winds came in and they and it
washed it all [ __ ] away
so I had no idea that's what the Dust
Bowl meant that's what the Dust Bowl was
it was literally it was literally people
tilling farmland and then the Farmland
blowing away in the [ __ ] storms so
weird so
no-till is basically like this thing
where in conventional agriculture they
don't want to till the Earth and have it
blow away or rinse away in rain
so they don't they don't till the Earth
they leave it right and they just dig a
hole for for the plant but a lot of them
use conventional herbicides and kill all
the weeds
okay so no-till inside is like this guy
just commented I thought no-till was
like not disturbing the microbial
content
well that's what weed people say
for no for no-till outside it's that but
it's also a huge amount of erosion
control
but you don't have erosion problems
indoors
yeah you could till all you want it's
not like you're going to get a windstorm
that's going to blow away your [ __ ] you
know yeah that's why I was confused when
you're talking about a windstorm I'm
wondering how that applies to indoor for
no-till but that's what I mean but like
no-till was designed so the soil doesn't
fly away
yeah and then it gets applied to an
indoor environment where there's no wind
yeah that's yeah
right yeah and then you know there's
people and when I'm talking about
nutrition I'm sure how many people are
going to get all upset because I'm gonna
you're gonna start stepping on toes and
they're gonna say oh well no it's about
the layers of microbial and fungal and
this and that not disturbing them or
whatever you know yeah
um but to be honest like cannabis is a
shallow root growth plant it likes to
grow wider than it does deep yeah and so
basically what you're trying to do with
cannabis is give it a not some kind of
aerated good amount of air and water and
the ability for the roots to freely go
where they want yeah
and also a hard compact soil that's not
that's not a good job I I've also been
I've also been accused of being wider
than deep this this is uh wider than
people sometimes yeah shallow even
shallow some say shallow some would say
shallow white is all in perspective
someone say so getting back so you know
getting back to like what all this means
is that you know I I was reading some
comments from some people the other day
where they were talking about like their
friends that do no-till it works amazing
for certain strengths yeah and then
other strains they do don't respond very
well to it
or you know you have a situation like we
have a buddy up in Trinity and it's like
if you're going to do depths organically
yeah that's a lot harder than a single
season where you can give it you know a
food designed for vegetative growth for
three years of months yeah and then food
designed for Bloom for a series of
months it's not as easy organically to
like get two or three rips out of the
same thing a year
no yeah that makes sense you know and
time it perfectly for what you're trying
to do so it's like and I don't go don't
get me wrong I think organic quality
weed is like can be better than any salt
to be honest but I think a lot of people
don't get there
like Seoul has a way higher floor
there's a lot of poorly grown organic
wheat
yeah you know and it's not like they're
messing up it's it's more just like the
availability of the food isn't there
when the plant needs it
yeah
it took me years years and years and
years to finally smoke organic weed that
was really grown well organic and and to
me was as uh well-grown as anything
grown bad acid salts and that was from
um Natalie that dude kills it organic
and changed a lot of my own ego with
like thinking oh [ __ ] salts are so much
better so much easier why why waste the
time because it was it was really
special I mean it all it also depends
you know like so you know you gotta fit
and this is kind of like what I said in
the beginning where it's it's like you
know you gotta fit your growing style
for what you're trying to do
yeah of course right and that's
important because they don't all fit you
know yeah and you know if let's face it
like in today's economy with wheat
prices so cheap and you know no matter
whether you're whether you're in the
traditional Market or you're in the
fully legal up Market
um you know times are tough
right and so people are trying to get x
amount of weight per Greenhouse or per
outdoor patch or per grow room right and
so you're trying to get as much pretty
weed because people are visual as
possible
yeah right and that's not necessarily
heads I mean even back in the old
traditional days a lot of the guys I
knew that were running 50 or 100
lighters would get their heads from
people that were growing six or eight
lighters
yeah yeah that's a pretty common things
right now yeah well the other part of it
too is like back in the 215 days when
anybody with a 215 card could go to a
like a dispensary and excuse me legally
sell their herb to that dispenser right
yeah
think about that dispensary there was no
regulations there was no cost of Entry
you they bought so much garage weed oh
yeah tons too and they could just pick
based on quality yeah and guys are
bringing in weed that's like you know it
was cut two weeks ago it's fresh it's
still in the perfect form it's in Turkey
bags it's like not very regulated and
they could just pick the best and ditch
the rest yeah now with all this legality
you know a lot of times some of that
weed doesn't hit the shelf for two or
three months yeah and it's being grown
in these big salt factories or it's
being grown at a scale where like all
the little things that the ache the the
eight lighter guy could do they can
you've actually experienced scaling up
major right oh yeah why don't you talk
about that I I've never done the May
except for the big big uh reversal and
having to save those dummies [ __ ]
already flowering crop for a reversal I
had never done major major scale as far
as feeding and all that stuff and it was
it was
significantly different especially
re-veging at that scale it was insane
any you know and there's a there's an
aspect to where you can talk about this
is pretty funny because you know there
was these people that just opened up
like whatever it is like 126 acres and
in [ __ ] SoCal and they're calling it
craft right yeah yeah
everybody agrees that there's a
difference between craft and Commercial
yeah the difference is is that people
get hyphy about like when does where is
that line
yeah you know and like I said before I
used to never see the people that would
do a great Growers and doing a great job
they still would not get the same
quality weed out of their 50 or 100
lighter that we would get out of a
garage-sized scene yeah
for the most part they just wouldn't
they had way less time per plant they
weren't doing quite as many little
things that made the plants happy you
know like it was a little bit more
commercial and yeah you know and then
there's an aspect too where it's like
they um so scaling becomes hard and a
lot of times when people scale they lose
quality
so we could talk about that for a minute
too and I'm not trying to diss them but
you look at like the the jungle boys
right or some of these big you know rock
wool factory farms yeah they're doing
that because they have all these
different rooms
and relying on a bunch of hippies and
Weirdos to like hand water everything
right every day is problematic yeah for
sure so you know they're trying to
automate all this different [ __ ] and
then just like work on looking at the
data and then messing with the the
settings and the data and not looking
each individual plant right yeah and so
what they're doing is is that there's a
lot of Technology from northern Europe
um that basically is the basis of all
Hydroponics
yeah uh grodan all that they all learned
how to do all this growing tomatoes and
peppers and cucumbers and all these
vegetables for places that are shitty
like northern Europe but have money yeah
yeah and you can go there and you can
see hot houses greenhouses that have
tens of thousands of plants tens of
thousands of Lights
huge
right so you see these trick systems
that they're installing they're all
based on that
yeah
right yeah so they get all these things
and they're looking at graphs right and
they've got they've got like the
moisture meter and they're perfectly
planning the wet and dry cycles and
they're and they're you know dialing in
their their salts and everything and
it's like even the setup itself is like
a plumbing nightmare
it's so intense
and then people call their weed
cardboard
yeah right because what happens is that
you're trying to do a one-size-fits all
and cannabis actually it turns out it
doesn't like being fed perfectly its
whole life no like they've done studies
where they've shown that certain amounts
of drought stress or certain amounts of
stress to the plant
um actually creates more terpenes and
more Crystal
yeah almost like beat the hell out of
your plant no I've seen it firsthand
though straight stress like uh where did
I first learn that about it was it had
to do with uh bugs attacking the plant
and and that's why the trichomes are
there yeah bugs like bugs signal uh you
know they they signal a thing to the
plant where I need to make more THC I
need to make it harder for them to crawl
on me I need to make it harder for them
to bite me you know and yeah so you get
these perfect rooms and everything's
perfect and everything's everything's
dialed in and they're like fine-tuning
stuff and they have control over all
their parameters right and then their
weed comes out nah not that good
you know and the guy that like you know
like they got a little dry and a little
wilty a few times and they stressed here
and there a little bit like that weed
was happy
yeah there was it was better but they're
trying to grow like a reasonably good
looking product at scale
yeah and they can't have [ __ ] you
know three dozen rooms and treat it like
you have a garage
or treat it like you have one greenhouse
and no job
yeah you know you know you have a
situation there's people that you that
are on IG that are quite popular and
they they don't have that many plants
and they have a greenhouse yeah and
that's their job and you can go out
there and you can baby them and you can
give them every little thing
but then you join a legal scene and and
like you're working I don't talk very
much about what I was doing but like you
try to develop some things at scale and
you've got to water some acreage
and it's a whole different thing
yeah and it's not that easy to do
no I can't imagine you know there's so
much to go wrong a lot of people messed
up even just going from how big they
were doing just to like two or three or
four ten thousand square foots yeah
like and they started really and they
started you know really messing you know
they started really messing up
yeah you know and and so like a lot of
and that's why because because like
dispensaries can't just buy the best
weed from whoever walks in with a duffel
bag anymore yeah they were able to buy
from like a lot of small time local
gardeners
you know and the bay would get tons of
people from even L.A and San Diego were
flooded with weed from Humble and Lake
oh yeah like there was people that would
drive up to my area every week to get we
had to bring it down to the dispensaries
that was their entire gig
was to flow it right into dispensaries
and so they could they could say yes or
no to any weed that walked through their
door
right and now there's all this
regulation and there's all this thing
and there's all this packaging and
there's all this testing and there's all
this time and people are trying to learn
how to grow on a lot bigger scale
and their weed is like
yep way down
way down in quality in my opinion you
know and people are going to learn
they're going to get better over time
but right now customers are [ __ ]
because they're paying more than they
used to
and the availability uh is shittier
but at least it looks good on IG and
that and that's another thing IG [ __ ]
it all up yeah because you couldn't
sniff it or smell it or anything like
that like you you know you could just
see it
and so cookies cookies was perfectly
timed for the social media wave
yeah because it was unusually visually
attractive and very unique looking it
definitely did stand out from what was
out there yeah and now there's a whole
thing where you see so many of these
different strains and a lot of them I
think have been chosen based on looks
and testing
and they can be like not to judge it but
oh look here's Apple Fritter and it
tested 33 look how fire it looks
and then it [ __ ] is the worst term
bomb on the face of the Earth for
breeding are you smoking and everyone's
all excited because the the people that
they respect are hyping it and then six
months later you know you're like I
don't think I'm gonna buy that 70 eighth
yeah it just didn't it just didn't hit
it for me
you know what before before we scooted
far too far along I do remember there's
one thing that I wanted to talk about
and when it's uh feeding for breeding as
far as vegetative stuff one thing that I
I find a lot of bridges do when I talk
to them and it's totally
counterproductive is when you are
running cycles of different rooms in
different different strains you're
trying to do multiple projects and
they're one after the other after the
other you start learning to feed
differently to slow down the growth
to try to make room and that's not
something that's that's totally
counterproductive and counter-intuitive
but some of us have learned how to stunt
our plants and bring them out of being
stunted because it's just there's no way
to to constantly have that room to feed
in new Cycles so you know there's things
you'll do when breeding that you would
never do for production because it would
absolutely just butt [ __ ] you for for
great flour well yeah I mean if you've
got if you've got a big collection of
moms in stock then
very likely what you're doing is you're
keeping a bunch at moderate it's a small
size under enough light to like keep
them going and happy but nothing too
vigorous and then you've got a lot of
great health and then you're playing
you're planning on putting some plants
in like a vigorous very well lit spot to
get them going
because you have projects in mind for
them and you want to get very vigorous
cuttings and small plants going off them
and so there's a rotation there that
goes in where it's like a fine balance
yeah if it's hurting to to not you know
if you're someone like kale you know
like like CSI or whatever and you've got
150 different plants
in moms and then you've got a bunch of
stuff you're keeping for Fino hunting
and all of a sudden you've got hundreds
of different strains and and you might
want to slow things down on a bunch of
it yeah a Fino hunt you might want to
keep it going really slow
yeah you know and even starve it
somewhat until you see what you have
because if you start pumping it like
you're trying to pump it to get ready to
bloom a room
all of a sudden you've got jungle growth
and where do you put it all
yeah
yeah especially keeping some of the
older lines the the in all five hazes
and stuff like that you get it gets
junkly so [ __ ] fast yeah jungling you
know and then you know and and so you
have an aspect where it's like I just
thought we could talk about it from a
flower perspective too because you try
to talk to people and like the thing
that I get the most when you try to talk
nutrition is like smugness
like they want people people are smug oh
yeah yeah like they want they want to
know that I'm growing the better way
this way works you know what the [ __ ]
are you talking about I get two and a
half pounds of light everybody thinks my
meat is fire
you know and I'm not I'm not dissing
anybody I'm I'm not like that's not what
I'm trying to say I'm just trying to say
that like
very few people are doing side by sides
to try to see what methods are giving
them better weed
they're growing the same style at one
time and if they change Styles they
change it over entirely
yeah you know and so you're not really
comparing you're just and you know most
people's goals are just to sell
right so yeah there's things with
Organic like when I first moved here
there was people that had been using
their beds or using their holes in the
in the Hills or whatever for 10 or 15 20
years
and every year those things got better
and better
right because they were able to add
amendments they were able to add you
know bacteria and various things it was
alive it was like old and aged and fully
functional and work and good to go
the first rip or two probably isn't
going to be as nice as the fifth or
sixth one
okay that makes sense because it take
like you know you've heard about green
sand
you ever heard about green sand green
sand doesn't even become bioavailable
for two years after you put it in yeah
same with uh normal silica you know it's
like one year I think there's things
that are on that are fairly immediate
there's things that take two or three
months there's things that take a year
you know and so if you have aged if you
have age stuff you know like a lot of
that breaking down on availability has
happened
and yeah and the natural cycles doing it
for you but if you're starting a fresh
facility
you're going to get a bunch of raw
ingredients or whatever like you know
tossed together and you're gonna have to
amend
yeah
you know and so if you're like if if you
probably another thing is that like if
you're a small tent farmer or you're a
small garage farmer and you're just
trying to grow the best you can
don't try to copy some giant scene
yeah they are not the way for you they
are not growing as good a weed as you
could on a smaller scale you're like
you're like a hobbyist slash farmer
right yeah if you're gonna grow at scale
you're gonna try to have to figure out
how can I take the methods that I like
and scale them up
yeah you're probably going to sacrifice
some quality at scale
you know and you know and if you're if
you're trying to grow for seed then you
know then definitely you're not growing
for flour
you're probably going to want to add
more nitrogen you're probably going to
want to top dress with some different
things
you know I also like to use uh and I'm
I'm a sucker for power SI just because I
used you know regular silica for so long
and didn't understand that it wasn't
really very bioavailable for the plant
and when I started using the power SI
stuff because someone was asking about
feeding for veg moms and stuff like that
that's probably been one of the the
biggest game changers for me was that
specific additive monosilicic acid or
orthosolic acid because it makes it
makes everything so readily and
bioavailable it's just so fast how quick
it up takes nitrogen and everything that
goes along with it and I should also say
something too right like so whether
you're organic or salt
uh one of the big reasons why things
don't grow in winter is that the roots
get too cold
yeah and then the pores shrink and when
the pores shrink and the and the and the
relationship between the pressure both
in the roots and within the the soil
itself changes they can't uptake salt
so if you're feeding with 50 degree
water
and you've got and you're growing with
like Canna or you know or Athena or any
of these things people are mentioning
and it's too cold your plants are all
going to suffer because the plant's not
going to suck up the nutrition your pH
can be perfect
right but the temperature's too much for
it it needs a certain temperature range
yeah and there's also a thing too where
it's like water in the 80s holds like
half the oxygen that water in the 60s
holds
so there's actually like a window there
yeah where like mid 60s to low 70s is
probably the best ratio of like
absorbability versus Like Oxygen ratio
because the only place your plant really
absorbs oxygen is through its roots
yeah it takes CO2 in through the leaves
and it takes O2 into the roots
you know and when people over water
that's what [ __ ] the plant up is
there's no Oxygen in there
yeah
The Roots can't breathe so they drown
right
and so you know there's an aspect where
it's like if you're growing indoor and
you want to be organic
um there's trade-offs like you see these
people that are like oh they're I'm on
the 26th cycle
you know I just add various amendments
over time I just water it the bio you
know the the
organic does what it needs to do the
plant absorbs what it wants when it
wants
but then I have people that grow organic
that grow in pots and their whole goal
is to give it enough food to veg and
Bloom to where they want and then run
out of food towards the end so that the
plant starts to starve itself for
nutrition and you start getting all
those beautiful autumn colors on the
plant
yeah and then when you harvest it it's
used up all of its excess because if
you're growing knf style or you're
growing like stuff that's amended that
you just you know you're no-till and
you're never changing it well then
you're never flushing for instance yeah
and so some people are a big believer in
flush
you know whether you even salt or
organic some people want to give it just
the amount of food it needs and then
starve it yeah and some people give it
chock full food right up until the end
of flower yeah and a lot of times when
you're growing for production you know
like people the other thing is is like
when you're growing through flour and
this always used to make me laugh right
is that people want the best weed
but one yellow leaf and you [ __ ] up
you know they're looking at a bag and
they're like oh there's a little bit of
there's a bit of brown in there yeah
there's a tiny little bit of yellow you
should give me a deal yeah this is some
[ __ ] up weed and you're like no I
flushed it for two weeks it's perfect
right that's supposed to look and
they're like no no it's got some funk in
it so a lot of people will just Pump It
right up until the day of harvest
because it looks better because it looks
better to the broker that's not going to
smoke as good
yeah but it looks better to the broker
yeah and that's what they care about
they don't want the broker to [ __ ] and
start kicking the tires and try to knock
points off yeah
right and so then people don't grow as
nice of weed I mean there's even a thing
where
like you know uh I'll say this about the
chems where it's like if you grow the
dog or what people call the chem 91 now
and you take it what we all use to take
it which is about 70-ish days
it usually tests between 18 and 22
percent yeah and it knocks your head off
right but if you take it 53 or 54 days
it'll still have white hairs all over it
but it'll test 28 to 32 percent yeah and
so a lot of people that like put it on
the market they take it early
right to get that high percentage
because the the shop and the and the
distro or whatever like it's one they
don't want to give you for a 19 or 21
weed they don't want to give you the
price point that's so [ __ ] but if
it's 31 so you'll you'll see weed and
you're like I'll look at this weed and
I'll be like that dog is like two weeks
premium yeah but a test at 30 percent
and the shop is happy yeah the distro is
happy and they'll give you your price
yeah and it's not as good for the smoker
right but yeah a lot in a lot of cases
like these regulations and these new
rules are not taking the smoker into
account I mean it in some sense though
like I think smokers may have priced
themselves out just by
just by
absorbing things like cookies things
things that are you know cardboardy with
high THC stuff and they were happy with
it despite most people like when you
really ask them like do you really like
like that you know the form cut do you
really like getting high off that like
they'll be like oh it's okay you know
for 20 minutes or 10 minutes and then
it's you know whatever but yeah they
kind of let themselves be told what to
buy
you know they do and this is where we
ended up they so there's an aspect one
of the things that's interesting and
it's something I mentioned before but it
Bears repeating I guess is like the
first four or five years that they
published like the emerald cup and like
some High Times entries for THC and you
were able to see like you know before
people were breeding by numbers
before a lot of breeders were getting
data on like what you know what what the
THC content was almost everything that
was winning was between 22 and 26 yeah
there was like four or five things in
the first five years like that ever
tested in the upper 20s or hit 30. yeah
yeah right like in like in two of them
were chem 91 there was a Strawberry
Cough there was another weird one you
remember how rare the 30 Club used to be
yeah yeah it was unheard of until like
2009 10 people started claiming the 30s
30 right and so now you have this so
basically all the favorite weed that
people were paying good digits for was
coming in in the low to mid 20s at best
yeah so it basically means as soon as
you hit High Teens to mid-20s that's
where almost all the elites were falling
yeah everything that everybody [ __ ]
drools over from back then cushions
sours [ __ ] all this [ __ ] was all
hitting that range yeah and then people
started growing because shops were like
I'll pay you more for higher THC yeah so
they start selecting cuts that test
better
yeah not necessarily ones that smoke
and start selecting the labs that test
higher so now that's why I say breeding
by numbers yeah so instead of breeding
by smoke testing and what your friends
think and how long lasting the high is
like you were mentioning or how intense
it might be they start being like Oh
well this one tests at 32 and four
percent terpenes
there is no such thing as a [ __ ] high
30 yet is there
I mean
so I mean there's there's a lot of
things that people do like like uh you
know CSI have talked about this a bunch
where there's a lot of labs that over
test sure because it's good for the
distro it's good for the store it makes
an easy sale everybody likes it and so
he's done experiments where he sent
things off to commercial labs and sent
the same Bud to a friend who he knows is
going to do an accurate test and it
might be as much as five or eight
percent different
oh yeah I've seen it much different
vastly different it's insane but the
thing is is now you've got five or six
or seven or eight years ten years or
whatever breeding by numbers and there's
a huge 30 plus percent Club oh good good
skunk Master Flex posted something
that's 40 well there we go so you start
getting higher and higher right and but
then the effect sucks yeah
something like what does that matter
yeah
I had a blueberry purple punch test at
34 so you know anything's possible you
can't even pull those numbers out of
them individually you know and what's
crazy about that is when you think about
30 or 35 or 40 like Matt was just
laughing about that's the percentage of
THC by weight on the flower yes so yes
it's crazy because you start getting
these numbers and it's like is it just
going to be like
you know how much THC can you pack on a
plant yeah and how much is left for
cannabinoids and other cannabinoids and
yeah and it's not obviously like alcohol
where Everclear is stronger than vodka
which is stronger than Wine which is
stronger than beer it doesn't work like
that like there is there is a certain
situation where like you know CSI and I
see Fletch on there there's some old
school strains that only test like eight
ten twelve percent yeah and they don't
hit that hard but once you get up to 18
to 20 to 22 to 24 that's where like all
the elites and the old best weed faults
you know where most of the skunky stuff
is falling right now that we've been
looking at low teens
no
four to eight
four to eight for the most skunky stuff
I mean you know the the Mendo perps is
supposedly you know seed from the late
70s or whatever yeah
um and it tests you know eight or ten
percent at best
yeah some of the s1s can get up into the
High Teens but the mom cut itself is
pretty low
you know and I think that used to be
super common like I think even like old
school skunk one right it was for 13 to
15 back then yeah when they could get
testing done you know
um and so we've gone from like the start
of everything where things were you know
low to you know single high single
digits to low teens to Mid teens to
Upper teens low 20s yeah and now it's
all maybe it's all fake or whatever but
um it doesn't seem like after a certain
point there's a big correlation between
High numbers and best effect no not at
all
because my friend would get all pissed
off because they'd be like dude I don't
know if
I don't know if I can get your weed for
the right price this dog is only this
chem 91 is only testing at 18 mm-hmm
but it took your head off
yeah you know but they would rather take
two week preeny chem 91 because it
tested 29.
yeah
right and so I just I just think that
like people started rather the only
thing that matters is like how how it
affects you
and yes the more people get away with
effects and like not testing stuff like
by smoking it with a variety of humans
yeah because even one person two people
like some of my favorite weed is stuff
that Matt doesn't like at all yes just
not that he doesn't appreciate it it
just doesn't make him feel good yeah
yeah some of it just [ __ ] me up like
paranoid or anxiety or yeah yeah some
people get some people get weirded out
some people love a buzz some people like
sativa I mean there's a range of of
effect
yeah and so I think if you get away from
like I don't think a bunch of people are
doing smoke testing anymore
yeah they're trying to find something
that looks impressive and tests
impressive yeah right and then all of a
sudden now we have a bunch of like mid Z
Elites
yeah right
we have a bunch of Elites where it's
like people are saying oh I hate Fritter
you know like well there was a minute
there where like and people are growing
stuff because they're like oh this weed
gets this amount of pound yeah it's an
elite so I'm gonna grow lemon Cherry
gelato
there I'm gonna grow this runts by this
or I'm gonna grow this jealousy cut
because my buddies can get top dollar
for it
and I'm not trying to call it mids but
it's probably not going to stand the
test of time
no you know like like right now sour is
coming back around diesels yeah why
because it's Fireweed
and it works and it smokes and it tastes
great
yeah you know and that we weed that
works is always going to have a
popularity basis
yeah we're a weed that doesn't work you
know like you can only the hype boys can
only hype it for so long
I mean Berner can obviously sell the
[ __ ] out of anything
yeah yeah you know he's he's great at
promotion he's great at getting hip-hop
and rap and various Stars smoking his
weed and exclusive spots and building up
but he's a horrible horrible kisser I
have no idea you know don't let it lie
to you he's a liar about that [ __ ] but
there's an aspect where it's like you
can only promote something for you can
only force people to life something for
so long yeah before they make their own
decision yeah right and so that's why
that's why you have all this [ __ ] that
like gets like flash in the pan that
gets popular for eight or ten months or
a year a year and a half
yeah and then it's gone it's replaced by
some new hype yep where things that used
to get popular before like the purples
or the cushes or the sours or whatever
the Skittles when they become
organically popular
right where it's like grass roots
popularity drives it they're a lot more
lasting
yeah than when it's hyped
you know because hype has become
marketing cannabis weed wasn't weed
wasn't ready for modern marketing dude
no we weren't ready for it at all we
were so ripe to be abused by modern
advertising techniques yeah then like
you know it just got overwhelmed and
people realized oh I don't even need to
have good weed to make money ten years
ago that [ __ ] wouldn't have worked
everybody would have laughed at a
[ __ ] for trying to front that
hard you know but nowadays it's just
flies ten years ago the only way
something became Elite was when enough
people that were respected decided it
was good yeah and like or you know the
market demand or the market demanded it
yeah and the market really when it boils
down to it when you have stuff like the
purple wave with the Urkel and the Mendo
p and the Grape Ape and all those and
Granddaddy and all that or you have the
cush wave in Southern California or the
sour thing that happened for 10 years
that was Market dictated a bunch of a
bunch of people wanted to get as much of
it as they could yeah because they knew
that the customers would endlessly buy
it and they didn't get burned out yeah
that's why you can have 40 different
[ __ ] named cushions in SoCal yeah I
was trying to name them all the other
day and like made me want to pound my
head against that because oh there's
literally like you could walk into in
you know 2010 you could walk into a
dispensary in LA and they would
literally have like two dozen kinds of
kush oh easily some of them had like 50
60 different types of OG's yeah yeah all
these different names on some of them
were repeated and just somebody of
course they just had different names
yeah but yeah like the entire dispensary
was one family a wheat and slight
variations yeah you know and you know
from the east coast and different things
coming to California sour was like
endless
yeah it was endless demand for gas
you know and now instead of seeing
endless demand for one or two things
that people can focus on a lot of
Growers are like what the [ __ ] do I even
grow yeah because if you're in the legal
Market
you don't have a direct connection with
your consumer
you have to get a distro and uh unless
you own them you have to get a distro
and then a dispensary to buy it
I remember red
um up in Canada talking about that with
the the Canadian legal stuff about now
they have the buyers or or people that
aren't even from Cannabis now and they
are who determine what value you're
getting for your weed non-smoking oh
yeah corporate people honestly that was
a depressing part of that I really liked
that interview he was super personable
yeah that was hard to listen to uh just
the just the reality of what matters and
what doesn't yeah and him looking at at
testing and paperwork and deciding what
to do without even seeing the week
because if it didn't have the testing
and the paperwork right it was
irrelevant yeah it just didn't matter
and so a lot of times okay there's a lot
of stuff out there that's really
Fireweed and the reason why you can't
get it is because it doesn't make
Financial sense for the grower to grow
it because the people that are in
between him and you don't want to do it
yeah so you get [ __ ] you personally
out there you get [ __ ] because the
Growers friends get to have it
sometimes you know it gets traded
amongst each other it gets survived and
all that you know but the consumer
doesn't get to see it yeah you know and
we were joking I'll mention it one more
time because there's there's this you
know huge grow that's getting set up in
SoCal it's like over 100 acres and
everybody was ragging on them or
whatever because it's like another big
corporate takeover type thing right yeah
and you look at their clone list and
they're getting a bunch of gelato
hybrids and Skittles hybrids
right like the market is under
underserved right now with gelato and
Skittles yeah they really got to fill
that niche
yeah of course not you know and so and
you know if if customers could buy
straight from the farm or straight from
cooperatives or whatever you know then
cooperatives would be able to grow more
Niche weed
you know and be like oh I'll do some try
to get some real Bubba Kush
yeah try to find some real Sour Diesel
try to find some Urkel try to find you
know they should be with legality all
the classics you should be able to buy
Led Zeppelin
in the in the in the record store oh I
was like what Digger Led Zeppelin I just
mean imagine like you're like oh no it's
not popular anymore you weren't around
the 70s you can't buy it oh yeah yeah
like legal weed there should be a thing
where it's like all the hits if we're
gonna compare it to music right you can
go get all kinds of punk that's like way
out of date
yeah but you can't get Acapulco Gold
yeah I can't get Urkel you can't get you
know G13 nl2 you can't get you can't get
the classics of wheat
right and so right now California itself
is a wash and all this candy name
[ __ ]
right which is fine if people want to
buy that stuff it's fine I'm not not
trying to throw it out there but you
can't
you know like you know it it can't all
be sure bellato
why can't I hit his though it is why
can't I get real Sour Diesel why can't I
get real push why can't I get Trinity
why can't I get Bubba Kush yeah why
can't I get Granddaddy Purple
yeah you know because because there's
there's like you know consumers don't
have power
to demand they have to go to the store
and they have to buy what the store
wants to put in their store
yeah
you know and that that might be getting
chosen based on their margin
there's this company up by me [ __ ]
floccana right they blew through a [ __ ]
ton of money do you know I don't know if
people know this but like there's a lot
of big companies that pay dispensaries
for shelf space
yeah straight self space shelf space
like be you know and that and that's a
profit they make just to put the [ __ ]
the weed on the Shelf so the consumer
can see it
you know in the 50s or in the 60s or
whatever there was that huge record
Scandal because everybody all the DJs
disc jockeys it was pay to play oh yeah
the Paola yeah so how did how does your
how does your hit get be popular if you
can't get a radio station to play it so
people hear it and they want to go buy
your album
yeah and there's people that were
getting bribed to play certain things
and not play others
yep I'm connecting it to music again but
it's the same [ __ ] thing these
dispensaries because there's not enough
of them they're deciding what gets on
their shelf and not and they're deciding
it what's based on what's good for them
yeah not what's good for the consumer
out there what's good for them
yeah you know so choice is actually gone
down
quite a bit quite a bit expenses up
quality is down choice is down and how
do you how do you like let's say that
that you know CSI or somebody like or me
or whoever Fletch comes up with an
amazing new hybrid yeah
right unless you're vertically
integrated and you can control the
supply chain you can't even guarantee
you're going to get it in a shop
oh yeah you can't guarantee at all that
a bud tender will give a [ __ ] yeah
you know so it's like a whole Deluge of
like everything that's already already
popular
and variations on that theme
you know and it gets controlled and so
the reason why I think that all these
Elites from I always talk about like the
90s and the early 2000s are still my
favorite era of weed is it's because the
best weed from then was consumer choice
sorry I just read that question popped
up after everything we said and I was
just anyway yeah anyway but you know but
yeah that you know it it all the you
know sour became popular Kush became
popular because people wanted it they
were willing to spend a bunch of money
on it there was demand and yeah you know
and and people wanted to fill that
demand
yeah and now it's like oh it's you know
it's here's a bunch of here's a bunch of
weed and with nurseries people might not
know this but most most like cultivators
they don't even get to keep their own
mom house they have to get it from a
nursery
that's so wild and then the nursery
might offer 10 or 15 different things
for this season
they might have a hundred things but
they're only they only mommed up enough
to do like a lot of certain stuff
yeah so then you're you're forced to
operate off their menu
so it's like the nursery limits you
right like when I was working in a big
scene a couple of years ago I was trying
to find some some real Sour Diesel like
on the legal Market metric yeah
and I couldn't find it pure
of course the best thing I could find
was spyrox Sour which was some Sour
across the some kush
I couldn't find it pure to grow on the
farm I was Consulting at yeah you know
but back in the day in 215 you could be
like oh we're gonna fill these four
greenhouses with this yeah and then
we're gonna take duffel bags to The
Dispensary
and then you're gonna buy it
people are gonna be stoked
64 ruin the [ __ ] world most of most
of most of uh most of the good cushion a
lot of the Good Kush that was in LA came
from my neck of the woods
yeah there was constantly Brokers coming
up that their entire job was just to
grab excess capacity from up here and
bring it down to the the SoCal you know
dispensaries
yeah you know and and so people could go
hunt the best weed
and then go me and then the BR and then
the you know the the uh dispensaries
could pick the best week if they wanted
to
yeah now it's like they have to buy it
from a dispense they have to buy it from
a distro and the distro has to buy it
from a farmer and it just turned
everything into like a commodity
yeah
you know and so as a result of that
everybody I never thought I was worried
about a bunch of [ __ ] with legalization
I never thought that like we would
accept way higher prices than the black
market or the gray market and shittier
quality
yeah but so far that's what we've got
yep sure is
you know that's what we've got and so
you know we started off talking about
and the reason why we've gotten that is
because you have all these
commercial Farms that have intense
pressure with taxes and overhead and
regulations and paying out all this
[ __ ] money right and quality and
consumer happiness is like they do the
best they can in some instances but it's
not that great
but they're doing the best they can with
the constraints they're put under
yeah and a lot of little things that you
used to get done to make weed nice is
getting eliminated
yeah and so your weed isn't as nice
you know and people talk about all the
time your weed is fire your weed's not
fire
yeah you know and a lot of times it's
like some of these things like the
emerald cup and all this different [ __ ]
you know
like and I'm not saying this I've known
Tim for a long time so this isn't a
distant him and on any level but
when you're forced to basically like for
the most part only accept from like
licensed buyers
people aren't entering the best weed in
California anymore
no no
because you have to cut off this large
segment of the population that used to
win [ __ ] cups
yeah that used to be able to come there
with their perfectly grown Greenhouse
weed
from their little Greenhouse that they
treated perfect and they got to give two
for two to four ounces to the testing
and then they placed third
yeah oh but you know but but the thing
is the difference Fletcher's like stop
[ __ ] on my weed the difference
between Fletcher from what like from
archive from what I understand is that
they have a dispensary
yes they have control archive can make a
choice to I'm like I'm gonna take the
moonbow I'm going to take this that I
love and I'm going to make sure
consumers get it
yeah
right
so but most performers most farmers in
California aren't vertically integrated
yeah they have to sell their they have
to sell their week
you know and so if you're vertically
integrated then you can have some
uniqueness and you can choose like he
could choose to take things that he
doesn't want to share
and you can only come to his stores to
get them
it's no fair [ __ ]
you know and and a lot of people are cut
off and a lot of people's top shelf yeah
dispensaries top shelf used to be six to
twenty lighters
yeah
you know done by small-scale people
and that was constantly filling the top
shelf because that was the top shelf
yep now all those people are [ __ ] cut
off
and what used to be the Mitzi shelf is
now top shelf for more money while those
people are looking for new [ __ ] jobs
you know and so a lot of the best weed
got cut off from consumers
yeah you know before they could even
smoke it
you know you can't like I don't know you
can't you can't get real Haze in
California
yeah
no
you can't get real Sour Diesel it's
starting to make a comeback maybe it'll
start forcing itself on some shelves
yeah yeah
but there's only but then there's all
this stuff too where it's like these
vertically integrated companies like if
you're gonna get from Jungle boys or
whoever you're probably going to get
mostly their weed that they're growing
because they want to sell their weed
through their Outlet
yeah
two so then you know you get the
selection from them
you know and a lot of these dispensaries
have captured markets
so yeah what you're getting is you're
getting a lot of commercially grown weed
that they're trying to grow for cheap
and get a minimum level of quality
and then you're trapped because you can
only there's only you know 700 stores in
California
you got to buy it in one of them and you
can't really get great deals so you end
up like getting a bunch of expensive
commercial
yeah and that access to that actual top
self top shelf that actual fire that was
treated deliciously and grown perfectly
with organic or salt or whatever and all
the little things done the right way
yeah you don't even get to see that
anymore
yeah like you know what's funny is uh
all these American beer companies were
never winning any any beer Awards
did you know that right no so these all
these like International competitions
obviously like Michelob and Milwaukee's
best and Budweiser and all that were
never winning any gold medals at any of
these at any of these competitions the
Beast wasn't winning medals no so they
made their own
they made their own category American
lager
oh now so now a bunch of these companies
have gold medals
because they were only [ __ ] competing
against themselves
yeah right when they were competing
against other micro breweries and places
from Belgium and Germany and all that
[ __ ] they had no chance yeah their beer
wasn't as good
yeah right so now you're getting the
same thing here where you're getting all
these big factory farms and they're like
do you want old style do you want Old
Milwaukee do you want Michelob do you
want Budweiser do you want cores
yeah you know like oh you want some
heady how about some Heineken
yeah maybe some Amstel Light get an
import
right and that's what they're you're
competing against you'd actually can't
get these little you can't get these
little things where the quality really
matters and until they open that stuff
up so if you're growing for yourself
I said it before don't emulate some big
farm
yeah they're cutting corners
they're doing things that only work at
scale
mm-hmm you know uh and and all that
right like do things there's there's a
there's a I mean it's I don't want to
get too technical because I'm trying to
keep it General enough that like uh you
know it it stays fairly popular because
I don't know how many people are actual
Growers on this thing versus just
smokers or whatever but yeah
um but yeah it's it's it's there's an
aspect where it's like plants don't
drink the same
it's really hard to like just automate
everything
and there is micro climates even like
yeah reversing a shitload how how one
clone to the next clone won't reverse
the same way even if they're two feet
apart from each other or a foot apart
from each other getting the same exact
feed microclimates are a real thing too
so yeah and some of those big rooms the
micro climates are really different yeah
you know and I mean we haven't even
talked about Spectrum but yeah that has
a big roof you're not growing with with
the sun
um one of the best lights to this day is
still the single-ended old school
horoluxe thousand
a lot of these grown under double endeds
and stuff like that like a lot of them
people are choosing spectrums that give
the most weight
yeah and not Blends that give a better
quality
yeah
you know uh and because because we're
not in a position yet it's like such a
regulated and taxed industry that the
best isn't allowed to Bubble to the top
yeah it's controlled buy dispensaries by
dispos by burner by people popularizing
things by celebrities stepping in and
people throwing their money around and
so that's why that's why if you're if
you're bummed at how your the weed sucks
in clubs that's why
yeah
because consumer Choice has gone way
down since 2 15.
we are at an hour and a half right now
dang people always want to be winding it
down we could start doing the [ __ ] you
want to take some questions or I could
take some questions I mean I could talk
to maybe I'll talk for five or ten
minutes even though we're winding it
down because I haven't uh I haven't
talked about it but aside from nutrition
and environment which we kind of talked
about a little bit before
um the spectrum that the plants grow
under makes a big difference
yeah and that could probably be its own
whole show but just in general plants
developed underneath the sun which has
all the Spectrum all the time everything
from UV to you know every color huge
where most indoor lights are
approximations of that and they have
relatively narrow spectrums yeah right
and you put Plants underneath them and
they grow vastly differently depending
on what kind of light they're exposed to
yeah we used to 20 years ago when there
wasn't all these other lights we would
grow one light of metal halide and the
buds would come out half the size
but they would burn better and they'd be
way frostier than the HPS stuff yeah now
you see all this stuff with Ceramics and
LEDs and this and that and everything
else and it's like
different plants some plants respond to
like a different different types of
light and do well regardless some plants
do phenomenal under one type of light
and then you like you move them and you
think oh I'm going to put them under
this and it's going to do great and then
they hate it yeah because they're not
getting sometimes you'd see people where
they were growing all these straight
hps's and then they'd have straight up
old school metal halides like hanging
from the ceiling yeah you mean the
vertical ones yeah vertical just just to
give but I just mean I still got scars
from those [ __ ] but just just to give
a different Spectrum like not to be the
majority of it but just the shine some
blue yeah so the plants had that to use
and you remember like the Crusty buckets
yeah that guy's that guy swore if you
didn't have 25 metal halide light you
couldn't get those kind of huge plants
yeah he swore if you if you had all HPS
you get you get shittier wheat yeah in
order to get the size and the frost you
needed some blue yeah and that's
partially why the old HPS single endeds
a lot of people considered them to be
the best all-around light and they were
the standard because they had 25 percent
more blue
yeah you look at their Spectrum versus
like a double-ended right now that's HPS
and the HPS is almost all orange and red
yeah very little UV very little and so I
have a bunch of plants like my headband
and my sours and dog and stuff you know
and you grow them under different lights
I groove that I grew the dog once under
pure ceramic yeah I cut it at 85 days
and it still had white hairs
yeah and you know what's weird is that I
agree the dog [ __ ] under that same light
and it finished two weeks earlier than
it normally would
with a different Spectrum yeah with the
with the CMA normally the dog [ __ ] would
go 12 or 13 weeks yeah I grew it under
pure 3100 ceramic metal halides it was
done in 70 days every hair turned fully
ripened I've got beautiful pics of it
it's shaved two weeks off but the same
Spectrum made the dog go two weeks
longer than I've ever taken her yeah
that's funny I've never taken the dog 85
days in my life dude yeah
you know she's she's 65 she's 63 to 70
and she's pretty done yeah and when I
finally cut her and I gave up tons of
white hairs all over
yeah so you know maybe like as a as a
final thing if you're trying to grow
heads Spectrum plays a big deal food
plays a big deal your style definitely
helps and like less is more
yeah in a lot of ways like just enough
and nothing more is a better style than
like let's give it way too much and pump
it let's supersize it let's get hot you
know let's run hot
um you know I don't that's not gonna
that might give you better weight but I
doubt it'll give you better better wheat
yeah you know and so and that's a lot of
times like what what it happens is like
like whether it's drying or curing or
growing or your nutrition or your
environment like growing the same
strains over and over they're your
favorites and learning why some rips
they come out amazing yeah and some rips
you're like eh
you know yeah because even good Growers
get they get the ant runs oh yeah
yeah I mean honestly people people are
still using [ __ ] other than LEDs I think
LEDs have come a long way I'm still not
convinced they're better than a blend of
other light
I still never
tried LED lights so if any LED light
sponsors want to sponsor I'll give it a
[ __ ] try but I I tend to like CMH
quite a bit do I think that LEDs are
great for for various aspects of heat
and do I what do I have I started seeing
a lot of nice weed under them and did
they have good applications I do
but I still think some of the best heads
you can ever grow are often old school
hortiluxe single-ended bulb yeah
you know
a lot of award-winning weed and a lot of
fire came out of that yeah the whole
indoor sour era the whole indoor Kush
era the whole indoor uh purple era all
grown under those bulbs you know I
always hated [ __ ] horror Deluxe that
is they had a chick that was running it
and they were so anti-fucking cannabis
it was [ __ ] how anti-cannabis that
company was and how much money they made
off cannabis Growers yeah I mean it's
it's well you know there's prohibition
it's it's it's dangerous there's a like
we could wind it down but I'll tell a
story so I live in Mendo
and one time
uh I was friends with the uh I was
friends with the produce guy at our
Safeway and there was one point in
Willits where that Safeway sold more
organic produce than any Safeway in the
country yeah because there was so many
[ __ ] of us
right it was just unbelievable so this
guy he tells me this funny story of this
guy from Reynolds comes in
right because this Safe Way was the
number one selling turkey bag store for
Reynolds turkey bags in the entire
country we were number one he couldn't
believe it they came out there to figure
out
what the hell is going on why are people
cooking so many [ __ ] turkeys why are
people cooking they had no idea they
were like this Zone
we have more like can we spread what
we're doing here to other parts because
our sales are through the [ __ ] roof
you know yeah and when they find out it
was all for weed like the dude's face
just you know he was just so bummed
right but it was it was like because
back then you couldn't get like turkey
bags and 50 or 100 packs like you can
today yeah you would have to go to the
store and like the turkey turkey they
came in like two or three packs yeah
yeah so if you had you know an indoor
and 20 pound you'd buy 10 bat 10 boxes
yeah and you're at the store you know
it's like buying like Lube or something
like that you're like you want to get
other [ __ ]
what I never got the turkey bag [ __ ]
thing because it's not like it really
kept smells
like it was the standard it was it was a
bag to fit a pound you could tie it and
like the thing is with fluffy weed if
you didn't get the bigger turkey bag you
could not have enough of a tail to make
a knot
yeah off a full pound so like where do
you get a bag that can fit a pound
yeah that's a good point that's a very
good point you know and it's like you
grow kush or something or you know Urkel
you're gonna get a a tight pound
yeah right you grow Diesel and it's
going to be like a a tall pound yeah you
know so there's an aspect to it where
it's like it just became the standard
and one days of fighting over [ __ ]
sizes of bags and weight
yeah and and so the amount what's crazy
is that like will the will it Safeway
learned and they just had I mean they
would just they would they would just
buy immense amounts of the [ __ ]
all the time it was like such a huge
seller for so long because there wasn't
eventually companies started making
where you could go to the hydro store
and you could buy like 25 or 50 or 100
and it was like something you could
purchase there and not be so embarrassed
but yeah you had to back in the day you
had to just go into the grocery store
yeah that's where you [ __ ] got it you
know yep and that's how it fit so
um so yeah I guess we've been on I mean
we've been I the reason why we wanted to
chat about this is because we thought
that uh and we could get deeper into it
so you can always reach out to us on our
Discord which model plug or you can
reach out to us on IG or whatever but
there's a lot of different strategies I
didn't want to nerd out too hard
but there's a lot of depth to what kind
of weed you're trying to grow and what
your goals are for it right and how you
want to feed it and how you want to
treat it and it matters you know and so
don't just look online at someone you
think is killing it
and just feel like oh I figured it all
out I don't have to ask any more
questions I'm good I'll just replicate
this one method that I know all I need
to know
yeah because a lot of times there's a
lot of issues with them
you know so you know
um
so yeah I mean Matt I'm I'm not very
good at doing the plugs Matt do the plug
on the Discord and the whatnot you got
it so
um our Discord you have to go to Google
type in breeders Syndicate patreon and
that's how you find us uh we have our
Discord we have all kinds of uh
additional features at the Discord that
we can enjoy together
um we're always there shooting the [ __ ]
talking [ __ ] around posting pics just
being obnoxious I mean I'm being
obnoxious under I try to be as obnoxious
I can be and um we have rights eco.com I
promise I'm gonna get the Hawaiian
lights hybrids up there's only three up
right now
um we were having problems figuring out
why they weren't displaying and
hopefully they'll that's fixed I think
so hopefully those will be up there and
you can grab them this weekend my
apologies for being late week
um or two weeks maybe I think
um what else is there uh Speakeasy seed
bank all of our friends are on there go
check it out go show support and also
unplug two after years of not dealing
with it
I'm my follower list
and I accepted thousands of new people I
also rejected a [ __ ] ton of people so if
you got rejected uh maybe who knows
maybe I was in a bad mood maybe you
didn't have enough posts maybe whatever
you can always message me and say hey
dude I listen add me you know I'll try
to keep up on it from now on we're gonna
try to create more content
um basically we're just trying to shoot
the [ __ ] about culture history and
growing better wheat
yeah and so you can always ask us
questions you can always hit us up uh on
IG if you have ideas for shows that you
might want to talk about maybe it takes
us a while to get them but
um you know we want to talk about what
you want to hear
you know and and so you know some of
it'll be can be user generated you can
always ask us longer questions and get
better responses
um on the discords you know and we talk
about various subjects and things like
that and it's easier it's easy to get
there so you know uh we're trying to do
our best we're trying to do a little
different podcast than most or you know
live or whatever and just basically like
you know just have it be like a little
bit about culture and life and growing
in a mix so yep you know thank everyone
for listening on their Friday night
we'll be back again same time same place
all that yep and uh you have anything to
add no I think that's it well everyone
have a great Friday night thank you so
much enjoy your evening