prepare yourself
[Music]
hey everyone matthew wright here host of
the breeder syndicate podcast and
founder of riot seed co
big thanks to our patreon members
patreon is why we can make this podcast
if you enjoy listening please visit
patreon.com breeder syndicate and join
our community to help make sure new
episodes happen we can't do this without
support from our community
click the link in the show notes of this
podcast episode for more information or
visit patreon.com breeder syndicate to
join
[Music]
hey everyone matthew wright here host of
the breeder syndicate podcast and
founder of riot seed co i just released
a new feminized seed making system
called riot reversal spray by our good
friends over at speakeasy seed bank
right reversal spray is my own personal
formula that i've used to create
feminized strains for over a decade now
i can honestly say it is the best
ethylene blocker for dioecious plants
that i've ever tested if you ever
thought about creating your own
feminized seeds this is the product for
you
click the link in the show notes of this
podcast episode for more information or
visit riotreversalspray.com to place
your order
[Music]
[Applause]
riot seeds podcast coming soon
[Music]
you