second verse same as the first see if it
works this time
i don't know
don't know what the [ __ ] happened it
just shut down my live feed all of a
sudden so we'll see we'll try it again
and uh see if when natsu joins us and we
might have to switch to the other
account i don't know what's going on
let's see
hey it worked we got the boot
yeah i got the boot it was real [ __ ]
weird so we'll see if it happens again i
don't know what happened
i don't know i'm just too pretty for
this [ __ ] sometimes i think it's
probably what's happening indeed
yeah
indeed so i'm gonna do a giveaway at
some point tonight and we'll have to
figure out how to run it
but i'll probably leave that up to you
because it's much easier to put it off
on you to figure out how to do the
giveaway
figure it out indeed yeah
all right we already got 114 116
something like that so whenever you want
to kick it off we can i mean the
funniest thing is because i have to do
that because i do this [ __ ] on my phone
yeah
like if i sit back
this far
right yeah
i can't see any of the comments
you also could potentially be getting a
[ __ ] off-camera it could happen i
suppose but then they
you know they did but so then if i want
to see what people are saying then i
have to make my head like take
the the full frame
you know
it is what it is on it it is what it is
so yes we have blue bonnet available
uncle brizzy it's on uh rightseepco.com
so yeah i guess we are getting we are
getting up there yep or whatever
um so
do you know actually i
i don't even know why this stuck in my
head but i can't remember what it's
called because it's russian and i have
terrible pronunciation
yeah but they used to do they used to do
this gambling thing where like there's a
bunch of dudes sitting around like a
huge table right
and there's like one chick underneath
giving head to someone
and you have to figure out who it is and
if they can tell you're getting it you
lose a bunch of money
so there's all these dudes with their
pants off and they have to sit there
like all stoic
yeah i know i think that's bad i'm the
one under the table oh my god down there
yeah sounds like falls
indeed it's it's a trust situation
it's a trust situation yeah you know i i
often speaking of russian i often refer
to
when you
go to to expel a fart and you're not
sure if it's fully loaded and you're
going to have some blow back i refer to
that as russian roulette russian
roulette yep i hope i know the chamber's
loaded i hope that i i i make it to old
age where that's just not a worry
yeah not everyone has the same worries
you know i have i have that worry at
this age
no good you get a unique collection of
worries that are just yours
you know they might not pertain to
everyone else
so
you know
um
anyway uh yeah we got enough people here
we can start or whatever thank you
everybody for joining again on friday
night um we have kind of like a
uh
a little collection of stuff we were
going to talk about tonight um it came
up on our on our uh our discord this
week uh like some breeding expectations
and just seeing what people commented
about breeders today versus breeders
yesterday or of yesteryear
uh we figured like we could chat a bit
about like even what people expected
yeah like what expectations were and how
expectations
like have always sort of shaped what
breeders do
yeah even from the beginning right
and then we had a comment come in that i
thought was kind of interesting that
like could sort of tie into that which
is like people wanted us to talk about
uh beasters
oh really
indeed which we actually have some uh we
actually have some good friends that
could talk a lot more eloquently
probably than we could on but
what i thought was what would could be
interesting is we could talk from a bit
about um
like how it affected america
yeah like how to change things here how
it changed the homegrown scene here how
it you know just certain aspects of it
right so
um
i don't know we uh we could start uh we
could start any any which way because i
guess i guess maybe two beasters would
be sort of like the
the first like commercialization of kind
but yeah
yeah
right
yeah because everybody else was getting
it usually from some there wasn't really
commercial scenes then
sure no and and you couldn't really call
mexican brick beasters necessarily no
there was a commercial mexican obviously
that had been commercialized for a long
time yeah but like there was a situation
in most parts of the country even on the
west coast where there wasn't enough
good kind bud
yeah i never even
got a a whiff of bc
beasters ever in my life never saw them
they didn't make it down all the way
down to bakersfield or san diego so i
never saw any of that stuff
i mean it it permeated all over the
place especially the east coast yeah i
bet i know and it had it had different
effects strangely enough in different
places i guess we'll start talking about
this because we're already into it but
like so you take bisters in somewhere
like the southeast
right uh or certain like that that might
be the only non-mexican bud you could
get
yeah like it might have been all and
like what people don't get is like in
the 90s and stuff like that
you know
um
it was still super prohibited right
and they
you know so it kept it really small
there was way more demand
than there was supply
right and that's kind of what made
everything easy to sell because you
could always always sell whatever
because
sell i mean
for example in a place we have here
called cottonwood
a type of
weed was going around called nade that
was
old commercial not i mean but mexican
brick uh sprayed with raid and they'd
call it nade and that was a thing and
they could sell that and move that
you know anything could be people i just
had some guy all upset like he's like
[ __ ] beasters we got fire here on the
southeast i mean the era that we're
talking about is the 90s
and so there wasn't enough fire anywhere
yeah
like fire was hard to get
and you know and people had it
but and fire's relative
fire is relative and for like part of
the reason why and people when someone
even asks i'm 22 what are beesters
beasters literally
is
indoor
indoor weed grown in canada
and shipped to america
yeah at scale
right that was in the 90s and into the
into the early 2000s right and so
people think people laugh at it now but
the reason why it was so successful
was because
for most people i mean you know your
access was like green mexican brown
mexican
oh you know or like you had a buddy who
had a buddy who had a buddy who maybe
every once in a while could get you a
quarter of a kind bud yeah
and so beesters filled that void you
know and now
it's like you say the word beasters and
people have all kinds of comments
they're making right now but in the
beginning
none of that was known
yeah
right like it was like so in a lot of
parts of the country it was the only it
was the only kind bud regularly
available
right and even in california
california it [ __ ] us up
right because and it has in in a way i
actually feel like it it sort of started
the purple wave in california
i don't know
i almost yeah i almost i i i think it
had a big play a big part of it
um how so what happened is is that back
then you know most indoor or most
outdoor or whatever even outdoor and
stuff there wasn't a tons of depths
there wasn't tons of outdoor and stuff
like that most people were growing we're
growing pounds in the in the dozens of
pounds not the hundreds of pounds yeah
outside and then most indoors were like
you know four to twelve lights or
something right yeah and so
um
you know there was an aspect where
all that stuff was expensive
yeah okay and so people
so you know what brokers are like right
yeah so you have this choice where you
can come to mendo and you can get a
bunch of fireweed for like 42.
yeah right
or
you can talk to these canadians
and you can get a bunch of bee stirs for
23.
yeah
right so what are the brokers gonna do
yeah nine times out of ten pick cheap
so nine times out of ten they're gonna
pick cheap right and so and they're
going to make a hell of a margin you
know and so what happened is is that
there was a in california there was good
weed to be smoked but what the brokers
tried to do which is what they tried to
do forever is like
it's no different than like can i make
these depths look like ends
yeah are these outs good enough to look
like depths are they good enough to look
like something better than they are
because then i can make the profit
difference
between like what those sell for and
what these sell for yeah so in like you
know in you know a lot of parts of the
country beasters was all there was so it
was like [ __ ] you take it
yeah i mean if one dude was the only
plug in town and he decides to take
beasters over some kind bud then you're
just going to get smoked beasters and
that's that yeah or you're going to buy
mexican yeah exactly those are your
issues right so but then in california
they had to pass it off a lot of times
as homegrown
yeah because other california people
were edu the west coast and oregon and
stuff in washington they knew enough
that like they weren't going to pay that
kind of pricing for it yeah because they
they had other options they could find
somebody that had homegrown yeah so then
the middlemen tried to make beasters
look like homegrown
sure right and it worked for a time
because everybody's commenting right now
and and i see all of you right and now
it's pretty well known that a lot of
beesters were grown like too much salts
they were harvested a little early they
weren't cured as as nicely as they
should have been they were packaged in
and seal a mealed airtight containers
and zipped close
yeah and then by the time that they got
to where they were going they had
suffered a quality issue
yeah it wasn't as nice as it was where
it began
right like sometimes it could smell like
hay sometimes it could smell a little a
little a little weird a little off a
little yeah people saying pgrs but at
the time people didn't know most of that
it was like you could either get mexican
or this
yeah
that was or like you had you had you
were a lucky enough person that you grew
or you knew someone close to you that
grew
right yeah um that you could get some
eighths or some quarters or a zip every
two or three months
and you know there's also mexicans that
would come up that were like almost like
a red hue
and that that was obviously a lot of
people used to work for tentacle we
didn't really use that because we didn't
get the bc beasters but our pretendica
was the uncompressed mexican that would
come down
do you know what
uh chicago for tentaca was
no
so chicago pretendica
was
in the midwest there's a ton of ditch
wheat
yeah right and ditchweed is basically
like leftover wild hemp from the world
war ii hempford victory thing right yes
well some of that can look beautiful
so sometimes entrepreneurs would go out
there and and get a bunch of pounds of
gorgeous looking hemp
yeah and dry it nice and they'd sell 300
ounces
of weed that looked incredible
but you couldn't get high off it and i
didn't even know what cbd was back then
you know yeah however i had no i never
it just didn't i i just was shocked
because my green mexican got me higher
yeah i always thought that was weird
because the uh uncompressed brick almost
always you'd get higher off the [ __ ]
shittier high compressed brick
so almost always so there was a weird
thing so what happened what i mean and
this is a roundabout way of saying and
so sorry for everybody but what i think
happened in california is that
you had this thing where
um
like they were flooding the west coast
with all this indoor
yeah right and so all these brokers are
moving this indoor from from canada and
they're taking the margin convincing
people it's
it's california or it's oregonian or
whatever you know it's washington it's
homegirl and then eventually people
started noticing the differences they
started looking for the rock hard pgr
buds they started looking for certain
noses
um sometimes they started looking even
for like the way it was seal a mealed
you know like people would get it and
they would cut open all the ceiling
meals and they would put it into turkey
bags
oh yeah yeah in order to like make it
seem like it wasn't from where it was
from you know yeah
and and you know and so what happened is
is that you've got all these brokers
trying to pass off weed that they bought
for 22 2300 bucks
yeah
into the force
and you're trying to actually find some
of that actual cap cali in homegrown
yeah right and so when the irk and the
and the mendo p and the granddaddy and
all that started selling in the bay and
going for it
there wasn't a bunch of canadian weed
that looked purple
yeah no that no now i get what you're
saying so you could see it right they
would see it they they would send up all
these people to humboldt and mendo and
all different spots and grab as much
purp as they could
because it was an easier hustle for them
because everyone they gave it to they
knew they weren't getting bunked
with some fake beasters
yeah and then once
once that toehold took place
in at least in norcal once that toe hold
took place then it was just like a
self-sustaining thing
yeah right and all the brokers couldn't
pass off
beast as
homegrown
yeah because everybody wanted like one
of these half a dozen purple strains and
you could sell endless amounts of those
i remember um growing some of the
canadian purples and there yeah there's
no way they could be passed off as uh
indoor anything i remember they most of
them had to be grown outdoor in the
first place and they were just very
loose
purple sometimes bud
not very not very grand i just think it
was one of those things that it just it
just like made it distinctive i mean
there was a time too where like with the
early dispensaries and stuff like that
part of the reason why the dispensaries
could move endless amounts of perps
was because all their customers knew
that the dispensary wasn't buying cheap
beast
and flipping it for the high
they were just buying
[ __ ] mendo perps and flipping it
because it won't get you high well yeah
i mean
it's not so much that dude it's like
because you know everybody's affected
differently but sure the canadian weed
because it wasn't dried as nicely as we
like to do it
oh yeah i'm sure and then it was it was
it was you know and then once you seal
something up for a few weeks wet
what you know it's going to firm it yeah
that's nice and then it's going to be
compressed lightly so like because any
kind of smuggling is all about shipping
it's all about volume and space right
sure so you get this weed that like is
like it probably if it would have stayed
where it was going to stay and got dried
really nicely it probably would have
been better
yeah you know but then you you harvest
it a little early you don't flush it you
package it a little too moist you put it
into an airtight thing and you scrunch
it down on itself
um
you know uh
you know they uh and so that and so then
there was occasionally some really nice
beasters
you know there was there was some really
good weed that came out of there but
just the over
the overall flood
was pretty low-brow
yeah the overall flood was pretty low
about but for a lot of places people
think of now right where it's like the
west coast is just sending
you know people joke on ig for years
about how the west coast just sends all
their bunk east
yeah right and it's like a running joke
because of how much work that gets grown
in on the west coast of
america would get sent to other parts of
america
but in the 90s there wasn't a flood like
that
yeah there wasn't a flood going east at
all i was just teasing about mendo perps
guys it's just
a lot of people always say it doesn't
get them high no i mean like he's not
joking
men i'm not it's it's there's very few
strains that that have everything
yeah vendo person has an unbelievable
look it has unbelievable set of terps it
breeds really well it does all this this
cool stuff
but because it's so old it's low thc
yeah
you know uh it is and so
you know like one of our buddy uh you
know uh caleb i mean one of his better
crosses of it is to the the bubba
yeah right and there's obamacush or
whatnot you know because the bubba adds
frost and density and some potency
and the mendo adds color and terps and
[ __ ] you know yeah
and so you know and then different
people like i i actually like if i smoke
mendo p in the morning
like it actually makes me creative
rather than couch lock
yeah that's a good though if i like wake
up and drink some coffee and eat some
food and i smoke some mendo pee and i
start writing down my list of [ __ ] i
want to accomplish
yeah like i my brain works at a pretty
good level
yeah i think i was sour dub in the
morning and then i usually am asleep um
right after writing that little note of
things to do
enough thank goodness this morning i
mean it's there for the future at least
yeah it is it's there for tonight but
so like for so basically like beasters
too it's like we're not gonna do a whole
show on it but beasters affected
different parts of the country in
different ways
yeah right in california it really did
kind of spark the purple wave
uh because people didn't want to get
stuck with beesters
but in other parts of the country there
wasn't that much choice like my buddies
and this is what this is what's crazy is
that so my friends in chicago that
stayed there obviously when i moved west
okay yeah you know how for a lot of
people uh beesters dropped the price of
what they were able to get
to some degree it affected price points
in california right
well in chicago it made their prices go
up
yeah because they were like well if this
if this goes for four then my shit's six
you know
yeah and they actually flipped it and
they did better because of it
because their homegrown was their home
their super nice indoor homegrown was so
much danker
yeah they were like well if this is what
you can get this for then ours has to be
that
yeah so it literally like their stuff
before beaster went for about what
beester did
yeah and then when it came in it like
created another grade of kind bud that
their bud was obviously better
smart marketing
you know and so it went up but in
california it hurt us
yeah because it was like the first flood
of cheap [ __ ] indoor
it's it's crazy that it didn't affect
socal very much at all like it just
didn't hit down here like that
i mean it up north
yeah well there's parts of it i don't
even know if i should say but because
there's like
there is because like you know i was
talking about like the
just like the weed impact of it but
there was obviously like some big groups
involved and a lot of money at stake and
a lot of smug and you know there were
there's aspects to it that
um you know and it got really honestly
the other thing that we should say is
that uh you know um in the 90s and 2000
and 2001
um
you know america did not spend very much
energy worrying about the canadians
yeah
our border with the canadians especially
was super porous
yeah right and there was a lot of
independence there was a lot of guys
like with friends on snowmobiles
with you know with duffel duffel bags
and there was all kinds of crazy [ __ ]
going on in terms of
getting stuff from canada to here
did you ever see that movie kid cannabis
yeah
yeah that kid was one of those dudes
i've talked to one of the dudes that was
involved in it before so you know it was
coming over in truckloads it was coming
over
you know but in a lot of places you
could just go to the border and meet up
with an american on the other side of
the border yeah right there was all
kinds of [ __ ] like that going on right
yeah and then
uh the [ __ ] al qaeda crashed the
planes
into new york
and flying became a lot rougher and they
started paying a lot more attention and
heat sensors and all that to the board
and the northern canadian border
not because they were worried about
canucks selling weed in america
uh but mostly because they were worried
about um you know terrorists sneaking in
through canada
so they tell you
yeah but it just i mean i get it you
know it's like so they tighten the [ __ ]
up yeah and then a lot of the ways that
and so in late 2001 a lot of the ways
that people used to move it across the
border whether it was snowmobiles or
mountain bikes or you know just driving
close and hiking it over and dropping it
in the woods and having the americans
come get it you know all that yeah
all of a sudden you know because we put
all of our money for the most part we
put the vast majority of our money into
policing the southern border
yeah because there was just a [ __ ] ton
of heroin and cocaine and weed and
issues and you know all that and so the
canadians we just weren't too
we just weren't too intense on that and
so
um you know the the and they didn't even
know that there was that much weed
happening either
yeah so there's an invisibility factor
to something for a minute
right
and and so
then they locked all that [ __ ] down and
they made it a lot harder
yeah they did they made it a lot harder
for like independents to get it across
the border so then it moved to like
trucking
and various aspects and smuggling and
then what kind of groups does that bring
in yeah of course a lot bigger groups
than just some like independent dudes
wanting to work or whatever then that
brings in organized groups organized
groups of various kinds traditional
organized groups various kinds of
organized groups that existed up there
which is easy to go and read about if
you if you so choose
um and then like the independents all
felt squeezed
yeah because they were all hiding from
like these other groups that wanted to
control everything right
yep and
you know and then it really
um
and the reason why that all worked was
because there wasn't there wasn't enough
like people people you know downgrade
you know california or oregon or
whatever sends all their booth east
but like there wasn't
you know i had friends that would drive
a bunch of work back east back in the
day you know and like there wasn't any
there was almost nobody on the road
doing it
yeah it was rare
there wasn't
there wasn't that much excess
yeah especially in the 90s with all the
helicopters and all that and how much
you could get away with doing or
whatever
it was like we could you know california
kind of served california in the west
yeah
and it really wasn't until 215 and a
bunch of other groups got in and things
started expanding on a large level
that those waves just started going
everywhere
yeah
and that ended up basically
doing two things that like
it
it changed the margins for both the
canadians and the mexicans yeah
because that that convergence of all
that weed getting sent in
you know they talk about it now it's
like uh mexicans send like 70 80 percent
less weed into america than they used to
oh i bet yeah
right and then that's [ __ ] up for us
too okay because those guys are uh you
know they're criminals uh you know
trying to make money
yeah so then they've got to replicate
that lost revenue
oh yeah and all the things that they've
decided to like replicate that lost
revenue with are all way worse than
brown weed
oh yeah i know
that's the big one well math fentanyl
you know
kidnappings yeah all traffic like
coyotes moving human trafficking like
yeah you know i mean they used a lot of
those cartels they would make 60 70 of
their income off of wheat
yeah
so then it's way different now yeah so
then two-thirds of that slows down
that's a lot of loot
yep you know it really is and then you
know same thing with the canadians the
canadians were sending a ton of that
down
and the mexicans were sending a ton of
it north to like the voracious appetite
of america to smoke weed
and then the west coast of america
started supplying americans with
american wheat
yeah and it sort of like shaved off the
top and the bottom and made it a lot
less likely
you know
yeah people are asking uh and this is a
good one and i think it's easy um
what were some of the strains that were
being labeled as beesters coming over
the border i think that probably you
know the funny part is is that i wonder
how much accuracy there was between the
grower the broker
you know uh i would think that a lot
would be different and um but come over
with similar names because i think
because that would be whatever's in
demand
you know this would actually be i don't
know if our buddy is on here tonight but
but a list of strain names he could
probably pump out or i see kootenay on
here
and people were actually commenting too
about how many good strains there was in
canada
there was a bunch of amazing strains in
canada it's not to diss canada it's just
that the choices that got made to be
grown for commercial consumption in
america
wasn't necessarily the creme de la creme
of the choices of canadian wheat
yeah
it was grown for export
yeah i remember a lot of hash plant
being talked about coming down the m39
the grapefruit yeah all the stuff that
they're naming specifically m39 a lot of
bc big buds things that things that got
them a bunch of shish kabari things that
got them a bunch of weight
yeah and didn't take that long
you know and a lot of times to me i
don't know about i don't know about if
if other people saw names
but uh mine was most most of the time
that we saw it had letter
grades they had like letter grades
like you know you hear triple a
oh double a
a b
you know b minus they would literally
have it would literally a lot of them
would literally have just letters on
them
okay i mean of course everyone tried to
claim their [ __ ] was triple or quadruple
a or whatever yeah i doubt many were
saying yeah i got some see [ __ ] wanna
try it yeah you know but sometimes i
mean sometimes it wasn't good enough to
like try to play the game
yeah like i'm going to give you some b
and i'll say this too this is this has
nothing to do with my world but
one of the reasons why
they were able to [ __ ] with us so much
as far as like the price rate is that
back then
one american dollar got you about a
dollar 60 in canadian
yeah
so the exchange rate was amazing
yeah you know what i'm saying so imagine
you could sell your weed
and you know and and for every you know
for a for in it's like they got such an
exchange rate
right yeah i mean you sell you weed for
you know
i mean it it's so so they were flipping
it and for us it seemed low but for them
they were getting a killer price
sure
you know because
and that's and that's and that's the way
it worked and it came
you know and so it took a while but
eventually
just like when i lived in when i lived
in chicago uh i never even heard the
word tweaker
you never heard the word tweet never
heard the word tweaker there wasn't
tweak in my high school it didn't exist
it did not it did not now eventually it
it [ __ ] it permeated and it was all
over the midwest
but i straight up tell you in the early
90s when i was in high school like it
didn't exist so if someone would have
said tweaker to me then
right uh yeah it wouldn't have meant
much now it has like an enormous amount
of meaning because you just know so much
about it right so you talk about what i
what i mean by that is you talk about
beasters today
and it has an enormous amount of meaning
to people
yeah but you have to realize when
bisters first started hitting america we
didn't have all this pre-loaded
knowledge about what it was like
yeah
it was just not weed that wasn't mexican
right
you know
and uh yeah there was a dude didn't come
to the first week i ever saw in chicago
it was ravers from san francisco who
brought it
yeah it was on the west coast but in the
mid in the early and mid 90s it was not
in the midwest
yeah and everyone pardoned me for
getting [ __ ] up before the show the
last few weeks have been
past my move [ __ ] so i'm not not too
terribly brilliant or quick with it my
apologies
so everybody's like [ __ ] he looks high
for once so people said people are still
asking what's what's a beast or beaster
is canadian indoor
yeah grown for america and usually it's
um it's usually it's harvested a little
too soon it's not flushed or dried the
right way and then they put it into
airtight ceiling meal bags
lightly lightly to somewhat compressed
and figured out how to get it into
america because there was such a demand
for weed
yeah
they could sell endless amounts of it
yeah and so there was a huge i mean the
new england was flooded with it
new york was flooded with it you know uh
the upper midwest you know the west
coast and all that and then you know it
depends like it got basically knocked
off
in
in the west coast reasonably fast uh
because of 911 and then because of the
burgeoning 215 movement right
but it persisted for years
uh in other parts of the country
i'm sure it didn't it
is it still persists now do you think i
don't know
yeah i don't know either i don't know i
mean
you know it uh i i couldn't tell you i
mean i bet i bet it does i bet there's
markets for it
maybe somewhere up in the north um i
can't say
you know who knows could be it could go
it could go all places in this it could
be gone i don't know
yeah i mean it's gone in california
i don't see brickweed as much anymore in
california rarely if ever and it was
that was like all that was here during
my teenage years i mean i live in mendoz
and and i'm not [ __ ] 15. so
i don't uh
you know i don't i haven't seen
brickweed in forever
yeah
yeah no england like even the past maybe
10 years it's still 99 percent of what
you'd see people smoking in bakersfield
blunts and blunts and blunts of [ __ ]
right
yeah so people are talking cali outdoor
is the new beasters in cali and stuff
you know and like there's i live in
california right and there's a lot of
there's a lot of weed that sucks
yeah you know there's never there's
never been an era where everyone just
grew the [ __ ] white hot fire and
that's all there was yeah i know i mean
how many people really grow out of
everybody that's in this chat how many
people really grow like the banging you
know i mean realistically if you compare
it all it's not all going to be the same
level and then you know on top of that
it's it's like sometimes that shitty
weed is still the best that you can get
like so that what sucks is that the
places with the least choice
probably gets stuck with the shittiest
weed the longest
yeah because it gets dislodged in places
with choice
you know
um and you know and so
you know and there's an aspect too where
it's like there's there's probably a
story there we've been talking about it
for a while actually but there's
probably a story there of how like
of where america gets its weed
yeah
and how that's shifted because in the
because there was an error there for a
long time where
you know all of a sudden uh a lot of
people were getting weed and you can you
can laugh at cali weed but like there
was a lot of people getting reasonably
good quality weed from from out here
that was grown with a reasonable amount
of love too
yeah you know and now there's an aspect
too where people are complaining about
where things have gone legal and the
black market is just exploded between
the asians and the eastern europeans and
the cartels and all that and southern
oregon and the deserts out by you
yeah you know and uh and all that and
like now there's a [ __ ] ton of weed
being grown by people that don't care at
all
and people yeah
we might have a resurgence too because
of all these people buying [ __ ] skunk
one seeds we might have a whole [ __ ]
beast of resurgence can't wait
and so you know there's there's an
aspect to where it's like a lot of the
best california weed is getting cut off
you know people think you know because
that's another aspect right where it's
all the it's all the brokers and the
people that make it go from here to
there
yeah they choose what what goes from
here to there yeah and they're looking
at it from their perspective of what's
profitable sure and just like with the
beesters if they can send some some
shittier stuff that way that they had a
much bigger margin on
and that and that that run makes them a
lot more money that's probably what
they'll do
you know so it's like everyone you can
all all y'all
on southeast or east or wherever you are
that like is bitching about california
weed it's probably your [ __ ] broker
the person that brought it there right
yeah they chose
there was fireweed that they probably
tried to
try to [ __ ] you know tried to lowball
or turn down because it didn't make them
as much of a margin sure right margins
everything's margins you know and so you
know if you knew somebody that like
their their whole gig was quality and
and fire and that's what they wanted to
work with fine yeah if you knew people
that were like well they're not going to
have much choice in this part so we're
just going to shift them with this
then you're probably [ __ ]
yeah you know
and uh
you know and so i'm sure you know
there's i'm sure there's still beast
you know even if it's greatly reduced
you know uh i mean right now it you know
most people were getting a lot of weed
from mendo and humboldt and trinity and
a lot of smaller scenes that would all
get aggregated together
yeah and now
all that all that is the asians and the
bulgarians and the and the freaking uh
and the cartels and all that growing
massive plots
yeah and you know why would a broker go
and and
you know and and so you're getting
shittier weed
yeah you're getting shitty or weed
you know lots of people in california
have the fire that doesn't mean that
like every person in the chain between
you and california is going to ensure
that that fire makes it to you
most of it's in one second most of it's
in the bathroom right over there there's
none in here
you must be at my journey
so people are yeah and you know people
are
people delta eight is the new beast you
know how many things when when hemp
became legal people started growing hemp
and then spraying it with distillate
oh lord yeah
you know and literally and then and then
moving that somewhere
right if there's a if there's a
arbitrage opportunity where people can
make a big ass [ __ ] margin
yeah by buying something shittier and
passing it off as something way better
they're going to and they're going to do
that with hash there was a whole thing
hash isn't my thing
but do you know how much you know you
guys know how much like crc cheap
extracted hash got passed off as
something nicer
you know
it's always been that way the most
common way in mendo was i mentioned it
before but these depths are so beautiful
i can sell them as indoor and i'll get a
better price point
yeah this outdoor is so fire it looks
like it like it's a well-preserved depth
and i can get you more money i think
that's why lumpa liked the uh west coast
dog because he could sell it off as
indoor pretty sure i mean people people
are and then and then there's everyone
and then and then even if you're
honorable all it takes is one
non-honorable person in the chain
yeah
it doesn't take much it doesn't take
much you know and so
yeah people are talking the old og is
around a bunch there's tons of people
that have nice ogs
yeah it's just a matter of is it getting
grown in bulk to come to wherever you
are probably not is it getting grown
with the same recipe they were using
back then uh probably not probably not
you know
and uh you know and so there's an aspect
where yeah hemp sprayed with distillate
there's any time there's a way where
they can find some cheap ass [ __ ] and
convince you that it's nicer [ __ ]
there's someone in the middle that's
making a bunch of money off that so yeah
they would go up there and they would
[ __ ] buy
you know 200
uh you know hemp pounds an organ
and then they would take a paint sprayer
and they would spray it with distillate
so it would get you high
and then they'd sell it as real outdoor
one way to do it
i mean that's kind of that's kind of
someone just said athena og
there is a bunch of i don't know what
the [ __ ] is going on but there's a bunch
of legal scenes and there's a bunch of
their followers and stuff like that that
have decided that the cheapest salts on
earth are of cour like automated
delivery is the way to grow weed
and their weed isn't as nice
yeah you know their weed isn't as nice
and so
you know there's there's going to be all
kinds of that with hash
there's going to be all kinds of that
with weed and
you know it it uh because if there's a
if there's an education difference i
mean you know how many times i used to
hear up here people would look at
something and they would be like oh this
is fire but can they break down some of
these bigger buds a little bit more
why right huh why
because indoor doesn't have big buds oh
my god
i guess that makes sense and they're
trying to pass it off so it's like i
don't need anything like this bro you
need to make it smaller yeah you know
because they're in their mind they're
gonna they're gonna they're gonna pass
it off at some bull as some [ __ ]
yeah they're gonna say they're you know
they don't and they don't want the
customer to be like oh these look like
sun grown nuts
yeah because then they just shaved off x
off their percentage they were planning
on making
so you know people california and the
west coast can get a bad rap and there's
plenty of bad weed here but it's also
like
you know it's it's it's also a bunch of
choices in between
yeah you know and i think i i don't know
i think athena is just like [ __ ] luxe
lighting i think athena is probably
owned by jungle boys
and they sure
and they and they promote the [ __ ] out
of it saying that they've tested it
against all kinds of different other
other nutrients and it's come out the
best and they grow the fire and then
they build up a bunch of sales for
athena and it's cheap and then they're
gonna offer and they're gonna off the
company and make a [ __ ] ton of money
possible yeah when if you want to use
something like athena you can go buy
some real cheap salts that doesn't have
the athena makeup that's probably the
exact same thing just in a different bag
that's how a lot of nutrient companies
are done i mean you know there's one
supplier and they ask for certain mixes
and ranges but it's all based out of the
same [ __ ] you know that happens a lot
yeah you know it happens a lot you know
and so
um
there's there's an aspect where it's
like i don't dis on all salts they're
salts i like quite a bit actually for
the application
i'm a housing garden sucker in canada
but mostly i like canna i like canna i
like cutting edge
shout out to my buddy john
um
you know there's there's good salts out
there used properly that'll do fine for
you you know there's
even even stuff like jacks the main
issue with some of the cheaper stuff is
now they do a bunch of testing a lot of
it has high heavy metal content or other
additives that aren't the jam
yeah
you know i like i like the empty
someone's asking for like a good dry
salt i like the npk brand um where you
can buy each
individual element separately so you can
run it exactly as you want i like that a
lot if someone's going to use something
old and basic i would i would almost
just say use jacks
jacks321
you know there you go it's like a
classic
you know wasn't that in the og recipe
jacks is that a poppy yeah and you know
i said cutting edge you know full
disclosure like my buddy john owns
cutting edge he started it in 0-1
he's been a grower he was grower up here
from the 70s on and so hum and mendo
uh he knows he it's like one of the
first nutrients formulated for growers
by an old grower
uh yeah and he's real he's real smart
and he's a real nice guy and it's
supporting one of us
um you know
and uh
people ask me how do i feel about the
new line i use the new line uh their
louder powder they call it i use that on
like a big farm down south for a year
and a half
uh before i left
um so
you know but
um there's an aspect there where it's
like they uh
you know beasters was sort of our first
beasters was sort of like the first
commercial weed that came to america
that wasn't mexican that was in the
first indoor commercial
yeah right because americans weren't
really able to pull off hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds of lights
like the way the bc crews were doing at
the time and the canadian crews were
doing
you know so it's kind of like
beast to me like some of that stuff
isn't that different than like a lot of
these like big rockwool farms you see
right now in [ __ ] legal scenes
it's almost like we've come full circle
yeah
it's just dried nicer
you know but it's still that cardboard
lead yeah you know sure
and all that you know so
um
people talk about cutting edge talking i
mean nutrients its own whole thing or
whatever but
um there's uh
you know nutrients pretty misunderstood
but you know there's an aspect where
um
you know you could get people that are
trying to grow the best weed they can
and trying to get a really nice number
for it
or you can get people that are just in a
in a larger group that are just trying
to grow the cheapest weed they can and
still get the best price they can get it
yeah you know um and so
you know there's uh
you know there's an aspect where it's
like
i don't know
um
i almost think that probably all that
stuff that they like people dis on
california for going east was probably
better
than their alternatives
i would think so i would have better
than it was better than b it was
probably better grown than beester and
it was certainly nicer than mexico
yeah
you know and it got so successful that
people diss it now
but why did it get that successful
because it was better
you know there was plenty of famous cuts
or varieties that were cont there were
uh during the bister era like i was
saying before
i kind of covered it kind of covered it
northern lights mighty mite
grapefruit dunking
donkey uh anything that was anything
that was big
you know uh mean the m39 was just is
probably the most associated with it i'd
have to say yeah you know and there's an
aspect there
there's a guy a a dude i know from mendo
saying organic sun grown you know
there's an aspect of like what's the
best
right but obviously what people are
facing in the in the in the market right
now
is that
um
you know a lot of times they're not
rewarded for the best
yeah island sweet skunk is fire um the
silver pearl is fire too uh friesland i
don't know if i'd call that fire that
was a little bit midsy at least as far
as the stuff that i saw yeah
but
um but yeah you know there's a there's a
part of it where see now it's like i
start reading the comments and i just
like lose track of whatever the [ __ ] i
was talking about so i apologize
everyone [ __ ] up
i i i started reading what people were
talking about
and then and then all of a sudden i'm
like what the hell was i even just just
discussing but you know it um they were
asking you to to do a um what do you
call those where when someone dies
uh on for jaime chiba i think they
wanted you a eulogy
eulogy
i mean
you know jaime was a jaime was an
interesting cat you know i i'll say that
um
you know uh
the old timers like him the guys in
their 60s and their 70s
a lot of times the stories they tell
they don't come with a lot of like uh
corroboration from others
so it's like how much do you how much do
you take at face value
and not just him neville sam you know
sam skunk man mel
you can name tons of different folks
right and
you know and and and so
you know he
he was obviously a collector
um and you know he the last five or ten
years or so probably he started he
started spreading his seeds out to lots
of different people
you would say right he wanted a lot of
different people to try his stuff yes
yes
you know and he was pretty free with
sharing seeds with people or sending
them things you know um i would say so
that's good in the sense that if you
want to keep his his work alive a lot of
people have it uh it'll be interesting
to see if uh you know i'm sure it's
already happening who starts to exploit
uh the fact that he's gone
yeah you know
um but you know he
i mean
you know he claimed to have rks he was
the original dj short according to
he claimed that you know he had a
massive role in blueberry yeah and that
yeah and that he was the real dj short
you know uh he was the guy that was
actually responsible for creating
blueberry yeah typing and he said his
they called him dj short literally
literally dj short
um and so you know uh
yeah he he was an interesting character
because obviously
you know he had a lot of claims
um it's you know it seemed like he was
he was doing his thing up there you know
in alaska and spreading his seeds out
and they all came with some wild stories
um and rest in peace buddy
yeah i don't know
i just yeah i mean
i'm glad he likes seeds i'm glad he
liked weed we all share that in common
rest in peace
and you know it's it wouldn't be the you
know like i mean what are you even
supposed to say about comments like that
obviously we know
the blueberry story to be what it is
yeah
you know and that would be like somebody
coming out and saying uh [ __ ] this sam
skunk man guy he stole my skunk and haze
seeds and fled to europe and i went to
prison and everything that comes out of
his mouth is [ __ ] he used to work
for me yeah
but you've got like this massive amount
of history of
assumption
yes which is that dj did it so trying to
trying to shift all that is a major
that's a big shift that's a big shift it
is a big shift that's a big but he
wasn't quiet about it no you know he
just said it like matter of fact so it's
like how the
how am i supposed to know yeah but then
there's also this thing too where i
think blueberry is a common enough name
you know um
that but
i mean dj short's not a common enough
name and especially
blueberry it kind of means that one of
them is not telling the truth and it's
just up to you guys to figure out who
you believe
yeah i mean he was i mean it's like i
don't know if he's i haven't listened to
the uh to the interview he just did oh
yeah so i don't know if he i don't know
if he wanted to do that i don't know if
he went into depth on it or anything
like that you know but
i mean people are talking about pre-dj
short blueberry there's blueberry out
there that people talk about 79
blueberry
that people are growing
you know so who knows um
but you know it it uh the one thing i'll
always say about breeders is um
you know is uh
i always give the advice of grow what
you like
make things that you like
you know and then at the very least you
know like it uh
um you like it
yeah
you know which is the core thing so
jaime
did a bunch of work that he liked
and had a lot of big stories about it
and started spreading them all out yep
you know i've never tried i've never
grown any of his seeds to be perfectly
honest oh yumbold so he's the yumble guy
too that's [ __ ] sick dude what a
reputation to leave behind
god bless i mean yumbolt was young bolt
was one of the nicest things that uh
adam duns when he started th seeds had
was it was a sacred method strain i
believe it was the secret strain yeah
and it was supposed to be
a seed representation of an old clone
called humble
and they just called a young bolt maybe
adam had a maybe adam had a i mean those
guys were all tied together yeah exactly
he might have used it maybe they had a
different version or who knows who knows
what who knows what the
the thing so you know i'm not i'm not
trying to you know it it's sad that he
passed motorcycles are dangerous yeah
you know there's no there's nothing
protect there's no nothing protecting
you
right so you could be an amazing
biker
and someone else could do something dumb
and you're [ __ ] yep
you know chris
it's [ __ ] dangerous and so but you
know it's
it's uh um you know he had a you know
he's given some interviews and he spread
out a bunch of his seeds and stuff like
that for neville
he said he was a backup for neville he
worked under neville
he
was the real dj short he had real rks
um
that's a lot of big claims yeah it is a
lot of big claims and you know and i i
always go back to like um
when people pass we tend to sanctify
them which you know means declare them
some sainthood uh
you forget about all the other stuff i i
have a really bad personality where i
keep the same energy that i had when
they were alive
um so i just say i wish that i wish the
guy and his family the best it's not fun
to lose anyone and i know i had a lot of
friends in the community and i hope they
all you know pull together and and and
find a way through it
yeah and you know hopefully people find
things that they like amongst his beings
yeah for sure
and if you do keep them alive keep them
going
you know and uh and and and figure and
figure all that out you know i mean i
have the same issue too like you know
with telling certain stories you know
it's always hard with weed because
there's certain people that don't really
want to be mentioned
yeah and don't want their stories told
all that much
um and uh and but then maybe they played
an important role in history yeah
there's one person just for people
asking there is one person that we know
for sure in the us that worked directly
with neville at any level and it was at
a very small level and that was clyde
stevens so anybody else making that
claim it cannot be corroborated at all
or even a little bit yeah clyde
and clyde was neville's photographer yep
and it's
it's verified that clyde neville went to
afghanistan together
and also on operation green merchant
they were both kind of a part of it so
they were both kind of a part of it yeah
there's a bunch of pictures there's a
lot of he was a photographer so there's
a lot of photographic
evidence of all that you know
um but you know what's what matt and i
always laugh about uh whenever we hear
whether it's from hawaii or alaska or
wherever
that of course you would pick
someone to back up your stuff that lives
on another continent
in a country where the dea is trying to
put you away for life in prison for
decades on end yeah that is the most
convenient place that you would try to
back up all of your stuff and do and do
pheno hunting and testing and
conversations and be involved
you know yep
uh rather than somebody down the street
in holland or somebody in in the
netherlands somewhere or europeans in
general
you know
um but then it was just i mean
so there's aspects where there's certain
stories that matt and i know are
provably false
yeah and then there's ones that like
they have some parts where you really
wonder could they be you know if they're
true or not
but you don't have any proof
one way or the other it's just the story
yeah
and um and in the interview i mean we
can kind of bring this up now so we
posted an interview on patreon for our
patreon subscribers that was an
interview with uh a man named kevin
bjornsen and he was a major part of the
northern lights crew he was a part of
operation green merchant um i don't know
if the story really is that he was green
merchant per se but i know he believes
that story very deeply that he is the
reason for the season on it um but we
did post it and i wanted to get some
feedback from you guys and tell me uh
from the people who listen what you guys
thought about it and i know one of the
questions right now was was he
the green merchant and um i do know
according to him
that he did write down some license
plate numbers from people he says they
weren't real but that was a part of the
operation green merchant bust
what the the the basic story of green
merchant so people that don't know is in
growth store
got busted for being tied into weed
and when they rated it supposedly they
found a series of neville's catalogs
with written out orders and money and
names and whatnot yeah and then they
realized okay that neville was selling
millions of dollars in seed
to
all these people all over america
right
and uh they freaked out okay because
they had no idea this was going on
and supposedly even more so than that
and this is that
neville actually did this thing where he
sent guys with suitcases full of wheat
full of seeds to america
and supposedly most of the seeds that he
did were mailed from america the money
went to the money went to holland yeah i
mean allegedly played allegedly and then
i mean he's dead what are you gonna do
he's dead now but no he's not oh neville
yeah neville never yeah and you know
neville had there was so neville was
mailing seeds from within the us with a
compatriot and then getting the money in
holland
and no one had any idea he was doing
this because he was the first seed bank
so nobody really realized that there was
anything going on and when green
merchant when they realized that people
in gross stores were like buying and
selling seeds yeah and some of these
stores were like buying a bunch of seeds
and then selling them to their customers
with the lights they did this thing
called operation green merchant where
they
raided every single hydroponic store in
the country yeah all at once all at once
boom same day same time everything same
day same time
nationwide nationwide raid
and the gentleman uh that we did the
interview with
um
you know he was part of that he owned a
grocery store he was tied into the whole
northern lights pacific northwest crew
right and had one of the only grow
stores in that area one of the first so
he was one of the biggest targets at the
time and so that is sort of the
the the domino that when um when matt
interviewed greg
all the northern lights crew got busted
yeah like it was rolling bust they got
customer lists they got all kinds of
things different people snitched
different people ratted on each other uh
somebody at 1989.
yeah 1989 operation green merchant
happened every single hydroponic store
in the country was rated same day same
time and then they took a bunch of
evidence that they got from that and
they took a bunch of people that's what
matt was saying was that they after they
raided him they made uh jordanson write
down a bunch of license plate numbers
and it's debatable on whether he gave
them real ones or not he claims that he
wrote down fake ones that were not
related to the gross store but they that
was when people used to get scared like
when i first started growing we would
always go to the grocery store in a
vehicle that a friend that lived a clean
life
yeah and i would pay him
because we were always worried about our
license plate getting written down or a
picture of the vehicle getting taken
with the license plate you know because
this had just happened
and they used to um
you know and because weed was totally
illegal everywhere
yeah and that's what got that's what got
neville thrown into
prison for a year
yep um and he was fighting extradition
to the united states and that's when he
lost his uh his seed company because he
had to sell it to the drunkards for them
to pay for him to get out of jail and
get back to holland yeah um and uh
you know and you know we we thought
about for a long time we didn't we did
that interview quite a long time ago
uh and uh we decided not to release it
mostly because our our general theme
here has sort of been like history and
weed education and and lead people
bullshitting yeah uh and most people
don't know but i was a i tried to be an
active participant in that interview uh
i just couldn't get a word in
he couldn't
he was so offended that's the first time
he's ever been quiet
yeah and then i think matt got a couple
of words in a few sentences here and
there yeah um but it was basically like
a mass monologue from the dude
and while he has an immense amount of
weed knowledge in his head and an
immense amount of stories he could tell
from that time frame
he was much more interested in telling
stories of his wild youth
and politics i think he thought the
interview was more about his life as
opposed to what we talk about
yeah we were hoping to sort of get a
weed centric
one thing that we did get was that he
did say didn't he say that the old g13
and the uw
was sort of
was one in the same yeah and i forgot a
few times in a few other places so when
i heard that i was like wait what what
what
what yeah no i mean he he i mean he was
and the the reason why we interviewed
him was because greg seattle greg of
nlfame was like this guy was there he
was around he was connected to all of us
he's the one that you need to talk to
he's the one that's gonna tell you
everything he's the one that you need to
know he has so much stuffed up in that
head yeah uh and then
uh you know it was about 45 seconds of
actual weed info
and then a bunch of you know crazy
politics and hookers and and this and
that but there was some interesting
green merchant stuff yeah the green
merchant stuff i thought was interesting
because he was really wrapped up in that
he was one of the store owners that was
raided by the feds
and he basically admitted that he had to
cooperate with them
to not go to prison for a long time yes
but that he tried to fake all the
information they got so no one else got
in trouble
yeah
you know
um
and uh
you know so uh
people are out like who knows dude uh
yeah right
but yeah but you know uw being g13 and
adding to that story and like you know
he set up tons of growers he grew a
bunch of different strains back then and
he probably could have chatted for an
hour and a half about just that yeah
but that really wasn't what interested
him so he just started
wrapping it was a very politically
charged time too it was like i think
it's right before the election so it
yeah
yeah it was probably fresh in his mind
and he's like
he's an older dead
in a retirement home i think or
something like that and so just to be
able to talk to people
you know there was a lot there was a lot
of stories
yeah
you know there was a lot of stories um
and so we didn't release it for a long
time because
um it was pretty light on wheat
yeah
you know uh it was it was certainly
colorful
sure yeah that was it was funny as hell
it was certainly colorful i mean there
was an aspect to people like where
he said he he uh he tested positive for
cocaine
yeah uh to his probation officer but it
was only because he was eating out a
hooker and he blew something like i mean
he had some pretty
it was uh
it was it was uh yeah it was um
he had some pretty crazy stories
you know yeah uh and um
you know and so but that's but with that
what that is is that's a really good
indication of
a lot of these old old-time guys that
you want to talk to you want them to
just like dish out an immense amount of
lineage and specific history yeah and a
lot of them it's really hard to get it
out of that
yeah for sure it is it's not it's it's
they either don't remember
or they didn't write it down
or you know dj short was like that
you know greg was certainly like that
when you start asking a bunch of
specifics about the various nl numbers
that was hard um if if you go back and
listen to that that first interview with
uh greg it was me and my friend kanza at
the time uh doing the interview and he
was not so much as interested in talking
about the past more talking about the
future and i think that that's a lot you
know i mean that's how a lot are
you know it's like you don't want to
diss who they are now
yeah but
what you're really after is like you
know you're lucky if you play any kind
of cool moment in history once
yeah
much less repeatedly you know so you
talk to some of these guys and it's like
they you know like you know the amount
of
knowledge and and
information that ben and alan drunkers
have
oh i'm sure but they're terrible
and everyone's told me you can't get
jack [ __ ] out of them and they just toe
the line that their business is the
exact same it's that like they don't
they won't tell it just doesn't matter
i think i think also like just because
they were there it doesn't mean that
they
paid any attention at all to what was
going on or
cared enough to memorize anything
they're business dudes you know yeah
they just it just wasn't it wasn't what
they were into you know i mean you would
think that like you know that steve that
uh that's greg would remember a bunch of
stuff but he was basically just like oh
the one and the two you know he knew a
couple things
yeah and then he was like the rest was
just a wild orgy of sativas and
different things we were trying and
notes got you in trouble so
yeah you know and nl9 never made it out
like that just for people to know that's
just never happened
um
yeah nl9 got popular i will say that nl9
was a legend and
neville sold it for like maybe one year
as a hybrid to some other [ __ ] like
maybe nl9 by skunk one or something yeah
and then it disappeared and nobody saw
it for 10 or 15 years yeah but what i'm
referring to is the nl9 from um
greg that wasn't one that was passed
yeah no and then and then all of a
sudden that the name nl9 started showing
up in canadian seed banks sure yeah
after like not not being around for a
long time yeah it was one of those ones
that like re-popped
yeah you know um
and uh yeah and so you know there's
there's parts of that where it's like
people uh you know um
oh jaime
kevin some of these old guys they're
they're like that they're they're you
know weed people are kooky
we and a lot of times we are quirky and
a lot of times we get quirkier as we age
i'm pretty [ __ ] quirky myself so i
can't throw any shade
yeah you know you're not even you're not
even all that old yet you know until
you're [ __ ] cranky and and 70 or
something like that you know yeah i have
no chance and uh yeah i am
no skunk too is interesting somebody
said my buddy had some skunk too from an
old's heads but he killed them all
um
yeah skunk too was uh i've been waiting
for someone to pop up and say they have
skunk too yeah you know it's it's it's
one of those i did hear there was there
was someone that i won't mention that's
that said they used to get it in the 90s
in arizona
oh really you know um it did exist you
know um yeah it did
it did exist you know and it was it was
a little it was taken in a little
different direction than skunk one but
it just
i don't know um
it seemed like uh
that's another one of those
skunk six and leadville somebody talked
about that that is a totally different
thing
that's a specific cut yeah right and
that cut uh and the ms and the original
mss
uh that my buddy um got back east and
brought west is the exact same cut yes
um i i believe it's lost and and as best
we know it was supposed to be what a
super skunk hybrid of some sort
yeah i mean what uh we we chatted with
the guy who made it um
uh skunk va's mentor or whatever too and
he was a little light on details like a
lot of these old guys he's kind of a you
know a rainbow cat or whatever but um he
talked about he got skunks from neville
and from super sativa seed club for two
or three years
yeah and bred them together and called
it his skunky skunk
right and then he took that
and he crossed it to super skunk when
super skunk first came out and then the
the skunk six or the super skunk that
that went to chemdawg and matt in mass
from my buddy uh who brought it west um
that's all the same pheno
of that dude's work
yes
you know uh and then
um
you know and then there's a whole story
behind that that guy had to go on the
run for some grateful dead related [ __ ]
for a long time
and it seemed like a bunch of people in
colorado called it the skunk six and our
little crew in california just referred
to it as super skunk
yes
uh both appear to be gone
me you know i mean me
i mean there's there's there's a lot of
rumor what it seems like what happened
is that there's some later stuff that's
way more afghan
that's called mss that floats around
massachusetts and that was pictured in
the high times later on uh this is very
different looking than the original one
uh it's
squatter more afghan thicker
um
all that and uh
um and so there's a lot of people i
think that have it but don't have the
first one yeah i know um there was a
selection blaze it panda did
from a uh what was it was sour dub cross
to reverse diesel that i had done
and he selected a pheno from it that was
dead on identical looking to the the
mass super skunk shown in the high times
kem dog issue and that that has made the
rounds as mass super itself and we've
tried to tell people that's not it but
it don't matter
i mean there's an aspect too where it's
like eventually because it's just a
legend to almost everyone right because
the percentage of people out there that
actually
legitimately grew the cut is quite small
actually right so
um anything that has those terps or
anything that could be plausibly claimed
we've already seen five or six years of
uh claims made without any proof
that people don't find anything right
yeah there's a whole era there where
there's there's there's companies that
put skunk on their logo real big on
their logo and they don't have any skunk
you know there's people that have
ancient skunk and old skunk and my skunk
is the rare skunk that before the skunk
got taken out of the skunk
and i don't have any wheat of it but
this is the skunky skunk or oh i got
this real mss i'm going to cross it to a
bunch of stuff
now we're going to sell all these seeds
you'll find the skunk in there for sure
yeah
and
you know and and it's like that that uh
you know but i mean anybody that came up
with anything smelling skunky would be
like that's kind of the goal that's what
people are missing
i don't i don't think it's so much the
actual cut i think it's the lost terp
yeah for the most part there's might be
some bragging rights to the old cut or
whatever
but it's it's basically more like like
skunk doesn't smell like skunk and the
closest thing we have is real diesel
the most most often when i see people
pop up and say man that [ __ ] smells
skunky is after someone has burned and
exhaled a bowl of really loud weed of
any type of smell
i see a lot of people uh pop up and say
that smells skunky after that
i kind of feel like certain old sours
you get that weird nose crinkle sure and
it's not a pure super skunk knows but
it's kind of on that same
path
yeah you know it's like an analog of it
or something like that it's a derivative
no yes you know it's a yeah it is it's a
feel and it's and they're and they're
volatile too you know so
um so there's hints out there of it and
stuff like that but
um i got i just got totally distracted
by
homie's comment
um you know but
uh we have talked about neville talked
about like crossing some of his or
shanti's old work together that had
skunk in it
and trying to see if you'd get
recessives to pop up
yeah and i think that's probably the way
to get skunk is to get
cuts of things that you think have skunk
in it
and throw them on one another
and hopefully you know you get some
recessives that pop out because that's
probably what happened with our homies
cut
the sour dub by the reverse diesel yeah
and it crybaby seen it i've seen it if
you cross two of two
different phenos of or expressions of
super skunk that are like you could
cross the lanky
longer flowering sour type with one of
the short stocky uh more mass super
mass super v2 i should say types then
usually you're going to get something in
there that's popping up that's pretty
skunky or candy push skunky
it does seem
like
using outcrosses to find it is a better
way than s1
you know yeah like it's got both of it
in there and then you're just hoping for
that thing to combine
yeah you know because it should combine
it's just a matter of uh
um it's just a matter of doing large
enough populations
sure
you know and you could do a thing if you
could do traditional breeding uh you
could do something where you got large
enough populations
where you could probably make make the
the quantity of skunk go up
yeah yeah so it's really hard to do on a
garage sized scene yeah
very
you know
um i agree with homie uh four-way is
dudded
the old-school four-way is duded it's a
shadow of its former self yeah um
there's some liars out there that think
they're knf and their various organic
treatments
heal things
yeah and while there's no doubt that you
can make a plant happier or unhappier
based on your treatment of it um that
doesn't mean it's gonna cure it of aids
yeah yeah
uh people asked i i do think it could
pop up in the la kush by chemdi
and i do think that a lot of people a
lot of people are finding potency in it
but i would not be surprised
um i wouldn't be surprised because the
the la is very diesel type and i do
believe they're super skunk and chem d
although that's controversial
um yeah you know but i'd also think
crossing different sours to each other
uh d by sour uh headbands at least the
the diesel headbands you know
um yeah we don't know if someone's
asking we don't know if uh
if if uh if tc works
there's some evidence that it does but
there's also some there's i mean it's
it's i don't know if there's a lot of
there's a lot of rumor that floats
around
and it gets mixed with fact
a lot yes there is
you know so it's not that easy to figure
i don't even know that we know the
definitive answer to all this stuff
it probably needs more testing
yeah
you know trying to find something for
the giveaway so start thinking of how
we're going to give this away
or a good competition or something i've
got to find something worth giving away
though
that sounds like something we probably
could have done off off camera but we'll
wing it i suppose nah off camera's no
fun come on now
and then tissue culture just so people
know
um
tissue culture
is just a method of doing something it
doesn't cure jack [ __ ] uh
tissue culture you can you can tissue
culture and all you're doing is
cultivating a bunch of small plantlets
yeah right um the tissue culture that
people are talking about to that
actually might clean things up uh or
like remove say like uh
you know remnants of various chemicals
that you don't want
is actually called meristem
tissue culture and it's where you take
cells from the meristem
and you regrow the whole plant
and uh it it um it took uh
you know it can take up to a year to get
that back
and the hormones are all nuts and out of
whack for a while too and we're not even
sure that it's the exact same plant
um
so there's a lot of aspects to marathon
culture that are and it's expensive too
it's like four to six thousand bucks per
plant super expensive and
barely anybody can do it correctly but a
lot of people will tell you they can so
there's people like there's people like
dark heart that spread the dud all over
the place
that then offer tissue culture and heat
treatment that they claim kills the dud
then you hear from other nurseries and
friends that you trust that it doesn't
really kill the dud on a perfect level
but they're gonna charge you for it
um
you know so
there's uh you know there's a lot of
there's a lot of issues with it on that
level
um and you know the disease is getting
very prevalent uh and there's a lot of
old strains that suffer from it
there's even rumor um that i don't know
that's proven that a certain percentage
of seeds made from dutted stuff the
virus carries into the children into the
beans
yeah and i don't think that's proven
i've heard as high as 50 and as low as
two or three percent
yeah then i've heard uh various friends
of mine including csi and others tell me
that they've grown out testers and
everything looked fine
yeah um so i think it's really hard to
say
you know i mean you could you could
still have a virus inside of you that
you wouldn't have it wouldn't have a
a physically visible level
that's very true you know
so
um
you know so tc is thrown around pretty
loosely uh the only pc that cleans
anything up to my knowledge is marathon
that's how i understand it
you know and meristem basically like get
mostly what it does really well is it
will clean your plant up if it was if
imma chloroplate or avid or a bunch of
funk was used on it
because those cells are taken from the
meristem not from the vascular system
yeah and so it's sort of like avoid the
area of the plant that's contaminated
and you can grow it back
um
but uh
you know um
the the dudding or the you know the the
uh you know the virus the viroid or
whatever
um
it basically spread everywhere because
when everyone started getting clones
from
dispensaries and everyone started
getting clones from certain nurseries
and nurseries sort of became a clearing
house for a bunch of plants
they spread it to thousands and
thousands and thousands of dollars of
gardens i mean
yeah you know and then once that
happened those gardens started spreading
it to their friends
you know and a lot of times
you know back in the day you'd use a
razor taking clones until it got dull
yeah
you know and now you need to per plant
you need to take a lot of different
things into account
and and that that one
vira viroid that causes dutting isn't
the only dutting
issue
there's other diseases
um you know uh tmv is the most famous
one that everything anything wrong with
weed for a long time people would be
like oh you got the tmv oh yeah for sure
and people used to think that like the
the uh mosaic or the variegation that
used to happen in chem strains and other
afghans was a sure sign of of uh tmv
yeah you know but i will say
that if you talk to tobacco people right
um they do treat tmv extremely seriously
and they do they don't allow harvester
you know people uh doing transplanting
and working on their stuff you can't
have a smoker in the home
yeah and you have to take off all your
clothes and get and go through a process
to get in there so it does spread
and you can definitely get it on your
hands from smoking cigarettes and you
can pass it
um
you know but
but there's there's pithium and fusarium
that are there's molds there's viruses
there's thyroids there's diseases and uh
they mostly were were
minimal in the illegal 215 era sure and
now they're all over the place
yeah um you know
so
you know um
yeah i mean yeah someone just said tmv
can wipe out a whole tobacco prop they
do they take a bunch of precautions
even by touch
yeah you know
uh
and um someone said that you know uh
someone said that russets don't dud a
plant out dudding is what we call
russets can i suppose
um
did i just lose you
oh did he freeze there he is am i back
you came back
yep
there i am did i freeze
yep i froze i don't know what the hell
happened but anyway there's there's a
lot of there's a lot of uh
um there's a lot of disease there's a
lot of there's a lot of stuff out there
that people didn't have to worry about
before
and as things have gotten commercialized
and as things have gotten spread around
um
you know it's become it's become a way
bigger issue
uh and it would be easier if it would be
easier if it didn't transfer to seat
not so froze am i back now can you
everyone hear me in real time
yeah you're back
i think
i can hear you you think
i can hear you in real time yeah bad
russet infestation can look like a
viroid
um
you know and there's then there's rumors
too that thrips and other and other uh
insects can spread
viroids or spread diseases like
mosquitoes can spread um you know
malaria and [ __ ] like that
yeah so
uh there's a lot of risks out there
there's a lot of risk out there they
didn't do before in the 90s i didn't
worry about anything
i've never seen pm
and an occasional bug every now and
again
no viruses no diseases no worries but
we've had friends that have taken out
their whole garden
yeah lost irreplaceable
and lost irreplaceable [ __ ]
you know
so
matt's over here in in real time going
through a seed collection and grunting
to himself and all that so
i'm really giving it his full attention
right now oh yeah you know
found some [ __ ] i didn't remember i had
some old afghanis and [ __ ] here
but it's interesting people are talking
about condoms or stds and stuff like
that like
you know it's it's it's it's they're
obviously plants so they're not human
beings but there is some correlation
between the various things that got
spread around
and the hiv aids crisis
yeah and that there was something
spreading that was harming and people
didn't know what it was and they didn't
know what to test for it and they didn't
know how to take precautions about it
um and so it spread like wildfire you
know yeah leaf hoppers normally uh they
they pass this curly top beat virus
thing
um so there's a bunch of there's a bunch
of diseases and some of them probably
existed for a while and like people just
weren't getting the proper testing
because why would you help why would you
do that
yeah you know because you're you're
you're in the in the shadows or whatever
um
and uh
you know and
you know they uh
oh man
i just got totally distracted by
somebody's comment i'm not gonna repeat
it but but they uh
but yeah they you know and and most of
the time when people were trading
cuttings
uh or uh or you know or or selling their
friends cuttings it was all within
little circles
yeah you know and it wasn't until the
215 era and these big centralized
nurseries
that things started getting spread all
over
yeah
you know and then once it reaches a
certain point it becomes really easy to
spread and then you're spreading it to
your friends and you don't know what
have and then
you know a lot of people would uh a lot
of people would give up on creating
their own mothers
um and and making their own clones and
they'd just be like [ __ ] the veg i'm
just gonna go to wherever and buy 200
cuts when it's time
yeah
you know um and uh
yeah weird comment of the united that's
what that's what gets me into trouble is
it's hard to [ __ ] and read comments
in real time when you read that
the other
yeah if you read a comment out loud it's
super offensive yeah
yeah so you can get it's you know you
can get thrown off the game
and so we made it we made it like an
hour and a half without actually talking
about
one of the things that uh
uh i don't think does pip have the
shoreline i don't i i don't know i don't
think he does we have some good friends
of ours that do and pip's a good friend
of ours but i don't think he does
um i don't think but we have we have
some really close friends of ours that
have had it for quite some time
um
and uh
it's fire i like it
i wouldn't consider uh people tell me
it's not it's people ask if it's rks
i would say it's skunky is from what
everyone tells me and it's got it's got
rankness to it but i wouldn't say that
it's uh
i'd say it's not sweet and then a lot of
people confuse not sweet for roadkill
skunk
yeah
if i was being a hundred
if you're being a hundred percent
yeah you know yeah uh kim was selling
chem four clones the other day at his
dyspo and
and massachusetts i mean you know kim
four is kim four is the uh
kim four is probably the most widely
spread chem
yeah you know it's that one being spread
out the largest it throws really nice
bats
um it's probably the least hoarded of
the one
of all of it you know it's still one of
my faves too out of the um
out of the cam
491 or de i prefer cam 4 for for what i
like
yeah i mean the most most people's
issues with chem 4 is that it's like 12
weeks
yeah uh and you can pull it at 10.
so there's a lot of people that pull it
at 10.
yeah that makes sense
uh
104 is not very close to the d in my
opinion no
no chem four is a big
lanky long running buds kind of hazy
uh type of not hazy in in like when
people think terpentally and i just mean
like
and it has kind of a racy buzz to it
um
and uh
do i think the cannabis community is
being infiltrated to destroy homegrowns
i think it's always i think that's
always been happening uh i don't i don't
know that uh i don't know that's never
not happened i think it's ebbed and
flowed how intense it's been
um but i think home grows have always
had
uh some issues
um and the main issue i used to have
with chem four
is that in california
you can everyone wants you to flush your
weed immensely right but nobody wants a
hint of yellow on anything yeah because
then they think you [ __ ] it up and
then they want less right
and chem 4 a lot of times
dries a slight light golden brown yeah
the golden the golden a little golden
color and that golden color
is um
uh
you know is bad people don't like the
golden color it can be fresh weed it can
be sticky it can be cured amazing it can
be fantastical and they'll get a little
hint they'll be like looking at the
calyxes and be like ah
you know it's got a little hint of brown
it makes me uncomfortable
you know um and
you think of anything for a giveaway
i haven't actually been thinking about a
giveaway dude i've been [ __ ] talking
[ __ ] well yeah i know you look
down it's called flow dawg
[Laughter]
and i don't think i don't think so chem
4 is a big tall rangy plant
uh chem d is a much squatter afghan
it's it's it's uh lighter green in a lot
of ways um it's just this whole
structure is different i don't think
chem 4 and chem d are very similar at
all
you know i agree uh
and uh it doesn't it definitely doesn't
take 84 days
you know
and what's interesting is we had our
buddy pip actually take an 84 day piece
of chem 4 and lay it on top of a picture
of neville's
uh 89 nl5 haze bud
and you could barely tell the difference
sure
you know
uh i do think there's haze in chem 4.
yeah i think that i think that i think
that it could be
91 by nl5 hayes maybe
i don't know
uh they're trying let's get back to
skunk tons of people are working on
skunk lines dude it's just that they're
mostly not skunk
yeah and i i always have to preface this
because people every time i have to
restart it and say it
when we say skunk we do not mean
necessarily skunk one what we're
referring to is the smell of a skunk
when we say it's skunky we're not saying
oh it's like skunk one we're saying it's
skunky so just just to preface that so
people don't confuse us saying skunk one
for skunk they are two different things
in my opinion yeah skunk one is floral
or citrus or maybe a little cheese
uh maybe some grapes
um you know
anything like that it doesn't have any
you know what people are talking about
is arc they want that rank nose curdling
pure skunk spray type of smell yeah you
know and there's a lot of people
you know uh we were supposed to talk
about about uh
uh breeding techniques and stuff like
that we never really got there
uh people ask are they working there's
not really very many lines being worked
right now by very many people
you know most people are most people are
doing one-offs of things they hope are
skunky and hoping you'll find skunk in
them
or just straight frauds because there's
now there's so many people that want it
there's a bunch of people jumping in
claiming to have it
you know
yeah and they know that you can't they
know that you can't tell them they don't
have it until x amount of months and
most people will sit on them so yeah you
know i mean
you can go through there's you know
there's people like you know blue or sky
vienna that [ __ ] has their own story
and they they have the skunkiest skunk
that's ever skunked but nobody finds
skunk in their beans
and you know there's a bunch of people
doing it that you know there there's not
there's something that's not there
and there's a market demand for it and
people are jumping in and saying you're
going to get skunked from me any day
yep you're going to find this is
unbelievably skunky you're going to find
skunk in it and then they sell a bunch
of what you know what do you people call
it hopium
hope you know opium hope you sell a
bunch of sell a bunch of addictive opium
you know
um
me and bodie were working on
just specifically finding
that type of thigh or smell in in old
lines and he went one direction i think
he went and looked in some afghani stew
and i popped a bunch of afghanis looking
for it
and i got very lucky and found something
early on it's not the easiest thing to
reproduce but i found ways to to
reproduce it
but by that point literally everyone had
jumped on the train selling skunk one of
everything or hybrids of skunk won
everything and saying it's gunky
um you had the blue skies vienna people
pick in and nobody wants to be
associated with that [ __ ] so some of us
just said [ __ ] it and walked away walked
away from it for good just because it's
i think it's easy to find now and i
think if you look in the right places
it's very easy to come across
and i think it's out there for people if
they really really want it you know
yeah somebody's just skunk lines over
9000 skunk clones zero yeah you know
i don't know you'd be a millionaire or
whatever else because it's like you
could have a cutting that did it but
it's like you
i mean maybe you may make a bunch of
money i mean one of the things like
pandas cutting does it to a tee
especially if you follow what uh csi
said pretty pretty openly about the best
way to get uh skunky line to express
skunky
but it's not conducive to
having skunky bud that you can carry
around for a month and sell it's just
not going to happen it's it's it's very
very um volatile compounds
you know and and i think it's obviously
got a recessive trait
and it's one of those things like people
talk about
people don't know this about genetics or
whatever but like i was talking about it
the other night where blond hair and
blue eyes is only like 11 000 years old
in humanity
yeah it's a mutation right and it's a
recessive so if you don't if both
parents don't have the recessive you
can't have it
so you go to like nordic countries or
something like that and there's a bunch
of it
but they say eventually as people mix
it's going to get lost and it's almost
never going to pop up because there's
going to the dominance are going to be
all over the place yeah and i think
that's what happened is in the 90s
there was more there was more plants
that both had the recessive
and so it could pop and be and be you
know an expressive trait in those things
and then as it got bred out and people
lost it and it got bred with other
things it kind of became a recessive
terp
and then you're trying to look for it to
pop
right
and there's certain terpenes there's
certain smells that are very dominant
penalty yeah yeah sure you know citrus
you know
you know a lot of times you can cross
something and something like 70 or 80
percent of its progeny will have had to
have that aroma strong
sure and then other times there's stuff
where it's only going to pop up in a
limited population
you know so for instance to use the
human example if you've got a bunch of
nordic people mating
right like a bunch of swedes or finnish
or whatever you get a bunch of blonde
hair blue-eyed kids
yeah but if every generation they
started like marrying africans or
mexicans or chinese or something
within a certain number of generations
the blue eyes and blonde hair would go
away or be a super rare thing to catch
up yeah
you know and we haven't really studied
which traits in cannabis are recessive
and dominant all we know
we have no idea we just have
observational data yeah exactly
shared amongst friends we don't have any
scientific basis
we just have observations
um but if it was dominant it'd be easy
to find
yeah i mean nothing and literally every
single person
that has claimed that they were six or
nine or 12 months away from releasing
perfect skunk to the community that was
gonna change the game
none of it has ever happened not yet
no i mean that was that was what that
was duke's claim to fame right when
dominion first came out he had a huge
skunk on the on all his shirts and he
was you know he was six months away from
walking in
skunk terps permanently from ancient
skunk
blue or sky vienna all these different
folks but then people don't find it in
the beans
no it's hard and
and the the best advice i'll even i'll
even repeat it for people that don't
understand and don't know
a lot of the reason you're not going to
see it is because we grow weeds so much
differently we cure differently we dry
differently how quickly wet weed moves
doesn't happen anymore you know like
people don't you're not buying wet weed
anymore
there's a lot a lot different going on
than was back then and if people kind of
applied some of those techniques to it
you'd see it pop up very fast i also
think too that all these techniques that
that
um he's talking about you can coax skunk
out but i do believe that there was
strains once upon a time because people
are talking about well maybe we were
just confused
no
no it's just something that went away
yeah through prohibition
and people getting rid of it and
changing
changing eras
you know
i mean imagine
20 years ago
you're [ __ ]
growing a bunch of skunk weed and it
smells rank skunk and you're having a
problem selling it and then your broker
buddy is like dude if you just grow this
urkel you can sell every gram
so you stop selling skunk
yeah and you get rid of the skunk and
you lose the skunk
because you're growing urkel and then
you move on from urkel to
freaking kush and then you move on from
kush to sour and then you move on to
skittles and then somewhere 10 years
later somebody's like you know oh man i
wish we had some skunk
but you got rid of that [ __ ] no one
yeah
never looked back
and then it was like not popular for
long enough that when the time when
everyone looked around and was like
where'd it go it was gone
yeah people were asking
when it showed up and i think i think
most people agree that whenever the
afghanis started showing up in
california is when the skunk started
popping up if you want to believe sam
skunk man
he'll say that in the start of skunk one
um i post you know that it popped up in
most phenos
that it was dominant that you didn't
have to look for it it didn't matter if
it was
who it was grown by where it was grown
what nutrients you use they came out
skunky
and it does seem when we interviewed
corel uh from super sativa seed club he
said the first skunk seeds that he got
from sam were much much much skunkier
than what came later yeah
and neville
got those same seats
and
you know i think the reason why the
super skunk got lost
is because they lost the breeding male
that through those skunk terps you know
and you know he they used that skunk
mail and all kinds of stuff and so i
think it was prevalent in the 90s with a
lot of those hybrids
and then times changed
and it was i mean i grew that old school
super skunk right
and
you know some people call the skunk six
and it really was
scary
yeah you know it made around your house
smell ridiculous for the last two weeks
before harvest
it was even before you really had um
carbon filters were really sold
yeah right so you'd have like the old
like uh juvenile like ozone generators
yeah and you'd run it you'd run the
ozone through like 30 40 feet of pipe
and a coil and then you'd blow it out
your house
but i used to pull up in summer and it
smelled like dead skunks all around my
house yeah
it was scary where you by your neighbors
you worry about getting in trouble you
know people talk about it going through
the bag yeah right well what if it reeks
like a dead skunk for 50 yards in every
direction for your house for two weeks
out of every eight
yeah that's sketchy
um people keep asking about shoreline we
mentioned a little bit ago i got to try
outdoor shoreline
and i thought it was pretty well grown
the person who gave it to me said it
wasn't but he's very humble and then i
got to try some indoor from bitter that
he had grown and i got i
i think it smells like hot garbage um
indoor and then outdoors smelled a lot
like real cat piss not terpenoline but
real cat piss ammonia um hot garbage so
it's i mean it just depends on what your
definition of skunk is and my nose i put
a lot of stuff up it when i was young so
i don't smell things certain smells i
can't smell lemon and a lot of stuff
that other people can so
it's hard to say it's hard to say yeah i
mean most of my most of my friends one
of the reasons why we we lost it was
i couldn't get anybody to help me back
it up
yeah i believe it yeah you know because
people didn't want to grow it out it was
risky and they were making good money
and growing other things yeah
and that's how a lot of stuff will get
lost is like they'll be like oh well you
know you can hold on to it yeah it's a
lot of extra risk for not a lot of extra
bucks and then and then you're in the
and then you're in the spot where it's
like then it's one bust or one fire or
one mistake or one mishap away from
losing it
and then you start trying to hunt it
down you know
somebody said that l.a cushion chem d is
pretty skunky um that's good that you
found that i would not be surprised
because i think both of those strains
have super skunk in them
yeah i would not be surprised on some
level to see
somewhere in there those those genes
combine
yeah and that kind of stuff to
to to come back up but you know it's
it's a numbers game
you know it's a numbers game uh so hob's
breath um someone asked about the
hogsworth lineage it it expresses very
afghani probably has some skunk one in
it i mean it has like a depending on how
you grow it slightly cheesy just
slightly sweet smell
um foot funk is probably my best
description of it though other people
smell different things in it um
it was said to be williams wonder to
northern lights uh to a northern lights
back cross there was all kinds of
different things people said but
probably if i had to guess
some sort of skunk one nl5 maybe
something williams wonder maybe i don't
know it's hard to say afghani
afghanistan of some sort
yeah so i mean it i think
i think people there's a lot better
chance for people to find it and some
random cuts like our buddies uh you know
uh panda that we were talking about yeah
pop up it'd be another thing if that
person could actually take it that cut
and then turn that into a line that
people would you know with at least with
a reasonable level of certainty find
some skunk in
yeah because that's that's where it all
falls apart is to be like oh you're
gonna get some skunk soon and then all
the beans they sell people don't find it
yeah you know
um
and uh you know so
you know they um you know there's all
kinds of people saying oh i've got this
oh i've got that oh i've got amazing
things and it'd be great if people did
but um nobody's really popped up with it
i mean we even had that that that
[ __ ] joint breath or whatever he
[ __ ] went to he went to like one of
those colorado uh one of those colorado
cannabis shows
and he got skunk spray from uh
that was [ __ ] that was emerald cup he
did it
he did that emerald cup or whatever yeah
and he went and got some skunk spray
aroma from uh
from uh you know it's called kinks
yeah from from the outdoor store you
know hunting you know kabbalah's or
something and and and rubbed it all over
his his jar
yeah so that he could crack the jar and
be like you want to buy my seeds this is
rank
and then people would be like oh my god
this just stinks and then they'd go to
smell the bud and they could and they
it's like they could barely smell it
because only a little bit of it had
gotten on there
one one of the people he let walk away
with some buds of it and in their bag
was just this orange oil all across the
back
yeah i mean that was pretty sweet i got
to give him props for actually doing
that a lot of people joke about doing
that but that one actually that was
actually he actually went for it you
know yeah and um and there's an aspect
too where you know they uh
um so yeah there's a bunch of people
that have claimed it
uh and uh
um i don't i like people talk about i do
believe that there's a way to make some
things express skunkier than they do
but i also believe that there was some
there's some plants out there
um that have a straight skunk nose
i i find it hard to believe that
anything after a full dry and after a
full cure it's going to smell super
skunky i just don't think it can be
captured like that
based on what it is that old cut had it
100 percent yeah even even like super
far
right yeah i mean it would only last
them i'll give you it would only last
you know uh a month yeah i mean anything
and then eventually
but certainly like the first two three
four weeks you had dry wheat of it yeah
it reeked unbelievably yeah 100 it
didn't go away um and so
you know i uh
you know they um
i think it's out there but i think that
the level of breeding required to lock
it in is not profitable enough
to get people to actually do the work
to make it all happen
yeah
and have everybody grow the same way so
it expresses the same way most because
most breeding you know there's some we
have some friends like you know archive
or kayla uh csi or you know there's matt
you know we have some good friends that
that that do multi-stage breeding
but the vast majority of breeding today
is is one-offs and they move on to
something else yeah it's not super
there's not they don't take something
and and like they're like oh i'm gonna
make this thing and then i'm gonna grow
out a thousand of them or 500 of them or
200 of them and select and re-breed and
it's almost all
uh
you know
um
it's almost all one-offs
st you know reversals and one-ups right
yeah i mean how many people do you see
finding stuff within their own work and
then using that in further work
yeah it's it's minimal and it's most
most common for someone to be like i
reverse this plant onto these plants
here's the names here's the packaging
my next drop will be this other plant
reversed onto these other plants and
yeah you know and so on and so forth
so
you know i mean rc archive on here
archive is one of the few people that is
like oh i got these phenos that i made
from my own stuff yeah and i'm gonna
work with it matt's done that you can
watch csi do it on his page
there's people that do it
uh it's not as profitable
and so trying to find someone that's
really gonna take all the failure
involved to
actually find rks
uh is probably rare
yeah
man
indeed
okay let's do let's get this giveaway
ready so
i'm just i literally picked just like
four random things one's a blue bonnet
mix so this is a mixture of different
whatever like females in a mixture
there's like 20 seeds in there or more
uh one's a
a durbin yeti fuel hybrid that i've
released is something called project
fruit was just fruity and i'm not big on
fruity but it was decent it had good
yield
one is uh
the narrow leaf bubba what i don't know
if it was really an s1 or if it was
[ __ ] paul and katan probably bonkin
down crossing the heirloom afghani mill
and then the old calio cut across to the
z cube skittles bx3 so we got to give
this away to someone i don't know how
we're going to do it yet um
so what matt doesn't realize is i i save
my botox for there so it's actually
it's it's uh uh it's probably the best
looking part of me really so i think i
have an idea i have an idea so whoever
gives whoever not so selects as the
funniest response
to the
to the given genetics for the strain
called natso's old balls so not those
old balls what are the genetics in it
whoever has the the funniest or best
answer you'll you'll get these four
people and it has to be it has to be
someone in the usa that's important
i'm not paying [ __ ] 20 bucks to send
you seats it's not gonna happen the
dumpster still exists
yeah you know yeah it's gotta be a
hybrid the dumpster still exists yeah um
you know
cali o is probably cali oh by skunk one
yes uh that's that's probably what uh
what what's what realistic is realistic
you know yes growth that's actually
plant-based should win i mean he just
said scrotox
um which yeah i don't know that might be
that might be the winner yeah um scrotux
is going to be hard to beat scrotox is
really uh
um
yeah boy you know but yeah that's that's
that that's that's how they look so
smooth and young
most people wasted most people wasted on
their face you know and on their
forehead and they try to work on these
lines and stuff like that but yeah you
know that's that's that's that's wasted
there that is that's a total waste
that's wasted you know
so uh
indeed
indeed so
they uh god the names that are gonna
come in and you [ __ ] me
yeah oh yeah this is a good one i i i
think um joe cool said scrow talks first
so joe cool i think you're in the u.s so
yeah
joe cool is
joe cool hit me up after i'll make sure
these go to you
um and then maybe we're getting close
we're getting close to the end but maybe
i'll do a rant
oh yeah
um sure so we were we almost got to it
earlier and then we got sidetracked and
uh
and thrown not so firm is pretty good
not so firm it's also pretty good yeah
but we were talking about like people
were asking a bunch of questions
and um
you know and uh
i think maybe just a brief like sort of
like what
what people get with seeds has changed a
lot
yeah so i was just talking now where
it's like really um what it boils down
to is right now what you get is you get
a lot of like one-off hybrids
that are sold and they exist until the
guy runs out of stock and then they're
gone
yep that's that's that's most of the
industry right now
is one offs but you go back 25 30 years
or something and that was not how things
were most seed companies sold lines yeah
okay and there's a concept called
um you know what's your floor what's
your ceiling
right and what what that is is that it's
like is your seed line does it have a
high floor which where most of them are
pretty decent but a low ceiling where
you're not going to find any elites
yeah or does it have like a low floor
where you could get some true junk and a
bunch of mids
but it actually has a high ceiling where
you could get some true elites mixed in
there
and people have this idea that in the
90s and all that in amsterdam like there
was all this magical weed
that's the weed that survived
yeah there was a lot of junk and there
was a lot of mids
right um and back then it was better
than mexican
so we
people were a lot more forgiving oh just
random kind bud because all random kind
buds still sold because it wasn't so
clone-centric or anything like that
right so you had a situation where
i don't know i don't know how i don't
know how to say it i probably have
bought 10 or 15 packs of scentsy and l5
haze
in the mid 90s so that's probably i
don't know it's over 100 seeds yeah i
didn't find an amazing keeper
yeah but yet there's pif and cuban
there's all these different named phenos
yeah from those exact same seeds that
are still around 30 years later and
they're the [ __ ] bomb and they're
still like competing with today's
strains and they're still still like
today's strains yeah and there's certain
old strains you know that stand the test
of time
and you know you might run through five
or six well today as matt will tell you
if you bought three or four packs of
matt's work
and all you found was junk and not a
single keeper you would be [ __ ]
typing on your keyboard and making his
life miserable because you'd be [ __ ]
pissed
so yes there's a lot of pressure today
to have a high floor with your breeding
so people will get stuff that is decent
enough that they won't [ __ ] yeah
and even back in the day 30 years ago
neville used to
neville used to complain that he had
these like you know afghan by afghan
amazing hybrids
right like that he wanted to release but
if people got 10 or 20 percent less
yield than the out crosses they'd [ __ ]
up a storm yeah so breeders are always
thinking about
what will sell
what's feasible you have to right and so
there's a lot of great weed that someone
would be like this is amazing weed
but it herms yeah so i can't sell it
because it'll be just endless
memes about me if you i mean all it
takes is one customer posting one good
picture of one single plant herming even
if it's in like you can tell the plants
all burnt up and it doesn't matter even
if they could show that one time it can
ruin a line for good that's just how it
goes you know so there's a bunch of so
there's a bunch of [ __ ] where if it
herms it won't get released
if it's too leafy if it's too low
yielding if it's to this if it's too
that it won't get released yeah right at
least back in the day and so there was a
lot of
there was a lot of uh there was a lot of
strains that never got released that
they thought were killer weed
but they didn't meet commercial
standards yeah right and now
weed has to be [ __ ] pretty
yeah cookies on all these different
hybrids have made ugly weed a really
hard sell
so what happens what happens if you have
some amazing tasting
amazing effect
kind of ugly weed that herms a little
that weed is [ __ ]
yeah
you know like and they probably won't
get released
um but it's amazing
but some pretty some pretty mids
that will get released every time
yeah you know the you know and and all
that and so
um
you know there's an aspect where it's
like
you know because more weed was accepted
in the 90s because it was better than
mexican it allowed a wide variety of
kinds of weed to flourish yeah it did it
really allowed and this whole naming of
clone thing has led to the same same
getting grown by everybody
and then that same weed gets crossed to
everything
and then everything's a blend of
cushmans and and kush and cookie and
this and that and skittles and da da da
da and you know and people talk about
purple punch purple punch has everything
but hot
i don't like that plant goddamn yeah but
there's so many mids and now that
there's now that there's modern
marketing and everybody has to have
white hot fire yeah there's there's all
these things that i call minzy elites
and then there's this thing where it's
like
if it's not an elite and it's not junk
and it's not mids what is it
we don't even have a name for better
than mids but not quite elite yeah no we
don't it's like junk mids elite
three-step process but there's things
that fall on that spectrum that don't
have like i have weed that i really love
and i'd be super bummed if i lost it
but i wouldn't consider it like in my
top 10 or 15 cuts
yeah as far as like effect
but i'd be super bummed if i lost it
you know which one are you thinking of
specifically right this second like the
maui i knew it i knew it i knew it okay
just because just because of like if you
were gonna compare the maui's high
yeah to say like my favorite highs out
there like an amazing nl5 haze vino or
chem 91 or chem d or the headband it's
not as good yeah but is it frosty and
has amazing flavor and like you know
throws nice purple chunks and is a great
yielder and like it has amazing features
yeah
but it's it's it doesn't have any elite
high you know
huh but you know it's an interesting
anomaly um among maybe instagram weed
today that i've noticed is the chem 91
because it's not exceptionally pretty it
is actually if you ask me it's
exceptionally ugly most of the time it's
very ugly
it's very hard to take good pictures of
it and most of its value is in the high
yeah and it's rare potency and it's rare
potency which is something you can't
convey in pictures yet still today it's
it sticks around and there's enough
people that say it's some of the best
weed of all time yeah that there's group
think there and people want to try some
of the best weed of all time yeah fomo
for sure
you know but and a lot of times the when
it looks the prettiest
is the people that cut it way too early
in my opinion like 53 or 55 days
yeah if you take it the full 70 plus or
something it looks more ugly yeah but it
works really good skunk va makes it look
beautiful when he grows it and i i never
got it to look like that it was always
just even when i tried to shut it down
on light hours like lower light hours
anything i would do would be endless
white pistols burn up ass [ __ ] leaves
it would just look hideous well you know
one of the things i'll say and maybe
i'll bring up like uh some totally
random [ __ ] like crockett and dna for a
second yeah
one of the things they did that was
really smart
when they started selling all their
strawberry banana and all those hybrids
and they were blowing up the emerald cup
is they grew out greenhouses of that
weed
and then they got professional
photographers with really good equipment
that understood lighting and understood
all that and color to come out and take
jaw-droppingly beautiful shots
and so that makes a difference too like
you might be sitting there and be like
man i can't get a good picture of this
right because you're not and i do the
same thing i'll be i'll take pictures of
weed and i'll be like i'm not that happy
with it
yeah you know but you get a professional
in there and they're like working on
shutter speed and aperture and they know
the lighting and they have this they
have the that and they'll make it look
like a million bucks
you know and so they were smart to like
pay for professional marketing
yeah by getting professional photos
subcool was a master at that and
absolutely he had some of the prettiest
[ __ ] pictures back in the day it
didn't matter that it was all space
queen you know it didn't matter it was
just
they look beautiful humans humans are
visual
yeah you know humans are visual so
i don't know we uh um
we're almost at nine o'clock here we
actually bullshitted for a couple hours
uh imagine that i'll be doing it
i am appreciative of everyone that
showed up
matt does his normal spiel uh yeah homie
that homie that came up with uh
um
yeah i don't know i mean i just randomly
picked it but i don't think anybody's
gonna
uh
beat that name so
yeah no no i yeah i know who gets it
matt yes he gets it thank you all for
your friday night as always thank you
for listening thank you for chatting
reach out to me or matt on ig
uh you can always ask for suggestions uh
of what you want to hear talked about
stories you want to hear things you want
to know about reach out to us we always
like chatting about what people are
interested in
appreciate your friday night you can see
us on uh the breeder syndicate you can
see us on ig i'll let matt do his thing
all right yeah um
it's sometimes it's easiest to get a
hold of us on our uh raider syndicate
patreon on our discord there um i think
it's like five bucks a month to join the
breeder syndicate patreon we all shoot
the [ __ ] there i think there's some
fights tomorrow night we're going to
watch um go check out riotsico.com i'm
throwing a bunch of stuff i just got
done moving and found a bunch of old
packs of stuff and random stuff that
i've never released so i'm going to be
putting up a bunch on the site this
weekend so
and i might do an option tomorrow i'm
not sure on the right sideco name so
check that out and uh check out
speakeasy seed bank they help us produce
the podcast when those go up
and uh i think yeah we're just gonna get
patreon find us
that's it
enjoy your friday night everyone bye
everyone