What up, fam? It's me, Chuck Dog. I
gotta give everybody a little warning.
YouTube don't like us much. So, I just
wanted to take a second to say warning.
This video is probably like rated R.
Don't watch it if you're a kid.
Everything in this video is a prop and
it's all for educational purposes only.
So, don't do what I do. Stay in school
and don't be a fool. But I just had to
get that out of the way real quick. All
right, Chuck Dog
here. After a long day in the garden and
outside in the hot sun weed eating,
there's only going to be one thing I
turn to in the refrigerator, and that's
a Ke stream classic cannabis infused
soda. These things come in seven, eight
different flavors. They're packed with
100 milligrams of THC that's going to
send you to the next
stratosphere. So, next time you get hot
and you want to keep it
extreme, reach for a keef
extreme. So, here's the deal, guys. We
just cracked open a Kef Extreme
uh Purple Passion. Okay, that little
skit you saw there, that's how we would
run a sponsorship ad if we had some. So,
you know, Keith or uh somebody else holl
at your boy, you know, can I shout out?
I could really use some Bloom. That
stuff's expensive. But here's the deal.
It's about an hour or so before I'm
going to film. I just got uh Keith
Extreme cracked open. Now, I'm not
sponsored by these people. I looked into
them a little bit. Uh, it looks like the
guy started this back in uh 2010 or
something like that. So, I don't really
know much about the guy or the company.
So, you know, as always, y'all do your
research. Uh, unlike me, cuz you know,
if these people are good or bad, I'm not
really sure the companies. You know, it
is what it is. But, we're going to have
some fun. I'm going to chug this Kef
Extreme right here, boy. And I'm going
to see what happens. You know, I tried
one out yesterday. The blue raspberry
got me a little little lifted. You know,
I didn't I didn't chug it though. But we
going to sit here. We going we going to
get this one down. We going to chill for
a second. And uh you know, I need to go
get something to eat before we start the
show. But we going to try to see if we
can bring a Ke extreme. We going to keep
it extreme. And we're going to do the
show and see if we can make it through.
So uh
cheers.
Now it's pretty good, bro. Tastes like
kind of like a watered down grape grape
soda, you
know. Can't taste much of the THC in
there. I could more in the raspberry one
yesterday, but it was uh lukewarm. You
know, you don't want to drink these
lukewarm. This is ice cold. I'm talking
colder than a witch's
titty. I'm excited for it, y'all. We
gonna rock out. Anyways, I'm not gonna
sit here. I'm not a chugger. I I've
never really, you know, a deep I'm not
much of a deep throer or a chugger. So,
especially when it's ice cold like this.
So, I'm going to finish this off. I'm
going run inside. I'm going to get some
stuff ready and then we're going to jump
right into the show. For y'all, it's
going to be instant for me. It's going
to take a second. So, anyways, I'm gonna
finish this up and catch y'all back here
in just a second. We got a good show
coming up. A like, a comment, subscribe
would uh be appreciated. Thanks.
Holy Holy crap,
bro. I'm just kidding,
guys. Hey, can y'all hear me? I'm live.
I'm live here, boys. I'm live, gals.
Anyways, what's going on? I'm Chuck. If
you don't know me by now, uh you should.
I'm somewhat of a big deal in Kentucky.
I'm slowly blowing up in the cano world
thanks to Matt and crew. And I just
wanted to say I appreciate you. Thanks
for all the love, the support, the
messages, all the all y'all. Everybody,
gals, girls, men's, every one of y'all.
I got messages from the south, the dirty
south. Everybody writing me saying,
"Hey, Chuck Dog, I appreciate you, bro.
I'm from the South. I'm from Tennessee.
I'm from Georgia. I'm from Florida. I'm
from these places. I'm down south, bro.
and I I relate to you and I I I rock
with you and I think you're a cool guy
and I appreciate y'all and I appreciate
the support. Uh you know y'all who I do
it for. I do it for everybody but I you
know I I got a special place for all my
homies down south. You know uh but it is
what it is. I wanted to also say we got
it wrong on the last episode y'all and I
apologize. The blue zushi that I got was
not blue zushi. I should have looked
more into the cross but I was lazy. I
just I got consumed by the blueberry
smell and I just assumed blue means
blueberry in the blue zushi. But it
apparently it was, you know, kush mints,
cross or whatever. I don't really know
and I don't particularly care a whole
lot, but that's part of going to the rec
stores, you guys. You get ripped off
sometimes. And that's a lesson learned.
You know, would I say I'm at was
extremely dissatisfied with what I got?
Not really. I'm used to hood packs. I'm
used to things not being named what
they're supposed to be. It is what it
is. I thought it was more interesting
that it it had a blueberry chirps
blueberry kind of flavor to it. Smell or
not flavor, but a smell similar to the
blueberry from Matt. And that's that's
really what I took away from that whole
little experience. But speaking of
dispensaries, we got a little show for
y'all today. I'm I'm keeping it extreme.
I'm jacked off jacked off. I'm jacked up
on Keef Extreme. If y'all don't know
what it is in the intro, I know what the
heck this guy's buying drinks or little
fizzy pop. Sod pops. What is it they say
out out uh you know in the middle of the
country up north? They sody pop. Uh we
say Coke in in Kentucky. Everything's
Coke. It don't matter if it's Mountain
Dew. I want a Coke. I want a Coke, but I
want the mount a Mountain Dew. Okay. But
the main thing is I'm jacked up on Kefir
Extreme. Like I said in the intro, I
don't know anything about these people.
I looked a little bit up about them. You
know, tell me in the comments if you
know something. I don't really know.
Educate me, you guys. I'm not an expert.
I'm here to learn with y'all. I'm here
to to teach a little bit, but I'm here
to learn. But we're jacked up on on
Keith. Bunch of different flavors. I
drank a grape one. Well, heck, we'll
crack this one open, too. We going to
get we going to get lit. You just I mean
once you pop the top the freaking fun
don't stop you guys gals. Let's pull
that tab back there right there. M root
beer. That's pretty good actually. I
like
that. I probably should have shook it up
a little bit. Just shook it a little
bit. Now, now back on topic here. We got
the Kef Extremes flowing through our
blood, right? Uh, you know, I should
probably do some kind of review on it. I
don't know. I'm not good at reviews, but
I will say last night I drank a
raspberry one. I sipped on it and I got
me a nice good buzz going. I'm a
hardcore stoner. I'm smoking all day
long and I felt like they did me pretty
good. You know, it's little felt a
little groggy this morning. I will say I
drank it later at night. So, I did feel
a little groggy this morning when I woke
up. I'm not a big sod pop guy. Would pro
probably prefer a juice. But these
things are pretty cool. Especially if
you're just having one or two a week or
something, you know, kind of hanging out
sipping on a little little Keef Extreme,
keeping it extreme, you know. Uh, as far
as like the flavor and stuff, they're
they're good. Uh, the price was decent
at the little dispensary I went to and
picked them up and they had a little
deal. It was like three for 20 or
something like that, which wasn't really
that bad considering uh you know, you
get your little little get you a little
buzz, little head change off of it. You
know, this ain't something I'd probably
drink all the time cuz I'm not a big
edible guys cuz edible guy cuz I'll be
honest, y'all know me in the Discord. I
go off on tangents when I go crazy. I I
push it to the extreme. I'm not trying
to get catch a little high. I'm trying
to go to the another dimension and go
through a, you know, freaking vortex, a
portal in time to revisit myself while
I'm stoned and kiss myself and lick all
like
lick lick myself, you know, [ __ ] like
that. But, you know, I try when I do
partake, uh, I do like these drinks. I
had a drink before out in Colorado that
I actually love. Sometimes they got a
little weird aftertaste with some of
these products like this, but the one I
had out there had a penic a lot of like
banana flavor, but it wasn't carbonated.
It was like a juice. Ooh, it hit right,
dude. I really like that. It's a little
bit before [ __ ] was more regulated, too.
So, it was I'll be honest, it was an
adventure. I went out there to the Rock
and Mineral Show out there in Boulder,
Colorado. Shout out Boulder. Shout out
Colorado. I appreciate y'all. It's a
Y'all have a beautiful state. Um, shout
out Kentucky as always. Shout out the
South. Shout out Cali. Shout out
Michigan as always. Michigan baby. But I
appreciate all the sport support from
y'all. Especially the Michigan people.
Y'all y'all are too sweet to me. You
send me the kindest messages and I
really do appreciate it. You know, it's
not going to be easy peasy all the time.
We got a It's not going to be a smooth
transition. You know, Matt in the show
has went through a lot of ups and downs
over the years. And you know, it's going
to be different, y'all. We're going to
do something different. I'm not here to
hijack a show. I'm here to show. I'm
here to entertain you guys. I'm here to
show off the plants. The whole plan was
originally for me just to really come in
and do some plant videos and stuff like
that occasionally, but the way things
have happened, I haven't been able to do
that because of all the YouTube strikes.
They don't like us. So, we got another
channel. I'm working hard. It ain't
going to be Wreck Weed Products all the
time. I got two weeks on harvest and
we're going to go through some CSI.
Matte blue sours TK times pure OG Kush.
We're going to go sour diesel times uh
you know pure OG. We're going to try all
these different little uh little strange
skank dogs. We got skank dogs and
flowers man. We got blue dream crosses
and flowers are getting close to semi
close to getting done. So we got stuff
on the
horizon. The I'm waiting for this
weather to shift y'all. I'm in a garage
right now. I'm freezing my balls off. I
can't, you know, I'm I'm a Kentucky boy.
My dad and and papa always said cold
weather makes
hard men and women. And you know, you
got to get it right these days. But, you
know, I'd said you you got a point
there. I'm from the south where it's
warm and it's hot. I work all day in 90
to 100 degree weather and that's hot.
So, you know, you put a you put a
Kentucky guy up here in Michigan and
what do you get? A freaking Super
Saiyan. You guys, I'm I'm here. I'm the
Messiah. I'm coming to save the
industry. I'm here to come and I'm
coming to save you guys. I'm here to
come to save the at tent home growers.
I'm really doing this, guys. But, you
know, I we won't always be doing wreck
weed products. I really don't like doing
that. It's just what it is. I ran out of
weed. My dad was sick. I had thris.
things just happened the way they did.
So, I ran out of bud. You know, I could
get a favor, but I'm not trying to get
favors. I don't like favors. You always
get favors. You get start everybody a
favor and then you don't want to be that
guy. So, we just deal with it. We smoke
a little wreck weed. We smoke a little
uh you know, I got some some random
outdoor [ __ ] I smoke on as well, too. I
got a bunch of the rank stranger jars
that I've been smoking on here or there,
too. But, man, I can't smoke a lot of
that hate [ __ ] I start getting
paranoid, you guys. I start looking out
the window like that the you know
nowadays people don't even pull up in
Amazon [ __ ] anymore you guys you they
don't even have vans bro they the other
night somebody pulled up at like 8:30 at
night and nobody pulls up hardly ever
right and they pull up lights on SUV
looking thing I don't know a Hummer or
something and dogs are barking and I'm
thinking like what the hell is this and
I look out the window and I see this
little bean pole of a man running
through my yard with the and I'm as he's
running back to his little car, his
phone is this way, bro. And he snaps a
picture like the most skillfully I've
ever seen in life. When he sent me the
picture, you know, on the the delivery
confirmation, it was a perfect picture.
I always thought to myself, this guy, I
if I had a company, I would hire this
guy because the skill that takes, the
precision, the precision, the uh, you
know, sense of urgency, the uh,
efficiency you could say. I love I loved
it. Okay, so
anyways, back to let's we jumping all
off topic, you guys. I know you don't
you don't mind so much, but I try to
keep it on topic. And I'll be honest,
the Keefe is kicking in. So, I'm going
to be bouncing around a little bit. So,
just please please forgive me. Okay. So,
at the end of the day, would I buy Kef
Keefs again? Hell yeah, I would. I'll be
honest. I would like a tropical flavor.
Uh, purple passion's cool. I like grape
soda. That's cool. Root beer's cool, but
I like I'm a more of a tropical guy,
like a coconut, pin colada, uh,
pineapple kind of guy. I don't. He's
saying that kind of sounds a little
fruity there, truck dog. But hey, I like
pina coladas. I I used to love tequila.
I do wild [ __ ] on tequila, but I can't
go there no more. I'm a uh I'm in a
happy relationship with a with a
beautiful woman. I can't be acting a
fool out there howling at the moon late
night. Uh chasing around riff raff,
chasing around little, you know, lot
lizards or whatever the things I used to
do back in the day. But, you know, I'd
buy Keef again. We bounced it around
today, y'all. Buy Keef extreme and keep
it extreme, you know. Anyways, is there
any products, any edibles, any drinks
that you have in your local area,
especially especially in the Michigan
area, uh, you know, that I could try to
track down and try out? Let me know in
the comments section below. Let me know
what what I should try to find. I'm
looking for some in the bud that you
guys recommended the last ones, but I
haven't seen much of that [ __ ] bro. I
I'll be honest with you. I'm looking
around. But it is what what it is. So,
if you got something, you know, you got
a couple more weeks of me buying some
Wede. So, if you got something you want
me to try out or find or buy or products
to try out, let me know in the comment
section below. Let me If you don't care
at all, if you think Wreck weed sucks
and you think I'm I suck, let me know
that too down there. [ __ ] it gets me
hyped up, you guys. You know, anytime
you guys take effort out of your all's
life or energies to watch a little bit
of my video, I really do appreciate it.
So, a negative or a positive comment is
appreciated. It really doesn't matter.
But, you know, this show thrives off of
engagement with you guys and gals out
there. Let me know I'm doing good. Let
me know if I'm doing bad. I'm trying the
best I can. You know, I'm not going to
be the best at it. I'm not going to get
everything right every single time. I
can really only speak from my own
experiences and tell you guys that. So,
if you guys got tips for me, my ego's in
the hot tub and that's where I left it.
So, out there at Lake St. Clair with
Denalian crew, I left it in there that
night. They punished me and took me in
took me in ways that I could have never
even imagined. And I left my ego in that
mazola soaked lubed up hot tub. And you
know, if you got something to tell me or
teach me or you got an opinion or
something, let me know. I'm trying to be
a better grower. I'm trying to be a
better podcaster guy. I'm trying to be a
better person in life. You know, uh, a
lot of be a lot of people get it
twisted, you know. Uh, you know, in this
industry, there's a lot of drama and
stuff like that. You know, I'm not rock
I'm not going to be leaving Matt. I'm
gonna be rocking out with the Breeders
Syndicate. I'm gonna be doing what I got
to do until I'm gone basically to the to
the death of me. So, don't get it
twisted. I ain't going anywhere. If you
like it, you like it. If you don't, you
don't. It is what it is. And that being
said, let's go ahead and jump over into
the products I use during my growths, at
least at the ones I have been using this
run. U you know, I'm kind of like Bitter
and some of the other guys recently. I,
you know, don't really necessarily like
to stick to one product. It's not really
about that. It's really about what makes
sense, what's cheap, what's available,
do I need it in a specific time, am I
going to be able to get it? Do they have
it at the hydro store? Do I got to go
through Amazon? There's several several
variables that go into that. Uh, and
really, my biggest advice
is if you got something that you're uh
looking at uh that's maybe a little bit
too expensive for you, try to go into a
hydro store. And you could do this
online as as well, but I I'm a visual
person. It helps me when I have
everything in front of me. Try to go and
look through different products and look
for the similar ingredients to what
you're trying to uh you know replace or
substitute for. And this ain't going to
work for everything because there are
some products that are specialized or
not specialized or whatever. So, but for
me, we'll talk about it here in a minute
uh about the Can of Bloom and a couple
of the other Cana line products uh that
I really can't afford or don't want to
pay for. and I've substituted a few
things. So, we're going to jump into
what I like to use. Maybe this is going
to be for people that are new beginners.
Uh people that are just starting out
out, you know, that don't really know
what they're doing, maybe or maybe you
do know what you're doing, but you're
looking for a new strategy. You know,
I'm not an organic grower as far as
organics are concerned. It's about as
organic as I can get is when I grow
outside in the dirt, and that's about as
as organic as it gets. you know, uh, I
live, you know, I got to climb stairs. I
got to take stuff up a couple flights of
stairs. So, I'm not really trying to,
uh, carry, you know, a bunch of crap up
into the house other than I really need
to. And in all truthfulness, I would
switch to Coco if I, you know, if I,
well, I mean, if I just had the
products, I mean, I probably would
switch to Coco. I got the Cocoa Can of
Amb products, but I, you know, it's a
hard switching up or or doing multiple
different techniques or styles of
growing at the same time. I've been
wanting to do some Coco. I've done a
little bit. I've done some vegging and
stuff like that. I think, you know,
Coco's great. Uh I think or Coco choir,
whatever you want to call it. I think
it's great. I've seen people in the
Discord. Shout out Local and a few other
people. Uh Bidder and a few a few of the
other guys and gals in the Discord get
great results from Cocoa Choir and stuff
like that. Massive yields, quick growth.
I think for me personally, I you know,
if I was going to do Coco, I'd want to
take clones into Coco. You know, I
probably would mess up starting off in
cocoa. It seems like a lot of people do
from what I can pick up from the
Discord. A lot of people have trouble
starting them off in in the cocoa. And
and that's probably just, you know, not
giving enough or giving a little bit too
much of that because and sometimes
people don't do stuff like pre-oak your
your meat, you know, your your whatever
you're growing in basically. And and
give it some cow mag. Give it especially
in the cocoa. There's nothing in there.
It's inert. So, it needs something to
get going. But personally, I like to
start my seeds in in Promix because it's
real airy. You going to get a lot of uh
you know, air to the roots. You going to
get quick growth, especially in those
beginning stages. It doesn't have a lot
of nitrogen and things in it that's
going to uh you know, burn your
seedlings. So, it's going to get you
where you need to be. You got about
seven to 10 days on uh Promix um you
know, for your seedlings and things like
that. So, and then you can start giving
them some food. But I like to start
giving them real low dose of uh you know
cow mag and uh the can of terra. I
actually run the can of terra lines.
That's the stuff I have the most
experience with. I do have can of A and
B for cocoa but I don't really use it a
lot and I haven't used it a lot. So I
can really only speak about uh the can
of Terara stuff. So let's jump in that.
And I'm starting to slur my words a
little bit. I can tell I'm slowing down
and that ke extreme just keeping it
extreme. So, please bear with me and
let's make it through. You know, uh I
try not to smoke a lot or whatever
today. So, I and I'm running on a a
pretty empty stomach. I did make some
pizza, but I just took a few bites to
get me through the show because I feel
like, you know, when you got an empty
stomach, you going it's just going to
hit you a little harder, you know. So, I
will say we're going to jump over into
the products. We've been trying to get
to it for almost 20 minutes, and I do
apologize, but let's get to it.
Also, if you d if you're a little dab ho
and you're trying to wonder what torch
you want to get, pick up one of these
freaking things, dude. Blazer, Big Shot,
GT8000. They make different ones,
different pro, you know, different
levels, different sizes, different
numbers. There's probably a GT69, I
would hope, a 420, whatever. You know,
these things are pretty cool. I like
them. They're great for dabbing. I ain't
a big time dabber, but when I do dab,
this is what I'm
using. I ain't sponsored by none of
these guys, gals, but if you want to
hook me and Matt up, let's get it going.
We don't make no ad revenue, so let's
get it popping. All right, first things
first. Some people, you don't got a pH.
All right. But I would recommend it. Get
familiar with your water. Check your pH.
Don't have to be every day, but check it
often because it can fluctuate. For
example, I'm running off well water. I
check my pH every single time. Because
if it's raining or if it's dry, my pH is
going to fluctuate dramatically
depending. Right. Also, when you're
adding nutrients to your water, give it
a little bit time to chill. All right.
eggs. Mix it up five minutes, let it
chill, then go ahead and pH it after
that. You don't want to be mixing [ __ ]
up. It's got you got to let it balance
out. Balance that pH out a little bit.
Especially you don't be dumping can of
like for example the can of terra stuff
that I use for for uh for during flour.
That stuff will drop your pH from like
seven or eight. If you starting, you put
that in there, it'll drop it all the way
down to like four or five. It's freaking
crazy. So, make sure you're checking
your pHes, guys. That's all. It's
simple. You can use a pen. The Blue Lab
pens work good. The more expensive
probes work good, but personally, I got
away from using them because I felt like
every time I was turning around, they
were drying out. I was dropping them. I
was breaking them. They were breaking on
me. So, I actually just used the General
Hydroponics
uh little color, what do you call this
little thing? I don't even know what
it's called. Little test indicator with
the different colors on it. All you do
is you fill up this bottle halfway. You
put in three, four, five drops in there
and you match it up with the colors. Uh,
you know, if you're color blind, this
probably gonna help you out much. You're
probably gonna stick to a pin uh pen.
But this is what help works for me. You
know, my stuff's pretty consistent
because I do run everything through an
RO system. People say, "Drocile, why are
you running it through an RO system,
wasting all that money and power in a
water?" Well, the the whale water I have
comes out anywhere from 3 400 ppms,
bros. I don't know what that is. It's
been tested. They say it's fine, but I
ain't risking it for the biscuit. I want
to start at a base level, a neutral
level, or not a neutral level, I guess I
should say, but just I want to start at
zero. I don't want nothing in that water
so I know what I'm putting in there. I
know how I can keep track of it. I know
exactly what's going into there. I'm not
a scientist, you guys. I can't tell you
what's biologically on a biological
level what's going on in that soil. I
don't really know. I just know that at
the end of the day, I need Mountain Dew,
Kim Dog blunts, and big titties. And
your plants going to need stuff, too,
just like a human being would. You know,
they need stuff. They they need uh, you
know, nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium,
they need micronutrients, cow mags, they
need amino acids, all this stuff that is
really over my head and probably a lot
of over your guys's head. But the thing
that you got to remember is hours and
experience are required to grow cannabis
greatly. I you know you can come in, you
can get a good run or two and you could
have a bad run from the beginning. I've
seen it all the way. Environments range
all over the place guys, gals, excuse
me. When I was in Kentucky, I didn't
have any problems hardly ever. no pest,
no PM, no problems
whatsoever. But the the the climate was
more stable there. I didn't have big
fluctuations. Here in Michigan, you go
from 70 degrees one day uh to the next
day, it's 26 and it's snowing, so you
got big fluctuations. So, you have to be
flexible. You have to be elastic. You
have to be able to to learn and adapt
yourself to your garden at all time. But
there is a language that you can read
that you can speak to your plants. And I
ain't getting hippie dippy on you. I'm
just saying if you watch your plants,
you can read a language. They'll tell
you what they need. You know, all we're
doing is giving them what we think they
need. And every plant, every expression
is going to want different things.
They're going to consume water at
different levels. So, there's no real
right way to do this or say this, but at
the end of the day, we're going to give
them a battery of food and nutrients,
micronutrients, all these little things
that they they they could need or not
need potentially. We don't really know,
do we really? We're just throwing stuff
in pots. I feel like science in and out.
But they do need stuff on a base level,
right? So, you're going to give them
this little battery pack, which is your
pot of soil, and that's what's going to
get you there. Uh, but sometimes if
you're like me, you're growing in onegon
pots and what's in that one gallon pot
ain't gonna get you all the way to
flower, bro. Sometimes you you growing
from seed like your boy Chuck Dog. By
the way, all my grows are from seed.
None of those videos are from clone. So,
make sure you understand where I'm
coming from. I've done taken my grows to
the next freaking level, you guys. And
you can see it in you could you could
see it in the proof. The proof is in the
pudding. They say in the pictures and
the videos. So, and your boy's able to
keep Kim 91 happy. Okay? They ain't
melting on me. You don't see me. My
Kim's melting on me, fam. Cannibalizing.
Hell no. That's for suckers. But at the
end of the day, you know, where were we
at? We lost track. The Keith's getting
to me. We're on We're talking about uh
different products and all this stuff.
Oh, batteries. Battery your battery
bank. What do you plan? So, if you're
growing in smaller pots, you know, you
you're going you're going to need some
food. You're going to need some some
bottled nutrients. You're going to need
some uh dried amendments. You're going
to need however you going to do it.
Organic guys, I'm sorry. I don't got you
really. Y'all up here harvesting kelp
out the ocean and sprinkling on your
plants or something. I don't really
know. You guys got to We'll bring We're
going to bring some organic guys on
here. We're going to have them teach you
guys how to do the organics, you know.
But, you know, your plants are a weed.
They'll grow anywhere. almost any
conditions for the most part. They don't
they can use a lot of this. They can go
without a lot of that. So, you know,
your plants are never going to die on
you overnight. If you're new, just be
patient. Growing weed is all about
patience and just being vigilant and
watching your plants and and trying to
to be preventative. So, uh, before you
have run into problems or or and just
keeping your environment stable and and
to where your plant can really enjoy its
health or enjoy itself and get that good
health, fam. That's all it's about. So,
you really want to start off pH. That's
going to help you out a lot. Especially
if you're doing what I'm doing. You want
to pH, guys. And really, you there's all
kinds of products out there. I know you
guys are going to say, "Well, you can
get some citric
acid." I know you can't. I've heard it a
million times from you guys, but I just
me I'm talking about what I use because
I'm I'm lame like that. I just order
[ __ ] right? PH
up, pH down. Let me see it. There you
go. It's this one. PH down. Acid, fam. I
know y'all know about some acid. Maybe
we'll talk about some acid stories on
one of the shows here coming up. Not
today, though. But you you got to get
you some pH, right? Another thing I like
to have on hand at all times is cloning
gel. It comes in many different sizes,
many shapes, many uh different
varieties. It comes in powders and gels
and sprays and dips and chips and salsa.
Man, I'm getting hungry. Uh but I just
ordered this cheap [ __ ] off of Amazon.
I've used Clone X. I've used other
products. They all work about the same.
It's a rooting compound. Uh just uh here
I'll show it up to the camera. There it
is. I don't know anything about the
company. don't really care. I don't got
enough time to break down every single
company that I buy stuff from. If I, you
know, and and and figure out if they
what they've done in their life, I don't
really know. We're all consumers. We all
buy products all the time. Uh, you know,
you go into Walmart, you buy a pack of
soda pops, you don't you're not thinking
about the the owners of the stuff. Who
cares? You know, I'm I'm trying to I'm
just trying to put on a show for you
guys. So, you guys want to know how I'm
growing? This is how we're doing it.
Another thing you gonna need,
measurement device. Don't be in there
with a one millimeter vial dipping, you
know, little one millimeter here or
there. No, that's weak [ __ ] [ __ ] These
plants, they could take a lot more than
that, guys. Get you something to measure
your [ __ ] out with so you can know. See,
when you're doing this, you're getting
data. You should be. You should be You
don't have to be writing it down because
some people going to be in places that
you probably shouldn't be writing [ __ ]
down. But take mental notes. when this
plant is this age and I'm giving it this
much, uh, how's it responding? And when
you do this with hundreds of plants over
a long periods of time, thousands of
plants, whatever your gig is, you're
going to see patterns and you should
know, at least you should notice
patterns. Also, I'd recommend if you're
doing a can of product or any product,
always follow their little charts
online. And I love Cana because they,
you know, they're a little bit more
expensive on the expensive side on a lot
of their products, but I do love their
their A&amp;B and I do love their uh the
Terra and the Vegas, I think it is. Um
or however you say it. Uh and I do love
their little charts that they got
online. I use a five gallallon bucket to
mix all my stuff up in. Uh and that and
that's what I like to use. You know, I
like to use little charts and I and I
they have different options on there for
light feeding, normal feeding, heavy
feeding. So, if you're new, start with
the light feeding. Do you know what I
mean? Go through it. Don't ramp up to
heavy feeding trying to get them to
pump. Go easy on them, especially in
those first few weeks of their life. Uh
especially uh you know, yeah, let them
chill. But once you especially when you
get a flower, pump them some [ __ ]
You know what I'm saying? And there's
nothing wrong with that, y'all. You want
to get the biggest less. You only got so
many grows in your lifetime. You know
what I'm saying? If somebody said, you
know, you can only drive a car 50 more
times in your lifetime or truck,
whatever have you, snowmobile, uh, you
know, stripper,
whatever. Do you want the best or you
want you want to do the best or you want
to go slow in your in a car? You want to
go fast? I want to go fast. I'm a fast
guy. I like doing fast [ __ ] Uh, you
know, that's what that's what it is.
Efficiency. I'm all about that. That's
what I like to do. You know, some people
going to leave nasty comments say, "You
don't know what you're talking about,
Chuck. you don't really grow whatever.
Go look at the videos. I I don't know
who wouldn't smoke that. I'm getting
more compliments than I've ever got. So,
I know it's not just in my brain. I'm
seeing it visually all this language
that we talk about. We We see the
changes in our plants. We see the visual
changes. We see them perk up. We see
them turn green. We see them beautiful.
We look at everybody else's grows and we
think to
ourselves, "The [ __ ] are they doing?"
But that being said, let's keep it
rocking. Another important thing, cow
mag. Some people don't like cow mag,
some people like to get it from other
other ways, you know, whatever. Thing I
like about cow mag is you can never
really give a plant too much of it. Just
follow the back. One to five. I think
it's 1 to three mill milliliters per
gallon. Uh when you're starting off a
plant, go light, guys. 1 milll is fine.
But then as you get up and you're
starting to get, you know, a lot of
growth, especially in the flower, you
know, you won't want to be doing, I
think it's like five five per gallon. So
25 milliliters if you're, you know,
doing a five gallon bucket basically. So
just use common sense. Start low, rev
up. Okay. Now, I will say on Cal
Mag things like KimD, I think even my
couple my triangle Kush uh S1's uh what
or yeah, triangle a couple other a
couple other plants especially in this
run. This ain't going to be that ain't
going to be enough. You need to give
them more of this or you can use some of
these other products I'm about to show.
Uh but you definitely need your cow mac,
guys. You know, cow meck super
important. A lot of people will underuse
it. A lot of people don't realize they
could just simply fix their plants. You
know, I can't really show you guys
pictures and break it down uh for
everything on here because we'll get
another strike. I would love to. We're
working on that though. We're going to
work on it. We're going to fix problems
on plants. We're going to grow. We're
going to do stuff for y'all on camera. I
got a new camera coming. New microphones
on the way. No more games. No surrender.
No more treat. Truck Dog's here to stay.
All right. We're going to freaking
battle. We're going We're building the
army right now. Uh we're doing
everything we need to do. Shout out Troy
over at I Love We live. We tuned in with
all the Breeder Syndicate guys and gals.
We jumped in there, hung out with them,
douche [ __ ] his pants on live. Uh go
check him out, you know, whatever. We're
make we're building a community, you
know. We're having fun and we're we're
talking weed. That's what we want to do,
y'all. We want to smoke weed. We want to
make friends. We want to have a good
time.
Cowme can never have too much of it. Oh,
messed the video up there for a second,
but we're back. Cow mag. Never too much
of it. Another thing that's super
important, mosquito bits. You're saying,
"Ch, what the heck's a mosquito bit
going to do in your garden for me, bro?"
Well, believe it or not, I can
read. Mom, I dropped out third grade
because I was certified BA. And mom's
got me on hooked on phonics. Believe it
or not, it worked.
But today we're talking about mosquito
bits, dunks, powder, sauce, whatever.
These are the little bits right here. I
like them. I've had this bag going on
for [ __ ] a year. It lasts a long time.
Get some cuz guess what? Read the
package right there below. What's it
say? What's it say right there? controls
fungusnats
larvae. It's going to help you on your
larvae or your your fungusnat larvae, I
should
say. So, you got to have this for your
larvas, bro. You got to take care of
your little if you got mosqu I got a
mosquito sometimes in my room. I'm
hoping it's taking care of mosquitoes. I
live next to a swamp, you know, shout
out Michigan, but damn, everything is
swampy up here, you know. Uh, get these
mosquito bits. They're gonna take care
of your fungus nats. And it really does
work. Last summer, I didn't really use a
whole lot of this. I'll be honest. I
slacked off gnats everywhere. Right now,
I can't find a gnat one. Maybe one. I'll
see one when I only time I'll see one is
when I crack open some new soil and I,
you know, plant some seedlings. I'll see
one or two flying around for a day, but
I give them hell with this. And it takes
it takes care of them. Get you some of
these. The dunks, the Holy [ __ ] The
dunks, the powders, the whatever. We'll
take a little sip. Another Keefe extreme
because we keep it
extreme. I know I'm going through a lot
of [ __ ] It's going to be hard to
understand, but we going to go through
more of this [ __ ] If you got questions,
drop it in the thing below the comment
section. I'm just trying to show you
guys there's visual proof. Go look at my
[ __ ] if you really care that much. Go
look at my gardens over on my
Instagrams. And uh yeah, we're going
through what I use. People ask all the
time, "What do you use?" I swear I get
two or three questions a day. What are
you using, Chuck? Freaking stuff looks
fire, bro. Well, we're going through
it. Drop me a comment. Drop me a like.
I'm freezing my dick off right now, but
we're going. It's good for me. You know,
sometimes suffering is good for you.
Remember that. You got to go through the
struggles of life and the pain of life
to come out on top. You got to
experience. You got to go through bad,
the good, the mediocre, the boring, the
exciting to become the ultimate human
being. Another thing I love to use is
the recharge. There's different probably
better products, you know, whatever. I
like the recharge. Not really uh because
it's the greatest thing in the world,
but I got some of it and it was cheap at
the time. I've had it for a little
while, but I like this for my little uh
you know, my little assets and things
like that. you know, it's got a lot of,
you know, just look on the back of your
product products, guys. That's all you
got to do. Look up what a cannabis
requires and look on the back of your
products. Do some reading. Don't just
watch videos like these and say, "Oh,
that that's the best thing in the
world." No, you could use all kinds of
stuff. You don't have to use this. You
can use cheap stuff. Don't think just
because your favorite YouTuber uses this
this thing that it's the best in the
world. Sometimes it's just that this is
what it was at the store. This is what I
was I was I was [ __ ] baked out of my
mind went into a hydro store and the
dude was like, "You need some of this."
Sometimes it's uh you know, the
packaging looks pretty cool. You know,
sometimes, you know, uh it could be a
lot of things, but you know, you look on
the back of stuff and it tells you all
the [ __ ] that it has. You know, got your
fulvic acids, all that stuff. I, you
know, I'm not going to break it all down
for you. I'm not a scientist, you know.
I just I just listen to the guys that
tell me what to do, you know. Join the
Discord. Join the Breeder Syndicate
Discord. You want to get some knowledge.
I'm implementing everything I've been
taught from those guys, those gals.
Shout out Peaches. Shout out Miss Jill.
By the way, Miss Jill, we got that TGAC
space glue rocking out. Shout out
Matt. That is a freebie. He's got the
space glue. Got a better camera coming
on the way, guys. And gals. I promise
you I spent $200 on this freaking swivel
camera, dude. it. This thing's on a
motorized deal where it's gonna turn and
everything. I'm gonna set up a little
spot over here so you can follow me from
there to over here in the garage and we
gonna do some videos. Like I said, we
going to rock out on the grill videos,
y'all. We're going to show them what
breeder syndicates all about. No
surrender, no tree. Got a couple more
packs of skank dogs. I know, I know. I'm
sorry. They're sold out. You guys are
saying, "But Chug Dog, you're over here
hug, you know, hogging all the skank
dogs." Well, fam, I'm trying to do a big
pop here soon. And when I do, uh, I'll
make some seeds or something if, you
know, or whatever maybe with them. I
don't know. We gonna find a keeper
first. We gotta find something good. We
gotta find something good. You know, Rob
saying there ain't going to be no more
skank dog seeds. So, I'm a little bummed
about that. So, we got to hold on to
these with everything we got. Shout out
Seed Trip Rob. Man, I love I'm loving
the skank dog. I got three or four of
them going right now and another two
chilling in veg just waiting. Uh, I'm
loving it, bro. But anyways,
so we got the skank dolls, we got the
the glue, space glue in this week. We
got a couple other things, but we're
going to keep it on the grow products. I
just want to shout out Miss Jill there
for a second. Another one that I like
that I that I I'll be honest, I really
didn't find much use for it before in
Kentucky. But at the time, I was a
pretty noob noob still, I would say, or
newer. I'm still a noob, but you know, I
didn't realize how much calcium and
stuff was and minerals and things were
in my water in the city water down
there. So, when I implemented some of
these products before, I didn't really
notice a big deal. So, like we said
earlier, some of you people ain't going
to need some of these products. But when
I'm using
Roro and this product here in particular
is a guy green basalt rock dust. And all
it is is some minerals, bro. We got some
calcium in here. We got some uh mang
magnesium. We got some iron and we got
some manganesees. And really what what
this is is when we're talking about
earlier with cow mag if it ain't enough
uh you know there's going to be some of
these products going to be lacking um
stuff that could be important for your
plants or whatever. You know uh I don't
know if they do that on purpose on some
of these products they obviously do with
like the can of stuff and like that.
There's certain products in the lines
like the can of bloom that's going to be
expensive when $400 for a five liter
when one of these is like I think like
70 bucks for the Terra Vega. So same
size 500 bucks. Of course you know it's
it is what it is. They got they're going
to charge more for certain stuff.
Certain ingredients require more money
to to you know to make or whatever. But
for the most part you can substitute or
find different products to help you on
your little way. I love implementing the
any kind of dry amendment like this,
especially for uh like my Chem 91s,
stuff like that. Especially when I mix
up my soil, I add a little bit of bit
into this as well. And you know, and you
would think all this stuff's going to
burn your plants, guys. You think it's
going to ruin your garden. I used to be
that guy. I used to think, dang, like
I'm just going to grow with with, you
know, like ocean. I'm gonna grow with,
you know, mixing a little strawberry or
whatever and sprout and and frog. But
now, the way I'm doing it now, and I I
should have said this earlier, but I
like to use ocean for, you know, what I
grow in. I love that, you know, gets a
lot of nitro uh nitrogen and other
things in there. Uh, and I like to just
pack that in there and grow in that.
That being said, there's different
options. Uh, I like to use that because
I can use the Terra line from Cana with
it. It works great. It's a a line that's
specially, you know, designed uh, you
know, to be grown in in stuff that's
already got food and nitrogen, things
like that already in it. So, at the end
of the day, uh, the guy green or any
kind of dry amendment like that, you're
just really giving it making it
available for the plant if it needs it.
You know, you ain't trying to go
overboard, but there are some plants
that going to require more. If you see
one that's having problems, you know,
you can give it some dry amendments.
Now, mind you, sometimes dry amendments
ain't going to be your answer because
sometimes they uh are slow release or
sometimes they just take a a while to be
active in the soil or being broke down
into the soil to be, you know, available
for the plant basically. So, that's that
that being said, you got to be be
conscious and kind of like do some
reading and do a little research on that
kind of stuff. I'm just explaining it to
you how I I do I really like to use that
kind of stuff for like a preventative
thing. So if I slack off or miss
something and it's just there in the
soil ready to rip and I'm seeing great
results with that um for you know for my
main nutrient and uh
veg as the Terra Vega which you know it
is more expensive guys. It's going to be
more expensive than probably what you
really need to to ever buy. Uh but at
the end of the day it's a great product.
They haven't changed their product for
like 25 years. It's the same thing. It's
the same ingredients supposedly. Um, I
never burn my plants with it. It It
works great. Uh, especially with the
ocean and like I was saying, all these
things I'm I'm showing today, it's
working great for me and I'm having
great results and I think the videos and
and the the p the proof is there. It's
already there. So, I love it for veg.
And man, when you're in veg using this
stuff, don't be afraid to use it every
day, every other day, that's what it's
designed for, especially as your plants
use up your soil, the food in the soil
or in the ocean or whatever uh you're
using. Don't be afraid to to give it
give it to them. Just follow the follow
what they recommend and it won't let you
down. You don't have much to worry
about. Um, another product I really like
to use,
uh, and this is like a once a week deal,
every 10
days, is some good old Meno honey
molasses.
Uh, this is a newer product I just
started using
and, you know, I can't tell you if it's
making a giant drastic change in my
garden. But because I don't run the Cana
uh, Bloom, like the Bloom Boost Booster
and stuff like that and a lot of the
other products from Cana, I like to use
a a few things to kind of kind of fill
in the blanks, you know. And this is the
Menoscino honey. Like I said, I just
started using it. There's other products
you could pick up, but really, like I
said, you always just want to look at
the back of your ingredients. And this
here is made got a total nitrogen
uh 4646%
uh it's
got different
uh let's see phosphat phosphat. I can't
talk you guys. I'm [ __ ] up on these
kef this keef drink soluble pot ash. You
get your K and let you get your P and
your K from here. Let's just say that
y'all. Jesus.
Available. Yeah. So, strive for
molasses. I mean, it's a newer product
that I've been using just to boost my
PM, my K's. Not really using it for
nitrogen or anything like that, but you
g you gonna get all your [ __ ] you need
from this and your cow mag and your
terra.
But next thing when you're going into
flower that I like to
use for flour, I guess I should say
mainly is the Terra Flores. And you
know, it's a great product as well. I
pump them hard. I just follow the chart
and it works pretty easily. I haven't
seen any burning. I haven't seen any
major problems or anything at all
really. Uh it's been a great great
product. I have used uh BioBiz and a few
of the other products. I and I've burnt
my plants. I've done you know I feel
like this is just a userfriendly really
easy to use product. It is a little bit
more on expensive side but it works good
and it's reliable. And you know, when
you're talking about popping a bunch of
seeds, uh, you know, and different
expressions, different cultivars, uh,
you know, you want something you can be
able to apply on a broad scale to to
many different things, many cuts, seeds,
whatever it is, uh, and be successful.
That's really what it comes down to. You
want to get that to the end of your
flower and get that get that good smoke.
Get them seeds or whatever it may may
have you whatever you're doing.
Um, but like I said, use the Flores, I
think it's how you say how you say it. I
don't even read it really to be honest
with you. Flores. Flores. I don't know.
Terra
Flores. And
then we got another product I've I've
been
uh using recent rec recently is uh
Mother of All Blooms. It's like a boom
blooster because I don't use the uh uh
the Canon one. I use this this in
combination with this uh this I think
total like 40 50 bucks whereas like the
Bloom Booster is like 400 bucks. So I
don't know. I like to save some money so
I can spend them on my Mountain Dews, my
Hodags and and [ __ ] [ __ ] like that. But,
you know, this is just gonna give you
your um the way you use this, I should
say, is you're gonna use it and when you
the beginning of flower and then like
towards the end of it, your last not
your last few weeks, but you know, like
just basically like week, well, we won't
say a week because there's going to be
people out there doing different
varieties of stuff, but on a, you know,
seven to nine, 10 week plant, you're
going to be using this, you know, three
or four weeks before, uh, the end, you
know, for harvest. But you just all all
it's doing is uh you know boosting up
your phosphorus and potassium levels get
you going and uh really you just follow
the the back, you know, it's like a
tablespoon per gallon or add more, add
less depending on where you're at. Um
you know that the actual directions of
it say you know uh can be used first
week of flower to help introduce
flowering. uh add mother all blooms
during the last two to three weeks of
flowering for added levels of phosphorus
and potassium. The amount base nutrients
may need to be reduced as such as 50%
when using mother of all blooms
overfeeding may burn plants. So there
you go. I've used it uh this run and
have you know haven't burnt any plants.
You know like I was saying earlier I'm
not a scientist. I don't know if this
stuff is working or not other than what
I can visually see. I'm not in I'm not,
you know, this tall. I can't look in the
soil. I don't know. I'm not in I don't
got a PhD. So, all I can tell you is my
plants are bigger and better. Plants
I've ran before, same cultivars are
bigger and better. Even hell, even some
of the autoflowers I ran recently were
bigger. I mean, the top the top cola on
these ones were so big, bro, compared to
the ones the same genetics I ran
before. So, I don't know. I kind of feel
like I'm I'm getting what I pay for, if
that makes any sense. And I'm stretching
these out over several grows, so it's
not like you're using this all up real
quick. But for the most part, that's
pretty pretty much it. Uh, you know, if
you guys got something to recommend me
to use, I know I could do it better
always and use the actual caner
products, uh, you know, and stuff like
that. Uh, but if you guys got something
recommend me to use down in the comments
section, let me know below. I love
trying out new stuff. Maybe I'm doing it
wrong. Maybe I'm doing it right. I don't
know. I'm liking the way my shit's
growing, so I'm having a good time.
Anyways, last thing I wanted to talk
about today for y'all as far as growing
tips and growing equipment. I know y'all
seen these before. This is a trim tray
right here. Uh they usually come with a
like a black bottom or a bottom piece so
you can collect your little your little
stuff that falls through your pollins or
or or your little hash or whatever you
whatever you got for mama's. But
speaking of mama, she done beat my ass.
She done hit me hit me right here. Can
you see it? Let's see. See that on my
nose? She done hit me with the
[ __ ] habachi uh magic vibrating wand.
You know big wands all the women's out
to use on their coochis. She hit me
across the head of the forehead the
other day. I was trying to get her a
little a little $50 square up with her
and she she came out the house with that
thing welded like that. She said, "What
are you doing back here, boy?" She
smacked me across the forehead and then
that's how I got that cut right there.
So, me and mom ain't real good right
now. I love you, mom. If you watching, I
love you. I'll be if you want to drop me
off a plate of food, that'd be great.
But trim trays, they come many different
shapes, many different sizes. I like
this one here because it's the first one
I bought and I've had it for many years.
It works great. You can put it in the
dishwasher, get it nice and clean once
you get done with it. Get a little
pilings off there, have you? But mainly,
I wanted to talk about this for using uh
when you're sorting seeds. You know, a
lot of people ask questions and I had
questions like this when I started off.
How do you separate your seeds from all
that bud and all that all that crap?
Well, how do I get my seeds out of
there, bro? Let me know how you doing
it. Well, if you don't have a seed
separator or a seed m separating
machine, whatever you want to call it,
they make those. You can there's a
couple guys on Instagram and there's
plan plans for them on the internet that
you can download to get your little seed
blower going and and help you clean
them. But if you're cheap like me and
you ain't got a lot of money or space,
you could use a tray like these. And I
like this one here particular cuz it has
the screen and a little lip right there.
Because what happens is you going to
take your tray like this. And you can
take it like that if you want, but I
like to take it just like this. I'll
take my little all my little buds and my
dried up stuff and my seeds, my my chaff
and all that stuff. I'll start crunching
it up just like that. As I'm doing it,
them seeds are bouncing down this tray.
You want to have it at an angle and them
a lot of times them seeds will bounce
over that white lip right there and
catch right here for you. So, and then
all your your shake and your trim and
all that stuff will be caught up here
and you simply just tilt it or you can
pick them up, tilt your seeds out and
get them out that way. And you sometimes
you'll have to do a few runs depending
on how much seed you got, depending on
how dry it is, how not dry it is,
whatever. Uh but for the most part you
want to do is when it's really dry and
uh it's really the best time and only
time you want to do it. Sometimes like
me though I have harvested stuff just to
try it out you know when it's still wet
and do it that way too. I mean it works.
You don't want to do it that way
necessarily but it does work. But
another thing you could do to use this
to for sorting seeds is put it like this
just like how I'm sitting in front of
you. And you want to mount you a little
fan uh kind of like basically I got I
feel like I almost got a booger in my
nose. Get you a little fan pointing away
from you or to the side of you. I like
to do it away from you. And I'll put
that little tray right there in front of
it with the in between uh have the fan
in between you and the tray and have
that tray kind of tilted up like that.
You you want to play around with you
don't want to put it on full blast and
blow all your seeds out, but you turn
you you get that fan going and you just
take that all that shake and your seeds
and everything and you shake take it
right there in front of that fan and
have this below it and it'll blow a lot
of that crap out for you. blow all that
extra [ __ ] out for you, right? And
you'll collect all your seeds down here
at the bottom of your tray. And that's
just a that's just how you have a good
day when you're sorting seeds. Some
people don't like it, some people love
it. I like sorting seeds. I think it's
freaking fun. Uh I got ADHD, so it helps
me keep focused and gives me some
something to do. And I guess really
actually a lot. I think the last tip for
today, I talked about this on the last
episode. Denali, shout out Denali. You
gave me these freaking uh what are
these?
Hydra Hydroarm. I don't know anything
about Hydroarm, but
these these uh little trimmers, bro,
these have been fire. They haven't
broke. A lot of these trimmers out here,
I get the freaking spring pops out of
them. These things have stayed sharp.
These have been awesome. They got them
at the hydro stores a lot of times. Uh
you know, some people don't got go to
hydro stores. I got them, but you know,
maybe you could find that. That's a
great great product. Great. works great
for me. Sorry, my balls were balls are
itching kind of for real. Um, but I
guess really that's it as far as the
grow tips are concerned for today. I
hope that's helped y'all out some. If it
hasn't, let me know. I know it's going
to be boring for some of y'all older
cats out there, but we're trying to
attract some new people. We're trying to
get it flowing. We're trying to get it
going, you know. Uh, but I'd like to
jump over into a weeder tip. I know you
guys are saying a weed eater too tip.
What the hell's that got to do with
weed, bro? Well, it's called a weed
eater, is it not? I think most of us are
uh you know, people of outdoors, we have
to keep stuff, you know, maintained and
keep stuff trimmed up. If you got a
little gorilla grow somewhere, you want
to cut you a little spot, you going to
take that weed eater up in there for you
and get it rocking, you know. So, I
wanted to give y'all a little weed eater
tip for today. And I'm going to try to
do this without unplugging a bunch of
stuff or knocking anything over here
real quick. But I got I might have to
put my headset down for a second. Hold
on. I'll be right back. Hold on. Hold
on. Keep your sticks on the ice, boys.
Y'all ain't never seen nothing like this
on a weed podcast, have you? Now, all
right, y'all might know I spent a
lifetime cutting
grass and letting it grow, but a lot of
cutting it
mainly. But I used to weed eat a lot. I
used to cut a lot of grass in Kentucky.
And when I got my job, my boss said to
me at the time, he said, "When I was
young, when I was young buck and my
thing was so hard, he said, "You ever
weed before?" I said, "Yes, sir, I
have." He said, "Well, if you have, let
me see you string a weed eater." So, I
got out there 20 minutes fumbling with
that thing. I don't know what the heck
I'm doing. I'm nervous. I'm trying to
impress him, you know? I never I don't I
don't know what a speedfed uh weed eater
head even was at the time. Right. So,
I'm here today to teach you guys how to
speed feed your weed eater head. If you
don't got a a speed feed head on your
weed eater and you got and you still got
your little guard on there like a little
[ __ ] or something wrong with you now.
You want full RPMs. You want full
agility. You want this thing to be
streamlined. You want it to be light.
You want it to rock out and [ __ ] strong
whenever you want it to. So today I'm
gonna teach y'all a little tip. No more
laying around out in your yard playing
with yourself in the weed of your head
trying to get it strum. So this piece
right here is too short. But keep in
mind, the shorter your string, the
higher your RPMs are going to be, which
means your head's going to spin faster
due to the the less weight that is on
the head, which can be a good thing or a
bad thing depending on where you're at
and what you're doing. But in
residential, usually if I'm doing a
residential property and and it's been
weeded before or the week before,
especially, and I just got to come in
there and do a quick quick cut, I'm
going to do a little bit of string. I'm
going to do a a smaller string than
this. This string here is going to be
made more for going through big [ __ ]
like brush. Right now, this kind of
string comes with downside though, too.
It's real heavy, right? So, you might
need a smaller piece of it to get them
RPMs you really looking for. You going
to get tangled up, bro. There's a lot to
weed eater science. I ain't a bro
science now. I'm a weed eater scientist.
So, I'm here to teach y'all something.
You could you could resupply your head
on your head your weed eater or your
string trimmer without even taking it
off. All right. All I want you to do is
you get yourself a piece of string
depending on how long it is. It doesn't
really matter, but you can get one two
or three. Back when I was out on the,
you know, doing 25 miles of horse fence
every day, uh, you know, I like to get
me as long as pieces I can get. And your
head's going to take about, uh, you
know, whatever, nine yards or so. about
basically take your arms all the way out
and you can do that two to three times
with most of these, right? You can fill
them up. Like I said, it's going to be
more weight. Keep that in mind. People
say, "Brother, why aren't you using a
steel or a husk of Varnner or something
like that? Why are you using a a
Japanese piece of equipment there, bud?"
Well, this is a Shandawa. I love my
Shandawa. They've been around for many
years. I I would lift it up and show
y'all, but we're gonna we're g going to
break something. Uh people say, "Well,
why don't you use something more like a
steel? That things are badass, bro." You
know, I did a lot lot of residential
properties. When I'm doing residential
properties and I'm getting in and out of
the truck all day long, I want something
lightweight with high RPMs that, you
know, I'm not Listen, guys, we're
hardcore. We don't use edggers. We don't
do all We don't have multiple equipment.
I do all my edging, my beveling, my weed
eating. Heck, I even mow yards with this
freaking thing sometimes. I'm not even
kidding you. There's some yards that are
fencing I can't get in. I'm using a
freaking weed eater. No push mower. No
more. We ain't doing no push mowing
[ __ ] [ __ ] I don't like push mowing.
I'm, you know, I've push mode many years
and I'm not into it. I like I'd rather
take this puppy right here and just burn
it down and look like glass, green
glass. Buddy, smooth you ever seen. They
the customer would never even know.
They'd be gone all day. They say, "Your
yard looks great." And I say, "Well,
good. I cut it with the weed eater."
Well, I like a Shandawa cuz a steel the
same commercial grade as this version is
about twice as heavy, right? If I'm in
big brush, I'm getting me a steel. If
I'm on residential, I'm going rock with
this here. Shandawa. Now, they make
different models and different products
for each one that could you probably
find a similar thing. This just happened
to be on sale at the time. You get two
for some price. And I've been using them
for 10 plus years and they've been
great, great for me. And I'm not
plugging them. I'm not sponsored by
them. But today, I just want to simply
teach
you how to string a weed
eater without taking the head off. A lot
of you guys and gals out there may not
know this [ __ ] Here, let me turn it
this way so you can see. So I can see.
See these holes right here?
What you want to do, look through that
hole and if it's all lined up in there,
right? After you lose a piece of string,
you should be able to see daylight. So,
what you want to do is take that head,
that hole, a head in that hole, point it
to the sky. Point it to the sun,
brother. Look through the hole and look
for the sun. Now, I don't know if this
weeder set up for this. It might be. I
had my little helper uh in here earlier
today. Yep. And I don't know if y'all
will be able to see us or not, but maybe
we could do a lighter here. I want see
if we can do it. We'll point this at the
thing here so you all can see it. Now,
watch. See if you see a light coming
through there. Maybe. Nope. It ain't
powerful enough. All right. The idea
is look through the sun or a light. Take
that string, right, and you stick it in
there. And magic. Look at that. They
call me the magic man. I'm going to
teach y'all boys something today about
weed eating. All right. You got her
through the hole. And this ain't like
high school, bro. Be you gota You got to
be smart. Be
gentle. Be steady, Eddie. You grab that
weeder. You bring that string out just
like that. Don't matter how long it is.
Get it straight. Get it taut. All right.
Once you got it there, easy peasy. Keep
it twisted. And all you got to do is
twisty twisty. And that's easy peasy,
brothers. Look at that. Y'all didn't
know that, did y'all? Taught you
something new, didn't I? Well, we're
going to improve gardens. We're going to
improve your yard. We're going to teach
you new techniques that you never even
knew about. I'm going to teach you all
how to wield one of these things uh
better than you could ever imagine. We
got edging techniques. We got all kinds
of stuff coming up. And I ain't talking
about these kind of edging techniques.
I'm talking about making your sidewalks,
your driveways, your pathways, any
whatever your businesses, making them
shine, making them look [ __ ] strong,
making them look crystal clean, making
them look good. That's what life's
about. Get out there and work hard. Put
that grind in, you know, makes make
something out of yourself. Make
something out of be proud of what you
do. Be proud of where you are. Be proud
of where you're from. Ain't nothing
wrong with that, you know. But anyways,
I'm going to jump into a quick story
before we wrap up here.
I do appreciate y'all tuning in. Means a
lot to me. I meant to have me a little
campfire going on on over here, but any
we'll f with that next time. I'm working
on the background, you guys. We're gonna
get this [ __ ] going, right? We going to
get there. But today, I just had the one
story for y'all. I got to save some of
these because we'll run out of them
eventually.
But let's just say this girl's name was
Nova.
I was 24,
25. I just got kicked out of a supposed
friend's house. Literally knocked on my
door one morning and said, "Bro, like
the landlord never knew you were here.
He never knew your girlfriend was here.
I was living with her. I was living with
Nova at this this dude's house that was
supposedly my buddy. Uh, you know, kind
of a weird situation. I was selling weed
to him. I was selling weed to a lot of
his friends. We got more stories with
this dude and stuff coming up, but just
for the sake of like setting the tone
for you guys. I was dating this girl
named Nova. We was living at this house.
She's a mixed girl. She was not that has
anything to do with it, but I'm just
trying to, like I said, set the tone.
She was fine, brothers. I mean, she
didn't have big calcium cannons like
your boy likes, but she was fine. She
was fine. Uh, anyways, beautiful. Uh, so
we get kicked out of this place
and well, let me backtrack. We're living
at this place for over I think almost
two years, a year, whatever. I'm
trapping. I'm doing my [ __ ] A lot of
stuff went down there. We'll get into it
another time. I get a knock one morning
on a Saturday,
November. Hey,
Chucky, can I talk to you for a second?
Yeah, what's up, bro?
our landlord's on the way over here with
the sheriff in the next few days and we
got to get out of here. He said he
didn't know that you guys weren't on the
lease or or all this and you gota you
got to go, bro. And we're actually not
paying rent this month and we're leaving
as well today. I was like, "What do you
mean you're leaving today?" He's like,
"I got a U-Haul truck." I was like,
"What the hell?" So this dude and his
girlfriend that were supposedly my
friends dipped out on us literally that
day. They're packing their [ __ ] up. So,
I get all my stuff in the truck that I
can get that I can fit. I get me and
her, we get in there and we go and stay
at mom's crib for a little while and I'm
working on getting a place and I'm
trapping out mom's crib trying to make
it work. I mean, you know, just a [ __ ]
up situation. I'm embarrassed. I got my
old lady with me in my mom's house. It's
embarrassing as [ __ ] right? But we
making it [ __ ] work. Chuck Dog will find
a way. I'm not a quitter, bro. I'll find
a way. And uh
so I'm about to sneeze. Hold
on. All right. So I'm living there two
or three months trapping. Shit's
awkward. You know, mom's seeing my balls
sometimes cuz she don't there's one
bathroom, whatever. Uh so we finally get
this. We look all over the place, bro,
for an apartment, for a somewhere to
stay. We got to get out of mom's crib
because I'm losing money because I can't
run them through like I usually do
because the
situation traffic. Can't have too much
traffic. So, we're looking for a place
to stay and it's hard because I ain't
got a real job and they want to know
where you work. So, that shit's hard.
Uh,
so we finally get this lady, this old
lady that lets us go check out this
duplex. We get this duplex, right? And
I'm trapping it out, bro. We get this
duplex. It's [ __ ] bro. There was like,
come to find out, there's bed bugs in
there, roaches in there, fam. I mean, I
was I was never alone. There was never a
moment I was alone.
There's
roaches, bed
bugs. My neighbor was always knocking on
on the [ __ ] door asking for a square.
[ __ ] like that. Can he bump some water?
Anyways, we're living in this place
getting it sorted out. I'm trapping,
bro. Middle of the summer. Everything's
looking good. Got me a nice little stack
stacked up in the closet, you know,
stuff like that. We're smoking a blunt
and we got the windows open, bro.
Got the music on. I'm thinking about
getting some
nookie. Got the Oreo cookies out the
milk. Looking for them calcium cannons,
bro.
But I'm sitting there,
bro, and we that duplex was set up
weird, but like basically our living
room was our bedroom type [ __ ] It was
weird. And there's a a window at ground
level that faced my neighbor's house
that was about 10 feet 10 foot away.
This is one of the moments I didn't live
in the country, bro. Couldn't find
nothing in the country at the time. It's
hard to find a place sometimes,
especially during that
time.
Uh but so I'm looking out the window for
a second, kind of chilling. We got music
on like I said and bro, three state
troopers like walk right right there and
just stop right there, bro. And are
looking around and look over my house
and [ __ ] bro. And I froze. My heart
jumped cuz dude, I just re up. Me and
her in there bopping, having a good time
because we got just got some new weed.
I'm blazing. We got the window AC units
and the windows open, pumping,
everything. So it's no no smell
protection, right? This is back still
when dealing and uh you know you defin I
mean it's still bad, bro. You don't want
to get caught dealing ever. Don't deal
guys. Stay in school. I don't deal no
more. But my point
is at the time it wasn't very like the
climate was still pretty sketch. So, I'm
a little paranoid at this point and [ __ ]
my pants basically cuz they're sitting
there and bro I go to the front of the
duplex which is this duplex was in I had
a front street and a back street and
there's a train tracks on the back
street next to the back road as well was
like a dirt road on there and I look out
front bro and there's a armada bro a
army of police around our whole duplex
dude I'm talking state police, sheriffs,
like everything, bro. And I told her, I
was like, "Damn, dude. We're
fucked." So, man, I take the money and I
[ __ ] throw that [ __ ] up in the
[ __ ] attic as far as I can. At that
point, like, I'm thinking like, I'm
[ __ ] no matter what, dude. This little
big place still going to find whatever.
And
uh I took uh all the weed. I told her,
"Go to the bathroom, bro." Like what she
was talking about on the last story. Go
to the bathroom. Get ready to flush all
that [ __ ] She's like, "Oh god, we'll be
all right. We'll be all right. Chuck
dog. Chuck dog, calm down." I said, "We
ain't going to jail, baby." I said, "We
ain't going to
jail. Not today. Not tomorrow. Not
never." Said, "It ain't We ain't going
down like that." I said, "I'll flush my
[ __ ] I'll hustle back up. I don't give
a [ __ ] bro. We ain't going to jail. We
gonna stay out safe and and and sound,
bro. Right. So, she's in there with the
[ __ ] And uh man, I dropped my stuff,
bro. I got to get my
equipment. Keith got me Keith got me
tripping,
bro. So, I'm sitting there,
bro. House around. I go to the back. I
look out the bathroom window. The
bathroom set off the back of the house
facing the back row where the train
tracks was. And there's like [ __ ]
eight state troopers walking like arm
in- arm type [ __ ] close enough like
they're on the back side of the road.
There's cops everywhere. They're talking
to my neighbors, bro. Like, oh my god.
Uh, you know, I wasn't growing at the
time. I was just dealing. But, um, I was
still like, [ __ ] I'm in like a small
town. I don't know. I just saw I was
tripping, right? And, uh, I see him
talking to my neighbor and I was like,
what the hell? Why would they just be
talking to my neighbor, bro? They be
over here [ __ ] with me. I'm all
paranoid, right? And uh cuz I mean your
boy had crazy ex-girlfriends at the time
that that's trying to cause me problems.
Their moms were trying to cause me
problems. Like I just had a lot of a lot
of enemies, rival crews that didn't [ __ ]
with me. I mean, the chick I was with, I
had stolen her away from some other
dude. You know, you know how the dab
hoes are. They just in it for the weed.
You should leave them up on the
mountain. uh you know, give them their
paycheck and and let it be. You know,
you don't need to make love to your
trim, girl. But I was I me and her,
Bonnie and Clyde, bro. We in there
making love, flipping packs, you know.
She was doing runs, I was doing runs. Uh
you
know, just making it work, bro. No jobs,
making it work. And uh I mean her I was
sitting here thinking like, "This shit's
over." Well, I call my neighbor right
after he gets done talking to one of the
state troopers. I was like, "What the
hell's going on, bro?" And he's like,
"Well, some guy stole a bunch of money
from the bank on a motorcycle and flew
down the back road here and crashed back
there. They're looking for
him." I'm like, "Damn, bro." Another
close call. [ __ ] my pants, you know. And
uh he's like, "Yeah." Uh I was like,
"What?" He's like, "Yeah, man. He came
ripping down through here and and like
60 mph and crashed back there.
Supposedly they found his bike. Well,
I'm sitting there,
bro. And I look out the window while I'm
talking to him and the cops are like
behind the dumpster like looking at my
house and [ __ ] They're looking
underneath my car and I'm like, "Oh,
okay." And uh and I keep weed in my car,
right? Uh I at the time I'd keep some
weed in there cuz not the I had two
cars. One car I keep weed in, the other
one I do like my deliveries and [ __ ]
in.
And I keep roaches, like blunt roaches
in there, stunk, you know, and I could
just see them over like looking in the
car. They didn't go in, but my windows
were down and [ __ ] They could they were
there looking and like pointing at [ __ ]
and all that. But they didn't [ __ ] with
me, bro. But I sit there sweating like,
"Damn, dude. Like, leave just leave me
alone. Don't need this attention." And
then like five minutes later, they bring
this dude up in the in the car. drives
by from out in the back alley and they
captured this dude or whatever and they
all just kind of left, bro. But
man, my butthole was like that big the
whole time, dude. [ __ ] my pants. So, I
don't know. Not that exciting of a
story, but it was a close call. Maybe
you guys can relate to that [ __ ] in the
comments. being high off your ass and
then being so paranoid when that [ __ ]
happens that you're like about to do
some dumb [ __ ] like flush all your weed
or maybe y'all can relate. Maybe you
throw it up in the comments. Let me know
if you could share if you can't.
Whatever. Whatever. You know, Keith
showed it was good. I'm feeling pretty
buzzed. I can barely feel my lips. It's
been hard to communicate, but I'm
feeling good. I'm rolling this up just
fine. I feel like we're doing did all
right with the solo episode. You know,
these are a little awkward. The solo
episodes can be a little awkward, you
know, because you're talking to yourself
essentially. But if y'all don't mind
them, I don't mind them. So, let me know
in the comments section what you think.
Think I did a okay job. I know we didn't
go super deep into detail, but I think
that'd be a little overhead over
people's heads and frankly over my heads
half the time. So, you know, get you
guys some good nutrients. Get you guys
some good stuff. Get rocking on your
gardens. I want to see what y'all got
rocking out. Let me know. Show me. Send
me a picture. Join the Discord. Join the
Patreon. Go check out Matt uh Riot's
website. It's the It's the name back
here. Uh you know, I don't want to say
it on the video so we get cancelled or
whatever. But we got videos coming up
for you
guys. Check out the episode every
Friday. Go check out Goat Farm if you
want one of these hats. Uh Pac is his
name as well. Look him up if you want
some of the the hats. Go check out his
genetics. Go check out all the laundry
list of genetics that Matt and the crew
have going. And yeah, I appreciate y'all
like always. Um, you know, keep your
sticks on the ice. Uh, keep everything
tight and
nice, you know. And Kentucky, I love
you. And I also love you too, Michigan,
baby. That's it. Like, comment, sub on
the way out. I appreciate it a lot.
[Music]