foreign
[Music]
ER Syndicate where we explore the
history of a clandestine scene Through
The Eyes of the folks who lived in I'm
Matthew owner of Riot seeds I'll
occasionally be joined by my co-host not
so Doss breeder and grower from
Mendocino welcome to the underground
hey what's up everyone welcome to
breeder Syndicate my name is Matthew
this is Michael
there he is
yeah we have with us today uh mad Jag
and Rico so uh this is one of the
episodes I've probably been looking
forward to the most since we've started
um and and I'll I'll leave it up to
Magic to kind of start his tale because
I this is one I couldn't possibly begin
to start
um so magic when you started getting
into growing what was the impetus what
was the start
hmm
well the start was a friend of mine who
was a dealer in Tempe
um weed dealer
he saw all kinds of loads coming through
over the years
um from the late 60s to uh
let's say 73 74 and he would high grade
the seeds these were all seeded loads at
first
um so if you had guerreran or if he had
oaxacan he would if he found that it was
a great strain he would keep the seeds
and over time he started collecting all
these seeds and then one day around 1975
he said why don't we just gross our own
with these seeds instead of having to
deal with
um the supporting this stuff so
so we
um decided to test that theory and
that's the very first grow in 1976 I did
with um him and I went up and found the
spot that we would potentially use in a
remote Canyon along the Mogan rim
ogan Rim is spelled like mogulon but
it's pronounced maggion or mogion and
it's the southernmost edge of the
Colorado Plateau so it stretches from
roughly from Williams Arizona all the
way to Mogan New Mexico 200 miles wide
this edge of the plateau and along the
edge are all these
cracks let's call them and they're
they're Canyons with streams year-round
streams there's probably
I'd say 20 Canyons with year-round
streams in that 200 miles
and we chose one of them
and and when you decided to choose that
was it because there you knew for a fact
there was no like real human interaction
there is it just so remote that nobody
was going down there
that's that's pretty much it
uh Hunters stay up on top of the plateau
edges and stuff or they're way way down
in areas that are easier to ex
more accessible sure to hike down 1600
feet into a canyon down a boulder stream
wash through bushes and stuff
um
Hunters wouldn't do it because if they
shoot anything they'd have to carry it
out and yeah it's just way too remote
and the criteria was we wanted it had to
have a year-round stream
so we had to make sure that it was
flowing in the heart of the summer
and
um a Jeep Trail dirt road that led close
to it so we wouldn't have to hike more
than maybe two hours one way yeah and
then
um we began testing it in different ways
I I'd have my friend who was the dealer
from Tempe walk around down below while
I was up on the rim and we had
walkie-talkies back then this is pretty
cell phone so
um you just you know I I just go oh I
can see you you're wearing a white
T-shirt
so that was that had to change and then
he had a straw hat that had to change
um just can't be doing those things if
you're in the bottom of a canyon and
yeah Cowboys ranchers still use these
areas back in the early 70s they were uh
they were grazing cows there even though
it was National Forest the forest would
was allowing them I think their their
permits go back to the 1920s or 30s or
40s and they just allowed them to uh
continue on and they got Tighter and
Tighter and then eventually by oh let's
see
late
late 70s they stopped all the grazing in
these areas in this particular area
which was great yeah
a canyon away
um some guys from Jerome were growing
and they parked there every week week
after week after week at the end of a
Jeep Trail and finally the ranch are
using that area called the forest
service and they came out and ran the
plates and found oh wow they're from
Jerome the hippie capital of Northern
Arizona so that didn't their scene
yet and they didn't wait for them they
just they didn't want to go down inside
in case you know it would become a
shootout or something so they waited
till they harvested it and took it all
back to Jerome and then they busted on a
Jerome it was like a hundred pounds
oh no and they didn't have any effect on
you guys
no it it bothered us because they were
within five miles by air of where we
were but it's so remote and so difficult
they chose a canyon that was a lot
better known and people were known for
hiking through it and swimming through
it because it was very long had sections
of wall-to-wall water you had to swim
our Cannon was unknown and you couldn't
hike down from the top because there was
a spot we called
um
oh what land not Lands End the Hall of
the Mountain King is what we called it
it was a hundred foot waterfall drop off
and you can't you couldn't you couldn't
go down it so we never had to worry
about anyone hiking Downstream from
where it started as a watch five miles
away
so how did you guys again did you guys
go in a certain way that that made it
accessible enough obviously for you guys
but other people didn't know
yep we drove Five Mile Jeep Trail
the first well this first time with my
friend from Tempe it was about a three
mile Jeep Trail and then maybe a
thousand foot drop off down into the
canyon and it it was a canyon that at
the top was heavily used by swimmers and
and people who were into
um Crystal Clear Pools and things like
that but the lower part where we were
um there was no one we never left
Footprints either we these beautiful
sand bars that are long creeks and edges
we would just avoid them because we knew
that if anyone did hike through that's
the first place they would walk because
it was easier so we could always check
for footprints
and our primary Canyon magic Canyon
which came the next year
um in five years we only saw one set of
footprints wow ironically my partner
picked up a hitchhiker on the way back
through the nearest town and he was the
guy who had hiked through there so we we
found out he he was all excited because
he had hiked this 12 Mile Canyon and saw
nobody and he had hiked right by our
Gardens and never knew it you know
yeah so that was good karma
meeting the guy
what I what I find so interesting when I
was when I was reading a little bit
about your your history and stuff is how
similar
um although although a little bit
different just due to geography like
when I first moved to Mendocino County
and we were doing gorilla before the
medical era really started uh was how
similar the criteria was
and that you were looking for somewhere
very remote
inaccessible uh normal people hikers
Hunters various people would never go
there but you needed water
uh and you couldn't really take a
vehicle up there or even like dirt bikes
or anything because you never wanted to
leave a trail that would have been
visible from the air
so you would only get so so close and
then the rest of it was sort of hoofing
it in and even hoofing it in from like
different angles so that you wouldn't
create a path in summer
that would be visible
was that can I uh let me interject a
question were they flying looking for
weed then or was that too early for that
um it was too early they there were
there were people who talked about that
that going on but we never saw that
happen we did have a helicopter land in
our Canyon in the only spot that was
wide enough this is another weird one
and their tracks went about the tracks
from the helicopter went about 400 yards
down the canyon stopped and then went
back and
we thought we were dreaming because we
didn't see the helicopter we just saw
these tracks and we followed them to
this little opening but when we got down
on our knees and looked carefully
little frag little pieces of paint had
had chipped off the helicopters
um I forget whether those the skids
let's call them yeah and left on the
Rocks because this volcanic rock so it's
very sharp so we knew we were
hallucinating and a helicopter had
landed there and later we found out it
was Eagle stud ears
oh from the University in in we're not
sure which university but they were
checking out all the Canyons up there
and and getting out and Hiking if they
saw eagles and trying to get some
numbers for their studies so we we felt
okay but the the actual looking for
plants
um you know if you were to open if you
were to like clear a huge wide area and
leave it open and then just start
growing
such that you could stand on the edge of
a canyon and look down in and go hey
what's that
um that would be bad yeah so you have to
go in and out between the bushes make
little
patties that flowed from one to the next
level and
work it out and then later we even found
out
it made sense because we were up on the
rim looking down after
watering and the reflection on the mud
was very obvious that this was an area
that had gotten water so every time we
watered which was once a week we spread
oak leaves and whatever leaves were
there we started piling them up in
advance and just threw them on top and
totally stopped the reflection
a lot of things
we painted all of our hose connections
with brown spray flat
sure spray paint so it wouldn't reflect
uh we never wore white t-shirts or hats
um
we we had this photo that you have up
right now that's my first my second part
he's my first partner in Magic because
the guy I started with who's the dealer
we um went separate ways kind of because
he didn't he lived in Tempe and it
wasn't just wasn't feasible for him to
come up and do this every week so I
lived in the Verde Valley which I was
still over an hour away but it made more
sense and this fellow that you see here
was my first partner he lived in flag
and
this is what the creek looked like
year-round water this Pond right here is
what we pumped out of
and our first Garden was 90 feet
above the the creek level
so we used a Briggs and Stratton four
horsepower
um two inch fire hose
and if it was it wouldn't pump up 90
feet so yeah you had to drop down to a
garden hose adapter that it forced it up
to 90 feet we just appreciated yeah
um
there's different pumps we could have
gotten for more money like six
horsepower that weighed 150 pounds or
something and uh yeah but we we it
worked so it took two hours that first
Garden to just move the hose around we
only had one hose and we'd just move it
in subsequent years we created um
systems of hoses so you just you know
they all just watered
those filled up little patties and then
those
pour it over onto the next level and to
the next level because the the train was
relatively flat on these alluvial
plateaus but you know maybe a foot or
two of of differences plus we we raked
it and leveled it and used rocks to to
outline little patties so that maybe
there'd be two or three plants yeah on a
Patty and then the next one would be
next to it it would drop off
we have free hoses though too uh that
were on Siamese shutoffs and we could
open them up and then you know spot hit
other plants and yeah it worked pretty
well we spent a lot of time developing
our hose Network on subsequent years
sounds like after that first
[Music]
you know Matt magic this is rajo so just
I want to jump in there you know you're
talking about all these gorilla
um
tactics
and you know this is back in the 70s
you're talking about could when you were
when you were doing all this stuff was
any of this kind of inspired by the war
that we had just finished fighting in
Vietnam and you know the everything that
we used to hear on the news all the time
about
the Guerrilla Fighters over there and
how they concealed what they did I know
that when I was doing my gorilla stuff
it was
you know I'm listening to your stories
and it's exactly like what I did except
my stuff was all green and not not rock
you know
but uh where where was your inspiration
for
the whole catalog
the written word has always been my
guide and
um
this is
domestic Growers Supply catalog from
1981 1980 and
I read about this in the whole earth
catalog and I I wrote in a way for it
look at these waterbed
classical tanks to fit in the back of
your truck so you can pull up to the
edge of a canyon and I knew people who
use this method then all
gravity feed downhill for 600 feet to
their spot and
um this this is a small little thing
small little catalog it has but it does
have a very nice section on
on pumps and
these guys I don't know once we started
making their second catalog in color
1982 and they were based out of I think
Oregon let's see where this is
um but they have all kinds of
guzzler pumps hand operated
um where you just that wouldn't work for
us but
yeah we've had a few times where
things broke and we had to Water by hand
using five gallon jugs dipping them in
the watering them well it takes
but but you you can't neglect it because
you're there to water in oh it was good
the way we did it
we were fortunate because one week
we would flood irrigate we estimated in
subsequent years that we were putting 20
000 gallons on
on our little gardens so that was it in
this soft dirt that we used it would
sink nice and deep and then the roots
would follow it oh yeah it's but you
couldn't go two weeks if you went like
even 10 days which we tried to do a few
times you'd come back and all the plants
were wilted and drooping and heard
freaked out because we thought we had
messed up and we went ahead and watered
the next morning everything was standing
up perfect and looking beautiful
they're amazing plants how they can
be almost shriveled and then one water
resistant or just yeah did you ever use
any like uh any water retention crystals
or anything like that to extend
um because that was that was some that
was some technique that it you know like
by the time that I got to Mendocino
County and started doing stuff like that
there was our already a lot of like I
don't know if you want to call it Hill
Tech or older people that were passing
down how to get away with things
um infrequent watering was always well
how do you retain the water how do you
how do you keep it how do you keep
things wet when you're only checking on
things every so often
so our Canyon was 12 miles long and we
we hiked it up and down to find the two
spots that we this was the first spot
that's on the camera right now but the
other two spots we found were up Canyon
and
we you just don't come across alluvial
plateaus at water level they're up at
least 20 feet above and we had to
scramble up and look and scramble up and
we'd be up in the room and look down and
say hey that looks like a good spot and
then go back the next week and check it
but when we finally found our two spots
um this soil is wind deposited over
centuries and decades multitudes and it
was so nice there was rocks in there big
boulders as you can see here but in this
our very first place down below here is
where that photo was taken
and
this is at almost at Harvest you can see
the size of the coal is beautiful and
um
we um the soil was just this beautiful
Rich volcanic soil although when Robert
Clark came down in the second year of
our new location not this one he said he
couldn't believe we were growing in dirt
and I said what do you mean the dirt and
he said well in Mendocino and up in
North it's not dirt like this it's soil
like black rich soil and ours was brown
and gray and just dirt but yeah it was
easy to shovel so that meant that the
water penetrated it and so did Roots
very easily we turned the soil down 18
inches I think and the only amendment we
ever added were bone meal and blood meal
oh wow that was it we didn't have to do
a folio story and the foliar spray saved
us from this twisting Leaf thing that we
it was a micronutrient that was missing
we think it was molybdenum but we uh
sprayed the plants and it saved our
butts because they all untwisted
no that's nice but that's it
just so when you were when you were let
me ask a question in terms of
um when did the growing season like when
were you when was it nice enough outside
that you were able to plant and how much
work did you do to prep in the winter
spring off Seasons like you said you
turned the soil and you had to run all
these hoses and prep all this different
stuff how much pregame went into like
preparing the areas you were thinking
about using
we had November and December and January
off and then we were back out in
February
um we you know preparing
we we started small like this Garden
here you're looking at in this boat is
probably 100 feet by 50 feet with
Boulders and trees and stuff in it it
it's it Blended in pretty well even from
the Italian did really well yeah
however the next Garden we used was
three times the size of this and if we
plant it in between bushes and trees
which you'll I'm sure you've seen in
some of the photos and
but when there were no plants those
between the bushes and trees were the
patties were I'm just calling them that
we had to build up with rocks and have
it spill over to the next Garden in the
next or in the next Patty and the next
one but we had free hoses too to be able
to walk around and in water with
it took
I don't know months of perhaps the very
first time because we had to bring down
so much stuff and then the third year we
grew we did two gardens that was The Big
Year and that's the year that Rob Clark
came down to see he he only came down to
see the one easiest to reach garden and
in this this photo is kind of an early
photo of that first Garden yeah these
are little tiny pipes in here in these
let's see if we can get actually that
that first Garden was so was that
primarily uh different different types
of Mexican that your dealer friend had
collected was that was that the primary
seed stock for the first season
I mean you were saying stuff about
oaxacan I believe and some other things
yeah is there any Colombian and stuff
yeah but the first year we just grew the
Mexican strains and it was in this other
Canyon that people actually went to the
top of it and would swim there but
our Canyon
we didn't start till my partner that you
saw down there next to the water
that I'll hold it right here if you
could hold that one but which one the
last one or this one yeah the last photo
okay
I was trying to jump through this one
that one this one you can see how they
stand out
yeah definitely the canvas
The Evergreens here were giant Pines and
small shrub oak trees and bushes
but from the rim
it didn't look too too blocky you know
they were scattered out if you really
knew what you were looking for yeah you
would have spotted this from 1600 feet
above but no one really went to those
edges in those Canyons this was not and
especially when it's 100 degrees out
yeah
it it was difficult so this is just I'd
say this is one half of this Garden it
extends over here and over here and this
was only 30 feet above above the creek
but it was in the spot that you would
never expect it and we hiked up there
when holy cow this is perfect so we were
able to pump two inches of water in a
two inch fire hose up to this flat and
that's why we put about 20 000 gallons
on here every week
and so wild do you mind the stories how
old you were
I was 28. 28.
yep 28 and 29 and 30. when we were doing
these three can these three Gardens that
you're seeing here yeah I
my partner was the same age we were all
just you know late 20s or in right
around 30 when we started doing this in
76 though I was only 25. mm-hmm
are you are you still in contact with
any of the other guys all of you all of
them said they're all still with us
that's awesome that's freaking awesome
yeah the the relatively speaking the
dealer from Tempe has
um
what's that disease he's now in a
wheelchair after 15 years he made it 15
years multiple of sclerosis
Ms yeah yeah so he's kind of restricted
another partner who was the very last
one I worked with he was a friend we all
knew each other
independently I mean it was great
because we're all originally friends
um he um has early onset Alzheimer's in
70 and he he has great um long-term
memory but he can't drive a car he yeah
he doesn't remember where he is within a
block so he's restricted but my first
partner that you saw there in Magic
handing down by the water he he's still
he's six foot seven and he's a big and
um he's still around and I I see him
every once in a while but my partner for
the last two years in magic
he lives in Taos
he's originally from the UK
one who just wrote The Year of the Mad
Jack he's got it on Amazon you can get
it it's a fictional account of
yeah all of us in our in all of the
characters but it's more about A Love
Affair he had
at the time and it's um pretty funny
it's he he got a an honorable mention in
the in the
F Scott Fitzgerald competition or
something oh wow
he he uh is writing a second book now
already that's going to be more factual
my that'll be great my my pilot friend
who
he's in the chronicle I wrote called
um I know the guy who knows the guy yeah
he I just talked to him a few days ago
he called me because he just fell and
broke his hip
I was going to invite him to be on this
show but
um he's in the hospital in Anchorage
Alaska now
I know bizarre so the universe didn't
want that to happen and I had kind of
thought he wouldn't want to he
he makes Mr Nice look small I I can
we'll go into his story later if you
don't mind yeah I'd love to the last
time I saw him physically in 1985 until
last year
they were just working on 60 tons of
hashish from Pakistan and this is the
level he worked at and
he retired never was busted it's
incredible you know he I know it's it's
amazing but if you knew him this is why
I I was so intent on getting this show
because I think you know we talk about a
lot of the people who who we I yeah
who've been put on a pedestal in our
scene um I mean of course Sam the skunk
man Rob Clark amazing people obviously
deserve their accolades I mean the big
heroes in the scene
um but there's some guys who did some
really big bold stuff that don't quite
get seen for many reasons a lot of it
has to do with the fact that it was
clandestine and illegal and it's in some
folks don't even still want to talk
about it but there are some amazing
Stories out there that I've come across
over the years and years was one and
speaking to someone that you were able
to bring with you um raho I wanted to
get into a little bit with you raho can
you talk about when you first started
collecting and getting into growing yeah
sure Matt
um
it's uh
man it seems like so long ago you know I
was just a kid uh 78 was the first time
I smoked weed and
back then you had to smoke you know
three four five times before you ever
actually felt the effect I don't know if
it was because the concentration of THC
wasn't so you know as high as it is
today or maybe
um the stuff that kids could buy on the
street back then wasn't so great but uh
you know by the time by the time
I got high that very first time you know
I was 15 years old uh after school at a
buddy's house and
um
you know we it took a while to kick in
and
after I was I was actually riding my
bike home thinking oh you know another
time that it didn't work when it started
to hit me right and it was a beautiful
spring day the sun was out you know the
air was just it was one of those days
where the air was crisp and it was the
temperature was perfect you know I'm
cranking away on this 10-speed bike and
the wind is blowing in my face and all
of a sudden I kind of noticed that the
the air and the light and everything is
just kind of alive and the the feeling
of the the wind and the air circulating
around me and in my face and everything
just became
um you know it was like it was like I
was connected with everything around me
and it was a just a wonderful experience
and you know I get I get home
and I put on uh I put on some music
because I'm really cranking at this
point right it's it's really kicking and
I'm like wow you know I mean I I drank I
drank plenty of beer and and you know
but this was nothing like it you know
and uh I put on these headphones and
it's Ted Nugent great white buffalo all
right
wide open cranked up and it's like you
know that's yeah you know that song you
know the Great White Buffalo
and uh oh my God the heightened senses
and all of it going with it yes
how old were you Rojo
15. you never do when I was listening to
that it sounds like you had your very
own Bicycle Day
uh because that's what happened to
Albert Hoffman when he first took lsds
he didn't know it was gonna work yeah
and he got on a bike and started going
around and all of a sudden colors and
wind and he's like what's going on I'm
starting to feel something unusual
and yeah
wow I had no idea man that's uh that was
awesome
celebrated today they call it bicycle
day uh because he took acid accidentally
and then he hopped in his bike and he
and he started drop you know riding
around and all of a sudden things
started altering on him and he really
wasn't sure what was happening he
thought it was the most beautiful
experience he'd ever had and wanted to
give it to everyone it was kind of
similar to what you just said it was
that's what made me think of the colors
and the wind and you were very in tune
with nature and like you're riding your
bike it just kind of triggered that for
me of uh yes of your your headspace
changed and all of a sudden the world
was born anew it was yeah that's amazing
um what I mean to share that experience
or or similar right with uh
with such a famous man pretty cool it's
a great story dude
um so you know I mean that was that was
the first time getting high and um as
soon as I came down you know and Mom and
Dad came home from work and I'm like God
can they tell you know of course yeah
and dinner's prepared and everything
it's you know and it's starting to
reflect on what's
you know what's what's happened to me
and I realized that you know the last
seven years of my life that I've been
told these things in school about drugs
are bad you know they're they're evil
and they'll make you want to jump off of
a building because you think you can fly
or you'll be violent or you know you'll
immediately be addicted and fiending for
more and you know I mean it was just all
of a sudden I just started questioning
everything I'd ever been told by the by
the authorities you know
um because they lied about this and if
they lied about that what else did they
lie about you know
um
so you know almost as every every bag of
weed that that I got after that and
there were many right because that was
the beginning and and uh of course and
you know I've never never been the same
but every bag came with seeds back then
yeah
that's right you know two fingers
yeah yeah
two fingers for a quarter one finger for
a dime bag you know half ounces it's
just you know simple math but there were
plenty of seeds in it and you know where
I lived um you know in the Southeast it
was mostly Colombian that we saw I know
I know magic you know they got lots of
Mexican out there and he was very close
to to where it came from and everything
but for us you know buying kids buying
weed on the street it was it was
commercial Colombian most of the time
and you know it was just loaded with
seeds so
um the the very next year in uh 79 I I
tried to grow my first garden and uh
you know I had a tray full of sprouts
I've been gardening with my mom ever
since I was a little kid you know in the
vegetable garden
tomatoes and cucumbers and watermelons
and you name it right but growing uh
growing weed was just another Garden
thing for me and
um so I got them to sprout I think I
might even use the paper towel method
you know I mean
um because after I started smoking and I
immediately discovered High Times
magazine and it became a monthly ritual
of going down to the bookstore and
picking it up and that was at the the
beginning of High Times yeah
76 77 75 uh yeah so it had been around
for a few years I mean except for the
first year
there you go yeah
um and uh but you know I took those
sprouts and I put them out in the in the
bright full sunlight you know that I
started them indoors under a little
fluorescent light and I and I put them
with no hardening at all under the sun
and I went out the next day and they
were all dead and that was the end of
you know year one
total failure you know
um the next year I came back and I hit
it pretty hard and uh me and me and a
couple of friends of mine how are your
parents with this
you know that's a great question
um just amazingly open-minded about it
um
you know
um it's at one point maybe it was 81 I
think I started I started breeding I had
picked up uh Rob Clark's
um marijuana botany marijuana botany and
it was just so inspiring you know I mean
it it really everything just clicked as
far as the science of breeding and and
um the way that he described you know
genetics and and selection and creating
hybrids and everything it all it was all
so intuitive to me it all just made a
complete and total sense so I
immediately wanted to make my own seeds
and
start breeding and uh you know that
meant
of course you know we we wanted smoke
too so I we needed to segregate the
males and I wound up bringing these male
uh Indica plants into my parents house
um you know I mean I had these things in
the dining room in the window
um just stinking you know I don't know
how I don't know how they put up with it
so my my mom's gone now so I can't I
can't again after that yeah I I have a
question for you so it sounds like
um you know obviously he's you know he's
messing with oaxacan and different
things from Mexico
you know Arizona and New Mexico and that
are not that much different climate but
if you're in the southeast of the United
States and you're getting mostly
Colombian when you that second year
where you didn't kill your seedlings and
you got a lot farther down the path did
you hit a point where you were like are
these ever gonna finish
that's a great question so um you know
that second year uh we had a neighbor
across the street had pulled in a
harvest in 79
um one of one of the one of his friends
had gone to Maui for Christmas
and had come back with seeds of what I
know now was Maui Wowie in 79.
um and he grew they grew a big patch of
that stuff uh and it was it was wide
Leaf it was you know I know today that
it was uh it was Mexican and and some
sort of Indica hybrid
um you know it finished early it had
amazing taste and um being a poor kid
that cut lawns for money
um luckily half of their crop was seeded
and they sold me the seeded stuff for
cheap because nobody wanted it yeah so
back then nobody wanted seeded weed well
you know I mean everything was seated
you know sure when you when half your
crop is is seedless and they made
t-shirts you know that said sins and
they were they were so you know yeah
yeah yeah they were I'd love to see some
of those today I I you know I'm such a
nerd for all the old vintage [__] if
you've ever seen one let me know you
know it's it's amazing you know kids
immediately turn into you know these
instant entrepreneurs when they wind up
with with you know a bedroom full of
weed hanging from the ceiling that's for
sure you know it's just all of a sudden
you know it turns into well all my
friends are gonna want this so how much
am I going to charge for it yep and uh
you know you got lucky in the sense that
you got a hybrid that would actually
finish in your area
yeah because yeah I always had this idea
and I'm I'm obviously like in 19 when
you guys are speaking of 1975 77 78 uh I
was still happily in diapers uh so
that's definitely not my my part but I
always thought that like maybe the first
American breeding was you're getting
this import from Thailand and Colombia
and Panama and all that and you're like
well how the hell do I get this to
finish where I'm at
take this Mexican and I can shorten it
up some because this Mexican seems to be
quicker but yeah exactly right yeah this
tie in this Colombian is taking a
million years and it's getting cold and
it's getting rainy and my stuff doesn't
even look like it's done yeah so I mean
that that Maui was was only part of the
crop that we did that year you know it
was um we we also had a Mexican and we
had we had a couple of Colombians
um you know it was and all my friends
were growing at that point right so you
know uh everybody had a couple of plants
out in the woods and we'd go to a party
on Friday night somebody's parents were
out of town and sometimes they'd walk
you out behind the house and you know
into the woods behind their house and
there'd be a little six foot Colombian
um Christmas tree in a in an opening in
in the woods behind their house you know
just a just a little hole in the canopy
where the sun came in and
um yeah so those Colombians you know
they would they would
we didn't we never really finished them
as as we know you know what you know
resin glands and yeah proper finish
probably they weren't they were never
really properly finished but they were
finished well enough that you know um we
we could get into the end of November
and sometimes even just you know first
couple weeks of December where I lived
uh before before the frost would that's
very helpful yeah and the hardest part
is actually you know not picking it
early kids didn't know any better and we
just wanted to smoke the stuff so
um you know I mean we were just going
off of the the weather reports and the
newspaper and
sure you know Farmers Almanac [__]
so maybe maybe I could ask a question of
both of you
um these first couple of years that you
guys are both describing what were the
what were the the Aromas what were the
scents what were the terpenes you know
no one's no one used terpenes back then
but like what were the what did the
weeds smell like to you
you know that it just smell like we did
you did you get Citrus did you get any
kind of skunk did you get did you smell
like weed you know if you can remember
what Aromas were you getting off these
original Mexicans and and Colombians and
these and these or even uh
1979 skunk one what would that smell
like well yeah we were gonna get there
but I was just curious as like what what
did oaxacan smell like
you know like did it because you know we
know we know these lines from like way
later when they've been worked by people
extensively and bred in different
directions and it sounds like you guys
were getting it basically from the
farmer the source and this yeah from
unadulterated from the farmer and the
source actual like what we would call
land race today I suppose right do you
want to go first uh magic or
um sure well
the very first
I'll just I have a little start up here
the first two joints I bought were in
1966 from the only hippie in my high
school and
um I I wasn't quite ready to smoke them
so I put them in a bottle and buried
them in my yard
and two years later when I dug them up
and thought I'll try them they were just
mold pure mold so that didn't work but
they had
you know your really earliest weed that
I remember smelling from my friend in
well when I went to
yeah
um
pine pine terpenes really stood out in
1975 or 76 some Growers weed from Santa
Barbara was showing up in the Verde
Valley in Sedona Cottonwood Jerome area
and probably coming through Phoenix and
it smelled just like fresh pine I've
never smelled weed like it again since
then it if you close your eyes and just
held it up you would think you were you
had Pine salt in your in front of you
and like a Christmas tree style or pine
salt what'd you say
um more of a Christmas tree style yeah
natural Pine yeah yeah and it was it was
beautiful stuff it was sensimilla it it
was strong and it was very inspiring
because when we smelled that tide wheat
though Thai stick had a total different
scent it was heavy and earthy
um
I remember seeing early Thai sticks in
1970s 71 that were
supposedly dipped in the Opium too or
opium yeah the pasta water yeah they had
white on the outside
we sat down with some black hash ones
that was opiated supposedly but little
black white specks to it and we cut out
with the razor blades every white Speck
so we could have been mold huh
so we could have enough to take a hit
and it wasn't opium I don't know what it
was it didn't get us any higher but it
made the costs go up when people were
buying it they paid more for it I've
I've looked a lot into that situation uh
especially when researching chocolate
Thai because a lot of that theory behind
chocolate Thai was that it was dipped in
something called Pasha water or pasta
water which was the the water that was
left over from producing heroin it had
the alkaloids the morphine alkaloids and
stuff in it and supposedly the story was
that they would dip it in that but
there's not really any proof of any of
this ever existing anywhere but that was
the theory behind it and where we're
kind of all stemmed from it may have
happened once or twice but I don't know
if it ever really got out there but I've
heard about people being charged massive
amounts of prices for these Thai sticks
that were supposedly dipped in this
water
yeah there's been long long debates
about that online but yeah you know it's
uh I think it's been pretty much
debunked mostly because the people
growing the two different crops weren't
really the same people and and a lot of
them weren't producing heroin they were
just Farmers right like not like before
we lose track what was the smells that
you were getting off uh off your uh
Hawaiian hybrids that you were
successful with that second year
right so I mean you know the the Mexican
versus Colombian
um you know pretty pretty distinctive I
usually associate
uh Cedar tastes and kind of a kind of a
citrus
um Citrus Pioneer cedery taste with with
Mexican and I grew some beautiful
walking a couple of times that you know
it flowered so much faster than the
Colombian that I actually let it go too
long to the point where it was it was
actually over mature and I I it had lost
some of its potency
um but but that was contrasted with the
Colombians which were
um you know usually we'd get a lot of
purple
because we they'd be coming in so late
that just the temperature change would
would bring out a lot of Purple colors
and then you know once something turns
purple that um
what's that what's that uh it's not
chlorophyll what's the other signings
yeah the anthocyanins really seem to
affect the taste and oh yeah you always
do affects the taste and smell but that
yeah and uh and personally I like it
right I do too purple fiend yeah but um
you know like like magic said the uh you
know the pine was was there in in the
Colombian and
um there's a you know difference between
the smell and The Taste when you smoke
it
um there's um
yep there is there's some of it has kind
of a chocolatey I I mean you know I
don't want to completely Sidetrack
things into a haze talk but you know my
my belief is when I when I started
growing oh Haze
um you know a few years ago I found that
the effects one day I just realized that
the effects that I got from smoking oh
Haze and even the tastes were exactly
the same as what I felt that first time
I got high riding that bicycle home
you know yeah the Colombian and you know
that you know it really kind of messed
with my head a little bit because for so
long people talked about Haze as the
mixture of you know four different kinds
of of sativity Mexican Colombian Thai
and and Indian right yeah yeah
um and you know trying to figure out how
this what what is obviously a you know
Sam's the ohaze as it's been released to
the world since since uh Sam brought it
to
Amsterdam yeah um you know is not
everything that they that they made when
the poster was made right and the
pedigree was described it's that's what
Sam brought with him that's what Sam
preserved that's what Sam shared a
three-way Colombian hybrid right not the
Indian not the Thai not not the Mexican
and
um the tastes are there you know there's
kind of a chocolatey taste to it
um you know earthy you could call it
there's Piney
um you can find some sweetness in there
some Citrus there's different phenos in
there but it's all coming from Colombia
as far as I'm concerned and you know we
can have a debate and I'll I'll let
anybody believe what they want to
believe but I I genuinely think like
right now uh there is a man with a
letter D for a name that is just smiling
ear to ear when it when enables old
partners and it's been talking to me in
not so a bunch specifically about Sam's
oh hey days being so Colombian dominant
being so Colombian dominant and the the
69 Hayes was it that Neville had gotten
the first time was very much more like
Southeast Asian dominant and that was
the main difference between the Hayes
Neville was using and why Neville cities
became so popular and why a lot of the
ohays supposedly that's one of the
theories why ohays didn't come as as
much as it had promised yeah it reminded
me of something actually because uh it
had been mentioned
um earlier on on the thing is that when
you know Thai and stuff like that was a
little bit broader leafed right
um and you know he made a point that you
know Sam and those guys you know they
kept reading towards the thin Leaf
because they thought that was more
sativa
um but that was actually more Colombian
sativa and that some of the Southeast
Asian stuff and some of the ties it's
not like they were fat weaved but they
were broader leafed than
um pure Colombian ones
yeah I've got a picture of a tie I grew
in 81 it was it was uh Thai stick from
1980 that A friend brought home from
college
um older brother of one of my partners
brought home from college and and uh in
Colorado and it's very thin leaf and I I
know that you know people talk about
with Ty the alligator tail leaves right
Broad Leaf extreme serrations
um and it's you know it's uh it has a
reputation for that but that was you
know it's a it's a big country and um
you know we all know from growing that
man you can't even pack uh pop a 10 pack
of seeds without seeing you know a
couple of narrow Leafs in there with the
wide leaves so why should we think that
an entire country is going to produce
nothing but the same thing of course
micro climates everywhere yeah yeah for
um for like Matt and myself
um you know when I was first started
smoking the only real two kinds of
import I ever saw was brown Mexican and
green Mexican
I came up a little later the Thai the
Colombian the you know the Panamanian
all some of these different Regional
things you know the the shift towards
all those groups mostly importing
cocaine had already happened so a lot of
the diversity and imports had changed
and there was still a bunch of Mexican
um but that's kind of all it was for us
yeah same experience for me even a
decade coming in a decade I think after
Naza where I was starting it was the
same we had Mexican was it
you know talking about these Mexicans
I'm thinking about mad Jag's experience
with that stuff and and I I don't want
to can we just stick a pin in that I
want to make one more point about the
haze and the co the Colombian um the the
Colombian roots of it as we know it
today for
um that you know Colombia just like
we're just discussing Thailand is is you
know obviously going to have a diverse
range of different uh different
chemotype phenotypes whatever
um but but you know in Colombia you had
Reds and and Golds and and green and and
you know black black yeah I mean so many
different types and and uh they all had
such distinctive flavors and tastes and
effects um you know I was lucky you know
when I started doing this stuff it was
it was the end of the Gory days of those
Elite
um those Elite types of of weed I got to
smoke the Panama Colombian red
um I I got to smoke real Santa Mara gold
and um you know they all have things in
common but but they were some unique
characteristics about them that just you
know Vive La difference you know just uh
yeah big big big fan of uh are The
Connoisseur and High Times magazine and
he uh he inspired me to become a
connoisseur of life and and appreciate
all the differences between things and
Savor them and I want to point this out
just because I I just even a recent
episode I I made a statement that I
thought R was Robert Clark because
that's kind of what people have been
saying forever or it's assumed but I
think that might be wrong Maybe
totally wrong totally wrong so yeah
that's that's an important note to make
because I have always Associated
everything Robert Clark's ever written
with Arthur connoisseur and I love
Arthur connoisseur and I love Robert
Clark too but I've always Associated
them as the same person and and they're
not no I asked Rob himself because yeah
long ago
um
I wondered the same question and he said
no and I I've actually heard r's real
name and I can't remember it right now
but someone I know from Manhattan knows
him and and said oh no that's a
different guy I wonder if he's still
with us
I don't know ah man you'd be a great one
to interview one thing I'm curious about
and I don't want to there's so many
threads that happen in these kind of
convos you could lose it at but
um when you were describing how
difficult it was to get to your Canyon
grows
um having done some gorilla myself and
and hidden
um obviously like growing it is one
thing but then harvesting it and drying
it and getting it out of there is
another thing could you talk for a
minute about what that was like if
you're going down some Goat Trail
through the rocks and all of a sudden
you have several hundred pounds that
would be Dr you know that I mean more
like a thousand pounds when it's wet you
know did you try to dry it there in the
bushes did you hike it all out one by
one
um how much effort went into that
because I that's a real struggle
we
once we started growing in our own
Canyon in Magic Canyon we did everything
um except for that first year where you
had the photo of my friend down next to
the water but the subsequent two years
with my partner from the UK
and we had a Swiss helper too who I'm
still good friends with I saw him three
years ago in Zurich he we did everything
down there we manicured it we dried it
manicured it boxed it we we bought
knocked down boxes from A supplier in
Phoenix that were roughly I'd say about
well
for 12 inches by eight inches by six
inches and that held a pound
so that's perfect what we did we we
brought Kelty pack frames that were just
bare frames without the uh Associated
baggage on them and bungee cords and we
could stack five of these boxes on one
Kelty so you could carry out five pounds
oh wow every every bit was hiked out
that way up this 1600 foot wash of
Boulders and strewn and we had pruned a
few branches here and there where you
just had to have clearance to get under
a pine tree or something
and we were very fortunate because
are one of the people in my life who's
still around he was one of the two
principles of peyote that I've written
about he also is a huge weed dealer and
he would meet us at the edge of our
Canyon after sunset
and we would just hike up hanum however
many boxes we brought up and he'd hand
us a paper bag full of cash and we
didn't have to even drive to Phoenix or
take them with
trying to take it back home because that
was actually the thought of working that
hard for a year and then losing it all
because you got a traffic stop that was
really influenced us so
we got a hundred dollars an ounce
sixteen hundred a pound and
that was the standard price and yeah he
sold it all by grams
smart man he's so he sold it for ten
dollars a gram to college students at
ASU he lived two blocks away from from
ASU in Tennessee he just would buy
everything we had and just slowly sell
it over a year or two and triple his
money so you had a you had a you had a
uh you had one or two friends that were
helping you
right so when it comes to hiking it out
if you could bring about five pounds at
a time that means each trip you're
probably at a maximum of 10 or 15 pounds
yep um yeah so at Harvard we brought in
six more people at Harvest Time okay
that makes more sense yeah I was gonna
say I was like man you were really fit
uh yeah your your legs your hiking
ability was intense because it's a lot
of back and forth
yeah well that part I mean I've
I've hiked down gasoline you know five
gallons of gas is like 35 pounds and
yeah garbage bags and it would still
stink it was amazing because shaking it
and moving down
it was so difficult to keep it not from
saturating everything but at Harvest
Time boyfriends and girlfriends of ours
and others
um at most we had eight people down
there
manicuring
um we
we set up a 10 by 10 foot Coleman
classic tents that were spray painted
so they were a light brown color but we
sprayed them with a little darkness and
green and they Blended in very nicely
and we limbed the plants
we we cut
we cut a whole plan if we could if it
wasn't too big we'd hang it
for a day or two and then we'd cut the
branches off lemon and stacked them like
like that all the way up inside these
tents so in case it did rain we weren't
going to get caught in you know there
yeah you know
did you do a lot of sun drying
no it was all and I know
we hung Roots between trees and just
hung them in there and it was still in
the 90s or 80s in the day at night it
would drop up where we were growing we
were growing at about 4 500 feet so it
at night it would cool down but in the
day this you know it was really nice
plus we were growing in our main Garden
was in an east west
situation so that the sun when it came
up it hit very early and it went almost
to the end of of the night because it
did drop below the uh Canyon Edge at
each end but
one of our Gardens was in the north
south section and it only got seven
hours or eight hours of direct sunlight
at Max yeah and still the plants grew
perfectly and beautifully it didn't make
a difference
um but the east west
Gardens you know they got 10 11 hours of
direct sunlight were awesome yeah they
grew much bigger plants much taller
for what uh when did when did the
Mexicans naturally finish like when was
your Harvest Time when when were they
ripe those first few years for you
October
October yeah the Colombian you passed a
photo by their earlier
that was the
it was
um it was snowing on the rim above us on
Thanksgiving
and that's our tent one of them yeah
there it is
right in there
well hidden that was a that was the
north south Garden we called the Anasazi
there's the Hall of the Mountain King
you cannot you know that kept hikers out
yeah anyway the Colombian the Colombian
we didn't know about these things about
finishing and how long they would take
and it was crazy because it was they
were the size of my little fingertip you
know the buds and yeah it was
Thanksgiving and snowing above us
so we didn't grow any more Colombian
after that first year
I think was it by R anyway there's this
famous there's this famous
um list of seeds that's been attributed
to Sam or it's been attributed to others
or whatever and it had a bunch of you
know hazes and skunks and different
things like that but what was
interesting about it
is it was organized by month that it
finished
and there was only three or four things
that finished in October there was
probably 10 things that finished in
November and then there was like 25
things that were December or January
which is like a polar opposite of today
um yeah well Rob was growing in Ben
Lomond
um just above Santa Cruz in the Redwoods
there and he you know the the
temperatures were very Mediterraneans in
a sense you know yeah
um back I wanted to jump forward to a
question when you were talking about
Mendocino and up north did you ever do
you know where Redway is
yes
because I met my Colombian friend in in
future partner in many escapades at the
country Tavern there in 1972.
oh wow a guy a guy from Scottsdale owned
the country Tavern
and he also had his own chemist and he
produced millions and millions of hits
of acid
that's amazing good when we went into
that Tavern the first time
half the people were tripping and it was
just wow it was like clean scene but my
Colombian friend who I just met there he
took me on a hike down towards Shelter
Cove Shelter Cove was was just five
houses then that were abandoned because
it was a someone tried to do a
subdivision there and it didn't work so
as we hiked down we went off into the
woods because he knew about a few plants
and I saw my first plants over there
that were growing they were individual
holes in between the Redwoods like where
there was a spot of sun shooting down in
and it was just this beautiful black
rich soil and their plants were you know
probably six or seven feet tall so I was
like wow that's cool
but yeah that's my part of the country
I've I moved to Mendocino County in 1998
and I've lived there since so Southern
humble Humboldt in general Mendocino
Lake all those areas that's kind of like
my stomping grounds
um and uh yeah and you know like like
you were saying with LSD or whatever
else
um you know there was back then it was
remote uh it was mountainous you could
get you know there wasn't very many
people uh your worries up there were
hunters and loggers
um right but lots of people went up
there to kind of get away from things
some people grew weeds some people did
other things but it was that isolation
and that and that being kind of out in
the middle of nowhere
Ville that was kind of no idea
I have no idea how this guy from
Scottsdale found Redway but that he
bought the cut the tavern there and he
was living nearby and his chemist was
somewhere nearby out in the woods and
um yeah if it was a interesting place
and that's where my Colombian friend was
Gerardo
so
he was on a student visa but he
overstayed an extra eight years
so
um yeah he he spoke he learned English
simultaneously with Spanish in Colombia
and Cali since he was five years old so
he spoke such perfect English that
later in life when we were
our big
big bust happen
um he was interviewed by FBI agents he
corrected their spelling twice
oh wow because they didn't know how to
spell the words that they were using so
it was pretty funny yeah and you know
another thought I had you met you
mentioned uh you know Howard marks's
book Mr Nice and how your friend kind of
blew him out of the water
um I remember a long time ago when I
read his autobiography that he said that
basically his autobiography was full of
people that had been busted
and that some of the coolest and biggest
people that he interacted with had never
got in trouble so therefore you weren't
going to hear anything about them in his
book
because they had skated through and
nobody knew about them and he wasn't
about to give any tips or ideas so he
said his book was essentially a
collection of people that had gotten in
trouble
and that there was many who didn't and
they were invisible
well I I can dig it my friend who who
broke his hip and was my our pilot
friend he um never got busted and he
gave my UK partner the go-ahead that he
would be willing to let him write a book
about him and interview him so
he's excited about that but I said to
him
um you're gonna have to follow this guy
because he's all over the world still
you know now he's in the hospital in
Anchorage so you could probably get some
weeks of talk with him but you know he
goes he still goes to Hong Kong and
Portugal and I mean the guy is
um he's 75 and
he got his pilot's license when he was
15 before he could drive a car and we
figured it out once he stopped keeping a
log book at 10 000 hours and he said
that most TWA Pilots never hit 10 000
hours yeah but he literally lives in his
his plane and then when he went to
Alaska and bought a a gold mine the only
way to get to it was to fly in and out
so and as you know in Alaska everyone
uses planes like cars you know if they
live way out in the woods
so he he owned the airport once in a
town that I lived in and he's just a
legend but you're right no one really
knew about him just like Mr nice's
Howard Mark's friends
um because
he got into Afghanistan in the late 60s
he was importing lapis the deep blue
stone yeah highly valued in Europe and
that led to hashish
and he was just sending home a few
pounds rolled up in Afghani rugs he
would just ship them and they would get
through back then they weren't even
using dogs really to check stuff in the
late 60s or 1970.
then his friends slowly
you know move to Freighters and they
were sending Freighters but when the
Soviets took over he couldn't go to
Afghanistan any longer so he moved over
to Peshawar in Pakistan into Star Wars
now is known as the terrorist capital I
mean that's where all that for sure oh
the terrorists hang up that [__] before
but he would um he was active over there
gosh I don't know
I like I said last time I met him in 85
in in um
he had a houseboat in Sausalito and I
met him there and
he was visibly shaking because he was so
excited about the 60-ton barge that they
were going to pull across the the
universe which they did more than that's
awesome that is so awesome wow yep
and they would go to Canada
Canada had he said they had only like a
thousand not even a thousand a few
hundred agents in involved in drugs so
all those West Coast places above Juneau
in Alaska and that were perfect I mean
in Canada along the coastline yeah
so Canada has much more of a hashish
culture than America did because of that
importing and you know I think not only
that but it was like the penalties if
you got caught in Canada were far less
than the American ones right right now
and once it reached there it would get
him exported over to the U.S
um yeah and
this guy
he he had a
a passport you pay ten thousand dollars
for from the UK in like 1969 or
something and it was a real passport
that
um he was able to have it fixed with his
name on it that's awesome and his photo
and he would he would walk across the
border to Canada
and then fly from Canada around the
world as a British citizen
when he was going to Afghanistan and
Pakistan he wasn't an American he was
British so and then he'd fly back to
Canada and walk across the border into
Washington and be and then go back to
his normal life over here man after my
own heart yeah he also had one of the
first phone scramblers I've ever seen he
bought it from a company in Amsterdam
and you held it up to the phone and the
little rubber cups went over each end
and then you talked to the back of it
and yeah it was used and stuff like that
you know by 1970 1971 very security
conscience fella
very smart
yep wow that's fascinating so so
I was gonna say I we've we've kind of
wandered off the Mad Jag part but
there's one part that like totally
totally enthralled me with the whole
story and it was about not just about
the wizard robes or any of that because
I find that so amazing like the pictures
of you guys with wearing the wizard
robes and being very you know serious
about all this but how well you treated
the land and how you respected the land
and the culture that came before in a
lot of your writings you talk about even
finding ancient like the ancient
petroglyphs but also some items and
stuff that you guys would not take you'd
leave it there because that's where it
was and and all and leaving nothing not
even Footprints behind so I was
wondering if you could talk a little bit
about the spiritual aspect of magic
Canyon
um well when we first started exploring
it I started from the bottom up where it
flowed into another Canyon which flowed
into another Canyon and
that's where I first met a mountain lion
I'm pretty sure it was it wasn't a
Jaguar but we came up with the term you
know mad Jag that I had come upon
because it was screeching at me in the
dark when I was trying to go to sleep oh
my God that Canyon oh my god when we got
further up the canyon and found these
spots we started finding Boulders just
covered with pictograph I mean
petroglyphs and in 15 minutes that rock
that you had a photo of let's see I'm
gonna try to find this yeah we hadn't we
had a projectile point and all these
pieces of pottery and we just left them
there like a little
little Shrine or altar yeah we also
found a cave across from our garden the
first year where I was working with that
tall guy
um and in this cave was a uh those are
Colombians there this is the Colombian
right here yeah those are all the ones
that's as big as they got this is close
to Thanksgiving this photo that's wild
they they grew huge but they they just
they needed to get into December in the
tropical
see where's the petrolys here
there we go there's some beautiful
and we we did these costumes and things
thinking that someday we would do a
movie you know and that's why we were
doing this and here's the I still have
this little Arrowhead here but we left
all the pottery behind and
and
we've found a cave across from near our
first Garden that had an arrow shaft in
it it had a a single Yucca fiber
um
moccasin that the ancient people you
know the made out of Yucca fiber and
they were like about half inch thick and
they had been chewed up a lot by a rat
but you know they were obviously in this
this cave
um so we just left them there as a
little
Museum we we put them all on a rock
together
I'd love to go back to it
but we um
the one thing we didn't do which I
regret but it could still happen was
take all of our old um hoses out of the
canyon and the pump they're still there
yeah oh my God still there oh yeah
they're tucked under the tree we went
back in the 90s and the bear had pulled
a bunch of them out so we could
re-buried them and pushed them back
under
um and the pump got hiked out ultimately
by someone who wanted to use it and
that's funny
this guy was a young
stallion man he's just strapped that
sucker on a single
pack for him and hiked it out himself
and we had taken it in two of us on a
pole you know between us but he just
hiked it out yeah so
if you can get it out you can have it
what year did that happen and he knew
you guys before and you guys told him
about the pump existing
he was this tall guy's mother-in-law
okay that makes sense yeah so um he he
went in and
he worked he came down I think at
Harvest Time and helped us a bit
he since left the planet though he was
much younger than all of us but he he
lived a
Rough and Tumble life you know and yeah
yep he uh didn't make it but it's
it's
um the spiritual aspect
I've slept right where he's sitting here
a few times next to the creek and
listened to it flowing by at night it
was the most fabulous thing in the in
talking about Dark Skies
in 19 you know late 70s the dark skies
in northern Arizona were extensive
um yeah Flagstaff was the nearest place
um I spent 400 Days out of my life in
the bottom of this Canyon and
over a year of my life and it's it's
just you know it became like my second
home in a way I can imagine five years
ago we grew for five years in this
Canyon
and
um since then it's been just quiet I we
every once in a while I'll go back and
go out on the rim and look down in and
um
more people are driving in four-wheel
drives and razors and little four by
side by side Vehicles you know they're
going out on all these Jeep trails and
that but they don't know what's down
below because they're not going to get
out and hike down 1600 feet
um
just on a hunch and get down there and
they wouldn't find these alluvial
plateaus they're just too
buried you know that's so wild
yeah 90 90 feet above the creek
um you wouldn't there's no trail that
would even remotely bump into it so yeah
yeah it was a special place still is um
I went back there four years ago looking
for this trail that a Rancher had made
years ago
that came down not far from this
original garden and I couldn't find the
trailhead again it had grown over so
much in 10 years that when I was there
to last
hunted all over man for hours and hours
and I know where it goes down but I just
couldn't find the trailhead so
I'm going to go back it's strange it was
it's in a forest fire area that has
still not been reopened
and after uh a fire that was over a year
and a half ago and I'm gonna go talk to
the Forester because I want to find out
why I have a feeling why is that
it's not about landslides or people
getting hurt it's exposed so many
architecture archaeological spots from
the trees burning and there's all this
that they're I think they're afraid of
people going out there and plundering
yeah spots that's very human
yeah
that was more used and where the guys
from Jerome were using it
um I've seen skulls
just laying on the surface where people
had dug to burial sites you know ancient
burial sites It's just sad but uh wild
it goes on yeah Raiders of the Lost Art
they did an article in Tempe in the
early 80s about guys who would go out
and just look for burial sites and dig
them up oh wow there's plundered one of
them I knew and he got busted got five
years in prison
um because of you know ancient
that's what happens I mean ancient grave
robbing is something that's been going
on for a long long time and they get
they get sold on the private Market to
collectors and you know the origin of
you know all that it's it's definitely a
I mean it's a shame that it happens but
it it seems like it goes on anywhere
there's ancient Humanity that existed
oh yeah
Egypt yeah Egypt Egypt would be the one
of the primary sources sure
yeah yeah
so I don't know I don't I mean we could
this conversation could likely go in a
million different directions yeah I
think they're feeling this is going to
be like a nine-parter it could be it
would probably be more than just this
one part because we can't touch on
everything but one of the things I do
want to touch on is that one one thing
that's like really interesting demands
ourselves is that
um you know some of these you know we
got a little off topic on Haze and you
know and but some of this stuff with
Haze and skunk one and some of these
American strains a lot of uh us younger
folk our first like legitimate history
on them that we know of comes from when
they made their way over to Holland
right and that's when they kind of
became famous and started getting bread
with and started getting sold where
people could hear about them and then
you have people like Rob and and Sam and
stuff like that who tell their story but
it's very you know with historians or
whatever it's always cool to get a
different perspective from someone you
know an alternate Source from the same
era right and you were talking before
about how for a minute there or for a
year or two you were Sam and Rob's
biggest customer
right yep in the sense that you bought
you bought something like if I remember
correctly off the top of my head
something like 3 000 skunk one seeds
was that 1978 or 1979 something like
that you said 79.80 and and on the back
of this if you look at it up close it
says that these were bred for the 1980
in 1980 for the 1981 season do you still
have it
yeah so you still have that
yeah
oh yeah and oh my I was telling Rahul
yesterday some of the loads we got from
from the uh
cartel in Mexico at a certain point in
for roughly
82 to 84.
um we would get we moved our first load
so quickly that they sent us another
load that was wasn't meant for us it had
labels in it from some one in California
and I've got two or three of these
labels I know you'd like to have them
and I'd be glad this time I
um Sam wanted them too Sam collects yeah
yes
this one this one was
it was a a Santa Claus in a uh in a uh
wagon pulled by horses and it was in a
black it's a black and white label and
then we got another one a different time
there was someone else's load but
because we were moving them faster they
just sent it to us and it was a raccoon
on the label and it was from Northern
California and um yeah it was it was
funny but these
yeah
these are precious
um little mementos
and
I I went to Amsterdam in 1969 right out
of high school I went on seven weeks to
Europe with a friend and that's the
first place I tried to get high I was at
the club Paradisio and I couldn't I
didn't smoke cigarettes so I took a big
hit of of something and I coughed my
lungs I couldn't even get it in deep
enough to get it but to give you an idea
this guy was selling a pound of of
Turkish weed for fifteen dollars
it was in a shoe box a shoebox full was
15 bucks and I have no idea
huh do you think it was like
yeah it was probably you know like
bagweed from Turkey yeah that's dark
brown it didn't look good
um but I bought my first chunk of hash
and I actually smuggled it back in 1969
I was nervous as heck yeah okay
um
I didn't
actually get high until later in 69 when
I went to college that was the the first
time and I don't know if I had that hash
still then or not but Denver in 1969 had
everything you know
Panama Red Colombian Mexican
um
every sort of acid you could possibly
want was being sold at On The Hill in
Boulder so yeah all you have to do is
drive over to Boulder and hang out
yeah was it called back then it was just
called the hill
it's called the hill and Boulder yeah it
was in the next is near the university
but it was this stretch
and it still really works yeah there's a
bookstore at the top where
um I actually saw Ellen Ginsburg reading
the book
um it was called brilliant works and
tulagi on the hill is still there it's a
place where they have live music it's a
bar with live music I saw lightning
Hopkins there and a few other amazing
people
um so wild
yeah and it opened and I think I have a
photo of it like in my
um Chronicles I think in 64 it opened
yeah I mean I was really a kid then but
yeah um
so
the uh what what channel are we on now
oh well yeah I mean that's funny so so
when I went when I was going to Boulder
in the 90s it that hill was still a
place that you could go and buy weed and
acid it had transformed and it was
called it was called hippie Hill
nice right then
um and it was still a spot that you
could go and yeah you could get um
obviously the the you know the type of
weed had changed but the ability to go
there and and meet someone and score a
bag of weed uh and you know the cops
sort of tolerated it and tolerated a
little bit of trade going on there or
whatever so
um it's a I didn't realize how early
that had started
um because at that point by the time
that I had been going uh which was the
mid 90s late 90s it would have been
ongoing that then for 30 some years
right um but what the the thread we were
on is I would love to know and I'm sure
Matt would too what Rob or Sam told you
about their skunk one lines
like you know aside from the
descriptions and stuff like that like
what they told you about what was in
them or why they were excited about them
what got you excited about them to buy
so many and then what your experience
was like actually growing them in terms
of like what they grew like what they
smelled like were they superior to the
Mexicans you were growing anything like
that would be probably wonderful to chat
about
well I met Rob through High Times he was
he wrote articles a few and yeah at the
end of the article he always put
something like if you want to
um if you're interested in any of the
things I wrote about or these seeds
you can contact me through the magazine
so I wrote a letter to High Times to Rob
and I put my phone number in there and
he called me up and that's how we hooked
up because the
the first year I grew skunk I had
already had two years actually three
years of growing before that but the
year before I made enough money that I
could afford I when I saw and heard his
description and other people's of skunk
number one I just went this is what I
want to grow something that has a
reputation and and these guys are
breeders he's written a book on botany
for Craig's sake so
um he um I said yeah I want to get 3 000
seats they were two bucks a piece and he
he knocked it down to 175. and he flew
to Phoenix delivered them to me because
you're not going to put that in the mail
back then yeah and yeah 500 in the mail
no so he flew it we met at the airport
Sky Harbor
drove him up to Cottonwood where I lived
he stayed a few days and
um
again 5500 in cash and he was super
happy when he came up he had this little
um zip case that he pulled out of his
jacket and he had he had pre-rolled
joints of Thai of Colombian of oaxacan
of skunk number one and hit and he was
standing there and he gave me one hit of
something out in my living room and I
was laying on the floor after that and
he was just standing there talking away
smoke and the rest of the whole joint
and he said oh but you got to try this
ties this time strain and I've never I
my friend in Scottsdale who was I mean
in Tempe who was the dealer he can smoke
like that my Colombian friend for sure
he started smoking when he was seven in
the Cali Colombia but my friend in Tempe
he would roll 10 hash joints
pin joints yeah just crumbled up hash
and smoked them in a day's time in 100
degree driving a tractor that was his
motivation just chain smoke hash joints
Jesus Rob was pretty much like that so I
I don't remember him describing to me
what skunk was like it was what I read
in high times that it just this skunky
smell and
it was going to be also have some exotic
strains in it
the original skunk number one didn't
have Indian you know the Kerala India in
it at all it was just
three countries I think right
um Colombian Mexican Afghan
yep it was just those three and
I had smoked each of those individually
but the fact that this was a hybrid that
was so potent and everything I don't
know what I had read I have all those
old High Times magazines I have the
first High Times I have the first Black
Belt Magazine I collect all kinds of
weird [__] I love that too
yeah and memorabilia we'll get into that
I'll I'll send you some things
um through a collection you just let me
know
but
um
The Afghani number one
I did get a few from him as a gift I
think from buying all the skunk and it's
funny because this says Afghani Hindu
Kush hashish seeds I noticed his label
and yet on the back he says this is
skunk number one and I have one of these
envelopes with Afghani number one
um yeah so
is kind of you know and he also has in
letters here extra early
so yeah I I was reading it it actually
is a description for a pure Afghani is
what it is like the whole thing is a
description for a pure unadulterated
Afghani but then it says skunk one right
there
these envelopes had two giant horse caps
um with 50 seeds in each one so there
were 100 seeds in two big joke I mean
cellulose caps yeah he'd get 50 cents in
each one and
I don't know what happened to the many
many of these very different people over
the years wanted one and I gave him one
and my sure I think my my UK partner
still has several
um
I don't know
how else to Rob came down to our garden
once and that's when he said he was
amazed that we could grow out of dirt
yeah
you've never seen Arizona plants I don't
think before and we averaged 6.8 ounces
across our entire Garden per plant which
roughly almost a half a pound per plant
which growing in the dirt yeah he said
he was used to two three four pound
plants in Northern California you know
up in that black soil but um
well there's a there's a there's a
volume you know thing too and like plant
numbers
um and so in in Northern California I
mean some people went crazy but a lot of
times people tried to
um maximize how much they could get per
plant
to not get you know so if they did get
in trouble in Northern California it
would be for Less plants
that was a big thing so it's way way
easier and I think you get better weed
growing up six or seven or eight ounce
plant versus a four or five or six pound
plant
um but numbers did play a role at least
in Northern California where I'm from
country
did they what what were the type Aromas
that you got off the skunk one that
first year you grew them
it it was very it was very skunky note
you know the smell of a skunk when you
drive over it on the highway it was that
exact no it we were we were stupefied by
it actually we were when this is
incredible and it didn't smell like that
growing so much but when you when it was
harvested the flowers dried and you
crush you know a flower and it was skunk
smell
and it was pretty damn potent we rolled
a joint once and went to this topless
club called the highlighter that we
liked in Phoenix and
one of the two of the dancers we went in
the ladies bathroom with two of the
dancers and we each had one puff that's
all before we got busted by another
dancer who came in and was in charge
that night and said you guys have to get
out of here and so we went and sat down
the ladies I think they had one puff
each more it was they were these were
New York needles we called them or pin
joints where you had to really
you know just to get a hit and we were
sitting there and they came out of the
bathroom they walked around the bar
they were laughing and they smiled at us
and then they walked right into a table
knocked it over all the drinks went over
they fell in the ground themselves and
we were just sitting there laughing they
were they had never been that high in
their life and we found out later that
they were um scared almost
I bet
but you know in 1980 or 81
there was you know we had already smoked
this sensimilla from Santa Barbara that
was very Piney and I've and there was
Thai weed around and other things but
for some reason this thing packed a
punch really quite a punch and
I I don't know how people would rate it
today compared to all these you know
chem dogs and and all the other
varieties that people have bred up to 35
THC or whatever they're at now
um but as you know the Entourage effect
is what counts the total package you
know the terpenes the bioflavonoids
everything everything someone said that
the test on an original Afghani I mean
uh skunk number one was it was only like
14 or 15 THC yeah most of the stuff I
like Falls in between 8 to 18.
yeah so all the other ingredients the
terpenes perhaps that skunky terpene
um
profile
and other things really added up
it's really nice to have another account
that isn't from Rob or Sam about skunk
one having that same smell even back
then because it's it's been heavily
debated for a long time whether that was
true that skunk one had that smell or if
it never happened yeah
yeah because
the stuff that got sold in Europe
um it sounds like Rob and and Sam or
maybe Sam only kept breeding away from
that Aroma and So eventually it became
very floral very Citrus uh maybe a
little cheese maybe some grapes
um but people have been hunting for that
skunky smell in skunk and seeds yeah
ever since and yet it seems like it
existed in the 70s and the early 80s and
then it kind of went away
um and he maybe they successfully bred
it out of the line entirely because
people have really hunted through skunk
one trying to find recessives that are a
throwback to what you just described
hey uh
so I uh I moved out to NorCal to grow
for a season and uh it was 1985 and when
I first arrived in Ukiah I had taken a a
Greyhound bus and my instructions were
to meet my new partners
at the laundromat which was near the
airport and the bus station I guess I'm
not sure that's that part's a little
fuzzy but I'll never forget you know
arriving in Ukiah getting off the bus
and as I'm walking towards the
laundromat you know following the
instructions I'd been given the entire
town smelled like skunk
the entire town I mean wow everywhere I
walked and I I had to wait for a couple
hours so after a while I got bored of
standing around waiting for my buddy to
drive down off the mountain and and you
know pick me up so I I walked around a
little bit
the whole town smelled just like you
know a roadkill you know people confuse
the Rotting Flesh roadkill part with a
look when I when a skunk gets hit on the
side of the road you don't smell
anything but the skunk right
it's not about rotting anything yes no
yeah it's just that sulfurous uh you
know that's been smashed yeah yeah I I
live about 15 minutes for I can be in
Ukiah in about 15 minutes from my house
beautiful so you said 1885 that's the
what part of where did you get that
first year do you remember what part of
of Mendocino you grew in do you remember
where you were now 1985 was the influx
like the major major influx of indicas
into that region I mean there of course
there were some you know making their
way bits and pieces throughout the 70s
and whatnot the 85 was like the smash
year for indicas right out in that area
so it makes sense a shitload of skunk
would be in that town
you know the indicus that I grew in um
in 81 and 82
uh were from NorCal from Ukiah and and
you know the the towns around there and
they were picked up by a friend of mine
who was hitchhiking around there for for
like two years and every time he'd he'd
you know get picked up he would offer to
to you know would you like hey I've got
some weed do you want to smoke one and
everybody always said yes but they said
you know
um let's not smoke yours here go in the
glove compartment and let's let's smoke
some of mine
and he'd pull out the bag and here you
you roll it and we'll smoke it and as he
rolled there were always a few seeds in
there and he'd ask him if he could keep
him yeah so my guy yeah I mean my my um
my first interaction with Indica was you
know Christmas 81. he came back from
California to to visit and he had a
collection of like six different
afghanis wow um and a story to go with
each one like there was one that he
called Ranger weed and he had he had
smoked this weed with a forest ranger
like a and this guy had and it was I
swear it was it was what I think where
Afghani number one came from it was a
very coarse you know Afghani with kind
of a candelabra style
um
you know
uh attack there was another one he
called plain weed and uh this was on his
on his way home he he at SFO
he was walking through the parking lot
and there's a guy sitting in a Corvette
convertible
um smoking weed right and he walked up
and he gives him the look you know and I
don't know if he you know held up his
finger like hey can we smoke and the guy
invited him to join him in the car
and um you know he got a couple of seeds
out of that encounter also that turned
out to be an an F1 Thai Afghani hybrid
which was just amazing and I knew what
exactly what it was because I had grown
pure Thai the year before yeah right so
I had these pure afghanis and I had this
I had pure tie the year before
and this stuff was just right in the
middle it was a 50 50 cross and you know
I used to sit there and make notes about
you know I'd sit and smoke it and write
down the the effects and The Taste and
compare it with other stuff and
um just amazing notebooks right yeah
that's amazing I do yeah that when you
first told me that you've kept these
notebooks like on sense and stuff I was
like man this guy's gonna be my best
friend I'm telling you this is amazing
like it's just it's it's only a certain
type of people that really get this far
into weed I think
um and and a lot of us think it has
something to do with being on the
Spectrum you know because we we get so
far into something so many people are
just like it's just we didn't smoke it
and we're like I mean so much more one
of one of the one of the cool Parts
about doing this uh these chats that
Matt and I do is like the realization
that like the vast majority of our
history is oral
right it's very little of it is very
little of it is written down you know
right and as people age evidence right
yeah yeah it was evidence and then so
there's all these cool stories out there
and there's all these bits and pieces
like Matt had mentioned there was great
debate like was Sam and and Rob lying
about how skunky it was in the beginning
and you know because by the time they
took skunk one to Amsterdam it was
fruity and citrusy and floral and all
that and so you know these these stories
and stuff from from the region and what
things were like
um is a big deal
um because now people look at me and you
know I'm only in my mid-40s you know but
people think I'm old as [__] and like
they want to hear like my stories from
the 90s but your guys's stories from the
70s and 80s are like a full generation
beat before that are these old mad Jag
notebooks
yep oh my God that's amazing and your
handwriting is so much better than mine
it's just around
my friends everything yep they made it
through the busts like the but like when
you guys did get busted they didn't go
after the notebooks and stuff not so
those a fees came in in like 1980 81 not
85 and I grew I grew mine in 81 and 82
and I was the only one in practice you
know that anybody in I knew that had
this stuff right yeah that year the very
next year
all of my friends had their own Affy
right that they'd gotten from different
sources from wherever you know I mean 83
everybody had it it was making its way
around the country probably through
deadhead you know Dead shows and stuff
like that let me ask you a question
about that then
um a lot of the old heads have said that
you know
um have told me that like basically like
Mendocino and Humboldt was almost pure
sativa
um and people really like the buzz and
the flavor and the effect and they said
one of the big things that drove
indica's popularity was when in 81 when
they started flying helicopters in my
neck of the woods right getting
something that would finish in September
or early October was a lot safer than
something that took till Thanksgiving
and was this giant thing right yeah
um and so that started spreading it
because police pressure and hiding it
and all that became more important
indicas were shorter and squatter but a
lot of people told me that that they
didn't like the buzz as much maybe you
could could you talk for a minute about
your experiences versus the the Mexicans
and the ties and the Colombians and all
those you were growing versus like
smoking indicas at first and like what
the differences were and what your
preferences were
yeah you know I mean and today what
people think of is Indica usually is
some sort of hybrid
um because there were pure indicas back
then that had a very sedative effect
without making your brain fuzzy
right I mean it was cold
yeah yeah calming and peaceful and kind
of dreamy but it didn't give you that ER
you know that that that just you know
the cow what we you know couch lock
is not just a body effect it's it's a
stunned mental effect right where your
brain just kind of seizes up you know
it's like distortion on a on a guitar
exactly
um so you don't have to have that to
have that body effect and most of what
we experienced today
um but with that Distortion with that
with that fuzz comes
um you know it's usually got a lot of
power to it right so some of these pure
a fees would have would have actually
been just kind of this just whoo slows
it down
right
um peaceful very high amazing taste
right just like just like pure hash
tasted exactly like hash
um you know and
at its best right
um but without that that that inability
to think you might be slowed down but
you could still you know follow a train
of thought uh and and eventually get
there but with and I think that you know
skunk as it originally existed before
Sam got it and and hybridized it and
used the name for the new thing that he
created which was no longer what it what
it was named after yeah
um if anybody can follow that right
blueberries the same to me it's the
exact same thing I want to let you
finish your thought but I'm gonna I'm
gonna come back to that to a part of
what you just said in a moment but but
please finish your thoughts so I mean
you know skunk was very
um was very Afghani dominant back when
it first came out and it was it hits you
like
like a like a sledgehammer you know
mentally it just stunned you
um you couldn't think you you were just
you were just seized up and I think that
you know what we
um think about as afghanis these days a
fees indicas whatever you know the chem
line is definitely you know got
hybridization going there with some kind
of skunk
um which gives it you know a combination
and that the extra power and the the
mental kind of Sledgehammer that you
know a lot of people like
um
so contrasting you know you you went
into this with talking about what people
used to grow up there in the mountains
and as you're as you were just talking
about it I was picturing Jim
Richardson's book uh you know since
Amelia
uh flowers
right and the garden that he
photographed in there and took it
through the the phases of fluorescence
and documented it just so beautifully
um you know I I first saw that book in I
guess 82 or 83 it
um my my buddy had brought it back for
me and said that it was on every coffee
table in Northern California
it had the Big Sir hola weed and Dolores
and all kinds of special plants in there
that weren't labeled and a lot of people
don't know that that that's the original
Big Sur holy weed and the tripweed and
yeah
NorCal had had spent years you know
refining these imported sativa lines to
turn them into things it would finish in
the season that they had there and and
you know selective breeding for quality
and yield and and
um and finish time you know things that
would work in the in the environment you
had there and it was you know you had
you had created something just as just
as special as anything from Hawaii right
as unique and special and uh those those
lines I think the last thing that we you
know on the market today if somebody
would go out and look for seeds that
they could grow that would be similar to
that or would at least give them you
know a hint of what it used to be would
be if they could find a good early Pearl
yeah
right because you can still taste the
Mexican in there and the effects still
have that it's still there yes there's
an Affy thrown in there and a half year
two in the mix sure of you know
different sativas but but the sweet
Neville called it the awaken zing
right and uh it's it's a you know when
grown as Cincinnati by a gardener who
loves what he's doing you know small
numbers and and pampered and cared for
it's it's so tasty and delicious that
there's hardly anything that can come
close yeah I'm a sucker for the silver
Pearl still but um I you know I really
want early girl because that's one that
I've never ran but early Pearl was a big
favorite in San Diego too amazing stuff
yeah so those you know early girl when
Pollyanna were you know from that that
era and from that region and uh they
were some of the some of those early
hybrids when when the first athies
showed up and they said well wow this is
the greatest thing ever you know can you
imagine growing a couple of these things
in your garden and never seeing anything
like it and falling in love with the
hash and the first thing you're gonna do
is you're gonna say I'm going to take
this new thing which is the best thing
ever and cross it with the best thing
that that I've spent the last 10 years
making yeah right that's exactly the
first thing you're gonna do right yep
in Mendo you kind of have till Halloween
or maybe the first week of November if
you get lucky
um of of a good chance of reasonably
good weather and not too much rain and
then the cold and the rain and the
weather starts to turn so breeding
breeding and Mendo and Humboldt
um you know you kind of have to have
some Halloween weed at the latest maybe
some early November
um but you really can't like trying to
push things full outside till
Thanksgiving uh it gets really dicey
yeah very dicey real quick guys so we've
made it through episode one because
we're already hitting the two hour mark
and it makes me stop at two hours so I
want to get in any kind of plug you guys
want to get in before the end of it and
I definitely want to do an episode too
if you guys are up for it next week or
whenever it's convenient for you both of
you that would be amazing
yeah thumbs up yeah I I've I've enjoyed
our chatting uh today immensely amazing
amazing actually
um it's been really cool I hope that it
can continue maybe even off Channel a
bit uh yeah there's a million things I
could talk about I'm intrigued at all of
the memorabilia
for sure uh and the experience I used to
drool I mean Sam used to post on
overgrown the Breeders breeder on you
know in the Breeders segment back then
in the forums a lot of those old school
uh pictures and stuff like that and art
that would get made with certain kinds
of people's weed
um and that that whole like sort of like
pre-marketing
of anonymous Growers was super neat
um and just uh so yeah there's a million
directions we could go but as Matt said
we only have four minutes before it'll
cut us off
so mad Jack we have you at madjag.com is
there anything else you'd like to talk
about
before we're uh wrapping up anywhere
people can contact you or get a hold of
you or any of it
what do we have here
laughs
this is beer this year's
it's a smaller one
um it's Santa Marta gold crossed with
Acapulco Gold and it's pretty much
a good friend of mine in California
um made the F1 and it's
it's gotten good reviews what's the name
for it
what do you call it Jim oh
um well I had a couple people test it
that I trust that smoke all day long
that live in Sedona and I said well what
is it on a scale of 10 and they said 9.3
I said well it's good we'll call it 9.3
that's perfect
yeah so instead of some fancy you know
airplane cookies or whatever
um I love it yeah
the
next week have any questions you have
um you can have them ready I have yeah
absolutely I did my own little tree
no
we've cut like I said we have a pretty
free-flowing thing and so it can head
off in all kinds of different directions
and sometimes we get to pick up on
threads of things we hear and pull on
that thread and hear more and other
times there's definitely things we
didn't pull on that I would love to
uh in the future
um so raho do you have anything you want
to get in yeah I'd just like to say um
you know first of all big big props for
your Discord channel oh thank you um
thank you you know you guys threw us in
there to kind of organize and prepare
for this meeting and your community
there is great
um we've been lucky good people uh very
responsive and you know a lot of good
information and knowledge up there so
just props props to that and thank you
for uh for letting us be part of that
I'm not besides that nothing you know
I'm just into this for the love and I'm
looking forward to doing it the next
time so yeah well I appreciate it I
appreciate the hell out of both of you
for your time all the love you've put
into cannabis I mean it's it you guys
are the reason that we are here digging
into the past while we're why we are
doing what we're doing so thank you for
laying that foundation for us I truly
mean that and I can say from myself uh
while I love talking about weed with
different people
um I'm leaving this conversation
particularly excited yeah I mean uh I
had a real good time uh chatting about
this so it was very enjoyable uh thank
you both very much for your time me too
let's make the people out there jealous
and and uh just say let's keep talking
after after we've finish the recording
you got it all right all right I'm going
to start the uh outro and then I'm gonna
remove us from the thing but after it's
done recording I'll pop us back in got
it okay I'm here okay all right thank
you everyone
[Music]
kind of
on it