what up fam it's me Chucky and I got a
little episode episode two scr scarecrow
with you we're doing it for Texas we're
doing it for Kentucky and we're doing it
for Michigan we're going to talk about
growing up hustling in the black market
we going to talk about getting held up
at gunpoint taking an L on the chin
coming back even stronger and doing what
we got to do to get the win you know
what I'm saying fam no surrender no
retreat sometimes you fall down you got
to pick yourself up again you know what
I'm saying G uh I appreciate all the
support on the last little podcast uh
throwing some likes up throwing some
comments up throw some up on this one
for me players I appreciate it y'all are
awesome like I said thanks for all the
kind words I had a ton of people reach
out saying they like the vibe of the
podcast you know these podcasts are not
going to be uh real serious we're going
to have you know fun and talk about [ __ ]
we get into and not take ourselves too
seriously
uh and just have fun cuz that's what
it's about we're going to have people
from breeder Syndicate our own community
on and we're going to rock out with them
we're going to have them back on catch
up with them a few months down the road
see what the [ __ ] they're up to and just
have fun you guys cuz that's what it's
about too many people you know uh
kissing ass and all [ __ ] worrying about
the wrong [ __ ] guys in life we just need
to have some fun grow some good pot and
and hang out and and just share it you
know share share experiences at the at
the least so you know don't be a little
hater don't be a little jelly little
hater I appreciate all you little
supporters out there and all my my
little fans and I appreciate the
Syndicate I appreciate Matt the Canon
Illuminati all you guys all the guests
that come on I appreciate all you guys
so show me some support show Matt some
support throw uh Chucky fam up in the
comments or something throw anything up
I really appreciate it like I said we're
going to talk about some different [ __ ]
on this podcast we're going to talk
about a lot of black market stuff
growing up in the illegal places like
Kentucky and Texas [ __ ] like that
anyways let's get to the episode what's
up guys it's me Chucky poins back again
with a little episode episode two of
breeder Syndicate TV and I'm here with
my buddy scrwen from the breeder
Syndicate Discord what's up
bro hey what's
happing nothing man I just uh just uh
chilling oh [ __ ] burning a hole in my
pants holy [ __ ] I just dropped a cherry
on my
dick I got swe I got sweatpants on dude
all my sweatpants got [ __ ] little
holes in them and [ __ ] because you know
I Dro my cherry on them and stuff but uh
but uh yeah man I'm glad to have you
here today bro um we've been doing I've
been doing these little episodes with
people I guess the viewers will will
have only seen the appy Hills one by now
by the time this one airs but uh yeah
man basically the focus of the podcast
is to kind of talk about uh what's going
on on in the breeder Syndicate Discord
what's going on with Matt and the can of
Illuminati guys like all the breeder
dudes and [ __ ] like that and today I
want to have you on and just kind of
talk about you and uh what's going on
with you and with this podcast it's kind
of uh it's it's more to I guess
highlight some of the other people in
the Discord that maybe aren't breeders
and just are regular people and uh I
kind of want to just see what
everybody's got going on so if you could
start me off bro with maybe how
you first came into contact with weed
maybe like the first time you smoked
first time you saw it like how old were
you stuff like that
maybe uh well I so I grew up in Southern
California um for like you know till I
was 10 and uh my uncles are really close
in age to me like we grew up like
brothers um because it took my grandma
and grandpa a while to have another kid
after my mom
um and
uh my Uncle Matt sold weed to you know
his girlfriend's brother was a grower I
guess which I didn't find that stuff out
until you know being an adult
um but yeah I came across some weed in
his room one time and you know we all
got [ __ ] beat for it
but uh I didn't smoke any till you know
after I came uh to Texas and I was like
12 and me and my friend took some some
weed from his mom and rolled a joint uh
he took his mom's little joint roller
the you know it's like the two bars with
the plastic pie
yeah and you know we' rolled one way too
tight and but from that first that first
smoke I knew oh [ __ ] I like this so you
know that started my journey did you uh
so you got high for your first time then
the first time you tried to
smoke dude I feel like I did but I know
I didn't inhale at that point like I
didn't know the mechanics of inhaling
you know I thought you're just holding
it in your mouth but I mean I don't know
I guess some got in somehow um might
have been when I was coughing or
whatever because it wasn't
until like a couple months later when I
was smoking a cigarette in front of
someone and they were like you're not
[ __ ] inhaling and then like showed me
how to
inhale and that was you know that was a
whole another
Revelation yeah yeah dude uh I think I
was
probably I would have been a freshman so
I guess uh I was younger than everybody
in my class for the most part I thought
I think I was
13 yeah my parents didn't really smoke
well my mom I found out recently my mom
smoked maybe like four or five times as
we grew up but it was just like when she
was going through [ __ ] and she would do
it while we weren't home but um but my
parents didn't weren't really partyers
my both my parents were my dad was in
the military and my mom was in the Navy
so like uh it wasn't like they were
hardcore about it it's just like they
just didn't do it but and we just didn't
have a lot of money so like getting
money for like weed and booze was just
like not even the option when you got
three kids anyway so um but well for my
parents at least I guess some parents do
that [ __ ] but uh yeah man um first time
I got high was not the first time I got
weed or rolled a joint this [ __ ] guy
he was a senior bro his name was Donovan
and he kind of had a lisp and [ __ ] but
he he he was real cool bro he was just
[ __ ] weirdo in my math class and I
was like really bad at math so I was
behind so they had me in a a basic some
kind of math class my freshman year and
this guy had failed a bunch and I I took
notice of him because he'd come in every
day and literally just sleep all day he
just slept every day and uh the times
that he would talk I thought he was
hilarious bro he reminded me of like a
chich and Chong type of [ __ ]
dude like somebody from a movie like
that and his eyes were so red and I was
like dude I just want to know more about
him I got to talking to him and uh he
showed me like uh he brought High Times
magazines and would tell me [ __ ] about
like Black Widow and white widow and
like all this [ __ ] and it just like
captivated me bro and he he gave me some
seeds I went over his house one day he
had like this [ __ ] ghetto ass setup
in the garage with like heat lamps and
[ __ ] and you know the plants this big or
whatever and uh he that day he gave me
like um it was Reggie you know had seeds
and [ __ ] but like a joint basically to
roll and he gave me a paper and uh I
went home like the next day was like the
weekend my parents left and I tried
rolling it up bro and like I got so much
slobber and [ __ ] on the joint that it
was just terrible and I didn't like I
didn't know I had never been around
people that smoked or nothing my mom
smoked cigarettes but I never [ __ ]
with cigarettes and bro I just like
tried hitting it tried smoking it all
the [ __ ] on the front porch and like I
just did nothing happened and I was like
what I didn't really understand like
what was about and then uh it wasn't
like it was probably two years later
when I was like 15 I started hanging out
with like some older guys that could
drive bro and we would in Kentucky like
your parent a lot of people weren't cool
with weed back then especially so you
would we would call back we would back
road was what we would call it so like
me and you know three four guys or girls
whatever would hop in a car and hit up
like a on lane road that goes on for
like 20 miles and we would you know Roll
Up and Smoke on there and that's like
some of the first times I really
remember getting actually high high
because uh yeah but we we that's where I
picked up smoking blunts bro was with
them with those guys because we had
Reggie right so that's like to uh smoke
blunt to smoke that [ __ ] you had to have
like flavored ass [ __ ] wraps and [ __ ]
so but yeah I mean it's also it's a lot
harder to roll a joint with compressed
weed with brick weed you know like that
[ __ ] just doesn't want to to lay
right yeah years later dude I got one of
those [ __ ] before I learned how to
actually roll uh I got one of those
little plastic cigarette rollers like
you were talking about your your um your
family had and uh those those were all
right if you actually would uh grind it
up and [ __ ] but yeah the first few times
I didn't even I I mean I still don't
even really use a grinder much today
unless I'm using the The Volcano or a
joint specifically uh actually withun
blunts I really like to break it up with
my hands bro and just feel it and
something about that process like the
anticipation of it and like it's it's a
mental thing I
guess but yeah well I mean also
functionally uh you know a blunt wrap
isn't G to get [ __ ] up with your with
your fingers being sticky you know like
it like a paper [ __ ] man I have to break
it up like I get the paper prepared and
then I break the weat up with the
grinder just to like try and minimize is
you know messing with it with sticky
fingers because paper will tear pretty
easy well if you get now if you're
rocking some [ __ ] like swishers bro that
shit's garbage bro the the [ __ ] I
don't know if you remember or if youall
have swishers but swisser sweets they're
[ __ ] uh usually when you get them
here they're they're bone dry bro so you
crack they're like you open them up and
they're popping apart and falling apart
so if you have sticky weed and you're
rolling with those those are garbage but
uh no I mean dude honestly like I need
to get off these [ __ ] but I
mean right now I got the uh I do the uh
volcano as much as I can but like if I'm
on a podcast or when I first wake up I
like a little nicotine so I'll smoke a
I'll smoke a blunt it's just a something
I like to do I know people [ __ ] all over
it but it's just what I like to do bro I
don't know I don't like Flavor anything
like that I tried uh The Palms or
whatever you know I do not like those at
all bro it's exactly like smoking a palm
leaf like it's what you'd expect it kind
of sucks yeah well I I look at it like
this bro I I I pass up on like a lot of
[ __ ] in life uh like mainly food and
things sweets and [ __ ] so I can enjoy a
little bit of nicotine bro it's not the
best thing for me and I know it ain't
but it's what I want to do and it's you
know it is what it is bro I don't drink
I don't do anything so it's like you
know if it kills me bro it kills me I at
this point I don't give a [ __ ] I I just
I just enjoy I enjoy a nice blunt every
once in a while for sure you know but at
that party when we all met up uh with
with with the guys dude only person that
didn't smoke it was ER bro everybody
else was kind of like I kind of like
this [ __ ] bro this is this was pretty
good and [ __ ] I know I talk about Rob
Clark all the time but it to this day
H&amp;L brings this up but he it like blew
his mind in my mind that Rob Clark's
just smoking blunts back to back like
smoking joints smoking [ __ ] bong rips
all this [ __ ] dude like all night for
hours I know especially the weed that
y'all brought too
like that says something because there's
a lot you know you watch these [ __ ]
podcast or you know you see these events
and [ __ ] where people are smoking and
it's like H y'all are smoking weed that
like you can smoke a [ __ ] half ounce
and just kind of be buzzing a bit you
know like that ain't [ __ ]
right smoke [ __ ] all the different
kind of [ __ ] that y'all brought is
that's pretty [ __ ]
impressive let me let me talk about this
for a second actually because it was so
awesome dude like uh one of the guys
brought a bunch of like black film
canisters you know like the little uh
half quarter size kind of jars or little
plastic flip things or whatever and uh
he they passed them out like four or
five to everybody and they're like fill
them up with whatever you want and you
know of course for
you know 30 different options to choose
from but it's not like like hanging out
with your homeboys where it's like you
know uh pretty much not all the same
[ __ ] like wreck weed but like you know a
lot of you times you sharing Cuts or
popping similar [ __ ] or you know
whatever but uh this [ __ ] was like I
mean I'm talking from like Hayes to like
uh ogs and all this weird [ __ ] [ __ ]
just you know because these are from
guys from different states and different
parts of the country and we're all the
same Discord obviously but uh everybody
kind of brought their own little thing
and and and or their own flavors and
stuff and H&amp;L brought a bunch of the
mango hazes bro and just being able to
like experience that uh on a level like
that and just being able to try all the
different ones like the Rank Stranger
the electric mango um there was a couple
uh other ones that he had but anyways it
it was awesome bro we would fill those
they were like fill up the canisters
with you so we go out on the the bass
boat we were there to bass fish right
and we're out there for like eight hours
so we fill up these little canisters so
I got a local sweet pee in there I got
all the different things in there and
dude it was awesome bro it was [ __ ]
just I don't know what I I I thought
about this [ __ ] forever when I was a kid
like just being able to hang out with
some of these guys that I didn't really
know who they were at the time obviously
but but just dreaming of like being
isolated in a country uh rural area
especially where uh you know weed's not
legal and it's not [ __ ] cool really
with anybody other than you know other
than like the stoner kids or whatever
the outcast people like having an
opportunity to like hang out with dudes
like that and smoke their weed and like
you know and all of them are sweethearts
bro they're all really good to me and
you know it was a dream come true for me
bro oh dude I bet I I feel you it was
not
um it was not safe here like I mean it's
still not but it's a hell of a lot you
know you you're not going to go to
[ __ ] prison half your [ __ ] life
you know any you know none of that
craziness anymore but before yeah no it
it was not cool I mean [ __ ] I didn't get
connected um to like the online world
for [ __ ] man a long time um just cuz I
don't know it's not like that out here
you know like you
you keep your mouth shut you know with
who knows what
um yeah so it was a I I get the
experience of like oh I want this you
know being the [ __ ] kid in in school
who's like no I want to [ __ ] do this
like and everyone being like shut the
[ __ ] up you know like you're not it's
that's not going to happen just [ __ ]
go to college or whatever you know um
and then now I guess you can totally
[ __ ] do it
legitimately which is you know cool to
see the change well for me like going
from Kentucky is probably is a lot
similar because I mean a lot of people
there are are you know churchgoing folks
and stuff like that from where I'm from
and you know a lot of people do look at
or for a long time I would say like in
the last like five six seven years
people have like changed their tune I
mean we just went medical last year so
um so people are like coming around to
it but yeah growing up like catching
getting caught with weed and [ __ ] was uh
not good bro and especially growing it
so like growing it that's why it took me
forever I it like took the first time I
grew was probably 178 in like a little
cabinet thing that I bought from [ __ ]
Lowe's bro I saved up money working at
Quiznos and I bought this like little uh
tool cabinet and uh cut a holes in the
back mounted the PC fans on there and uh
I was using shoe boxes and a little net
pots and I was doing I guess it would be
dwc if you want to call it that and uh
uh yeah in there and I was doing at the
mom's house and then my brother ratted
me out had it in the closet they they
didn't get they didn't get but you know
10 inches tall but they were healthy
like they actually for for the time I
went up to this little hydroponic store
and I read on I was on 420 Chan at the
time like trying to learn how to uh
learn how to grow and uh I was
downloading uh uh Jorge Sant videos bro
like the old ones from like back in the
day where he's got the dreadlock wig on
and [ __ ] and I was downloading those off
like pirate bay and [ __ ] watching them
and trying to learn how to learn how to
grow and then I saved up enough money
with my buddy and we got a house out in
the middle of right and uh right it was
like perfect timing they like was the
first time I've really seen grow tents
come online and uh I got like I got a
grow tent and I got a real big giant
like uh they're like the shoe bo they're
the totes for like shoes that go
underneath your bed they're not that
tall they're about six inches tall but
real wide this tent was probably like a
2x4 or something and uh I had an old um
uh old CFL spiral lights with like
Lowe's [ __ ] reflectors with the clips
the big ones and yeah did yeah I just
rocked that out a few times and every
time I get to the point where I was
going to do like 1212 my landlord would
like show up like one time the house
started vibrating like you know I'm in
my I was literally in there [ __ ] with
those plants and the house is like
vibrating dude and I'm like what the
[ __ ] is going on man and uh I go outside
in my landlord he NE which never come by
he never comes by right he's on the roof
with some other dude like blowing leaves
out out the gutter and he's like yeah
bro I'm going come in and put a new sink
in sometime next week just giving you a
heads up I was like [ __ ] so like every
time I do some [ __ ] like that uh that
would happen but maybe to keep it on you
bro I'm high and rambling uh what's
what's the first time you uh maybe
started to grow and stuff uh and messing
around with that or got the idea of it
or tried or or whatever uh well I mean
it was pretty much immediately trying um
just because I didn't
I did not uh you know obviously I didn't
have a job so doing like choring for
other people um washing cars and mowing
lawns and [ __ ] like that
um I just I could not keep up with the
amount that I
smoked and you know I figured [ __ ] it
I'm you know my only option is to grow
this um which I have no agricultural
backgr around um there's you know I
didn't have anybody who who actually
grew there was a ton of you know like
some one of the guys I bought weed from
and [ __ ] uh one of the high schoolers he
uh you know he pretended to grow um so
he'd be telling me [ __ ] and I'd be
trying it and it [ __ ] fail
entirely um you know I didn't know the
whole uh 1212 thing to begin with like
it was it was a meth you know I was just
trying to grow for the longest time um
unsuccessfully very unsuccessfully did
did you ever have somebody tell you that
Donovan guy was talking about in high
school he I tried to grow a couple of
those seeds I forgot about that I did
try to pop a couple of those seeds years
back when I was probably like I guess 13
or whatever but I he told me to use a
black light bro back then and and I know
he just said put a black light on 24
hours and let them grow and like of
course you know they got enough energy
and [ __ ] that they'll pop up so I'm like
I'm growing you know I'm like they
popped up out of the thing but my dad
asked me my dad found them bro he I had
him like a TV you know back in the day
the big TVs uh like the C CRT or
whatever they have big entertainment
centers and a lot of times they have
yeah with the doors yeah I put put a
couple pots and soil in there and some
of seeds in there and he can't this this
[ __ ] never came up there bro and
he for some reason he came up there and
opened that up and he was like what
what's in there growing and uh I was
just like oh you know I just [ __ ]
around some tomato plants and stuff you
know and he bought it bro or maybe he
didn't I don't know he just just like
whatever but uh he he told me stories
about what got me wanting to try that is
because he told me stories about how he
smoked like when he was a kid which was
like I think he was saying like uh
Colombian red and AAA gold and he
talking about five finger Lids or licks
I think it's Lids ain't it I don't know
yeah all this [ __ ] like that and he he
did mushrooms and acid and [ __ ] not a
bunch but he would tell me [ __ ] about
that and he was real into watching
movies bro and we watched like uh Fast
Times and then we watched uh of course
chich and Chong and like just kind of
all this got me curious about everything
you know over the years and [ __ ] with
it and I unfortunately couldn't even
grow I I actually entered into it more
from like a like dealing uh side of it
because like you I realized quickly like
I can't afford to [ __ ] buy weed bro
like I want into smoke I think everybody
kind of realizes that and I realized
pretty quickly like man like I'm G have
to do some skipp of the flip here or
something and make something happen so I
think it's like everybody's Journey
right you know you you get a zip you you
keep a [ __ ] uh a quarter oven you
sell the other three you know this is 20
years ago mind you uh but uh you know
break it down and you pay for your smoke
basically so it's yeah that I was bad at
that
too right I kept I kept trying uh you
know I had one of them uh I got one of
those uh the little like balance
scales
um and I you know
got my [ __ ] up I bought an ounce of and
it you know just swag uh
and that you know make I just end up
smoking it and you know I tried the same
thing whenever I had you know made the
switch to uh Dro only
and you know [ __ ] man I bought a quarter
pound and was like oh I'm there's no way
I'm gonna you know before it's just
because I had too little you know it
wasn't that good I smoked too much what
you know but then you got you know me
and my friend taking a [ __ ] eth out
to just go drive around town and [ __ ]
off and doing that every day you know
and then getting home smoking
more I mean [ __ ] D I was so bad at
selling weed that one of my one of my
best friends uh I met him because he was
uh selling selling phones at T-Mobile in
the mall and uh I tried to sell him weed
I was like hey you know you you need any
weed and he was is like do you need any
weed so my [ __ ] dumbass is like oh
well let me check out what you got and I
end up [ __ ] buying some of his weed
like that uh you know everybody was a
dude right in my town or was trying one
to be or whatever so like for for a long
time I would just rock with this one guy
um he ended up going to jail and at the
time my all income was weed and uh uh I
remember at that time he got locked up
for a month bro and uh he he was pivotal
for my success and what I did because he
was not from there you know he was from
like Cincinnati so he had connects you
know out of state and stuff and long
story short he was my plug for like
[ __ ] 10 Years bro and he ended up
going to jail at one point and uh so it
made me realize I [ __ ] I need to have
other people so like yeah I would take
more risk after that and if somebody was
like yo I got weed you know any kind of
weight I would go check it out even if
it was kind of risky just cuz like I
said at the time I I just didn't
understand like how I would be able to
manage a normal job bro because I'd been
doing this for so long that like it gave
me anxiety and like at that point I was
young still bro and I you know you don't
even develop fully until you're like 25
and I'm I'm just getting to the point my
mid 20s where I'm starting to use my
head head a little bit and when went to
jail bro like I I would meet anybody if
I saw you buying real i' be like yo man
you you know you buy weed and and then
like and if they were like not really if
they did say yo I I got weed too and
then I would go check their [ __ ] out
right but for me I did I did the same
[ __ ] as you did I sucked at selling weed
for a long time and I smoked it all
until I met this guy by chance bro it I
was making music at the time and I was
making beats and I was making uh beats
to trying to like collap with people you
know I couldn't I'm not like a rapper or
nothing like that so I couldn't I was
just trying to find somebody to rap over
my Beats and I met this kid uh and he uh
he's a lot younger than me but when he
came over we smoked and [ __ ] or whatever
and he's like you know my dad Sals or
whatever and I was like what or he's
like my stepdad Sals and I was like for
real and I was just like everybody you
know at that time would be like yo you
know I got weed and it usually was
shitty bro and uh this [ __ ] guy I go
over his house one day to record with
him and his dad comes down and he brings
two ounces of whatever it was at the
time bro and uh the best weed I've ever
seen in life other than maybe like some
GDP or something I'd seen a couple years
before that and uh that was like the
start of it like at that point after
over as time went on I quit even hanging
out with that kid and and recording with
them U we went our separate ways but
like for like literally like 10 years I
[ __ ] with that one guy and that made
me that set me apart from all my
competition in town because they were
all [ __ ] with literally the same two
plugs the main big guys right and I was
able to differentiate from them this is
mind you back in like the 350 $400 a zip
like days it was good times for like a
couple years because like I said I was
the only one with that and back then
that that was before like the the big
hype [ __ ] really came into play bro like
it was before whiz and all those
[ __ ] came out with cookies and
doing all that [ __ ] and
basically it was just more
uh variety of weed back then it was
really good like that weed back then I
feel like is better than like weed to
this day that I see in the black market
or W weed but yeah but he was pivotal to
my success there for a long time and pay
my bills bro like uh I don't know raning
there but uh yeah so you so you you're
[ __ ] around with weed you're growing
trying to figure it out like at what
point do you feel like or maybe what at
point do you have your first successful
Harvest and do you remember what it even
was uh
so like I had so I had finally gotten to
where I was harvesting something I
wouldn't call it
successful uh this is like 06 07 even
into ' 08 um I was just getting like cuz
I would grow him way too [ __ ] big in
the veg because I still did
I don't know I guess I didn't [ __ ]
put together the stretch of it
um so like I would end up with super
[ __ ] just like tiny little Brack real
wispy like
not I thought it was cool you know but
like really it wasn't even worth [ __ ]
drying and dealing with any of it
um and I didn't I didn't actually have
like a like a true successful Harvest
until
um I went off to the military for a
bit and like I don't know when I got
back I was like no I'm gonna [ __ ] do
this I'm gonna do it right so I got a
book I I read the whole book I had um
actually got like real internet access
because before that like you know we had
a computer and internet um at my mom's
but it's like that computer's right
outside her her room I can't be [ __ ]
on it you know I I searched up tits one
time and got [ __ ] caught you know
like there ain't no way I'm gonna be
looking how to grow weed and
[ __ ] and uh you know but then I left the
house um in ' 05 and uh I was you know I
was basically a [ __ ] Street kid um
you know living in this ghetto ass
[ __ ]
apartment
uh definitely did not have the internet
for that like we didn't have cable we
didn't have [ __ ] um just bed
bugs yeah well dude like
I I I was so disconnected from the
because like I had a phone that I
couldn't even send text messages on you
know it's like call me or
nothing and then like I got out of the
military I had a phone with the internet
on it and it was like actually pretty
decent uh you know
working and uh yeah that's when I
started
actually like researching stuff and I
don't know
the the because I dropped out of school
so early
um it made like learning things
difficult and the Army really helped me
like learn how to learn stuff like how
to teach myself stuff um so I was able
to like really [ __ ] hit the ground
running and
uh start getting actual harvests um
and I don't it was bag seed what I had
it was either because I had started
getting I had also went back to you know
like well I'm GNA sell wheat again um
and I got good at it uh and you know I
was I was pretty honestly I was pretty
reckless at the time
um and uh you know a little
bit yeah uh I need I i' had been
jacking uh up my cortisol levels like
really high just as a day-to-day life
thing for you know three years
and it made it to where like when I got
out I just didn't give a [ __ ] you I was
like ah whatever you know like this
ain't [ __ ] driving back with 50 pounds
from Colorado nothing you know like I
didn't care
uh I could relate to that dude uh I got
I got robbed at one point in life dude
when I was really young and it happened
one time bro and it was literally over
an like an a [ __ ] ounce bro um at
gunpoint right and at the time like bro
the way I operated was I never I always
looked at like anything over eight
ounces was a felony of where where I was
at so I would always try to you know
obviously I'm not getting the best
discounts operating like that but I was
playing the saf is way that I could and
uh bro yeah I understand how you what
you mean by not giving a [ __ ] because up
until that point like I really never had
like issues with anybody over weed or
like you know you have couple people you
get Gram front or whatever that wouldn't
pay up [ __ ] like that usually like some
chick or whatever you know but up until
that point bro you know I had made made
a name for myself in that town in my
hometown and uh uh some cats that had
gotten robbed themselves ended up uh
setting me up type [ __ ] and I was
Reckless at the time I had [ __ ] three
girlfriends I literally left the party
at 2 amm been drinking you know weed on
me money on me all this stupid [ __ ] bro
I was young and uh yeah bro got held up
and uh everything was cool uh you know
uh but after that that moment it made me
realize like Yo dude if you're if this
is the life you're thinking about trying
to do and sell weed uh it ain't uh it
ain't all [ __ ] uh rainbows and
gumdrops or whatever how you want to say
that so at that point like it got a
little bit more serious uh you know for
me CU it's like I'm not trying to go
back to work but I'm also not trying to
get robbed again and uh that's that's
when I changed everything up bro and uh
uh I didn't really give a [ __ ] but I
also was really cautious about what I
did and who I dealt with and I got
really into doing [ __ ] uh like drops I
would drop [ __ ] on like back roads and
[ __ ] bro for people and not even like uh
meet face to face cuz up until that
point bro I was treating like a college
kid probably would do it just
[ __ ] in and out all day long
people I barely [ __ ] know you know uh
people that are friends of people's
friends that you know what I mean just
whatever how however I can make a dollar
basically you know I would do it because
like I said I up until that point man I
had never in my life uh dealt with you
know intense situations like that
especially with like weed because my the
way I had been operated before is like
weed makes friends like you know like
weed is not not that expens like at the
time especially like some of the when I
was dealing with Reggie like this [ __ ]
was cheap as [ __ ] so like the idea of
somebody robbing you for you know 50
bucks worth of Reggie or something like
I don't know bro it's like a [ __ ]
weird ass thing but people did that and
and as years went on there were people I
mean I remember stories of some of my
some of the people I ended up getting as
uh customers bro talking about how in
the city like a mom with like a kid in
the car which I would never recommend
going and picking a weed especially back
then with a kid in the car but uh
getting robbed for like a quarter bro
and gunpo like the city for for weed bro
so ah but I can relate to you I know I
went on a rant there but I can relate to
you uh about having those moments of not
giving a [ __ ] anymore because you're
like damn like you know I don't know but
I wanted to ask you maybe how did uh how
did I guess you said you know the
military kind of straightened you up as
a person and your lifestyle but is there
anything that like has other than that
that maybe you've taken away from you
know being in the army that you've been
able to put into your grow maybe like
the discipline or or something Have you
have you used anything that you've
picked up over the years from being in
service and applied it to the grow in
any kind of way or or the plant or weed
in
general uh not really I mean I guess uh
doing clean technique like with taking
cuts and stuff like that would be
something that because I was a medic so
like you know we learned how to make
sterile f and [ __ ] like that
um really just the [ __ ] I don't know
the the ability to learn greatly
increased uh you know turns out I just
need someone [ __ ] beating it into me
to get [ __ ]
sorted hardheaded
yeah but uh but yeah dude um so I mean
we've talked about like the beginnings
where you you know you're getting to the
point where you're you know getting out
of the service and you're getting
Harvest under your belts and [ __ ] like
that uh maybe do maybe we could talk
about uh you know did you did you
eventually find you a crew to be a part
of did you eventually I mean how did you
figure out about breeder Syndicate uh
how' you figure out about Matt uh maybe
you could take us
there well so I actually like I read
about Matt um
long before you know back then in like
2011 2012 when I was when I was lurking
on uh Forums on uh like THC farmer was
where I mostly looked at stuff
um and like I you know I saw a [ __ ]
link to that whole
post uh and you know saw people arguing
back and forth over it [ __ ] like that um
and like at that point I knew that I
didn't know
enough to
even be able to figure out you know
who's telling the truth who you know any
of that [ __ ] so I just I was like well
I'm just not gonna get his
stuff um same I did the same with swerve
you know I was like H I'm seeing too
much like negative stuff and don't know
how to parse what's you know what's real
versus what's you know
someone having a a monetary reason for
saying the things they're
saying um you know I I still at that
point I was not
quite I didn't understand the value of
clones outside
of like
multiplication of of plants you know
right I didn't grasp the like oh no you
can keep this exact one like it took
after popping you know continuing to pop
seeds and taking clones from them and
stuff like that um just
to just to make more plants because I
was doing a sea green uh style like on a
flood table at the time MH so um you
know after two years of doing that I
started like oh man that one was
significantly better than than the other
ones even though they're all very much
you know they're probably [ __ ] s1's
of whatever they had growing that [ __ ]
up uh that the pounds were moved into
um
but like then I started to realize oh
you know like I can I can keep the good
one the quote unquote good one from the
bunch
um so yeah I did I just I knew that I
didn't know enough back then to even try
uh to to parse it so I just stayed away
which then ended up making me um buy
seeds from like places that were just
straight up [ __ ] um you know buying
the
greenhouse the the circular packs where
there's like [ __ ]
one seed of each thing in it you know
like not
understanding
um just not not getting it yet
um because they were the ones who didn't
have you know I thought that they had
the bonafides well of course everyone
knows about [ __ ] Greenhouse seed you
know like I didn't understand the Nuance
to it
yet well they also like when you I think
when you everybody starts off you think
like oh they said sell one seed at a
time like that's cool cuz like I got 400
bucks so I could get like one of each
seed bro and you think it's like or at
least I'm thinking like a tomato or
something where like you pop it and it
you'll get something good like
consistent every time but like like you
said I'm buying like crop Kings and or I
love marijuana.com or whatever that type
of [ __ ] and like it just yeah it
wasn't working for me bro I wasn't
excited about what I was growing like at
the end of the runs like I was like what
the [ __ ] is this like once I really
started to to finish up runs and stuff I
was just kind so now I will say there's
been stuff that like white label seeds
every once in a while you get a plant
that was cool but yeah like that was
rare but you know and you [ __ ] you
just I know back then I would go on
Google and just be like best marijuana
seeds or whatever you know I I wasn't
like I'm like you I I didn't know
anything so I was like man these guys on
these forums and [ __ ] the only forums I
really even paid attention to um was
like I said 420 Chan and bro like they
were on another level like there were
some of the people on there kind of
hateful and [ __ ] and like I don't know
it was just wild on there so I didn't
and I was also scared too like man what
if I get on here and this is like you
know back in the time when I Kentucky I
was like man what if this is like all
like you know gonna get me trouble on
here or something so I didn't [ __ ] with
that but so I watched a lot of the M
like I said George santes and all that
or Jorge savantes I always say George
but Jorge santes and those dudes I would
watch videos and YouTube came out like
perfect timing then bro and there were
starting to get people there were
certain people starting to try to put
[ __ ] on there I remember this
video it was like some dude in like
Amsterdam the guy didn't even talk it
was just like uh or he wasn't talking it
was somebody like dubbed over it and it
was like him going through like a grow
and like you know it was the old setups
with like the HIDs and [ __ ] and I
realized quickly like I'm not going to
be able to [ __ ] can use those because
like in my spaces were always small I'm
like I'll burn my house down I didn't
have the money didn't know anything
about that [ __ ] so that's why I would
started off with those [ __ ] little
shitty ass 6500 uh CFL compact for
Essence and all that
[ __ ] yeah that was what I started on
I ended up uh getting um back back in in
God it was like
07 uh it was right after those UFOs came
out and um you know I saw it in High
Times uh because I was I was a very
proud owner of a high time
subscription um and uh yeah I [ __ ]
you know me and my friends hustled up
the money 700 [ __ ] dollars to buy one
and
uh yeah you know I thought it would oh
this will grow the entire [ __ ] thing
this is going to be great and uh dude
back then they didn't have there was
like no it was just blue and
red so when you would walk out when I'd
walk out of the [ __ ] closet
everything would be green and like melty
like mushrooms almost yeah you know like
[ __ ] it was very
disorienting yeah um I remember I want
to say I kept looking at the it was like
the 150 watt or 100 watt uh h pressure
sodium that I want to say that Mars
Hydro [ __ ] made back then because I
remember like on eBay and stuff you
could like there was certain [ __ ] I
remember getting on eBay and was able to
find like grow tents and you know back
then I was just how I stumbled on it and
I remember like reading on like 420 Chan
and [ __ ] like that uh about hpss and
metal highlights and stuff like that but
like I said like the heat restrictions
and like my space I trying to figure out
how can I I kind of put two and two
together at a certain point like compact
frants are not going to give me like
dense nugs and [ __ ] like you were saying
earlier about wispy ass nugs and all
[ __ ] and um so I realized at a certain
point you know through Reading and doing
research like yeah I need better lights
and I seen that [ __ ] little little
bitty like 100 watt uh like I said 100
watt I think he had a ballast and all
the [ __ ] and uh I was going to try to
rig that up in like um uh a cabinet or
some [ __ ] but I never ended up doing it
and then I just ended up kind of falling
away for a long time and flipping packs
dude for years and it wasn't until like
[ __ ] two years maybe before Co hit uh
that I started growing like seriously or
again or whatever [ __ ] with it again
and uh for like two years bro I just
brought like white labels and [ __ ] and
then I came across like CSI on the
[ __ ] some panel thing he did and then
like a month or two later or something
like that I [ __ ] saw Matt NATO on the
uh Matt show I think it was like a
recording of maybe like an IG show or
something I don't really remember what
an episode even was but for a long time
I would watch just watch I because I'm
like you bro you were talking about
earlier about not trusting people and
like is this dude for like monetary [ __ ]
not not even particular but I was just
kind of uh skeptical of people already
because of like I'd already been in
discords and [ __ ] with other people with
like other hobbies and [ __ ] I was into
at the time and I had like gotten like
kind of ripped off and like I don't know
just a lot of dumb drama and [ __ ] and
I'm like you bro from the far I was just
kind of like watching for a far and then
I finally like I don't remember why but
I was like man I think it was my old
lady she was like you know why don't you
join their Discord or whatever and just
see what's going on no I remember it I I
joined this other dude's Discord that I
don't don't want to name on the podcast
he's a [ __ ] little dwee but I didn't
know anything like I I was just trying
to find a community like we talked about
earlier I'm in the country bro I'm
wanting to connect with somebody or at
least chat about it feeling a little bit
more comfortable as times went on you
know and uh I joined this Discord for
literally like a day or two and they
were weird in there bro like really
[ __ ] weird and I I kind of already
felt like this is sus so I left that and
then literally I wasn't even going to
try to join nothing again and she was
like why don't you just try a different
one one time and then I saw that mattx
was like paid and I thought to myself
like I P like you know you had to pay
like five bucks or whatever to get in
and I was like man maybe that'll like be
enough to keep like the shitthe heads
out and I'll actually be able to like
get in here and chill you know and
that's kind of how I ended up uh joining
the Discord and [ __ ] you
know yeah I uh dude because of that
um that experience before um I I I'd
been you know started uh listening to
podcasts and stuff like that uh I
watched uh the uh Adam Dunn one uh quite
a bit in like 2016 17 I think and um
after uh when Co started that's when
like everyone started you know really
podcast streaming just a ton so so uh I
started getting you know much more
online uh there cuz everyone else kind I
guess the regular people started normies
started you know get getting online more
uh
too and um I had put off listening to
the breeder Syndicate because like I saw
it on my Spotify list and [ __ ] I was
like ah no cuz I I'm not I'm still not
sure I was still unsure and then
you know finally I ran out of all new
material to listen to um because I'd
just be like cleaning the house [ __ ]
you know running errands all that [ __ ]
um just while listening to
podcasts and
uh I finally was like well [ __ ] there's
nothing else to listen to I might as
well I'll start this
one and you know I I was hooked [ __ ]
right away cuz things made sense you
know like to where I was like man I
wonder if this is
why you know I'm not I still don't know
[ __ ] you know
like um and that you know that
was it sucks because it you know I kind
of like started to put together like you
know oh man all this [ __ ] time I've
wasted like
learning stuff that isn't real you know
like the learning the marketing
essentially um which is cool and all
whatever but
like in terms of growing you end up
not having a good grasp of things um you
don't have good if you don't have good
uh like reference
points you're it's all [ __ ] useless
information it's all just random
um and that that was when I started like
oh man you know like well let [ __ ]
let me check this stuff out a little bit
and I and I started popping you know
like asking questions uh because it I
ran out of all of the past
episodes and saw
that uh it's on IG live
um so I started that's actually what
made me start using
Instagram was going to watch the
episodes and just like trying to trying
to learn participate and [ __ ] yeah yeah
um yeah
man I think I got so lucky dude because
like yeah I bought a bunch of white
labels and [ __ ] I mean I wouldn't even
say a bunch because at the time I had
like one t so I'm popping and I was
doing like you were doing I'm growing in
like I think at the time like seven
gallon [ __ ] fabric pots like four PL
so they're getting big you know and and
not to do my own horn or nothing but
like those first few harvests that I did
uh I'm not saying I've never had a bad
one I've definitely had bad Harvest I
had a bad one my last Harvest was
terrible just because of [ __ ] thrips
and [ __ ] but um and my dad being sick
and [ __ ] I just like I was my head space
was not uh you know I've talked to you
about this before but my dad I thought
he was about to pass away and [ __ ] he's
going through a lot of [ __ ] so um I just
like my grow and [ __ ] I just didn't give
a [ __ ] about it so I trimmed it down to
basically whatever was in hour at the
time I finished it up and I had brought
indoor stuff or outdoor [ __ ] in and
lesson learned there bro did some of my
trimming up inside and then literally
like two or three weeks later I'm I got
thrips in the in my garden you know in
inside that's the only thing I could
think of because I've been you know I've
been growing for a good time a good good
while and that's the first time I've
ever had a real pest problem other than
like some gats or something right um but
I think I got lucky dude by something
about CSI bro when I watched him on a
panel one day because I was looking for
information because I felt like I was
tapped out I like I I started growing uh
again and I like kind of was just doing
it I knew I knew what how to grow like I
said I [ __ ] around as a kid so it's
like wasn't much to it like put the
seeds in the ground water them but you
know like every new grower I'm
overwatering my [ __ ] doing stuff like
you know not doing the greatest and uh
watch I'm looking for information on
more on how to grow better but also was
curious about genetics because what
really got me into this whole journey to
like kind of look for guys like y'all
and stuff was uh actually Grandaddy per
and people [ __ ] on me but like that
[ __ ] weed was the first some of the
best uh I guess the first good weed I
had ever really had bro and this was
like right out of high school that
particular weed was so good at its time
for me that for up to like to the point
I met uh my buddy's dad the dude I was
recording music with I hadn't seen weed
like that basically so and I'd seen that
GDP like four or five times throughout
the throughout my uh time doing what I
was doing and then even the dude that I
ended up [ __ ] with for like 10 years
he ended up getting that same GDP but
like uh that I wanted to experience that
again because it's like we talk about it
on the show or Matt does and in the
Discord like sometimes you smoke [ __ ]
back then it's not what you really think
it was or maybe you just your memory of
it was terrible but like I feel like I'm
so familiar with that because I smoked
it so many times over the years bro and
I was buying like whenever that came
dude I would get a pound of it bro and
like I said before I would normally be
[ __ ] with like QPS half pounds but
when I see when that came I would get a
pound of it so I could have it and I
could smoke it and I can just remember
it and I will always remember it and it
always look the same it always smell the
same I always smoked the same one of
those few weeds you could smoke at the
time for me and mind you I'm smoking all
day long this is my job bro like every
time somebody got buys a bag you're like
you want to smoke a blunt of course I
want to smoke a blunt with you bro and
so I'm playing video games and Super
Smash Bros and selling selling [ __ ]
half quarters and quarters and Zips all
day right and uh that GDP sent me on
that mission bro because I had popped
some from uh I love growing
marijuana.com and it was [ __ ] like
not even close bro I was like what the
[ __ ] this is not even close so it made
me wonder like you know what is going on
so yeah like I started looking for that
like using that term like GDP actually
searching for that I came across the
[ __ ] Ken stuff and something about
all that I was just like dude this don't
feel right he's like in the video with
like these rapper dudes and like I I
just was like really confused by all
that the Ken what is his EST I always
forget his last name EST yeah and you
know I don't whatever and I'm like dude
I don't know and I started watching them
panels with CSI and you know how he is
he's real humble and the way he talks
about [ __ ] I don't feel like he was
trying to sell me something it was like
the first person I had seen that was
like man I feel like he's and he's
talking about how he's been doing it in
his family for you know whatever it was
30 or 40 years 40 years and I was like
if anybody [ __ ] knows this guy knows
but I go and look at his website bro and
and I'm like oh man this dude look like
this is a scam dude right here bro look
at this [ __ ] right dude I thought the
same [ __ ] thing about I was like no
I'm not getting that there's no way he's
got all of these things and look at this
[ __ ]
website cash only I'm sitting here
thinking like what the [ __ ] bro and at
this point it's it's been like it just
like opened up Medical in like Colorado
or recreational and think like Michigan
was coming up or like I don't know it
somewhere in between all this [ __ ] and
uh and that's another reason why I was
back in in it too because these places
were going wreck and uh I was going and
visiting them I went out to Colorado and
I went out to uh Michigan a couple
different places over the years as stuff
has come online and I always thought it
was so funny dude that the black market
weed that I brought with me to get me
there was often better some than the
[ __ ] I was getting from some of these
places and I was like the experience was
still cool but at the time some of those
places would have like four or five
strains or or cultivars whatever [ __ ]
you want to call it and uh yeah it just
wasn't it wasn't what I was expecting
now like when I went to Colorado that
was just a dope trip in general because
it was beautiful bro like we went and
did like a lot of [ __ ] we went to like
Red Rocks we went to like um uh couple
other other spots went to like rock and
mineral show that they have this big
massive one and that was cool because
I'm you know I'm getting High legally
pretty much walking around that was cool
that was like the first the experience
of like going somewhere and not being
like pursued or feel like you have to be
careful and like look over your shoulder
was like a a a breath of fresh air and
as time is went on you know over the
years when I got the opportunity to move
up here to Michigan bro and just do [ __ ]
legally and not worry uh I took it bro
because I was like man like I made it
for so many like that time I got held up
and Rob that was like my only time
knocking wood didn't never have any
other problems you know getting caught
up or anything so I looked at it that as
like a sign and and I I met her years
ago and and I you know I got out of
doing all that [ __ ] years ago I just
don't have a need for it and really man
like you know as years went on the
market the black in black market even
it's tanked and um so like the way I had
operated for years like back then was
having the best of the best and once
everybody had access and even the dude I
was talking about for like 10 years
eventually even he had like all cookies
all you know gelato all the [ __ ] like it
was all everybody had the same thing and
then like basically my advantage in my
market uh was gone because everybody
else had had the same exact [ __ ] so and
you see it you see the disappointment in
my I saw the disappointment in the
quality with even my customers because
like these are all the same channels
that I'm getting the same [ __ ] from
right that I have for years
but they're complaining that it's not
getting them high or like it's bunk and
it's of course it's like runs or some
Skittles or whatever you know whatever
it was you know and who knows if that's
what it actually was but like it got to
the point where I wasn't even having fun
anymore and it wasn't easy anymore and
you know you could still get I don't
know I would say probably 150 close to
200 depending on what you got but that
that Norm is probably like 75 to 120 25
like for a zip in Kentucky now and
that's like basically you're getting
Oreos or lava cakes or [ __ ] like
that yeah that's pretty much how it is
here I
mean
it's it's [ __ ] pitiful honestly yeah
know it's like God damn I I uh see it
um you know I still keep in touch with
people and and watch uh what's going on
and stuff
and uh [ __ ] the game's just gotten so
[ __ ] diluted
um to where now it
is and I'm sure there was like there was
that to a degree um back in the day of
people just shopping based on price
points
um but I don't I don't know how it was
out there but out here uh we had like a
tier system basically where
it was either
schwag baby Dro or
Dro and like within those three tiers
the price can change a little bit up or
down whatever
um
but there was not a oh this is this is
more fire than the last batch every
single [ __ ] batch there wasn't as
many people pretending to have better
weed
um you know the weed he had was like
literally you gota imagine right so I'm
in a small town of maybe 15,000 people
and in that town for years the reged
trade was dominated by cartels and they
would basically distribute um between
two guys two main guys and those guys
would distribute to the younger guys and
basically in the projects in government
housing and stuff like that and that
those were the dealers and um you know
with his weed was just so much better
bro like no you know there was a tier
system kind of for a while I would say
this was before I met him but it was
more like people started calling [ __ ]
like $10 a gram but or 10 bud or they
would say uh oh this shit's $15 a gram
or 15 Grand but or they would say hey
hey I got Reggie I got [ __ ] that's like
$10 and I got [ __ ] that's like 15 but
that was only like for like a year or
two at a certain point I remember this
one dude I started [ __ ] with that I
met at this Factory where I was working
and he was getting [ __ ] like I want to
say it was like Fruity Pebbles like blue
dream uh I can't really remember the
other names other than that I just
remember those two in particular it was
always something different each time but
that was just like people started
calling that like row or kush or like it
was a lot of stupid little names but um
yeah I mean that was only like a year or
two where they had like that tier system
and then it got to a point where it was
just like $20 a grand bud but there were
still a lot of people those people I was
telling you about the distributed to
everybody they were still trying to pass
their [ __ ] off though as like $20 a gram
type or three $400 ounce type [ __ ] but
it wasn't really worth that especially
when I brought uh when started hooking
me up with all the [ __ ] it was like a
whole different level because he had
money you know he worked a really good
job and he hustled he had he had money
money you know what I'm saying so uh he
was trying to get the best [ __ ] bro and
he was getting weight and he was getting
like it wasn't just like it was the
first time I went to a dude that was
like it wasn't just one thing of each
like different price point it was like
yo like this is all this price and I
have all these varieties that you can
choose from right any like basically any
amount I could probably ever want you
know and
um uh yeah so there wasn't really much
of a tiar system other than like I was
saying 10 bud or 15 a bu bud or whatever
but after a while everyone was just
trying to do 20 a gram because you know
gramming it out dude [ __ ]
sucked uh you know time TimeWise because
I could I don't know and when you're in
a a place where it's illegal still you
don't want traffic like that so like
you're charging people for you know and
the more you buy you get the discount
obviously so yeah I mean I
would $20 gone away
too yeah I remember when uh ah man so I
had a friend who uh was getting in you
know he he was the the uh broker
essentially
um getting
in very large quantities at least you
know for for us
um and then like me and and the rest of
my friends would [ __ ] boom you know
split off with six pce for you eight for
you two for you just what we had for our
Market
[Music]
um
and that dude when he started get in
order to to gain Market capture he did
the same price all the it's like well
[ __ ] why would I
buy why would I buy anything
more than you know my [ __ ] why would
I buy 10 pounds when it's the same price
as if I buy one pound you know yeah [ __ ]
does it
matter yeah um that's how my was too my
dude was too like you only got the
discount bro if you went up to the p and
I never did the P that often because
like my my customer base they were kind
of picky and like I said my whole
business model was having the best [ __ ]
in variety so like I didn't want to get
stuck with uh I mean I could work to a
pee in a week pretty pretty quickly but
like I I try to avoid people that wanted
weight because I always thought to
myself like those are the [ __ ]
that are gonna like try to get you or or
or tell on you so like I really focus on
like like more like your mom and dad
type crowd that got a job you know you
know I stayed away from older PE or
younger real young dudes and I stayed
away from other dealers for the most
part as best I could you know like I got
held up because I had because I decided
to have a partner and my partner is
basically why I got got in my sticky
situation that first time you know or
the that that time or whatever so um I
was just like after that after that I'm
like I'm not trying to chill with you
but yeah my dude basically you it was
like 350 and uh ZIP or 400 or whatever
type [ __ ] all the way up to where you
get a QP you get a discount then you get
a a little bit of a discount the HP and
then you get a discount at the p and
that was it you ain't nothing even if
you bought more than one p you ain't
getting a
discount yeah see that was the problem
is is this dude there was no like he
would be selling QPS to at the same the
same breakdown so it's like well [ __ ]
man that kills the secondary Market
because who do you think I'm selling
[ __ ] to you know
like that was going to be my my c c
customer that I would make you know 50
bucks off of or whatever and now I don't
got it
um yeah that now that's just that's
standard [ __ ] practice out here yeah
I wouldn't know bro that was all that
[ __ ] like [ __ ] all behind me but uh I
I'll catch up with but when I went down
to Kentucky not too long ago I went and
hung and and he's still up to his old
chick um now I mean I could get [ __ ]
obviously extreme cheap I smoked some of
their [ __ ] and uh you know it it
literally was like lava cake or
something like that and I was just I
smoked it and I'm just because I didn't
really bring any weed with me because I
gotta go down through Indiana bro when I
go down there and I'm just like they're
everywhere bro in Indiana like on this
highway with uh lasers speed checks all
that [ __ ] so it's like I usually bring
like maybe like a half quarter with me
and you know or or sometimes not even
anything just because I'm like bro it's
you know it's not worth getting pulled
over to just for some weed bro like I
don't when I was younger you know we're
talking about getting wild when I was
younger I didn't give a [ __ ] but now I'm
older and got you know a old lady and I
don't do that kind of [ __ ] no more bro
it's it's not worth my time but um yeah
my dude was like that too bro like I
can't knock it though like he paid my
bills for Years bro and and eventually
you know as time went on you know I got
better deals than that and he was really
taking good care of me like but you know
I always appreciate him but yeah that
[ __ ] was fun bro I miss it sometimes but
like at the same time being out the grow
maybe we could dial it in uh I kind of
forgot we even on a podcast bro we've
talked a few times and and we've known
each other for a couple years now so I
almost forgot we're on even doing the
podcast bro but uh yeah dude
uh you know maybe we could talk about
like what's going on now like currently
uh and kind of highlight the Discord and
maybe stuff you're growing right now and
uh talk about U some of the guys gen
genetics excuse me yeah cool
um yeah well I am right now I'm
currently smoking some garbage Cloud um
which is Shoreline by Santa Cruz Blue
Dream from pack at Santa Cruz goat
farm uh this is from my second run um
I'm going to have to do a third with
three of the Clones because I still
can't
pick um they're very good
uh definitely what I was hoping for like
more than I could have asked for out of
that pack
honestly um what were the garbage clouds
again for people the cross for people
who maybe not know anything about it
Shoreline by Santa Blue Dream yeah I
think maybe you said that bro I'm
[ __ ] bake my bad I
did but yeah but it's it's [ __ ]
killer killer killer what uh what's the
T like what kind of flavors are you
getting on it in the in the the smoke
how's the
smoke uh so in pretty much all of them
uh they had very good representations of
both par
um on that first that first run of them
uh I could only cut out two um just due
to and it's not because they weren't
good it's because they weren't as potent
as the other
five
um so yeah really good expressions from
both parents uh I am I'm liking the
shoreline leaners
more and that may be because I am a bit
biased uh when it comes to that cut
because that that's like
a it's a pretty pivotal cut for like my
development as a smoker like that's what
got me to you know make the switch from
not smoking swag anymore and only buying
you know good
weed
uh and I
so you know it might be that um but I
tend to like the shoreline leaners more
they are the potency on them is [ __ ]
fantastic um there's a couple where the
blueberry from the Blue Dream pops
through and like Blends in with the
nasty funky [ __ ] rankness of Shore
that is man really [ __ ] nice
that that's awesome dude I actually um
if I got one in reach well Matt says we
can't uh show plants I guess because the
YouTube's I was gonna pull one I
literally got um got sleep disturbance
these are all by goat farm by the way
the same same guy uh from the Discord uh
I got garbage Cloud Kim dreams turp
Queen and what was the other one bro all
my tags are a little bit I can't see
them for from here but anyways I got a
fourth one anyways yeah I got I got that
one going bro I got a full pack um and
all of them have made it so far so I got
full packs of well yeah got them going
dude you're gonna you're gonna like that
one quite a [ __ ] dude it's nasty and
it's strong I'm excited bro um D like I
gave uh one of the weak ones to uh to a
friend and he was like oh my [ __ ] god
this is you know like breaking my brain
and then you know I let him know like
dude that's not that's not even the good
one try this one and gave
him gave him uh the number six and yeah
that [ __ ] it like has my [ __ ] ears
ranking it's crazy hell yeah I um I'm
excited about uh South Coast uh asan
L's uh Rec drop he's got the uh East
Coast hour diesel times the Southern
Gothic which is Irene the Southern
Gothic uh the Irene to the Appia I
believe but um yeah man I'm pumped for
this one and then I also got dude hn is
taking so such good care of me bro he
ended up sending me some super silver
haze F5s I'm probably gonna run some of
that [ __ ] outside but the another one he
ended up sending me another pack of the
Kim dog BX bro I'm so [ __ ] hype for
that um and then uh yeah dude I got some
cronel stuff going mats Blue Sour
going uh I'm trying to think what else I
got going a lot of matte Elite
stuff um I got a couple got some skank
dogs huh you got some skank dogs going
yeah I got some of them they're in the
flower tent right now I got one or two
flower right now and I got another two
that I'm I just up hotted uh last did
you take clones uh no not yet bro but
I'm listen I I have taken clones of
other [ __ ] already I got a I got two
clone things up here filled up I
literally need to do that like now I
just I had a mattj episode with Matt
yesterday and then I was planning to do
locals episode like an hour or two after
it but he had to work a little bit over
and then obviously Friday I had the show
with Matt to do and then uh I've just
had a lot of [ __ ] to do and literally
I'm not kidding you bro I have to go up
flights of stairs and [ __ ] so I have
spent probably a day and a half up
potting like two to three tents just
because I have to uh clean them up I
took them downstairs cleaned them up and
obviously I've been trying to like uh do
my soil [ __ ] outside or just downstairs
or a different place uh obviously just
to keep the you know the air clean as
possible and [ __ ] because I mean you you
mix up your soil and [ __ ] Bro in your
room with your grow plants and [ __ ] or
with your your grow room you got [ __ ]
[ __ ] going airborne and everything so uh
especially like if it's real dry uh some
of that fox farm [ __ ] comes a little dry
same with Coco you get dust in the air
so um yeah so I it's literally taking me
like two days and of course I got the uh
I've been having to write up questions
for interviews I've also been um doing
stuff for
uh just different stuff for The
Syndicate bro the Discord and just doing
other [ __ ] trying to stay busy and then
of course I got my real life I have a
bunch of animals and [ __ ] so I got a lot
going on but uh yeah man I got skank
dogs going need to take clones of them I
also have uh I actually just bought two
more packs of them from Matt uh there's
only two packs left I know you said you
were wanting to get a pack bro you
better [ __ ] get them after that
episode people started buying them again
with with Rob with SE drip
Rob yeah
if uh if if people don't know what we're
talking about go check out Matt's uh
Matthew Riot's uh last episode on the
breeder Syndicate the main show from I
guess it would be last Friday's episode
with C drip Rob where he talks about the
skank dog and the
SSH SD or I forget I think H HD whatever
anyways this the super silver Hy Super
Silver Haze cross he's got and uh he
also he's got other episodes with uh sea
trip Rob that you can go watch from like
a while back but yeah man um doing the
skank dogs and yeah I got just random
[ __ ] I got the stuff from The Grove
contest going as well um from Pac as
well so I don't know what those are
obviously but yeah man I'm rocking bro I
even got some Auto flowers
going oh yeah I saw you added some of
those to the for the patreon packs Yeah
well yeah I put I put I think like 10 or
20 packs there's like 6 see people uh
they get packs from the patreon or
whatever so I put like 10 or 20 of them
in there you know if people want to
throw them in the garbage that's [ __ ]
cool I don't you know it don't matter to
me n they're literally just going to sit
around and rot I'm running some of those
myself like just to check them out right
now but you know if people want to throw
them outside that's fine too that's cool
but speaking of seeds have you made any
seeds
yet not
intentionally yeah true
um I you know D I'm a I like good weed
you know that's why I do this um and
also it keeps me like mentally and
physically engaged
um but
um yeah like I you know I do this for
for the flower uh
not you know there is enough [ __ ]
ridiculously good things that I want to
check out from these guys who
have uh who've been holding on to these
clones for a long time I've been working
stuff
um you know and like I especially now
that I've been able over the past couple
years to like watch them do it
essentially
um you know it there's enough fire out
there for me just to I'm cool with just
packs from people um I do want
to I might end up
uh doing like an F2 on this garbage
Cloud
um to you know maybe if I can find
something that is better than than two
of of the parents like two of the uh of
the Clones that I really like um you
know that'll be cool
but it's not it's not all of any seed
making anything
that I'm ever going to end up doing is
just to just to find a cool cut in it
you know not I I make my money elsewhere
I don't need to I'm not trying
to I'm not trying to do that kind of
work you know I don't have I don't I
don't see myself as having like the
space really to
be dealing with all of that while
I'm and still be able to like go through
the stuff that I want to go through
because that's that's like that's where
my strength is is just uh being used to
sea of green growing from when I was you
know doing the flood table growing
and that's what I do now to look through
like my space I'll I'll put it this way
my space probably
seems much bigger than it is whenever I
talk about it um just because of like
the amount of stuff that I pop and the
the stuff that like I'm going through um
each time I flower it's just because I
keep I keep stuff small and I uh do
denser planting with it
because I'm trying to see
I'm trying to find the good one that I
can dedicate the whole Space to just
growing that one you
know yeah yeah man no I get you dude I
uh I like I like to make seeds dude for
one I I enjoy the process of it in
general um I think two as I've gotten
more involved with breeder Syndicate uh
you know and the guys in there a lot of
like Matt's work and a few of the other
guys
uh especially like H&amp;L he has uh like
most of his [ __ ] are all regs and um you
know I really love this [ __ ] dude like
whether it's a female or a male plant I
treat them the same for the most part I
put grow them in the same pots and stuff
unless I'll recognize one really early
sometimes I'll take a mail and grow it
in a smaller pot so like a lot of times
I'm wasting some materials probably
inputs that I probably don't need to but
I got it there already and they're handy
so like for me I got space so I can move
it off to another place or take it
outside and by the time they're dumping
you know you only need them for a few
days collect a little bit of pollen and
then you dust a little bit just here and
there and then for me like I have a seed
addiction bro like I I for for a solid
year there when I first joined the the
Discord bro I was buying like seeds like
every [ __ ] week and dude like crazy
amounts and I know we all go through
that [ __ ] bro but I like for me I found
if like I just dust a little bit and
just I know like I'm not I don't sell
weed so like finding a seed or two here
or there uh like for me it's not really
like a problem or whatever so I don't
and I don't mind it and uh so for me I I
like it too because it's uh it's already
there I already got usually have
multiple males on on on hand I don't
have any expectation from it and then
also being a part of the community bro
bro so many people give me free [ __ ]
like in the beginning I was so many
people were giving me free seeds and
[ __ ] that I felt weird I'm so weird
about that bro I don't know if it's like
the country country in me or whatever
but like where I'm from like nobody has
anything so it's like when you when
someone gives you something it means a
lot CU they're probably giving up
something that they actually probably
need to give you or need themselves but
they're giving it to you so like that's
just how we were raised so like if
somebody does something for you I don't
like feeling like I owe anybody anything
so for me like I don't want to send
people weed bro it's like kind of sketch
so for me like sending some seeds of
what you know what some Chuck or
whatever I did if they don't pop it like
whatever like I don't give a [ __ ] like
it's just something to share and uh like
yeah it's like almost like currency for
me in a way like that where it's like
you know and two another thing which has
been awesome is like Matt does the uh 50
tier where he gives like seeds out like
a pack a month quarterly
and there's been there's been times
where like maybe he didn't because
that's all like donations and stuff from
like the guys basically so like being
able to like contribute to that dude I
don't know it's like a mini dream for me
bro like just hanging out like going
through the processes of like taking a
plant that you like and then even if you
don't really know a whole lot like just
smashing them together and just like for
me put like last year for example I took
the I'm slowly getting through [ __ ] off
chucked so last year I ran the uh I
think it was Space Invaders uh creamy
punch uh I guess Matt selection whatever
uh but the creamy punch uh had chucked
some appy F3 Paul and male pollen a
couple years ago like it was like right
when I joined the Discord and I was
trying to learn about like breeding and
seeds and all this [ __ ] because that's
what that's what I was interested
especially at the time and uh I chucked
some appies onto like a bunch of [ __ ]
from the Discord like uh pox atw or the
train his train train wreck
s1's um the triangle
choke uh and a a couple other ones but
long story short I ran the triangle
choke cross the Appalachia F3 and then I
ran the creamy punch across to the
Appalachia F3 Outdoors last year I had a
jar I actually have a jar of it sitting
over here um and uh just being able to
try out was awesome bro like and what I
found is like that weed was just as good
as like any other [ __ ] weed I had ran
dude it was awesome like I don't know
like and it was outdoor low inputs I
didn't do soil I barely gave it I didn't
even really feed them I gave it some cow
mag and I this is my first year being up
in Michigan so I wanted to try just
straight into soil and see what what
would happen and even like that I still
got a good harvest I mean that triangle
choke cross it molded like a
[ __ ] anything I had that was
purple molded out dude PM all over it
but it was like six foot tall super
purple dank you know it was nice the
structure was nice smelled it was good
it was dank all the [ __ ] but you know I
couldn't smoke it or didn't want to
smoke it so end up throwing it out of
the
backyard but but yeah dude just being
able to I was really into Pokemon and
[ __ ] growing up bro so like I know it
sounds dumb as [ __ ] but like uh in that
game you could get like shiny stuff and
hunt and like breed stuff and like get
crosses of stuff and something about
that like the unknown any my point is is
I enjoy like the unknowns or whatever so
like for like the stuff I've chucked
before I'm not proud about or think
they're cool really or anything like
that at all I I am literally just now
thinking to myself like damn the skunk
dog mixed in with like any number of
these other things that I've I've ran
from like H&amp;L or um whatever might be
awesome because like for me I like dank
like gassy
fermentation like [ __ ] bro I want I want
funk I want like like you were saying
with the shoreline I haven't tried
Shoreline so maybe that's the answer bro
but uh yeah uh the these here in
particular bro um from H&amp;L the the Kim
dog BX bro oh man runchy like like I
said this I'm not good at this kind of
uh TP talk or description of this kind
of stuff but but it was just raunchiness
dude like fermentation not like Fruity
or nothing just like raw raunchiness
dude like and almost like uh some of the
[ __ ] that I Grew From or some of it
almost kind of smelled like I don't know
being where you're from maybe you
visited the gulf and like you smell
there's like kind of this almost like
rotten
seaweed uh smell sometimes especially in
the mornings when the Todd comes in kind
of smell like that bro and it was just
right up my alley bro so if I could get
something like that in a Chuck bro and
not have to like Fork out because you
know bro if you want to find anything
good you most likely you need to pop a
couple packs and dude that [ __ ] adds up
and I'm a little seed addict so I can't
I can't keep up with uh purchasing you
know $100 packs every every week so for
for me it's it's as simple as that
saving money and yeah just having
something to do and I'm ADHD bro so like
the more [ __ ] I keep myself doing and
busy uh the better and something that I
found really interesting uh was [ __ ]
around with the Autos bro is like
pollinating like uh I don't know the
scientific uh terminologies for this
stuff first signs of like your sex and
stuff especially like on your females
you get that first little white hair
that comes out but the my point is I was
able to pollinate those specific things
with one seed bro and was able to
pollinate the actual buds with a
different pollen and like obviously if
you're selling seeds or you know if
you're worried about contamination
that's [ __ ] [ __ ] but the way I
did it was I had Max blueberry ex
right a male and I hit it to Blueberry
ex females I had some blueberry Autos
outside so I took some pollen and I
dusted those little little just those
little pre flowers and it took and then
like literally a week later I um I had a
male Auto of some kind I forget like
some kind of what it doesn't matter but
I hit that to the actual main buds as
they as they start to fully come in and
I'm just now going through those to see
if they actually if it worked because uh
you know I'm curious if you could do
that like I don't think you could do
that or want to do that with like your
traditional plants but that was just
something I thought that was really cool
about the Autos in particular was just
being able to like for my own personal
stash just uh I was able to do multiple
hits to it you know I don't know I
thought that was cool and what what was
neat about that is like when I run the
the ones that I think are crossed to a
non-auto obviously if they don't Auto
flow then it worked and then obviously
the ones that I crossed to the the bud
the auto to Auto when they start pre
when they start to flower within a you
know three or four weeks I know they're
actually Auto so it's pretty easy to
determine you know which one wasn't or
whatever but I don't know just a fun
experiment I like to
do yeah I mean
I so to be clear I probably am going to
do
uh like seed
projects um but yeah it's going to be
you know just for me to like you said
just to like look at stuff also so um
I'm going through all these uh Shoreline
hybrids
and uh I probably in a couple of years
going to try and
reverse
uh Shore back onto those Keepers just so
that so I have a uh you know in case
something happens I have a little little
bit of a seed backup to be able to you
know pop
out what I like about Shoreline
again I I think it was either farmer Dan
or uh Kush the giant that said uh and
this was on a podcast with Matt that he
said he wished he had you know a lot of
those guys operate with clones out there
only and um he said that he wish he had
just Chuck something over the years I
forget what particular plan he was
talking about but he said he wish he had
Chuck something over the years because
he ended up losing that cut and didn't
have any seeds of any kind of it and I
think it's important to say for people
who are watching like just because you
cross two plants together don't mean
you're exactly going to get uh a
representation of like a particular
plant in there but that you know there's
the odds that you can find and and like
for example when I crossed the the uh
creamy punch to the Appalachia f3s it
was interesting because I could see the
the Appalachia that I used to do the the
original uh pollination was u a really
tropical one it had a little bit of
mango like as like two or three months
into the Cure but not much mango at all
it was more like this real tropically
like reminded me like a tropically kind
of drink and when I that creamy punch
kind of like really just like
personified that and brought it out and
made it a little bit more smooth but you
know you can definitely that being said
you definitely can get some sort of idea
from some stuff sometimes but yeah I
mean like an S I know a lot of people
will buy s1's and I've done this myself
thinking like oh man like this is like
inting the cut you know we talk about
this in the Discord and it's not always
the case obviously so I think yeah we
actually we just talked about this today
in the in the Discord server
um yeah no I feel you and that's uh you
know that was what I was telling telling
that guy um I don't necessarily want an
exact carbon copy even if you know like
which is it is not likely with you know
s1's depending on what what the actual
um clone being like reversed onto itself
is um right because it's gonna it's re
jumble reshuffles everything uh so if
it's if it's not very homogeneous you're
not going to get you know homogeneous
results um for some stuff obviously I
mean [ __ ] those 991 s1s were it was like
growing just clones of each other the
whole [ __ ] run
um but you know I don't even if that
were if every clone that you if every
time you made s1's it was you know
perfect in line with how the mom was um
that's not necessarily what I want
because everything has its drawback no
matter how good it is you just you know
there's only so much room in the cup uh
and very few things like very
few just check every box
um what I'd much prefer is is something
that has a representation of the
expression that I
like but with improvements on you know
whatever else is wrong with it um
whatever failing it has you know if I
I'm I'm much more excited about oh
that's what I that's what I love about
that
weed but in a better
form I I can I understand it completely
I you know um I've gone through stages
where I hate keeping cuts of anything
bro uh I really enjoy like that unknown
of popping seeds dude and you're right
like I'm not
like has there been plans that I want a
an expression a certain expression that
the mom or whatever you know whatever
that I want to see of course but like
sometimes like that's the fun part of
popping some of these crosses that some
of these guys make is like for example
the P Haze for you know scen P Haze is
uh sweet PE times Band-Aid Haze number
seven I believe and that's yeah one of
our uh local U from our Discord one of
the guys
um selections I guess or cross he made
uh something that uh I enjoyed about
running those was the finding the ones
I'm not a big the hazes that I've tried
there's certain ones that there's
certain things about Haze I just don't
like mainly like the flavor the profiles
and stuff like that the highs obviously
I enjoy um growing
them do I say I don't know if I would if
I had the right setup I would enjoy them
most of my tents are not um set up for
hazes are growing hazes uh the am hazes
that I grew which I didn't
finish uh just because of my that was
some [ __ ] that I through with when dad
was going through all this [ __ ] um those
what blew my [ __ ] mind and you were
talking about
like the way plants are and the way they
express and the negatives and drawbacks
something that blew my mind about those
am hazes was how they didn't like light
they literally the one and a couple of
the other
noticed this too I'm not going to take
credit for the one knowing that I just
they told me like yo they don't like
light like that and I was like I want to
try [ __ ] and test stuff you know you
know I I like to think that you know I
want to try [ __ ] and see it for myself
it's not that I don't believe people but
sure enough put them direct the ones
directly under the center of the light
uh started to kind of just not really
like look terrible but just little
yellowed up and kind of just you know
did some droopy [ __ ] and the ones on the
sides were perfect and I moved I
switched some stuff around and move
those to all the edges of the tent and
sure enough they perked up so something
about like that blew my mind that it was
like okay now not only do I have to like
flower this longer flowering variety
plant out in a tent that sucks now I
have to like worry about the how much
the light it gets and [ __ ] and for me
I'm popping different [ __ ] and different
tins you know I'm never really running
uh I mean I'm running full packs a lot
of times but sometimes like for example
I might have two of each like right now
I got a full pack of skank dogs which is
six seeds going but I have them at
different stages based on how fast one
grew or how slow one grows so I try to
keep plants together and and I do train
to a certain point but you know as I've
gotten more involved in more plants it's
harder to do all that [ __ ] or it's I
don't have all the time in the world to
do that I have a real life so um I try
to just do it based on um yeah how tall
they grow and [ __ ] like that so um
what were we getting at with this oh
drawbacks so yeah just seeing that uh
kind of blew my [ __ ] mind because it
was like yeah it's negatives that I
never would have thought I would have
thought this [ __ ] sativa would have
loved Son you know uh I don't know where
all the shit's from and don't pretend to
but in my mind I'm thinking this plant's
GNA love like light oh [ __ ] no dude it
hated it so it's kind of funny like that
sometimes it's weird yeah I just had to
turn down the light on on
the PES packs that I have going because
they same thing they started
like they started getting pretty
stressed out from just and it wasn't
it's I didn't even like Crank It Up
higher or anything you know it was just
what I normally would put it at for you
know their distance from The Lion I saw
that too on my my batch and I feel like
a terrible grower because I've seen
other guys grows of PHS and I'm just
well I had thrips and like I said I
always had a lot of [ __ ] going on and um
I actually when those were transplanted
uh she transplanted them for me while I
was out of town and like I'm not saying
she [ __ ] them up or anything like that
I'm just saying it's not the most ideal
situations there's like three or four
things going on there but yeah I also
saw that too I had to dial a lot of [ __ ]
back I also made the mistake of running
them um she put them in two two gallon
pots instead of like three or or five
gallon and uh that kind of [ __ ] me a
little bit because at the time uh wasn't
really leaning into a lot of U like I
wasn't really feeding a whole lot I was
really kind of relying on like what was
in you know the the soil and stuff at
the time um these runs I'm doing the
canera dude and I'm [ __ ] loving it
bro I wish I could show you some of this
[ __ ] bro I'm so happy with everything I
I've just surrendered to it and I'm
doing exactly what they call for like on
their everything to it not not
everything in their line but I'm
literally just doing the the the the
tana floras and the Tana or the Vegas
and floras or whatever it's called and
then I'm doing some cow mag some
recharge and um uh there was something
else some mosquito dunks and something
else I forgot what no I think that's it
actually but uh yeah dude and I'm and
I'm loving it dude I'm running in Ocean
though still so for like the first few
weeks I'm I'm you know when I upot I'm
not really like pumping them that hard
and and right now I'm kind of I'm right
like five 600 ppms whatever maybe some a
little bit more like I said I got a
couple different stages so like my
seedlings and things like that I'm like
two two 300 somewhere in that area maybe
a little bit more by the time I had some
C mag in there but um yeah man it's it's
great dude it's more expensive and I
know you could get stuff for a better
price and I'm going to experiment uh
with it this is was this happened to be
the time I was going to experiment with
the can of some of the Cana products and
dude I [ __ ] love them bro like
they're I've messed with biob bids a
little bit I [ __ ] like that bro that
[ __ ] was it burned a lot of my plants
you know a lot of those [ __ ] they call
for the certain amount and it's always
way over bro it [ __ ] my [ __ ] up so um
that's I think that's why I had a little
bit of trouble with Kenna in the
beginning because I was I'm used to [ __ ]
Burning uh so I really didn't
surrendered to or didn't really like do
what they recommended I was you know
that Golden Rule going half or half yeah
and didn't really wasn't really excited
about what I was seeing and I was having
some issues with one of the blue sours
it just like I could tell it was hungry
and I like I was like dude I looked it
up on their little chart and they were
like you know add whatever it was at the
time like 50 milliliters of the the
Vegas or whatever the the the grow the
grow part of it the and uh so I did bro
and literally like within like six hours
that [ __ ] was like Greening back
up and like perked up and I was like
[ __ ] so for like a week straight I just
followed their regimen bro and like it
feels kind of I feel like a goober kind
of because like normally like the way I
would do it in the past would just kind
of just operate not completely off
visuals but you know you grow for a
while and use the same pot size you kind
of have an understanding of when your
plants are uh needing food at least the
way I was growing and I would kind of
operate in that uh way of growing and
then like I would maybe uh top dress or
I would lean in on bottles especially
during flour but like doing it this way
uh that's been interesting because I've
tested it out
like freshly transplanet [ __ ] for
example literally um I
forget the bars uh Bittersweet
recommended the bar lights they're
little clone lights little bars
four-footers I forget the brand I guess
it doesn't really matter but I got them
under that
and bro I gave him 200 uh 200 ppms of uh
the can of stuff and some cow mag and
they're like a week and a half old and
they haven't burned they love it bro
they're perked up like I'm also running
the these ones in promix I don't have I
don't really use a lot of promix uh so
I've up here in Michigan bro I've just
like had a lot of issues with starting
seeds and just weird little things and I
thought a lot of it was my water um I've
dialed that in I got really a decent
little setup with r and a couple things
uh actually need to do some work on it
today but um I didn't couldn't figure
out what it was back at home the water
the city water U had a lot of calcium in
it and other stuff I guess uh you I knew
it had a lot of calcium in it because on
my fish tanks you get a lot of calcium
buildup and stuff like on the filters
and [ __ ] like that and um that water was
great here this water I'm ating off of
[ __ ] whale water and it's dog [ __ ]
bro it comes out like 300 ppms that's
the [ __ ] tap bro that's fil like not
uh red but it's semi filtered or some
[ __ ] Bro there is a a pre-filter down
there on that system on that whale
system and it's dog [ __ ] uh so I do have
to run R so I did switch to the pr miix
with the micara bro and I I don't know
if I'm sound like Rob or not Rob but uh
anyway
I'm sound like somebody else anyways uh
it actually really my seeds these these
Sprout are great dude I'm really
impressed with I don't know if it's a
coincidence you know you gotta take that
[ __ ] with like grain of salt but uh I'm
gonna start maybe trying to start all my
[ __ ] in promix because I mean you know
you got like eight to 10 days there uh I
went ahead and started at like I guess
it's probably been like seven to give
them food and they it's it's been really
smooth normally I run in the uh uh Happy
Frog
or like a mix of Happy Frog and cocoa or
a mix of Coco and fox farm and sometimes
Fox Farm can be a little too much and uh
yeah just really impressed with the
promix dude I don't know do you run any
promx have you [ __ ] with promx at all
I know you do a lot of organic [ __ ] but
uh have you [ __ ] with promix at all no
not really not other than like you know
clone that I've gotten from a friend who
has it in there uh like that cuz that's
they use or whatever um I just get uh
either I make you know I'll make three
cubic feet at a time uh just using cubic
foot of uh pee cubic foot of castings
and a cubic foot of pmus and
that's that'll get me you know pretty
far usually um if I need to feed I give
a bit of uh fish hydraulis from
dram
um I mean that's pretty much that's most
of my feed really is uh just some dram
fish iyra
aate um yeah it's been you know I end up
I still give uh microbes and fulvic acid
little pinch of uh saponins in there
just to like help um the uh the Water um
because I've been I've been like messing
around with dry backs a little bit
um for the last several uh last several
flowering runs
and
uh it just helps to like soak it up
um yeah I end up switching
to uh what's it called a like a I guess
it's a pure eps salt stuff from uh from
envy and some gypsum some Diamond
K uh that's like what I taper taper down
to whenever I'm not when I'm trying to
give cow mag but not give anything else
attached to it
besides uh you know
sulfur the organic shit's over my head
bro I'll be honest like a lot of that
[ __ ] uh I admire you guys for doing it
dude and it's awesome I I think that's
something that is so cool about weed in
general how many styles there are and
how many ways there are I know we all
joke on each other bottle boys and [ __ ]
but I think it is really cool how
especially like with like the Discord
scene everybody's way they grow and [ __ ]
and we give each I know we joke on each
other but I really do enjoy seeing
people's way of doing [ __ ] because it's
you can learn a thing or two from people
you know oh dude I I got so I was
growing
successfully in Organics right but when
I started talking more and more to you
know people like bidder and local and n
and you know people who are running
[ __ ]
uh doing like hydroponic or drain to
waste whatever um
salt um like trying to pick
up what they're doing and incorporate it
into
into my program you
know uh and that's been like that's why
I've been messing with
dryback um messing with
uh how I feed um doing it like more
based
on on when they're pushing
stuff
um to try and kind
of you know because I mean it's still
it's still the same
plant um in our systems there there may
be differences in how we deliver those
nutrients or how we how we do things but
those plants still do better when you
know they're they're finished without
nitrogen you know but they're going to
need calcium still so finding a calcium
and you know just [ __ ] like that um and
being able to like uh break down other
processes better because you know
Hydroponics is is such a you know they
fine-tuned it to such a
degree where
um I guess it's a it's a lot more like
scientific in in what's actually going
on uh because they're controlling you
know much more of
that um and just just incorporating
those you know those hey we found out
this that's why we do it this way now um
and and figuring out how to you know
kind of incorporate it into into how I
grow cuz I
still
I I have friends who grow both and it
really doesn't matter I don't think um
it's more so on the grower and and how
well you can actually grow you know and
how how many uh problems pop up in that
in that
grow yeah I think uh I think I'm that's
a good place to end it for this one bro
um I think what I got on this free uh
version only like two hours so I think
we're about to hit our our two hour
Mark um I'd like to have you back on
here in like a month or so if you got
some time maybe we can go into like
growing and stuff maybe go into Organics
a little bit more get more because this
is such a a [ __ ] huge topic I feel
like we could go on for
probably all day really and um I'll be
honest dude I got to take a [ __ ] I
gotta I'm starving bro but I do
appreciate you coming on here with me
man oh yeah thanks for having me yep I
got local coming up uh to record I got
uh peaches wanted to do one on Edibles
so hopefully I'm gonna do a deep dive on
that with her and then uh yeah so y'all
look forward to that and uh I appreciate
you bro hell yeah thanks all right I'm
going to do the outro on the uh like I
said I got a little skit and the outro
I'll do then and I'll plug all the matte
stuff but do you have anything you want
unplug Oh no just uh join join the
Discord [ __ ] yeah [ __ ] no all
right man I'll talk to you later later
peace bro thank
you so what did y'all think did y'all
have fun did y'all like the episode let
me know down in the comment section
below and as always if you want some
sweet genetics go to Riot seeds.com
check out all the good [ __ ] on there you
guys you want some sweet ass gear pick
it up from there also tune in every
Friday where me and Matt and sometimes
not me uh you know have a little podcast
for the main show um and you know if you
want some more in-depth top topics like
breeding uh and different things like
that just a more headier version of of
of a podcast a weed podcast check that
out it's like every Friday uh like I
said 900 p.m. Eastern we're going to
keep dropping our [ __ ] uh this this
podcast on Wednesday at 900 p.m. Eastern
and we going to grind it out you guys
we're going to rock out so I appreciate
you guys supporting all of us over at
breeders Syndicate and both the podcast
we we going to grind it out you guys
this going to be our year 2025 you guys
I promise you guys we're going to grind
it out and we're going to take over the
game I appreciate y'all and mom says hi
and uh yeah like I said throw a like or
a comment join the patreon it's five
bucks a month you can join the Discord
and hang out with all of us and get a
[ __ ] dick ton of information for free
get tips get help with your grows and
[ __ ] like that heck you might even
freaking make a friend or two along the
way and like I said appreciate y'all
always and have a good day Michigan baby