what up fam it's me Chuck dog and I'm
back with the episode four of breeder
Syndicate TV it's good to be back you
know YouTube tried to take us out with a
7day little ban we couldn't post videos
for seven days I put out a little mini
episode the other night Friday when we
finally were able to post something go
back and watch that go back and watch
episode one two and three of these uh
breeder Syndicate TV episodes I sure
would have appreciate it a lot it would
mean a ton for me just a heads up I do
have a chicken in this garage right now
walking around so she squawks or
something that's what the sound is she
might jump up right here on me I
couldn't get her out of the garage mom
kicked me in the chickens out so I'm
living in a garage down the road at a
buddy's house freezing my balls off it
dropped from like 60 70 degre to 40 last
night and I'm out here with a few sheets
and a pillow basically that's why I got
the hoodie on cuz I'm freezing
but I do got a space heater so we're all
right but I got the space heater off
right now for sound quality purposes of
course we're going to bring you guys the
best quality the best show the best
entertainment that we can do over here
on Breer Syndicate TV I mean that's what
this is all about I know there's some
people in the community might not like
me that much might think I'm a little
bit arrogant or a jerk or whatever you
know or play around too much and that's
fine y'all but I'm here to rock out for
breeders Syndicate when no one else is
willing to to do so I'm willing to lay
it all on the line I'm willing to leave
my ego in the Maola hot tub get up here
and say and do what I got to do to
further the breeder Syndicate way of
living truth justice in American way put
a fork in me I'm almost done but not
quite we got a couple things on this
episode y'all I got to be careful
because we can't show plans I had to
refilm this whole episode on the blue
Zushi because I showed macro shots and
all this other stuff in the in the video
I had already filmed for this episode so
this is a rerun or a redo I should say a
few hours before it airs tonight so I do
apologize if it seemed a little off or
you know the pacing is a little weird
it's kind of on the Fly freestyling this
essentially like I do everything but you
know what I'm saying this is just more
freestyle but I got some growing tips
for the new people out there we got
we're going to talk about a couple
things
not real heady stuff you know and to
some of you OG's watching I know we had
a couple people on the last episode say
a few things I know there's other ways
to do a lot of the stuff that I'm
talking about but keep in mind we're
trying to make an episode or a show that
will bring in some new faces some new
people you know we can't have the most
headiest craziest topics for these
people at all times and I'm not the one
to give it to them anyways like that I'm
very chill I want to have a good time
I'm trying to drink some some beers I'm
trying to look at some titties I'm
trying to smoke some blunts I don't care
what anybody thinks about it they don't
like it they can kiss my butt we got a
freak we about to get hit we got a jet
flying over top of us what the heck
what's a jet doing out here but we're
here to have fun and that's what it's
all about I don't care about the drama
I'm not into the the whole breeder drama
I don't really care some of it I find
funny will I joke on it occasionally
probably but I don't get into it like
that it's not really my scen I grew up
in the middle of the country in Kentucky
y'all you think I give a [ __ ] about what
Jimmy John has to say out in in
California about somebody else or this
or that I don't really care you guys I'm
here to have fun I'm here to teach I'm
here to give you some education I'm here
to entertain and that's what we're all
about so let's get into the episode blue
Zushi what is it I really don't even
know still to this point my old lady she
picked me up a bag I was out of weed
I've been out of weed I'm almost the
Harvest time I'm getting there 3 or four
weeks out I don't know if you been
seeing my pictures or videos on my
little Instagram but I'm working on
there we got some freaking really good
genetics we got some Blue Sour going in
there that smelling ultimately funky I
can't believe it I can't believe it
we're back sour baby
it's that's all I get when
S I get freaking I get going man when
the the sour comes out man I get that I
get that I'm freaking getting pumped
thinking about it I got couple blue
sours going one smells runch as hell I
got skank dog going smelling runchy as
hell I got TK times lupa's headband I
Got U lupa's headband times U pure OG
Kush I got Kim 91 S1 for Kim dog for
sour for OG for hazes all that [ __ ] you
guys you know I got all kinds of stuff
going I got a lot of P stuff some H&amp;L
genetics going Southern gothics we got
you know for Pac we got sleep
disturbance we got
Kim dreams we got all kinds of Blue
Dream crosses going we're rocking now we
got matte stuff going we're doing it so
we're almost the Harvest time but I did
have to get some weed from from a
dispensary I know I should kick my own
ass I really should but your boy has to
get a head change I don't drink anymore
I turn into a wild animal if I drink at
tequila I end up cheating on my wife and
doing crazy [ __ ] y'all see me on TV if I
get on that tequila again I won't I I
won't do it and I can't do it but I do
miss tequila so I got to get a head
change so she goes this new place I
never been to when she was out grocery
shoping she said you never been in this
shop Chucky you want something from here
I said yeah I go online and blue
Zushi pops out right on top I said blue
Zushi what the heck is that I want to
know Matt makes fun of it I see him
mentioning it we joke on it I don't know
if Matt smoked it or knows anything
about it whatever but I thought it would
be funny and kind of a fun little
episode to do so I got the blue Zushi I
did a whole episode on it and now I'm
here refiling it so I open up the bag of
course this machine trim looks like
anything else from a
freaking uh wreck weed store a little
purple on it Frosty you know given looks
are all there wasn't expecting a smell
you I wasn't expecting a blueberry smell
of all things even though Blue's in the
name you know this is wreck weed mind
you so I'm expecting nothing
really but I couldn't help but realize
I'm getting the same exact blueberry
TPS but toned down way way down now if
this was a grow of a blue Zushi you know
homegrown maybe on the same level but as
far as you know what I had there was not
on the same level uh intensity wise or
range uh you know it there was that
blueberry turp but there wasn't a
spectrum if that makes any sense on the
blue Zushi but it brought me back to my
Groves of the blueberry X of Matts if
you like blueberry turps if you want one
of the best expressions or the best
blueberry strange cvars whatever you
want to call it out there pick up the
blueberry IX or some of the blue bonnet
work from mat but I would recommend
doing the blueberry
IX it's going to give you the most uh
blueberry plant you could really find
that I've been able to grow I haven't
haven't grown a lot of blueberry stuff
but definitely can smell blueberry in a
range of blueberry turps I mean I'm
talking candy blueberry pies maybe even
all the way the muffins to a sharp candy
kind of smell and this is what that
blueberry Zushi kind of reminded me of
more of that kind of sharp candy
blueberry turp or smells whatever you
want to call it now that didn't really
translate to the actual smoke itself but
the turbs brought me back to the
blueberry ex which made me think like
man like all these people are out here
getting hyped off this blue Zushi
Meanwhile my boy Matt got the best
blueberry turbs in the world over here
on the IX and people might say I'm
biased but I grew them out and they are
a lot better I mean they are some of the
best blueberry turps I've had in life
the best really I mean the only other
ones that compare would be more of the
blue Bonet stuff through matte but the
ixs were delicious they're great if you
want something blueberry it's all for
you right there now the high on anything
blueberry to me is never is never crazy
from the Expressions that I've got grown
myself I just haven't seen crazy potency
like I'm not trying to knock on it it's
just that I smoke a lot of weed so a lot
of the buds I'm smoking you know I need
some real potent stuff you know now I
will say that kind of that kind of weed
there is great for going to work cuz you
ain't going to get get blasted blasted
you'll be able to function and still
talk but that weed is great for waking
and baking maybe uh if you don't like
got to go to work or if you got maybe
you ain't trying to get blasted and
laying on the couch I don't know I don't
know I don't really do that any I don't
get blasted hardly anyways off anything
but you know I do want some potency but
I will say if you want to experience
that blueberry stuff check out the I
exes and what something I thought was
more important if you're growing wheat
and you're picking up blue Zushi
just get a pack of blueberry ex they
regulars and do some chucking like what
the heck you
know and Matt's telling me I can get
that blueberry turch to express on a lot
of different stuff pretty easily so my
me being a chucker I was sitting there
thinking like why would I even grow blue
Zushi if I could grow a blueberry ex and
then make some Chucks and you could
really pretty easily make your own cool
blueberry esque plant with little little
to no work like I don't know I don't
understand the hype on it on the blue
Zushi stuff I don't really get it uh but
to each their own and maybe if I had a
homegrown version of it I would speak
differently on it you know it's hard to
compare one plant that's grown
recreational to four or five
plants homegrown with different
Expressions that were all I mean it's
just a whole different thing but I did
find it interesting to say the least so
I think moving forward you know we're
going to talk about uh more modern stuff
uh to get up in them algorithms of
spread the breeder Syndicate message cuz
we got to be let's be realistic most of
us watching this [ __ ] are like 35 plus
we got to get some new blood in whether
you like it or not the next generation
is going to have to take the torch at
some point right so we gotta educate we
got to educate them we got to teach them
we got to tell them like look bro
there's other ways to do this [ __ ] you
don't have to be out here looking like a
weirdo smoking the blue Zushi bro you
just grow some blueberry ex like a
normal person a normal grower and you're
all gravy baby but I don't know if y'all
got a strin that y'all want me to look
up or look into put it down in that
comment section I'm not scared I'll go
into these weird places I I'll buy the
stuff I don't care man we got a freaking
sponsorship we got the money rolling in
we're going we're going to do it to the
most y'all and I hate to say it but I
think we might try the water melon
Martini I think it they should call it
watermelon disappointment I would
think here you guys go I this feels
dirty this feels real
dirty I literally smell
nothing maybe
like yeah I don't smell anything bro
this ain't good let's get this mug lit
up it's too cold to be lightting
lighters in here let's get her lit up
y'all
little moist I hope that dude wasn't
licking on this before he gave it to
her oh that's harsh that's dry as [ __ ]
that's a shake joint right there
boy it's a shake joint why do y'all do
this [ __ ] don't do this [ __ ] if you own
a dispensary don't don't do this
[ __ ] oh it's nasty bro
God so
dry it tastes like y'all ever run out of
weed back in the day and you scrape all
your Shake together and smoke that
that's what it's like dude we'll hit one
more just in case I'm I don't we what do
you want me to do y'all
yeah dude I don't know why they even
bother with this it's just
disappointment I feel like I've
been [ __ ] and used
up yeah I don't know man this kind of
weed you you
[ __ ] just throw behind you say oh you
don't even want that all right that's
done no more wreck pre-roll y'all I know
you I probably lost your respect in this
video y I
know shame on me oh no all
right we going to roll something that
actually gets as high and then we're
going to jump into the growing
tips I'll be in the comment section on
this video talking so if you got
questions ask me there if you don't
whatever that's cool too I do appreciate
the support
I God
damn it's [ __ ] nasty bro I need a
drink oh
tastes like smoking attic dust bro like
dust from an attic off the floor yeah
bro what the actual [ __ ] man I feel like
I just deep throated a Porky or a pine
cone or something
bro God
damn that's just offensive
bro they running game on Chuck dog up
here in Michigan some of these spots
what the hell bro what are we going to
do man shout out to my local spot that I
visit y'all take good care of me up
there for what it is you know there are
a couple places up in Michigan uh in the
Battle Creek area that are cool a lot of
them suck though but anyways let's get
into some grow tips I'm going to roam me
one up while we working on that for
y'all tuning in that are old school that
have been growing for a long time I'm
sorry this is boring to y'all at this
part but it is what it is we're going to
do some
edication and uh teach the new new
generation of Growers you
know and today I got two things for you
well three really I really got
three
but I've talked about sulfur before and
I'm sorry that I'm rehashing it but I
wanted to give you guys a vision that
you know you guys ask I have people
message me on a daily basis if I don't
get back to you in time I'm sorry but I
do got a lot of people writing me at
this point everybody wants a piece of
truck dog right now we got sponsorships
rolling in we got people asking
questions we got people sending me dick
picss titty pics I like titty pics man
or female I do not discriminate I love
them both you know I I am particular
about nipple shape though so you know I
might say you got weird nipples but
don't take it personal but we talk
about you
know protecting your plants we talk
about sulfur we talk about pests and
things and today I wanted to talk about
some sulfur cuz I felt like we talked
about it before but people were a little
bit confused cuz I know I'm a visual
learner too guys I got to see the
boobies in front of me or you telling me
the Double D's and they're under a shirt
I might think they're A's I don't really
know I got to see it to believe it you
know
so I think we needed to talk about two
what kind of person would want to use
sulfur if you got a tent if you got two
tents if you got a few tents but they're
spread out in different areas of your
house you know depending on your climate
maybe there's a few different things
where your average little new grower a
you don't really need sulfur I see
people all the time saying my plants get
everything they need so they don't need
it well there's a difference Bud from
growing 10 plants versus you know
somebody met hypothetically growing a
lot of plants 100 plants maybe in a
small smaller room you know uh you
really at that point if you running a
lot of plants you're really a dummy for
not running sulfur unless you're just
got the super best climate ever and you
don't have problems like that there it
is possible I mean I at home back in
Kentucky I'd never had PM I'd never have
any kind of problems
really but we've talked about sulfur
before for using it for PM powdery
mildew and let me tell y'all it works
like a charm when you have one tent two
tents you don't need to sulfur out I
wouldn't even recommend doing it really
if you just got a couple of plans but if
you are in an environment I'm next to a
swamp I'm next to Woods I'm next to
decaying matter I'm next to all kinds of
[ __ ] so I got to prepare for the worst
up here I've never experienced this in
my life back in Kentucky so a lot of
this stuff I'm learning for the first
time myself so I figure we'll share it
but if you're getting PM especially if
you you first off you need to get your
circulation going a little bit better
that's the first off you need to get
your your fans going you need to have a
fan on the bottom blowing on the bottom
there some people you won't need to do
this but for me up here I have to have a
me a fan on a bottom blowing like to
have me one up on the top of the canopy
and I like to have me one blowing up so
I can blow that warm air up and out
through the exhaust so you need to
increase your flow for starters but if
you're like me and you got plants
crammed and they're so damn tight and
you got too many where you can't keep up
with the folan like you should or
whatever or you're not training them
maybe you're going to run into some
problems sometimes so I start getting a
little PM in the winter time this season
or this winter I didn't get any in the
summertime except for out outside but
the with the climate being cold it shift
all cold one day and shift warm the next
Michigan's got crazy weather where I'm
at right so I got to talk in the bitter
I seen bitter talking about sulfur like
using it for plants to take care of PM I
said bitter home dog what the heck is up
if you don't know who bitters is he's in
our Discord the breeder Syndicate 3.0
Discord he's a the OG God the goat of
the OG's he's super knowledgeable
probably one of the most knowledgeable
people I even know when it comes to this
[ __ ] he's he's one of them guys that
really knows his [ __ ] and one of the
guys I pretend to be but anyways we uh
he got to talking about sulfur one time
and I I ended up asking about it I said
how you use that how you implement it in
your garden if you get a little peen
he says Chuck Chuck it's simple bro and
he
recommended buy that Bondi or what
however you say it I'll hold it still
there for you so you can look at it
there's a couple different versions of
it and this is going to be your cheaper
alter you know your cheaper version of s
of you know powdered dry sulfur whatever
you want to call it um micro
rized uh but you can get a a better
brand that's more fine that that really
all you're getting out of it is uh not
having to use so much and and it is
finer so you know in the water itself
it's just smaller particulas or
particles I guess you could say so it's
it stay stay suspended as well more in
the water too I'd imagine different
things but I actually just went with the
cheaper stuff and it's been working
great but to way you want to use this in
your garden let me finish this up
y'all don't just take care of PM as well
it takes care of russed mites and I
think maybe one other thing but I know
for sure bidder was saying that it takes
care of Russ russets as well which is
pretty cool I never experienced russets
so I don't know I you know whatever but
there's some better stuff and I forget
the brand of it and maybe uh bitter or
somebody can drop the brand down or
maybe if you guys got some brands of of
micro eyes sulfur put them down in the
comments for people to try I like this
one here just cuz it's cheap it's
affordable it's off Amazon it goes a a a
long way you know and it gets to my door
in a day so when I needed it that's what
I happened to order maybe I would have
bought the better stuff if I had more
time or whatever but that's what I had
and ultimately that's what I'm probably
going to use for now because it works
great and I'm going to implement it into
my Gardens outside this year cuz we did
have some PM outside last year on a few
plants I'm hoping that helps me out but
the way you want to use it in your
garden is if you got a little bit of
PM you want to use one tablespoon per
gallon right if you got a real bad case
of it you can do two
tablespoons and you really want to put
your little drop drop of soap in there a
little molier you know and put you one
little drop of dish soap in there and
you want to mix it up real good and it's
best to use it right after you mix it
mix it but I have used some that's sat
around in a spray bottle for a day or
two it still does work but the way you
want to use it least the way I do
it a is a foil I can't talk right now
you guys you want to use it as a a
spray and you mix up your little gallon
or however much you want if you're doing
a half gallon you could do half of a
tablespoon or what you know you just
break it up
accordingly you mix it up and I like to
use these right
here the Z bottles I really like Zip not
because I'm sponsored or anything like
that but they uh they just last a long
time I've had literally one of these
since since I started growing again uh
for last five or six years and it's
never broke on me I've tried some of
those little pump little tiny half
gallon pump ones and [ __ ] little gallon
ones like you know it's got I don't know
you see them in like lows and like the
gardening section those always break on
you the seals go bad [ __ ] like that but
I also like using these this is a
smaller one I do have a two gallon one I
do like these wand uh this is the brand
I got um I think I ordered this in like
a two pack uh off of Amazon for like 20
bucks or something but it's a
gallon I like these cuz you can really
if you got a tent you can get up
underneath cuz you want to spray
underneath the leaves and on top and the
stocks like for me I didn't really get
much on my leaves but I would get it
more on my my stems my lower stems like
at the very bottom just above the soil
so I really like those uh but another
thing too is you really want um you
really want to do this at night time
because if you do it with the lights on
or in the sun it'll burn the [ __ ] out of
your plants and trust me I tried it and
and it not I didn't try it but I I you
know I've experimented a little bit and
I found out yeah definitely will will
burn your [ __ ] not by choice but but by
accident I did burn a couple things not
too terribly bad but um you can burn
them and also you don't want to use it
if you have any kind of oils or anything
like that man if you put any like NE oil
or anything oil based on it you want to
give it a few weeks before you put
anything else on it or it's going to
mess it up bro another thing
too is if you got
clones you can dip your clones
especially if you got like a rock W rock
wool cubes it's really easy man you just
take that thing turn it upside down and
bring it all the way to the don't don't
put your roots or your your actual Cube
down in there but right above it and
just bring it right down dip it in real
quick and pull it out I'll give a little
shake or so so it's not real heavy
especially on a fresh clone you don't
want a bunch of water sitting on top of
it but and then what I like to do is
with when I do the Clones like that I'll
let them kind of dry I I'll
intermittently we got a chicken in here
chewing on stuff I told you she's going
to make racket at some point now she's
chewing on styrofoam quit chewing on
styrofoam there chicken it's eating
eating styrofoam I I got the weirdest
chickens hold on a second let me let me
shut this thing up don't why you eating
styrofoam God damn it boy get out of
here what the hell Mom's done put me in
a a messed up situation you guys got
chicken living in here with me I mean
damn my old lady don't even want to come
kick it with me got this chicken hanging
out you can dip your clones in it and I
really like that but something you need
to be careful on on what that is if you
got your clones domed you're you know
your the water is not going to really
evaporate off of your uh dipped clones
that much so what I like to do is I kind
of occasionally I'll for like the first
12 hours or or whatever I I kind of keep
them more in the in the shap like not in
direct light I'll kind of put them in
ambient light I run some uh ions I think
they're like 35 Watts a piece or
something like that and I got a rack so
I'll kind of set them off to the side a
little bit and occasionally I'll take
that Dome off and let that that water
evaporate or even put a a little fan on
just a little bit increments at you know
a little bit at a time because you can
dry your [ __ ] dry them out like that so
you need to be careful but I like doing
that it is easier to probably just spray
them uh you know but dipping the clones
and stuff I it's the way I like to do it
you can use a paintbrush of some kind
too if you have to just hit a few spots
so if you got a plant somewhere and you
want to you don't want to spray it down
or or you know whatever you can go in
there and kind of hit it with the
paintbrush a little bit of that sulfur
just dip your paintbrush in and keep
hitting it now you want to do this like
two weeks like you could do it right as
you flower basically right when you flip
you can spray and let it chill but you
don't want to be doing that [ __ ] like
really like after a week cuz some stuff
will flour faster on on you and the
others and it'll burn burn your buds a
little bit and stuff so you you really
want to sulfur It Up is like a
preventative thing you know right when
you flip that's probably gonna be your
best time you know you can do it like a
weekend but you want to do it really
before your buds start to your you know
your flowers start to form and stuff but
uh yeah man if you so if you got
problems with russets or if you got
problems with with PM pick you up some
microzed I can't talk tonight y'all
sulfur and I think this is a you know
you could dust on too if you want uh I
like doing it like bitter said with the
soap cuz you know the water and the soap
cuz it kind of all helps it stick to the
plant and yeah man I think I covered
everything yeah don't don't use it with
the lights on or you know you burn them
uh use a little a drop of soap one
tablespoon per gallon two if it's real
bad don't do it at least I would say
seven days after flip don't do it
anytime after that but but try to do it
right when you flip this is going to be
better for somebody that's got a lot of
plants so if you're running into pm get
you some sulfur dude this stuff is so
cheap and this thing's like a 5B bag it
I mean this is an extra bag I've ordered
a bunch of them because I'm not going
out I'm going to have it till till I
need it you know I'm always going to
have it I'm always going to need it so
that being
said if you got russets I can't really
tell you how to implement it I'm
assuming it's the same way but if you
want to know more information like that
jump over in the Discord it's $5 join
through the patreon it's five bucks what
is that like a sod pop
nowadays and if you want to know more
about
russets jump in the disc
Discord and talk to bter or some of the
other guys like that and they'll help
you
out I'm very thankful for guys like that
and gals peaches all y'all that help me
out thank you very much y'all saved me a
lot of headaches a lot of time and a lot
of money and had a good time doing it uh
you know another thing I see people talk
about and this might seem silly for some
of you old school grows your old heads
uh you know I see a lot of people asking
when are my plants done when how do you
know when your plants are done well when
you've grown for a while you know by
visuals you know by looking at the
tricomes you know by you know the look
of the plant if you're feeding it right
she's fading pretty good for you she
ain't dark green on on you when you're
done or at least you shouldn't be most
genetics if you if you're doing it right
but for me I like to use one of these
right here and I see people say all the
time I you know I use my phone and this
and that and that's cool some people
they got little things you can attach to
your phones some people you like to cut
off something and take it over to a
microscope or whatever the heck you want
to see I got to use a microsc scope to
see my [ __ ] to be honest with you so I
get it I really do I can relate to you
guys fully but this is from AC infinity
and I don't and I'm not plugging them I
just I use a lot of their products I use
a lot of other people's products too but
I really like this uh Jeweler Loop here
I've tried an actual Jeweler loop I got
even got some I got this one that even
goes across your head and I'm like y'all
I can't see [ __ ] with that but this one
actually here I really like cuz it's got
for one it's got two different sizes and
I can't remember I think this is a 50
time and then 100 times but I'm not 100%
sure on that I suck I should have
already known that but something I
really like about these ones here is
it's got a light on it so you got a
light for one side and then you got a
light for another one and I actually get
pretty good results with this and I'm
able to actually see I I wear glasses
sometimes and I can actually see with
those without glasses so if I can see
with that y'all should be able to see
with that but I think that thing's like
eight bucks or something on on on AC
infinity or through Amazon you don't
even have to go through them you can I'm
pretty sure they sell them in different
places and different different brands
probably have more like these I just
went with AC Infinity one because I was
already ordering some stuff from them
and they gen generally make pretty good
products all their products are pretty
good um only product I didn't like from
AC Infinity is y'all's dang cheap uh
trimmers man what the heck everybody
sells cheap trimmers I got to get I'm
going to show off a good branded
trimmers here Denali gave me a good pair
and I swear by these I'm going to give
me a couple more pairs cuz all the ones
the grow company send you for like
freebies are dog [ __ ] they break the
Springs go flying I saw uh George Jetson
shout out Canada brother uh I saw him he
got him a pair of nice ones and I I said
man I need to get me a pair of nice ones
like that I might heck I might go big
and go order something from Japan bro
get some Damascus steel ones have you
seen some of them over there some of
those shears those they use for bound
trees and [ __ ] bro
are thousands of dollars crazy it's wild
sh out Japan I want to come over there
you guys I like y'all stuff yall cool
shout out
Australia shout out to all my little
sick [ __ ] down there you know what I'm
saying if I wasn't from here I'd be from
there bro shout out shout out to New
Zealand as well shout out to Africa bro
we got that South African Bros uh you
know shout out to everybody I appreciate
y'all tuning in and watching it really
means a lot to me but
get one of them little magnifying
glasses y'all look at your freaking
tricomes look for you know I don't know
some people want 5% 10% 20% 69% 3,000%
Amber dry combes you know look at them
freaking things see if they're milky
you're going to look through that little
microscope bro and if they're all clear
you're not ready to rear if they're
milky then it's silky if you got a
little Amber
that's what you want you know and it's
simple as that guys U as really all the
tips I got for y'all other than yeah uh
sulfur oh I do got one more tip for you
guys uh maybe I you
know this is for demonstration
educational purposes so I think I'd be
all
right I know we got some dabbers in the
chat and I know some of you old school
heads out there are like
man dabbing is weird I think it's a
little weird too but I do got a dab rig
here that I
use occasionally when I pick up some of
Peach's Peach's stuff I gotta I want to
try something you know I got to have
something for when I pick up some homie
stuff want to try out some concentrates
I'm not a big concentrate guy but
occasionally like I said a homie will
send me or you know we'll get something
going but I see people all the time they
talking about the old days when people
hit hit your your dab rig with the torch
full
blast 5,000 degrees fam that ain't the
way to do it I'm going to teach y'all
today about cold starts if you don't
know what a cold start is it's pretty
simple it's dabbing a form of dabbing
that don't tort your lungs my guys let
me get this over here so you can see it
all right I put some tobacco oil in here
you know so like for a demonstration so
we wouldn't get in trouble
but oh man anyways this is I think they
call this a quartz bangers is what this
is I forget the little names of these
bro
but you tell I I'm not really a Dabber
like I said I don't know the names of
anything bro I just use it I don't have
nobody talk to in person about this [ __ ]
so really a cold start's pretty
simple all you doing
is warming up that tobacco juice wink
wink until it starts to smoke a little
bit or not smoke I should say vaporize a
little bit it'll start to bubble and
vaporize a little bit so turn your torch
on and hit it it might take a second or
two it's a little
cold well you watch it'll start the
bubble
you see the you might not be able to see
the smoke but you see the bubbles you
see them bubbles there you go you can
see the smoke pull it
off and then you hit it guys it's easy
as simple simple like that that's all
you got to do you can lift it up if you
want you lift your finger off the little
little rush hole whatever and that's it
put your little water some Kool-Aid
Mountain Dew whatever your preferences
and you save your lungs guys gals I know
some of the old school guys are like
what the what is this guy on talking
about crazy [ __ ] but like I said we're
going teaching them we're going to teach
them the ways of the Chuck dog we're
going to save y'all's lungs don't be
like me smoking blunts smoke cold Stars
save your
lungs um that's really all all we got
for Education today y'all I'll be honest
uh but I figure we go into a few maybe
one story I've dragged on a little bit
about the sulfur so we're going to maybe
just do one story I guess so T so
tonight I figure we'll jump in we's see
which one am I gonna give y'all today
we'll
do I think the running through the field
one's a good one I know people have
heard this one before but the the
viewers that aren't in the Discord
probably have not so we'll do that one
uh you know I dragged down a little bit
too long I had three stories planned but
we're just going to do one for
tonight and I used to live in a cabin in
Kentucky with my old lady and we kind of
lived out on a on Lane Road up a gravel
road you know off a beaten Trail type of
thing which is often the case in
Kentucky that's where I like to be bro I
like to be out out there in the woods or
on a farm just away from people
Obviously good them [ __ ] around with
pot and [ __ ] like
that
and had three tents rolling
bro just flipped
had some really cool genetics had some
stuff that a guy like me probably
shouldn't even really had uh you know
people you know how it is people give
you [ __ ] I'm a new Bro in the in certain
community and give you some [ __ ] that
you probably shouldn't have well I'm
growing some of that kind of [ __ ]
probably the to the time the best run
the most money I've sunk into a
run up until this point and uh I'm
chilling me and her are chilling One
Night in the middle like summer
bro
and I like the dog starts
barking it's like what the
[ __ ] so in the country when you got a
dog and a dog's barking especially live
in a middle of nowhere usually it's
coyotes or somebody's come up your drive
or somebody's around or you know maybe
they see a deer or something but usually
you know somebody come up the
drive so I look down bro and I we're
purched up on a hill in this
cabin and at the bottom probably 4 or
500 yards down there's a creek a
bridge a mailbox in the main road and
you could see the bridge and you can see
people coming across it driving or
whatever and I look down there
bro and I see two like this is like
right at night time but I can still kind
of make out the shape of the vehicles
there's two SUVs down down there bro
spotlights on them like on the driver's
side I'm like what the hell is that bro
well I told her I said there's two
trucks down here or two SUV looking
things uh with spotlights on them down
there I said her dad come up there
sometimes because we have a a bunch of
fields up there and stuff that uh we
work and stuff and grow tobacco and
stuff like
that and uh
I'm like are they coming over because
they drop big combines and tractors and
[ __ ] off all the time at night like
random times for the next day so I was
like are they supposed to be over here
or something she's like no not that I
know of this is like on a weekend night
or some weird [ __ ] bro like sus time you
know um so I'm looking and like they're
just sitting there bro and they sit
there for like 15 minutes man and the
whole time I had just gotten high bro I
had like [ __ ] Harvest some
mushrooms like all shit's for myself but
like I'm tripping cuz I'm like man like
like what the [ __ ] is going on bro I'm
too paranoid I done smoke too much this
a weekend I'm partying I'm had a little
bit of I think I had like a a panut
colada or something occasionally I'll
drink a panina Cola with her or whatever
she'll make me one and uh relive them
tequila days
y'all and uh so I'm sitting there like
kind of paranoid bro it's building you
know and I ain't never got caught doing
[ __ ] so I'm sitting here like this ain't
going to be the time especially when I
ain't hustling I'm just trying to grow
some [ __ ] few plants for me to smoke
and stay out of streets I'm sitting
there looking at the
window and bro I'm like these
[ __ ] have been here way too
long like I heard like yelling and like
or not yelling but I could hear I went
outside I could like hear [ __ ] I could
hear talking and stuff and I don't know
why I didn't think of it
like but
a different way but my mind I'm like man
I'm about to get raided
bro started think or
robbed one of the
two
so
uh I was like [ __ ] bro I told her I said
that's either the cops or somebody's
coming up up here to get some and uh cuz
I didn't never have really anybody over
so it's weird that they were even there
right so so I tell her I was like all
right flush the mushrooms get all the
weed get ready to flush the weed
and just just hang out in the bathroom
and wait for wait for me to do something
I said close all the windows up and the
shades and everything you know so she
did it and while she's doing it bro I'm
in I'm this is the most clones I ever
had at one time I'm in there [ __ ]
grabbing clones bro all the cubes
grabbing them grabbing them grabb them
throw them in in buckets five gallon
buckets and trash bags bro and uh I run
I get all them in a bucket bro and I go
to my big tents and I I just start
whacking them bro cuz I'm thinking like
at least at least if I hack them down
like I could say there's something else
or like what are they going to do if
they come in there just a bunch of
stumps lay around like whatever I'll
just keep my mouth shut and tell them do
what you got to do and uh so I'm cutting
these big ass plants and then I get to
my final T bro and these [ __ ]
back then I was growing in five and
seven gallons bro and are huge dude and
the pots are huge and I'm like [ __ ] man
like so I grabbed them there's four of
them I grabbed those four [ __ ] plants
drag them to like the back door where
the back porch is that faces the fields
and [ __ ] and uh I get all those buckets
right there and I just start pushing
[ __ ] through the dog door bro cuz we had
a big Mastiff so we had a big dog door
so I started pushing these all these
bags of [ __ ] chopped up plants and
all the [ __ ] through the dog door
right and uh I'm I take off running at
the back door open the gate and I just
run as fast as I can like along the
tobacco like trying to hide my
Silhouette like cuz there's two tobacco
Fields I can run along the barn and I
run to my neighbor's property bro and I
dumped him trash bags over over the
field and I run back bro and and as I'm
running back I like kind of look down
there as I get to the back door and look
down at the road and these [ __ ] are
coming up the driveway bro and I'm like
[ __ ] they're coming I told I told her I
said get ready to flush it I said if if
you hear a knock or anything just start
flushing all that [ __ ] and uh I'm like
[ __ ] adrenaline's pumping dude I'm
sweating you know in my underwear cuz
I'm like you know I think we about to
hook up or something I don't even
remember bro but uh I'm I'm in my
underwear I'm running through these
fields with the weed um or the plants
and then I run back grab them buckets
I'm running as fast as I can and I go
back and and grab them four uh two of
them plants and run back again and I'm
sprinting hauling ass cuz these [ __ ]
are coming up the driveway but it's
weird they're like coming up like a cop
with bro like real slow and they got the
[ __ ] spotlights and they're like
looking around for [ __ ] and I'm like
what what the what the [ __ ] is going on
like if they gonna come get me what the
[ __ ] what are they doing so I'm running
these plants and I run back to the crib
get all them out and I'm trying to clean
up the the tents turning all the lights
off [ __ ] throwing random [ __ ] in there
looks like it's been there for a while
whatever and I'm waiting
bro and they come up I watch them out
the window they come up the
driveway and I told her I was like if
they knock flush I said but we ain't
open this goddamn door I was like I said
they come to the door I'm going to tell
them like hey I'm in here my hands are
up you know kick in the door if you got
a [ __ ] warrant dude just you know and
and uh and I told her said flush the
[ __ ] if you know and uh so I'm watching
out the window bro when they coming up
and the driveway kind of runs in front
of the cabin and I'm running out the
back doing all my [ __ ] on the other side
so they got to come around though to
like cuz we're on a hill they got to
come around to where you can actually
Park so they come up and they come
around bro and they come up behind our
truck and they're sitting there for a
second and I heard like talking bro but
I'm like I ain't going out there or
whatever you know dogs are barking and
[ __ ] they sit there for like 10 minutes
shining spotlights everywhere like what
the [ __ ] bro I got the lights off in the
house and [ __ ] I'm telling her like what
the [ __ ] is going on and uh they leave I
like I look out the window again they're
gone and I look out the other window and
they're leaving the
driveway I like what the what happened
what the [ __ ] bro and it Dawns on me
like maybe I go look at my phone real
quick I had looked at my phone this
whole time I'm [ __ ] bricks you
know and I go look at my phone and I got
like six Miss calls like what the
hell well it was my neighbor Tom from up
the road him and his wife were in their
uh Range Rovers or whatever the [ __ ]
they drive they got a lot of money so
always got weird
[ __ ] um they're up there with spotlights
on their SUVs looking for their cat so I
call them and uh I'm like yo what's I
said what what's going on and he's like
oh you know sorry to come up here you
know on your property but we my wife
lost her cat and we got these spotlights
and we we were up just up here drive
around trying to see if we can find it
we've had them for you know 19 years or
whatever it was some crazy [ __ ] and I
was like oh you know that's cool bro I
was just like you know you I was like
man you scared of me bro I didn't know I
said I know who was pulling up the
driveway that's why I didn't come out or
anything and he's like uh oh it's cool
bro and little he don't know this but
I'm [ __ ] mad I'm my anger is starting
to build not really at him but kind of
the situation just cuz I had just thrown
out probably you know $2 $300 worth of
soil you know at least $3 $400 worth of
CSI gear uh you know from seed cuz I'm
growing from seed you know and threw
away some really cool [ __ ] that I got
real early I shouldn't had and yeah dude
just a gut punch you want to talk about
depressed and not wanting to grow for a
while those were one of the moments like
for like a month I was just like dude
like I'm an idiot bro you want to talk
about feel like a dumbass man [ __ ] like
that when some it's [ __ ] like that that
when someone calls me a dumb ass I'm I
pretty much agree with with them bro
anyways I appreciate y'all tuning in
it's about all I really got for you you
know I had it a little bit better but my
enthusiasm kind of was lost because this
the second time record recording this
episode but I hope you enjoyed it if you
didn't let me know in the comments let
me know if you didn't like it let me
know how I can make it better also if
you like me if you think I'm cool or
whatever maybe throw up a Chuck dog or
you know Chuck fam or something in the
comment for a bro and a like and a sub
show me to your mom your dads your
sisters your brothers the swans man the
the Iceman the freaking the ice trucker
Road Trucker guys show them show them to
everybody let's spread the love let's
spread the message let's spread breeder
Syndicate family as always you guys
gals go to WR
seeds.com to pick up some of the most
fire genetics in the world and that
ain't no lie you can trust me believe me
believe in me
all right I love y'all join the Discord
join the patreon support the
homies when you you know that's pretty
much it so I might drop a midweek
episode but if not I'll see you [ __ ]
back on next Sunday we'll do something
we might do an interview if you like
these single format
episodes let me know I'm working on them
they're work in progress talking to
yourself is [ __ ]
weird by yourself but I have fun doing
it it's fun I like learning I like
trying new [ __ ] you know I've tried so
much new [ __ ] that my [ __ ] is blown
out this point but I do like trying new
[ __ ] when it comes to weed and
technology and entertainment I like that
[ __ ] so anyways as always support us
over on Fridays at 9:00 P PM Eastern
with Matt right and your boy we have a
podcast on there about history I haven't
really contributed much to it but Matt
has in and stuff over the years so go go
check out all the work that he's put in
go check out all the history go check
out all the breeder knowledge join the
Discord join the patreon and have a good
rest your Sunday night I guess really
that's it and as always shout out
Kentucky shout out Michigan baby