howdy
howdy daryl flam
stinky hey flynn if you have time this
might be a good one to record
with uh not so coming on
thank you dear hey what's up green candy
press what's up brother
long time no talk curbside
what's up foo constellation keeping on
and on how you guys doing
welcome welcome
that green can depress i miss you guys
all right good i love you too
sketch sketch [ __ ]
what's up
swerve of lisa someone said where's the
swerve of lisa
that was bryn's uh lovely creation
like that was all her she saw the venus
the milo and saw swerve standing like
she's like
this [ __ ] had to [ __ ] prepare
it this way
swerve to milo
okay so wait a little bit for people to
start coming in
for those of you already in here so i've
got a big box next to me
of some oldies and goodies and
there's a lot more this is just the
stuff that's packed up but
but we've got some cool little treats
like this for the auction and now
so you guys know at the beginning we're
gonna do the auction at the
end of the show near the end um
but i'm not sure how how long this one's
gonna take this might be a um
this might be a two two hour long one we
don't know yet
um depends on how long they want to take
it and how annoying is that that
everybody who
messages me and makes a loud ass noise
there he is awesome awesome
beautiful beautiful beautiful what's up
dude
how good is it how you doing i'm good
you're perfect man it's good to see you
good to see you as well
all right so yeah i i decided like you
know i mean we talk all the time
uh we've been trying to figure out the
whole super skunk
fiasco yep from from
point of where um i guess
uh what what how do we wanna um
label certain people well i mean we can
just call
a skunk voss gunkva since uh
everybody knows uh everybody's familiar
with that moniker
yeah but yeah others hem dog is chem dog
that's another familiar moniker skunk
von mai's old buddy
um i think during the podcast he called
him his buddy from staten island
okay let's do that yeah and he's a
private dude and kind of out of the
scene at this point so we're just gonna
like not say his name out of uh respect
and that he's he's uh he's long
uh you know his part is important but
long ago so yes
i don't respect for him we won't we'll
just refer to him in code
yeah that's perfect strangely he's one
of those rare people in the industry
that is not seeking past fame
yeah no it's not peabud guys no he is
actually
the opposite um yeah so
let's start with where do you want to
start the super skunk story at where
should we start it at
uh we'll start at the beginning there we
go okay
so my buddy from staten island uh
him and skunkvaa were very good friends
and they used to travel and tour
together
dead tour days right and in the early
90s
dude wanted to move out to the west
coast
in california and he was more into
seeing
jerry garcia shows than he was into
seeing the actual dead
right yeah but jerry would play at the
warfield
basically every month right like a big
ass hippie gathering
at the war field you know and so my
buddy
uh kind of stopped touring uh moved to
sonoma county
um and uh started seeing every jerry
show
there okay right obviously jerry shows
are uh
uh you know they're like honey to
deadheads
so you know so a whole bunch of
deadheads would always attend
uh these shows at the warfield right
correct
so skunk bob being being from virginia
right a lot of his old crew and mentors
and various things like that were east
coast right
yeah so one time some of these guys came
out
and from the east coast and uh
they uh were partying with all those
guys at the warfield
okay okay um
so skunk violence mutual friend
used to have this strain called the
francine all right
and then tell us about granting a little
offset but tell us about francine a
little bit
francine is a mystery indica that
uh we didn't use the term at the time
but it was about as terpy as
terpy gets yeah um eventually dude
dropped it because
like a lot of afghans um it had a
horrific mold problem
yeah and as you know you know when you
uh when you grow things uh that
horrifically look beautiful and
horrifically mold
at times it's very depressing harvest
time
oh yeah happened to you a few times with
a cut you can get ptsd
and decide to drop it you know like
get people get emotional about it so
what does she smell like
you know it it was a really good
combination
of like that like that afghan kind of
acrid funk yeah right but with
with like a fruity aspect but not like
the tropical sativa kind of fruit it
just had like
a really deep like like foot funk fruit
kind of flavor to it i think oh wow so
anyway so
these dudes loved it yeah right and
uh um they loved it so much
they were willing to trade this skunk
that they had for it
okay so separately to all this story and
uh skunk vas kind of talked about this
extensively on his on his podcast so
i'll just briefly touch on it
but chem dog wouldn't give out the dog
which is what we call it to anyone
right he held it super tight he didn't
want anybody
in his circle getting it he didn't want
to get cut off
you know um or have other people sell it
but when homie moved
to california he agreed
look i'll give it to you if you just
don't ever
share it with anybody back east yeah
right yeah don't want to compete markets
totally don't make sense
don't share it so basically what
happened
is that skunkva arranged with his
buddies
to trade the francine for the skunk
okay yeah dude decided to make a double
trip
where he would bring the francine out to
virginia
and he would trade it for the skunk and
then he would drive up to massachusetts
and he would
get the chem dog that was promised to
him right
dude that's committed that is committed
in 1993
uh homie drove across a bunch of shady
ass states
with little plants uh you know
not very many and small but still you
know still yeah
fancy if he got pulled over he probably
would have had to eat them you know or
something
yeah yeah and we have their state
checkpoints you gotta
do all kinds of you know this was
actually pre-pre
uh to use the term we joke about most
yeah
the highway 80 drug checkpoints and
stuff like that yeah
this was in 93 so they really hadn't
gotten wise to that too much
oh good if you took the middle route uh
you
you were pretty much safe for the most
part i mean you could still get pulled
over
you know and he definitely looked like a
hippie
i bet like he wasn't yeah no secret
sauce or anything like that he didn't
look like a young republican or anything
yeah yeah and so so he drives out to
virginia and uh and
meets um what we just learned actually
recently
ended up being dude's actual worker
because the dude had already kind of
gone on the run for a bit
and was weaving and so he gets this
this super skunk cut and i want to
interject
as far as we know the person we're
referring to um not by name the staten
island guy
yeah um that as far as we know this is
scumfier's mentor
so this is how close we can put skunk va
to the
beginning of this cut as far as we know
the guy that agreed to do it is the
mentor but apparently
the guy that actually did the trade is
one of his workers exactly
um but i asked when all this confusion
came up a few years ago i read i
asked staten island um
do you remember the exchange well enough
to be absolutely sure what did he call
it
yeah if you fast forward to like when i
became friends with these guys in the
late 90s
it was always called super skunk right
yeah
so staten island uh he gets
you know he told me that straight up
dude said this is a super skunk cup
okay so he gets it straight forward
yeah so he trades he gets it then he
drives to massachusetts
okay and he meets up with chemdawg and
he gets the 91.
uh we all call the dog but you know
everybody on the internet calls it skunk
pho cut or 91 or whatever so
yeah um but everybody back then it was
just the dog
a bunch of these dudes were organic
growers and so even though it was
chem dog they didn't want to put him on
it yeah my buddy they weren't super into
calling it
chem dog because they grew fully organic
so
um so we destroyed the dog and amongst
all of us long before it got famous or
anything like that
that's just kind of the shorthand you
know i've been writing that on labels
now for
two decades right so so
he got an extra cut or two of this super
skunk
okay okay and he gave one to chem dog
okay okay so that's not so
chem dog got it basically by accident
yeah he got it by proxy
just like by accident by proxy he got it
because
homie decided to go to virginia before
massachusetts
that's crazy what a what a wild what
yeah he could have reversed it and gone
massachusetts virginia
home yeah but he went virginia
massachusetts home
that's enough it changed a lot that
act that choice in my opinion i mean
we've talked about this a bunch or
whatever that ended up
leading to a whole series of accidental
events that became super important
right right yeah so um
you know so then he drives back home
right
yep now he's got super skunk in the dog
okay
and if you went to warfield shows in san
francisco to see jerry band
you probably could have seen him
slinging all that
in front of the show every single month
yeah
yeah oh um
so skunk fall took a different tact and
he could speak to this for himself but
he kept touring basically
right so when jerry died in august
uh this next week here we call this the
days between
because jerry's birthday is on the 1st
of august and
his death is on the is in a week now or
something like that and so these are
like easter for hippies yeah it's sort
of like the
yeah it's the it's the easter week or
whatever so
uh you know skunk vod decided to settle
down after
jerry passes right and that's when he
started growing
now because obviously to grow you have
to be semi-stable
it's not a really dramatic lifestyle
right so yeah
um so those pictures that he's been
posting
of polaroids and everything like that or
after our buddy gave him
the cut from his friends in virginia and
he started growing it
yes right yep um so that's basically how
that's basically how this this cut from
virginia made its way to
sonoma county the bay and massachusetts
and see and then this is a great intro
too to the kem dog story as well which
we will cover
in our podcast which will eventually be
here soon
so so that's the start of that's the
start of the super skunk
movie um you know i uh
i met uh i didn't know them then
personally
uh a couple years after that um
and uh my you know my uh my buddy
uh he fell in love with the mendo p
yeah a couple other things or whatever
and so he ended up giving me the super
skunk
and the dog for safekeeping you know
and uh and that's in the late 90s and
that's kind of how i got it
and you've had it well like not the
super skunk but the chem 91 and it
stayed with you ever since yep i've had
that since i never lost it no
unfortunately the super skunk was lost
uh but we'll get to that uh yeah okay so
you know
so we have this stuff right and uh
you know this is obviously um
what is it you know so late 90s 2000
2001 this whole little era right then
so you've got like the internet is in
it's like infancy
essentially right overgrow had just
began in 98.
yeah so there really wasn't any internet
fame
yeah right all these things that have
become super famous and like holy grails
and all these people trying to figure
out stuff right
uh most of the stories that i believe
that i've heard about this stuff comes
from that era
because that was when there was nobody
gave a [ __ ]
yeah in the sense so there's no reason
to bull about any of it there was no
fame associated with it there was no rap
there was no i mean it was literally
like
there was like four people in california
who had it
yeah exactly there was me skunk bar our
buddy
and uh uh icy collective
yes i see collective yes right who was
really close friends with skunk bar you
know
uh yeah and and greg and that and he
and he ended up like uh moving in with
skunkva and that's how he got the cut so
there was literally like four of us
yeah um so not very big and now
back then you had enormous rooms or
anything like that you know
yeah there really wasn't very much of it
even being produced
yeah you're blowing it up with the four
lighter essentially you're blowing it
mostly mostly
spiders oh okay you guys are slinging
hard
12 lighters or whatever but yeah um
but yeah you know and so uh so just to
keep it back on the super skunk tip
um you know obviously it's been
quite a long time um but here here's
what i know for sure
um it was uh
i never ever heard it called anything
but super skunk
obviously we've had some debate amongst
friends oh sure
there's a whole different thing we can
get into later about whatever about some
different
different names and stuff and yeah or
may not be the exact same thing through
different crews or whatever
but as far as as far as my little group
goes
um that's what it was always called
right
straight super skunk and so buddy from
staten island
okay he would love like when we'd have
trimmers over
you could pull side branches of that
thing and you could hold it up to the
the picture in the catalog of the 90
seed bank
right and it was like a dead ringer yeah
you would you could find buds on the
plants
that like match that look exactly yeah
it was
very very uniform witnessed him dozens
of times
over multiple crops right
just because he was just so cool because
it's like yeah exactly like the picture
in the catalog right yeah and he could
show you hey
this really is super skunk you're buying
you know and so
uh you know in a lot of ways you know it
was a sketchy plan
um yeah that was you know that was the
very beginning of the 215 era
right um but it wasn't really you know
215 had like multiple
eras right the first five or six 215
like the cops the courts everything it
was still pretty much
underground yeah yeah you're still
getting [ __ ] people hadn't grown
to like let's have a greenhouse outside
my back door
yeah none of that thrilling uh indoor
was still sketchy it was still not the
jam
you know yeah so um
so the super skunk you know the last two
or three weeks it literally people joke
about carbon filter killer
right yeah it was the only strain i've
ever grown
that um absolutely defeated every
opportunity i ever had to win
i don't even know any other way to
describe it the amount yeah
burn it would give me like i would pull
up with two weeks to go in front of my
house
in summer and it would smell like a dead
skunk
in my driveway yeah i know the feeling
not with
skunks but yeah every direction out and
and so you know back then you're just
like oh my god you know that is yeah
be nerve-wracking and so at which i had
obviously people know on this on this
thing what scrubbers are i had a
co2 scrubber with a fan scrubbing the
room
i had uh or a carbon filter sorry not
co2 i had a carbon filter
right yeah and um so that's scrubbing
the room and then i had a carbon filter
on the exhaust
and then i had one of those huge uv on
air double
uh yeah um you know ozone generators
yes even did the recommended 25 or 30
feet
of tubing before it went out the
building to make sure it had time to mix
yeah and it still smelled like i was
slaughtering skunks in my backyard
that's kind of how it was you know so
uh it was trippy in that regard um
and you know it it was it was
i don't know it looked dense
even when it looked dense it was still
it's still weighed light
yeah it was just those things where like
you you know you put a nug on there and
you're like oh this is going to be
impressive and you're like oh
no it's hollow how did they make hollow
weed
it was like solid but it was fluffy it's
like almost like ice cream or something
that had a bunch of air whipped into it
you know
and uh um you know and
the terp the weird thing about the terp
is that
it was super volatile in my opinion like
it didn't
really stink until the last bit and then
it
dunked for about a month or five weeks
after you cut it
yeah if you let super skunk go too long
in your jar or whatever it would have
eventually kind of smelling semi to
generic green butt
oh yes yeah that makes sense
i could crack a jar in the other room
and someone would walk in and ask me
what was going on
like you would have to like crunch the
[ __ ] out of it
and deeply smell to try to get a whiff
yeah that makes sense
but fresh it reaped yeah
um you know and you know it's kind of
hard to trim
it was it could be sparse you know when
it didn't
uh you know i mean for most people um
probably the easiest way to think about
it is
uh you know real old-school sour has a
lot of similarities to it
yes you know so when sour doesn't want
to come out the right way
it's a [ __ ] to trim you know like
people lose people start
you know your your crew gets
disheartened oh my god i got a trim
diesel
you know yeah right now i posted some
stuff for you the other night
uh that i sent you where like my old
sour diesel cutting
it looks like those tops those colas
they really
oh yeah see those same super skunk
tops that skunk bob posts yeah
you can really see the similarity in it
you know um so the other thing that
that uh so it had unbelievable terps i
mean when people talk about
rks terps or whatever else it was
the terpest skunkiest rankest thing
imaginable you know uh
it really was um and uh
you know it also you know uh
it also harmed like a [ __ ] yeah
that's that's like really the first
thing i ever heard about
mass super when i first started getting
into the scene and
learning the history and stuff that that
[ __ ] was a herm bomb it was a herm bomb
it could harm
um you know we would pull it about eight
weeks
sometimes you would um you know you
would try to take it longer because you
think maybe it needed to be done
more and they would hurt for sure
yeah but the other thing is and this is
kind of weird about it
is that it hurt early too
because well as a breeder right
yeah yeah full if you let's say you pull
the super skunk at 58 days
and you find tiger striped beans in it
yeah
when were those beans made yeah you know
they're early on
they're probably primordial they had to
be arrogant because it takes a good four
to six weeks
yes to mature it to like fully mature
and get that dark
tiger striping that looks all healthy
and stuff you know sure
um so you pull a strain at 58 days just
by the law
of how beans grow
yeah had the pot you know it something
bad bad had to happen in three weeks
yeah yeah but that act that
in my opinion you know and there's a
certain amount of you know
we can get to opinions about it but that
factor
created a whole bunch of weed that we
like yeah i did
that's that's the crazy part craziest
part about all of it through live harms
yeah and so okay so you know in the
in the uh you know uh
the the buddy from staten island right
he was not very into sharing
yeah no um i uh you know when i got
when i got the dog i had to promise
that i wouldn't give it out you know
which i didn't for forever
you know yeah and i would have like we
would have like really good friends of
ours
that would um beg me for it
and i'd be like you know who you have to
talk to get him to call me and say that
you can have it and i'll take cuts for
you tomorrow
yeah but otherwise like i'm not breaking
my word
yeah of course because like we're all
good friends and he's gonna know you
have it
and then that makes me look like an
[ __ ] you know so no
you know issues and it's like well this
is the
you know this is what i had to do so he
wasn't as strict about the skunk but he
kind of felt the same way
you know and you know me like i try to
be as like
as etiquette as oh yeah possible with
cuts
yeah i don't even like to pressure
people i'm just not into it like
yeah have their own vibe and their own
energy about why they come to you or not
you know sure and so you know so
what sucks about that is that
we didn't spread it very far yeah right
like we weren't on forums or anything
like that or whatever
um staten island buddy is not weasel
clop glass no no no he's not
i'm not paying very much attention to
the words at the bottom of the screen so
it's all right as anything maybe mac can
say it or repeat it again or something
but yeah
he's totally not it's totally not him um
so uh you know so the fact
there's two things right is obviously
back then most people are growing for
profit
you know on some level and so having a
cut that reeks the high heaven
and scares your neighbors and herms on
you
uh you know it made it dicey on people
holding it
yeah and so you know we never
you know skunk von myself you know our
buddy
we never really spread it we weren't
trading we weren't active on the forums
you know we weren't swapping cuts out
right and left and stuff and so
you know uh that's uh you know that's a
different discussion but as you know
like every time
my opinion is like every single time a
famous named cut happened
yeah like purple craze with urkel and
gdp
the sour the cushes whatever a whole
bunch of amazing diversity just goes to
[ __ ]
yeah because people want to fill their
room or their greenhouse or their
whatever with something that some guy is
going to come and
snap it from them right yeah they want
the
the ship that's going to sell not for
the most so even amongst most of my
close friends
i've always had a [ __ ] of a time
getting people to back things up for me
yeah people want one or two plants that
they're currently doing for production
and they don't hold on to a bunch of
stuff that they're doing for
safe keeping or heads or whatever you
know
um so it wasn't that easy for me to get
it to be backed up anywhere
right particularly because uh
you know when it comes to you know
production and stuff like that some
broker finding seeds is [ __ ] doom
um so like hey do you want to grow this
thing that could potentially lightly or
heavily seed your room
no not at all not not really no
right you know so
you know i mean uh so we all grew it
um and sorry i'm sorry i just had to
boot someone
i didn't want to but he was being a
jackass and being real rude
so oh i have no i i wasn't even paying
attention it's all good
um so i don't know i mean that's kind of
the start of the
of the cali super skunk uh
you know thing it stayed with our little
crew um
and you know and um you know the
massachusetts side of things
and greg and all that other star chem
dot one second
masonic i'm being real [ __ ] serious
you're being [ __ ] disrespectful as
[ __ ] and i'm gonna
[ __ ] you up if you keep it up knock it
the [ __ ] off have some respect
i've been real [ __ ] cool to you okay
cool
so i don't know i mean so you know i
don't know
uh i have no idea like you know what
happened with chemdawg in massachusetts
you know who when how he shared what
with you know all
that type of stuff um you know
as far as as far as the actual super
skunk cut goes
yeah you know but it's one of those
things where
like you know uh nobody wanted it until
it became
sort of this legendary famous thing and
then everybody started poking around
trying to figure out who might have kept
it
you know so yeah uh staten island and i
um we had this thing where like two of
our favorite strains were obviously the
super skunk and the chem dog right
yeah and the super skunk had the
the lime green and the frost uh i mean
you know from the chem du you know from
dog dog
isn't particularly gorgeous it's not
super frosty compared to
grains it's darker cut you know it
cannibalizes its own leaves
it doesn't even always taste great you
know
sometimes it can taste amazing and i
love the flavor but like
i could grow it all year long and only
two crops out of five
be happy with its flavor at times yeah
you know and why
exactly um why why exactly that is i
don't know
so we had this idea um and this is long
before
you know i mean there was no real
american seed companies or anything like
that right so
we were we were doing a bunch of
breeding but we were doing a bunch of
breeding that was literally
for our taste buds like it was not for
public consumption at best it was going
to be grown by us and spread out
yeah you know we created this we created
this thing over time
uh staten island started it and i came
on and helped
uh and you know we did some work on it
together uh that we eventually called
the superdog
uh which is in the can of bible the
second one i think
yes um that was my first that was my
first experience with
kind of uh really finding a strain that
i wanted to
hunt and right there even though i got
along quite well with jason who wrote it
um and i gave him a bunch of accurate
information a lot of that
got twisted and turned into some of his
entries about
the the dog and the chem dog and the
super and all that type of stuff you
know
so be that as it may what we were trying
to do is we were trying to
combine the terps and the look of super
skunk
with the potency and some of the density
and some of the
the niceness of the dog sure you know
and it was like a
you know and so um you know and
strangely uh and this is another thing
of why i think maybe it disappeared as
we we've talked about this recently too
i i tend to believe that the skunk
and the herm is related yes
like i i can't say for certain but i
think it might be a linked trait
i i and there's a lot of uh um
evidence for that yeah you know and as
you know um
you know there's there's very few traits
that people breeding
have you know more prejudice against
than
uh banana banana sacks with herminem you
know
yeah and so i think inadvertently
uh people bred away from the skunk
yeah without realizing it because you
know you breed some stuff it's a hermit
mess it reeks you're like oh god that's
a hermit mess i'm gonna get you know
i'm not gonna breed towards that side
and the idea that you could have a
linked trait
where you have a very desirable trait
and a not so desirable trait
uh together you know is the biggest
breeder pain in the ass
ever is a link trait with undesirable
traits he's like oh all the potency
comes in these low yielding ones that
suck
you know all these huge donkey dicks and
like have the structure is incredible
they're all bland
you know yep and so
you know uh the problem is is that you
know you have a situation it's like it's
kind of the same thing
like you know like i told you about with
the trinity right where the trinity
didn't spread very far
and so when we lost it and i kept trying
to get it back
um people would give me fakes yeah
it's not because they were dicks most of
the time but because they never had it
back in the day so when they got it from
someone they didn't
they had no way of knowing that it
wasn't it yeah
of course yeah um and so then i would
have to be the bearer of bad news
you know and be like no this isn't it
yeah and people hate the bear of bad
news
and that's kind of what's happened with
this super skunk right
is that yeah there's obviously this
desire in the community
to have these these road killed terps
come back right
everyone who finds super skunk has a
current seed company
and is making seeds to sold to the
public
no one ever shows up to
events with a couple jars of fresh skunk
and lets the proof be in the pudding
yeah right
they get the cut they advertise the cut
here's the cut we're breeding with the
cut
buy my seeds find the amazing terps in
the cup
right or they get kinks you know yeah
and so
so you don't know you don't know if if
they're lying
because i don't know or whatever or they
just have no id
they just never had it in the past you
know to know that
to know what skunk is yeah but actual
to what the actual skunk cut is you know
and so you know by the early to mid
2000s it had been dropped enough
um that uh you know uh
various people had lost it through you
know
lots of the same reasons that everybody
loses cuts
fires busts accidents breakups
you know people not returning it um i
had backed up with a couple people they
refused to give it back to me at one
point
uh and then lost it in the future and um
i had some stuff happen and i lost it
and we've been
you know we've been hunting it ever
since and uh
you know i mean we're both obviously
friends with skunk bar
um all these new school super skunk
finds
i mean what are you gonna say they just
end up they end up not looking
i mean what's awesome is that he's got
these
he's got these you know uh these
pictures these polaroids
that are undisputable
that was the cut i had that is so big
that he has those pictures we're buddies
we got it from you know
it came from the same place the story
was the same thing
you know so um you know it's it's it
and you know you have all these other
shorter
squatter afghan all these other
different looking
you know super skunk cuts and then the
other part of it too
is that you have people that like okay
so this guy had the super skunk at once
right well then as soon as that dude
verifies
right yeah well then all of a sudden
okay we have it now we can trade bait it
now we can get spread out
now this person has the cut and you know
that's the problem
and that's the problem you know and so
you know i mean before everybody who's
listening holy [ __ ] we're up to 242
people on this thing
but uh yeah the super skunk was not a
perfect cut
you know like it wasn't in my opinion it
wasn't the holy grail did it have
crazy rare skunk terps absolutely
it had that spades was it enjoyable to
smoke
sure right i don't think it held a
candle
to the dog the d some of the cushes
a lot of the modern cuts right now that
we would consider to be elite
you know you would consider it to have
moderate potency at best yes
you know it wasn't it you know i mean
you know various cuts have various
uh qualities and and yeah and other
things and you know and so
it didn't check all the boxes yeah
was it a great cut or was it worth
having yes uh
was it a pain in the ass to grow at
times yes
yes think about but you know and you
know i mean in
i think you know i mean obviously you
know all of
uh chem dogs early breedings were all
accidental
right yeah you know that as far as we
know that's the correct yeah
but he was well i mean the thing is that
nobody was reversing back then
no jesus [ __ ] christ right and yeah
noah's making feminists
on purpose feeds back then and so you
only you know
so you know the only way you're crossing
two female cuts
is accidentally yes you know
and those accidents you know um they led
to some of the best
weed ever yeah you know uh yeah
in many people's opinion yeah and you
know i mean that's that's like a whole
nother
uh thing that steps you know maybe it
steps on toes or doesn't to talk about
all those kind of theories about various
things but
um i have not seen the real super skunk
um since i i lost it um
which has been you know uh quite a while
at this point yeah
we've been hunting it for a long time um
you know i i don't think it exists
you know there's always the possibility
there are still pockets in america
where um you know people aren't really
connected they're not on the internet
they're not dialed in to like the scene
so to speak
so yeah i mean obviously just like we
know right so
to jump on a european trip everybody
thought the a52 was lost
for well over a decade yeah right
yeah at least yeah nobody could find it
and then karma found a guy that was
holding on to this cut for neville
neville told him not to tell anybody and
it was the a52
yeah and karma wasn't even sure what he
had right so he had to give it to
yosemite who grew with neville forever
to grow it out and confirm it was it
so it's possible right it is absolutely
possible exactly and i think we are all
desperately hoping that happens too
no yeah it's possible that that could
exist because the a5 was lost
for a long time i mean a short period of
time that it was lost i mean
i i think it's i think it got lost in
the switzerland raids
um when they shut down shanti and those
different
and stuff and it got lost in holland
during the bust eras
and then it was lost for you know
10 12 14 years
something like that until it just popped
up within the last few
last few and now losing friends fast
over it
everybody's [ __ ] arguing over it real
fast
i mean yeah it's cool that we were that
people are still fighting over
over cannabis made in in the late 80s i
know right
to how good it is and it's you know it's
also not only as a testament to how good
it is but like people want to make money
off it too
some people so if you've got rare and
and you've got rare access and you can
bring some things you know you're
you're you're a breeder who operates in
the market so if you've got something
nobody else does
and you can hype it and it's worthy and
you can you know
i mean that's what all these super skunk
people are trying to do right
right exactly what's going on yeah they
make they're trying to make a bunch of
money before people realize they don't
have what they have
correct and that's that's the jam you
know a lot of people want to sell seeds
or
pass cuts or do this and that and you've
got a good
at a minimum four months three months um
before you're gonna get
any kind of pushback now the other
problem is that i've noticed
when people either invest in buying that
cut or they've invested
um emotionally in that cut at that point
now they think they've got
a really rare cut that's gonna you know
bring some kind of value to their life
however they see fit and um they're now
in that mindset where this is it if it's
not yet i don't have
whatever agenda purpose that i had like
i was saying with the trinity people
would get butt hurt at me sometimes when
i would be like politely that's not it
and they would do a whole thing and you
don't know what i traded to get it
and da da da da da and i'd be like well
you know i'm sorry about all that like i
have nothing to do with any of that but
yeah remains to be seen it's still not
it
it just isn't it you know yeah and so
you know uh it's gotten to a point where
there's a narrow group of
people who had stupor skunk it
you know and some of them had longer
relationships with it than others
and so some of them are a little bit
better at identifying than others
yes exactly you know yeah
without um naming names or stepping on
toes or doing anything like that you
know
we've had issues in the past in the
community
with people that you know are you know
well thought of or respected that verify
yes then once it's verified right
well that's all that's all she wrote
that's it it's verified
you know and then you know i you know i
hit up you know skunk vod or something
and i'll be like what about that
verified cut and he's like it's not
it absolutely isn't it i don't know if
they ever had
it if they think that's it yes right
and so you know like if he tells me if
he hits me up and he tells me i think i
found
it i'm gonna get excited yeah absolutely
because he's
i i tend to think him above everyone
else is gonna
know that cut really really intimately
being that it came from his mentor and
he
worked with it for so long i mean you
know the the fact
the fact remains is that him our buddy
and myself
we cropped it quite a bit for three
years so you do that
you do crop after crop after crop for
that a bit you run anything for a number
of years is your is your main squeeze
you know you learn a lot about it
absolutely uh when my buddy and i were
i mean that's the thing too and you know
we've talked about this before is that
since we bred with it a bunch i got to
see
you know that's one of the things that i
really respect about you know
uh say like uh csi or
archive who i see on here you know um
where there's only so many breeders out
there right now that actually test their
own gear
sure so don't test your own gear you
don't really know
what uh you don't really know what
traits your clones pass
yeah you're never going to see it
firsthand never you don't see
what how they breed did they breed clean
do they breed a mess did they throw
consistent phenotypes do they
you know growing a bunch of growing a
bunch of um
uh oh man uh
truth man someone's asking about truth
band band yeah that's that's a horrible
subject so um but uh
um yeah you know but so we grew uh
you know buddy from staten island and
myself we grew out hundreds
of you know uh dog and and skunk and
other various skunk hybrids
you know and um and we saw what it
passed
you know you see what it throws out you
know and
so a lot of the the various like
semi-proven
semi-unproven theories i have about
certain things we've talked about a
bunch
are just on my observation of like not
very many people
like have had both parents yeah
my buddy myself we're like literally in
like a handful
of people um that probably had both
yeah and we're familiar with both yes so
and all that and so um
you know uh i mean
you know uh the the skunk definitely
seemed to be connected to herms
yeah and the you know when we were doing
the
the superdog stuff if we bred away from
the herms we brought away from some of
the stuff we liked
so then the trick was to try to find
like a minimal or acceptable amount of
herms
yeah or okay like say take the chem d
for instance
yes md herms like crazy at times if it
gets a little test especially in depth
sure you know not as much as indoor but
in depth certainly or if it gets a
little stressed
sure but it's not live pollen yeah it's
not it's not it's sterile
it throws bananas but there's not really
live pollen in those bananas
you know um so then you're looking for
you're looking for
you know one throws herms and has the
stink but doesn't have the danger
inherent in um in all that
you know yeah uh it was a long and an
expensive breeding project
uh because back then uh
you know obviously herb went for a lot
more and it was a lot riskier
um so anytime you dedicated rooms or
areas
to constant breeding that could have
been just some kind of production run
and then you're not even selling the
beans they're just for you and your
friends
um you know but uh
but you know we had we always had dual
stuff like we always had this goal of
trying to like
you know improve the gene pool a little
bit you know
and create more weed that we liked and
so now it's like
most most people's breeding is like take
two famous things that people want
mash them together and then sell the
name
yeah right where it's like we were like
okay like
we we like the skunk smell and we like
the color
and we like the the you know the
quickness and all that can we marry that
to the dog's potency
and feeling and warm happy buzz and all
that is there some
hybrid that we can create that marries
those two things together
sure and so that's obviously the classic
way to breed is you look at two
different things and you're like
i want traits from this and traits from
this to end up in its progeny
yeah right you know and uh so that's
that's really the gig
so um you know it uh
you know sadly it seems like a bunch of
the stuff that got passed it got passed
around in
massachusetts quite a bit more
but it seems like from what we've been
able to determine
that it uh maybe
it the actual cut itself wasn't passed
around nearly as much as people think
maybe in that one maybe bag seed maybe
something different got passed out and
it got called super skunk and it was
from
said dude so of course it's it
and then you're off to the races and
then that thing gets spread around
and then the more you know i mean we've
we talked about this before too
but like you know rez calling his
[ __ ] line
sour diesel yes yes because
they [ __ ] everything up a named cut and
then makes a [ __ ] line out of it
finding the actual named cut once
there's a whole bunch of
of you know yeah other stuff out there
that has the same name
is problematic yeah and it became damn
near impossible
in some cases with that you know and uh
you know and so i mean uh you know
the uh i think
the super skunk has a semi there's
obviously there's some pretty famous
people in the weed community that had it
so that means like some gravitas to the
fact that it was killer
and then they was killer and then it
comes from this 90s historical era
obviously right and you know and then on
top of that it probably
is in a bunch of other things that
people don't realize it's in
right correct and everybody knows what a
rank skunk smells like everybody in
america for the most part is probably in
america yeah
ones you know and all that and so it's a
really distinctive terp
yeah right and it doesn't expire it does
not
you know i mean some people on here know
some people don't but i got lucky enough
and i cracked them and what became known
as the mendo p
you know and what's interesting about
that cut
is that like if that cut didn't exist
there's no other
line that i know of that has those terps
yeah like those terps are in cannabis
obviously yeah they're obviously in
cannabis but it's very unique
the modern cannabis and anything you
find that ends up smelling like that
you discover it was descended from that
yeah
right and so you know um
you know the the skunk knows in my
opinion
really only pops out here and there in
its descendants on occasion yes that's
the mendo perps
yes mendo purple indeed um
so um you know and so it just doesn't
even
it it uh nobody's found it nobody's
nobody's made the terps nobody's found
the terps nobody's
been able to produce seed lines or
cuttings
anytime because if they did it would be
announced they would be it's they would
be at
conventions or you know emerald cup or
whatever with jars
and they would be you know it's a lost
terp that people want back
anyone who can capture that that
terp into a seed line that reliably
produces it and
and let it stay in the bud form is
is going to master it you know so um so
it's obviously
a lot of constituents of it um
but man trying to get something that
really hangs with that smell
past flower is very very hard to do
yeah and and you know and so everybody
ever it's got universal recognition of
what it should smell like
yes there's a whole bunch of fake cuts
that people try to pretend
smell like it right it really
did smell like it you know and so
with it there's no faking the funk
unless you have skunk
oil and you can rub it on a jar i mean
yeah and all
and all that and all that regular it's
it's like it's like the scientific
method right
like if somebody can't grow it and
produce the same smell
it's not there yeah exactly it wasn't
like
you had to do a bomber job of growing it
dude you know i mean
you know obviously in the 90s uh we've
all gotten quite a bit better at
gardening
oh yeah yeah older you get more
experienced you learn more
there's way cooler products that make
your life easier
you know um and i mean we used to mix
soil in a
[ __ ] cement mixer yeah from raw
amendments
yeah yeah all these biological
amendments there wasn't all these like
you know inoculants and booze and teas
and this
and that like there is now it was like
it was like gh
and you know earth juice and i mean the
even just the stuff that you could get
and and like you were and you were just
happy that the store carried
yeah sure pretty limited compared to now
you know
um and so that terp just it just existed
you grew it uh you grew it um
someone's saying about the mendo perps
it is not from the pacific northwest no
think about that question for a second
think about that question
is mendo purp from the pnw i mean you
know it's too it's cool dude any ques
whoever asked that any question is no
he's turpin bird is cool
you know yeah and it really down to it
like most that's the thing right
is that just so you know like you know
matt and i are going to do uh we're
going to
we're going to do a a podcast pretty
soon here
and chat about history and really what
it boils down to for me
is like without the i don't really give
a [ __ ] about fame or rep or anything
like that
most of our history in the cannabis
community is oral
you know passed down from people to
people and there are people
that have heard the real deal and have
verified and cross
verified type stuff you know um
but it can be really hard for people to
come along later or don't have
personal connection to something i mean
[ __ ] spreads like wildfire at times
you know and certain people have vested
interests
in in spreading [ __ ] and so
you know counteracting that with truth
um
and uh you know so
but yeah you know it really is it is
it's an underground it was an
underground
illegal venture and lots of little
individual groups
um you know like passing on knowledge to
each other
you know and it just so happens that
you know like uh the grateful dead uh
and the kids that followed the grateful
dead
um that was probably like the greatest
open-air weed market in american history
at a certain point oh yeah
after them after jerry died started
growing weed
because it kept the lifestyle going and
for a while now it's not it's not true
anymore
you know we're just a segment but for a
minute you know in the 90s and
mid-2000s like almost all the best and
and most famous cuts came from some
hippie or another
some crew you know some related group
and you're only so far removed from all
those people because it's a small world
so you know um
it uh you know most of this stuff
i just got lucky in the sense that
you know i mean you have no idea what's
going to be famous or not
no you don't we're doing like you know
the dog didn't get famous
until skunkva decided to get on forums
and start chatting about it sure nobody
knew who
you know except for on the east nobody
knew who chemdog was nobody knew peabud
was nobody knew
any of these people's names or what they
were involved with or anything else
you know sure and uh you know so it's
like
um you know all this stuff kind of
happens after the fact
you know when right you're just like
you're just kids
we're closing down on this first episode
i don't know how much time you have and
i don't want to take any you got a busy
busy guy with all your family but if you
want
we could start reinitiate it and
continue again for a minute yeah i
actually
my family is grocery shopping right now
so okay perfect time
all right well i'm going to end it i'll
restart the live feed and then we'll
continue on to
kind of like what we're seeing with
diesel and stuff like that word
all right see you in a few
you