what's up everyone so i'm sick tonight
so i probably won't be talking a whole
lot not so hopefully we'll be doing most
of the talking like usual um
but yeah
our riot seedco account got blocked from
going live and i found that out the
second i tried to go live
that's [ __ ] weird but i do get
reported a lot so whatever [ __ ] them
we'll do it on this uh platform and it
may be a smaller show but i don't really
give a [ __ ] so all the people who want
to be here will be here oh
and if y'all look back there
look at that beauty that is a tender
telecaster look at that [ __ ] hey what's
up hey
yeah so oh oh
[ __ ] uh instagram blocked me because
someone's been reporting me i wonder who
i mean uh you're popular
i yeah yeah it could be any one of my my
loyal adoring fans so you know so we can
uh
yeah i mean it it's hard to to uh
um
it's definitely got the potential for
abuse
yeah i mean if
if you want to tell history you're going
to be pissing people off no matter what
you do no matter what you're talking
about no matter which subject it is
because there's always someone making
money off the subject you know
oh yeah there's people that are make
there's people that like
uh what is it the more mystery less
history
yes yes
that's like relationship advice but i
guess it comes into play with cannabis
you know it does it does i was thinking
like
even in ufos dude people go [ __ ] nuts
on each other when they don't
necessarily believe the same exact you
know thing
and and they report each other and they
get real nasty and like dox each other
and swat each other i mean everybody
likes science until it challenges their
assumptions
yeah there you go i mean
you know and it's rare
that
science is going to back you up on
everything that you believe
yeah yeah exactly oh wow we do have 80
people in here so that's a plus it is
like this account being much smaller
it's it's looks like it's popping up so
and it's only been a couple of minutes
so hopefully
uh more people pop on
and whatnot and i guess if if we're
interesting enough we'll have a podcast
on it or something too maybe so we'll
see yeah we'll see how it goes we'll see
how it goes
all right is there anything you wanted
to touch on early on
uh well i mean we kind of like uh we
were kind of going to have a grab bag of
things to chat about today we were going
to talk a little bit
since it kind of ties into what you and
csi have going on we were going to kind
of touch on
a little bit of hawaiian history and
what hawaiian means in general in terms
of cannabis you know yeah um and uh you
know and then we were gonna then there
was something that kind of irritated
both of us about terpenes and some other
stuff that we were gonna [ __ ] about
i think that's right i printed this out
too so so we can you know so yeah you
know um
so not too bad so
maybe what we can do we got 91 people in
climbing so that's pretty positive
yeah um so maybe what we can do is we'll
we'll keep off the the
semi-controversial stuff for a little
bit and we'll start on
we'll start on the on hawaiian right
hawaii
to be hawaiian so uh so hawaiian is
interesting hawaii is a trippy place
because
i believe it's the farthest islands from
a continent
in the world
yep
right
um of of one of the seven continents
it's the farthest it's the farthest
thing and so um there are no
there's not much on hawaii that's native
yeah of any kind anything most things
are non-native to hawaii because it's
essentially a volcanic island chain in
the middle of nowhere
right um
but one of the interesting things about
hawaii hawaii is that
um hawaii i believe is the only american
state that's actually in the tropics
oh yeah that would make sense so like
even even if you go down to like say um
florida like the very southern tip of
florida or the florida keys for instance
yeah those are still considered the
subtropics
yes not actual tropics yeah right what
about what about guam
you know guam isn't a state
that's that's true yeah it's a territory
territory uh and i will admit that i'm
not familiar with all of america's
territories and where they may or may
not be located
yeah i only know that guam people are
called chamorin that's i learned that
because i had a friend that was from
guam and i said he was guamanian he got
real pissed but but i'll say this like
from the perspective that we're speaking
of
if you're doing something in the united
states in the 50 united states you don't
go through customs the same way as if
you're outside of it
yeah
so
um you know we've got this you know i i
don't have it but um they they're doing
some you know hawaiian lights and i have
a pretty old strain from hawaii and so
we thought we'd chat about what that
meant
so there is no wheat unlike most of what
we talk about where
mexican or colombian or panamanian or
thai or african or any of this [ __ ]
there really is no
record of
marijuana in hawaii
um much before
you know
the 60s or something yeah you know um so
there's not like there wasn't really any
indigenous cultures cultivating it there
yeah right
and
so there's an aspect where
um
you know it's rumored uh and they
certainly were involved that the
brotherhood of eternal love
yeah um that was one of the locations
that they used to grow cannabis um
before helicopters flew yeah and
so as a result of that
a lot of the common strains back then uh
mexican colombian that kind of thing
could be grown successfully out there
yeah even today
in hawaii
most people if they want to grow in
hawaii they veg
indoors or in greenhouses with
artificial lighting
because it's it's basically so close to
1212 there all the time
that anything that we normally grow in
our in in our stuff unless it's some
kind of pure equatorial sativa would
flower immediately upon going outside
oh wow i didn't know that
yeah i mean it's it's it's you know i
mean that's part of the reason why
equatorials take so long yeah is they
don't have any like wintertime pressure
where they have to create seed before
they die
yeah it's always kind of warm and nice
and there's not you know you take
afghanistan or hindu kush or something
like that where there's a pretty good
amount of difference between daytime and
nighttime versus summer and winter and
in the equatorial regions there's not a
big difference yeah it might be a couple
of hours
yeah right um and so you might be 12 12
or you might be 13 and 11 or you might
be 11 and 13 but you don't really vary
much beyond that little
aspect
yeah um
so hawaiian hawaiian basically is a
catch-all term for anything
in hawaii
yeah
right yeah uh and what apparently what
used to be grown out there
was some combination of colombians
mexicans ties
and uh
um and then some of that stuff was mixed
with afghans
for structure and weight and this and
that you know and and all that type of
stuff so
um
you know when when for instance like
they were talking about you know the the
stuff that seattle greg and those guys
were getting in the 70s or 80s
that they were mixing with their afghans
they were getting hawaiian
right
but you know that was probably some
combination of colombian thai mexican uh
blended together
and or maybe mixed with afghan
yeah
is kind of is kind of that you know and
so
um hawaii used to be a pretty bomb place
to grow cannabis
uh and then the problem became is when
the helicopter started flying in the
early 80s and stuff um there's not very
much land mass in hawaii
yeah so it's not it
it's not like northern california or
other areas where they just have this
vast area to search through
yeah there's you know volcanic areas
that it's really easy to see if there's
a weed growing there's jungle areas that
are unsuitable there's only so many
you know human area human habitation
areas and so the area they have to cover
is pretty small
yeah it wouldn't be too hard to just
fly up a little bit and see so there was
a big boom in the 60s and 70s of people
growing out there
and then as soon as
the helicopters started flying a lot of
people got a lot you know hawaii kind of
ceased being an export place
on any major level i'm not saying that
it wasn't some of it still didn't exist
but a lot of it moved into greenhouses
and moved on to the edge of jungles it
became really difficult to get off off
any kind of large-scale stuff
yeah because the islands are so small so
when matt did his interview with with
greg i think was the very first breeder
syndicate interview
um
you know he talked about he thought that
the hawaiian that they were using an nl5
was some blend of
mexican and colombian
yeah
was his was his that was his take on it
yeah that was his take some kind of
mexican colombian which would have been
uh pretty common because that would have
been two of the main imports
seeded weed imports that were coming
into america at the time
yeah right
um and uh you know and so i have a small
tie to uh to hawaiian uh not that i
lived there or anything like that
because i never did but
um one of the strains that i still have
is we call it the maui
and of all places i met a guy from maui
in the in 94 in amsterdam who had come
out there to
trade seeds with some of the breeders
out there
and we shared a joint and stuff like
that and i was with some friends and he
gave us a small handful of seeds
and uh one of them became the maui
so they have truck stops in
hawaii is what you're saying
so or i'm in amsterdam i mean so they uh
they i mean they have a whole district
district you know they don't even have
they don't even call it they just they
just it's very much more open there so
um and so being 19 or whatever the [ __ ]
i was i asked zero intelligent questions
of this man
uh i thought he was a super old-timer
which he was probably about my age he
was probably mid-forties but to a 19
year old yeah he seemed a grizzled
veteran yeah i'm sure you know
and that trip i spent thousands of
dollars on seeds uh and the only thing
that i ended up keeping was this female
from a handful of seeds that he gave me
when we shared a joint
wow
it was pretty much all the dutch stuff
out of all the dutchess that that
particular trip uh which was was one it
was my it was actually my first trip to
amsterdam believe it or not in 94. um
that particular trip um i didn't find
anything that was a keeper amongst the
stuff that i bought initially do you
remember what you bought i bought all
kinds of [ __ ] yeah i bought nlf i i went
to scentsy
in 94 and i bought nl5 haze
i bought nl5 skunk one
uh i bought um
super skunk yeah um
from them
um you know i bought some uh
you know i i
i think i bought some bubble gum that
year
yeah um i bought i bought a a random i
bought some stuff from maybe dutch
passion
anyway i was stupid um and instead of
buying well i was 19 right so instead of
buying like three or four things and
buying like you know 50 seeds of each
thing yeah i bought like 15 or 18 things
and like one or two packs of each yeah
right so then you like crack a pack and
it's ten seeds and you get four females
and you don't like any of them yeah and
i was that wasn't at the era i was so
young then that wasn't at the era where
we were like keeping males or breeding
or anything like that right
um so that's the other thing too is i
got that maui and we tossed all the
males because they were [ __ ] useless
right what are we gonna do with those
you know um
but uh but so hawaiian hawaiian is
definitely
you know in that it's kind of it's in
the lexicon right
and you know someone just said oh maui
wowie uh maui wowie was is kind of like
matanuska [ __ ] or this or that or
whatever it's a catch-all term
it was
it was originally
made by a guy named eddie from the
brotherhood of eternal love so there
really was a maui wowie at one time
unlike madness of [ __ ] we can't
trace it to one person but that one we
can but what has become maui wowie i
think most of what we see is maui wowie
are mostly afghan dominant types yeah
and they
um you know they used to uh they used to
ship
uh some of that stuff in macadamia nuts
oh wow they did they used to ship it to
the states they used to hide it in the
center of macadamia nut tins yeah that's
funny and stuff like that and so
you know hawaiian was sort of a was sort
of a catch-all phrase there is no
indigenous hawaiian
yeah right it was all basically
entrepreneurs bringing other indigenous
weed to hawaii and trying to figure out
how to get worthwhile buds
is basically what it boiled down to
um and uh
you know what's interesting about like
the the hawaiian that i have what we
call them and the only reason why we
call it the maui
is because i was dumb and i didn't ask
any [ __ ] questions so
uh the only thing that we knew was the
dude was from maui
yeah
um but that's it right i met fast eddie
i doubt you met you met fast eddie um
because uh the fast daddy that you
probably met was a very famous dude from
dead tour
uh
who is part of the wrecking crew
uh maybe you met fast betty from the
brotherhood of eternal love but around
but i yeah i've never been able to get a
hold of him i've tried a lot but the
fact the fast eddie that most people are
familiar with um is from the wrecking
crew he was he was a pretty famous uh
person on he goes yeah that guy it was
it was a pretty famous dude on deadlock
if you went to dead tour uh on any level
um you probably heard him be like doug
says he had the deepest voice dow says
he would scream at little kids and stuff
and they were all drunk and they were
just a mess but anyway
um
so there's an aspect where
uh you know so that's hawaiian hawaiian
is anything that got brought to hawaii
and got grown there
yeah basically right yeah um and then it
just gets the name hawaiian and just
like a lot of like we've talked about
this before but just like a lot of stuff
where it obscures like we give nicknames
to things and it obscures the origin of
where it came from yeah that's what
hawaiian did
you know seattle grey got hawaiian
which isn't very helpful
did he get pure mexican pure colombian a
blend a blend with afghan
he didn't know
yeah they they said he could tell was
after uh mexican colombian because the
best we could tell was mexican colombian
you know and so
you know um
and so that's what got blended in and
back then
especially you know nobody knew that all
this stuff was going to be famous and
lineage and all that was going to get
poured over and be super important right
yeah and notes were a bad thing
so it is like saying oh i got the
californian
there was a california indica that made
it around the answer i got i got the
californian you know it's about it it
like gives you an idea of where the area
was from
right
and so
um
you know what's interesting is that
being that i'm not from hawaii and i
don't really have any ties there um
i do have we i do have some good friends
that grew up on the island on various
islands and grown there their whole life
yeah and when i showed them um pictures
and flowers of uh my maui cut they did
say that there was that wasn't that
uncommon of a phenotype that they had
seen in the past in hawaiian that they
had grown from the past
yeah you know um so hawaii is sort of
like a catch-all from people get stuff
you know i mean like like there was even
a thing we were talking about a couple
episodes ago during the chem dog episode
where
um there's a maui dog
yeah why is it called maui dog because
someone got a supposedly a dog bud seed
and took it to maui
yeah popped it on maui and now it's maui
dog
you know so the interesting thing
there's some pictures of maui on my page
it's really interesting it's huge it's
chunky
uh it's pretty short it's got a bunch of
afghan influence but if you look at it
the leaves are incredibly skinny and
double serrated
yeah
there's this asp
um
is my audio kicking out
it's just on my back off from your
video
kinda i mean we can hear you but it's
just off from your speaking you look
like you're in a kung fu movie i look
like i'm on a kung fu is it better now
no wait it'll work
it'll work so sorry that uh sorry that
it's ad-libbed or whatever like i'm i'm
dubbed
uh hopefully that changes but um
but yeah so my maui
uh is you know csi is always looking to
um do things that match right and so in
addition to my headband you know i've
shared a bunch of stuff with him in the
hopes that he would breed it uh and it
would get out to a wider audience a bit
and um one of the things that's going to
get dropped with matt and and csi is
um my maui by the hawaiian lights
i think it's i don't know if that one or
maui by nl5 it might just be it might be
maui by nl5 yeah but anyway he used it
so
um
you know and so there's an aspect too
where it's like
you know uh it's it's been out there
before there's a cut from mandelbrot
called the truth
which is uh maui by superdog that i made
20 plus years ago or something like that
um so it's percolated around and it's
kind of been a mendo it's been a
mendocino county classic
because it's uh probably not now with
the way the market is but for a long
time it was one of those cuts that you
could put outside reliably get four or
five pounds off it and it would be done
in the middle of october
yeah
you know decent that's very decent and
it's pretty i remember i remember seeing
pictures of it i've never uh i don't
think i've ever smoked maui but i've
never seen pictures of it and thinking
it was absolutely gorgeous especially
for an outdoor plant yeah and it turns
purple in the cold you know and stuff
like that and it's it's obviously some
kind of sativa afghan blend because if
you look at the buds and the density and
how quick it finishes it's got a heavy
afghan you know but its leaves are like
that's i mean it's like super skinny
leaves they don't even fatten really
they're just like consistently skinny
the whole way down and they've got a
bunch of double serrations
what's it smell like
um
you know it smells kind of
it smell i mean it's one of those ones
where when i asked oh god let's not do
that yet cause i'll get all irritated uh
it
it's one of those ones where i've asked
trimmers for years and years what it
smells like yeah um and you get ranges
from my favorite is uh you know wrigley
uh wrigley fruity gum
that's a good smell you know um it's got
a super distinctive smell and i will say
jokingly that it's uh i joke that it's
like my longest female relationship
because
we popped that seed in 1994
yeah and i still have it
so she's
uh
28 years this year
yeah [ __ ] old yeah that's really old
it's [ __ ] old and so i've had her
literally i
she was the next to the crystal chunk
um she was the second weed that i ever
really started religiously cropping
yeah um and if you're in indiana or
chicago or illinois area and you ever
smoked the maui it's very likely it's
the same cut
because that's where we cropped it first
and a bunch of friends um grew it out
there and probably still grow it here
and there
you know yeah it's not elite by today's
standards in terms of like the high but
it's probably it's got a good high
but it's it's not up there with the best
of the best in my opinion you know but
yeah it's got a bunch of amazing
qualities and it it's um
you know it breeds really well for for
color and frost and structure and all
that type of stuff
um it's really consistent and
uh it'll probably be another show but it
is blended into some very famous stuff
you know that we won't dive into
um
but
uh all i know is uh all i know is um
where it's from
yeah that's the totality
that's how it goes it was from an old
dude on maui that had been growing there
for a long time and he basically said he
grew things and acclimated him there and
he came over to amsterdam to trade seeds
with friends yeah and he would bring
stuff back and mix it into his lines
so he said it was an afghan that
finished quick and yielded well and was
rot resistant and you could see the
you know you could see the the sativa in
it and so
i have pretty high hopes uh that csi
will blend into a few different things
um because it's such a stable breeder
and the other part about it that i
really like
is that when any time you get anything
that's that old
its lineage ties to something completely
different than what's a mishmash of
today
yeah that's true anything from the mid
90s doesn't really have any of the most
famous 40 or 50 cuts that we usually
talk about that's in it yeah
so a lot of times when you're breeding
you get the best results when you start
breeding things that are kind of unlike
each other and not too related
um so it's not related to chem or kush
or this or that or da da da da da da you
know and so it hasn't been overused and
over blended
um
you know and so there's uh matt sent me
a a a thing this morning um about all
the
um
i'm sorry i started reading stuff and
got distracted
but you know we could one day do i we
have some good friends that probably uh
would be a a lot better experts on like
hawaiian growing culture and famous
strains and stuff like that i don't
really feel it's like my place to like
lead a kind of discussion like that it's
not an area where my knowledge goes
hella deep
yeah you know i couldn't talk on molokai
frost like people are asking or quite
electric i couldn't talk on any of that
yeah i mean you know i've heard plenty
of stories second hand i've had you know
i know a bunch of growers uh from over
there and stuff like that over the years
um
you know but you know we could do a
whole episode
uh where people could ask questions um
you know but i we did think it was worth
mentioning we did think it was cool to
talk about because hawaiian is sort of
getting like brought back in because of
this interest in the nl and the nl5 and
what greg was doing and
and you know maybe maybe there's an
aspect of like talking about what
hawaiian was yeah yeah was beneficial
so
you know hawaiian is is sort of and like
what hawaiian was
isn't what hawaiian is that's correct
yeah because what hawaiian was back then
might have been a mix of colombian and
mexican and some afghans and stuff that
the brotherhood of eternal love was
doing but hawaii now
is just another place that clones get
sent right so it's got cherry pie and
it's got skunks and it's got this and
it's got chems and da da da da da and
you know so on and so and whatnot um
yeah it is a cool place in the sense
that there's uh you know it's super
humid there
and um
it's a totally different environment and
so you have to find things that do well
in that environment
yeah you know what i that would be a
good idea maybe we can have paccololo in
paradise on and yeah that's why i just
want to talk about it we have some
resources and some friends that would be
far more educated uh because that's
their neck of the woods yeah to talk
about that kind of stuff than we would
be
i just wanted to bring it up in the
sense that we've been getting a bunch of
questions about hawaiian
and hawaiian lights and
what's what's your maui and stuff like
that and
you know maui is one of those ones where
i even lost it
sadly for a number of years due to some
unfortunate circumstances
um but because it was a classic grown by
old timers around my area in mendo
um it it it lived
yeah because like i said you know there
was you know in in an era where like
weed was weed to some degree um
you know a four to six pound reliable
plant that was done in the middle of
october was pretty beneficial
yeah
so it was kind of one of those things i
brought i brought it out
in 98 or whatever yeah and started
spreading it around
and it's kind of percolated around our
area off and on since then and it's
still around there yeah uh yeah i mean i
still have it i live here
uh there's a few friends that have it uh
it's certainly probably under pressure
with how few strains sell currently
you know and how rough the market has
become and how how low the market has
become recently um but it definitely
still exists
um i gave it to like i said i gave it to
csi
um
to breed with
you know
and preserve help preserve you know it's
always it's always risky when you're
trying to save things you have to find
people that have an interest in stuff
that were willing to hold on to it yeah
right because there could be a fire
there could be an accident there could
be a bus there could be any number of
different things
um people are talking about what's aloha
white widow i don't really know much
about aloha
except for amsterdam except for it was
white widow from amsterdam popped on in
hawaii no aloha seeds was from amsterdam
oh they were
from amsterdam yeah they were a dutch
company and they they made it
and they just called it aloha white
widow so everybody assumed it was you
know a hawaiian white widow
see there you go i even assumed yeah
yeah i just assumed that it was a it was
another one of those things where
you're in um
you know you're in it's it was just one
of those things where it's like oh it's
from hawaii let's add hawaii i actually
called aloha seed bank in amsterdam
god when i first heard about the string
because i wanted to see if i could still
source it at the time um
yeah they wouldn't even talk about what
was in it or any of that but yeah it was
it was their their seed line they
weren't they just weren't interested in
selling it anymore so it's sort of one
of those things where uh soma decided to
call a line new york city diesel exactly
and it's not sour diesel but we'll call
it diesel because it was the first you
know yeah um
so who knows who knows i was mistaken
right there i didn't actually know it's
back history i've never personally grown
it you know
um
so so
i think probably like
99 of people had no clue that it was
aloha seeds amsterdam um it's just it's
just how it's always gone everybody was
a aloha widow of course it would be and
that's that's one of the things that
matt and i always talk about where it's
like
you can make misleading statements and
not outright lie
and then people will just assume
yeah
exactly
these genetics are authentic
by the way i i was super stoked a long
time ago i made a joke about how you
could rename blueberry or blue dream and
call it blueberry [ __ ] yum yum and
someone would probably buy it
i just today saw a string called
blueberry yum yum taken off oh man damn
hot damn
called it
oh somebody's talking about ncga
rock 10 rock
you know so yeah i mean there's the
the the name game and then creating
assumptions based on that yeah
you know i mean
20 years ago if something was
was named after some kind of smell or
aroma or whatever it probably had some
kind of distinctive
remembrance of that yeah
now it's it has no connection to it
you know is it a ludicrous song i call i
pull blueberry yum yum out my ass but
goddamn it's hard being original
i wouldn't have known that it's very
hard being original so
yeah i mean there's there's aspects
where
you know hawaiian um
uh you know it's probably going to
remain a mystery and when any time
anytime you have like a mystery
right that's hard to be proven
you're going to get people that are
going to claim that they have knowledge
yeah and they have facts behind the
rumor and it's like oh well you might
not have had the hawaiian that went to
greg but we did
yeah that was my uncle
yeah yeah
my uh that was my dad that was my uncle
that was my that was my dad's best
friend that was my you know my aunts you
know my my aunt's boyfriend whoever you
know because you can't
really refute it and that's really
popular in cannabis
um is
being able to not refute things well i
mean you saw just just in this episode
just in this
20 minutes or whatever that we've been
live you saw one person coming here
ask for an opinion because they weren't
sure and then flip out because it was
counter to what they wanted to hear
i missed that part
i'm not very good at patting my head and
rubbing my stomach so i ignore a lot of
the comments not because they're not
valuable but because i i have a hard
time like
bullshitting
uh and reading at the same time yeah you
know my brain
my brain was in here repeatedly asking
about someone non-stop
and then asked about someone that
referred him to that person um someone
from virginia that dude so i was just
like dude stop yeah i mean i don't know
there's and there's aspects too where
it's like sometimes people make a really
good assumption that like this is old
enough and this is mysterious enough
that it'll never be outed oh yeah yeah i
think most of them that do it think that
think that it's old enough and it's in
the past enough and it's i mean we even
saw when i won't even mention their name
but we did this that we outed somebody a
few years ago
um that consistently had he was a
younger cat and he consistently had
strains that were from one to two years
before they were ever released
yeah and you could just tell that they
were just hunting on the forums for
early info yeah and then they figured
they'd they'd ratchet it back for a week
a year or two
and then they didn't realize that there
was people that were actually alive and
in cannabis then
yeah you know
um
yeah he didn't even that dude didn't
even go look at the catalogs to see if
he could get the you're right he's just
like [ __ ] it
i mean
we won't even talk about that but when i
first saw him on instagram i thought
that dude was like in his 50s
he would have had to have been and then
i figured and then i figured out he was
like 27 and i was like what in the [ __ ]
you know no yeah
so you know and yeah there's a thing i
mean there's multiple people that that
have claimed um you know that have
claimed connection to various seed banks
or various people or various this or
that and
you know uh one of the cool things about
the internet is that it's linked a bunch
of us
yeah and so you get a chance to you know
you get a chance to ask those people
and then they're like hell no
yeah
you know and uh
you know and so
you know there's uh yeah it's go hey
someone picked it up skunk 18 fam uncle
fester skunk 18 uh nature fraud
i noticed someone mentioned about the uh
seeds being federally legal and i at
first i was like what
first that's from a source like a single
source and i'm not 100 sure on what they
posted but if if um cannabis seeds were
to be classified as hemp seeds you'd
still need a hemp license you need a
seed distribution license and you'd only
be distributing in your state
so no i think you can send it i think
you can send it out of state but i think
the issue is is that you can't just be
like i'm gonna send my buddy in florida
a bunch of seeds and write
hemp and we're good
no you have to have there has to be
legitimate companies in both states
because
they have to be registered in the state
of california as a california hemp seed
company yes and you'd have to send it to
a registered i use is that how it works
you'd have to be in the market for that
because
because hemp is hemp was put in the farm
bill
yeah so it's um it's legal in all 50
states yes it's not a state it's not a
state by state thing and there's even
there's even hemp transports where you
can transport legal hemp
clones from one state to another
interesting but you
still to this day after working at the
hemp farm i know that they cannot buy
anything not licensed to be sold in
california by a hemp register that might
be a different so yes technically it's
legal but there's but
it's still like you have to have two
hemp businesses it has to be a
legitimate sale between hint businesses
it's not like i'm gonna send a bunch of
hemp seeds legally
we haven't gotten to the point where
it's like tomato seeds or something like
that where it's just like enthusiasts
can just trade whatever the [ __ ] they
want yeah i mean i i just ran through
this and experienced it with uh the
california hemp laws and like register
trying to register to be a breeder of
hemp and stuff like you have to do go
through so many [ __ ] hoops maybe
that's just california too
but you have to go through so many hoops
to be able to grow hemp in california
for sure yeah i mean i'm sure i'm sure
state state by state they can put their
own regulations on it yeah but i don't
believe that any state can make hempy
legal because it's a federally federally
legal on the farm bill it's just it's
not illegal but it's
heavily regulated
and i think what happened is is that all
these people in all these different
states jumped into hemp and there wasn't
a pipeline
for that much cbd or cbg or
hemp products yet
yeah and people are saying
that um
like costco doesn't have a license no
but they're selling hemp that's been
treated with heat that's a whole another
different kind of license everything
else once it's been treated with heat
it's unviable so of course they can sell
that
yeah i mean that's that's been around
forever but yes it has
so i don't know i mean
there's uh but yeah there's there's been
i mean that's one of the one of the
reoccurring frauds
in cannabis is just
like you know since
new people are in every five or ten
years you can recycle the same garbage
over and over again you know sure and
then people get all mad and they start
coming on and defending themselves and
then the people that told the lie first
they start to change aspects of it
because they realize they've been outed
you know and they have to shift what it
is you know
um and it's just one of those it's just
one of those areas that's like right for
[ __ ] yeah you know um and so maybe
maybe i should
maybe i should do like i never do a plug
on here but maybe i should do like a
plug right yeah so
uh anytime you see
like
quote unquote my headband cut or like
when i just talked about the maui or
anything like that like
my entire intention for spreading
genetics is for people to have good weed
yeah so
um
you know
i don't um
i don't
i'm not making anything off of uh
off of cam off off these things i'm not
profiting in any way i'm not trying to
jump into the seed game i've had a bunch
of friends trying me to trying to get me
to uh one of them is on is your is on
your screen right now
um but uh i've resisted you know um and
it's nothing it's nothing against people
that make seed for money or anything
like that because obviously i have a
bunch of friends that do so um but
like part of passing out uh you know
clones and stuff like that to good
friends uh and especially csi is that
he's got enough of a matt and csi and
others have enough of a customer base
that you can get good stuff out there
that's different
yeah and one of the ways that like you
know i've said it before but um probably
the person that probably the person that
did the biggest
guarantee that my mendo perps will never
disappear from the community is caleb
yeah because he fell in love with it and
he
grew he crossed it to a [ __ ] ton
of different things and enough people
bought that that even if the mom was to
terribly get lost her children and
grandchildren are freaking everywhere
yeah
and so that's really if you want to talk
about legacy with seeds um or anything
else you know anytime anything gets
popular like all of a sudden you know
caleb releases um some
some chem d and and l.a
and some and some tk in la right um that
he reversed and people are finding
amazing things in it and now for the
first time ever all of a sudden you
start to see clone cellars popping up
with the cut
you know
um and you start to see
freaking uh and you start to see
um
you know people popping up with with you
know crosses that have it you know
and all that different types of [ __ ] and
so
you know it's just one of the things
that goes along with popularity
yeah you could probably go back six
months and before a year before i
started talking about it and nobody has
it yeah nobody was ever talking about
the la kush headband before
we started talking about it so nobody
was mentioning it nobody was mentioning
it i mean not that it hadn't existed
before and not that it didn't exist with
mandelbrot seeds 15 years ago or
something like that but in the last five
or six years it was it was nowhere yeah
right and so and and now all of a sudden
and really it only got my name i didn't
even want it to have my name
um people were just trying to
differentiate like
how what to call what headband yeah and
so they attached it to it so it's like
people always assume that i'm getting
some royalty or i'm getting some kind of
um you know aspect or i'm getting cuts
or you know payback or whatever and or
they're assuming also sometimes that you
verified said cut yeah that i verified
it and that's why it has it and so
you know there's an aspect to it where
it's like the only reason why i passed
it out to a few good friends is just to
hopefully have people that get weed that
i like a whole bunch
yeah and get that into some hybrids
that's really it just so everybody knows
you know so if you start seeing you know
people pop up on clone traders and this
and that and everything else
it's not like i'm the only person on
earth that has it but it's very very
small circle and it's most likely a scam
yeah at this point you know if it
becomes incredibly popular like
everything else it'll probably leak and
there'll be some you know but
i mean it's really just oh somebody
somebody's finding a bunch of fire i
have that yeah you want it it's 400
bucks
oh i'm breeding with that i got seeds of
it already
i got that yep
and that's the seed name game you know
this is name game and that's it's as far
back as like as people in amsterdam not
wanting to give out lineage just so
their competitors would all copy that
lineage instantaneously
yeah so you know just for clarification
on that like it it it's not and there's
nothing wrong with selling seeds or this
or that or whatever else but it's like
my entire breeding has like not been
that's not been i bred for because i
like good weed yeah
you know
um and i think it makes some people mad
that they can't attack me for [ __ ]
them over or like or breeding hermes
[ __ ] or this or that or whatever you
know and and really when it comes down
to it too is like you know a bunch of
our friends have been talking to talking
about it and it's like if this seed
crash leads to a financial crash for a
bunch of people
it might go back to a small handful of
enthusiasts making seats
and it will be i i really think it will
be yeah because 95 of the people has you
know have gotten into seed breeding in
the last five or six years
with the intention that it could be
another revenue stream and it could get
their name out there and it could get
this and that and
part of the reason why so much stuff
today comes from so few breeders from 20
years ago is because nobody bothered to
breed
yeah it wasn't all that common
yeah because it was there wasn't money
in it yeah there wasn't a lot of money
in it
people think there's a lot of money in
it now but there's only a few people
making a lot of money
yeah there's only a few people and
there's and you know and so there was a
minute there in ig where people could
sell seeds and make their own private
hybrids and like sell them to their
followers and all that and that seems to
be collapsing a little bit right now
yeah um so we'll see in two or three
years how many of those people really
love making seeds and care about
breeding and which ones it was just
another avenue
yeah for revenue
and not that there's anything wrong with
revenue you know yeah nothing wrong with
that
i have seen a massive
the one thing i mean whether people hate
me are like me i haven't gone away and
i've seen a massive overturn since i've
gotten here and i'm i'm expecting a
super massive overturn because i mean
just in the past five years you know
thousands of people making seeds trying
to sell that has popped up and that's
going to get a lot harder that's the
problem too is that since most people
started recently
you know they're grabbing what they have
available to them that's recent
so all this breeding is like all the
same five or six you know five or six
years of the most recent most famous
stuff
yeah and i uh i don't think that you're
going to find anything magically
different crossing cherry pie and kush
no
you know i think that people have tried
that
yeah over and over and over and over and
over
and you know and you're probably not
going to find anything new using
cushmits
no and i'm not even dissing those
strains don't get me wrong i'm not i'm
just saying nothing's unique
to today it's funny to me from it
you know yeah i mean there was there's a
guy commenting there was a bunch of
people that had
the surprising thing about about the
head my headband cut is not that it's
mine or whatever because i didn't make
it or anything but
that
most people won't hold on to anything
unless it's making them money right now
yeah
so there's an enormous amount of stuff
like uh you know 15 years ago i knew
dozens and dozens of growers that had
urkel and grape ape and gdp and green
crack even yeah and green crack and then
as soon as the market changed
six people kept it
yeah there was a bunch of people that
had headband 15 years ago
you know or sours you know yeah i mean i
even had a friend call me the other day
uh who's lifelong
resident of
southern humboldt
and they're looking for sour cuts
yeah because in the last two or three
years everybody
has been um
popping all you know working with all
this candy and all this dessert and all
this purple and all this stuff
and now people are starting to ask for
it again and nobody kept it
it's not like it doesn't exist they'll
be able to get it back again eventually
but maybe they don't get back the same
one
yeah that's that's that's a big deal
that's why a lot of people don't have
vertical like you said oracle was one of
the most grown things up there everybody
that had more than ten lights in mendo
was growing urkel or grape ape or
something like that mendopa they were
all growing purples yeah
you know um and uh you know and then you
know when sauer and kush came in
um
everybody dropped it yep when cookies
came in a bunch of people dropped sours
when this came in a bunch of people
dropped that
and i do think there's going to be a
renaissance of some of those strains
because they're better in my opinion
than a lot of the modern cuts
absolutely
they'll come back they taste better they
work better they're longer lasting they
have more unique eyes
you know that type of thing so i think
they will make a comeback
um you know uh but
you know there's i mean
the my sour that i have i've had this
sour since the very early 2000's i don't
know which one it is
yeah um but it's not most of the one
i've collected a whole bunch of them
um and it's not most of them
yeah i haven't found one i haven't found
one i kept hoping i'm like oh maybe it's
the choco maybe it's the amish maybe
it's the joe b maybe it's the
uh ecsd maybe it's the nycd maybe it's
the
you know yeah um
and uh it's what's really hard is you
really can't tell diesels apart by
pictures
no not no they all tend to look super
skunky you really have to grow them side
by side and you really have to kind of
smoke them if you want to pick out
differences yeah
you know
so
um you know what i know about my sour is
that it's old and that we kept it
and that's about it you know the
headband got renamed sour by a bunch of
people um it got
you know it got tossed around but it was
a little bit more finicky than regular
sour and it could freak out on you
sometimes so a lot of people got rid of
it because it wasn't as easy as the
other ones
yeah you know and and then people get
rid of their cut
and one thing that i've learned is that
if i would have lost my sour cut even
though i have six or seven other
different ones right now
um
it none of them are that one
yeah and there's a bunch of people that
always talk about you know i tried to
get back that thing that i had
and i can't find the sour diesel cut or
the blue dream cut or the gdp cut like
yeah or the trinity i can't get it back
it's like this one's good
but it's not um but it's not it's not
what it is
i um dookie made a good comment he said
the skunk search should start in a sour
s1 and i i agree but i think
the places i saw it the most were when
you crossed two
different expressions of super skunk was
where i was seeing it just constantly
pop up i thought that was but i think
that you can probably find that miss our
s1 i'm it's just you can't make them the
problem is with sour s1s is that like it
fails or you get like 20 seats exactly
that's why that's why i even went with
crossing two super skunks that are that
are different expressions like a sour
and a diesel but i do agree with them i
think that
diesels are modern skunk
yes i think it's one of the most classic
examples of a modern skunk away type
plant that we have
yeah
diesels are modern skunk and the good
thing about the diesels
is that unlike a lot of other things
where you could be like oh that one's
fake or whatever
most of the diesels are pretty [ __ ]
nice man yeah they burn good they smoke
good they have you know they range in
gassy to more headband aromas stuff like
that but grown well taken long enough
dried right
they they work
you know um they work they're good you
know so it's one of my favorite families
so you know there's probably at this
point from my experimentation there's at
least 10 or 12 cuts that are all
different from each other that circulate
yeah of course everyone wants to be like
oh mine's the oldest mine's the original
mine's the one you remember
that's why you should pay x amount for
it
yeah in clone form or in weed form
because it i can try it take take it
back right to 95 you don't know the bros
that i know
except for most of those people haven't
been growing since i mean whatever you
know i just yeah yeah in the sense that
that it's like then it becomes a
you know that's really what it becomes
it becomes a marketing gig uh but
luckily um
you know
they a lot of them still exist and
they're most of them are all good
there's only one or two that i didn't
like very much yeah i liked i liked um
uh your growth the amish i never tried
it before that oh that was that those
couple years that i brought it to the
party it was fire it was dude all the
diesels you grew were flavorful they all
had that mouth coating thing in common
but they they were all super flavorful
outdoor i never really had much diesel
outdoor that was good and that year it
wasn't it wasn't straight outdoor it was
greenhouse so i was a little bit more
controlled thank you it was sun grown it
was sunny
i i dude i'm i'm an indoor grower so
anything that's not [ __ ] pure indoor
to me is outdoor
i mean somebody mentioned somebody
mentioned i'll bring it up somebody
mentioned pips ecsd yeah um you know pip
gave me his ecsd to try
uh as one of my like which one of these
sours is my sour and it wasn't my sour
it's one that i liked a whole bunch and
when he came out to the party that year
um he was like dude i've only grown it
this good once or twice
yeah
you know and i mean some of that's
probably i did a nice job on the growing
it but uh you know sun's real nice light
yeah dude
i love the sun the sun is a great light
so if you get good weather with the sun
and you get warm nice days that go into
late october early november and you can
take that sour late
most people with sour the problem that
became was sour up here is that
as soon as it got the nose people would
cut it
yeah
and it probably needed another 10 days
to two weeks and it's real easy for it
to go from being a good nose when you
cut it to turning complete boof once you
try to [ __ ]
cure it i've seen sour go bad so many
times just in the cure people are asking
what ajs is you know i i don't i mean i
know aj a little bit but
um
you know what aj's was what aj's was in
the late 90s and early 2000s
does not seem to be the same thing that
he has currently as aj's yeah
i'll say that um and it's not you know
and there's even times where i people
are talking about like oh there's like
like names i've never heard of
yeah right like oh now there's the real
sour
now there's that albany sour yeah now
now there's names that like never even
existed during the forum days or
anything like that but there's new terms
that are popping up the real deal
yeah and then people will be like i'm
convinced that this real deal sour is
your headband
yeah and i'm like i don't know how would
i know how the [ __ ] would you know how
would i how would you know you know like
how would you know
you could give it to me and i'll try it
i suppose or whatever but it's like it's
not i i can't tell you you know
um but like i said luckily
most of these cuts of diesel cuts are
real nice
yeah most of them get you nice and high
most of them burn well
um
you know uh
yeah i mean amherst sour diesel
right
[ __ ] i mean he's he's passed now but
mandelbrot made that up
yeah that was my sour diesel that i gave
dawn that he crossed into a bunch of
stuff and he just decided that it was
from amherst and added amherst to it
because that's what he thought i didn't
get it from amherst
you know so
but it sticks yeah albany real the real
sour
that's not a that's not a leading
statement right yeah trying to convince
people the origins which one is it oh
the real one the real one the original
one you know yeah the original original
the real original real
verified
you know actually sour diesel i'm still
actually
yeah and some of them you know it seems
like the choco cut is the same thing as
the ecsd yeah these names are so it's
kind of like kush the names get so
interchangeable
that one piece one person's diablo og
could be another person's sfe
yeah
you know um and and all that you know so
um
you know and and really like when i got
my sour cut uh it came helpfully labeled
sour d
yeah it didn't have any moniker on it
and then i never got i never got aj's or
reza's or choco or ecsd because i
already had the diesel what what is a
plant spanker sour i've never heard of
her never heard of her okay keep going
you know and so so yeah people people
get people get stuff that gets attached
to it
yeah you know whose is it oh it comes
from this dude so it's his who's is it
oh it's this well you know amish got
named it because it came out of
pennsylvania and there's a bunch of
amish and that one was from shroomie and
it's also called shroomies diesel too so
called shroomies diesel yeah you know
um and so there's you know there's
there's a lot of stuff like that where
nicknames get added and subtracted i
don't know what the real deal sour is
i don't know what the albany sour is but
it's like as as more of the story comes
out i would assume that like albany is
just
trying to tie it to manny and
some of the original sour people
yeah and you know what's funny is like
we know the term from vondo that they
called the sour that they all preferred
the manny
and we don't really mention that much
but i guarantee
that someone's gonna pop up with that
[ __ ] manny in two weeks or a
week you know
you know yeah and i i mean there's
and you know and and so sometimes one of
those things just like
just just like the the dog isn't really
you know it's not really you know skunk
va's dog
yeah but he gets on the forums and he's
the first guy talking about it and which
cut is it oh it's the skunk vaca
yeah you know oh it's not so's headband
yeah because you're trying to figure out
some kind of language
to chat about it it's matt riot's
12-inch [ __ ] i get that all the time i
just just because i
yeah that's just the difference between
our measurements and metro and metric
you know
people getting inches inches and
centimeters you know totally confused
totally confused inches and centimeters
but
but yeah you know and no i mean someone
just said hey for the preservation i'm
not even dissing i've known uh skunk va
sin for
20 plus years i'm not dissing him that's
that's not my intention whatsoever i'm
just saying he didn't he didn't attach
his name to it it was it was actually uh
caleb who attached his attached skunky's
name to it
because that was the source that it came
from yeah and it's like so you know
which head you know which headband
you know uh not so headband
you know uh
yeah i hate that one oh my god i don't
even use i don't even i don't even like
that word hate but i really despise the
murder and like the funny thing is like
the 56 day that's what it was told to me
when i got it no six
but it's not 56 it's more like nine
weeks or ten weeks at least someone just
said sun simulator had something to do
with cincinnati later had nothing to do
with the creation of diesel but he did
make some nice diesel hybrids later on i
do agree with that he did a cool
strawberry diesel
yeah loompa headband lumba headband is
most likely a og kush s1 bag seed and in
that case lupa did name that
[ __ ] after himself and he did he
did have an ego boost and name it after
himself that was intentional but
sometimes it's not intentional skunk va
he didn't intend on it and actually kem
dog got a little hyphy about it
because it was like technically his cut
yeah all of a sudden people are calling
it skunk the a's cup yeah you know i'm
kind of embarrassed about my you know
not so headband because
um you know i don't really attach myself
to stuff like that yeah you know i
didn't name it not so's mendo perps
yeah you know or anything like that like
you know i guess you got to have depends
on whether or not you want to have a an
ego attachment to it yeah you know but
really when it comes down to it when you
get back to breeding all the stupid
names all the attachments all the all
that everything else the only thing that
people are going to remember is if it's
good weed
yeah so you are my phone my phone's
getting down to like 10 so let's cover
some of that real quick
all right so there's this thing going
around right now that really irritates
the piss out of me and um there is a you
know they've been pushing all this stuff
with the emerald cup judging
and all that and sc labs has come out
with this new classification
and they're trying to get rid of using
sativa and
indica which that's a different
discussion yeah i agree i agree
that we that there could be better terms
there could be better terminology
applied to that but what they want to
replace it to
um is they and what they're using for
the emerald cup this year is the most
ridiculous [ __ ] i've ever seen yeah
and the reason why is because they have
six categories and i'll try to do them
off of memory
um but
it's
haze jack and hayes
yep
and it's um this probably won't be in
order
uh
og and gas
yep sweet dreams
sweets and dreams sweet and dreams
desserts
exotics
uh what's the final one tropical and
floral tropical and floral right which
are two different and so like that's the
most ridiculous smell and terpene
classifications i've ever heard in my
life exotics what is this what's exotic
i mean do they go off the exotic mic
definition of exotics where runts isn't
exotic well i mean just exotic is like
exotic is something that's unusual to
you
yeah exactly that's all exotics i'd be
like like you know maybe some southeast
asians i would consider exotics or some
wild africans but if you live there it's
not exotic it's common exactly so how
cookies might be
over there what is sweets and dreams
sweets and dreams is the one that makes
them like no sense to me then and then
you know like and then there's an aspect
of okay so you've got sweets plus dreams
and then you've got
desserts
now i get dessert cookies has a
marketing campaign where everything they
name is dessert based yeah so they get
their whole so they have cookies and
they have sherbet and they have flan and
they have [ __ ] this and that [ __ ]
and whatever
none of it tastes like the specific
dessert
exactly it's just they have a theme
yeah right uh i will say that cookies
the original thin mint uh which they
can't say anymore because uh girl scouts
sued them um but
it did have kind of a doughy flavor
yeah i don't get that from any of it all
i taste is og but i know people do do
get that from it so it's it's also like
how you smell how you taste yeah
different things i mean i can at least
okay it's got some kind of doughy type
aroma to it you know that some people
but what is exotics but it was neither
thin nor mint that's right for sure what
is what is exotics what is
what is dessert weed what is dreams what
is dreams what is that even [ __ ] even
like blue dream even jack and hayes okay
so jack and hayes in california
like
um
you know that it's mostly terpenoline
yeah but that's by no means the only
haze aromas in haze
in fact
i would put blue dream in the jackson
haze category more than i would like a
blueberry category but i certainly
wouldn't make a category for dreams
based off one strain but you know it's
like even if so even like all in back in
new york right uh where there's a bunch
of haze cuts that are still pretty
famous and kept
yeah you know they don't the the best
ones they have back there aren't
terpenoline they don't smell like jack
they smell like frankincense they smell
like church they smell there's a variety
of smells
so
hold on i'm going to respond to one
thing
someone said they are leaning into
genetics no they're not and chemovar
this is not based on chemo bar which i
think is important and i appreciate the
effort in advancing the discussion the
thing is this discussion was already
advanced past indica in sativa and
hybrid long ago
and it's it's only the people that
aren't very well read on the subject
that are still there and they're still
there which is so it's been realized
just so everyone knows that when you're
judging at the emerald cup all these
jars are labeled and no one has any
supposedly has any idea what they are
yeah
they're supposed to just just blind
smoke and guess and smell and look and
share it doesn't come with oh this is
white runts from xnx farm
yeah it's just sample number 148.
yep you know and we're going to name
does this is this dessert to you
is this dreams do you feel dreamy when
you smoke this yeah is this dream that
that still blows my mind because i you
know even the even the even the og even
the og and gas it's like with nog
there's piney
there's earthy
there's so much depth in og itself and
you can't just combine
diesel and kush
into the same category as gas eogs what
yeah what about what about the the like
the irene ones that are more sweet
cereal oh geez like
ones that are like lemony and pine soul
yeah and ones that are straight earthy
mouth coat
yeah um so really to me i'm not trying
to to diss them or whatever but it it
really is a step backwards and i really
don't want that kind of language to
start being used um because you know
what the [ __ ] is dreams
yeah what the [ __ ] is a dream yeah the
thing my point was like i i agree in
advancing the conversation because i do
not think index indica and sativa and
hybrid are accurate however
someone already did that but like
someone pointed out merlin and and clark
came up with the broadleaf dominant
narrow leaf drug i'm sorry broad leaf
drug type narrow leaf drug type and um
from there i mean you you know you can
classify it any other way but those bld
and nld
yeah the ld and nld is a great way to do
it because it doesn't talk about the
high type it just talks about this the
outward expression and maybe we should
you know we're planning on having uh our
buddy crybaby come on uh one of these
shows and we're gonna have like a
terpene and an aroma episode uh because
he can probably talk more intelligently
about those kind of things than we can
he's got a better language
but really what this is it's about
communication and language so
when we're talking about our eyes
it's really easy to be like this is
periwinkle or this is burgundy or this
is orange or this is and you can be like
yes that is we can both see it but when
it comes to to nose right
other than sour
bitter
dead
salty there's only like five or six
things that you actually taste
right yeah and then the rest is
impressions so people will be like oh
this smells like pencil shavings or a
fresh car
or it smells like you know something
common like oranges so you don't really
describe the smell
you describe something else that it
smells like
yeah but but that classification what
the [ __ ] does dream smell like
yeah that's
what is what does a great smell like
yeah you know what used to be exotic in
europe pepper
yeah that's true huh yeah spices
from the far east they were exotic
you know you can have exhaus exotic
dragon fruit but if you live in hawaii
it's probably not exotic
at one point you know mangoes were
probably exotic
what is oh yeah yeah
have you had those before
i know i remember yeah fresh vinyl
linoleum you know new car smell all that
and so there's a whole bunch of those
things where it's like it's really
difficult to have the language to talk
about smells with people
and
i'm bad at it and you know and i always
i always when trimmers and stuff like
that i always try to ask them away from
the rest of the trimmers what do you
smell when you smell this wheat
yeah
and try to get a bunch of different
people's feedback and then do i see
things that people keep talking about
yeah is there a commonality that you can
pull out of their impressions
because not everybody has the same
impression like for instance how would
europeans know roadkill
yeah right there is no roadkill in
europe
no no roadkill skunk no roadkill skunk
but that's what they mean when they talk
about roadkill yeah roadkill skunk i
should have been more specific but it's
like you're not american there is no
you've never smelled a dead skunk on the
side of the road yeah unless you came
here yeah um so you know there's an
aspect where it's like i looked at all
this stuff and you've got all these
judges this [ __ ] don't
understand the concepts of monoterpenes
try terpenes sesquiterpene shut the [ __ ]
up we don't you obviously don't
understand the discussion
so go back
you can talk about terpenes and you can
talk about individual terpenes but like
the language around how those terpenes
blend into different aromas
yeah you know like just like there's
there's only so many primary colors
yeah and you know terpenes you can
combine two different things and have
them smell the exact same way no matter
what terpenes you're using you know like
you there's certain ways to make
strawberry smells and there's other ways
to make strawberry smells that are very
similar that two people could smell as
strawberry but the problem is it's not
it's not a terpene conversation in that
sense the level of the level of
education amongst people to discuss
aromas in cannabis is very limited even
amongst the educated yeah it's a limited
conversation and so i don't think it's
advanced by and they're all pushing oh
my god we're breaking barriers and
here's how we're judging stuff and we've
got different colored stickers to put on
jars whether it's dessert or whether
it's haze or whether it's exotic
yeah and i just think that's a joke
yeah i think the categories are not
related to reality
yeah
you know and it's not dissing them
you know no it's not dissing them i mean
if anything it's probably dissing sc
labs maybe but it's just it's just
another way to try to talk about
language and talk about classifications
um
but it's not accurate it's not helpful
most weed before cookies nobody said
nobody was like oh my god all this weed
smells like desserts yeah i this is like
this is flan at my favorite mexican
restaurant to a tea
i just exhale flan
no yeah i just exhale strawberry
shortcake no
yeah
you see but yeah yeah
yeah i think that'll be a good episode
with crybaby too yeah he's way worse
knowledgeable about
that the language than i am
he's got he's got a much deeper base of
talking about the language and the
terpenes and stuff like that you know
yeah
so we're gonna do matt's phone's gonna
die i got some stuff i gotta take care
of and whatnot so we're gonna do a
little bit shorter normally we try to
take it to like an hour and a half two
hours every friday we're gonna cut it a
little short uh today for a variety of
reasons um but we just kind of wanted to
do no matter what we wanted to kind of
bring people together on friday night
[ __ ] about different subjects with
cannabis give people things to talk and
think about
um and so matt if you want to do any
plugs
oh yeah um
go to
google
type in breeder syndicate patreon
if you want to join the patreon we have
our discord where we talk about all this
stuff
incessantly because we're [ __ ] nerds
that's what we do and it's what we love
to do
um
uh we got our hawaiian life stuff
dropping and of course i did not take a
picture of all the hybrids like i was
going to and print out but there are
some really awesome hybrids that uh csi
did with the hawaiian light stuff and
that's going to be dropping probably
this weekend but expect to see some old
rare [ __ ] in there including the the
bomb threat bubba which hasn't been
released in ages in any hybrids no
that's not good
yeah that's a [ __ ]
i've grown that one myself it's a fun
it's a fun one
yeah um but anyway you know and you can
always reach out to us you can always
give us you can always hit us up on
instagram or or on discord and give us
ideas hey i'd love for you guys to talk
about this i'd love for to learn more
about whatever we're super open about
that we just want to
[ __ ] on a weekly basis about
cannabis and keep people interested so
yeah thank you so much
uh right teaco.com hawaiian lights f2
open pollination is up right now and
tomorrow are the fights for those of you
on the discord we're gonna get together
for the fights uh it's gonna be
major awesome ones so yep cheers
everybody have a great night
you