so
what's up everyone
i almost did the show on the other
account because it's back up for live
feeds but i figured i already told
everyone we'd be doing it here so [ __ ]
it right
um
the last time you'll be seeing this
background we're getting ready i mean
we've been
moving but
um finally moving the last of this stuff
probably this weekend so it's gonna be a
whole new background whole new
everything no more ugly [ __ ] checker
wall which is awesome
um
yeah
so what's up everyone
yes i i play this guitar sometimes this
is one that has
um
special pickups and it's uh
what do they call them
um
seymour duncan
p rails
i think yeah
what's up reuter
to cramp
everyone um we will be joined by
uh csi and
not so dog in a few nats has been a
little under the weather so
i'm going to try to hold it down for him
this week
uh
he's got the chest aids
so yeah
you'll miss the ska wall yeah it's an
ugly ass wall though
want my choice
but
next one will be
so we'll see how it goes
sweet [ __ ] work
so rob
oh yeah i got my crummy shirt on
the man admit the legend
no i actually really suck at guitar to
be honest with you i can play punk rock
and
old reggae tunes and some northern souls
that's about it
how much is rent out here the place i'm
leaving was 3 000 a month
where i'm going
uh slightly less because we bought so
it's 2300 roughly a little bit more but
not much
um it's a lot smaller than this place as
far as the house but the property is big
so
kind of stoked on that
tonight we will be covering oh what are
you smoking expels tonight we will be
covering
the forum era post 2006
which really was i mean i chose that
because that's when i come in
so mostly
the tail end of overgrow uh
cannabis world a little bit
uh
i don't remember when planet ganja
dipped out
some grass city troll it up
um
pop pimp trichome kings
the farter
stuff like that there's a seed depot
stuff
yeah i see mag of course
there's a big point to it too and and
it's that a lot of people like that
weren't around during the forums it's
really easy to tell who they are and the
ones that pretend
like they were it's also really easy to
tell that they were because or that they
weren't because they only reference the
ones that are still up and only quote
the forms that are still up which is a
very very
i can't i can't mention that one sub rob
since it's private i don't want to
mention it
try to follow rules on that one but um
yeah i mean
people try to quote stuff all the time
but you're only seeing
a brief glimpse of what happened back
then some of the most salacious [ __ ]
horrible [ __ ] went down on sites like
sea depot where
a lot of people started popping up a lot
of people that are selling seeds started
popping up on seed depot and i'm sure
they are super stoked that you can't
find that [ __ ] but we do have the
wayback machine and i actually haven't
tested that for seed depot so we'll see
yeah uh ganja plantage was on um way
back machine as well but
uh only certain
threads were it was really hard to find
any consistency in why certain things
were or not
oh here we go there's not so
see
i wonder if i can still bring in caleb
once i bring in the best
we got to teach you how to do that let's
see how long request to join
but how do i add in people
bobby
invite to join okay that's right all
right
what's up dude
i i exist
you know you look like you're not dead
yet i am definitely not dead good deal
good definitely not good i'm in need of
a haircut
that's what that's [ __ ]
so
what's up with the third party uh
waiting for him wait we're waiting for
him for a few minutes i just talked to
him he'll be on
fantastic
yeah so i was just telling everyone
we're going to be going over the forum
era post overgrow so 2006 roughly and on
and uh i was explaining how there are a
lot of a forum still up that were around
during that time like the farm
um
i see mad
troll it up some of the some of the
others that came around that time
um but there are a lot that are not up
and people that like to pretend that
they were around back then
often reference the ones that are still
up that they can go back and like reread
and pretend like hey i was i was there i
know what was going on but they're
missing like 90 percent of the
conversations that were going on because
those aren't even accessible any longer
one of one of the things i notice about
that era
is that
you know a lot of times we catch people
on stuff
because people go back to [ __ ]
yes and they read
uh you know threads and things like that
to pick up years and tidbits and
information that like make their their
story sound better yeah but they weren't
there
to know
who was who or like who to take
seriously or what was misinformation
even then
yeah you know and so a lot of times it's
a tell
you know it is a big deal it's a big
tell but to someone that never read any
of those forums you can come out and
confidently
start jabbing about a bunch of stuff
yeah and sound like you were there
yeah um
not i'm not gonna say anybody's name but
uh someone made a post the other day
that obviously was not around on the
forums
and said you know
x person got cloned from y person got
cloned from z person and it was just
super off like the most
off it could be i mean
that's learning from me i try we try not
to name names when it's not but it was
pretty funny the chain of custody
yeah that was asserted
you know you you just had you just had
to laugh at a certain point but yeah i
will say even back then
like
uh
you know
i don't know exactly how to describe it
but i would say that like
like overgrow even had some of the best
commentary
but also some of the worst
like you kind of the forums really
helped figuring out what you were doing
if you already went in there with some
connection and some ability to discern
yeah you know cannabis world was a
little bit more like where the adults
gathered yeah uh over a girl you could
have like
everyone from like some 17 year old kid
[ __ ] posting you even though we didn't
use that term back then yeah to like
camara and sam skunk man and phds and
breeding talking [ __ ] in another in
another area
yeah so it really was like a
cross-section of weed in america
my main my main thing would be like i
would compare that to like grass city
from my era grass city and um roll it up
we always called it troll it up but
those two were like what everybody would
say like that's where everybody
everybody had an account on those pretty
much because that's where everybody
started during that era and then slowly
you'd see people migrate but then those
the ones that hung out in that area area
kind of never really seemed to go
anywhere as far as their knowledge or
making any headway with anything really
that's how i saw it yeah i mean and you
know it should be said too that like you
know there was different different
forums had different
i don't know different ethics maybe is
the best way to put it yeah you know
some some were more lightly moderated
and things got left up um you know
obviously like hate speech and and
various other aspects was was eliminated
um you know or but a lot of times you
know unlike ig or whatever um you know
if you didn't like the threads got left
they might get locked if arguments got
too heated but they would typically be
left
yeah where in today's environment on ig
a lot of times people just
get rid of it
yeah oh yeah
it's all
it's all uh what do you call that
curated it's all curated as soon as it
starts going off the rails or as soon as
they start seeing information they don't
want out there yeah um they'll just
delete comments or they'll delete the
whole thread or they'll turn off
comments yeah right away
um you know and then you know i see mag
you know there was you know there was an
in crowd and an outcrowd
mm-hmm
you know definitely that was the
outcrowd
i think i had a record uh for being the
person most banned from every forum and
it it i think i mean i even had my own
forums back in the day that people
rocked on you know it was it got bad i
mean it was interesting in the sense
that like in the beginning in
overgrowing cannabis world and stuff i
was super excited and i got on there to
share information with uh with a bunch
of people
um and then you know but i was always
nervous about doing any kind
like you know i lived in mendo or
whatever so i didn't really need to like
meet new weed people yeah but i liked
learning what other people far away knew
yeah but a lot of people used it in the
dms to trade clones and do all this type
of stuff i never really did that i was
more like an in-person kind of kind of
guy yeah um and then when obviously when
heaven stairway got in trouble and they
shut all that down yeah i got scared
so
um you know this era that we're going to
talk about like 2006 on it really is csi
and matt's
era
yeah
it really is where you know i might have
been lurking a little bit and poking
around here and there
um and even some other friends of ours
that aren't going to join like uh our
buddy hi and lonesome oh yeah yeah you
know there there was some people that
were that were extremely active in that
area sure and know a lot of the the who
you know who was who was a jackass who
who was kind
uh who was a problem back then
you know where stuff came from
and one of the interesting things about
weed is that it reinvents itself every
five or ten years yeah
so
you get all these new people coming in
and people get to rebrand themselves
yeah now it's happening every six months
it seems yeah well it's modern fast
turnover yeah modern marketing
i mean i mentioned that i mentioned this
before but it was kind of like what the
uh what the old deadheads told me about
how dead tour used to be before the
grateful dead had touched a gray a big
hit
yeah where it was small
everybody knew kind of got vetted in
you know things didn't change that much
and then um you know
oh my god big ups to daniel okay so then
and then
and then there was a top they had a top
10 hit
and literally hundreds of thousands of
new people showed up
yeah and how do you assimilate them into
your community that fast yeah
really yeah
you know it becomes difficult so a lot
of times like old-timers or whatever
they feel overwhelmed
because like the norms of their
community and what they could expect you
know and instead of being like a
respected elder somebody's like who the
[ __ ] is this guy
yeah why do i have to listen to you
yeah
you know where before when it was
smaller like those people might have had
respect
yeah
yeah it's a much it did get very
different and i want to say it wasn't
quite at cookies where everything took a
big swing but it wasn't much long after
cookies came around that that the forum
the whole idea forms kind of changed but
i think that also had to do with
instagram which is also why cookies kind
of even got even more blown up i think
uh social media
um yeah
the kind of the difference between the i
would say the forums
were
mostly writing with some pictures
where instagram flipped it 180 degrees
to being it's almost all pictures with a
little bit of writing
yeah so you see some of these old
write-ups that people have and their
paragraphs and you know they're like a
small essay
yeah right where people ask me stuff all
the time on ig and it's really hard
because it's like what are you going to
write a novel in the comments
yeah yeah it's kind of like you're
trying to write something that's like
this long like what can i yeah it's like
a haiku yes how can i get my my thing
across in like x amount of syllables or
four sentences
yeah yeah you kind of have to especially
if you're on twitter right and then and
then you end up and then you end up
leaving on a lot of nuance in detail
where on the forum era people could like
write three or four paragraphs each back
and forth
and some like kemke could write really
really just
bad really bad
un illegible stuff for paragraphs and
paragraphs i mean when you write
paragraphs you really realize why we
invented punctuation yeah for sure you
know why we invented paragraphs in the
first place spacing periods commas all
the various aspects it really helps
because
yeah you know one one of the things that
hurts you online is that um nuance gets
lost yeah it does are you being
sarcastic
yeah are you being funny what's your
body language
you know all those types of things
you know um yeah that was actually a
good point uh you know in the overgrow
era digital cameras
um you know didn't exist
yeah
i mean i was talking i was actually
talking about that in the
in the one that you missed because you
were you know you were otherwise
occupied where it was like
people documenting their stuff really
advanced a lot more when digital cameras
came out oh yeah and then exponentially
once uh phones had cameras yeah once
phones had cameras it was all bets off
the era where you had to get your own
stuff developed
that's unsadly it's not oh yeah i can
only imagine it's not very documented i
mean i was at i was at csi's house i
don't know half a year ago or something
like that we were looking through a
couple of boxes of his um
uh polaroids
right yeah but they fade
yeah that cat sucks
you know and maybe if he would have kept
them in some kind of like
perfectly sealed environment with the
right humidity or something like that
you know but yeah you're looking at
polaroids from 95 or six or seven or
whatever and a lot of them the colors
are bleeding into each other and it's
hard to make it's not
it's not you know it's not shark
yeah
you know yeah that sucks that sucks bad
i would have never guessed that until he
told me that yeah i mean you know he's
got a couple shoe boxes full yeah and i
was busting his chops to get him [ __ ]
scanned i was like you got to get those
scanned at least for history he's like
don't do any good
i mean i you know i had my i had my my
uh my first daughter in 09 you know and
i think and i can look back on my phone
i think you know the first real camera
on an iphone came out no 8.
oh wow yeah i don't remember yeah laid
out late08
you know and and that's kind of that
that was a revolution in itself
oh i'm sure because now you can just
pull it out of your pocket and be like
there's my weed plant click
it's always amazing that with all these
cell phones we don't really see many
like real documented ufo pics i know i'm
it's kind of off tangent but i just
thought about that
well i will say
as a as as a you know somebody who's
pulled a lot of tarps in their day
that you know a lot of times when you
pull tarp on you you're doing light
depth you're you're pulling tarp at six
or seven o'clock at night right yeah and
then you go back out there after dark
which in june might be 9 30 or 10
o'clock at night
right to pull the tarp off so everything
can breathe because you only want to
darken it for as much as you need to
right oh yeah and you don't want to trap
in all that moisture and all that right
so you got to go out there and you know
mendo or whatever in the woods
and sometimes i would see the most
beautiful skies the most beautiful moons
just yeah and your phone could not show
you what my eyes could see oh yeah for
sure i would take i would take you know
pictures
and you know and it would just never and
i'd go online and look how do i take
better night photos
yeah and it's just not a camera with
like a nice lens and you know the
ability to like
you know it's just not it's just meant
to show dicks and tits that's all you're
supposed to be taking pictures of fellas
ladies you know and yeah and so you know
there's there's an aspect to that where
it's like i can bet like if you can't
see like nobody can imagine how
beautiful this full moon is tonight
yeah and you can't capture that well
how are you gonna capture like i'm sure
there's like this is that there's a
weird thing in the sky it's yeah
how are you possible
you know especially back in 089 how am i
going to pull out my two or two and a
half megapixel camera yeah on my phone
yeah i'm gonna like capture it
no
you know it took a long time for
phones to even begin to catch up to like
what 35 millimeter could do you're
busting my skeptical comet not so
know crushing my skepticism
i fully believe that there are aliens
i just disbelieve most people that tell
try to tell me a bunch of facts about
them yeah yeah that's what i'm sure
there are i just don't know if they've
ever been near earth you know like i i
have i that that's where my skepticism
comes in when people start writing
getting like very long youtubes about
all kinds of specifics you know yeah
i get weird
yeah yeah i mean
i'll say this you know and then caleb
and then he's officially [ __ ] late
yeah but um
you know when we were talking about the
the early the early 2000s or whatever i
you know i did that whole episode when
you weren't here
yeah i was hunting so hard for old stuff
then stuff from the 80s stuff from the
70s hell even stuff from some of the 90s
yeah and it was a royal [ __ ]
and nobody cared about it and i i
searched for years and years and years
and you know like we have a pretty good
network of friends yeah you know and it
was really hard and now within the last
five years
as ancient stuff has become popular
mm-hmm and i'm not please don't take
this the wrong way if anybody's holding
anything but i've never seen so much
like
79 blueberry
72 you know brotherhood of eternal love
acapulco gold you know
74 oaxacan
you know this that like all these 70s
and 80s strain all the famous strains of
your
yeah boom hey
hey it's not dark it's just blurry would
you please go he's in that humble fog
you smudge your
camera on purpose he's in that humble
vlog
you know
he blew a load on the camera
but wait the sun's going down so you
know thank you [ __ ] good to see
you dude thanks for showing up right
right
so yeah we were just talking about um
the different you know what was kind of
going around post 2006 it was the end of
the overgrow era end of the cannabis
world era and maybe maybe uh you could
talk about some of the things that you
saw during those those uh that integral
period between the end of overgrow and
the beginning of things like the farm
what kind of what kind of strains were
people [ __ ] with around then what was
the hot [ __ ] uh
are are you talking about like oh six on
oh six to like oh six to oh eight
somewhere in there yeah yeah yeah yeah i
mean i think that's when chemdawg really
started becoming unpopular
yeah
um chemd
came out i i think i honestly think that
that's the year
uh you know
mass g uh posted up on icy mag although
that's right that threat is gone
oh is that threat gone i did my research
i think it's like
is that the the creation of sour d1
no no no that's that was the overgrowth
that was okay
so
yeah that that's well long gone unless
somebody has a archives
yeah
who would have that [ __ ] um
so do you remember like around overgrow
what kind of the strains uh what kind of
strains were mostly popular around that
time like in the in that end of overgrow
era
amsterdam strains
the dutch dutch [ __ ]
yeah how about
a lot of these stuff
yeah bc stuff yeah it was kind of
it was kind of like a lot of the stuff
that
um was at some of those ron parties
yeah yeah yeah right we're actually
where where caleb and i first met um you
know it was a lot of white widow and
blueberry and
um
a lot of the work coming out of
switzerland
was big then so like the sweet tooth the
block head the louie
um
uh genius
yeah you know
and c99 were around back then for sure
genius c99 you know i forget is genius
apollo but you know the apollo 11 and 13
hybrids of all that stuff and it was it
was pre uh pre-reversals
you guys hadn't really started your
revolution yet so
uh it was all males
well uh
i mean we were borderline starting it
yeah it was just kicking off
i mean hype was hype was selling his exc
way back in like i don't know what 02
maybe even earlier
yeah on a cannabis world
and uh i did my first you know
um
real reversal in 06.
the intentional reversal intentional
reversal
i i i did that one reversal where you
know i took a bunch of pollen from that
urkel back in like 304
and uh
yeah yeah that was oh 304
um
and uh
pollinated a bunch of stuff
on purpose
yeah
but that that was just that freak thing
so
yeah now it's canada it can't it kind of
counts it counts it does count it was
with intention
yeah yeah i mean there there there i did
have some friends that i mean we didn't
use i didn't we didn't know anything
about any of the any of the chems you
could spray on plants
but people used to try to torture their
plants
to get them to free if it was if you
knew it can herb
sometimes you could put it into too
small of a pot you could let it get dry
you could beat it up a bit you could try
to collect see if it could throw some
that was like the that was like our way
of
you know right can you beat it up enough
to get some pollen off it remember uh
soma's someone's way you just flour them
out for like 80 or 90 days and get a
couple bananas
yeah wrote
it
yeah yeah
i don't know where he got that term from
for it but yeah i remember
yeah
yeah he's a special guy
actually i did like as when his book
came out or whatever i do like the soma
beds
they were interesting they were
interesting they're just they're just
deep indoor beds on wheels
you know
is basically what they were
um
you know with with you know some
drainage in the bottom and some layering
you know maybe they have some rocks and
they have some like and then they have a
layer of
of uh ground cover or something and then
you put soil on top and
and they have you ever seen
huh
they had the air tubes on them in all
four corners where the air kicked down
to the lower roots you would put like
big pieces of pvc with holes drilled in
and you would put those on the side and
those would go all the way in the
corners to the bottom yeah so that you
would actually and that would connect to
the gravel at the bottom so that you
could bring air
yeah yeah yeah it wasn't the worst idea
no no no
i've done that
and especially for well it's not so much
you had to go trees
you know i mean you know look out look
at look at a bunch of you could you
could actually grow a bed
with it you know homie style with 25 or
30 plants if you wanted
yeah right right right you know and then
you didn't have to worry about
individual ones dying
right right because you just water the
bed and everything stays alive
oh yeah
i used to use those no drain beds way
back in uh
2000 or so i didn't know drink beds
just shallow like six inches deep heads
you know
how'd that work out
i did pretty good
yeah yeah yeah um definitely some
interesting stuff
uh that was back in my not so organic
days
i used to know this used to be pretty
funny where i used to know a lot of guys
in mendo
that were organic like april through
august
and then come august they're like not or
september they're not quite seeing their
buds get as big as they want
and then they figure like well what's
one big tub of pink powder gonna really
do to my organic it's it's basically
organic yeah yeah a little just a couple
a couple doses of this zero 50 30
it's going to get me where i need to be
and it's going to make it happy and i've
been organic for five months already you
know so it'll all flush out at the end
and it's definitely still organic
uh yeah that stuff was tough
yeah
bud blaster
three cheers for grow more
blaster was the was the the canadian
heady version
yeah was it
yeah
it was canadian it was it was it was it
was one of those you know powdered
whatever
it was all this it was all the same
there was a bunch of people that came
out with zero fifty thirty and tried to
make it seem like their zero fifty
thirty was special
all right mono so the one thing i'll say
about the the bud blaster is that
they had a they had their own special
grinder
so their powder was super fine and it
actually dissolved
ah some of the cheap stuff you get there
in like a thousand gallon tank or
whatever and you're up on a ladder and
you're dumping stuff like that in there
and then you get some softballs at the
bottom that you're like wondering how to
hit with a stick to break up
because it wouldn't actually dissolve
yeah you know right so but that's off
topic you know i suppose we should
probably ratchet back around
um
so we got to convince we got to convince
caleb and matt to talk because this is
really their era
yeah this is 0607.0809
this is not my online presence
right so the various characters the
various things that were going on the
the stuff that was happening it's pretty
much this is when these two
uh
you know uh csi used to be known as uh
you know white trash redneck
green inspector
inspector indeed
you know on all those aliases
oh yeah aliases but yeah you know but
that but that's where i mean
you know uh
archive was doctor or the doctor
right yeah yeah
you know it's where a lot of the money a
lot of the oldest nicknames and monikers
uh people still kind of reference each
other like buy some of those first names
yeah
don't know nobody's real name
you didn't need to ain't no purpose in
it
you know yeah and unlike ig you didn't
you never a lot of these people you
never saw
yeah right right my chick always asked
me like
what what's his name i'm like i don't
[ __ ] know why the [ __ ] would i ask
him that you know that's just weird
yeah she thinks i'm a freak for not
knowing anybody's first names after all
these years i mean i don't [ __ ] know
i don't want to do his taxes for the
[ __ ] then you know that for
it was very it was very similar to that
on like on dead door and stuff like that
because everybody you know everybody had
a nickname yeah
yeah
you know
everybody had a nickname
so
um
but yeah i mean maybe maybe you guys
could talk about like you know uh
who who who were some of the big i don't
want to say the word influencer maybe
but who are some of the people that were
sort of like driving the conversations
who were you excited to hear
you know posting on stuff
like and then maybe just like how hard
it was to get information back then
because a lot of these forums
you know you guys were talking about the
chem dog you know there was an aspect
where the reason why you know somebody
like you know skunk va has his name or
chem dog 101 or any of these things is
because
at some form or another on icmag or
whatever it was the first time these
things started getting argued about and
debated
yeah by people outside and a lot of
times
what happens too
is that these things become references
because then you've got
this guy comes out and says this thing
on ic mag at this year
and then three years later on whatever
on roll it up let's say he's saying this
and now on ig he said this and this
you know and they always they always
want to be like this is the most current
story this is what you should believe
yeah yeah and in some cases those forms
don't exist anymore and they're very
fortunate that they don't and you know
one of the one of the ways that uh csi
got his reputation as inspector as he
was really good at at using your own
words against you
yeah
well i just but i just mean in the sense
of someone would like confidently say
this this this and this and then he
would be like well why did you write
in your own words
that bastard this right how do you how
do you make these two things come
together
i've got a bunch of swerve quotes i can
share
oh yeah
you know and and that's a lot of things
most people probably don't even know who
swerve is but there's been there's been
a bunch of people
you know that come that you know flash
in the pans that come and go yeah they
come up they have their moment they they
they spew a bunch of [ __ ] they make a
bunch of money
all of a sudden their stories start to
implode
right
yeah
and you know in some cases they rebrand
themselves
and so it again to the to the new badge
right right
you know
who i looked up to is going to be a lot
different than maybe who caleb looked up
to because when i first started coming
in it was way different than when caleb
started coming in you know so who like
who were you looking up to during those
years or who who is who do you think was
influencing really well that that had
some respect during those years
um
i mean i liked you know
just just for information you know
alone i liked joe brand i liked uh you
know chem dog mass g
yeah
uh
you know skunk va
yeah
and then on like the the og side of
things you know i was i always liked uh
you know big ricky uh he was old family
red back then actually
a lot of people don't even know but
uh i named my old family purple my first
tk hybrid kind of after his old handle
old family red you know oh i didn't even
know that yeah
you know i had a connection yeah i gave
him a lot of credit um
you know chrome that was those were the
years chrome was starting out with the
white you know yeah he actually was
growing some of my my hybrids
um
and then he introduced the white when he
was growing them so yeah that's when
that started um
i i think i was mostly into bubba's ogs
and chem dogs back then
yeah
but uh
what what were your
your main main interests though
so when i popped in you know like shanti
baba
um was still
pretty big and still had a good name a
lot of the stuff i was looking at when i
came in was was dutch stuff i really
didn't focus a lot on americans at the
time because i just didn't i wasn't hit
to it you know i hadn't right when i
came in i wasn't hit to the fact that
all those dudes were white labeling and
most the americans were making their
seeds or spanish or actually back then i
don't even know who was making their
[ __ ] seeds you know right but
yeah i mean
it was very different i mean uh
greenhouse hadn't been totally trashed
it was still kind of under the radar for
new people at the time
that that they were doing anything
you know
untoward dna was massive during those
years
they were why i started doing six seeds
of pack because their [ __ ] was six seeds
a pack and they were the ones selling
the most so i was like okay i guess
that's what you do you know what i mean
right um
yeah and then sub cool of course it just
started [ __ ] taking off and i was
fortunate that i met sonny chiba um very
early on so i learned very quickly oh
maybe that guy isn't someone i should be
looking at for breeding tips you know
right right it took me a while but i got
it but yeah that's it was it was a much
different take yeah
it's interesting then because that's
kind of when everybody first came out of
the shadows
yeah and you could walk out of the
shadows with any stories you wanted
about yourself or the strains or
whatever else and a lot of times you
were the only person
um you know from sam skunk man on
yeah you were the only per you were the
only person telling the story about
those strengths
right right i mean you remember huh
the audience was so small finding people
who are actually there
you know
was was very difficult
yeah it was it was a lot smaller than
now i just don't you think people that
came later can grasp how small the
community was
and how slow information was
now it's pretty rapid fire
right you know and a lot of people
connect all the time
um oh yeah somebody said crunch bubble
you know
uh that guy i mean he that guy used to
move massive amounts of what was it blue
dot
through the third floor in oakland you
know he had all those warehouses of 600
watt
hps's on hydro tables
bumping out a bunch of stuff for third
floor but it was you know what what's
funny about that guy is that some of
those pictures were like some of the
first warehouse scenes that people were
willing to like throw up on ig on on the
internet
yeah
most people were growing in closets or
bedrooms or greenhouses or in the woods
or wherever and all of a sudden you see
a 40 lighter
right and for a lot of people that was
the first time
right
it might look rudimentary now
yeah now but yeah but even just then 0.5
or 0-6 or something like that you know
finding people
and i think too that like what most
people don't understand maybe is that a
lot of the a lot of the breeders like
that got famous later like a couple
people on the show or whatever like
almost all the breeders
were european or american or canadian
yeah right and the people that were
working
breeding in america were generally doing
it through friendship circles
there was a lot of trading and via dm
amongst friends and amongst
contemporaries it wasn't like
like on you know at least from what i
remember it wasn't like oh i've got a
big drop coming next friday
here's the fifth here's the 15. here's
the names i made up for them here's the
hybrids here's where you can get them
here's how we're going to sell them all
it was like you know you trade seeds
when you saw people or people were trade
selling them via dm or something like
that like but
it was different um i remember
as far as americans went there was not a
lot of americans doing direct sales on
websites you would never really see that
like it was all done you know dms or
like on weird little auction sites that
were floating around but other than that
there wasn't a really good way to market
yourself as an american breeder without
mostly giving seeds away to people i
mean did you have that experience csi
i
i didn't get involved in any of i wanted
to back in the 0.608 era
i looked into it but
um
you know i was i was still way way too
paranoid to do any of that stuff yeah
i i should have done it you know like
you know dna and subcool and hell even
swerve you know
yeah
you know uh
i mean all those guys
you know made huge names because there
wasn't competition yeah there was no
competition you didn't really have to
have a whole lot of talent to be very
successful
someone just said mr soul handled all of
sssc in the 80s
well you know so i mean what's
interesting about that is that you know
there's been a lot there's been a lot of
talk about american sssc right
and you know matt and myself got to
interview uh the owner
uh who was very cool and
you know all that kind of stuff got put
to rest
yeah hard the part wasn't there wasn't
any american help no but not for
maneuver but it goes but it goes to show
how you know in our world you can kind
of step out of the shadows and be like
oh i mean there was a lot of people
uh that
you know they came out of the shadows
and they were the first time that people
were like you know oh i'm i this is my
cut
yeah and then it turns out that they
just got the cut early
yeah but they got a few years of like oh
if you want to use my cut you got to
give me 50 of the proceeds of the seeds
or you got to pay me or you got to this
or you got to that it's my work it's my
my my my and then it comes out later
that they just got it from these other
people early but they were the first one
to go public
right you know and a lot of times what
happened is is that the first person to
go public
um you know got credit
yeah
yeah you know um you know they got
credit and their story was the story for
a minute
and sometimes other people would get
upset and get online and start you know
i mean i actually think that's kind of
what got uh you know you were talking
about uh kem that's kind of what got kem
online
was you know skunk va got online a bit
you know and started talking about
different things
and then people were like oh my weed's
famous i should talk about it
right and then that and then that got
that got joe brand and and peabod and
other people that hadn't really met met
up or like even linked or even realized
what was going on after 15 years to
connect
right because stories
707 seed bank uh shaw bud he's the one
who
you know got uh skunk va onto overgrow
and icymag to actually post about that
stuff otherwise
i think there'd be a completely
different chem dog history
oh yeah if he hadn't done that
you know
do we remember what the very very first
claim of the chem dog seeds not
necessarily the first one people
remember but the very first claims of
kim dog who was the first one to claim
that strain was it even greg or were
there other people popping up as it was
getting popular going that's mine i've
read that [ __ ]
i don't remember anybody claiming it
um lots of people claiming they had the
91 or oh yeah yeah sure that there's
just like well
i don't know how all these different
cuts could be the right one
oh you know because it's purple that's
how you know when it purps
i i saw a few chem dog cats and
they they uh uh some of them look like
mass super skunk chem dogs
yeah
but that that just basically means
somebody bought some weed
that
was was called chem dog and it had some
seeds in it and whatever had pollinated
that chem dog
you know kim dog's not a bad
hermaphrodite just by itself i mean not
so nice
you know no and
so usually if you find seeds in your
creme dog you know
it's been pollinated by something else
yeah
well there was there was also a thing
too that was that was really confusing i
think and this isn't anything against
greg or chemdog but you know
it's it's like for people that want
specific lineages
he was pretty famous for when you buy
weed you're buying chem dog weed
from chem dog
it didn't really matter exactly what it
was
it was weed from chem dog and so i think
that created confusion too because
everyone was like oh it's this one
specific thing
you know
um but it really was chem doc yeah it's
just branding i mean back then branding
was branding you know it was it was it
was early it was an early form of
branding yeah for sure
you know
and people weren't and a lot of these
guys were young and nobody knew
especially then when things first
started getting famous
i don't think anybody knew that some of
these strains were going to be so
lastingly famous
so a lot of times they wrote down
various stories or this or that they
didn't really expect it to get
become part of canon or become part of
the fabric of the tale
and then they have to look back and
defend it
you know
um and you know it's hard for people
sometimes to say you know my memory was
a little that's what i remembered at the
time
you know right after more after more
information came out and i talked to
more friends i kind of revised a little
bit because other people had it's hard
for people to say that a lot of times
people would dig in their heels
yeah and then you've got two or three or
four versions of the story and you're
trying to figure out which one works
which one is the most believable
right right you know what what's your
favorite wildest story
um from the forum errors that you knew i
mean you that that you knew was kind of
like that's too [ __ ] stupid to even
be possible do you have any that stick
out where you're like that was a bold
[ __ ] claim and really wonky
what comes to mind when i say that
um okay so
i hate to keep bringing up my boy swerve
it doesn't really have a whole lot to do
with him
but the guy he got pretty much most all
of his early og cuts from in
um
this guy
uh had an account on icmag
and
then he made up another account and i
think this was in 07
and oh he made up another account
pretending to be his own mentor you know
with all the same spelling errors all
the same you know
type styles all that and
he made a whole thread on it and acted
like you know he was the original
creator of the uj kush blah blah blah
and his boy right here his little
student you know he's he's the best
student i ever had
and we're of our boy and we we hooked
him up we laced him with all those those
cuts we've held since the
and then maybe
yeah that there's still that story on on
uh icy mac it's still oh my god you know
and i'm i'm up in there with a bunch of
other clowns just laughing away
you know but that that one right there
was it was pretty much the tops for for
me back in those days
i got one for you i got one for you
little old lady with asian fantasy
oh that was a really good one too i like
it was a good one
yeah yeah
that one was
was a uh there was a string called asian
fantasy made famous i think i think it's
fair to say about the can of bible jason
king pretty much made that strange very
much so yeah known it wasn't a
well-known strain i don't think was it
no no no no
and you know he he talked about the
rarity and how this guy never lets it
out blah blah blah a few years later um
a person that we we know who it was but
i don't think he'll ever admit it
right went on and tried to say that she
was the the wife of the man who held
asian fantasy and he has died and she
wants to get those genetics out there
you know and ended up i think it's
pretty sure it was nyc kid um
kind of big upping himself trying to
give himself some provenance on a cut
he'd never had access to
well we don't honestly we don't know
that part of it because
who
have you
or anybody
ever seen this asian fantasy keyword
fantasy
outside of the candle bible and
nyc kid and his crew
no
i mean
it's kind of a fantastic yeah yeah and
in fact african black magic i mean
there's some there's some pictures of it
or whatever but i mean jason king even
talked about how homey wouldn't give it
out to anyone
and you know was it was a massive
hoarder of it you know
and so there's an aspect to it there too
where it's like people
people can hoard something so much that
it doesn't become famous
yeah right you know because nobody ever
sees it like before
before this forum time that you were
talking about there was probably like
you know four or five people or
something in california that had the
chem 91.
someone just said i have asian fantasy s
ones from t h gobs so we're still doing
it go nyc kid you go
but yeah i mean it was like one of those
things where like if you know if if og
kush if some of the if some of these
famous things don't slip out
and people don't start cropping them you
know there was an aspect where it was
like for a long time there was only four
or five garages pumping chem 91
mm-hmm yeah like every you know so how
much weed is that not very much
it doesn't really give you very much
opportunity to try it it doesn't really
get give you an opportunity for like a
fad to
you know like if og hadn't snuck out if
all those guys hadn't been money hungry
down there in l.a and it snuck out it
probably wouldn't have had that kind of
impact
yeah because it has to be there
you have to be able to get at even even
if you have to pay a lot for it you do
have to be able to access
it right so asian fantasy is one of
those things where like it
you know um
it never got out and then so as a result
of that it allowed scammers to be like
this is it
right and how could you tell the
difference
hey um
you know you you still
you still buddies with the
with old jason
mr king
um i haven't spoken to him in a minute
but we're cool yeah he lives on maui
i know uh i wonder if you can uh ask him
kind of
maybe some of because i talked to him
before i like met you met you yeah
you know he
he uh
he affirmed that you know all my
information was right and then he was
like where'd you where'd you find all
this stuff out
you know
i mean he might know some some
background details that you know
definitely didn't make it into the book
yeah i bet
one of the one i've been actually
thinking about reaching out and talking
to him because one of the things that's
interesting is that he probably has a
[ __ ] ton of pictures
uh of weed from myself and my and some
and friends and then people that i don't
know obviously too but um that didn't
make it in the book
yeah because you know you might take you
know dozens or hundreds of pictures or
something and then two make it
yeah you pick a couple
um you know uh and and all that but he
um
you know and i think i think the asian
fantasy that he was talking about was in
hawaii
i want to say i remember and i could be
totally wrong so maybe i shouldn't say
it but i think i think bodhi knows the
asian fantasy person maybe
i might be wrong
hmm
i don't know i'm gonna ask him
i'll figure it out i mean to me it's one
of those it's one of those like
legendary strains you know yeah that
like just never
i mean you know there's i'll mention
another one did any of you guys have any
uh any um
uh experience with elvis
yes yes but i don't know if it was i
don't know how real it was it was just a
cut called else because there's some
really famous stuff out there that just
it was never in my crew never in like
the extended circles of cruise and you
hear about him for a long time and it
got famous in various aspects but it's
just like
you know
i also thought i had albert walker too
though
so there is that you know like who knows
who knows never got it from a good
source that that could say yes this is
where i got it none of that [ __ ] uh and
last one i had i passed off to skunk
master flex and i don't think he backed
it up
and your albert walker was the orangey
one right yep dagger walker yeah yeah
little [ __ ]
yeah um
did you ever see the mothership come
through i can't remember if you said
yeah
uh-huh yeah so i told this story before
but like it got mailed to one of our
spots
uh-huh so uh jason king's i don't think
it's shady to say this but his
girlfriend at the time was this chick
named rebecca
yeah and she was from asheville area of
north carolina
and so
she you know he used to rave about that
cut all the time and so she finally got
some of her friends to send it to us
yeah right and dude it was like uh our
buddy hi and lonesome has a terrible
story uh but
um it was kind of like that in the sense
where i was expecting to get this tiny
little box with some clones
and we got this box that was like you
know
this big by two feet tall or whatever
and it was two mothership plants in one
gallon pots with steaks and each one was
about 18 inches tall
in 03 or something like that and it was
like so all those pictures in the can of
bible that you see of mothership
those all came from those two moms that
got mailed to us yeah and then we mom
those out
and uh you know it got they got grown at
eddie left and they got grown to various
friends houses and stuff like that so i
actually had i actually i had the
mothership for four or five years i
think
um
and uh it wasn't
i think it was a super unique plant uh
it wasn't one of i didn't have it didn't
have the nicest flavor i didn't really
like the flavor that much but it had a
pretty cool high
and it did this weird thing where it
would fall half over but then hold
itself up
so like you know how most branches if
they flop they flop
it would like flop but then it would
like raise itself up and it would grow
sideways through your garden
almost kind of a little like train wreck
it would get would catch itself
and and just like and it had like these
it was a really odd sativa um
it had thin leaves and it was big
branchy thing
um but you know i mean i honestly like
compared to
all the other [ __ ] we've been talking
about like bubbas and chems and you know
super skunk it was it was a little midsy
you know
uh in all reality but it was one of
those things that probably like was
genetically very different
than everything else
so i like i like you know we like those
weird things
yeah it's real quick to touch back on
elvis since you were you were on thc
farmers stuff for a long time right
caleb
or at least attentive to it
um
i was on the outskirts of the devil's
harvest crew
back in those days too and uh there was
there were some of those guys that one
circulated through that crew
a good bit and it it started uh i think
iraq from maybe like
i don't know if i should say a state
that's a long time
uh you know uh
i think he's he circulated elvis for a
while through there i wouldn't be
surprised if a doctor maybe had grown it
was he uh he was he was real good
buddies with a lot of those cats
and i mean the whole time i was i was
online i only i only traded cuts uh
through the mail maybe tw uh i only
received cuts through the mail twice i
think
like you know 40 50 plus
you know uh packages that cuts but i
only received twice i did all my other
business just in person up and down the
west coast
so that's me i'm very much
i'm in
person miss elvis from the farm
um
i wasn't very active on the farm at all
very very little it was a person who
showed like they were the main person
showing the the elvis cut back then
there was something called like the pink
cadillac cut and then there was the
elvis cut
um that's that's the only person i ever
got it from but i never
they disappeared like
not even a month after giving it to me
but they were the ones that were always
documenting it on the farm but i never
knew if that was if it's just someone
from
that
[ __ ] and made their way through
because they disappeared so fast uh
after me popping out and get it from him
was it super incidency
uh no it was exactly like what they talk
about like a vinyl smell
vinyl just artificial vinyl
yeah not instantly at all
one of the things that's kind of
interesting about that era too is it's
kind of like the last era before like
the the clone name dominance thing
started happening
where everyone's growing og or
everyone's growing sour or everyone's
growing
all that kind of stuff so there was a
lot of these odd strains
you know not odd in the sense that
there's anything wrong with them just
odd odd
random strains that were easily sold
you know and so they they people liked
him and they got traded
yeah you know people weren't looking
necessarily for like oh i need to get
this specific cut because i'm going to
be able to move it and it's going to go
for x price
you know they were more interested in
like the legend or the history
or whatever of said cut or the person
behind it and you could get on there and
start talking about your cut
and all of a sudden drum up a bunch of
interest
yeah and especially like if we wanted to
go back
um you know when we were talking about
how small it was
i mean think about how revolutionary you
know just some some of matt's favorite
some of blueberry stuff got you know and
how it looked
there wasn't that much competition there
wasn't that much stuff outside of europe
or shanti or scentsy or you know uh
simon from sirius or some of that stuff
like there wasn't that many american
breeders so the few people that were
doing it like
like mr soul or or dj short or whoever
that were willing
to to show their work i think it kind of
got like outsized
you know outsized impact
you know like cindy 99 probably got way
more famous than it should have
was super kind
you know just to be just to be just to
be perfectly honest i don't think in
today it would have the same lasting
impact
right no not today now it wouldn't it
wouldn't have it wouldn't have been able
to break through but it was like so
i do think because it is is like when
you try to think of an outdoor plant
that's fast enough and still considered
sativa to most people i think that it's
it would be very hard to find a
replacement for c99 that's that fast
with those type of high qualities and i
think that also had a major effect
because it was it's a perfect outdoor
plant for blast and fast you know and it
could be grown indoors i just mean it
got like
all his work got real there wasn't that
much competition so there was a lot of
time to talk about
you know like not only cindy 99 but like
we were like the genius or the apollo or
this or that or whatever or like you
know everybody got plenty of time to
debate the four or five things that dj
released
yeah because there just wasn't that
there wasn't that many different things
you know there wasn't that many now
there's there's thousands of breeders
and so standing out is very hard then it
was like you know what was what was
there like you know a dozen big people
doing stuff yeah it was a lot easier for
people to [ __ ] keep other people down
too like the ones at the top since there
wasn't a lot of competition and they
they held a lot of sway they could
really cut fucker's throats real fast
and it happened a lot too and it was a
lot easier to do that
you know
i would have probably got cut then uh if
i had even tried to start back then
dude
like i said i was banned off every forum
and it got to the point where i was like
[ __ ] this let me start my own forum like
mr nice i i never got banned from um i
got asked to leave after a picture
contest because the the wright berry
pictures beat out one of mr nices and he
thought that was kind of [ __ ] of me to
put it in
um
but yeah all the rest of them it was
really hard because a lot of the ones a
lot of people that were running those
forums also had a seed company
right and most of those seed banks and
seed companies would eventually start
[ __ ] people and if you were one of
those people to speak up
you're done you know they don't want you
around yeah i mean i
i see mag definitely had uh some of that
aspect to it too
yeah there was the in crowd and the
outcrowd
you know
for sure as far as that goes
i'm just surprised that forum is still
alive after everything that went on with
it
yeah
see people somebody talked about that
people talk about 89 super skunk there
was no 89 super skunk
one of one of the things that gets that
that annoys the hell out of me uh
honestly and this isn't to call out
whoever has 89 super skunk but just in
general
is like they'll take the first year
that something was ever released or
named and be like i have that weed from
a year or two before then
yeah that's a big problem
like so the first time super skunk ever
got used was in the 1990
seed bank catalog
yeah that's when it had a picture that's
when it had a name that's when neville
released it
you know um and so people are like oh
i've got the 89 super skunk
well how
you know and then they're like oh you
know then they got to come up with like
well you know it was all that
pre-release special [ __ ] because i my my
uncle was buddies with homie who gave it
down on special kick down
oh they'll be like you know you know i
got that 95 93 scentsy star
i actually have pictures of that
1989 super skunk and they look awful
cookie-ish it's pretty pretty
but you know it it happens all the time
and then you see a lot of these old cuts
right now the years keep getting earlier
and earlier
yeah
you know i mean one thing and this isn't
you know this isn't to you know
obviously uh bodies use this or whatever
else right
but there is no g13 hash plant in the 88
catalogs
no no it came out in the 89 catalog
for the first year 89 90.
you know
but 88 much better
it sounds nice
you know and i'm not trying to throw any
shade on it or anything like that
there's plenty of people that have found
nice weed and you know buddy made a
bunch of hybrids with it and it came
from ndn guy i think right yeah yeah
uh origin originally or whatever you
know he reproduced it but it's like it
got released in 89
yeah right right but everyone calls it
the great you know the 88
right close enough you know
that you know some of that first pif
some of that first stuff they talk about
um they'll call it the great 88.
yeah that [ __ ] got released in 89.
so there's a bunch of stuff out there
where people will be like this cut is
from a year or two before this line ever
got released here's a quick question
though i mean i have zero experience in
this uh because i was living in my you
know whole and humble
but um
you were there so
or maybe maybe you were there years
later what was the possibility of them
doing uh releases of their seeds
um
at the canvas cups
so that is true
it is possible like for instance the
first cannabis cup i went to the was the
jack herrera cup
uh and the whole thing was themed on him
right
right and it was all about like it was
the whole like all the festivities were
all about the emperor wears no clothes
and they released
jack herrera seeds
um
you know from uh
uh in 95
94 yeah 95 they released them but it was
you know it was late november
right
um but it wasn't in the catalog until
the following year
right so it was like literally it was
literally the first time for instance uh
jack was dropped was at the camp was at
the cannabis cup
right in late november so i suppose you
could have gotten it
jacqueria at least six weeks before the
year turned
right right
you know
i mean uh
for example salmon creek big bud um you
know uh
you know homeboy homeboy from sama creek
you know he bought those seeds at the
cup the year it won the cup and then
smuggled 50 of those seeds home in his
little belt
you know hi hideaway belt thing
and
that's you know his selection from those
uh scentsy big bud seeds or whatever is
what made salmon creek big bud
i mean that's that's definitely possible
a lot of times
um
a lot of new seed releases
would get dumped in late november then
because because it was like an industry
gathering
right right and there was tons of and
honestly there was tons of custies there
i ended up hating going to amsterdam for
the cannabis cup i went three times and
then never again
mostly because it sucked
uh and the reason it sucked was that
uh
amsterdam is pretty far north
and so it's cold as [ __ ] in late
november there right so you can go in
summer and it's nice and it's beautiful
and you're on a bicycle and you're
cruising around all stoned or you can go
when it's sleeting
and 29 degrees
and that's not as nice you know and then
all the best weed would get saved for
celebrities that were coming in
and who's who so there was worse weed to
get because it was all getting saved for
you know snoop dogg or you know sam
skunk man's friends or you know whoever
whoever the high times crew or whatnot
and then on top of that
you could buy tickets to go to the
cannabis cup out of high times
right so you go to europe on vacation
and the coffee shops are full with all
these dudes from jersey and new york
yeah screaming about wanting to get the
best bud in the world
so it's like you fly
12 hours away from your house and you're
surrounded by a bunch of obnoxious east
coasters
and there's not as good weed and it's
crowded and it's cold and it's raining
or it's snowing and it's like i much
preferred going there in summer
you know just because it was nice and
chill
you know but it was like an event that
was like the it was it was an event then
you know
um and you know really like the story
goes you know uh neville didn't even
want to release jack carrera that year
um he didn't think it he didn't think he
didn't think it was done but they wanted
something new and hot that they could
call jack herrera
and isn't the story of [ __ ]
uh cindy 99 that that [ __ ] dude
bought jack herrera in a coffee shop and
found seeds in it
yep and then took him home and started
his whole cubing [ __ ] princess
whatever thing that he did
i don't think rick did anything like
that i'm just saying
that's life
yeah you know he found bag seed and uh
in buds that he bought at a coffee shop
yeah yep yep yep
mm-hmm you know
c99 and genius
are both uh
jack ferrer at best hybrids
yeah and really like and you know i
think back then that was even earlier
like we weren't using the improper term
back cross yet
or you know bx
uh
they were talking about [ __ ] wasn't
it cubing
yeah yeah it was it was it was cuban you
were cubing it you were like
[ __ ]
and they had all those like long-winded
posts on
on [ __ ] the forums about what
percentage and how much it was
increasing with everyone you did and
laying it all out you know yeah
there was some really bad breeder tech
being shared
that seemed cutting edge at the time
people still repeat that [ __ ] [ __ ]
like like a
mantra oh you gotta back cross it four
times and you get that's as good as a s1
that's a clone man and i saw and i saw
somebody talking about i like the super
silver haze better than the jack herrera
um the whole reason super silver haze
exists is because
um neville didn't feel like the jack
herrera project was ready for prime time
he just released it due to
you know allen and ben drunkers from
sensei were businessmen and so when he
left he kept working on it
and then a couple of years later i think
in 97 or something
he they released mango and neville and
super silver haze
because he felt like you know they'd
actually gotten somewhere on it
right right right but they still did a
couple and i actually think that was the
last big release that neville ever did
right
um
but i mean i smoked that
that super silver haze cut because two i
went in 90 i was basically like every
other year like i went 97 and 99 two to
the cups
and those last two cups that super
silver haze was all over the place
because that right that was in that was
like the first and third year at one
it was like the hot [ __ ] over there
right right it really was it was the hot
[ __ ] i mean it was super there was a
female of it that went like 14 weeks
uh will the community let rez back into
play
uh res is doing his own thing
you know
uh what most people don't know about rez
and our our a couple of buddies remind
reminded me of not that long ago was
like
before all the [ __ ] with the with
the law enforcement and all that
um
he was a dick online anyway
you're right big time he was a big time
troll jerk
generally a pain in the ass to get along
with not a pleasant homie
yeah at all despite despite any of the
rest of the bull whatever you want to
believe about
you know all the mess that happened
legally or whatever uh yeah he was a he
was an early troll
he was a jackass
he had a huge ego
i mean he still does
he he had a decent level of intelligence
which would have been i think much more
appreciated if he hadn't had so much ego
with it yeah a little humid you know i
mean
not you know a bunch of ego and a bunch
of rudeness
you know there was some root there was
some rude people you could put up with a
little bit better but they were like
borderline geniuses
right right right you know like tom hill
could be a real dick if you ask a dumb
question
i wouldn't know anything about ask being
rude that's you know i put up with it
you know or sam skunk man he could be a
dick too because you know you get tired
of i've told the same story five billion
times
right right you're gonna question me
you're 23 shut the [ __ ] up you're a [ __ ]
sucker you know yeah eat my dick you
know basically
yeah
rude kind of rude you know but it's hard
it's hard to have patience
you know and let's face it right a lot
of us are weirdos
a lot of us don't have the greatest
interpersonal skills to begin with
you know for yourself
i mean speaking for me i probably have a
little bit more than your average grower
just a bit
yeah you know but a lot but a lot of
them it's like you know we're kind of
harsh edges people that live in the
hills don't talk to people hang out with
plants
and they're really good with plants and
they're not so good with social
interaction
right
so you put those people on the forums
and you put those people like you know
on ig or whatever and it's like it's not
the easiest thing
i did have an adjustment period that
i will admit i had an adjustment period
of where
i may have been a little meaner in
responses and talking to people a little
snappy maybe a little bit of ego
you know it happens
but some of us grow into beautiful
smiling faces like this
i'm also still banned from breed bay for
uh picking on sub cool
it's also it's also the way i look at it
is like you know i mean everybody has
the natural inclination sometimes but
it's like are you trying to get your
point across are you trying to [ __ ]
argue on the internet
oh here's this dude who says his dad
created dog bud i remember that guy
he's trying to dox me i think i'm gonna
block him okay there you go i mean the
thing the thing about the one thing
we'll say about dog bud and then we'll
move on is that joe brand and peabud
were buying and selling wheat on dead
tour all the time
for cash to go see dead shows right and
this one weekend they sold some weed
and then they mailed greg some more weed
and then 15 years went by before they
even heard anything cool came out of it
[Music]
right they literally
they never saw
chem 91 or anything like that until 06
until the reunion when the forums got
people back together they had no idea
they were on dead tour right they met
this you know you know these guys
uh greg was in it was a teenager from
the east coast and they sold him some
weed in indiana
right which was just one stop on summer
tour
and you're buying pounds and you're
selling eighths and quarters and halfs
and ounces and it ran out and you buy
some other pounds and you just keep
doing that and you did that for a while
and one of these sales turned into
something
and now you want to well hey 15 years
ago do you remember
uh it was summer
uh on dead tour do you remember this one
couple pounds you had that you were
hustling for like a weekend
do you have any clear memory of that
because it's kind of important
well i think uh
i think you might have uh
remember just because he
um
hit joe brand up you know
gee
hit hit joe brand up again and had him
mail him some more weed i think 2m right
2 ounces and we don't even know if the
seeds came from the deer creek show
or the seeds came from the weed that joe
sent him later
i it's i from based on the stories i've
kind of deciphered i i think it
it came from the ones that was sent that
one had
no seeds but then again we know these
stories are a little up and down
i mean you know not to i like two of my
favorite cuts of all time come out of
g's little rooms but i will say that um
all of us on this thing have tried to uh
have tried to interpret what he meant by
rejuvenating the 91 after it got tired
in 1994.
well hybrum's always rejuvenated
rejuvenated yeah the rejuvenation he had
to let it go and rejuvenate it
that's how you fix it
from scene and that [ __ ] never got
explained
you know
um and so i don't you know there's
when it when any time you have a
situation where you know we can even go
back and take you know like ancient you
know ancient virginia skunk bud grown
for ssse or mr soul you know working for
sssc
you know you you create these ancient
legends and it's like how do you
disprove them
yeah in a lot of cases you can't prove
or disprove because they're so old
well let's get back to the forums i got
a question yeah yeah
um
what was the first place do you remember
where the first like seed bank the first
seed bank that carried your [ __ ] when
people could actually buy it which one
was it
well we don't talk about that
okay so is it an unmentionable
i ain't friends with that guy anymore
my fault
dude a little loco
yeah okay gotcha
you gotta remember i didn't even uh
start my food company until 2014
yeah yeah i remember
yeah i i
could say one thing is that my buddy
that i never mentioned his name but
staten island when we were doing all the
super dog work and we were doing all
those hybrids that made it into the can
of bible he had big dreams
of realizing that you could probably
make more money like off of an eight
lighter of seed
than you could off an eight lighter of
flower
and he saw what was coming i honestly
didn't believe him
you know i didn't think i didn't think
that we you would ever be able in
america to like package up and sell
enormous amounts of seed or anything
like that because at the time we were
making all this stuff and we were
literally giving it away to good friends
and stuff because we had more than we
knew what to do with and there wasn't an
outlet for it
um you know the era that that caleb
talks about getting involved is one of
the earlier eras where you could really
actually start to sell it
it wasn't simple in the beginning even
even if you were an active breeder
finding out how to get it to the
community wasn't very simple
no
you had to trust i mean like even even
with me i started the um
selling seats directly really early for
for
a u.s person um but when i first started
you still had to
really put your trust in someone in
europe for the most part if you wanted
any kind of traction for your seeds if
you wanted any
i mean you had to work with seed banks
for people they
eventually know who you are if the seed
bank didn't carry you you probably
weren't [ __ ] important that's why
everybody looked at it we were about to
go into csi after dark
[Laughter]
yeah
but yeah i mean uh you know a good bit
of that was in the 90s
you know when dj short wanted to get his
blueberry seed out there
he had to give it away
to
uh two different groups in europe
yeah first he had to give it to tony at
sag martha and then he had to give it to
dutch passion i don't know if he
intentionally gave it away but i think
that's how it ended up working out i
think he did
huh
didn't didn't he
purposely give him to him and maybe he
purposely did i think he thought that he
would still retain all control and this
and that that's where he was probably
mistaken
but in order for him to even like get
money for his seeds
he had to send them to an established
seed bank
yeah in a different continent
that's how hard it was to move seeds
then
yeah but you know when he i think sag
martha they had his seeds in what like
you know the mid-90s or something like
that um
right around there
the internet didn't even exist then
really
right right
i did but not not not like any level
that you were going to be able to use it
for that
yeah yeah i think overgrowth started in
either 98 or 99
or maybe
yeah yep now you're right about that so
like the first forums the first being
able to exchange stuff like how would dj
have even set up an internet was gonna
set up a geocities like [ __ ] you know
web page and sell illegal beans
you know
um i mean up until up until they passed
the the 215 in in late
96 i think it was
it was it was illegal in all 50 states
there wasn't any there wasn't even a
legitimate reason you could possess any
of it
yeah
and i think he feels burnt he felt
burned
but you know what were you going to do
when you gave it away to the dutch
right if he didn't know that those those
dutch guys were going to do whatever the
[ __ ] they wanted with it then he was
just
he had just done his groundwork
yeah right
well yeah that that that's a
blueberry is almost a
a a full days topic just by itself it is
but i just meant in the sense that like
just to use it on the example of how
hard it was to sell seeds if you were a
small american breeder
yeah he had to work with the dutch just
to get it out there there wasn't an
avenue what were you gonna do
i mean
you know um
you know even like early even early
american you know seed sellers or
whatever used to try to fake that their
stuff was based out of europe right
right
you know i i mean one of the things that
ig did and and the middle and and the
sort of the middle era of to middle late
215 was things opened up enough that
people felt free
to be able to like you know you could
have a swamp boys
you could have a csi humble you could
have a you could have just these people
that were like i'm gonna make my own
packaging
i'm gonna make my own beans i'm going to
go to these like gray area cannabis cup
swap meats
and hustle seeds i'm going to start to
mail
um i can say back in
0203.0405 i mean my buddy from staten
island would tell me about this stuff
that he wanted to do and i would laugh
at him
i was like oh you want us to all go to
jail
because that's what that's what it seems
like you're talking about to me
you know yeah when i started i i was one
of the peo i think i was one of the few
people that pretended that my website
was in amsterdam just to like
try to hide under the shadows you know
just because no one was doing it it
[ __ ] was a big red flag so even
though i'm just waiting for that hit
even having the infrastructure set up to
be successful
yeah
and and that's kind of why there was so
few breeders back then
because it was generally done out of
love
and you were trading amongst other
people and there wasn't something like
there is now where somebody can be like
oh i'm gonna drop
my mac one drop and i'm gonna make 200
grand and you know i'm gonna i'm gonna
i'm gonna hype it
yeah you really couldn't hype it there
wasn't marketing there wasn't an ability
to reach a big audience right right
i don't think
you know
it took a while
well and uh
in in in the era you know oh six you
know
through 08 even 2010 i mean most of the
marketing most most of the availability
was all based on internet forums right
yeah
you know that was and
and people should also remember that
when overgrowing cannabis world got shut
down
they got shut down because a very big uh
you know seed vendor got raided
uh
heaven's stairway
that was and that scared a bunch of
people
and there's still repercussions and
ripples hitting from that [ __ ] bust
you know
and you know and then you know and and
you know and people even in canada and
stuff like that you know mark emery you
know uh i mean he he went to [ __ ] he
went to jail
mm-hmm you know
it was yours
did you have any dealings with mark
cameron kayla
at all oh no no no interactions
no interactions at all but uh um
you know i was i was getting uh
cannabis culture or cannabis canada from
pretty much like the first issue
you know i've always been a historian so
i mean i have hundreds and hundreds of
kind of books and i was you know for
years i was getting every single
magazine that was put out on on
everything so i've always been way more
of a reader than a talker
yeah
you know
it helps put details together sometimes
yeah it does
yeah
but no no no uh direct you know dealings
i mean
uh the stuff i liked from
from those magazines though and and him
were like the abc stuff from back yeah
late 90s and then the purple indica
purple kush stuff
that was in those early issues as well
but uh and then i think emery was
working with the same purple indica
that's around now or at least a relative
uh it wasn't emory uh there was an
article based out of snohomish county
in washington
and it it basically dated that that
stuff back into the you know at the very
least you know early mid 90s
yeah that's cool
so
there was a question we were talking
about the other night and i was like i
need to ask not so that and i can't
remember what it was
it had something to do with uh
how did kim do you make it to california
not so oh yeah
how did it make it here yeah who brought
it oh that's that's pretty simple story
so
it ties into the forums so
people's in 06 people started getting
excited about uh chem dog
and the chem dog story because it
started getting posted
uh like um
uh caleb was saying
our shabba had got
uh
got um skunk va to start posting about
his you know recollections and different
stuff like that and
and then
you know that's kind of actually what
started to reunite
um
uh people like peabud and joe brand and
uh chem dog all they all started
chatting i believe they even called like
the the seeds that ended up being the
one through four the reunion seeds
or yeah the number four they uh named
the reunion fino specific reunion fino
that's what it was right because it was
like they had all they'd all kind of met
up as this you know like different
people were like hey dude they're
talking about your story on the internet
right
and so
chem dog hadn't actually had the chem 91
in quite a long time
um he had gotten in trouble and lost it
and he had been working with some of the
chem dog
super skunk hybrids that he had and bag
seed and different things
and when it got famous again he wanted
it back
but nobody had it
so
he got um he got skunked he got skunked
va
to go back east with it and he was like
if you bring it back to bring it back to
me and i've got this different one that
you guys don't have out there
and
um i'll give it to you
so he went back east and and saw a dude
and gave him the and gave him the dog
and then uh greg gave him the d
and he came back and mommed it up and
that's how uh me and uh i see collective
both got it so was it skunky a that did
it brought it 100
oh cool and that was it
it was him it was it was all it's he's
the reason it's he to me
he's the reason it's on the west coast
very cool he put forth the effort he
went back east to see
uh he gave he gave the dog to chem dog
he got the d
that was and i think
if i remember too
um
uh i believe that um
chem dog tried to give him back the mss
yeah he just said that but it was the
shorter one that was in the high times
and it wasn't what uh homie remembered
at all that makes a lot of sense too
yeah so then yeah so then he came back
and he grew it up into a mom
or whatever and then
i see collective and myself got it not
that long after that and but to me it's
like the reason it's on the west coast
is is skunk va
well on greg
on g's tour um
he uh
he he dropped it off uh in
the you know la area with swerve the
chem d in oh six but this is off of o6
he um and swerve traded him a bunch of
fake cuts for it you know
no big deal and then he also stopped at
uh
he stopped at um you know obsoletes in
central cal
um on his tour and then he stopped at
joe brands and then he headed up into
oregon and stopped at some other folks
place and i think he might have given
them the chem d2 but he he stopped at a
a good handful of places giving cuts out
selling weed at dispensaries all that
kind of stuff on his
you know reunion tour of sorts and this
is
like first week of august oh six
so it sounds like uh
skunk va went over there you know
earlier in the year and and and got
the same or similar cut i don't know
seems like there was a few cuts that got
passed out that year
yeah
yeah i mean it so but that's that's kind
of that's how that's how the the and
that led to a bunch of stuff that led to
the one two three four
getting popped and started to get traded
around
right now
um that led to the d that led to the one
through the four and the d and all that
starting to get added to the mix
um
i don't know that the weird thing about
the the chem stuff is that my buddy
disliked the sis quite a bit
he thought it was ugly and he didn't
like how it got him high so he never
brought it west
and so it never really percolated around
our crew
um you know we
way later we saw some of the s-ones
um but not the actual not the actual
first one
you know yeah
so
but yeah i mean that's and i you know
i'm pretty sure
uh you know he i i never lost i never
lost it after skunk gave it to me
um
yeah i mean that and that's that's the
kind of thing like you know uh csi and i
talk about it all the time it's like are
there strains where like the chain of
custody wasn't broken
right right because once you lose the
chain of custody
um you know it's hard
it gets hard you know like um
because
who knows you know you try to you you lo
i lost the sour diesel you try to get it
back it's not the same thing you
remember you lost to this you try to get
it back it's not the same you remember
um you know so on and so forth so
kind of like when a 707 uh showboat got
his bubba back from me
um i i
i don't think i did it on purpose it was
an accident it got mixed up in a flat
because i was bringing a ton of people a
bunch of stuff
at a party and uh
then like a year later he's like yeah
and inspect his bubba and i was like
what's this inspector's bone
he had bomb threat and not oh [ __ ]
but i was like oh my bad my bad i'm
trying to give you you know the fake
that's one well not fake but you know
yeah
but yeah that happens all the time
i think i'd take a bomb thread over
over original maybe
you can always get a new bomb threat if
you have that that's true that's true
it's a good point
you know
here's a question for you since uh we've
kind of meandered away from the forum
stuff but
do you
csi do you do any work with jesus are
you planning any work with it
uh
maybe if i could find a mass super skunk
yeah yeah
that was for you too really
i was telling him last night that i
think he should because
i think it's a it's a rad clone but it
is it is very finicky and it does make
it a lot harder to to pull off reversals
on unhappy finicky [ __ ]
right it would it would be really cool
to kind of
uh attempt to remake like uh a sour type
from
you know building blocks i mean yeah
we all have the the 91
but you know what building blocks you
know it might not have to be the exact
thing but what could you get close
enough to
to make a sour diesel out of you know
the original building blocks yeah
you know
i think i think jesus leans closer to a
sour type than it does a chem type
personally
oh yeah definitely definitely yeah i
think so
it's a cool one yeah yeah
all right so people want to hear
something about irene i don't know what
they want to hear about irene i think
we've already told the story of irene
but do you have any good irene tales
oh i don't know i
mean she's cool
i think
um
i i had irene for a little bit
and didn't realize she was
she was you know as as nice as she was
until i think i grew her outdoors
uh in maybe 2008
i'm thinking
yeah
i don't want to fudge the fudge the
dates though um but yes she came out so
nice back then
you know
good old-fashioned atlanta
atlanta's finest
yeah it is a special one
yeah
i mean it doesn't have a whole
whole lot of a story you know
yeah just another another bag seed
really
that's what it all boils down to it's
just another [ __ ] bad seed
i mean that is one of the most humbling
things about breeding
is that a lot of the most famous strains
are total accidents
right and you put a bunch of time and
work and effort into stuff and then you
know your air conditioner goes out and
some [ __ ] herms and the seed off of that
is better than anything you tried to do
a lot of times when it comes to like
these stories
the accidental weed is so good it's what
makes people want to try to like
shoehorn in that they
had some intentional part of making it
not so much that i was just there or we
got late they don't want to say well i
just got lucky in my room
they want to be like oh well i did this
and i did this and i did this and then
that happened and yeah now it's all the
weed that you all love
look everybody's got to work their stud
isn't that how it's done you know but
but really it was more like you know i
was i had my room i ended up partying
for a few days i [ __ ] off i walked in
there there was some bananas i found
some seeds trimming
that's like 99
of bag seed stories
yeah that that's kind of why i believe
uh
matt burger and josh d story because
it's not impressive it's not a
it it's a herm you know in a little
closet under the stairs story and it's
just like who makes that stuff up that's
not right
that's just oops
yeah yeah i mean you know i it it that's
very humbling but i i also do think that
a lot of that 90s weed it just goes to
show that when you're crossing things
that like aren't
when you're crossing real fire
you know right um it's a lot easier to
get
you know like was was neville an amazing
breeder or did he just get to get the
best of the best from america and cross
it together for the first time
right right
you know what i'm saying there's a
there's an ad there's arguments to both
he was you know he was the first person
to cross nl and skunk right
huh
not so what are you saying i'm rude no
uh
no uh
i was thinking you should get uh tom on
and try to get uh
figure out a little more details about
pine tar and all that kind of stuff
because love to
you know
i don't think he even knows who i am to
get him on
or he's not likely
i i think he's banned off i see mag so
uh yeah i mean let me ask you like a
real question do you think that he would
be better for a live or do you think he
would be better for uh a lightly edited
uh podcast or something oh probably a a
heavily edited podcast you're right
because i mean we definitely matt and i
have definitely interviewed some like
knowledgeable old-timers
right been like
yeah no
mom's a character i like him but man
he'll
yeah
he might pray off topic
you know yeah so there's there is a
question everybody is asking and it's up
to you if you want to talk about i don't
even know if you want to deal with this
one right now or save it for a full
episode caleb
backstory on z what do you think
oh man
um i don't want to like
say anything yet
because yeah let's say you want to save
it for a full show of some sort later
well i i still have some groans to do on
that whole thing but yeah
man
i
i wouldn't be surprised if it's not just
an s1 of of uh that green sherbert cut
yeah um there's there's just two too
many similarities
and
the whole you know uh heterozygous
homozygous thing between the two of them
really kind of leans towards it just
being a as one of that
yeah but
i don't know um
yeah i could go on and on on some
comparisons on
you know how some of that stuff could uh
could potentially make sense
um yeah
but i don't know i don't know
yeah we'll save it for another time but
yeah that's a that's a good answer one
thing one thing that is going on
uh about that is that um
uh csi and i and matt we all talk all
the time about how when you compare
stories
to what the plants tell you
uh how they breed what their s ones look
like um what what they look like when
they get crossed to different things
and how what your eyes tell you lines up
with what the story is
right right right you know and sometimes
it it sometimes it adds a lot
in terms of what you see
um you know like about i have a heart i
have a really hard time believing
that the the cis the 91 the chem d and
the one through four all came out of the
same bud
yeah yeah you know um they're just too
vastly different to me um you know but
that's i wasn't there either
you know and a lot of this stuff is like
the most famous stories
they
almost because almost all of them come
from accidents and because a lot of them
come from other people it's like the
people that marketed stuff or marketed
skittles or marketed cookie or whatever
like they probably you know different
people get it maybe it doesn't get quite
as famous
you know um you know and they should get
great credit for marketing it to the
point that they did
yeah right oh yeah
i've never disputed that um you know i i
give lots of people accolades for mar
successfully marketing and you know
building you know clones that would
never have been anything up you know to
what they are
uh
what i've always you know frowned on of
course is you know people being
dishonest doing it i think you can do it
honestly
and still be successful
sure
you know having to just make up big old
big ol you know fictitious backstories
or yeah like you're the one responsible
for it
that's why instead of you know i mean
there's cats like
you know josh and matt who are like oh
yeah it was a herm accident under the
stairs and then there's other cats you
know who are like yes we created that
from our multi-thousand plant grows
aren't we awesome yes yes we popped we
popped 15 seeds and the 20th was the
best
so you know
um you know i
i think the the truth is is
the the biggest factor for me
yeah and yeah there's an aspect where
and and you know we should say this too
is that truth is a most people everyone
likes to say they want the truth but
like people that really care about it
it's like a really small percentage
yeah oh
most people like truth if it helps them
burnish their money or their reputation
or whatever else
sure and the truth is usually boring you
know people who are looking for
excitement from the truth
they're going to be like oh well that
was lame
yeah something up i don't care
especially when the answer is 99 of the
time oh it's a bad seed
yeah
or yeah or you know or it happened an
accident at my buddy's house
or yeah i said this or i was you know
like you know you were early involved
and you know the story even just knowing
the story is cool
right but then people want to be part
like they want to be this active
component
that was critical to the story
you know
right
and i i did forget someone earlier that
was really important when i was was you
know coming in and that was that was
doing reversals before i was and that
was rascal i think i think i would be
remiss not to mention him because he was
doing good things and had legitimate
cuts you know for the most part as far
as i know like he was doing good [ __ ]
work and he was doing it at a time when
it wasn't popular when people were
pushing back against feminist seed so i
give that guy props too all the stuff
that that guy made between whatever it
was 09 and 12 or whatever yeah all those
hybrids are fire yeah there was some
good [ __ ] in there i mean he really
maybe not all but like the vast majority
of the stuff he had some really nice
cuts and he was crossing them together
and they led to some really nice things
yeah i mean white fire you know a lot of
people don't even know like about the
white anymore like not a lot of people
talk about it but that was the essence
behind the white fire that was [ __ ]
cool
right right
yep
that
uh what
that's one i'd like to touch on too in
the future um oh yeah they they uh you
know
the swamp boys uh big ricky in
particular he uh
he's alluded a lot to
knowing exactly what the hybrid of the
white is because it's supposedly a tk
hybrid
um
but you know he
he likes riddles and secrets so
riddles
i call it a haiku hillbilly haiku
sometimes i wonder how long he takes to
craft
uh some of his instagram posts and how
to make it like you know he because he's
got his own
language when it comes to that you know
have you seen have you seen stuff like
the white inside the tks ones
yeah
yeah yeah
there there was a there was one plant in
our first run of them
where
um
actually there was there was there was
four plants that uh we pulled out of the
first run
um and uh
one was a green girl scout cookie like a
green forum cut
um other was a plant that looked just
like the white
you know not
but
so similar
yeah it was obvious and then there was
the number 50 and the 51 were
which were my two actual favorites of
the whole bunch and then you know i i
smoked both those heavily and the 50
turned out to be my absolute favorite of
the whole bunch
and so that's the one i kept and
still play with from the first and then
i did another 100 plus you know tks one
pop and
you know got other selections from there
yeah
so caleb what do you think about cookies
uh
great question from ask what do you
think
i think that goes into the category of
uh what 2010 and on 2010 2011 yeah
people people ask a bunch of that
and i think i mean
it's a story
you know and it's a story that like
there's a lot of pieces that aren't
known that well
um
but it's a definitely one that's going
to create a it's you know it's a super
popular brand there's a lot of money
involved there's a lot of rep involved
and it's one of those things if you
don't get it exactly right it's going to
be gunning for you
here's a relevant one here's a relevant
one for caleb are you going to s1 any of
the nl selections
i was going to leave that up to you
buddy yeah i think we might i think we
might
we're going to see how it goes
uh yeah no i think they'd be worth it i
think they
do that
you know i like my feminized so
i'll grow
i'll grow some of matt's uh
s1nls
hell yeah
there we go well we kept him here for
god damn a long time so i know he's got
a busy night i gotta get back to packing
um anything else anybody wants to talk
about
awesome
so when you so what's what's the next
drop caleb and where where can we find
it
oh i don't know if i'm
dropping dead maybe yeah
drop the next drop is dead
i'm i'm good for now
yeah okay well go check out humboldt
csi.com correct
yeah
humbledcsi.com keep your eyes peeled
he's always putting stuff up on there on
and off he doesn't often announce it so
just keep checking back um
i'm still waiting for those next drop
what's that i'm still waiting on natso's
next drop yeah where the [ __ ] that at
natto
it's slowly developing
okay good it's slowly developing through
you know i'm not that i'm not that
public of a guy uh it's changing though
you know
yeah both of you uh
basically like if if the two most
important people for you guys seeing my
face on a weekly basis is the two people
on this
uh talk tonight
guaranteed without them i would not be
showing my face or chatting about stuff
they both pushed for quite a long time
to get me to tell stories and talk [ __ ]
um
so really it it really is they gave me
the confidence to say you people would
want to hear it
let's chat let's talk history
and you know and there's an aspect to it
too where it's like a lot of the stuff
we're talking about with you guys this
is what we have all been doing amongst
each other privately for [ __ ] ever
yeah
so we've all heard each other's stupid
[ __ ] stories 100 times you know
and and all that and so this is this is
really how information gets information
and cuts gets saved and shared
and you know history survives and
generally the point of all this is to
get you know versions of history out
there and gets passed along
right yep so other things newer people
can hear it so it's it's just not a wash
in [ __ ]
and everyone keep your eyes peeled for a
sterling
sterling green drop eventually
yeah eventually eventually eventually
when it when it comes around everybody's
asking about it so i figured i'd plug it
and there's a bunch of good questions
today we didn't get to uh as always if
just because just because you asked and
we didn't chat
um you know doesn't mean it's not it's
not worthwhile you can always message us
about them uh we're always looking for
different things to chat about what
people have interest in you know so uh
keep all that stuff coming we always
appreciate you guys it's friday night
for 100 percent
so yep super and go
go check out the breeder syndicate
patreon you got to go to google type in
reader syndicate patreon go check that
out go to social love to
speakeasybank.com there who edits and
and gets these things up for the podcast
version so show them some love and uh
check out riotcedco.com and
humboldtcsi.com
and we will see you next week probably
at the same time exactly
peace
night everyone
you