welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
can you kind of Enlighten us a little
bit on on Mark Emery both of you just
give us a quick take from a Canadian
perspective on Mark Emery because we
don't have a really clear one at least
from my era and point of view in the
United States well like one thing I'm
not sure about was Mark Emery involved
in cannabis cannabis before like the
hemp Nation constitutional challenge no
no no no wait well the Constitutional
challenge he started NPC by that time
but you have to remember Mark's from
this town from my town yeah yeah
um he had a bookstore here called City
Lights
you scam those people also when it came
to selling it but um Mark
um I call him the dark enemy for a
reason
um I think it's very suiting it on it
ironically matches his name but he is
somebody that you know in his own word
said he was against legalization of
cannabis
due to the amount of money that he was
making from selling seeds illegally yeah
um he proved this when
um after hemp nation was busted for the
second time well first time was Great
Canadian Emporium second time it was
Temptation yeah um
the
uh Chris was not allowed to sell
paraphernalia after that so
we desire he decided that
um he reached out to to Mark who had NBC
and said Hey listen do you want to buy
all the inventory from hemp Nation
because we need to raise the money for
the Constitutional challenge
and he agreed he's like yeah send me
everything and then it was like pulling
teeth to get paid from him and by the
very end of it I mean it wasn't a
shitload of money you know maybe it was
only 10 20 grand or something like that
in inventory but when you're fighting
the government to legalize cannabis
every penny counts sure and Chris kept
getting the you know oh talk to my
account and talk to my accountant at
this time it was in around this time uh
uh friends of mine through through Red
from Legends a mutual friend worked for
for Mark
uh basically almost as like manager area
of sales for his direct seeds yeah and
he was doing something like
20 40 60 000 a week in cannabis sales
and Seed sales
wow and when it was all said and done
with hemp Nation Chris claimed uh uh
bankruptcy with Mark Emery still owing
him money and it was only maybe a
thousand or two thousand dollars at the
end of it but it kind of just showed
what the term douchebag and yeah wrote
my use of the word douchebag
I I have to start saving it for like the
appropriate people and dark enemy is I
feel the biggest douchebag in our
industry he you know claims that he
donated all this money and stuff like
that but he didn't he uh he would you
know he did a a interview I think it was
on like CBC or something
and Jody him and Jody and him were
together for less than a year maybe and
he's sitting there having her like click
his toenails on camera while he's being
interviewed and I think he's my mistake
he got up and he was butt naked or
something like that and I was just like
what kind of [ __ ] douchebag again the
word douchebag yeah uh lets or allows
his girlfriend
who was barely out of being a teenager
at the time yeah but his [ __ ]
toenails on national TV I mean yes my
girlfriend and my my wife sure she would
probably if I asked her to yeah we're in
a [ __ ] lifetime ask for her to do it
on camera the show crazy there was a big
thing that came out like he he was just
very inappropriate
I can't say I don't know of any charges
um that were laid I mean there should
have been I do know he did run from
political office here in London and uh
he was dating uh
somebody that we knew he was dating uh
this guy's ex-wife
and uh this guy had I think two kids two
boys
and marked during his speeches kept
saying I'm a family man I'm all about
family you know here's my wife and my
kids and this guy was like dude you
can't call my kids your kids like and it
ended up that Mark I believe was giving
a a
speech or something down at one of the
parks
and he said that and this guy walked out
of the crowd walked up and punched him I
don't know if he did it on Hallelujah
but like basically punch Mark in the
[ __ ] head and said stop [ __ ]
claiming my kids it's yours because you
know he's he was he's a showboater and
the thing is is he has he's done certain
things he used to do something here he
fought for uh
uh for stores to be open on Sunday when
before when it was illegal yeah kudos
for that he uh paid he had some of his
staff or something follow
um minute uh the guy is doing the uh
parking police whatever and walking
around with nickels or quarters and if
he saw an expired meter he'd drop a
quarter or Nickel in it kudos for that
but you know Mark Mark is like the
Donald Trump of the [ __ ] cannabis
industry like he talks to talk but he's
burned so many [ __ ] bridges yeah the
thing is I got no yelling matches on
um on the phone and because he was like
why the [ __ ] you bashing me I kicked him
out of my store when he came into town
he can go to High Times the guy my
competition
as much as he wants but uh I know him
and furthermore when I opened organic
traveler I took over all of hemp
nation's uh gear everything down from
the display cases including the
computers so on these computers I had
access to all the files and all the
outstanding debts that Marco so I was
bad-mouthing him and trying to be loud
enough that he would hear me yeah and
obviously he did because he called me up
one day on speakerphone with other
people in the background and uh and try
to [ __ ] me like try to make a scene
yeah Mark I got the [ __ ] computers
here I can tell you what date you made
payments and what date and how much you
owed at the very end you tell me he's
like Peter was only [ __ ] thousand
bucks a couple thousand bucks I don't
give a [ __ ] you still love it in colors
man we were trying to [ __ ] change the
laws Chris went to [ __ ] jail for this
um Sarah went to jail for this this
guy's out there making tens if not
hundreds of thousands of dollars a month
yeah and he's gonna stiff some [ __ ]
guy that's trying to fight the marijuana
laws so that he can do that and now this
comes through word of mouth but the
people that tell me this kind of thing
um I give 10 times a thousand times more
credit than I give Mark yeah and they
said you know he'll admit that off
record obviously that why would he want
to legalize cannabis when he makes so
much money off the fact that it is
illegal
and especially in the states he wasn't
charged in Canada he was charged in the
states yeah right like [ __ ] buddy like
to move to the states I mean I'm I'm all
for spreading the seed everywhere we
don't want him use that [ __ ] you know
and what got me also was back then I was
actually
breeding I'll do air quotes because it's
not I was just breeding for seed to get
the seed out there and again we're going
back to the mid 90s kind of thing
um
we would send Mark seeds and this when
he was first started his uh seed
business and uh we would tell him or
whatever it was a buck a seat or
a couple bucks a seat or something like
that and we'd be honest like listen like
I told in the last interview I would buy
seeds from uh Scentsy or Greenhouse or
something and then do a breeding just
using those genetics and saying Hey
listen this is
um this is our Northern Lights we bought
the Northern Lights five we bought the
seed we made our own seed we're selling
it right yeah or we would say or we
liked uh we wanted to blend it so we did
like a Northern Lights chemo which was
something that we really liked and we
would sell Market seeds and he would
change the names or he would remove
certain things like he would just call
the Northern Lights chemo just chemo
right yeah
itself better right yeah so he was
didn't want us when he when it came to
what he was selling and um you know it
didn't happen he wasn't he wasn't
selling it as you know Scentsy seeds
[ __ ] Northern Lights he was just
saying hey this is pure Northern Lights
but it wasn't pure it was [ __ ] bread
by me or or hemp Nation crew and or in a
hemp Nation Garden or my garden and we
were just doing it to spread the Johnny
Appleseed we wanted to sell this yeah
you know we were selling I think it was
uh 10 seats or 25 bucks if something 250
a seat to get it out yeah the thing
right so you know people that again I've
even said in the last interview people
that focus on the money in this industry
uh are in the industry not the movement
and people that claim to be in the
movement like Mark does you know and he
he was hiding behind Jody
till the very end right like I don't
know what the [ __ ] is wrong with that
and I'm not going to get in any personal
[ __ ] because there's some
[ __ ] he's done to friends of mine
personally yeah I mean if you if you
Google Mark Emery and you look for stuff
it's like there's stuff out there it's
like when he got out west I I think it
got worse you know yeah it's all about
ego he always me and my friends
when we were out in Vancouver we
wouldn't step foot in the shop no like
on that strip like like we wouldn't like
we didn't even want to go into his
establishment like that's how much we
disliked him we just knew like he was a
piece of [ __ ] like [ __ ] him yeah
again he's it's about self-promotion
with him it's nothing to do with the
movement he's not one of them he was
anything but [ __ ] you know he went to
I think it was Thailand before he went
out west
you know uh or maybe it was during
because he went out there and like
dropped a bunch of money on some locals
said hey I just bought this property
here's [ __ ] x amount of dollars I
want a [ __ ] house and I come back you
know when he came back he went back
there the land was just overgrown
nothing built and his money was gone
awesome so yes I I would honestly wish
that there wasn't so many you know he
comes back to this town and he thinks
he's [ __ ] he ran for political office
last year yes oh yeah and uh it was
hilarious because every time I drove by
him I would call him a [ __ ] douchebag
yeah don't listen you're not liked
around here get the [ __ ] out here he got
very little votes and the funny thing is
is I was either driving my Volkswagen
bus and my Volkswagen Karma gear on my
truck or my Mini Cooper or my Jeep I was
always driving something different so
he's probably thought the whole [ __ ] I'm
I know I hope other people join me but
yeah was [ __ ] yelling at him left
right and Center because
he doesn't [ __ ] live here while he
might live here now I don't even know I
think he moved back here for a while I
can't believe he would go back honestly
like I like when I lived there I didn't
know one person that had anything to say
but negative but he he didn't choose to
leave London right he had to leave he
ended up he ended up [ __ ] he saw he
ended up [ __ ] a fireman's wife and I
don't for for some reason I thought he
was fairly high up in the fire
department I don't know if he was a
chief or or something like that but uh
rumor has it yeah they walked into his
[ __ ] bookstore
and so there's a lot of paper in here if
this is probably places probably go up
pretty quickly and sometimes we hit red
lights or something along that line was
said yeah kind of thing right I and
again could have been folklore it could
have been anything but because you know
I knew the type of person I know the
type of person he is right for sure see
that so you know it sucks to see people
like that get all the attention and it
gives us a bad name yeah people out
there especially as a Canadian like to
hear Prince of pot what the [ __ ] like
come on like that was yeah especially
like in BC he kept going in BC it's like
yeah well let's let's get to this so the
one thing that was resounding the
resounding criticism from the last
episode was that there were one or two
really loud BC Growers that they were
misrepresented very extreme can you can
you explain to Sean better than me I I
before like when before we did the first
one before we even recorded the first
one in our little homie chat I said
there's going to be some BC people
pissed off yeah and I have I have a
specific question in mind but I didn't
even ask that question and they still
got upset but
I actually went back and listened and I
know what he what the one guy at least
was upset about and and it was that Pete
said it all started here I was like yup
and then there was a comment about of
course there's there's good growers in
BC they're all from Ontario yeah but he
was like this by that you know yeah
whatever well but
I have a very specific uh Viewpoint
right yeah
but hey Dr not so I'm Back Where I Come
From right like I grew up in London so I
grew up around like I like there is like
commercial what my friends called
bikerweed right which was just the
commercial right yeah
but once once you found like that like
fan that downtown family which was not
hard to find you know
um you look you got great pot right yeah
yeah whether you were getting it from
well whatever I'm not gonna name but
like
so me and my friends like you know we
went on tour right we were like [ __ ]
this we're going on dead tour and we
just wanted to like we wanted to see the
shows because we we were heads but we
also wanted to see [ __ ] pot you know
that was like the two were just as equal
so we went down we did tour for a while
that led us to the west coast of the us
and we we saw that area and like
we were kind of like blown away like
number one the cost we could not [ __ ]
believe people were paying what they
were paying like that was just
mind-blowing right because it was
comparable to back home to us yeah and
then when we got to the West Coast it's
like same thing but like the only like
the only thing about the west coast is
we saw new stuff that like names we'd
never heard of and obviously there was
people breeding there right because it
was all this weird new [ __ ] it was the
first time I saw like white weed right
like it looked like mold in somebody's
hand but they're like no that's you know
that's [ __ ] you know resin
and then you know I lived in Arcata for
a while right so I lived in Arcata for a
good stretch and like I was there for a
while so I kind of saw and experienced
what was going on in that area and it
was really good weed like back home
though you know like for me it was like
what we had back home and then I got
back home and like I went into Pete shop
to like chat him up because back home
there's not too many people that you
could talk about that stuff and they
understand what you're talking about
and at the same time it was taking me
out to Vancouver with him right and
Pete's response was like you were just
like disappointed super disappointed
and you're like everybody goes out west
and they think the weed is so much
better there and it's not it's not you
know and I think and like I said I stand
by the what I said before about
um uh all the good Growers
well I would say all but I can't say all
right because we don't know yeah I'm
gonna say a large percentage and I'll
give you a few examples because a large
percentage I I got hired uh after a
state in Switzerland by a one of the
larger brokers
in
um the Vancouver area and uh like red he
was named after a different color let's
just say blue and um
and
I think he's from Ontario too honestly
but uh so they they've brought me into
this middle of butt [ __ ] nowhere between
Jasper and Kamloops along uh I think
it's Highway five and
um
built a huge Greenhouse in the middle of
the Bush off-grid I lived in a little
Log Cabin off grid or they already had
a 300 uh 300 bales of pro-mix hiked into
a bush and big huge uh outdoor beds and
I thought [ __ ] right man I'm in the
middle of [ __ ] nowhere I'm finally
gonna meet some of these you know
grassroot VC Growers that I [ __ ]
heard about read about didn't meet
[ __ ] one person from BC every single
person I met was from Ontario or I'd say
80 from Ontario and the rest were kind
of mixed so when you go out to uh to
Vancouver and the island and stuff like
that
you know yeah ask ask anybody where you
from I'm from BC I was like really where
were you born what part like I was born
in Etobicoke what the [ __ ] is that very
rare
six months ago well no you're not from
[ __ ] BC you know they all in the 90s
it was very rare like most people that
are from BC were born in the [ __ ] 90s
you know yeah like it just wasn't
populated it wasn't populated the
population was Tiny and like what I was
told actually I'm not sure if it's
totally true but I think it's believable
was like in the 80s they were offering
offering stimulus sort of situations for
people to move to BC because it was so
underpopulated and they were even like
doing that to like you know lower income
people like we'll give you money and
we'll give you a free trip to go to you
know the [ __ ] Vancouver area like it
just wasn't populated right so by the
90s
the great majority was not from there it
just that's it's true the Cannabis moved
out there again like why everybody moves
out there they think well you know it's
beautiful it's more climatized and so on
all the power to them for sure you know
but again the genetics and the the
techniques and the and the information
in their heads it's come from Ontario I
mean there's a a breeder out on the
island he thinks he's a pretty great
Gardener I think he's okay you know
um besides you know
um but he's not from [ __ ] BC you know
he's from he's from this [ __ ] town
you know but like recently maybe dark
enemies from here Chris Clay Chris
Clay's from here you know I don't know
about you know some of the other Growers
sure there's phenomenal Growers
everywhere BC definitely has but we're
seeing a lot of podcasts now right like
this where a lot of people are speaking
out and like see Ray not from BC scabby
not from BC Jay not from BC like every
single person that that has spoken out
about BC is not from BC right right I
don't think we've heard what I almost
moved out to BC I mean I got I got bit
by the bug also like everybody and
um just some beautiful [ __ ] people
out there and it is a lot stronger there
because the laws were a lot more
forgiving there it is
um but you know when it when push comes
to shove you ask the people like okay
where are you from
if they say BC ask them when they're
born because you know it's not like they
I'm surprised they got [ __ ] maternity
Wards in [ __ ] Vancouver because
nobody's from [ __ ] Vancouver but
there's some there's some right like
like
less than an hour I was off the plane we
were smoking texts at a time warp yeah
and like there was a whole bunch of
Americans there like like our whole like
deadhead crew that was in Vancouver like
we were strong supporters of the island
organic outdoor you know like that was
good [ __ ] it wasn't good yeah that'd be
a good story for red too if you ever
want to break
but there's a lot of cool people in BC
there's a lot of good growers in BC and
if somebody's like insulted at the fact
that like BC isn't everything maybe
you're not growing great weed if you're
that insecure you know yeah I mean I can
throw like obviously like I Mendo Mendo
has some similarities and humble too
because like as like you know you start
talking about like oh well where were
you born you know and I mean I'm a
transplant out here now granted I ended
up getting here a lot earlier
um you know like uh than most people and
I've lived out here a long time but I'm
not from here right and you know when
you look at the map of Canada almost all
Canadians are from where you guys are
yeah yeah in the large population
Southwestern Ontario and like I was
saying before in the last podcast where
because of how we're situated the great
lakes and glacial runoff we have some of
the best soil in Canada I mean people
don't probably realize this oil in
Canada Canada is a huge place but like
that's mostly you look at it like I I
think it's like 80 90 of the people in
Canada live within 100 kilometers of the
Border or something like that even even
that I was I was kind of like well
because like Matt thought when we said
London we're talking about BC like his
geography is like way out but like
I was trying to explain to like my
American friends that like we can't just
say Ontario we can't just say BC because
it's too huge like BC right I was just
saying even the coastal area you have
all these independent islands that are
like a place in themselves then you have
Vancouver then you have like the the
Vancouver Island which could be split up
in sections then you have the Kootenays
which is like [ __ ] 12 hours down the
road that way like it's just totally
different places and when you say BC
like I'm sure the Coots had much better
um Quality because it was smaller and
the Vancouver area and the coastal area
was so big it was so commercial that it
was just it gets flooded with commercial
yeah it was so [ __ ] flooded with
commercial it was hard to find good weed
because there was so much commercial to
get rid of it was like nobody had time
to even think about quality it was just
like it's because a lot of the organized
uh Growers organized crime Growers yeah
that's where they were going to be
around but when you get into like the
Kootenays to Nelson area you know when
you get into the kind family mentality
that still grow For the Love of the the
plant so yeah again air quality the
movement people not the industry people
if you're in the industry you are going
to be in probably Vancouver uh you're
going to be someplace west of Hope
um and south of Whistler kind of thing
and then you uh get on onto the island
same thing you're going to get more of
the the kind family uh Vibe and
mentality right yeah I spent some time
out in Nelson and win law that area
and they were just like you know what
they grew phenomenal I named my dog yeah
it was called you know our friend our I
gotta mention because he passed away I
don't know a couple years ago maybe
cormy's Farms yeah yeah he passed away
uh not long ago but he he was like a lot
of our friends are there right a lot of
the people we grew up are there yeah
I would say like of that of like like my
age people that were brought up there
like 90 went to the Coots I would say
like the drum circles I used to have at
organic we used to have all like the the
hippies that would hippie kids I call
them like
kids were your age maybe even a little
bit younger
um they used to all come to the organic
travel of I did drum circles on Sundays
or something like that I say 90 of them
ended out in the Nelson area and
probably a good portion of them [ __ ]
played in wasabi kind of thing like they
were all well but that's the thing like
there was uh
uh in London they were called kangaroo
right this band they were like a little
fun damn band called kangaroo but like
they all like when they when
go to college they went there and like
everybody went there yeah but then you
had uh you had uh
um [ __ ] on my dipstick what are they
called Jimmy's band back here Yaki
Mystic yeah
kangaroo and those guys right like oh
Jimmy went with them Jimmy was with well
that because that when they all got
there they joined up with uh Wasabi
Collective like Jimmy was in there yeah
yeah so I mean that's what I was trying
to get at about you know the the
Cannabis industry and you know I invite
anybody that wants to challenge me on
[ __ ] you know East Coast West Coast
where'd all the Growers come like you
know you think about it
um yeah it's not a pissing contest you
know it's not a pissing contest you get
yeah
but it is for some right and like and
that kind of brings me into my my next
thing because when I talk about you know
Legend seeds right and and uh Sol
um they're from this area right yeah and
they're old friends and I I listen back
on my uh on the last podcast and I use
the words the term we a lot when I talk
about these guys because they're friends
yeah but when it came to their breeding
and stuff like that Legends and and Sol
um I was just I wasn't part of their
um
their company or part of their their
group I was friends with them I was
there I might have you know
um did whatever they wanted me to do
kind of thing as helping out a friend
but I wasn't ever when I say we I don't
mean I helped breed anything with these
guys that is a friend's Circle it was
like yeah it was and it brought me to
another point where in my book there's a
typo which I'm surprised
uh Steve hasn't
come and [ __ ] try to fire by my house
yet but um when we were talking about
the uh the fast fear which we spoke
about oh yeah you said that though the
last one you said this already
guys on the on the very last paragraph
of the one
um chapter it says I grew it was
supposed to say I grew an award-winning
strain okay and it said I bread oh no
train sure and but it taught the whole
chapter it just talks about me being a
grower and being a grower there and
working for Mr hemp and you know I
answered to Steve it was his program and
uh but the very last thing was just it
was a typo and Greg brought it up and I
was like oh [ __ ] man Steve's gonna kill
me because he thinks I'm trying to you
know yeah steal his [ __ ] Limelight
even though he stole my medal but uh
trying to Jack his STEEZ
you know I think that's a common thing
in cannabis actually because of how in
the shadows and clandestine it is yeah I
do the same thing dude where some of the
stories I tell where it's we it's like
there's people that are known and
there's people that are unknown some of
those people that are unknown wish to
remain unknown yeah you know and so
you're trying to tell history and tell a
story but you have to sort of edit it to
some degree because what you're giving
is accurate information right and then
the flip side of that is that there's
people
that wannabe can of famous yeah right
and they want to aggregate all the fame
to them and so even if it might have
been a collective of friends all doing
it they're going to tell the story like
it was them alone in their basement
working for 10 years and then they came
out with all this and no one else has
[ __ ] to do with it when you know
personally that there was like seven
other dudes and it was this loose
Collective of friends that were all
involved in this breeding happened at
this house then and then this accident
happened over here and then this
happened and it can be kind of weird to
tell stories that way because a lot of
money is made on
you know every breeder and mics except
for maybe Neville but most breeders are
like well no Neville was very clear
about I got this from this person
I did this and this almost all breeders
after him were like this never existed
before I carefully crafted it and no one
else has had any of these genetics ever
yeah
[ __ ] land race kind of yeah like like
they just obscure yeah I'm gonna I'm
gonna break in because like not to
interrupt the flow but I didn't get to
actually ask my question when we were
talking about the BC stuff and I want to
ask this question do it so we're gonna
but it kind of is the same thing because
it's a dishonesty thing or like an
illusion thing I guess you would say but
like that conversation going back to
that conversation when you were
disappointed
um you mentioned something and at the
time you mentioned it I kind of thought
you were crazy like I didn't like I
didn't know because I didn't know right
when somebody tells you something you
don't know you're kind of like what but
you said something about High Times and
hyping
what's that magazine or the store
the magazine that like BC was only got
really popular because High Times was
hyping them to kind of draw attention to
them
do you remember this conversation
no no well what I what I remember which
this could be totally false was that you
were like BC was like hyping up the big
bud because at the time like BC was
really blowing up as like right but you
were like
the magazine was kind of like trying to
draw attention from the US and DEA
attention to to BC
um I don't remember that conversation
but I mean part of that sounded a little
familiar okay I think what High Times is
trying to pimp was because California
was such a huge market for cannabis
Counter Culture yeah right because High
Times isn't a candidates magazine right
it's a count of Culture magazine so
that's why it has so much music it has
so much uh cannabis is only a section of
it right and then for a few years they
got rid of it right they didn't have
canvas for a few years
um and that's when they started grow
America for for a little bit but
um I think because the term BC Bud right
anything Canada was BC Bud right right
right so
I think they were pimping that
as well as because of the climate you
could have larger outdoor grows than we
could in Ontario okay
um they wouldn't go into Quebec where
you could also have fairly large
outgrows because of the language barrier
um so I think for High Times
I wouldn't say I know for for a fact but
pretty damn sure with my interaction
with them that they were pushing the BC
Bud because of its popularity in
California because your top dollar you
know anything from your tuna cans
[ __ ] anything that was the BC bud got
the top dollar and okay and then I mean
I mean there's a name that we mentioned
uh in our last talk and he was a broker
he's still in the industry he's I think
he's a [ __ ] great guy he knows he
knows a lot of history of this uh of
this movement from the West Coast but he
was a broker and uh he used to sell be
able to sell a certain type of outdoor
and it was uh it was a pink something
but uh he was selling for twenty nine
hundred dollars
a pound for out to LA because it was
that's nothing though people were
selling 32.
for out yeah I realized that but this is
outdoor
um what year is this I was Canadian or
U.S what year
oh okay okay
the beaster era yeah I would say like
late 90s oh so like people and I it was
so it was strained I think it was called
sotica
cream sodica
yeah so we grew that out in Switzerland
actually yeah and uh the guy that's
growing it is a I'm gonna use the word
douchebag again which I said I was
trying not to use but this guy's a
[ __ ] douchebag he ran the uh farm
that I was uh hired to work on in uh in
the interior
and um his name's Jay I don't know his
last name I wish I knew his last name
but I'd say it here too what was the
cream sodaka like I the first time I
ever saw that it was really unique uh
plant uh it had really bright uh pink
stigmas in it where
um it wasn't a huge producer but it it
grew kind of like a really short kind of
like the pink freeze land which I
wouldn't be surprised if it might have
you know again traveled West which a lot
of genetics did back in the day as we've
talked about before that was just like
you know it wasn't a very strong
structured plant but it just grew all
these golf balls that would just would I
mean maybe a little bit easier to trim
but just look beautiful rock hard it
would give you the the BC bag of marbles
again it's kind of what I call a lot of
the you know any pot that comes across
my desk nowadays I can basically look at
it and tell you where it come from by
bag appeal because you know BC had the
tendency for a while there of not
trimming the pot but shaping it so every
nug looked like a [ __ ] marble right
yeah right you know but I mean if back
when they were making tons of extract so
they were trimming off a lot of the
stuff because they knew they were uh to
be able to use it kind of thing and then
you got the bag of marbles the BC bag of
marbles that uh was just kind of a look
so I think that the cream sodica was um
uh was a strain that was
kind of easy for their outdoor to look
like indoor yeah and that's why bubble
was able to [ __ ]
you know for ridiculous amounts of money
I mean that strain out here called the
West Coast dog like that it's just
outdoor for indoor type [ __ ] that's been
the game I mean and where I live in
Mendo it's like that's been the game
forever of yeah Brokers being like well
this outdoor pass is light depth yeah
does this light depth look good enough
to pass as indoor yeah
um because where there was uneducated
areas of the country or whatever they
were like can I can I put this into a
different bracket right can I buy this
for what it is but claim it's the next
grade up there's tons of people I mean
again that's the that's the industry
enveloping the movement the movement
right because there's going to be people
like myself that say Hey listen you know
it's outdoor it looks like indoor you
know but [ __ ] I I'm gonna be honest with
you and if you want to be dishonest
after that that's up to you but I'm
probably going to charge you
[ __ ] uh more money you're gonna pay a
[ __ ] tax on something that looks
spectacular I don't give a [ __ ] if it's
indoor outdoor or [ __ ] Greenhouse or
you know small crop large crop you know
hand trim machine trim you know like
there's there's so many variables at the
end of the day if it [ __ ] looks good
smells good and [ __ ] kicks you in the
nuts then what the [ __ ] who cares how
it's grown for me I think like what do
we what do we do when we grow indoor all
we're trying to do is mimic outdoor
we're trying to mimic from other nature
mother nature has the [ __ ] the
formula down where now we're able to
with technology and so on we're a lot we
can better mother nature but for the
longest time we were just trying to
reproduce Outside Inside
I do think we can do everything better
than nature indoor yeah except for the
Sun
no no of course you can I mean the sun
is the sun's still by far is the best
light right and I've done all kinds of
spectrum experience
and all this and you know to some degree
it's interesting too because like all
almost all of the award-winning hash
made in California is all made with the
Sun right you know they don't use indoor
grown stock indoor might get you know
humans are so visual that indoor might
look prettier
right you know
um and I I also wanted to make a comment
when you guys were talking about Ontario
you know just different areas there
could be a lot just for the simple fact
that BC Bud Rhymes yeah yeah you know
well yeah Southwestern Ontario nug
doesn't really like what do you what do
you call Ontario weed like so you know I
live in Mendocino County or whatever and
like
whether it came from Trinity or
Mendocino or Sonoma or or whatnot if it
went on dead tour it was Humboldt County
organic outdoor yeah exactly well and
that's what I was going to say like what
you were mentioning is you know humble
is the BC of uh
of the states pretty much right like
anybody that was anybody that wanted to
be a pot grower moved to California then
once they were like oh we're in
California now what do we do like humble
again probably didn't have a [ __ ]
Maternity Ward didn't need one because
there was only a few [ __ ] people that
live there and then all of a sudden the
Cannabis craze came and of course they
were like oh well I move up there I can
name it [ __ ] Humble County
yeah I'll tell you when I first moved to
Mendocino County in the 90s there was so
few people moving here from outside that
everyone thought I was a cop
yeah oh yeah also because because you
look like a cop yeah yeah yeah well you
know and [ __ ] that dude I I can tell you
I mean we want to talk about dead tour
the first time I saw a cop tackle
somebody on the lot with dreadlocks down
to his ass and then pull out handcuffs
yeah I was like oh yeah yeah no no I'd
say you can't tell what a undercover cop
looks like but you can tell what regular
cop looks like yeah I'm like that you
know but the only reason I said that is
because it was before like what we call
the green Rush yeah where people weren't
moving like people didn't move to the
towns that I was moving to yeah like
out-of-towners didn't come there within
five six years as medical Advanced and
sort of the green Rush occurred it got
overwhelmed by much like you were saying
with BC yeah almost none of the Growers
from Mendo were born in Mendo right they
were all transplants I mean there was a
small core certainly that was from there
yeah but if you added them up by like
number it was probably like 90 90 10.
that's the same thing with BC like again
I'm not gonna pull you know I I think BC
had has produced and still does produce
uh phenomenal Growers I'm just saying
that back in the day most of those
Growers and therefore a lot of their
genetics
um came from you know East or south
I mean there's there's a debate on that
too like not so much in but just in the
sense of where is something from yeah
exactly you know like like the you know
we have this you know the whole thing
came from came through it came through
because there's this whole thing we're
like oh the cush is from Florida
well what's the story of the Kush and
they're like oh well is this clone from
the Emerald Triangle
and then pollen from some stuff we got
from Neville and Holland right but it
happened in Florida
right you know so I see and again back
when I was growing the kush before it
was kush kind of thing it was just
basically the you know from the Kush
region of Afghanistan like I would say
if people say well where's the where's
the Hindu Kush from well probably the
Hindu Kush mountains right like these
are they might have you know took a
cutting or a seed you know they might
have brought something back during the
war times you know which a lot of the
genetics did you know come from soldiers
returning from [ __ ] overseas and
bringing seed that they uh that they
grabbed and planted in California
Florida [ __ ] Wyoming anywhere
everywhere it was just what ended up
happening is where all the uh cool
people or where the the population that
were like-minded ended up moving to in
Canada it would be BC you know in
California it was going to be probably
San Francisco
or that area
um
following kind of the whole hippie
movement and so on so I would say I
don't say
I shouldn't say that the strain oh their
genetics came from uh Southwest South
Southwestern Ontario I could say that
they most likely came through and they
probably came through California to get
to BC but again when you get strains
like Texada text at a time warp there's
certain
um and I was I found some seed that from
Gabriola right like
um where they come from I'm sure there's
people on the island that will claim or
and rightfully so say well Texada came
from Texada because they came from
California and we took uh we took pollen
from Ontario or we took pollen from
[ __ ] you know some seed that we got
out of Africa you know I used to order
seeds from [ __ ] Africa back in ham
Nation days like literally from
uh uh uh seats dealer out of [ __ ] yeah I
think I don't know if it was South
Africa the swazi and swazi pepper and
there's another stream
but uh you know I would use that in my
breeding program
I'm gonna put that in quotations again I
would use that when I was making seeds
and uh
that made that strain from here right
did it originate here yes the seed did
but the genetics that it came from
obviously didn't come from here because
we have very little if any land races as
same as BC has very little to any same
as you know California they might they
might have a land race there I don't
know of one
right but no land race no no I mean I
think I think most most California
breeding if I had to guess like what the
very Inception of California breeding is
it was like how do we make these sativas
that we're getting free seeds with these
kilos we're getting how do we make them
finish in our area yeah oh well I have
some Mexican and that stuff seems to
finish earlier so maybe I'll take some
of this Thai or Colombian and I'll cross
it to Mexican yeah that was literally
very like very it was very I don't think
people had goals other than the fact of
like I need this to finish before
January well I think that's where a lot
of the you know genetics were built and
why they were built because I know and
that's why again going back to the East
Coast West Coast
um we had draft Dodgers that [ __ ] ran
the border and uh and brought their
genetics up to Southwestern Ontario
again because being so close to Detroit
so close to uh Buffalo you know the most
southern part of this country
um the soil the so on so forth Perth
County conspiracy the whole kind of deal
um what were we breeding for what was I
breeding for I wasn't breeding for
anything other than I want to take that
[ __ ] strain and grow it in my house
in my basement and I don't want to run
it for 14 weeks right so I'm gonna find
so and again my a lot of my I miss I was
a sativa lover so I wanted if I could
grow uh an original Haze in six weeks
that produced uh that one and a half
pounds per light I mean heaven so that's
where I was that's my whole program
that's what it was about when I used the
I used to read Neville's catalogs and
Scentsy and God anything that was in
that 45 to 50 day range just looked
attractive it did and I just you know I
I didn't get any I didn't believe any of
this [ __ ] I really put the [ __ ] uh
the Amsterdam guys through a lot of [ __ ]
in my years just because I called
[ __ ] on a lot of them because I grew
out a lot of their strains and I was
just like this is you know I'm at 60
days I'm not going to argue out of 55 or
60 Day flower right that's fine with me
inside but you're saying 45 today 45 to
50 days and like yeah don't know about
that you know and they'll give me the
[ __ ] yields yeah I don't know about
that you know like but again maybe again
that's business though they need to they
want to sell that seed and they want to
sell that seed to be
um attractive to the indoor grower or
attracted to the North American grower
who if they are going to grow outdoors
they want it to be done uh in September
they need it to be done by October you
know I mean when you when you look at
like California history before the
helicopters people were fine with things
taking into November right no big deal
when there was no police pressure and
they weren't worried about their crop
getting chopped yeah November is fine
all of a sudden you get camp and you get
all these helicopters in the sky and
they're like when can I pull down in
September yeah that extra two months is
a real prop three months is an extra
problem we had snow that we had to worry
about up here right like the cops the
cops here go out in August right so the
Choppers are there in August September
maybe kind of thing right because uh we
have to be down ideally
end of September early October if you go
anything past that bud rot and stuff
like that you know we still get the
humidity we are surrounded by the Great
Lakes we get you know we get the cold uh
the hot days the cold nights we get Bud
rot like you wouldn't [ __ ] believe
you know I believe I I believe it I mean
I I think as as some of these states
like New York and New Jersey and and a
lot of these New England start to open
up and what they want is they want all
these California bread strains yeah I
know uh because that's what's famous and
they want to sell the name but what they
really should be after is the Canadian
bread stuff well they again but they're
like we were saying before the BC bud is
going to sell the SW Ontario Bud they're
gonna what the [ __ ] does that mean right
even the Quebec nug Quebec Bud they're
gonna say oh I I know of Quebec they're
not going to know of Ontario and Ontario
is the biggest [ __ ] most populated
state
um it definitely by far has the most pop
growers in it simply because of per
capita the amount of [ __ ] maybe not
per capita but because of the amount of
uh people's population
right but it's um it's going to be a
hard sell to say Canadian Canadian buds
it's all hot they're all going to say BC
Bud right and it's marketing that's uh
it's what's going to sell it kind of
thing unfortunately or you know
fortunately whatever to me I really
don't could give any a [ __ ] of a less
honestly but um
you know it is it is hard for
me here trying to sell down into the
states
unless they they knew me or they knew
the uh genetics I was growing and High
Times their office knew what I was doing
because I used to fly down there with
um
weighed out eighths and wait out
quarters in glass jars uh
I also what was it it was a 25th
anniversary party they had Cypress Hill
and Joan Jett and whoever else
um I supplied all the pot to that party
because
High Times couldn't really afford like
back then especially the high-end pot
all the super super nice nugs that you
see in that magazine and you see Snoop
Dogg with a big [ __ ] plate of buds in
front of them and fake joints they rent
all that pot they rent it they rent it
rent you can rent weed yeah they rent
weed for the Photoshop for the photo op
and then anything that is smoked they're
paying four or five six hundred dollars
an ounce
so they're just when they were telling
me that uh they're like oh [ __ ] men
they're all [ __ ] big fat
[ __ ] uh blunt that's gonna cost us
[ __ ] 300 you know what a bunch of
clowns yeah I'll do it well you gotta
remember what era it was though too I
mean yeah it was it was it was
ridiculous
you know I know Sean was trying to get
us to talk about like our our uh you
know some of our Amsterdam and cup
experiences because we overlapped but
you know when I would go I went to three
cups in the 90s I think like 95 97 98
right right and what I experienced was
that like you were just saying all the
best weed was set aside for like the
celebrities yep and the people that were
gonna pay top dollar for it and the
people that wanted to show up and like
they didn't care if they dropped Mad
Coin so it was actually like one of the
worst weeks or months to visit Amsterdam
yeah because if you were just a normal
person they're like well we have good
weed but we're gonna sell it for three
times what it's worth yeah because uh
North American Tax right you're gonna
pay the North American Tax because we
have all these celebrities coming in and
we have all these musicians and stuff
and these entourages right we've got all
this weed and hash side aside just for
them and we're going to charge them out
the nose for it and so we can't give it
to you unless you want to pay this like
exorbitant price yeah and so it was like
it gets ridiculous and again New York is
the same way La was the same way New
York and La obviously were the highest
markets uh I think ever any place in the
world and when High Times used to do
like in the very back of the pages like
the prices from around the world and
around the country and how much a an
eighth was and how much an ounce was and
so it was always La in New York at the
[ __ ] top kind of thing but with with
um with uh with working with high times
and
Kyle knew my genetics like I said when
he was coming here to buy it uh and and
shipping it back to uh Detroit
I would send uh I would send nugs down
to him
um and we had a thing going where I'd
mail it to the High Times office
and then inside I'd be like I hope this
gets you busted you [ __ ] douchebags
and and putting in all this you know
hate mail with a half pound of pot in it
kind of thing right and uh when the 25th
anniversary uh party was coming up they
reached out to me and said Hey listen
you know would you be interested in you
know selling us pot and I say you know
sure I was like I I mean we've been
doing it enough
kind of thing I said
um what were you guys thinking they
threw out a number and it was something
like
like three grand a pound or something
like that
and I said uh I said and U.S
so I said okay let me think about it and
I'm like thank you to myself what
[ __ ] kind of people are these [ __ ]
morons so I had called back up I said
listen I can't take three grand you know
and then Kyle's like you know Pete
that's pretty fair I was like okay I'll
do this I'll take 2 400 a pound right
U.S
and I'm Gonna Mail a few boxes of jars
so I didn't like I didn't mail Ziploc
freezer bag half pounds of pot other
than what they wanted for the party
which was just a few pounds or something
like that but I mailed probably
at least a pound that was already
weighed out and in and sealed in glass
jars with [ __ ] homemade labels on
every jar and I would uh I would mail
them uh separately and then when I got
down there I sat in Steve's office I was
either bloomy's office or um
um
there's one other office anyways I would
just I would sit in their office and
they would come in like one at a time
and choose I was like and I was like
listen it's [ __ ]
um
I I think I was
stiffing them a little bit I might have
charged 50 bucks an eighth kind of thing
um because I could and it was like
I was shipping literally jars that were
cured and it was like my my nicest stuff
I got that's a risk I got to sit on the
couch with Jack Herrera and I was super
stoked because I was like listen Jack I
want you to uh smoke this
um uh golden Haze it's my strain I bred
it but I used some genetics that you
know with these nl5 skunk one that made
his that sense he used to make his
strain yeah um I used some of that
uh
uh I used a uh
a version of keeping that kind of blend
in mind because it was exactly what I
wanted in my stream I wanted like I said
before a short fat sativa
giving high from a plant that's going to
finish in less than 60 days and I could
grow in a [ __ ] room with nine foot
ceilings yeah and it was like when he
when he you know tried my my stuff and
he's like wow that's [ __ ] really nice
tasty so on so forth
I it made my [ __ ] it made my career
at that time kind of thing just to get
there and and smoke a joint with them at
the same time having
um
who's the head of who is a Hagar Hagar
yeah Hager yeah Stephen Hager yeah so I
would I think I was sitting in his
office actually because he was the head
honcho and uh I was selling [ __ ]
uh quarters and eighths and [ __ ] like
that pre-jarred up to the entire staff
kind of negative and then the party was
you know that night and I was just like
they paid me [ __ ] ridiculous amount I
mean and I took less far less than what
they were offering me because I was kind
of honored one that I can yeah you know
Supply the pot but I was also making a
shitload of money by selling them my
private
uh Growers jar collection kind of [ __ ]
so that's a testament to London because
like you don't know how hard it is like
being on on the internet and talking to
weed guys trying to say that
Southwestern Ontario had [ __ ] great
pot nobody believed it nobody
they have great pot man all you have is
[ __ ] cities and cornfields but again
it comes down to population when you
when you have
10 to 15 times the amount of people
jammed into a certain area
there's gonna be phenomenal pot growers
as well as the
the the people that really want to find
that unique strain
and they travel the world maybe not for
pot
but due to the amount of people
the population they travel all over the
world and if they [ __ ] find pot in
Thailand or North Africa or someplace
and like oh I got a couple seats I'm
gonna throw in my [ __ ] in my shoe
yeah and it's just because of the amount
of people that we have coming back here
and again why I would always say that I
think Southwest Ontario produces some of
the best
pot growers and
um genetics
uh passing through
uh in Canada
a lot of that though is due to community
building because like you know the hemp
Nation thing like when that happened and
you were offering what you did at that
place a lot of people learned a lot
it literally planted the seed for a lot
of people right because yeah Chris gave
uh gave people the option to buy their
own seed not take bagweed and find a
seed and not know you know what the [ __ ]
it is we were we were kind of weeding
out some of that we were telling you uh
what it is we can we'll tell you it's
going to be something within this range
because it is an F1 we just took this
Scentsy seed and we took this greenhouse
seed and we grew them and this is what
we got
and the mother was this and the dad was
this and this is what they look like and
that's when they finished and and so on
so we gave him an educated guess but it
was literally planting the seed of
people uh when I started that uh grow
your tuition campaign in in London here
just for all the students right giving
them discounts I had a coupon on a on a
flyer that gave them a discount on grow
guides and uh and then like I said uh
information the best thing about
information is it's free if you uh
wanted to come down on the Sundays and
we have cultivation talks you know I
didn't mind sharing that I [ __ ] love
talking that's what we're doing right
now right like yeah we were doing this
back in the mid 80s mid 90s kind of
thing
it's really awesome it's actually really
hard for me
to tell people today with like what
we're doing right now and all the forums
and IG and all the ways that people can
connect how tough it was to get
information
how how small groups used to be how rare
it was to find people that like knew
what they were doing
um and then the other thing is like I
always I'd still consider like 90s to be
like the Golden Era of weed
um just in the sense because
basically any like weed was rare enough
that it could take too long it could not
look that great as long as it worked
really well yeah it was going to gain
popularity you know because there was
there was only so much of it so like a
lot of the famous strains in the 90s
Rose to the top because they were really
good yeah you know yeah and they didn't
really have
I think a lot of people nowadays you
know
um the placebo effect comes into play a
lot with all these new genetics sure
there's a lot of fire out there but
there's people that are just like oh
well this is this strain right oh this
is a Kush oh well and it has the smell
of a Kush but it has a you know it
doesn't really rock you like some of the
other yeah but since it since it you
know smells like it looks like it [ __ ]
it must [ __ ] be the close enough and
then they're just like oh yeah I'm super
high I'm super high you know I've done
that with my my clients at The
Compassion Center where they were they
were like oh you know what I Northern
Lights doesn't work for me it's you know
I've tried it and it's it's just um
you know I smoked it back in the 80s it
I I didn't like it didn't didn't get me
high okay well the Northern Lights I
have is not the same but I give them the
northern lights that is fire for other
people they're like yeah it didn't
really do it for me I mean your mind is
quite strong tool yeah so I would do the
same thing and I was Infamous with my
organic traveler crew like all the the
you know glassblowers that were
downstairs and all this that thought
they were these these pot snobs and
they'd be the same thing like oh yeah
you know what that's that stuff's you
know it's not that great okay well they
had that tasty Bud [ __ ] that little
[ __ ] flavoring crap oh God yeah
implant Juicy J's tasty buds yeah
whatever [ __ ] so I would actually take
some of that and I would take [ __ ]
great pot but you know fragile this one
glass blower uh he was just always
against like yeah I know that but he was
like oh I had this Cherry Bomb once and
it was [ __ ] awesome so I [ __ ] took
the Cherry yeah did a little light mist
on it kind of thing and put it in your
jar and let it sit there and and uh same
[ __ ] string that I gave him right
yeah made the nugs look a little bit
different made them look a little bit
smaller I was like Hey listen this is
not called Cherry Bomb it's called
cherry blossom this guy just came
through he's from uh uh a tobacco or
[ __ ] Peterborough and he opens it up
and he's like oh yeah it smells me like
this is good and [ __ ] smokes he's
like yeah that's [ __ ] see we need to
try and this this strain I was like [ __ ]
you dude that's the goddamn what's that
we [ __ ] you smoke [ __ ] two weeks
ago you said with [ __ ] you know it's
tasty butt on it and now none of those
guys would [ __ ] trust me to give him
any [ __ ] pot I know oh [ __ ] no yeah
you ruined that [ __ ] you man that's
[ __ ] tasty Vibe and I was like no
it's actually not kind of thing but so
yeah we've been accused of using that on
uh some of the blueberry stuff we put
out
the tasty Bud stuff like when people
smell like good blueberry stuff yeah
this is a syrup I think a lot of people
you know
um and if you smell my B-93 like it
doesn't it smells like uh not the
blueberry smell but it smells like a a
pint of actual blueberries right you
know I see a little bit more that that
sweet earthy Aroma kind of thing and
again it's from it's from 93. that's
when we started the seed right like it's
an it's an old [ __ ] plant kind of
thing right I got them I'm going back to
that that era and it would have been
I would I would have gotten indirectly
uh okay or basically it was when he was
first releasing his blueberries if I
remember correctly I mean Tony could
have had it earlier don't get me wrong
but I think that Tony had with Simon and
they had cerebral
in 94. right and then they split and
Tony made sag Martha and Simon made
serious yeah you know but I think I
think Dan I think DJ Short was with um
Tony with Tony and uh they did the
bubble gum and they called it 94
blueberry if I remember correctly yeah
he worked with Tony he sold it through
Tony first and then they had some
falling out and then I think he moved to
Dutch Passion yes yeah and he got angry
at all of them and then he and then he
moved it to Canada yeah yeah yeah yeah
and that's the thing is and this is
where
um he met up with Steve and red and I'll
call him the air mechanic because I
don't know of a nickname for him but uh
he was uh
great grower
um
didn't do anything huge like 12 lights
or something but I I not if I'm not
mistaken again red would be the better
uh
uh information on background on this but
I believe they bred the blue satellite
okay or I know they were doing a grow
out for DJ and
um
but that was a little bit later so I the
seed that I got was just before that and
that's where I was thinking that it
might have came indirectly
from DJ
um but it would have been like I thought
it would I know it was 93 but I thought
it was actually from him and not from
from Tony from is it is it a clone
that's still alive yeah
oh
um
I literally just killed off like six 75
to 80 of my genetics yeah guys I'm just
I'm retiring I'm tired really frustrated
I was actually there today trying to
salvage what
um one of my staff
uh from the center he's like if you
could save me all these strains I'll
find somebody to grow to to babysit them
for you until you get over this divorce
[ __ ] and if I wanted to go into it like
out of the hundred and
123 strains that I had
I had data collected on their use
medical uses through the compassion uh
Center going back almost 15 years yeah
so because in Canada we cannot say well
this trade works for this medical
condition sure
um what I could do is saying out of the
30 people that suffer from Ms this is
their the top selling Indica this is the
top selling sativa I think that's
responsible actually and it would just
be basically giving them
um
well it's data
say again it's data to use I mean
like literally for almost 15 years I've
collected this that's the most important
[ __ ] I had it all [ __ ] ready and
packaged to go into the LPS up here and
I just [ __ ] saw the dark side of the
[ __ ] industry that was just chewing
and spitting out anybody from the
movement yeah and I took a lot of heat
from people I think we talked about this
last time from you know people in the
movement that thought I sold out by
going to um
uh into the lb
um legally I mean it's crazy because
it's what you've been working for your
entire life you know yeah it's like
[ __ ] like that's [ __ ] crazy you
can't [ __ ] steer the boat if you're
standing on the shore [ __ ] yelling
like get on the phone well I mean as
like in the best Direction you can and
that's what I was doing with my genetics
I was like I can't I'm again
strange names or names to me because I'm
I'm out for the medical benefits of it I
don't give a [ __ ] what you call it
that's going to come back to the dog
[ __ ]
um where it doesn't it didn't really
make a difference now I had a I had a
strain that called warm diarrhea right
oh okay wise
really marketable yeah you know it was
this one strain didn't produce was a
[ __ ]
but holy God Jesus did it ever smell
like dog [ __ ] [ __ ] warm diarrhea like
hot summer time [ __ ] diarrhea
squirted like kind of smell yeah
[ __ ] I know it phenomenal
it's like so I called it that I was like
I don't I don't know what it is it's a
[ __ ] clone that I went to I was
Consulting a guy's Garden he [ __ ]
said these are my strains I said where
are they from he's like I [ __ ] you know
my brother-in-law gave me some of this
and some of that and I found some seed
and this and that and this one [ __ ]
one plant was like holy God Jesus that's
nasty I Gotta Have It kind of thing and
um
you know with uh with Sam when he was
doing his skunk and um everybody was
like oh it's you know you that that and
I was just having this conversation
today actually with my cousin because
he's like I had a skunk one back when uh
back when uh Tilly was [ __ ] growing
for the center right and I'll find the
picture because it made it was a full
page picture in high times and it's this
kid holding one of the nugs up and he's
holding his forearm and the nug is twice
the size of this kid's Forum oh wow that
was my skunk one and it's you know you
grow the true skunk one I I believe is
mainly grown for structure more than
that skunky smell if I'm not mistaken I
think Sammy was actually trying to get
rid of uh and I think I was that's his
claim yeah you guys will cover this you
don't you don't follow like modern IG
culture and stuff but like there's been
a massive massive movement on finding
roadkill skunk which everyone because I
was gonna I'm making that this the
cuttings that I sent out west today
this guy and I don't know his [ __ ]
name I'll find out but he sent one of my
uh Sasquatch the kid that works for me
uh who's like the Cannabis connoisseur
he ended up getting
um this [ __ ] jar of skunk one I
opened it up and I was like
holy [ __ ] that's my skunk one it smells
like and I called it roadkill skunk one
I didn't know that was a name called
roadkill I was yeah yeah it's not a
strain though it's just it's just a
reference to a type of expression that
can come from afghanis or skunky plants
okay well this uh this skunk one grew
the the structure and the and my cousin
just said listen if you get it I want to
breed with it because
um
it has
the if it's the same cut that this guy's
sending me I it smells the same the nug
looks the same I have to find out if the
structure is the same because the
structure was what the the skunk one was
all about like yeah have that big nug
that [ __ ] can hold itself and
um
like I said this uh Tilly kid that was
um growing and we're doing on an Evan
flow cable and they were just spikes
they were just these big beautiful
[ __ ] fragrant roadkill smell uh
skunk one
so you know and I think I was I lit I
try to put some of your guys podcasts on
I don't listen to podcasts so in all
honesty the first and only podcast I
really listened to was like three nights
ago when it was while I was going to bed
and I wanted to hear what we did yeah
and uh something else came up and you
guys were talking about Sam's breeding
trying to breed out the skunk one the
skunk yeah you know actually and uh and
uh focusing on structure and I was like
that's ironic because that's what I
wanted but I was also chasing that
um that super skunk kind of uh Aroma
yeah and it was this roadkill like Yeah
because it doesn't smell like skunk when
you spray it that tarry kind of burnt
[ __ ] stuff it had that [ __ ] you
driving down the [ __ ] road and you're
like holy [ __ ] yeah you know that skunk
you know yeah it adds that smell to it
so
um maybe I remember that from like
London I definitely remember skunky
smells and like I I I kind of related to
like the Heineken skunky beer smell more
than animal smell right I have a
question for you Sean this is totally
off topic yeah does Canada get green
Heineken bottles or brown greens not so
yeah great no okay so check it out right
so you can say Jesus Christ but I go to
Holland in the 90s and they have the
Heineken Brewery right is like was again
it moved now like but it was in
Amsterdam and they gave tours you know
and so if you buy a Heineken in Holland
it's in a brown bottle right and you you
talked you talked to like the the Dutch
about it and I'm like well why why is it
in a green bottle in America and they're
like oh cause you guys are dumb but it's
iconic over there so you want the green
bottle but it oxidizes so it makes the
beer go skunky and [ __ ] yeah yeah and if
you get it in Europe it's a dark brown
bottle okay because we don't want the
light to [ __ ] it up but that tastes the
cost of taste
oxidized skunky beer yeah so it's like
and he's like you buy a Heineken
anywhere in Europe it's in a brown
bottle you go to the USA it's in a green
bottle and he's like it's just
advertising we have we have two we had
two beers that were like the pot beers
and it was Heineken and Moosehead
and Moosehead was also in a green box
you know but they both had that very
skunky skunky like to get a six-pack and
and some weed and smoke weed and smoke
like and drink Moosehead was like that
was the thing you know that was like
they paired you know you guys are so
Canadian bro yeah I mean I don't talk I
haven't drank beer and
like 20 years
I I just I you know I just had to throw
it out there because I was like shocked
when they literally were like oh we only
do that to the dumb Americans right
that's like legit what they said you
know and so I was like oh I guess that
includes Canadians but yeah um what's
funny about what's funny about the skunk
you know uh is that like we're all so
old now right there was this thing that
tripped me out because you don't feel
old in your head even though when you're
getting old where I saw this thing where
like the 90s are as far away now as the
60s were in the 90s yeah
right and so there's all these smokers
that like they all the stuff we're
talking about all this stuff that's like
our youth you know and you know in our
20s and everything else that was so
common this is all legendary just words
now
the reason why they're hunting that
skunk is because it's gone away and
while it was super common in the 90s and
there was lots of weed that was very
skunky or had skunk type Terps
it's kind of gone away
you know and so now it's like you know
we were talking about how BC Bud Rhymes
or whatever but like Northern all these
strains are coming back again and they
don't even have to be the actual strain
anymore
it just has to have the name yeah
because the name is going to survived
the population the users are so young
that they won't know the difference they
don't know why I was smoking the NL back
in the day
um they're not smoking pot anymore kind
of thing right so mark this down you
know like the big the big strain back in
my day was like the nl5 skunk one right
like yeah that was the go-to that was if
you know the center of the road easy to
grow big yield depending on what
phenotype you got you know it kind of
was the best of all worlds and it was
again it was an easy grower kind of
thing but uh you know to find anything
like that I think like pot now is so
bastardized yeah I agree it's it's not
as simple you know and sure
my Matt well I did have another question
we were talking about the triple SC last
time yeah yeah yeah right and so do you
have have any contact to any of the good
old boys that were part of that group
yeah we interviewed them okay Corel the
original owner okay now was he out of
Amsterdam or very much very much so he's
a Dutch born
yeah okay so he's but he's not
originally from the states uh trans he
didn't no he didn't move there from no
he's like he's definitely Dutch okay so
did they have offsprings of the
their group in California no they said
they never worked with anyone in the
United States ever now what now work
with I'm just saying thinking that after
they were there
that they moved that after maybe some of
their colleagues staff or something I
want to find out about the Golden Boy
because the way I what I was told was
that this strain came from
Ontario and I I wouldn't say maybe like
more up Central north of Southwestern
Ontario but it came from the triple SC
or somebody from that group that is now
living in Canada and we're going back to
like like SSC didn't have a strain
called Golden Boy either
they had they had like M1 M2 M3 M4 M5 M6
they'd have little names after but it'd
be like Nigerian Kandahar or skunk one
or uh
basic five it was very very basic
there's Williams Wonder small names like
that no Golden Boy though
can you ask them though like yeah if you
can reach out just ask them because the
story that I had was it came from
from
their group and I believe it was bred by
them and it might have had like an M24
or something yeah yeah
um
but and it was a it was a 45 day
finishing plant and that's what was so
was a [ __ ] crazy wasn't the best
dealer it was a really weird looking
plant but it was 45 days was it an
indica or sativa it was I I would say it
would have leaned I would say I wouldn't
even say it was leaned either way I
would have to look at some of the
pictures that's so fast that I think I
even have
I might have the picture that's like
Mighty might fast isn't it dude it was
super fast it was ridiculously fast it
wasn't a great strain on its own but it
was great for breeding yeah and that's
what I again made the and why it's where
it's called Golden Haze
um because there was other things and it
was chemo and
um uh uh skunk in it
um
and uh we crossed it with the golden boy
because I wanted to speed it up but my
my
um what I was looking for was a fast
growing short fat sativa yeah right so
the um the haze it was a uh uh
Early Skunk
uh chemo
crossed with the haze and then we
crossed it with the Golden Boy to speed
it up and yeah you know see all over the
place I just I found one that seemed to
fit the uh the mold I was looking for
and uh I just caught I didn't have a
seat of it I just had a uh a cutting of
it yeah and then we did breed it with
some other strains my buddy skifa
um who in 40 years passed away but he uh
he crossed it with something blue string
maybe it was even like blue sky got to
look it up I might still have some of
those seeds too but I just wanted to
find the lineage of that Golden Boy
because
um I was told it came from the triple s
c boys early 90s maybe mid 90s so they
were done by then yeah they were done
that's what I mean yeah yeah they were
long gone by then um I'm thinking if it
was Offspring from them yes and even
being off literally Offspring for kids
of theirs or something like that that
moved to Ontario
yeah I wonder I wonder if his son moved
out there because his son took over the
company eventually yeah he's the one who
runs it now yeah yeah and then again
this wasn't anybody that um
I knew it was yeah sure that was a story
that was brought to me and like I said
the strain was a really unique stream
but it was super fast and I was like
[ __ ] we need it was going to be a
breeding staple for us until we grew it
out and we're just like yeah this plant
is [ __ ] up look any kind of [ __ ] did
you really weird [ __ ] did you like c99
at all since you were looking for plants
that were fast hazy uh I'm growing I
haven't seen 99 right now
uh came from this guy tank out of
Toronto area
um I
did grow I'd have to look at my notes
um
it just tends to be one of those ones
that speaks super fast it didn't stand
out as the you know 45 day okay it was
uh it might have been like a 55 day a
lot of the stuff we do was like 56 day
kind of stuff because we had 50 lights
and I needed to produce I needed things
to grow
and finish all around the same time yeah
for the summer and uh we did we did do
this Indy 99 it did have a um uh
uh a following yeah wanted that we did
uh we did want to bring it in
Incorporated that photographer that you
couldn't remember
yeah Andre Grossman yeah somebody
commented yeah I thought it was going to
be male frame I think did I
did I I said you notice I was like oh
yeah
but uh yeah Audrey Grossman [ __ ] I love
that guy he was a phenomenal [ __ ]
phenomenal him and there was another
photographer at Amsterdam called himself
Yap he he did like the first really
micro trichrome photography oh okay and
uh he yeah he shot through a microphone
a microscope and uh he did some pretty
interesting uh photography he was like
one of the he was the first I think that
did micro photography on cannabis but uh
Roseman uh
really nice guy uh super talented he's
the one that shot uh Kyle's Special
Blend poster yeah you know
um and uh I lost track of him
um I should try to find him I know I'd
like to talk to him last time I spoke to
him I believe was right after 9 11 and I
called him I was trying to find him in
more of a panic because being a
photographer myself if he was in the
city he would be the type of guy that's
running towards the [ __ ] buildings
yeah photos before they came down kind
of thing so I was kind of concerned
about uh about that but yeah anyways
yeah we did a few uh I would say shoots
together because he was well well more
established than I was
um but he did help me because I would I
would find out through him what he was
getting paid and I said well like if
you're going to use the centerfold for
me I want to get paid the same or so
close kind of [ __ ] right yeah well back
then like you did did you do school for
photography yeah yeah I started uh
did a three-year program here in London
okay so like you were like early early
cannabis photographer right how many
photographers were around back then
yeah there wasn't very many of us like
um
I was Andre and I both were listed as
contributing photographers uh in the
um inside cover
right but he ended up getting lots of a
lot more Centerfolds uh covers and stuff
like that
um
and uh
um yeah I don't I think he might have
went to school I'm actually I just met
with fanchon we're gonna I'm gonna put
together a scholarship in my name
ironically for uh the program because I
want to
um
uh
uh I want you know kids to know that you
don't have to be a [ __ ] portrait [ __ ]
photographer you know you can be a pot
photographer and still make good and
kind of you know even though I went to
jail for it and [ __ ] like that I think
it would make a good story for a
scholarship but uh well like yeah cool
in the last episode you mentioned like
when you were at the border you got 10
000 negatives like ten thousand that's a
lot of photos man oh dude I had boxes
and bought and I just found uh
um
I'd love to have you scan some of these
like that did you have you ever thought
about doing a book
no no
did you keep track of the strains in
these pictures like did you write on it
what stranger what I used to do
um is I would take a picture
um of the plant and then I take a a
piece of paper and I'd write what the
strain was and put it in the picture and
then I would do a shoot of that train
yeah most ups and and uh full plant
shots and stuff like that and then um if
I if I liked it enough for and I thought
High Times would like it I would shoot
it on a positive on a slide yeah because
we had better uh color saturation and it
was better for them to uh and then uh a
lot of the times I would bring out my
old Super 8 video camera and videotape
what I was doing in the garden just so I
would have reference uh because I was
doing it for information for myself on
different genetics as well as for for
High Times and for future you know
I mean that's going to be super
important like I don't know if you
understand that but because it because
so much has changed and so many things
have been renamed over the years it was
a really prime time during those years
to get Point like when you say like
point of origin for like land race stuff
this is like point of origin for a lot
of these strains like in their natural
habitat like getting pictures of let's
say Romulan in Canada during this era
that's very special we don't have a lot
of pictures and things like that anymore
when I was up there's a string called
Biker Bob which was a big yeah I've
heard of that out in California in BC
for a while there
um who has set up that I know I I did
this shoot
um
with High Times in mind I think red set
it up
but maybe Mark uh no I don't think Mark
set it up somebody set it up but like it
was up in north of Whistler and
um I used to blindfold myself on all
these photo shoots I wouldn't go to a
photo shoot so actually if I didn't know
the people yeah when blindfolded yeah
you never be blamed or anything yeah I
would just wear sunglasses and I would
tape the inside of sunglasses even if
they said I didn't have to do that
they're like dude we know we don't want
to pop up on that radar ever as someone
I was just like you know what dude you
have a list of and on that list is
everybody that knows about your garden
yep I don't want to be on that [ __ ]
list if something goes south I don't
want to be on that list kind of that's
smart yeah and uh we ended up in some
really [ __ ] up
back [ __ ] area countries you know good
old boys million dollar [ __ ] Bros I'm
sure um when I was working in the
interior we ended up going to one and
definitely AJ or something like that but
super nice [ __ ] guy and uh ironically
his he blew his [ __ ] Transformer on
the pole when I was there
sparks flying everywhere [ __ ] like
all the lights going off his entire
[ __ ] cruise I met this guy this day
uh it's when I was working on that uh
greenhouse and um his entire [ __ ]
crew [ __ ] bailed everybody [ __ ]
ran because they knew [ __ ] Hydra was
coming right like oh yeah little [ __ ]
Transformer you know it's on fire kind
of [ __ ] and I'm so used to being the guy
that you know back in the nation days
I'm the one that had the pickup truck
with the topper on it that could fit all
the pot plants and everything in the
back yeah yeah you know I'm not scared
of the [ __ ] cops I mean I think I can
outrun a lot of the cops especially back
yeah so I was just like [ __ ] what are
we doing what are you like how yeah what
do you need to grab let's go you know
and use those things but we need to take
this down we need to shut this door we
need to screw this we need to do this
and I was just like [ __ ] right we
were there for
a couple hours maybe before the hydro
people showed up you know because it was
all I think I think he put up his own
[ __ ] Transformer on a pole or
something and and it blew their
Transformers some so he was definitely
like [ __ ] he's fine but you know we
were just like
we're here to [ __ ] hell I was like I
don't want to know where your [ __ ]
Garden is I you know so I'm blindfolded
when I get here I'm blindfolded when I
leave but while I'm here I'm your
[ __ ] best friend kind of yeah I'll do
whatever it [ __ ] takes but
um yeah I ended up
um I ended up always you know even at
that Garden I don't remember what the
strains were because I think
um one I was a little worried because I
didn't know what I was walking into on
this one there was a friend of a friend
kind of thing and when I got there you
could tell it was definitely organized
guys on two wheels yeah
I don't want and but the Biker Bob you
know most of the guys that were riding
the bike of Bob's road bikes yeah yeah
it makes sense well I'm just gonna turn
on the light so you can see me better
but yeah yeah did you bring your seed
case with you
I didn't I want to start going through
it I didn't start going through it I'm
sitting on my desk downstairs
because I actually want to go through it
all
um I want to I want to go through it on
the the video with you so we could just
uh so it'd be easier I guess you should
just do a whole session on that yeah
just do it again I mean yeah we have to
find like because a lot of the seeds I
have are just like
seeds that came to me with a story
that's the but that's the best part
right like that's what people want to
hear is the story so that's these these
seeds can evoke a lot of these stories
that you probably didn't even remember
that you had about certain strains yeah
but again like the Elmwood I've no one
said no what the [ __ ] the Elmwood is
right like the Elmwood is a a strain
that was
super popular in
certain circles in uh uh Southwestern
Ontario for outdoor right but after this
people gonna be chasing it guaranteed
people going to be trying to find out a
shitload of those seats I'll send it and
that's something else like I was saying
is
um yeah but see that's the same thing
like now you know would would uh I'm
gonna call him Double D because I don't
know that's in Canada I used to work for
him
um he's out on the East Coast obviously
um but um if he would know about that
box story yeah I mean Ed would know
about it but um I don't know too many
people that want to talk to Ed yeah but
oh you're referring to to Rosenthal
right yeah yeah because someone in the
thing was like no he's referring to Ed
Borg I was like no he's referring to
Rosenthal nose board yeah yeah so yeah
just because
um again that's what he told uh
Miss for Hampton Steve when uh when he
was working in Switzerland with those
guys
yeah I think so you know again
everything that we talk about
is and I was just reading something
today about uh the natives a native
saying where you know people like you we
wanna
remember
a purpose on this planet is to uh uh
remember our Legacy or something and it
should be to continue our story kind of
thing and everything that we you know
like we're discussing here as we said
earlier was this is what I was told and
yeah a lot of this shit's just not
written down it's not good and it's not
going to be written down for obvious
reasons so that's why you know when I
get to meet guys like you I'm saying
well if you know somebody that knows
somebody this is what I heard yeah and
they might say yeah there's no way that
happened and then say okay well at least
I know now yeah well that's kind of the
purpose of this podcast is that a lot of
the history is oral like a lot of
history is like verbally passed on you
know and it always was it made it to
[ __ ] down you know we had some carvings
in the in the uh in the um uh on the
walls in the caves you know and on
stretched out leather but no we have a
uh everything is you know it's around
the campfire and tell stories and yeah
hate that to the young ones and you know
when I was at rainbow gatherings you
know the granola Funk with the uh camp
that we were uh staying with and their
contribution was uh building a stage
luckily the one I went to I was able to
help uh build a stage so the elders
could come and tell stories about
earlier years of the rainbow and the
history of jingle Gathering and I was
like well [ __ ] you know we need that and
that's what they said what I feel this
is is for the uh for the Cannabis
industry for the seeds is you know a lot
of the [ __ ] this is uh this is what I've
been told is what I hear
and if we can find people to like I say
with the triple s c Golden Boy story you
know is that you know was somebody
pulling my leg with somebody that told
me this did believe it because somebody
told them that yeah I'm still tempted
they go he's like the one person that I
knew that was worked with Neville will
help them
I wasn't sure about using names yeah
yeah indeed okay yeah I think that
I think he'd be that would he would at
least know something I would think yeah
so and like I said what the story was is
you know there was uh uh somebody never
was supposed to sell a uh a bunch of
genetics to somebody never came through
he threw him in the back of a freezer
when he was pulling out of I believe
Amsterdam
um he came across them he passed him on
to Ed
supposedly for like an outstanding debt
or something like that or maybe just
because he had him and they ended up
um with Steve in Switzerland yeah and
whatever happened to the fast beer and
and all that stuff yeah the fast few the
fast parties and night Queens are they
still alive
no
yeah but the Ortega which was one of
them is in the Louie yeah um
I don't they didn't really like it like
I said before they didn't like any of
the strains that I liked like the the
fast Spear and the night night night
Queen uh because they were um sativas
yeah uh Steven and red and those guys
were all big Indica fans so they love
the Ortega you know
um I wish I could remember some of the
other streams I'll have to kind of go
through I have a thank you for joining
us on this journey we are forever
thankful that enough people watch us to
keep us going with that in mind you can
show your support for the show by liking
subscribing and sharing the show we
don't advertise so we need you also hit
righteats.com and syndicatecare.com to
show more support for the show
kick over the statues and bring it back
to the farmers
[Music]