thank you
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not soja breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
can you hear me I can hear you're good
all right we're good
okay so we wanted to start out last week
or of two weeks ago we ended with part
one we went over the introduction of
smell boat seeds kind of how it all
started how small boat came to be what
it meant what the word even meant and um
and some of the naming conventions of
some of your lines we went over rainbow
we even touched a little bit on your
brother at the end which I'm sure people
were like surprised that we'd even cover
and then we talked a little bit about
what we didn't cover what we missed like
some of the other things we wanted to
talk about so I wanted to do a part two
everybody like this is one of the the
episodes I think I've been hit up about
most for people wanting us to do a part
two like they're like you've got to do
them next week and we already had
something planned so we're diving back
into it I had a lot of people reach out
I I mean unexpectedly sort of you don't
have a lot of friends like people who I
talk to on Instagram and stuff but there
was like strangers that were reaching
out to me and they were like hey I
listened to your podcast a long time ago
and then you know this one and I want to
hear more like you know could you like
go more in detail on this more in detail
on that when are the [ __ ] seats being
released again because I am a stingy
bastard when it comes to releasing seeds
we all know this yes um yes [ __ ]
horrifying it's like no we're my
pleasure
close enough [ __ ] I work with them
for four years before I let anyone touch
them but it's so much better than
flooding the market with just crap that
you that you're not proud of or that
you're not sure of you know what I mean
yeah 100 dude and we were you guys
didn't get to see our intro but we
literally were talking for another 30
minutes or we gotta [ __ ] stop we have
to stop we have to stop because we have
to have [ __ ] for the show yeah it could
have been another episode in itself yeah
right now yeah and it would have just
kept flowing
um so you want me to talk about what
what's coming up yep let's talk about
the seeds that you're going to be
releasing in the next week or so because
I have to go meet up with him to go pick
these up so I don't have them in hand
but we are going to release these in the
next week the plan was for today
um I had a a rock monster come out of my
penis and uh rock monster I'm a [ __ ]
kidney stone about hurt me to death so
and then so I had an ugly night last
night so when uh Matt and I talked this
morning he was all hey things are going
on and I was honestly I'm glad you're
saying it because I'm beat the [ __ ]
today so let's just do this and then
we'll meet up this week and uh yeah so
uh I kind of want to do this release a
little different so there isn't going to
be like here's 15 varieties so yeah
we're the ones that I really really
really have loved so I mean I shouldn't
say that the the ones that the they're
all [ __ ] good I'm not even going to
mention that so the reason five these
are the five that are coming up yeah so
we're gonna start off with the London
pound cake 75 by the rainbow sister okay
the cool thing about it is is that the
London pound cake
terp show up but not it's weird
but not it's a weird structure of yeah
like if you don't nail that plant like
she will get poofy on you not Lara fee
per se but poofy like an old hash plant
not not as um not as dense as like a
cookies or OG exactly yeah like so now
you add that rainbow to it you get that
turret but you get the rainbow high
profile growth pattern structure all
that and then it's been yeah and it's
[ __ ] been repetitive it's been over
and over and over
um we have found a few that are gassy
like a gassy fruit is the only way I can
describe it like a aerosoly fruit that
gets in here
uh sensors but most of them are like the
a lemon OG or a berry OG or something
around that one did you just say get in
your sensors yeah [ __ ] right
there in the center like you're a robot
get it right up in here get up in there
with your sensors
so that's that's the [ __ ] first one
have you named it yet or has your
daughter named it yet she hasn't and um
I don't know you're gonna have to just
do a spinning Board of names of names
and uh well yeah that's something that
we should discuss because I am the worst
at naming plants my names have always
been this plant by this plant is what
this plant is called
and yeah I think we're getting back to
that like yeah people wanted everything
to be like [ __ ] cream puff pie with
cinnamon strudel and Twinkie dicks and
things like that but I think it tastes
like Twinkie dicks and it never smells
like cookie Dix yeah it never tastes
like a Twinkie tick knuckle taste like
Twinkie dicks I've tasted so many
Twinkie dicks and none of them
just so really [ __ ] Twinkies
so that one is really [ __ ] good I I
am not uh
uh a huge fan of uh some of these these
these plants uh they that are popular
like yeah I did some runts crosses and
stuff as well
I released it to a few friends because
they were very much wanting it yeah um
but for me it was I don't trust the the
rats plant as much as I did the London
pound cake 75. uh the London pound cake
75 has shown
it's it's a lot like Sunset Sherbert
yeah but it I really enjoyed the sunset
Sherbert I got years ago the first one
that I worked on I like sure whatever's
pretty good yeah it has that funk to it
so anyhow that was number one the second
one is a plant that is uh blue Hawaiian
by Romulan so is that a Jordan at the
islands one dude I have no idea of the
islands somebody gifted me this club and
they were all hey you have to try this
plant and I was all cool so it sat for a
long time and then I grew it and it it's
[ __ ] good it's [ __ ] good what's it
like on its own so it is do you remember
uh
oh God what was the name of that [ __ ]
plant uh Jesus it's an old Europe Europe
guy uh it turned like this weird purple
on the inside I think Black Rose is made
from it
um
God damn it I still haven't Blackberry
or black rice I think it was even like
uh around those times so anyways uh I
think
I'll go grab the seeds Sani Sani seeds
made this plant okay okay
yeah it actually turns like this weird
lilacy purple
like right off the bat yeah and um it
will come to me uh in a minute on what
the name of the plant is because I still
have some of sami's original release of
the seeds in the freezer oh so anyways
Killing Fields there you go Killing
Fields yeah so this is uh old Jack Herer
hybrid yep so it will remind you of
Killing Fields right because of the
color and stuff but then it has this
like Berry flavory smell taste thing
going on to it from the blue Hawaiian
I'm assuming blue Hawaiian is a
blueberry hybrid is it yes it is I I
actually crossed the blue bonnet to a
blue Hawaiian this last round you've
probably got a lot of [ __ ] blueberry
though I actually saved you a pack of
the London pound cake cross the blue
bonnet too oh that will be [ __ ]
interesting yeah I didn't make many of
them like I just had a small clone you
know of it growing but yeah I saved you
something I think I brought you did I
bring you that cologne I did you did
everyone I brought you that I saved it
it's okay so and then the Romulan part
so
the Romulan part was weird because I
kept seeing more of the blue Hawaiian
show in color and stature and everything
and then with the rainbow you were
getting more of a rainbow look and the
rainbow thing it was almost like the
rainbow overpowered the blue Hawaiian
romula except for
coloring you will get these rainbow
plants with that Killing Fields looking
purple like that weird purple you crack
it open like you said the lilac color
Yes like a lilacy purple look to it and
um you want something that will like
remind you of
like a different time a different era
yeah that would be [ __ ] one because
yeah it's just a trip I don't when
people ask me like what is Rainbow
tastes like it's dirt profile the thing
that I get the most is it reminds me of
the first time I smoked good wheat yeah
like it reminds me of that time like
when you know Green bud or kind buds or
whatever it was it was it reminds me of
that time and no one can really like
give me like an explanation other than
it reminds me of that you get like that
Menthol minty like Joey you know that
soury dot I think so that Rainbow's
sister like I said that was Bryn's
favorite and that was one of my
favorites too but it was it was more
chocolatey version of that which is
super cool you know it has like a cocoa
stuff yeah they do and most of the [ __ ]
that you see that promises chocolate
doesn't provide chocolate now a lot of
the the stuff that people uh promise
chocolate with turns out like earthy and
it's not chocolate it's not it's the
milk chocolate it's just earthy and you
can vaguely hope for some chocolate over
there yeah yeah I used to have a Bubba
cross
um I don't even know what it was crossed
with once again gifted plants man you
remember at one time late 90s early
2000s when you started getting in with
these tight friends and stuff like that
and people would gift you things oh yeah
there was above a cross that I had that
was like espresso like straight up like
drinking a cup of [ __ ] espresso she
ain't yield for [ __ ] [ __ ] it was like
the world's smallest plant but the
flower like that coffee like literally
you open the bag and the house smelled
like [ __ ] a bag of coffee beans yeah
that one was cool we had a clock that's
one called smart Alex that was like that
that was uh you open it it just smelled
like opening a can of folders like
sticking their nose in it I mean exactly
just like how does this even exist you
know yeah how does this terpene exist in
cannabis yeah super weird yeah so that
was too
um the third one was rainbow sister we
talked about that one already the S1
version uh the San Diego OG which I have
went over in detail with people uh I
still got to get Matt uh cut and some
flowers of it so he did kind of idea to
see where
I think it's either related to or from
the same time and just one of the cuts
went one way and one of the cuts with
triangle uh yeah I think I think they're
all around that same area the same time
frame the same same thing
I personally growing a triangle plant in
the San Diego plant beside each other I
would I smoked in San Diego every time
it hasn't it does have us a different
profile like a small profile but that
could still be from like a drift you can
still get drift in your smells and your
growth patterns and stuff especially if
one plant was beat up for decades you
know yeah yeah so
um so there is a there could be that
drift or they could be seeds from the
same parents where they both came from
or something they're definitely [ __ ]
related 100 yeah structure everything
looks the same it's just a little that
San Diego has more of this uh
putrideness like that's always good
[ __ ] nastiness people like the nasty
dude and that plant they're nasty that
like that one will [ __ ] you up like how
it gives you that yeah like old school
like
like locked in like I don't want to move
a lot of them and sit here and fish or
play video games or yeah just gonna sit
here and [ __ ] drool talk about my
life that's just my life that's where I
exist in natural yeah this is my every
[ __ ] day
so all right so that was four now so
right we did okay and then I think
before I don't know that was four and
then the um
okay uh uh uh oh great pie great bye
the great pie for me would by itself
it's interesting it's pretty I love it I
love it yeah it's beautiful it's super
[ __ ] easy to grow it is it makes
everyone look like a rock star when you
grow it I the funny thing about that cut
was it was from Canada I can't remember
I think it was Harry Harry Palms who
selected it it was like a one out of one
seed selection just one pop and it just
turned out phenomenal I think they were
saying something about that I think
three or four seeds yeah something
ridiculous yeah I remember we talked
with Canada at one of the shows and he
was talking about it and it was like
before it hit the this Market I think
yeah you're giving me the cut really
early on yeah he was showing me pictures
on this phone and I was going over some
of the pictures of the rainbow and he
was we were both just comparing some
notes that was one of the nicer dudes
yeah really really nice always always so
cool um yeah you know I think a lot of
people have a lot of impressions of them
because he released like me he released
a lot of femlines Femmes across the
fence and stuff so they just assumed
that that's all he does but like I have
loads of regular seeds and like of
course old lines that he's reproduced
and stuff so he does some cool stuff
just not a lot of people are privy to it
yeah and I think a lot of people too
like um see like when you do thin lines
and you do the reversing and stuff like
that I don't think if people seen what
our DMS look like yeah they would
understand why we released so many or
you so people I haven't really released
fins this is going to be one of my first
I've made them to like you know hold
down genetics yeah but my DMs are when
will you release release films when will
you make films and are you gonna do a
fimsy FMC there's so many people who
don't keep moms who don't make clothes
they don't keep moms they don't want to
wait inside Nails space space space
that's the one [ __ ] thing we get all
the time and I hear you I understand man
I get it you know
not all of us have 120 [ __ ] lights
yeah like I I have a lot of lights so
for me I have [ __ ] mom rooms that are
size of most of the people's flower
rooms so uh it's for me like I I kind of
forget that you know like uh yeah I
remember those days like in the early
90s or mid I should say early mid to
late 90s and I had this tiny little
[ __ ] closet in the bedroom you know
with uh yeah dude light I stoled off of
the [ __ ] uh street light you know
because it had about it well into the
2000s man still using old magnetic
ballasts and [ __ ] yeah no I had the
Tweakers steal the [ __ ] actual street
lights oh yeah yeah that's how my dad
used to run it yeah yep the metal allies
off the street lights and then I would
flower under those and then
um I got my first magnetic ballasts and
I remember they were like just pieces of
[ __ ] but they didn't ever stop running
no that was part of the pro I still have
some of them they're like 30 [ __ ]
years old and you could still plug them
in the problem is though they never stop
running so even if they get sprayed with
water they never stop running if your
room floods they never no other stuff
right they sure don't yeah you're gonna
let you get [ __ ] out of yourself so that
was the the five
um that we were talking about yeah uh I
think that was the five uh I was I was
considering doing the wedding cake uh
rainbow uh assist or the GMO rainbow
cyst
um the GMO Rainbow Six I don't think uh
I don't know if people will will grow it
to its ultimate potential yeah you want
to take her 75 80 days and a lot of
people aren't wanting to do that yeah um
so if I release it and people are like
hey look you know because it throws like
poo butt bro dude what's crazy is she
looked at 63. yeah she'll look down at
63 but then she'll hit a second growth
yeah 67 and then by 78 she is just the
nastiest garlic Bo thingy uh so they
will eventually get released but it will
be a short release and it will be like
hey understand what you're getting yeah
understand what you're getting with this
cross like you're not getting a 63 day
here yeah like you you're gonna add two
more weeks to that people are going to
pull it there anyway so it don't matter
what they will they will and then
they'll wash it and it'll wash
beautifully and people dip it in the
hydrogen peroxide yeah
get all my [ __ ] bugs off of of it
yeah speaking of bugs yeah hello let's
segue into our next our next little
topic all right so all those seats are
going to be available righteats.com next
week well I'll make a post on patreon
and Instagram and all that and so people
will know when they're available
also uh yeah everything is before we go
everything is packed for our seat
winners last week okay uh everything is
literally packed sitting over in the
little area yeah and uh I'm going to go
get everything out so would you guys
watch the show it's not your
[ __ ] seeds are going to be
flying away to you there you go I think
I have four or five packages heading out
to good friends
um be patient yeah good friends know
they just slide into the [ __ ] DMS
when they want [ __ ]
the only fans pick them dicks right
there boy the drink it did I need that
Twinkie dick [ __ ]
when you're talking about your feet
cramping and I literally have my feet
stuck in a foot massager right now like
a dual foot massage I'm so [ __ ]
dehydrated the back of my eyes and my
feet are just like keep cramping up and
I'm all goddamn so you're gonna see me
itching around today
where a lot of people who don't know
I've had my colon removed years ago so
um I did a number on him yeah it was bad
it was
well it shouldn't have been in there
so we had to remove some it was it was
bad so uh I get dehydrated really
[ __ ] easy so
um and I have been a little ill lately
so I'm a little puffy a little
dehydrated so I'm super [ __ ] crampy
right now like I'm having my man my
manstration yes cramped up for my
menstruation Jesus Christ I demonstrated
down to my penis kidney stone yeah oh
yes he also has kidney stones he has
some good kidney stone stories too about
airplanes maybe Did we tell that story
ever before I don't think so but we
should we should we should tell you
things to not do with kidney stones one
fly two sit down to pee
he's also a sit spinkler I think that's
what they call it sprinkler you're like
oh my God I'm gonna pass out I'm gonna
have to sit down to pee but when you sit
down to pee it kind of Kinks [ __ ] and
that kidney stone gets in there and it's
all like it's like yeah it feels like
the tip of your dick gets blown off uh
well it did yeah and then when they
pressurized the plane oh my neck at
least now drops out into your ureter and
all of a sudden that [ __ ] plane
pressurizes it sucks everything up oh my
Lord I can't you took a bunch of volume
before you fly and then you're passing
out because you were working at the
place where we're gonna go with this
story for in like 120 degree hot houses
and you're pouring sweat and you're
super dehydrated and all of a sudden the
stone hits you and before it hits you
though you're all like hey I got a six
hour flight I'm gonna I haven't slept in
like three days I'm gonna take these uh
muscle relaxers and I'm gonna go to
sleep on this plane and uh it doesn't
work that way
more relaxed and it's hitting my head
way out yeah yeah it didn't do any of
that
um I just kept chopping and hitting my
head and then throwing up and then going
crazy eyes and then get back yes you
were a treat to be next to you on an
airplane oh my God I had taken friends
with me so so we had like the Rope so it
was it was uh Myro and then my friends
were beside this so and then the guy
behind me was the nicest gentleman ever
he just kept offering me drugs
and I was so out of it I he was like Hey
I have nausea medicine I have pain
medicine I'm all like we're probably
gonna have to be best friends
let's just text we'll text and be side
boyfriends so oh but Maui is the best
place ever if you are in pain because
yeah right will take [ __ ] care of you
I walked into a clinic and they didn't
accept my insurance but the lady doctor
was all like it was all ladies in here
and
um she was I don't care send them back
anyways we just won't charge his
insurance instantly morphing into the
art oh wow yeah they called an ambulance
because my blood pressure was out of
sorts because I have afib and [ __ ] too
yeah lots of stuff going on so they
called an ambulance the ambulance comes
and picks me up the ambulance driver is
all oh buddy morphine so they drive me
this is a tiny Island it has one little
hospital we get to the hospital he's
like hey it might take a few minutes for
them to see you morphine
um I go inside the hospital the doctor
comes in so it looks like a pretty big
kidney stone morphine yeah
and then he saw hey we're going to
discharge you morphine
here's one free way out [ __ ] morphine
I was so you know in California they'd
give you a Tylenol yeah and now we they
were all like hey this guy looks like
he's dying over there let's give him
something to help and then they gave me
Flomax and I had that kidney stone for
seven of the ten days before I finally
passed it and it was like a big black
rock but the whole reason that was it
though was where I was uh fiddling uh
the couple of days before we left
um was a a giant grow like it's a it's a
really really big legal California legal
grow everything like that yeah
and uh I remember we talked a few days
before you went out there like we knew
that there was like this potential to go
out there you're like I think I'm gonna
go yeah and I talked to you on my way
home and I was telling you like hey I'm
going to be leaving let's meet up and I
can get you this and this and this and
um
so while I was there the cookie the
cookie fellas show up like this van yeah
literally with their [ __ ] what did it
have Windows did it have writing on the
side it was a cookie fan like it was a
they put that [ __ ] logo on everything
they would put it on somebody's forehead
well honestly I guarantee there's
thousands of people that have that
tattoo like instead of a tear just to
see a c yeah they see the they got their
Edgar haircut and their cookie shirt
yeah so anyways I get there and I'm
working and I brought PD with me of
course because baby has to go because he
rocks yeah yeah so he was my little
[ __ ] worker bee
um so we're busting ass man and we're in
there from
literally eight in the morning to five
or six in the afternoon and the hot
houses are like 110 115 degrees
I was so sweaty that like my clothes
were soaked like I had been swimming
like everything and I wasn't smart
enough to bring extra clothes so our
whole drive home I just didn't have
shirt on like I was a tough guy like I
was a real sex pot from a four hour
drive with no shirt I always I thought
that part was hilarious anyways the
cookie guys show up yeah and uh they're
uh bringing all these clones to to be
flowers
uh at this facility and they were going
it's uh White labeling I mean you know
they say they grow it or whatever
um I think what they do is have clean
rooms they grow a couple pounds in the
clean room have those pants tested and
then slide in hey we have 300 pounds of
that yeah and then they slide in the
greenhouse and the stuff in on that
license or whatever yeah on that number
California doesn't know they're stupid
as [ __ ] yeah
and so I go in and I want to see all
these new ones because they have like
what's mechanar plant names and I
remember this is when cheetah pin
cheated
literally the white reds pink rats all
these rats plants were there and I had
never even seen run so we had only like
barely heard of it uh the different
there's multiple different pound cakes
gelatos and sherbets and everything so I
was looking at them
and these clones were like an inch and a
half tall tops like they were like these
tiny tiny clones uh they didn't have
Roots most of them like you'd pull them
out and look it was like it was
literally like they had been trying to
root for three days
um that's enough yep I did find a few
with roots that I ended up uh uh
procuring to the to the facilities
um but it was a scary situation because
these plants were covered in piano yeah
covered in spider mites and when I mean
[ __ ] covered I mean like literally
I I've never seen like baby baby clothes
with PM because if you have pm on the
mom plant you're taking a clone you just
[ __ ] dip it yeah
yeah and so to see like these tiny
infantile cuts that means they literally
were taking them off of PM covered moms
not Karen she's [ __ ] plugging and
going and then delivering them to
somebody else to let it be their problem
just grow it out for us and we're gonna
put it in the bag anyways you know you
know what I think they're probably doing
is is some of their moms are probably in
a in a in a have pm on them but dormant
like they think it's gone but once they
stick it in those domes it's like it's
done yeah they're probably right in that
little Sports just pops yeah they start
going yeah but they were
it was it was like I I remember even
texting you and I was all like hey so I
have the the white runts and the pink
runts and the lpc75 and but dude they're
like scary like and the rest of this
facilities plants were absolutely
[ __ ] amazing yeah huge months
gorgeous super healthy moms
um all Sun grown with a supplemental Des
on these like football field size glass
houses gorgeous beautiful setup and uh
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
different uh plants and the fella I
don't want to say his name and I'm not
going to say his name but him and I have
talked for years and uh he has done
clones for [ __ ] you know for his
whole career it's big clones yeah yeah
and uh
he uh was a telling me like I have spent
the better part of 10 years like just
harassing asking collecting cologne moms
moms moms and then he had what was funny
is I got there he had a whole little
like section like this little table
section dedicated to
I want to say it was the Mendo by
rainbow and the Skittles by rainbow
because the guys that did so well
outdoors in Santa Cruz with those two
those two plants that he was all like so
we've been moving the [ __ ] out of these
ones and I was like hey those are mine I
made it yes that's [ __ ] cool you know
like yeah yeah and then partially like
some of the stuff I make is here in
California in [ __ ] weather people I
don't think people know what our
weather's like here sometimes no I think
they think it's all just like rainy per
or not rainy sunny perfect like yeah we
had 116 I slaughtered the pigs this year
when it was 116. yeah it was bad this
year yeah
growing season also the outdoor around
this part with there not being rain
anymore is so nasty yeah it's just
covered in
dirt dust debris uh fear has been so
many pesticides shot in our area since
the 30s and 40s for all the things
because we're like the agricultural
[ __ ] Capital
um that dust isn't just normal dust it's
like it's death dust yeah it's bad and
valley fever dust man yeah for real yeah
so
but yeah I went up there and uh I just
happened to be there the day the guys
were nice enough and everything like
that you could tell they were all like
oh you're gonna steal our plants I was
like maybe never never got them no yeah
so I that was what was funny too man
like that was before the whole wrench
your life up thing was a thing like oh
yeah typing it yeah yeah they hadn't
started hyping it yet and uh
one of them was nice one of them turned
nice and black but it looked just like
gelato like it was literally spinning
image that's runs that's the runs clone
it's just gelato 33. yeah and then there
was the white ruts and the pink runts
and the white rinse was all right
um they tried to say it was the white
with the rats crossed together or
something like that seriously yeah and
then yeah that was me yeah I don't think
you guys spread anything with the white
yeah I think it was just another bag
seed that you found that look decent you
know what's a cool white strain oh let's
see the white yeah and then yeah there
was the pink Reds but at that time they
had multiple [ __ ] rights yeah trains
like they did now I don't know if they
still do
um but they had the all their gelato's
the sunset sherberts
um I don't know what mechanar is but
they had one I remember being robot name
and then all kinds of chicken Arts yeah
all kinds of cheetah pisses names just
cheetah piss this cheetah piss that
cheetah piss this and
it was funny because
um I remember you were talking about cat
piss and in a lot of your podcasts
leading up to seeing this and a lot of
people had started to go like oh man I
remember the old pissy strains you know
and this was years back like oh yeah
four or five years ago or whatever when
we were reminiscing about the fish
strains and just so happens
that they have clones that is now cat
piss and gelato and you're all like yeah
but yeah yeah but cheetah cheated
because they're much faster than it
right yeah does anybody have you smelled
if they didn't even smell like catfish
at all uh I have uh the cut that's
gunflower right now I've held that cut
for this [ __ ] long yeah yeah and I'm
finally flowering it took this long to
get clean
oh my God so yeah it it it it's ran
through its testing it's clean yeah it's
uh but I finally did I'm doing a cheetah
piss uh clone now that I'm gonna flower
out I let a friend flower it before I
flowers did he say it was pissy at all
it wasn't pissy at all it was uh it was
um but it also wasn't like it was like a
small tape bro and things like that yeah
but
it the plant was really pretty like it
was really pretty but so is gelato and
so is Sherbert like yeah
I'd love for some of their names to
match up with what's going on you know
what it is yeah it would honestly yeah
there's no way it has campus I just
don't believe it it looks just like
every other [ __ ] cookie plant I've
seen like the exact same structure
everything like that you know the long
Spears the chunky little buds you know I
genuinely think that they just take
gelato bag seeds just they do of the
Herms and just like they're like
I've never met the woman or anything but
I'm gonna name it after okay that's
exactly what the [ __ ] it is that's
exactly what it is you know it is like
because everything all their stuff has
little arms on them all of them have
little bag seats on them you find them
you grow them some of them are home runs
some of them are not do you find the new
home run you're all hey it looks like
gelato but it has a slight variation
let's just say that we crossed it with
something yeah I mean remember run just
means making it successful on IG that's
literally what the meaning of a home run
is anymore that's all it is that's all
it is I there's so many smoke in it
doesn't matter it doesn't matter it's
what gets hyped up on social media uh
what people talk about on social media
and
that's it like yep I couldn't imagine
now they have uh
oh they have some other cookies and milk
[ __ ] stuff and they have so much
stuff but it's all it looks all the same
but I got to see like their Mothership
if you will what comes from the
mothership and it's it was rough man
like I feel bad for the people who
actually go and pay that money to buy
that stuff uh because
there's no way those plants are clean
um
like without using something before it
gets to you yeah and you're not testing
the dirty plants they're not testing
that they're they're testing clean
plants and then saying that they have
lots of pounds of those clean plants but
in reality they're just sliding in
because
they're not testing every bag that's
brought to no to to every single day on
the market no they're not testing it
they're you're bringing in an eighth or
a few grams having it tested and then
telling the state I have 200 pounds of
this yeah
states are okay we want taxes on it and
you're all like yeah 180 of those pants
came from a greenhouse but no one knows
that it's all going into these fancy
jars and bags anyway so and people like
I if you remember when cookies first
started getting real big
and they started getting the mylar bags
do you remember people on IG like
opening up those mylar bags on video and
like just showing all the mold and
people going to cookie stores and in the
store window you'd see their little
clones that they put out there as
display and they would just be filled
with bugs and [ __ ] VM and just in the
store window like the clue that they
were displaying this bad [ __ ] because
they were just so inexperienced two two
things that that reminds me of not to
talk bad about anybody but uh High times
did a article on swerve oh yeah yes yes
they went into his Grow rooms on THC
former too they were covered in [ __ ]
spider bites yeah and they were taking
these close-ups where they were all like
smelling the buds and stuff and I saw
how the [ __ ] is this a center fault yeah
High Times
no none of them but it was like it's it
wasn't something that you like catch as
a mistake God damn you could see it
every [ __ ] where they were big top
tents in there you know they weren't
even that like I remember the pictures
not even being that like detailed and
you could still see the PM inside your
mind yeah it was bad it was a different
time a different era a bygone era but we
always do what spider mites look like on
leaves if you were a grower especially
from California that was the dude
spider bites and uh caterpillar damage
like yeah for outdoor Growers exactly
you know what to do you know what you're
going to be dealing with but I remember
that article in looking at those plants
and I was all this is like this is real
life like this is like who works there
have you guys ever seen cannabis like
does this look normal to you and then um
so there was that one
I got we were just I had another one
that was the second one that I wanted to
bring up and now I can't remember what
oh the um when they were asking Berner
beginning what was cookies and he was
all oh it's F1 like F1
horrible yeah and that should have told
people right then that it was just some
sort of bag seed stuff that they had got
from the bay at the time yeah
there was so much purple weed in the bay
at the time whether it was granddaddy or
Urkel or yeah uh the SR-71 and I've seen
so many mutants in uh Urkel Crossing and
deep Urkel lines where it looks like
ogkb and ogkb looks like Urkel because
they both have the slow trait they can
get the weird Leaf patterns and then so
I could imagine there's a Herm with
maybe there was a Herm with an OG or a
Herm with an Urkel and they got a bag of
Urkel and they're all like hey let's
start growing and the OG Herms in a grow
room and threw some pollen on an Urkle
and now you have this plant that looks
could be cookies I don't this story
could be different but I could imagine
that these were the things and they
found the you know a couple of pounds or
ounces or whatever that had a few seeds
in them and they decided to become
Growers and that's their F1 their F1 was
the first generation bag seeds
they weren't sure if F1 was across
that's such a weird plant to pick yeah
the dirt like it was an odd plant to
pick because I've never ever seen
anything come out of any cookie cross
that resembles their at all ever not
history I don't think they knew like I
think they pulled a name out of the sky
that's what it was popular strain and
like they didn't know they were
attaching like a South African sativa
like look at this point yeah yeah that
would 100 show up yeah I it was because
I think they were if I I can't remember
exactly but I want to say it was like
granddaddy or cherry pie with uh Florida
OG and Durban Poison Something along
that mixture yeah like cherry pie was
supposed to to be
one hybrid and then cookies was supposed
to be another hype and one had GDP and
one didn't if I remember yeah or one had
derb and one didn't something stupid
yeah and then I remember
um
cherry pie before the cookie Fiasco like
the cookie stuff happened I remember
having Cherry Pie and I got it from
friends at darcar cart and guess where
we're going now yeah the dark cart Story
the dark heart rug the dark dark Road of
dark heart Nursery
oh God so yeah so I remember I had
friends that were uh that were the
Growers if you will they had a fancy
name for them
um you know like how you have Baristas
that oh yeah but they're like you're
you're making a coffee like when I
worked at the coffee shop we weren't
labeled a barista I just yeah coffee
makers yeah and [ __ ] would make you a
sandwich and [ __ ] too if you needed that
I wasn't in the apartment I wasn't a
[ __ ] Sandwich Artist yeah yeah I
should have been I [ __ ] should have
been I could have drew on it with my
artistry
yeah
you want to dig Twiggy with cheese baby
girl
with cheese
queso
all right so dog cart Nursery yes so the
Cherry Pie though I do want to get a
little bit into that okay so before
cookies came like to prevalence there
was cherry pie yeah it was around and
then uh burner's name got attached to it
yeah somehow it wasn't like cookies
cherry pie this plant was just called
[ __ ] cherry pie like that's what it
was called and it wasn't it was a nice
bun it really was it had like a menthol
thing going on with like a a berry thing
going on turned purple had a nice look
to it uh but that's it so the Cherry Pie
was around dark heart had it and then um
dark heart never and then they had
another one they called three kings
yeah yeah it was that was it was it was
I think it was like a Sour OG Bubba or
something like that yeah another one
that they tried to say ended up coming
from later known as the cookie family so
Cherry Pie and the three kings were
supposedly those guys as like first
rendezvous with the clothing yeah uh but
that was before they were you know this
and that and the other I guess they were
well known in the bay at the time
already
um because the rap scene and things like
that and uh but they weren't well known
in the cannabisy yeah so and I had both
of those the three kings was
right uh I would still grow cherry pie I
would definitely did this pop up by the
way yeah so these are these are Lumpy's
old pictures of cherry pie they were
doing some of my favorite pictures the
earliest ones that I saw just so people
can get an idea of the plant we're
talking about of what we're talking
about and that's that's her that what
that's right yeah lump status yeah and
that's cherry pie like that is Cherry
Pie and uh
the fun part about cherry pie is it did
have this Menthol
Berry Cherry e thing on the finishing
touch of it I don't know but that was
like that whole pastry name right yeah
like that kind of started like oh we had
cherry pie why don't we need this Girl
Scout cookies you know that started the
pastry craze for those knuckleheads yep
yeah so dark art Nursery
um
dark heart for the people who aren't
from uh the area
they were putting clones at all of our
medical dispensaries Harborside after
blue blue sky or Blue Sky Blue Sky Cafe
yeah after Blue Sky was like the place
there was a place there and there was a
place
what was what was the blue dot one do
you remember the Santa Cruz place right
they had blue dogs
that was down south yeah yeah but they
had these two shops and like literally
at Blue Sky and the one that Santa Cruz
no that's a different one that's
Berkeley
Berkeley's patient was another one
though that you would these places would
get like a few thousand clones that was
it and there would already if you were
late there would be lines I remember
going yeah like 11 o'clock at night
staying in a parking lot uh with a buddy
because there was a plant I wanted you
know and it never was
it was hard finding [ __ ] clones back
then yeah it was hard finding clones man
sourcing real legit legit someone you
knew that like knew their [ __ ] yeah that
was impossible it was super hard that's
where I Source like uh a sour grapes cut
from and that's where I got grape
stopper from which
uh that's where yeah Blue Sky that's
where the scdc cut was scdc cut was
being sold out yeah
and uh the AK-47 the White Widow the
Urkel the SR-71 that blue sky was
responsible for a lot of stuff
um but it was really hard to get [ __ ]
clones there and plus they'd only let
you buy like five at a time or some
weirdo [ __ ] yeah there was something
yeah so more people could get them so
anyways
after those places got like [ __ ] like
those places got ran out they shut them
down the city was constantly after a
Harper's side really took off oh Steve
D'Angelo I think he was learning how to
pad Pockets before other people were
yeah like I think Steve was learning how
to like juggle
certain things corporate people's balls
in their mouths yes exactly super good
at that yeah it's [ __ ] cleaning them
like golf balls yeah
one by one and he was giving these
places shut down but he was able to stay
open and that's what brought Harborside
to like
Mega thing and I now yeah in their TV
show and all that [ __ ] that happens
yes God that's have you seen lately that
he's been like railing against prop 64
even though he's like one of the people
because he got run out yeah because he
realized oh I'm not [ __ ] Rich enough
to compete with the rich people that I
put in power
um
like oh I have a millionaire they're
billionaires they just told me to [ __ ]
off
yeah oh my God
I was telling everyone please vote no on
64. it's going to ruin everything
everything for everyone not going to get
cheaper cannabis you're gonna it's gonna
be illegal at a higher price they're
going to crack us down I mean
um they were just using the National
Guard last year to eradicate out yeah
cannabis gross in California in the
legal State I thought we were a legal
state but they were eradicating them and
they weren't going after the cartel
Grove no no they were using it to go
after Mom and Pops yes they were going
family dude Jimmy times I've had to deal
deal with [ __ ] code enforcement oh
yeah holy [ __ ] just finally the uh
sergeant in a of the police department
well it's in the city he finally said
I'm taking your name off the list so
they stopped harassing you and I was all
thanks man yeah like after years so
thanks yeah anyhow so darkheart Nursery
sword to start to coming along
with Harborside so dark heart was
feeling Harborside shells with clothes
and in one time they were very short
like they had 10 strengths they had
Blackberry they had the Cherry Pie the
three kings you know and uh a white
widow they had this one called a
chocolate hashberry that was the purple
Caper things and that's kind of how I
got offered some stuff from dark heart
because they were looking for breeders
at the time yeah and for house projects
I remember yeah basically wanting me to
be an employee
and anything I made was theirs yeah so I
would just work on their time in essence
but for my grow yeah and give them all
my best stuff yeah
sounds like a plan yeah not like a per
cut sale percentage or no that sounds
like how like the Dutch used to do it
yeah you can make us Femme seeds just
send us the seeds we'll send you some
money later yeah we'll send you money
later oh seriously
yeah so uh so dark heart had a like a
monopoly on clones like legit and there
was little guys who were still trying to
compete and they were doing fine but
they had to find specific things that
dark art didn't monopolize yeah star
cart would have these 10 inch [ __ ]
beast clones with these huge stamps you
could tell that the plant had been
blasted with God knows what to explode
with growth and yeah super Thrive
non-stop yeah look you're all like super
steroids don't stop super [ __ ] uh
carcinogens yeah like oh you guys are
just just that whatever it's not good
it's in a proxy I dip it'll be fine it's
going to the home grower it's not gonna
get [ __ ] tested who cares what's in
there yeah good point there's that I
shot the [ __ ] out of it with the
dirtiest of dirt so yeah anyhow my
friends who all have words for Dark Art
quit in the past five six years so
let's get to this point uh stardog dark
heart had a cut of stardog a friend of
mine went and bought a thousand star dog
cuts it was I think he actually did buy
a thousand it was 500 per grow and he
calls me about
day 40 or so you saw hey can you come
and look at my plants use all some
things wrong so
I go over and I look and it would be
like pretty plant
plant that looks like pretty plant
without resin without structure like
without density just puffballs pretty
plant puffball no resin pretty plant
puffball no resin puffball no resin
plants also started throwing out little
banana herbs like just little little
pollen bags the the other ones didn't
now you could tell that they were the
same plant it wasn't mislabeled these
were the same plant but they weren't off
of the same mop clearly the healthy
plants probably came from one mom and
puffball plants came from another month
so you know what I've been learning from
the the hpld whatever the [ __ ] is called
um is that some moms like you can take
clones from the top part and it won't be
as like it won't have as high of a
viroid count yep and then you take it
from the bottom so you can take it from
the same exact plants and have different
virus load yeah yeah you can have
different viral loads and we actually
seen that with a thousand plants we
actually could see this now mind you
this was way before this was a
you had full Duds half Duds yeah that
plant looks pretty [ __ ] good and yeah
that's kind of dotted little dudded yeah
how is that and you start thinking like
okay this
these plants are all getting the same
thing these plants would be on the same
[ __ ] table literally the same table
flood the drain that's how they grew and
everybody had I was pulling plants up to
check root systems big white healthy
root systems healthy plants leaves are
healthy uh pH is Right everything seems
right uh
[ __ ] plants wrapped and I couldn't
figure it out uh so I start contacting
dark heart and tell them about it I was
like hey
um we're seeing a lot of debting plans
like from Star dock they ended up
pulling star dog from the menu they did
um but they never wanted to admit to me
yeah of course not these plants were
dudding yeah so
they sold
millions of clones you like millions of
clones yeah people were buying thousands
at a time and tens of thousands of
people were buying these yeah um so how
did hplv explode
well dark heart Nursery so everybody who
has a hip new strain dark heart started
pulling in every [ __ ] hip new strain
when glue hit the scene dark Arc had it
Blue Dream hit the Disney scene dark Arc
had it when [ __ ] uh the cookies hit
the scene Sherbert hit the scene
anything that hit the scene that was
popular they were getting rid of the old
stuff like Blackberry rum they had
[ __ ] a legit romulink up yeah they
had a legit Romulan cut that they
got rid of they got rid of it for me
yeah it's not like it's not in demand of
course you're going to try cookies holy
[ __ ] that wrong dude for real and but
the shallow thinking process of these
companies you're like okay so blue dream
was one of the most popular plants
explode onto the scene that I had
actually seen right yeah every outdoor
grower grew it uh the problem was is
that not everybody had the real blue
dream cut people were getting they were
doing yes things like that and then Blue
Dream people are oh it's not that good
and I'm a bull [ __ ] [ __ ] I still pull
out my blue dream cut every now and then
and just [ __ ] people over there yeah I
don't know what that is also it's
[ __ ] Blue Dream you guys just got
Shady Blue Dream the same thing happened
with Gorilla Glue the exact same [ __ ]
thing the glue cut that came uh from um
um I almost said his real name um uh
where did he go Josie thank you yeah
Josie and lone Wadi yeah yeah recipes
Brothers yeah Josie sent me uh glue and
uh uh it's funny how far back Josie and
I actually go and it was before he he
his screen picture his little avatar on
the site was if Josie Wells but his name
wasn't yeah and then his name became his
Avatar and things like that anyways long
bed yeah uh this is so nice to me like
he was just a really really Jesse was
her sweetheart I didn't I didn't really
know loan but Josie was real sweet I
know um I know CSI had a project going
with him at the end I had a project
going with them at the end and he was he
was always so freaking cool I still have
some of his seeds that were like
unlabeled projects with like remember
when Uzbekistan came out that yeah yeah
uh the priests of uh or whatever yeah
because when the Soviets came in the
weed went bad somehow so he was working
with a few things and he sent me some
stuff you know and uh the free Soviet
height thing whatever I don't know what
that plant is but he must have liked it
to breathe with it it's like nine
different plants called pre-soviet
afghanis yeah yeah so anyways he sent me
a bunch of stuff he sent me some uh he
called it like Cherry feel or cherry gas
or something because he knew I was a
cherry fan a few other things um
so uh but that's what was going on a lot
of those plants got watered down because
of people getting bag seeds and growing
it and saying it's glue four or it's uh
specifically with blue dream I I
remember when when it blew up there was
a company called Emerald Triangle seeds
which I remember in the Emerald Triangle
people didn't like them because they
weren't they weren't from the emerald
trying yeah it was like a Spanish
company it was mass producing a
blueberry Haze in seed form yeah and
then uh Humboldt seed organization I
believe sold the same exact seeds I
don't want to don't quote me they at
least sold a blue dream that was not the
same Blue Dream their own creation if
not the same exact seeds the Emerald
Triangle were settling under their label
the Humboldt seed org when they first
came in too I had so many friends
telling me that they were
bad for a lack of other words they
weren't from the this place they didn't
have these that was that's Emerald
Triangle seeds that was Emerald Triangle
okay okay okay okay I got those two
mixed up then yeah I used to do all the
time because they got both really dream
yeah they both had the blue drink that's
who it was then Emerald Triangle and I
had friends who were just like this is
horseshit and they're spreading
horseshit so back to dark heart dark
heart spread hplv
I don't know how to really explain
the epicenter that they cost it would be
like very hard to say you know in a
viral situation let's just like kind of
take covid for example right so uh why
are we allowed to say that word I don't
know well there's yeah I'm not going to
use the 19 part so I'll just use the
co-fit name let's say a virus let's say
a new virus
hits humans and there's an epicenter of
that right and there's
a thousand people who live there
those all those thousands of people move
to a new state yep just and that's kind
of what Dark Art did because when they
did this it was at the like this new
peak of the internet the new peak of
Clone Cherry the new peak of all these
seeds
of of Clone internet sales too close
Internet it's not going to dark heart
picking up a tray of clones taking them
on their their Instagram page their
money yeah sometimes at least all over
the country yeah they dude I know of
people who have sent them to other
countries oh yeah so and the same
[ __ ] Cuts so
that virus shouldn't have spread at the
speed it spread
through our industry without assistance
the best part was that after everybody
figured out oh [ __ ]
Dark Art might have been the epicenter
for this stuff then they're like huh we
got a solution yeah we will sell you a
cure for these a cure for this but they
never said that they were the reason for
the season you know that all this is
happening but they did say we will sell
you a cure and it is the real cure for
hbob and guess what it didn't work it
didn't work didn't work also darkheart's
clones dried up at uh these shops in
Harborside for a few months they were
gone like you couldn't find dark heart
cuts and other that's when like purple
City genetics sort of kind of like blew
up because they were able to like fill
shelves
yeah and uh all of a sudden dark cart
comes back and what they did they knew
they had sickness so they just uh they
took the uh God I was just talking to
you about it like before we came on so
they uh
and now I'm drawing the blank on what
the tissue culture so they tissue
cultured everything rebrother along
built it back up I'm assuming that they
were probably buying clones and selling
clones so they could keep their business
going I'm sure you know what I'm saying
yeah a lot of people do that yeah yeah
or they were shutting down one facility
to clean it while they were still
selling nasties over here and then this
this facility was back up and running
with new clean cuts from the tissue
culture and then they shut down the
evidence the thing we know about tissue
culture it's so hit or miss on whether
it's this you know get that like even if
they do Mary stem culture they try to
not get any of that I forgot what they
call it it has to do with their um their
vascular tissue but to make sure none of
that gets along goes along with the Mary
stem is really hard and really
unpredictable yep until it's grown out
is this you don't know until you grow it
out yeah and you don't I have a friend
um on Instagram and that's what he's
doing right now he does a ton of tissue
culture and uh
super smart kid super [ __ ] God man
some of you guys are really [ __ ]
smart some of us older dudes our brains
aren't like yeah we're slow dude we're
[ __ ] drugs dude we're so much [ __ ]
slower than you guys so that's why I've
attended so much LSD is so many drugs so
and if so like sometimes I'll stumble on
my words and it's not because I don't
know what I'm like trying to say it's
because my brain and my mouth they're
not like communicating properly he did
have a part of his colon removed if you
remember I did that was that was
actually between the brain and the mouth
yeah and I've had seizures yeah seizures
really helps my brain yeah the seizures
really [ __ ] that that pathway what's my
excuse I haven't had a seizure yet but
I'm sure brain damage drugs yeah just
just drugs so I did those too but with
also the other good stuff so yeah so he
was still he was telling me about his
tissue culturing and that some of them
they can they can get and
it they're clean the plants are come out
clean so he was really excited and then
later on they found traces of the virus
in the plant and it's like how do how do
we go about this will that virus load
stay as a trace or is that virus load
going to grow as the as the plant is
that grows and I think I think they said
it takes like two years of testing and
constant testing to make sure it isn't
showing up in the in the never stem
culture yep and that was what was so
scary is like he was telling me it's
like once you get it it's like you have
it oh yeah it's like herpes yeah like
you always now your herpes can be like
unnoticeable or you can be one of the
ones that have like the uh
but
um that's what's fun man about that
Twinkie dick but like knowing people and
like actually putting myself out there
more is like meeting more people like
intelligent people that have shared
knowledge and they share I'm good at
certain things they're good at certain
things and they can you know we can kind
of communicate and stuff and uh
I do I do think that there is uh a cure
for it I I I hope we find find it we've
all been working on certain things yeah
certain things are showing uh promise oh
God I hope it works it's right now we
have a plant that had it and now when we
had to test it it doesn't so we'll see
it's like you said it's going to be a
couple of years before I actually get to
talk about it really but we'll see yeah
it'll break my heart after it's been a
year-ish and it pops back up and yeah
it's possible though it's going yeah and
it will absolutely just
be a [ __ ] gut punch but we'll see
where it's at and it was with a spray
that was right important part like we
sprayed the plants it wasn't like
it's things that you can do at home yeah
you don't have to inject it into a
specific yeah into phloem or xylem or
any of that stuff it was a spray yeah we
put it into the roots and we put it onto
the the entire plant and uh
it tested clean and I was the the first
thing was is seeing the plant grew resin
yeah and that was like holy [ __ ] like
that's something that was the first step
right yeah yes and then the plant looked
like what it was supposed to look like
and then the flowers look like what it's
supposed to look like everything was
um now I didn't smoke the flowers
I didn't smoke the flowers
um but I don't humans ingest this that I
think that we use so I mean people
actually take it
uh either but but combustibility I don't
know like yeah you know we can eat
things but if you smoke it it's probably
not going to be super healthy for you
yeah yeah a lot of a lot of um cancer
stuff just comes from the combustion of
certain things and whatnot yeah yeah so
that's where we're at with that but I
think that's exciting it's exciting it
it is it's pretty cool
um so yeah oh God so we went with the
cookie stuff so yeah don't buy their
flowers because the Lord just get away
from that we don't need that anymore the
the gelato times gelato inbred cookies
we're losing so much bottleneck because
of it bottlenecking it's I don't even
really want to call it like
bottlenecking
it's like braiding and intentionally
unusually but yeah this is just idiots
it's like Washington apples man when we
were kids I this is always my analogy
for what's going on in cannabis When We
Were Young Washington apples were
[ __ ] delicious they were kind of ugly
they were off a little bit and like
oblong with knots and stuff but they
were crispy they were juicy they were
all oh my God tastes like apple now you
go get a red delicious apple and it
tastes like wet foam yeah and it was
because they bred for looks on the table
more than they bred for flavor foreign
packaging and transport and all that
yeah yep so have you seen have you seen
the square watermelons the Chinese bread
for packing and shipping they just have
no flavor at all but they're squares so
you can ship them easier and they pack
into boxes easier who cares if they
don't taste good I mean they're Square
yeah
god dude so and that's my concern like
with the Cannabis is like every breeder
it's not like okay you bred something
with gelato or you've read something
with it no no you're taking ruts you're
taking gelato you're taking sherbet and
you're reversing it
to more runts and gelato and Sherbert
and then somebody else is finding clones
from those and they're reversing it to
more runts and gelato and Sherbert so
purple punch really did a [ __ ] number
on the scene
um there's so many people who bred with
punch and so many plants look like punch
and taste like it and and I'm not [ __ ]
talking purple punch I'll smoke it
doesn't it's I don't mind the flavors I
don't need to get blown the [ __ ] out and
that plant does me fine some people need
higher strength than I do that one does
me fine
um and then but basically what we're
getting down to is gelato purple punch
yeah I mean to be honest I rarely even
see punch stuff anymore like you don't
that was such a small wave and it seemed
like for two years everybody hit
everything to punch and then now it's
just back to gelato or cooking
I shouldn't say gelato it's back to
cookies with different names different
names
cookies whether it's sure gelato [ __ ]
yeah whatever you're doing all the [ __ ]
the same thing with the cookies to me
like it's all the same base genetics and
all has a similar look they're different
expressions of the same exact genetics
and and the more people breed them back
to each other even if it's they're not
intentionally breeding trying to inbreed
for for like uniformity yeah that's
what's gonna happen that's what happened
I had a lot of recesses are gonna happen
too so
I wasn't necessarily looking for no
they're not and it's like do you
remember uh when cookies first came
right and it was that little rabbit turd
looking plant it was like this little
little black plant with like these
little tiny buns and
I remember somebody sent me that cut I
was super curious about it because he
was weird yeah it looked [ __ ] weird
and I was always about The Oddities
that's why I like Duck foot and [ __ ] was
my thing you know and uh I got it I grew
it and it was like oh yeah that's that
was pretty cool it's an interesting
point I could never really grow it
though because it's so light like it's
not it wasn't good enough quality to
like Mass produce it to get like top
tier money in my head that's what I was
thinking
um but then when I put it on the market
and then I told people oh no it was Girl
Scout cookies and at the time that's
when it first started to go and people
started telling me stories about oh my
God it's not like eating a Girl Scout
cookie but it's like the Box you know
like after the cookies are gone you
smell the box and I'm like cardboard
it smells like [ __ ] cardboard like
yeah are you telling me my weed smells
like
what the [ __ ] is wrong with you and then
then there was this new one the second
one the animal
um of the Forum yeah with the Forum cut
and that one had like a little more
chunk to it
yeah and um uh then the animal cookies I
remember when animal cookies came out
and two these two these two eight oh
seven no it was it was 2010 and nine
right in there yeah nine ten somewhere
they they always put the 09 label on it
but I didn't see anything about it till
2010 and the animal cookies and these
two dudes went and did a YouTube review
on it and they were like it tastes just
like animal crackers bro do you smell
that like and everybody's just like oh
my God animal that's I love the smell
animal I love that yeah and then they
all smelled it they're like man it does
smell like animal cookies and I'm like
it's not like gas I'm like oh geez what
are you talking about
it's that whole uh
thinking something and you find what
you're looking for you know
um and then that one too the animal
cookies there were the stories about
like oh it was this OG with girls yeah
this one and this one and people started
trying to take credit that they were
like oh yeah I created that yeah
and and back then it was really easy to
pass [ __ ] off yeah because everybody was
new to the inter like these not the
internet but these websites yeah so like
all these cannabis websites you started
popping up popping that popping up like
tons of them and you could just go in
there and have a picture of something
you grew and say oh I created this yeah
I remember when cookies came out
um I was the first one to put it out in
seed form and shortly thereafter swerve
started selling cook cookies and people
were punking him because it was you were
just like relabeling sfe or some other
OG hybrid as cookies and selling it and
then um BC Bud Depot also did same thing
and people are growing up there [ __ ] it
was just awful it wasn't even related to
OG it was just garbage oh garbage yeah I
so [ __ ] God but Jesus Christ
the perps in God Bud
um
I wish that never happened because other
companies back up in these [ __ ] [ __ ] up
for like 10 years yeah and they [ __ ]
it up for other people like God Bud was
from Jordan of the islands he did good
with that they take the name slap it on
their [ __ ] and just like whatever seeds
we got right now this is what you get if
people don't know what you get about BC
Bud Depot like
I mean it's one of the main advertisers
in high times for many years just
exactly smart about what you're buying
um it's it's a very well-known thing
that's been going on for a long time so
just pay attention you know know what
you're buying know your breeder ask your
breeder questions ask for your questions
yeah you know and that's the thing like
how are you going to ask a breeder at BC
bad Depot questions yeah good luck good
luck you're going to get a receptionist
that responds back to your [ __ ] email
that's all like My RCS they're good yeah
I mean do people and here's my question
too do people really still buy their
seats with all the Breeders out now like
I don't know I don't I I think how do
they exist
like how do you think they capture all
the new people just like Cali Connection
like anybody's been around for you know
more than five years knows their their
gig and like they're gimmick and they
don't buy it but there's a constant
influx of new buyers constantly and
that's what these companies rely on they
rely on they rely on you not knowing not
having done the research not knowing
like if you're gonna buy cookies from
them they're they know that you probably
have never [ __ ] grown cookies you
don't even know what it looks like
there it is dude I remember uh
when I I said the story about when I
started doing like these huge grooves up
in a small town called [ __ ] Valley
um and the ones up in Three Rivers it
was funny if it's we had talked about
somebody else who was talking about
stuff oh yeah getting out of Three
Rivers yeah yeah and I was like yeah I
was producing tons of [ __ ] out of Three
Rivers but anyways yeah so the guy that
was up there who owned the land had
bought like thousands of dollars worth
of seats legitimately like
spent so much [ __ ] I think he ended
up put like 15 16 Grand in the seats
yeah but I went up there to
they had growed the year before and got
eight pounds of the worst garbage ever
and they grew like thousands of plants
so they asked me to come up and I was
like yeah man I I will make this I'll do
a thousand pound Grant I promise yeah
it'll happen so he pulls out all these
things he bought
and uh PPP remember that purple Power oh
yeah yeah yeah your power plant yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
and then he had uh BC Bud Depot's
blueberry all right BC bug Depots got
butts BC butt Depots the perps and uh
God they had another one that was God
bud and something mixed together so
he had already uh popped the seeds so
they were already little plants so I had
taken uh at the time I was growing a lot
of this plant that we were calling uh
White skunk or White Rhino
um uh White Buds and I literally just
filled up there was a mountain and it
ran downhill so I started at the top and
we just did rows going down so gravity
could water and just like little ditches
with little offshoots to each stump and
we had like 300 gallon rest 300 gallon
rest 300 gallon rest fill up the
nutrients turn them on and it would just
shoot down the pipes into the little
shoots that the guys made and as they
ran down they would offshoot to each
plant so it was no plastic no anything
it was just dirt you know I mean grow in
thousands of plants is [ __ ] rough
back then especially when it's you and
like two other dudes you know you're all
like oh [ __ ] so anyways
he wanted to grow these so there was a
place over by the old horse corral that
didn't have anything in it it was a nice
Square so I went over and planted all of
his seeds in that horse corral uh the
power plant one he called it purple
Power Plant and it was purple I I don't
know if pure power plant turns purple
but that company could have had multiple
things right sure and it was the
weirdest little plant but it it was it
was whatever but yeah every one of their
blueberries were full-blown herbs
every single one yeah every single one
was full-blown term one of them was one
of the best blueberry smells I've ever
smelled like back to Three Rivers State
blueberry like legitimate blueberry but
it had more [ __ ] her balls on it than
you could ever imagine so you're like
this smells great but dude there's yeah
like half of it is balls like so then
the God Bud was they were all just [ __ ]
yeah there was nothing I don't know what
it was it wasn't the pictures that they
used online who knows yeah it was it was
literally old [ __ ] Dutch [ __ ] not
even good Dutch stuff like yeah just
whatever they had yeah yeah and then the
uh the perps so yeah the perps was we
had one of them that was different it
was like a grape jelly and um but the
butts were small and Airy and so it
wasn't something that you'd want to grow
but there was something in there that
gave it like a great jelly smell like
they had something at the time that made
it hurts you know I don't know what the
[ __ ] they were using but uh that was
kind of like when I was like to show him
like Hey buddy um
just you can't just like go into High
Times magazine and like yes you know
this company and this company they're
paying a lot of money to be in that
magazine they're not in that magazine
because they're cool or good they didn't
earn their spot yeah out of accolades
it's our like what was the other one
um uh the [ __ ] Vancouver Island yes
Vancouver Islands yeah [ __ ] awful I
call it yeah you actually bought those
and ran them that's incredible
I had already at that point seen BC by
the blue trash
um I do still I did order seeds
a couple of times like when I had to
have the little paper and Mark my little
thing down and put a money order in
um but it was like a haze strain and I
got uh some stuff from Sani yeah that
was later though um but I had got a
couple of different hazes I still have
one I I the Garbage barge
um
Uhuru Andy Randy Randy
it's a Randy it's like the old Cincy
seed bank they end up changing the name
I don't know but it was called boo Randy
and I believe it became like sweet tooth
or Blockhead later on in life uh
damn it I'll have to send you the yeah
yeah I'll send you a picture of it but
it's in the the one that I did with
Garbage barge
um
God damn it man this is what I was
talking about the younger ones the
brains the brains the brains
but I'm pretty sure it's what ended up
becoming
either Sweet Tooth or Blockhead there
was two different strains probably block
it Blockheads like a a project 19 cross
and it's just some weird like African
sativa hybrid of some sort yeah so it
was probably Blockhead if I know it's
one of those two but it was
boom boom ranthi or something it was
from the region that they had got the
seats from and that was like the first
pack of scenes I ever ordered was those
and I don't even remember why I wanted
this
that specific what yeah what pulled you
into that I remember I want to order
that one for twelve dollars I remember
ordering like some canopy and they put
out something called Leches at one time
it's like a Lesotho Haze and I remember
ordering it and thinking God's Gonna Be
bomb and I remember getting it and
thinking why did it why
like a South African lesobo and a haze
it's gonna be 25 weeks they grow this
for my entire year why did I think that
that was gonna be something for me yeah
that's why I think it's funny that I see
a lot of these projects now from guys
who are uh just like trying to get their
name onto the scene and a lot of it
they're trying to say it's like oh this
African Haze or the this uh Thai strain
or this uh uh oh God Vietnamese strain
or whatever and some of them that you
see are legitimately
sativa and some of them look like it and
you see some of them that look like
[ __ ] cookies and you're all
like caps Colombian like when he said
his nine-week Colombian I was like whoa
I forgot he also had a land race
Japanese plan
yeah yeah
she's always been super [ __ ] nice to
me
like like that we message and email and
stuff but Mac isn't
any of those things no I could remake
Mac from Colorado flow Super Lemon Haze
and like a few other things it's it's
the lemon part that constantly shows up
and it's off projects it's breathing
projects and then
I've known Jaws
or
I since Canada's on yeah he was my first
troll yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah uh he's
really bad at trolling uh but uh he has
like all these alien cookie candy yeah
yeah candy cookie aliens alien rocks and
all these different strengths and uh
that I could imagine that and lemon haze
type or I don't even know if it's like
pure Lemon Haze
um there was that uh really soft lemon
plant that was going around
right you know a couple of years before
that came out
um before Matt came out and uh I
remember growing it and I was like wow
that's really interesting the way it
looked because it had these puffier buds
but they kind of looked like how scdc
looks like oh really yeah yeah it's not
like a sativa like it was like like
almost like Northern Lights you know
like like it has a structure to it you
know but it had this lemony zestiness to
it which I still don't know what the
plant was like I was given the plant
they were like I don't know what it is
and I was really intrigued by it super
resonated I mean all right
erase all that imagine purple punch with
lemon
thank you instead that's what it was not
as resonated as purple punch but for the
time you [ __ ] resonated yeah
it wasn't as powdery of a resinous
purple punch there was a little more of
an oil stickiness too yeah but it had a
soft like not like a lemon chemical like
a like a like a lemon peel like a sweet
like a Meyer lemon type thing this thing
Sweet Lemon there yeah it was the thing
but it was there and I grew it for a
while and I I was like I could like you
wanted to smoke it like because like
that flavor yeah yeah goddamn you'd want
to put joints out halfway so you could
smoke it again yeah yeah yeah not the
half out joint that joint got thrown
away because
I like joints so I can have an MF gets
there now and then I will like I want to
do fresh green one I don't want that
other [ __ ]
I need to smoke that [ __ ] Till It's Gone
But I am such a press now it's like no I
only want good fresh green [ __ ] that's
it I want all the fresh turnips right
now have you have you seen the riptek
thing that I used did I show that to you
the [ __ ] it looks like in anal
torture device but it's a glass probe
that Heats and it connects to a bowl and
it and it has like holes on the side so
when you suck it you're sucking air down
through this like heat Vortex that goes
into the bowl into a bong so you can
actually like
you hit a bong of vapor it's it's
amazing that's okay you can get some of
the most amazing like a lot of the Terps
that normally you wouldn't get through
vaporization or combustion for whatever
reason because you can dial it in So
Perfect like you can get so many
different flavors that you normally
wouldn't expect it to be in a Bud that
you smell and it's it's pretty
phenomenal I don't think they make them
anymore but they they should if they
don't
I know when I first started to like not
put fire on the ball like keep my
lighter up high and like like trying to
use the heat from it yeah yes and that
was the first like time like I was young
when I started learning that that was
like the first time where I was like
holy [ __ ] like that tastes way [ __ ]
different back then it was brick weed
and yeah of course
I wish people could see some of the good
Breakaway holy [ __ ] there was some that
would come in uncompressed that was
really nice every once in a while big
[ __ ] buds my my dad had uh
so my dad would go to Mexico
yeah and bring in hundreds of keys and
uh they would all be labeled in
different colors I I don't know if I've
said the story but I'm gonna say it
anyways yeah go ahead so there would be
like black uh ones that were wrapped in
black and those were like for his
personal like these you keep then they'd
be green red orange and [ __ ] like that
and each one of them was a step down
yeah so when you finally got Kai you got
caught with 180 of them but uh yeah
that's why we've had that like take off
you know yeah and like disappear for
some years when I was really little uh
so
he is the like the guy that like I
always went to when I had questions
about anything from Mexican way Mexico
we
and that's why he was all like oh the
orange buds that all comes you know like
that was coming up from Mexico in the
[ __ ] 70s and yeah I was like you know
and he was all even like a lot of this
green Piney stuff he was all like the
skunks that I was growing in the 80s was
coming from the Mexican seeds from the
70s like that he was importing you know
so and that was his Scots like not like
skunk number one these are like the
plants that they were all like God damn
it smells like a skunk it actually
smelled like skunk so they called it
yeah they called it [ __ ] skunk you
know and uh
so ah
yeah and then there was a guy he's
they're all they're all passed now so I
don't feel bad news in their names he
went by Mikey Dale and uh so when my dad
left uh so my dad worked the fields they
were field workers and that's where he
met all the young uh the Mexican kids
they all grew up together and so then
when they all went back to Mexico
my dad stayed here and he was in high
school they would come back for the
summer and they would bring weed with
them and stuff and uh they'd make like
little pipes he said out of like the
grapevines because you could Hollow them
out and like smoke it like that and uh
he was also by the time I graduated high
school uh he was going to play
professional baseball and he got drafted
by the Angels oh wow this [ __ ] and uh
instead my mom got pregnant and uh she
went and let them leave so he's all like
well I gotta make money so he hooked up
with his old buddy so he was just
driving back and forth yeah uh into the
border and uh most of the time he didn't
actually have to go into Mexico they
would just meet down on one of the
Border areas he just pull up and they
would be waiting and loaded up the
[ __ ] videos off and gone
but he still would tell me like and
before he passed I was growing a lot of
really good we like I was growing a lot
of [ __ ] really good weed and he would
compare it
to some of the stuff that he would have
back then now he would say most of the
stuff that I was growing now was way
[ __ ] better but there were still a
few that he would get uh but those
Growers those generational Growers those
Family Growers they did get run out they
they lost all their land they recorded
out by cartels and and big money and
things like that
so those people who are growing and my
dad was getting it from they no longer
exist their genetics are gone and then
when the new [ __ ] Growers came in
there they were trying to grow whatever
I've seen their grows in in Mexico I've
seen how they grow it here yeah I've
been on
actual cartel grows I've
I've been told that I was going to be
kidnapped and all kinds of crazy [ __ ] so
I could go and build grows and yeah just
wild stuff so like I needed to be
careful and
due to some of the [ __ ] craziest [ __ ]
um so anyways uh it's horrible they
literally will just have like a sack of
seeds and they were just throwing them
down like you would [ __ ] corn yeah of
course just growing out and males and
females and it didn't [ __ ] matter the
good Growers knew not to do that the
good Growers cold meals and they
actually bred what they wanted for the
next season and and it was like um
in what is it Morocco I think the really
good hash most of their hash was made
like from the year before so the plants
that they would Harvest they would sit
all [ __ ] winter and then they would
start growing the next year and that's
when they started making the hash that
was plants are old and beat up and all
that stuff yeah I think laying in dirt
yeah exactly but it was easier for that
[ __ ] separation of the trichome you
know and yeah they just sit there
yeah tap that [ __ ] yeah tap it over the
sieve screens but the also
I also was told like learn from some of
the older guys who did serve a Vietnam
that yeah they would they would uh bury
the Cannabis even when it was wet yeah
molds yeah and it would ferment and then
they would smoke it and it would be like
a loose in The Chins yeah that's what
it's What DJ Short and his book referred
to as African black magic which is
fermented Malawi cob
um like buried in a corn cob and stuff
yeah it's wild
smoking beer yeah and so I uh the friend
who told me that story he's actually in
hospice right now he's still with us
that's too bad uh yeah and but he was
like like one of my dad's best friends
so he knows all like my dad's old
stories and everything like that you
know but he was telling me he did I
think two tours in Vietnam and he was
not a big heroin guy like most of the
soldiers that's what they were getting
you know heroin and he would have been
the Cannabis guy his whole life because
that's what they did they switched weeds
from the 60s you know they're on and uh
yeah he said that they've started to
finally like start making trade for
American cigarettes
uh Foods you know candies and stuff like
that and people would start giving them
heroin but they also would offer them
weed Buds and it was all like some of
these buds were weird because some of
them were tight like yeah
yep and then he was all some of them
were like like rotten Brown weird stuff
like he was all but they smoked it it
was like their version of like cannabis
opium if you will oh weird is all I'm
telling you he was all like that stuff
would be buried for I have no idea how
long but they buried it fresh too like
yeah that's right very it like so it was
cured underground but by hearing it and
he was said that he would like
hallucinate and like go on yeah I've
heard people do it yeah I want to show
you what this this anal torture wand
looks like
look at that can you see it yeah it's
like electric yes yeah and in this end
attaches to a bowl and it never touches
the weed it only Heats it to a certain
temperature and it's it's I don't know
anymore but it was seriously like I
would buy this company if I could
because it was it was that old
revolutionary of a of a thing for me oh
yeah smoke that I could imagine because
all Vapes are kind of the same you know
vaporizers you know there's a hot plate
and they exactly the flower like it's
not due with ceramic plates secondary
heat yeah there's actual contact with
this like you're heating something
that's heating something else every
single Vape I've ever smoked oh there's
always this uh popcorn taste to it that
never that's always there like no matter
what you do yeah and this doesn't have
that because you can dial it in so
perfect and it's secondary heat it's not
touching the butt oh it's just so cool
hopefully [ __ ] it I I do hope the
company gets I remember the last time I
talked to him someone wanted to buy one
and they said they didn't have any
American plugs for them which whatever
that means they don't have to hear it um
yeah but yeah I mean they're so worth it
anybody who like wants to sample or or
try any cannabis and get the real like
flavor profile and and really nail it
it's the easiest way to do it because
you're not you're not tasting the
chlorophyll and all the other stuff that
you're trying to move through you know
yeah like we don't really like
yeah I understand like you want to get
that flavor you just want that Essence
and that's why you just want the oil and
that's all it is yeah
the combustion gives you a different
high like compare the fleet but if you
want to just pure flavor this thing
makes me uh I can imagine flowers and
just be like
and I I didn't I thought it would be a
lot lighter because I don't know why
like you don't get as much smoke in your
lungs because it's vapor so it doesn't
feel the same thing if you're gonna get
as high yeah you don't think you're
gonna get as high for whatever reason
but I always end up doing the mumble
jumble like after we come from the time
when if it we didn't choke we weren't
smoking like you know
yeah exactly exactly you know like man
my weed never makes me [ __ ] cough
anymore it's so smooth now you know like
oh I love you I don't cough anymore
that's true it's I think these things
are just so filled with [ __ ] and ass but
lungs are just so [ __ ] wrecked it's
all like I don't care I'm good let's
smoke some of that dirty dirt and we
just look dirty dirt oh God damn you
don't even know some of it I mean we
don't even know what dirty dirt we smoke
to be honest God no God no the nastiest
of pesticides yeah
yeah we have done a whole nother episode
and I'm sure we can pile down a hundred
thousand more problems so yeah but yeah
uh this is this is the smell boat
episode two yeah episode two and this
time we actually have a time for the
release of the beans I know yeah so we
should have them out in a week which
might mean two for us it might be two
enough uh tin is the max 10 is the max
yes uh and I think there might be five
of one of them I'm gonna have to look
but I think it's ten packs Max and
that's it okay literally from that one
that'll be it so if you really want
something
um
I don't flood [ __ ] like I just don't
flood my markets I never have I never
will
so if you buy some of my seeds you're
getting something that other
[ __ ] won't have and you know
it's it's just different it's it's good
uh I think uh I think picking these ones
first is uh I think people are gonna
like freak [ __ ] out
because I that rainbow sister dude that
chocolate I like I like that one yeah a
lot do you still keep the cut you still
have her oh yeah I have rainbow rainbow
sister I haven't done the rainbow for me
when I see you yeah I have another one
that I haven't shown off as much because
she's kind of ugly it's the only rainbow
I've ever found that was ugly but it
really pulls the OG like the old school
old school OG
um but good God like you literally could
like squeeze the buds and it would stick
to the wall for all day yeah you could
just stick it on there and it wouldn't
[ __ ] come off it's like that sap it's
like I remember my dad told me that when
at first afghanis came through that was
the one thing they noticed is that you
could
stick it on a wall and they all said
like it would stick to the wall they
were so surprised by it because it does
yeah it pops when you smoke it the the
resin pots inside there's like these
little pods and they have like sap
inside of it so when you smoke it you'll
actually see it looks like fireworks
and people that are inexperiencing
people like oh you need to flush it
better yeah yeah
you need to [ __ ] off yeah you need to
learn to smoke dude I've only had that
happen with a few different strains uh
where the pods get so filled with
[ __ ] resin that like as you're
smoking it they like they sparkle the
[ __ ]
uh one of the one of the weirdest ones
God I hate saying this too it was the
sfv by rainbow that did it that sfv that
cut so weird but man there's some good
ones there's something yeah
uh so that was when you brought up
swerve was passing sfv cut yeah yes
cookies I'm all like why didn't you just
say what the [ __ ] it was that shit's up
if you had a real sfe that's a [ __ ]
Banger man like no he wanted cookies
yeah no one would give it to him
anyway episode episode 2 is smelly in
the bag
um is there anything else you wanna you
wanna uh plug before then or just the
seeds we got the seats I think that's it
if anybody you know has questions or
whatever you guys know where to find me
smell smell boat on Instagram and
Instagram is where he responds best I
don't social media and other places
really so I made a
uh what is it called a Reddit thing on
accident somehow so and I got a message
on there and I didn't even know I had a
Reddit thing now you know if I'm saying
it right Reddit is it ready
yeah something like that's like porn
site I think I think
that's what it is I think it starts but
thanks guys for listening thank you for
all the messages the responses the you
know all that stuff it's [ __ ] great
and Matt thanks for having me on again
I'm gonna take us out and uh run the
music and hopefully it'll run at the
right spot it never does
see you
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray from making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]