[Music]
welcome to breeders syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene through the eyes of the folks who
lived it i'm matthew owner of riot seeds
i'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not-so-dog breeder and grower
from mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
so i decided to add in this jj new york
interview because there's some really
good info in it um there's a few
technical difficulties in the beginning
and uh yeah just want to apologize for
that in advance but there's good info in
here
jj has been an old friend for a long
time uh early member of the kim crew
family and always has good insight so
hope you enjoy
what's going on not much just dealing
with the normal [ __ ]
you know how it goes
so um yeah there's a couple things i
wanted to talk to you about
let's do it one being
one being the jesus jesus uh the jesus
is super scum
candy to my knowledge
right you you stated it was super skunk
i think uh it could be a super skunk s1
we don't know because there's no chem d
coming out of the progeny at all in any
of the s1
um
that came out of a chemd uh mother
though chem the
flower i was told i was told by greg
that it came out of the super skunk
flower that the chem d hearn
uh i thought i i i was uh told the
opposite but maybe
either one of us
either one of us could be robbed greg
didn't keep good notes as we know
right right and that's
from those guys you know him and the
weasel both you could ask
the same question twice and get two
different answers
that's a fact dude
right
but um but uh have you grown
the mass super skunk no i have never
grown mass super skunk never never had
it
okay because uh
you know
with the speculation that the mass super
skunk is
with the
sour diesel i kind of have a couple
discrepancies about that
because the mass super skunk if you ever
grown it it grows kind of medium height
and it's it's a single cola with a very
thick stem
i mean so like the
the theory that it would be part of the
the chem dog um
with the chem dog making a sour diesel
uh the grow thought the growth structure
is just is way off
you know what i'm saying um
like if you ever
if you've grown cabin 91 that's the sour
diesel
like this the the growth the sativa
growth on the shower diesel is just
you know if you've grown it i don't have
to yeah yeah it's night and day from cam
91 sure
right so
so if the theory of
the super skunk went into it
then where does all that sativa growth
come from you know i mean unless it's a
recessive trait but
i kind of uh disagree with that because
uh i've i've grown that the dnl
that that i think that
is part of the uh
sour diesel and it grows
exactly the same just that really
stretchy sativa you have to top it off
and just branch it out and everything
all right
so that that's just my my yeah i i agree
with your ddnl and i saw a lot of sour
traits in it as well
i would agree with it right and i
thought and i was gonna ask you that
because i thought a while back that you
had uh grown some of those uh dnl
crosses and i wanted to get your i
thought it was good dude
i love that [ __ ]
yeah i still sitting on some beans i i
haven't uh brought them out in a long
time but uh
i got so many different things i've been
working on that uh
i don't know i got to try to get into it
soon especially with all this uh with
all this skunk uh controversies that are
going on
and then speaking of controversies over
uh
this whole thing with uh
[ __ ] giraffe net
dick nick yeah
yeah i mean
you know if i was skunked va i would
have just ripped his head off right
there on the side i'm surprised he
didn't
uh yeah that dude is just like a mellow
dude and he's the kind of dude that
once he snaps
like
you know there's no stopping i mean he's
got
he's got
his arms are the size of my thighs
it's like popeye he's like a wrestler
he's like a shirt yeah i mean like i
couldn't believe what joy joy brett told
him to suck his dick or something online
uh yeah but there was he went up to his
booth
and they uh had some kind of uh
conversation and then he came outside
and i was in a circle with uh
the swamp boys
and
uh bronson was there and he just like
[ __ ] lost his mind you know i mean i
thought i was gonna have to fight him at
first but then but then i became like
his therapist
i mean
i kind of had like a a shred of uh
sympathy for the guy he was saying he
went to jail and
everyone hates him and how he wants to
be accepted and and all this other
[ __ ] you know you were the voice of
reason usually you're swinging
unless he stopped fronting i was like
you know you're
he's he's handing us you know a jar of
skunk around and i'm like yo you think
that's real road kill i told them i give
them you know some kind of skunk one or
something like that
like but when you smell it i mean it
kind of has that smell to it but the bud
structure itself is like very kind of um
leafy and sativa-like and then smoke it
just it tastes like straight-up pay and
i'm not saying not to be a hater no no
i'm giving you my
opinion and i told the mother hey listen
if you had something that great i would
congratulate yeah for sure
you're just thinking that everyone's
saying [ __ ] to be a hater i'm giving you
my honest opinion and everyone i talked
to that was in that expert i saw that
stuff was just like
yeah he brought it to emerald cup too
and it was uh
and the people that touched the
underside of the jar got some orange
[ __ ] on their fingers that smelled like
real skunk
he didn't have any of that going on but
poor fella you know
he's charting in dangerous territories
[ __ ] around with duke and skunk
[Music]
we'll see what happens at the next yeah
right
let it boil over a little bit
but you know but you know in there and
then there's all these other guys that
you know
you know say they have the the road
killing and i had the original super
strong back in like 1995 and let me tell
you when you just cracked that jar or
just permeated
you know
and then i had gotten to cut years later
it was just this wasn't the same it
didn't give out those same kind of terms
or whatever i don't know if a different
cut or the
you know you know
cuts just dud out after
and and it's starting to happen with the
sour diesel because everyone asked me oh
where's that that was that sarah diesel
at you know with that old time sour
diesel and
you got to figure it that's like 25
years that's how
how long that
that cut is now so
and it just been given you know from
person to person from room to room and i
think you know
cuts adapt to the room that they're in
so you know
your shower diesel is going to come out
different than my sorrow diesel now if
you start giving out cuts and i start
giving out touch you know after a while
i think there could be you know some
type of genetic drift that you know
might happen not anything drastically
but you know there's just seems to be
these
small subtle things that seem to be
missing from the from the sour uh
nowadays sure yeah i mean acclimates
from room to room to room to room and
that thing's so [ __ ] old yeah
right but i've had we had you know the
original underdog which was super skunk
now times in 91 it just went bad on us i
mean we had the cut
and then after a while it just
it only showed glimmers of itself you
know when it was really really good and
then we start you know the um
the harvest went down it was harder to
clone and everything and then after a
while my phone was like he gave to me i
did a little bit of work with it and my
phone was like listen i'm just going to
let it down yeah
but we just let it go you know and that
was it but i've heard up and i remember
just buying from buying weed there's
this stuff called the wheelchair or the
the wheelchair and back in the day
that [ __ ] you know
was giving you bomb and then
the same thing after a while you just
could not get the same batches
just from buying it after a while and
the same people were growing it and
everything but what's the wheelchair
i'm not sure it was just some type of um
local um strain that was sold in new
york city
in the back of the 90s
you know back then we didn't really have
uh you know
names weren't really
you know the thing that they are now so
uh yeah
i have no idea what it was
so let's talk about i-95
yeah i think i've seen so or i think
i've seen some stuff referenced like
as the wheelchair or the crippler or
something like that and
i'm gonna have to uh really find out a
you know where that really came from but
i think that you know
that stuff came from amsterdam back back
in the day sure did yeah
let's talk about i-95 that's it that's
this
yeah that was the other one
let's talk about the history of it all
of it
you know um
that's a money mike strain and
originally he bred that back in like
2014 we brought it to the
denver cup
last denver cup was 2014.
and we and we brought that it was um
it was uh legend star dog male times uh
the triangle cush yeah
so he bred that we brought that out um
and we were friends with tara rojo
and we went over to mindful and he gave
us a tour and you know and so we gave
him some seeds i gave him some store dog
seeds he got some i-95 seeds and
you know we you know we're just trying
you know
to help the guy yeah just be nice not
right not knowing well
you know going further back
he had invited us to
uh share his booth in one of the first
few denver cups it might have been 2011.
yeah i mean so um you know we you know i
always you know respected phil and you
know uh thanked him for you know helping
us and everything and so yeah
he needs to you know to play with and
stuff and um
so you know he grew those seeds out and
then
see this is where
it starts getting kind of fudgy because
oh no when i confronted him you know he
says you know that
he had started the seeds
and left mindful or i'm not really sure
but
we gave the seeds to fill yeah i mean
and then before we know it
uh one of his workers uh matt ross
um started a seed company basically
with the seeds that we gave phil yeah
phil
phil claims that he
he stole him from mindful took him out
and started playing with him at his
house and all but
um you know we held us phil responsible
for that
and
he claims that but you know he
uh like
he hired the same guy to run uh some
kind of you know get some kind of job in
chicago
so to me i think that
you know he kind of set him up to kind
of be the bad guy
and while phil
spread those genetics all through his
his um
his you know his dealings with eight
yeah yeah
and he said he's got the acreage thing
and he does you know other smaller stuff
on on the side
yeah i mean like i know you know you got
some stuff in baltimore and maryland and
then uh pennsylvania and i don't know if
those are acreage
uh related or not but i do know they're
running the i-95 chemd yeah that those
guys made
and um
and then you know so
you know they they did that and then we
had uh elite the elite guys which those
guys are friends of ours yeah they're
good friends of mine too
and you know they you know they took a
packer on i-95 and just you know they
did the same thing
i mean they bought them
i mean but then you know they saw what
uh
what these guys did with it and they and
they started doing the same crosses that
they did but they didn't sell it
[Music]
they didn't sell them but they were
giving them away
but just even doing giving them away
you're trying to like make a name for
yourself you know i mean and the way
that i look at it is if you know if you
bought if you're given a pack of i-95
candy
do you think you're ever ever gonna buy
one from me
yeah i mean the chances
did you guys ever release the i-95 md or
the i-95 publicly
oh yeah i'm selling them i didn't know
that because
yeah so i'm selling them now so
everybody go grab your i-95 md from jj
top dog seeds right here
well basically i took um
you know i took f2s from them guys and
then i
i mean
well they gave me f1s and i made f2s
with them but then i started um
crossing into some of the different
other strains and then money mike also
uh did a remake of his uh
i-95 into the chem d and made the chem
chem uh the d95s so that's money mike's
take on yeah and my periods on is just
an f2 on it so i took dirt yeah and then
i took their original that um chem daily
uh
chem that the the the chem d um
the chem d leaning uh
fina was the one that that i f2 that
that i had gotten but i had they had i
mean
and i went over there with with those
and went after phil left
and uh and
uh matt and his brother uh jackson both
gave me seeds gaming buds tell me told
me how much they loved me
you know all
the whole thing and then and then he
went around and did that yeah i mean
and then wave gem
did the same exact thing they came up to
our booth in in boston and told us how
much they loved us and blah blah blah
and money mike wanted to punch the guy
out because he was playing around with
with you know he was he was getting into
dangerous uh territory
at that time and i told him yo you
better just back off and you know i mean
you're getting a little bit too close
yeah i mean and then he got all stupid
and did the same thing yeah i mean so
everyone tells you that they love you
how much they respect you this and that
come and kiss your ass
they get your gear and they want to be
like you and they just go and just you
know
just try to copy it all the work that
you've done yeah and
so you know it just needs to be a uh you
know common trait you know i mean
you know on instagram now yeah it's a
different world
at least on the forums like people would
get called out
all the time by a lot of people you know
what i mean
yeah but you know now you know it's just
as easy to you know you just block
someone not no one really you know has
the you know respect or
the decency anymore you know back in the
day was a lot different
it was a lot different than now i i've
never heard of that wavegen is that a
new company
uh is just some some guys i think there
were some kid that was at a rhode island
rhode island and he's up there um in
maine now
all right
i'll keep mine i don't want to get
yeah wave wait uh yeah wave gem or jim
wavegem genetics or
he's changed his name a few times he's
gotten deleted
you know and then you got green point
another one here i mean
man he he took the i-95 he took the star
dog you did the same thing you know this
guy right here
yeah wave genetics all right yeah
someone put it up wave genetics that's
that's the guy
so hey i got a question for you
um a lot of people don't know what dnl
is in the first place can you go over it
for people
well as far as i know the dnl originally
originated
was the rfk skunk
which the the
um the weasel mike
and gabby went down to a dead show
at rfk and scored a bag of kind bud and
found i don't know like eight or ten
seeds or whatever
so
um they both agreed to split the seeds
and when they did it they actually put
all the seeds out on the table and they
and each one by one i picked this one i
picked that one i picked this one i
picked that one
and um
when the weasel um
and he wound up um
getting i don't know like three
different finos
and and that's when i first met him in
central park he was selling skunk one
skunk two skunk three yeah that's what
he called them and then um
a friend of his
uh
wound up getting like some type of um
some nlc's and some hawaiian seeds
and i think that
uh he wound up having no siege and he
gave him uh one of some of those
uh rfk clones
and so he he made his own stream by
combining the three
and he just called it the nl but
you know it might have had some l in it
but it was mostly sativa dominant in in
structure
and you know and the uh the hawaiian it
kind of had these tropical like
tropical skunky tones a little bit yeah
i mean
kind of you get you get little bits
you know you could taste in a sour
sometimes you mean
um
so you know so that was a strain that he
grew exclusively
and i think that he gave it back to
the weasel to grow
and
you know that's what what i just suspect
was in the room
when uh
you know
those uh seeds were made originally
weren't made but were found originally i
mean in the 91 because i mean i
you know i used to sell weed for the
weasel he grew it i sold it but he had a
few but he had vondo
and there were a few other people that
were that would weasel in and try to uh
to buy to buy because it was
it was like a race because i would you
know he would only get like a couple
pounds so it was like
you know
you just had to grab everything that he
had at the time just cashed him out and
you know this way you had control of of
all of that
because
you know back in the day people would
just come in and just want to buy it all
you know i mean and i would be like i
can't sell it to you all because you
know i i like to spread it out and
i would sell to other people that did me
favors you know man so
you know
when i get something
you know i'll hit you off you can make
some money just do me a favor you know
get me you know receive me you know this
or that and so you could use it as like
a bordering tool
to you know get other favors from people
sure what do you know if the rfk's still
around or is that long gone
no that's been long gone yeah and then
really recently they lost the dnl within
the last like two years or so also so i
mean that's why i was thinking about
trying to
you know fall back on some of those um
seeds i've made yeah dude
let's see if i can pull anything out
that's like the original that would be
real cool real cool
because really i wanted to try to
reverse that into the 91 and see what
would happen
because
when i first started growing
uh
in like 99
you know i
you know i i had been selling wheat for
a long time and anytime i had some
anything that was super killing i found
seeds i would save them i mean yeah and
then
then at one time i had a you know really
badass collection from the 80s and and
all that and the cops took it i got
busted back of cakes and that into the
cops wearing a cake in it so i wound up
starting a new one
and then so i started that one and when
i started getting the chem dog you know
uh you know every once in a while you
might find
a seed or two in there so i would save
them and so when i started
um
i popped a few of those seeds and really
back then there was no really such thing
as the sour yeah
but you know but
you know
looking back i had
found some stuff that was very sour like
very sour ish you know i mean
and i remember i had um
i had
something happened i think that we were
we were we had to
close down the grill whatever and i had
just popped these seeds and i sexed them
and i grew them and then and
i gave the clone to my friend and i was
like listen i was like
i said the only thing i know that this
is like you know came from out of the
cam dog into female
and i gave it to him
and he grew it out and that
became uh the gua the guava but not the
guava of today i got
you he so he called that cut the guava
but it was kind of very sourish and all
yeah
and and he ran it and then eventually
lost it you know i mean
and then um years later
i wound up doing the star dog and i had
gifted my friends some seeds
to give to andre grossman the
photographer of high times okay
and he um
he grew him out and he found a fino
that was
today's guava
so what happened was um somehow while he
well what happened was
they liked that cut so much
uh and at the time
they had
at high times they had the um
kyle cushman strawberry cough yeah and
they actually had they had a plant they
had a plant in the
in the office
and like anyone that that went into the
office if they liked you enough they
would cut you off cut you a couple
clones right off the plant in the office
and let you go home with them
so
so eventually the same thing happened
with the guava
and
both the guava and the strawberry cough
became the
the office strains
so
years later like i was saying the same
guy that named the guava tells me
that he got the guava he got the guava
back
so
um
we
eventually find out that it comes
full circle back from the high times
guys
and so like um
that was how you know that the guava
kind of got its name of today though
uh but it was originally uh
some type of uh sour chem
something the original cup but i
remember it and
it was very soured usually but i don't
think well i didn't get to ever finish
it out actually well one of them i did
and then another one i didn't yeah
i mean i did get to finish one out
but then
i had popped another seed and that was
the seed that i gave my friend
but it came from the same batch of seeds
now
was the star dog guava similar in terps
or anything to the other guava
not really i mean the guava
uh of today is more comfor-ish
one of my things more like become full
where
the other one was
more more uh
kind of 91-ish
yeah
it's a little more fuel easier a little
more fuelly sorry
the original one was
do you still have any of those old uh
the purple afghan cross i think you did
a purple star dog with it
um
with a purple star dog with water uh i
think it was british empire's purple
afghan yeah i did i never really um i
never popped any of those seeds i do i'm
sitting on them
and i think i did some into the chemd oh
wow
and i think i did some into the original
haze too those all could be real that
afghan original haze could be [ __ ]
real interesting
i i wound up um
flowering out some of that stuff and
some of it was green and some of it was
purple just by zoom out yes you know
and uh i wound up using a male and you
know i [ __ ] up and never made f2s out
of that you know
but i do have that just just the crosses
into the star dog and the chem dude yeah
that would be fascinating to see pop
back up
yeah but the the purple star dog that i
uh that i me you know the purple came
from the trade dog mail
and and the purple probably came from
the afghan and that bass danny was a uh
scentsy seed uh afghan
field afghani one
afghan one yeah and i think you know
looking back into that that wasn't
really like a true
uh
cultivar as in one string i think it was
a mix of their best afghanis or
something like that
and then even like looking back into um
the the the maple leaf
i think even like the maple leaf really
wasn't really uh
really like one stable strain i think
there were
uh a variety of different phenos in
there
because there if you if you look back
into the the seed the seed bank catalog
they actually offer that
like a 50 pack or something like that
and it's more of like a breeders
you know i mean they don't really you
know i mean
but it sounded like you know there was
you know a lot of different different
varieties in there
but the one
guy that they talk about uh maple leaf
uh whoever they called one guy maple
leaf yeah
of uh you know the finos that he was
growing at the time so i guess all that
was based off of his stuff you know i've
always um found that a lot of the the
stuff that was listed as maple leaf
indica like that was used tend to look
like afghani one so i don't know if they
have a similar parentage that way back
up
i think you know because i look back and
i think you know if you look into the
catalogs on the afghani one it says it's
like a mix of their three or four best
afghanis or what or whatever you know
but when i grew it
it kind of it grew um
very fat stemmed
a single cola
kind of short medium height
and um
it didn't really have a really uh
the terps on it weren't really super
strong it was kind of subtle yeah
so that's why i figured it would be a
good out process to go and yeah yeah
i'll cross into the chem because it
wouldn't be dominant you know because it
kind of had like a kind of a madisony a
little madison knee popping
you know it was decent you know i mean
i i smoked the flower
but you know it wasn't anything
uh that would compare to the chem dog
but the structure
you know that you know definitely added
you know because it gave you that really
thick stem yeah
you know and and all
the all the um the calyx the blood ratio
you know there wasn't much leaf on that
so
you were you know you're one of the
first guys i saw from not necessarily
the modern era but um
prior to the modern era that was
actually using like the northern lights
the
super skunks the afghani one [ __ ] like
that and that always inspired me to go
in that direction for those bass lines
so i appreciate that
yeah well i was always a big scentsy
seed fan back in the day yeah i mean
their genetics are not the same
unfortunately
yeah
but you know but if you're looking back
most of that stuff they got from neville
yeah i mean all that stuff was seed bank
stuff that
you know when neville was in jail and
you know they bailed him out and
you know they gave him money or whatever
so
i'm pretty sure that that was the story
behind that yeah some of the best stuff
there is as far as baselines go i think
if people don't grow that stuff they
won't have an idea of
a lot of the traits and modern stuff
like they're they're they don't have a
good base knowledge
and
and looking back like i know people you
know they have talked to the drunkers
and they've admitted that they've lost
all their mother plants in the back in
the day
but you know someone like adam dunn he
was working you know with them back in
the 90s
and so he you know knows firsthand a lot
of that stuff that went on
uh
but you know he uh he you know he left
after he left that's real you know
and then uh i don't know who else was
doing i don't know who else was doing
their breathing
um
back in the 90s i'm not sure
but you know
because you used to be able to get those
cellophane
uh cord packs yeah
and then they upgraded to the box with
the bubble yeah the box in the bubble
all that stuff was junk
and leading up
leading up until today because
my friend he had bought
a pack of jack carrera like you know the
year won the cup or whatever
and um
you know he grew it out you know i was
selling the weed and
after a while uh
they need this kind of people got sick
of it you know i mean they started you
know they told them to stop doing it
he's like oh don't worry
i'll kill it i still have the whole pack
left
you know years later i said hey why
don't you look for that pack well i lost
it i mean so
then i was able to grab a pack of the
boxes
and i gave him a pack of the jack
carrere and he grew it out and
[Music]
this way it just
and you know i think really by then
that's when a lot of people started
outsourcing
to uh yeah
a lot of that stuff
comes back you know it's kind of like
jack knee
they have a jack turk to it but it's you
know it grows very sativa-like but it
you know it's kind of wispy and like
i don't know i just call it like generic
hamster yeah
and and like even like uh adam says you
know like that the the jack itself is
like i don't know like a 12 way cro
you know 12 way cross or something i
mean just
four things that just cross back into
each other and
after a while just becomes like uh
you know a
genetic like
meth yes where
this comes
it's just very generic in
in what it's producing becomes a muddled
mess
it looks like we've got a minute left
anything else you want to get in my man
well we got into pretty much everything
i'm surprised we're able to squeeze it i
know dude well hey it's a pleasure
having you on uh
you're one of the best thank you very
much man
i appreciate it i'm glad we were able to
go over these things and just you know
iron out some of the
confusion that might have been out yeah
for sure man appreciate it talk soon
brother all right
peace out
want more breeder syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out
need seeds check out riotsheets.com
where you can get our seeds and our
reversal spray for making your own
feminized seeds
[Music]
so
you