hello everyone welcome to the uh breeder
syndicate riot seeds germination
tutorial i figured i just start from
scratch um but the first thing i can't
really show you because there's no sink
here
wash your hands wash them thoroughly
wash them with soap
get up in there
hot water super important kill all the
bacteria
a lot of the germination process is
defeated by bacteria
so yeah so we'll start with that we have
some fresh paper towels brand new
we have a clean surface for our
um
for our wet paper towel to sit on in
between before it goes in bags also i'm
gonna do a little advanced
tutorial while we're doing this we have
some old scissors here but one of the
first things we want to do with our
scissors as well
is everything else involved we want to
clean those i'm using some lysol wipes
on these just because because i've used
these for trimming and all kinds of
crazy [ __ ] but um
yeah these scissors are nice great
they're small if you'll notice they're
very small in my hands
and you can get these on amazon pretty
cheap
and they're sharp and they're precise
when you're when you're doing advanced
seat cracking you want to use
uh sharp precise
um scissors that you can control with
your hands and that you can feel stuff
through because you're going to feel
that seed crack and you want to stop the
second you fill them so
first off what we're going to do is get
our distilled water so i've filled this
up this beaker up with 500 milliliters
distilled water
you know a lot of people like to wet
their paper towels in distilled water
that's fine
um but
what also helps a lot is hydrogen
peroxide there's been scientific studies
done on this i watched one recently the
other day on youtube where uh i can't
remember if is utah university or
somewhere like that did a study on
cannabis and hemp seed germination rates
with hydrogen peroxide and hydrogen
peroxide did increase the rate so
i um
yeah i always
i tell people to use hydrogen peroxide
it's been an old standby for years and
it keeps the amount of decamp
decontamination down as best as you can
that's important okay so there's a brand
new hydrogen peroxide normally i do like
a one percent solution
so uh
milliliters to 500 but i'm just going to
eyeball it
there we go should be enough should be
enough maybe
right there
okay
a little more than five but it'll be
okay for what our purposes are
next step
you get your seeds right here we have
some ice cream bananas which is a banana
og blue bonnet
you want to open up the package um so
open it up
everything got a good lysol wipe down
before this so it's a little slippery
all right so it comes sealed package
one of our shells
right
you want to take your paper towels
here's three i only need one because
we're only doing one strain today so one
section of paper towel
you want to make sure that this is all
nice and mixed up homogeneous as best
you can i mean there's no magnetic
stirrer under it but for our purposes
it'll be fine
you take your paper towel and you fold
it
and you gently dip it in the water
hydrogen peroxide mixture
and then
very importantly is the moisture content
that you want to use you want to wring
out the water
pretty good
you want it to where there's enough
moisture to the to the embryo wanting to
hunt its way out of this of the shell
but you don't want so much moisture that
it's waterlogged so as you can see
no drippage no nothing it's just wet
it's wet not sopping wet
and then you'll take your seat pack
hopefully you'll be doing more in
10 to 13 but
for this like i said for our purposes it
works well
so you put down your seeds how many
seeds are in this five 10 12 seeds
um
now i was going to show the advanced
cracking tutorial so let's say you get
some
really
really nice
healthy
thick shelled afghani type seeds so i'll
pick the biggest shell we got here
thickest shell now sometimes some people
may think that the seed isn't
germinating but what's happening is that
water isn't getting into its shell
right so i've seen people throw away so
many good seeds thinking that they
weren't germinating they weren't viable
but the problem was the shell was just
too thick to let water in
in these extreme cases and
it really is a case-by-case basis on
whether i do this or not sometimes i'll
do this with seeds that don't pop after
you know three days of being in the in
the wet paper towel i'll tend to take
them out hand crack all the ones that
didn't just in case that's the issue
i don't normally start off by hand
cracking anything but for this purpose
so you can see how it's done i wanted to
show you so
we take it
now there is a seam along the top i know
this is not going to be perfect but we
have there's a seam along the top of the
seat and we gently rest the seed so it
sits in there like like that
long ways
and you want to gently apply pressure
put it all the way at the very very back
as far back as you can go inside
the thing and when you start applying
pressure the second you feel and hear
the crack you're good
hopefully you were able to hear that
and we hand cracked that one so we just
then toss it back
with the rest of them we close it up
close up shop
get a brand new ziploc baggie i like to
use the the court freezer baggies
because the thicker plastic heavier mill
or whatever
i put it in the baggie
we
i always take out most of the air for
whatever reason just so it doesn't move
around
we labeled the baggie so this is what
ice cream bananas i
scream
and the last thing and i'm not going to
show you here but what i would do is i
take painters tape or certain kind of
tape and i put it on the back side of
like a cabinet or something on the back
side and tape it on there we don't want
it getting a lot of light we want it to
be in the dark and we want it in a cool
place we don't want it super hot we
don't want it cold
just mostly dark right
some temperatures might be too cold for
it check your check your temperatures
you want to keep it right around i don't
know 75 80 degrees-ish
it's about where i keep it um
but yeah so the reason that we tape it
up on the back side too is so gravity as
these seeds pop gravity will start
pulling the tap roots downwards and
i don't know if you've ever tried like
popping seeds throwing them in a drawer
like setting them in there and being
cool with it to pop they curly cue and
they're very hard to plant in whatever
medium you're going to plant them in
so that's why we suspend them so gravity
brings them downwards at least and so
they're all in a nice pattern for for
planting in your medium i usually plant
them into cocoa
um another little trick that i do i let
the seeds stay in here until they have
pushed off their seed shell so they tend
to be long seedlings with good taproots
and the reason for that is
after planting if any kind of bacterial
problem happens in whatever your medium
is it'll be attacking that that fresh
root system and if it has
you know true leaves past the cotyledons
if it has tree leaves then it can still
intake water or nutrients to everything
it needs to do
while the while the roots try to
re-establish and survive so
yeah those are my tips i hope you all
enjoyed it again um
five mils to 500 milliliters distilled
water to uh
i'm sorry hydrogen peroxide to distilled
water
keep everything clean clean is the key
keeping it clean is the freaking key and
i wish
if there's anything i can impress on you
with this it would be that clean is key
anyway thank you for checking everything
out um
check out breeder syndicate patreon go
to google type in breeders syndicate
patreon and it will take you there uh we
have a discord where we talk and hang
out and shoot the [ __ ] and high five
each other and talk nerd stuff uh 24 7
really
we also watch movies together
certain shows pertaining to the subject
sometimes we watch fights together and
it's cool so come check it out reader
syndicate patreon
cheers