mom I'mma blow you in some
smoke we going to hot boox that [ __ ]
out one second oh what's going
on it's me Chucky Chuck the [ __ ] piling
and I'm here on a mission Matt Riot from
the breeder Syndicate has sent me here
to give you guys the best [ __ ] [ __ ]
weed podcast on the planet we're talking
strange Cult of ours for you [ __ ]
nerds out there we're talking smoking
we're talking all the good things that
come with marijuana and we're going to
be talking with the people from our own
Community you know what I'm saying G
today we got appy Hills on appy Hills
grower I should say he's a great dude we
had a fun
conversation we talk about all kinds of
[ __ ] we talk about Gro contest we talk
about H&amp;L seeds we talk about Pac we
talk about Matt RI we talk about
blueberry's all that good [ __ ] if you
like this kind of content let us know
we're going to do a little fun show for
you guys I know I know you guys are
saying but Chucky but Matt is this going
to replace the show on Friday because I
really want to see dudes from 1963
twerking up and down showing me how they
used to grow and get down but the truth
is guys this is not going to affect the
Friday show at all this is just going to
be bonus footage for you guys bonus
podcast we're talking bi-weekly maybe
once a month and we're going to have fun
doing it y'all you know I want to
apologize for the audio quality in this
[ __ ]
podcast it went up and down because we
had some headphones die on us [ __ ] like
that so I'm sorry if you can't
understand it fully but it is what it is
G and we're going to work on that we're
going to make [ __ ] a lot better we're
going to make the quality better and
we're going to put more effort and
energy into it so appreciate a like I
appreciate a comment like I said appy
Hills is a good dude he's from our
Discord we sit around have a good time
and that's about it show us some love
and support goes a long way I love y'all
and have a nice day let's get to the
show what's up guys it's me Chuck the
[ __ ] pollins and I got a little podcast
for you today Matt Riot's done giving me
the green light to do a little podcast
for y'all we're gonna be highlighting
some of the people in our own community
in breeder Syndicate
3.0 uh today I got a special guest with
me one of my good friends that I met
through the breeder Syndicate through
the Discord appy heels grower thanks
than for joining us today bro how are
you doing pretty good how about yourself
I'm good bro we had some technical
difficulty technical difficulties but
we're rocking now it looks
like what happens when you get redneck
technology yeah amen dude uh but uh
basically this this podcast that Matt's
got me doing here is uh like I said just
kind of highlighting people in our own
Community uh talking about stuff that's
going on we're gonna be talking about uh
you know strains cultivars whatever you
want to call them we're gonna be talking
about smoking uh just stuff that's going
on in our own Community maybe broader
stuff too kind of just depends on what
the guests are wanting wanting to talk
about uh that being said uh you know
we're not I'm not a professional uh I
don't know if you are happy but I'm not
a professional so take everything we say
with the grain of salt this is more just
kind of you know to hang out and
something a little bit less serious than
Matt's uh show on Fridays and uh well
let's go ahead and take it uh maybe we
could start at the beginning with you
appy and uh maybe talk about your first
uh the first time you heard about weed
or the first time you smoked or maybe
your first interaction with it and you
know as far as back as you can
remember first interactions was always
family because whenever family got
together they'd go sneak off and when
you're 10 years old trying to figure out
why everybody's coming back into the
house happy and
hungry and you know my dad wasn't the
most Pleasant son of a gun sometimes s
and that family get togethers he and I
are tp's in a pod but when you get him
coming in happy and hungry like oh [ __ ]
what's up with that so the smell that's
where I smelled it first was the family
G togethers uh first experience with it
was probably 15 years old with
friends uh of course all brick I mean my
experience I we didn't get good stuff
out here till
probably right when I start right when I
graduated high school in 92
was when we started seeing better stuff
because other than that I mean dude we
didn't even get the Christmas Bud like
when it would come in green M all we got
was the brown brick it either smelled
like diesel fuel or r or something and I
mean heck you would buy a quarter hoping
for a [ __ ] joint out of it because by
the time you got the stems and seeds out
that's what about what you
had I can relate because I mean growing
up Kentucky uh you know not super super
far off from where you were probably uh
that's the same thing my experience was
all brick weed dude just press brown
brick weed for years uh probably from I
think I didn't really start buying weed
until
probably 17 or 18 but that's because I
was around older people that smoked uh a
bunch uh M mainly Reggie and I didn't
really need to pay for it because when
we growing up we would all just stay at
each other's houses all the time s you
know sit I mean [ __ ] as long as I can
remember staying over my buddy's houses
so and I was real poor dude so all my
buddies I couldn't have bought weed
until I had a job anyways really so um
so but yeah most of the weed for the
first you know four or five years of me
smoking uh was Reggie brick [ __ ] weed
press stuff but then we started seeing
more like kind of light green stuff that
didn't have as much as many seeds in it
and uh that's right and we had that for
about a year or two and then uh then we
started getting this stuff called $10 bu
or 10 a gram or 15 a gram 20 a gram and
then as we a few years into that we
finally started getting some good [ __ ]
but um when you said you said your dad
and and your family and them smoked did
you ever was your first time smoking uh
smoking a leftover joint or something
like that or was it actually just oh no
they were way too secretive I mean dude
they were way too worried about covering
their tracks and they're damn good at it
cuz none of them stunk horrifically when
they came back in the house cuz I think
my grandfather had to put a kabach for
that [ __ ] real quick beat their ass but
oh God no my uncles were huge and my
grandfather was not a big guy but my
idol but anyway it it
it I always got mine from buddies
because I grew up rougher than a cob and
with some of my friends yeah we were
always the outcast pick on group you
know
thees and that's why I gravitated I
think more towards cannabis than I did
anything else because I mean when you
were the the cool kid you were [ __ ] F
pounding mag Boon's Farm in [ __ ] M
Dog 2020 I didn't like drinking all that
damn much now don't get me wrong I truly
enjoy a good
bourbon but I don't sit there I'll have
a drink I don't have to drink the damn
bottle
right now put a freaking nice dab in
front of me and now I'm in trouble you
know all many of these we gonna do right
see I you know I can't say that I ain't
a drinker I'm not a drinker anymore but
uh it runs in my blood my grandfather
was an alcoholic my brother's like I
said a I told you before we started an a
recovering addict sometimes sometimes
he's a fullon addict uh but man tequila
was always my thing I mean don't get me
wrong uh
we couldn't get Bud a lot of times I
mean I remember droughts still I I'm
sure you experienced this too oh God Dam
yeah like there was times where we
couldn't get Bud so when we couldn't I
mean tequila was my uh I dude it made me
a problem not a fighter but man I just
get wild and and act Goofy and chase
girls and you know but
uh we went even cheaper it was Natty
light Natty
light Milwaukee's best
or anything we can get cheap yeah I you
know I never been a [ __ ] Beer Drinker
dude I you know I've drank beer before
and I threw them back when I was younger
but I just I've always had uh problem
just drinking all the the fluid you know
itself to fit like the foam and
everything I'm sitting burp and got a
piss a bunch so I like I like I like
shots dude if I'm going I haven't like I
said I don't really drink anymore I'll
have a my old lady she'll make me a
panut every once in a while that's a
that's about as far as I go nowadays but
I in the same way though once I did once
I had a job in a car especially and I
was able to get Bud all the time I just
I I would rather go to a party and just
roll up some joints or some blunts or or
whatever and pass them around and and
just hang out you know uh and you know
we makes friends dude getting drunk you
get into fist fights and the old lady oh
yeah problems with the old lady and all
that [ __ ] you know well heck I I had a
Hiatus because of my kids because Ohio
had such strict damn laws and I was a
single dad with three kids that I quit
from right
around
97 till probably 2008 damn I
mean did you go cold turkey let me ask
you always wonder about this [ __ ] yeah
I because the only thing is here I am a
single dad and all I took was one of the
baby momas to go hey that some [ __ ] is
smoking and then I get pissed for some
stupid ass reason and I lose all three
of my
kids I mean you know no not there's
there's no I don't care how good it is I
don't give it's the best [ __ ] you've
ever smoked in your entire life you know
comes out of a Himalayan [ __ ]
Mountain man's golden ass no sorry I
don't care but now I get to make up for
it and I get to smoke with my youngest
boy I was gonna ask you I was gonna I
was gonna ask you do if you had a
relationship with with your kids now
being oh God yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
now my eldest boy's in in norol he lives
with his mom but him and I are really
tight and whenever I go see him I bring
him presents you know he doesn't have to
he doesn't have to rent the mason jars
he he just gets them
hell yeah dude hell yeah no that's
awesome dude that that makes me happy
because I'm real close with my dad and
uh maybe that's why I felt the kindred
spirit with you a little bit just uh you
sound like you're a good good pops and
and that's good and I understand dude if
I ever had a kid that's something that
probably stopped me from having a kid is
just is uh growing I wouldn't say my
parents were were bad parents they were
great parents but just when it comes to
financial decisions in life they didn't
weren't the best about it uh the
decisions they made and they had kids
when they were young so stuff was you
know it was rough I mean we grew up
taking baths out of buckets and boiling
water and you know oh taking shits out
back and stuff when all the bills were
cut off I mean that being said I had a
great childhood a great upbringing uh
but my parents as far as my parents
apparently I talked to my mom about this
recently but she had smoked maybe three
or four times growing up my parents
weren't drinkers or drug drug people
really my dad smoked when he was a kid
and did mushrooms and [ __ ] but like that
but uh I want ask you uh did you ever uh
get a chance to smoke with your dad or
did you do you have a relationship with
him so he still around oh God him and I
yeah him and I are very close very very
close now we had a very I had a very
rough time with him growing up because
he was a little more physical than most
and he apologized to that to this day
and I mean [ __ ] dude I weigh 300 goddamn
pounds my dad's lucky to be a buck 80
and he'll look at me every time I come
over there Giggle and like God damn I'm
glad you don't believe in Revenge I'm
like why would I do that I mean you know
even even though my dad got a little
physical with me at times he's still one
of the two people that I look up to it's
him and my grandpa and that's what made
me a manual labor than I am today but
funny thing about it you mentioned your
brother that's where I actually work now
I'm a counselor at an addiction Outreach
that's cool yeah so I work I work in a
boxing Clinic that's cool uh my mom
that's what my mom she's uh you know uh
with my brother being in and out of
treatment he uh that's what she's
ultimately doing with her life is kind
of just uh working in that field and you
know just working that's where she works
at a a h like a Recovery Center yeah the
knowledge she brings is so beneficial to
the people that will come through that
house it's not even funny and she knows
how to read tells yeah I mean that's the
beautiful thing about it you know
anybody can sit there you know I mean
you've been around your brother you know
and I'm sure you love him to death but
you know damn getting well hope sit
there and lie to you when he's on a bad
in a bad spot brother I'm not doing [ __ ]
you know dude he can't
stand just druin on yourself man come on
well you know even with him you know you
can't even lend him $10 dude cuz you
know that $10 that I think I'm helping
I'm out by getting him a cheeseburger or
whatever he he'll go off and use that
for something he don't need to get into
but yeah not to take it into a dark tone
but yeah that's I think everybody's
affected by uh these types of things
nowadays I think everybody family family
me member or a friend that's going
through this kind of [ __ ] so I think
it's it's kind of important to talk
about but uh yeah and then everybody
needs to remember that if there's
somebody in treatment man give them
their prompts even if they're struggling
still give them their prompts because
they're they're trying to make a change
yeah I mean dude it's it's rough man and
I hope anybody that's going through that
kind of [ __ ] can get the help that they
need dude I talk and you know that you
gotta want to change man you know we've
I we've both lived R rough lives and
made mistakes I'm sure but you got to
want to change to get better when it
comes to that kind of stuff don't matter
how many people want to help you you got
to want to make that decision to get
better but uh but yeah U maybe back
we'll steer back towards marijuana here
but uh uh maybe uh so as you you're
smoking with your friends and stuff like
that uh maybe did you guys ever attempt
to grow or or what point did you decide
hey I want to try to grow some of this
[ __ ] so we lived I grew up in the
suburbs and we had a huge Community
Center behind us it was like 15 soccer
fields behind us in Harris
Ohio and behind it was a bunch of wood
so we tried growing in the woods but we
were so damn deep into the woods and I
mean dude I think we were
14 and you know we had found some seeds
in a bag of I think one of my buddies
brother you know you know his his older
brother's stuff right and that's where
we got most of our stuff from was his
older brother in the very beginning but
yeah I mean we put it in the ground I
don't think any of them ever sprouted
and then after the tornado came through
Harrison and that's a neat fact we we
were the first ever episode of Rescue
911 but back to
weed the we moved out into the middle of
nowhere and Harrison I mean it's it's
country out there I love it but it's in
the woods so there's no Farmland so all
you got to do is go find the biggest
tree that just fell down and I mean
we've got some scraggly stuff nothing
nothing like I'm getting the
privilege I me it was barely above the
brick and I don't what anybody says
about
brick if you gave me the [ __ ]
[ __ ] myar stuff they got today and
I'm talking to BS stuff not the stuff
that you can find is still decent right
I'd rather smoke I'd rather smoke the
brick Because I Got High as a damn tight
smoking brick it was [ __ ]
weed and it didn't look good but damn
did it get you baked I can't say I miss
those days cuz the [ __ ] we were getting
bro looked like the got cocacola poured
on it and [ __ ] I mean you
was that
thick main was that thick you smoke a
joint bro and the [ __ ] Ash is
black oh yeah yeah I mean I can't say I
miss uh miss that but I I do know what
you're saying there is that uh those
myar bags nowadays that are [ __ ]
track and I've seen some you can get
some [ __ ] at some of these uh
dispensaries that's like the cheapest
[ __ ] they got it's like $20 ounces $30
ounces it looks damn near like that [ __ ]
just without seeds dude you know all
oxidized and [ __ ] dark looking [ __ ]
but uh well not only that but it's just
okay I'll ask you your opinion because
you do go to a lot of dispensaries and
I've had to here also and between grows
and different [ __ ] like that oh yeah
everything
smells like nothing like packing peanuts
almost like like there's no smell to it
it smells like the inside of the myar
bag and I don't know if just from The
Cure or the strain selections because
they're trying to flip them at six weeks
every strain they get a hold of because
it's money well it's probably a
combination of multiple factors right
you're probably pull they're probably
pulling early just because of the
industry and how it works they're
probably probably uh you know pumping
them full of nutrients to they're
probably cure is probably quick or or or
not slow enough or whatever uh and also
are they spraying for stuff like there's
so many things that could go into that
uh now I will say like I've made it a my
mission to explore all the [ __ ]
dispensaries that I can find in my
general area which is you know upwards
to like 20 plus in in my in the city
that's probably uh you know 15 minutes
away or so I'm in the country myself so
I have I do have to driving into town
but over the last year I've made a an
effort to go check everything out and I
you know I've made multiple purchases at
of them to make sure I get a good uh
idea of what they offer I mean when
you're talking about M what you were
talking about specifically earlier they
all offer that prepackaged Mage [ __ ] you
know real colorful packaging uh usually
sold in E you know they're trying to get
the attention with that yeah I agree
well they're trying to get Indiana Ohio
Kentucky Pennsylvania and everybody El
sit up there coming up to get the
[ __ ] cheap ass mid yeah yeah of
course and and that's a big that's the
thing I I even talked to I asked some of
these people [ __ ] man like uh I asked
this girl that was working at what of
them I was like you know have you been
busy today because it was a holiday I
think uh and she's like yeah and you're
the uh she's like you're the first
person that from inate that's come in
today out of a 100 people so that that
right there is telling you a lot hund
and some people I'm talk and this is uh
like 10:30 or 11 o'clock in the morning
or something and they open up at like 9
or 10 so it's all out of state people
and this is during the summer so I mean
during the summer they're crushing it
because you got out of people out of
town people coming to boat to fish I
mean Michigan is a great place for that
kind you know to to finish up my point
about the dispensaries uh I will say
this you are going to find a lot of that
uh stuff you know uh I call it soulless
weed you know a lot of it's U machine
trimmed uh a lot of it is early pulled
early stuff like that but I will say
that often you can find at least one or
two things in that store that even a
seasoned person you might not walk away
extremely satisfied or blown away but I
have tested this out with people that
that I mean some of the guys in the
Discord even I've when I've met up with
them in person at parties I'll I'll slip
some of the [ __ ] into some of the smoke
and not many people can tell the
difference if you if you got the right
right thing or the right uh yeah the
right uh trrain or cultivar whatever but
I will say uh lately I've I've kind of
like tried to go to the more expensive
places uh people that are more I
wouldn't say it's not fully integrated
because they have separate Lo locations
but they grow their own stuff along with
other stuff uh local people local
farmers plus they have the prepackage
stuff now I will say like on that stuff
yeah it is worth an extra $10 on the
ounce to buy buy that if you are gonna
buy anything I will say that a lot of
that in there in a couple of these
stores and I won't name them but that it
was pretty good smoke dude is it better
than yeah what I grow or what my buddies
grow or is would I prefer that hell no
but uh you know if I was coming here out
of state for a day or two I would be
pretty satisfied with the overall
experience now you're going into going
into these places looking for experience
on uh strains or or how to grow or any
kind of thing like that you're not going
to get that there I don't think for most
part but uh yeah uh what about your
experiences with with with with wreck I
mean Ohio just went wreck not too long
ago yeah yeah
it's I'm not going to lie the only thing
that I've bought
in God I want to say four or five years
that I've ever actually been able to
smell is is always the the Jack or the
train wreck that's the only thing I've
ever been able to smell everybody's like
oh this smells and I'm like dude you're
so full of [ __ ] come
here you want to drag that kid into the
house and bring him into the shed like
hey why don't you come in here and stick
your nose in this tent
dude I'm telling you what that like I
got to grow some amazing stuff in the
very beginning when I first came to the
Discord I was getting into CSI pretty
damn heavy and I mean there's so many
people here that grow Caleb stuff too
but my God the different smells that
came off of that it was
awesome yeah I mean I should excuse me I
should
say uh in the last year there's probably
only been two or three things that I
would ever think about potentially
growing or even really wanting to smoke
again one of them I had recently was the
I can't ever say it right bro because I
got like a third grade reading level
what's the uh do doce de UA or whatever
I can't say it yeah that that was
actually decent I've seen some of the
guys in the Discord out in Cali talk
about that too if it's the same cut it's
it it's pretty decent for what it is but
like you were saying bro it's nothing
compared to you know a good H&amp;L uh pack
of seeds that I pop of whatever you know
it doesn't even compare especially when
you're talking about if you've cured it
right it was a good grow if everything
went perfect which I know it's hard to
do when you're growing but but uh yeah I
you know we'd ra I'd rather grow Homer
smoke homegrown all day if I can you
know but um so at what point did you uh
get a little bit more serious about
growing I guess or or maybe start buying
genetics because you said you were
getting stuff out of bags uh your you
know little bags and stuff you all were
smoking bag seed what once once I knew
that I wasn't G to get in trouble with
the kids because I dude I mean I
had the Rob Clark's indoor grow Bible
that was the first book I ever bought
and this just before I mean I just
wanted I just
wanted really or was that Rob
Clark is it this one sorry yeah sorry
named the wrong one but then I bought
the other one with the Two Fellas that
wrote it the indoor grow bible the white
one blue
letters I had book and then that one um
H Ed Rosen Falls okay so I bought those
both from a place called high on the
hill in
Cincinnati that place on me made me
laugh cuz you couldn't say bong those
people would lose their goddamn mind if
you said bong like come on man but I got
it they can get in trouble but so I
started reading and I I am one of those
people that loves I am ADD like a son of
a gun so I I want to make a t-shirt with
a chrome squirrel on it that says on the
back of it o shiny and on the bottom of
the shirt says
squirrel but but marijuana itself is
always always had a place in my heart
I'm always trying to learn about it
and where I really started getting into
it honestly was the podcast the first
couple episodes when Duke got on there
and you know was talking it up and then
skunk was the second one Matt was on
right after that and I [ __ ] I I
chased his ass down I mean that's when I
started really listening to Instagram
and everything else with Matt and you
know religiously watching his lives on
Instagram but I didn't know how much the
patreon would cost and I was draft as
hell back
then and you know just anything I could
find that was giving me information and
knowledge and all the guys would give
you places to go
look so you know I've been at it in the
shed probably four or five years
now and I mean it's just it's not the
fact that I think I'm doing all that
great it's just I'm taking and the
knowledge that I'm learning from these
guys that I really look up
to that's that's exactly what this
podcast was all about bro it's not for
me I want to get people on that maybe
I'm not saying you just in general but
myself hell I [ __ ] grows up all the time
uh just people who are actually out
doing it enjoying it more on a smaller
scale people joke I hear all these
[ __ ] podcasters talk about we doing
it for the at tent Growers at home and
all this [ __ ] and but then they
interview like the worst people in the
world so and of course and then burner
sitting next to them like come on yeah
you can't [ __ ] a bullshitter no you
can't I just you know uh I I just wanted
to do something that is more at home
with like what we're actually doing in
people like us because it's like you
said it doesn't matter if you're the
best grower in the world I mean we're
you know I'm learning every day myself
dude I learned from uh everybody in the
Discord um and it's a journey really I
know it sounds corny but I don't think I
I I was talking to one of the guys the
other day about this uh and I don't
remember who it was but it was somebody
in the Discord but it's growing weed you
know you learning until basically you're
you're about to die when you're old
enough you're you're at a point where
you're a master at it and then you die a
few years later but but no you know it's
just a learning process I love that dude
I mean I'm like you dude I make mistakes
too but sorry to cut you out there oh no
no you're fine yeah heck I wouldn't I
I'll be I'll put it out on Front Street
be completely honest with you I would
have never known that I had
thps unless one of the guys in the
Discord would have pointed it out to me
and I respect the hell out of this dude
and I'm I'm very thankful he did it
because now I know what the hell to look
for and now they're gone I live on a
farm dude I'm constantly having to do
work on a farm I mean and it's 82 acres
and it's all family there's five houses
and it's all family and I'm the manual
labor that knows how to fix [ __ ] trust
me I'm fixing [ __ ] out in the [ __ ]
weeds constantly but then I think oh
[ __ ] I gotta go water not thinking you
know and now I take that a hell lot more
serious you know guys are always like oh
you gotta change clothes before you go
in [ __ ]
that dude I just SP 16 hours [ __ ]
fixing a cattle fence dude I'm not I'm
not good no I gotta go water and that's
that's what caught me in the ass is is
from Mowing and weed whip and I know
that's it's from and I just it infected
the plants but um if anybody's
curious that right
there get of thrips like a s [ __ ] I was
about to pull my bottle out but I I got
a couple bottles uh hanging up here
somewhere I was you're talking about
thrips man uh you know I've also been
[ __ ] around since I was like 14 15 16
growing bag seeds I like to I don't even
consider myself uh a grower back then
because I never even really would get to
harvest a lot of times I was I was
growing in my mom's house I was hidden
mind you in a [ __ ] closet uh I was
growing in uh rental property so I would
get to certain points where I'm about to
flower and of course I'm learning at the
time too back then I was on uh 420 Chan
that's what just at the time that's what
I was using to learn and I watched a lot
of the hor Jorge svantes grow videos I
would download them off like lime wire
and [ __ ] Bro Pirate Bay and uh and 420
CH that's how I was learning and uh uh
but uh back to my point uh I over these
last probably about a year and a half
maybe two years before Co hit um I
started [ __ ] around with growing I
wouldn't say serious but I had a tent
right and uh over these last few years
I've been doing it Non-Stop and some of
the uh I've never really had some of the
issues that a lot of the guys have gone
through with thrips mites [ __ ] like that
I just got lucky I had a few spider
mites with one of my first grows because
I was taking stuff in and out like a
dumbass yeah yeah yeah but but this
summer moving up to Michigan it's a
totally different environment dude it's
it's it's a lot more challenging to grow
I would say for me inside and out uh
humidity is a little different humidity
in mold uh so out last year last summer
last season uh
I did some of H&amp;L stuff outside and uh
didn't have really I saw a few spider
mites here there nothing crazy and then
uh I also had never seen a thrip before
bro so I bring everything in back in
October uh and harvest everything and
you know I tried to clean all the leaves
out and stuff off as much as I could
outside before I brought them in I I
kind of would do showers like you were
saying I especially if I'm going in the
grow room I definitely would change
clothes maybe not shower all the time
but anyways month month or two after
outdoor Harvest I brought everything in
I've had everything in for about a month
and stuff my plants are doing [ __ ] Bro
in one tent specifically and it was a
H&amp;L gr that I was doing and like what
the [ __ ] is going on I start looking at
the leaves and I see these little things
crawling around them and little spit
looking marks all over all over one of
my bubba crosses yeah and bro I was like
what the [ __ ] so I get to look in and
I'm like man I got kind of look online
and look in the Discord [ __ ] like that
you know how it is you trying to figure
out what you got going on diagnose the
problem and uh sure enough had thrips
dude and I [ __ ] uh you know barely
made it to the end of the harvest my my
Harvest was [ __ ] but I still got some
plants out of it and some seed out of it
but uh yeah dude just [ __ ] my but long
story short not short I guess I should
say was that was the first time
experiencing that dude and it just was
such a depressing time for me because I
didn't know how to manage it and
something I do I use some of that spray
that you got the what is that called do
I always forget what it's was called
doctor Bond Jack Captain Jack yeah yeah
you thinking of Dr
Bonners or Bondies or blondies or
something there's all kind of [ __ ] uh
some sulfur [ __ ] I ordered recently but
uh anyways H&amp;L actually uh H Lonesome
recommended me that same [ __ ] dude when
I was going through the my thrip problem
and it and it kicked kit ass dude it
like I could within a few days maybe a
week I don't know dude what what is that
which one
D oh nice
dust H yeah dud so if you're way into V
or Clon just went into
solos yeah dude uh so yeah man thanks to
H&amp;L I kind of shut everything down took
everything down to clones cleaned
everything out sprayed the [ __ ] for like
three or four weeks didn't really to
grow anything really [ __ ] my Harvest
up and that's why I recently did have to
go get some weed dud because I [ __ ]
ran out I smoked all my phes I smoked I
smoked it all dude I got a bunch of
butter left but sometimes and I'm not
that type of dude or I'm not I'm not
gonna ask my buddies for favors I just
I'm not that type of guy really so for
me I'll just go pick something up and
deal with it you know but
um uh back to my point uh thrips dude
that [ __ ] sucked it taught me a lot and
I feel like failures bro make you the
better grower than not having failures
because now moving forward uh I a't I
don't have an issue to worry about
thrips I'm sure you can agree you get
you know how to handle it you know what
to look for that's something you
probably look for now for now on like oh
yeah yeah and the snail Trails is the
instant giveaway yeah if you've got many
snail Trails on your leaves you got
Thrift F and simple yeah you could see
them too at least the ones I uh the on
yeah if you flip over the seed or flip
over the if you flip over the leaf and
they're normally on the bigger fan
leaves that's where they go first
because there's there's more for them to
eat yeah and you'll see the really tiny
little white flexs and then when they
get older they turn to black and then
they start flying yep yeah and I think
too what um I think where what got me
[ __ ] up is I've seen a couple flying
originally bro and I and I wanted to say
I just thought they were gnats bro I
didn't really pay much attention I
thought they were fungus snats cause but
if you get to looking at them they look
totally different they almost got like a
the ones I had were almost had a reddish
Hue to them uh kind of looking things
once they flying they don't fly very
good they yeah they don't stay up very
long and they're yeah like you said
they're completely different color where
the fungus knots are a little darker
yeah almost black yeah that's the thing
is when I I realized that they're
terrible Flyers so uh I just increased
my my fans doubled up on fans and sticky
trapped the [ __ ] everything out dude I
mean stick so many goddamn sticky traps
you could couldn't walk an inch without
getting one on you dude I get them with
my hair and everything bro but uh but
then see I get those taken care of and
now I got a tent right now that's
[ __ ] PM bro not extreme extreme but
just on the lower leaves I've done
stripped everything out I've increased
my air flow I've my my [ __ ] humidity
is right on point my temps are on point
uh only thing I I'm I can think of is
I'm middle winter I have an experienced
winter up here so it is a little
different um I'm I'm actually installing
an air boox with a filter uh a filter
box today and another exhaust uh up into
my attic today so hopefully that will
help and then I also got some uh um
sulfur show um some powdered sulfur
showing up and I'm just going to take
clones of just I don't it's just one
[ __ ] tent bro I don't understand no
not a single lick of it in the rest of
the [ __ ] Garden but just this one t
in the corner is I've cleaned this
[ __ ] two or three times it just
just a little bit of PM bro so I'm gonna
[ __ ] you know what's funny is I had
uh I was reading and I remember my
grandpa and them using [ __ ] milk dude
like a what is it like a third to twoth
thirds water uh and bro I I was already
I already got the sulfur on the way bro
and I'm thinking man this is some
redneck [ __ ] dude right here I said I
wonder if this is work and I and I some
of the plants I had it uh bro they were
like on their last little leg there was
a couple that were ate up and bro and
I'm not recommending this to anybody but
for me I sprayed them dude and sure
enough the next day not even eight hours
later bro I come I look in that tent
took all the mold out bro of course now
I got this [ __ ] dried milk on
everything right took all the mold out
and the the new growth the new growth is
is coming through they greened up it's
weird dude it kind of surprised me now I
don't know if that's going to affect
when I go to dip uh and sulfur if I need
to or not I don't know I you know and I
need to talk to a couple guys bitter
gave me the uh recommendation of using
sulfur because that takes care of molds
that takes a mil you know mil or PM uh
you know mites rust itss or whatever and
a few other things so U if I can't get
it with the milk I'm hoping the [ __ ]
sulfur takes care of it if not I'm gonna
cut them all down and start start over I
guess I don't know but well that's the
beautiful thing about it too if you
really think about it just from the damn
patreon packages alone so is this going
out on YouTube yeah yep okay if you're
watching this join the Discord it's
worth it yep don't go in on the $5 go in
on $50 you're always gonna get more than
what you pay for I can I can attest to
this I'm a damn
nobody and I'm getting some of the
greatest damn seeds to
GP well maybe people don't might might
not know what it it is so uh so in the
breeder Syndicate uh Discord we actually
uh have tier systems and you could join
for five bucks uh that just get you the
discount on everything on Riot seeds.com
uh or not everything but most of the
stuff on there specifically uh Matt Matt
gear and a few of other guys and then uh
there's a 15 Tier and then there's a 50
tier $50 tier which uh a lot there's
confusion on this I wanted to say this
here so people understand um
it's you get a a pack per month at that
$50 tier but sometimes Matt will do it
you know once there's two to three or
four built up so it saves on shipping
stuff quarterly is what he's trying to
shoot for is every every four months he
tries to shoot one out and and I mean
dude if you grow what the hell you just
got from him in that patreon package
there's no way in hell you're going to
be ready for the next patreon package
right and you're getting some ker damn
genetics got in there right
now and the blueberry I mean I got the
blueberry a T1000 that I got off of uh
bong toes for
Jesus
and uh the granddaddy per time space
queen and the haspl time space
queen awesome dude and and the good
thing about this one is is I was
actually able to get the blueberry it's
just due in the uh vegetative state
because of where I had to flip so quick
the last time to get in on the
contest yeah man um speaking of the
blueberry dude uh those things are the
they're more Squat and chunky so I
understand what you're talking about
vegetative growth and in my run dude I
enjoyed all I did four of them uh the
rest are males I enjoyed that the
blueberry so much man the turs were spot
on blueberry um and dude I actually and
like you dude I don't feel like I did it
justice cuz I actually took the mail and
hit it to them so I can get some more
seed and uh I'm a cheap bastard dude I'm
chucking everything I got I want more
seeds dude but uh so I I made more of it
so I could kind of do my own uh run and
my own little little hunts I guess if
you call them but uh yeah I also feel I
want to rengge mine out or even do one
outside dude I think that would be fun
to do outside but I love the
apprehensive of growing anything outside
around here because of our damn humidity
it I mean once it hits October we get so
funky here that I mean I'd almost have
to dig out a a six inch deep freaking
platform and put sand in it but then I
gotta worry about Dr and everything else
put a greenhouse over top of it to keep
humidity down I mean yeah that's how we
used to do it at the when I was growing
at a farm that I used to work at we'd
grow winter plants on float beds but you
had to have sand in the middle of the
aisle to help take the moisture off of
the greenhouse right yeah uh that's a
thing I had uh last season up here uh I
just was a little hesitant about growing
stuff because it was my first season so
and I didn't know what to expect so what
I I just said hey I'm gonna put stuff in
the ground here I'm not gonna add any
soil I'm not gonna add anything I'm just
gonna see what it does on its own just
to get a base
idea and uh dude I put some hypy stuff
out I put some uh some some stuff from
the Discord a lot most stuff that I put
out was from HL the rank strangers which
you know those are a haze uh uh a mango
Haze cross that's the kimd times the
mango Haze and dude I I didn't think it
was going to finish but it ended up
finishing up here and it was the least
moldiest plant I had I don't think I
really had any mold maybe like a nug or
two but dude anything that was purple
for some reason just [ __ ] molded the
[ __ ] out bro I mean bad like really bad
yeah yeah um but that being said uh I
had uh what was it the dog walker snacks
from konzo I think that's and I'm sorry
if I'm getting that wrong I think it's I
can't keep track of all these names and
[ __ ] but I think it's the dog Walker
snacks that was a little bit more dense
uh but it that came out uh it wasn't
purple but it did come out uh didn't
didn't have much mold on it like that
you know but uh yeah man uh growing
outside is [ __ ] it it was a new
experience and probably the most fun I
had I went in into it thinking like man
none of this is probably gonna work out
because a lot of the guys are like oh
dude you're gonna get mold [ __ ] like
that sure enough I got some but it was
fun bro there's something about going
outside
it's not been the fact I mean yeah
granted they're telling you it's going
to mold but [ __ ] you're learning you're
not trying to freaking Harvest a bunch
of [ __ ] hey let's see what the hell
happens yeah the whole the whole verbage
is throwing [ __ ] on the wall and see
what's this yep and you you're hella
lucky up there compared to where you
grew up because where youw is like my
soil it ain't nothing but [ __ ] play
yep and you get up there and there's a
lot of sand yep you know
uh it's yeah it's it's all
sand it's all [ __ ] Sand Dude um that
being said this year dude I'm gonna run
H&amp;L soil mix he gave me his little
recipe that he runs Outdoors so I'm
gonna run I'm gonna mix that up I think
and this year I'm gonna be [ __ ] ready
dude I'm gonna have my my titty milk on
on tap I'm gonna have my suful ready to
go no I'm gonna have my [ __ ] ready I'm
gonna cover them this year I'm gonna do
nets this year and uh yeah balls the
wall bro no no surrender no mercy you
know well if you're GNA just remember
the biggest thing I mean go to Harbor
Freight and get yourself a fan yeah and
you don't have to necessarily get a
greenhouse fan but you want to move a
shitload more air than what you're
comfortable
with people understand once you put that
damn once you put that plastic up how
much moisture that DRS in there right
right I think this year I'm gonna cut me
a big SWA I'm gonna cut me a big cut all
the way around my my area far get all
the weed shm way way way down uh and
just yeah just really uh just try to do
it to the max this year you know because
last year I saw a lot I was shocked
because dude I had plants that were big
as me bro or bigger than me you know and
I put out I put I I want to say I put
everything out mid July well late you
know it was late for what what it they
could have been and they were huge but
uh but uh let's get into some of these
questions here man we we're getting on
the long rant here we'll get which is
fine but uh we'll get it we'll get into
some of these questions uh I got a
little uh compiled some stuff here and
we'll go through uh maybe we'll start
with uh what's your uh all-time favorite
strain and
why pack train rack hands down the smell
the effect the growth the [ __ ] the
absolute beauty of that plant is unreal
I mean dud you not true train wreck I
mean yeah flops who gives a
not when you're done and you harvest
that that is something I think you could
keep in the jar for 15 damn years and
it's still so good yeah I mean with this
cardboard turs BS that is a beautiful
damn plant and right d behind it is this
mango Haze chem 91 that we had for the
H&amp;L 500 stuff dude I have literally
beening that for at least a month half
hour whatever the hell it was I know
ICT but pressed flow so my first flower
press a week into drop so it still has
little for in
it it's okay I mean it doesn't I don't
think it tastes any different because
you're pressing it
out I have not hit
itday like when I tonight I will still
get the same effect that I did on that
first day you can't knock that dude you
got two beautiful cross you got like
like HL said the whole reason he put
them together his two favorite
drains neither does mango Haze and the
funny thing about it
it the more mango I get I the more funky
chem leaning smell but the longer I'm
burping these jars and the longer it C
the more that fruity almost fermented
mango on the more cheman it's fered
mango that's
awesome two
tops that's awesome dude uh so you got
goat farm with the train wreck which is
the Arcada the s1's I'm assuming right
yes sir the S1 I got uh three of those
it when people say support when people
say support the discard
I got those because I bought the uh
Santa Cruz blue
dream or the yeah the Santa clu Brew
dream off of him when the s1's first
came out that was a thank you package
that I got for buying the Blue Dream off
with the damn
train
awes talk about hooking it up the Blue
Dream podcast we might as well talk
about that that is awesome dude the S1
and all those all those crosses dude
super Metal Shop hazy smell I I mean I I
personally in the three plants that I've
grown I have not gotten the blueberry
end mine have all been that metal
shock amazing effect ho smoke stuff hell
yeah yeah before we before I forget um
the uh Kim 91 times the mango hay is
part of the hnl 500 um that's a little
grow competition that kind of concluding
actually will be concluding tomorrow
officially on the 4th um little they
little grow competitions that we do
where uh like this one specifically we
grew out H&amp;L 91 times the mango Hayes
and I think there's 15 or so contestants
in this one and uh basically what we do
is we run run the plants we send out the
or we send out the seeds and uh
everybody runs the plants and then we
judge based on visuals and things like
that uh the overall winner and we do
like you know top three with prizes and
then there's a belt as well that we
always have on the line it's like a
little not a fullsize belt but it's a
little miniature kind of wrestling uh
championship belt with that kind of
stuff we had a Solo Cup uh competition
with the belt previous to that one and
uh we're on the 500 and actually we just
sent out uh all the poac stuff speaking
of poac we had just sent out all the
goat farm Pock stuff for the most recent
contest which is a mystery grow and we
got I think probably I think there's
nine different uh cultivars strains
whatever have you People's Choice of
terminology whatever the [ __ ] but
anyways we uh got nine different strains
and I think 30 something people are
running in this one and uh I just popped
M my uh sevens and my fours are all
popped 100% germination brother I'm
ready to rock oh and that's the thing
any of the stuff that I've done from b
or Highland from the germination has
always been 100% now if I've lost
anything after germination was
completely on
me not V it enough when the seedings
were coming up because I use the uh oh I
don't know if I have one Cy but I just
gonna lie I bought them off team and
they're just a
little seed starters that are like that
tall that they have the clear plastic
lid and have on the top and I put Coco
in there and put them in my darn clone
tent and the one that I showed you
earlier it's double Shel and I've just
got freaking
uh shop lights because they're 6,000
Kelvin and can't remember how many
lumens but yeah I'll do they
yeah and you put of them and it's just
as bright as an hlg because I've got two
of the hlg uh
oh yeah I uh
yeah I'm always impressed with how much
you can get out of your space dude I
mean I've seen what you what you're
working with and what you do I'm always
impressed dude that's
awesome it's My
Sanctuary I I I understand dude it's my
peace and serenity my place where I
chill and get high and think about stuff
uh maybe rock on to another one of these
uh uh questions here um what strain
would you recommend to someone new to
cannabis maybe the first time
growing for
beginners that you that you've grown
yourself I guess I should
say girls best friend because you're
gonna bring in it's still hype
enough because you've got the warm
cookies times 1091 so it's going to
introduce them to
[Music]
Kem because the chem's dominant in that
one and it grows unbelievably
inside just it put or any of any of the
bub
acrosses but out you know and then you
know because I wouldn't suggest train
rest because you're gonna freak out when
it starts
flopping but after you get a gr or two
under belt I would Point anything high
and
[Music]
lo put two in and only put
one and and then of course any of ma
stuff I mean that blueberry stuff is UN
but that's another one you almost want
to coup under your belt because you're
GNA get so frustrated thinking
hey for four weeks no you might have to
six
eight and then send it out on the bottom
get it up to the top you know already it
to vation towards your tril and when the
stretch kicks in you're
perfect yeah I uh I would have to
agree on the blueberry and the train
wreck really is blueberry is easy to
grow but I feel like yeah I
mean if you were I don't know if I'd
want to do that my first if I was
recommended to I would actually
recommend I've said this a million times
skank dog dude it's an
e pleasure dude you could grow that with
low inputs you can I'm I'm doing full
strength terra terra can right now and
it's eating it up dude big chunky leaves
I mean the the stock on one of these
plants bro I kid you not is this is the
thickness of my finger while all the
other ones are like maybe a pencil like
it's insane dude and dude it Stacks nice
it's chunky dense stinky runchy skunky
kind of coffee bit
smell to it dude it's just it is what
you know it's one of my favorite
favorites to grow and dude it comes out
pretty consistent that's another thing
too you know uh just coming out really
consistent but but uh another one you
said that Bubba I think um H&amp;L has uh
the uh pre98
Bubbas uh times the uh Kim D times uh
Appalachia dude that one was another
easy one it was Ron it's stacked nice
all this stuff that I usually talk about
is from seed I I do run clones of stuff
I try to but man I'm usually going
through so many plants that I usually
just will and I like to run the seed
plant or you know the the plant from
seed first and then I'll take Cuts if I
like it and then run you know that's
just the way I do it some people like to
take cuts for more stability and [ __ ]
like that and that's fine I
just on everything I see everything that
I pop from seed I try to take
just a redneck version of anic Road
areic literally got how many on
that and just a 27 gallon fre Co that
I've got weather on the top of the lid
and then you know I on four not four
corners but the two on each side because
the handle click
but still got enough where when you run
that pwn pump in with the emitters it'll
out so you want to put little clamps on
the side so it feel it against the the
thing or against weather shipping but I
try to run coins on everything that I do
and then I'm done with it I'm it I'm not
saying that the I'm not looking at Brea
the only thing I ever want to try to do
anything with is going to be the 500
stuff because know there no more seeds
of it right I can get it I'm gony to
reverse it spray I'm gonna do my G on
probably two runs now to really do a 5
by five of nothing
but of that and I mean just yeah I'm not
dude I've got so much of the most cill
stuff in my fridge the hell do I want to
keep same thing for right you know I
made wine they do that way I I got rid
of the best smoke I've ever had in my
life but what I'll find some more
yeah to run out of growing packs in H&amp;L
stuff D I mean yeah that's that's
another thing too for me like I want to
work through so much [ __ ] that I can't
keep every [ __ ] thing bro and I'm not
so much of an expert on weed that I
think I got everything I pop is [ __ ]
the greatest so I I I I mean is there
some stuff that I've lost that I've
popped that I'm like damn I wish I had
more of it but sure but it's like you
said dude I'll I'll just go get more
seeds of it dude right now I mean that
being said though bidder and a couple of
the guys were saying you
know you're you think like that until
you do lose the one one of the greatest
ones you've had and then you feel like
[ __ ] but but I I'm kind of like you I I
want to go through seeds and I want to
look through different [ __ ] and if I
find something great uh you know I'll
pop more of it hopefully find it but you
know also I like to uh do a little
chucking you know I I don't like to I
don't call it breeding I like to Chuck a
little bit because a lot of the stuff
that the guys are are making our RS I
mean some of it's them work too but um
you know I always have a mail around or
at a stage where it I might as well do a
little dusting bro so and obviously The
Offspring aren't going to come out
exactly how you want or maybe they don't
maybe they come out [ __ ] maybe they
don't come out close to the parents
whatever
but yeah you know it is what it is but
that's I got so much seed at this point
that I've gotten from homies in the
Discord and the patreon and that I've
chucked my stuff to look through
probably a couple lifetimes you know so
that's thing I get it I get it because
you're always gonna have but the thing
is two of my favorites I know I can go
to both of the get something very
comparable you know what I mean
like dude L this home [ __ ] I need it
back you know both of
those up
yeah
just the Discord is so cool and and
that's what's fun don't get me wrong we
act likees
intime you know lot of
dick
and I'm not afraid to admit it we have
fun and nobody you know and get it
doesn't matter
because for five minutes and then we're
back to the point and that's what I love
about
this because that's why IED
it and and the reason I
joined go back to way earlier
question was listening to mat you know
listening to the two podcast
episod the and find
patre his YouTube
awesome yeah the the Matt in the podcast
and the Discord and everybody in there
has been so helpful helpful to me bro
hey could could you before we keep going
could you bring your uh mic or whatever
you're picking up could you for some
reason I can hear your voice coming
through that speaker a little bit or
your speaker does that make sense all
I've got is my phone on speaker phone
okay that's fine we we'll make it
through it I can understand you and
everything it's just I didn't know if
you could get it a little that's that's
a little bit better when you lean closer
uh but uh so yeah yes we could be
[ __ ] in the Discord a little bit
but I like to look at it is like uh like
a it's fun dude we all we all cut up
like brothers like uh I don't know if
people this kind of reminds me of
working in a mechanic shop or auto body
shop or something like if you can take
that kind of razin you're G to be fine
now don't get me wrong what I do
appreciate about the Discord there's
people like yourself and at the
time
thousandfold yeah where something gets
hairy
he'll proba like
he it's a little aggressive down
that's you know what I mean and that's I
love about that place if you've got an
opion everybody's allowed to State at
first
being a little violent about it do so
right right yeah yeah I mean that you
know you when you got a bunch of guys
and gals in Discord that are really
knowledgeable and have been growing for
10 20 30 40 years it sometimes you're
going to butt heads on different
opinions and things you know uh and not
to mention in life I mean right now
everything's a little crazy so and
depending on your stance on stuff so but
but something I love about our community
and and and what we're trying to do is
just you know focus on the plants focus
on you know learning focus on having a
good time I mean if you're a person that
gets your feelings hurt pretty easily or
maybe uh maybe you're you're made out of
tissue paper you probably shouldn't join
the Discord you know with that being
said because you know are you really
looking at the Discord if you're that if
you're that soft probably not yeah
probably not but that also being said
that that kind of uh environment uh
often kind of for us at least produces
the best people and that's what Matt's
after Matt's after good people it's not
about people that uh you know are the
the got the most [ __ ] or the best cuts
or the best Growers all the time uh so
yeah everybody will answer you too and
we got the Godfather come on and
every I mean the D
come on and one of the most humble
people
and just to do stuff I mean come on yeah
he's I got the other day I didn't he
didn't ask for a penny for that and I
mean know what those cards are worth and
I'm still freaking
out yeah
yeah yeah he's uh he he sent me some
seeds he uh another guy a bitter H&amp;L h
of course Matt um and there's a lot of
other guys I'm probably forgetting about
but they've helped me a lot you know and
uh even the other people that we just
hang out and talk it's kind of it's It's
a it is a community you know we all cut
up and hang out and I'm I know you've
met up with a few people probably and
I've met a few up with a few of these
guys and met some of them in real life
and they're all they've all been really
great to me dude so well that's one
thing I really wanted to propose to you
and now we're on live spot I truly think
this summer
we and meet up and or something yep I
mean that's I want to pass on to you I
want you and your mes to get your asses
up to Holland to see
the well thing to behold beautiful I
mean Absolut beautiful and it's not too
far away from where you at maybe an hour
or two
Y in a once in a lifetime experience
because I know there's some [ __ ] going
on there that you guys may have to move
but you know definitely try to get up if
you're still there in the spring get
your ass up to holl it's a Once in a
long time thing to see i' I've been up
there actually you talking about what
the uh
windmill yeah yeah have you seen the
toip No No but see it's unreal and of
course you can go buy
some oh yeah yeah um actually I was
sitting there last night thinking like
about maybe like some kind of meet up uh
of some kind you know I don't want to
set anything in stone but maybe uh as we
go through I'm G to have guest on and
maybe as we work through guest we'll
start uh you know U arranging something
figuring out something for the summer
because I I had Michigan it for us
coaster it needs to be Michigan because
the one thing about Michigan is is even
if you can't travel
with you know we can go get it from the
dispensaries I hate to say that but if
that's what has to happen
freaking sweet peach and we all come
with the kick ass edies yep we we'll
figure out a way well there's other ways
we can we can get [ __ ] there yeah I'll
rent a house we'll do a Airbnb or
something like that that [ __ ] would be
fun because that last summer I did that
with the guys and I want to do that this
summer I know there's a couple meetups
uh maybe happening at some point I don't
know if I'm going but that would be
great to have something in my own you
know somewhere here in Michigan there
close by man that'd be awesome then we
maybe we could all bring
bring there's a lot of people um that
that the one fell has been talking with
us a lot on the the the stages I mean I
know he's right there
Ino yeah so I
meanig
is yeah there's quite a well yeah it'd
be great to get together like Midsummer
bring some smoke that we' all harvested
from stuff we grown out and and all that
[ __ ] that would be great dude I think
that' be awesome um so uh maybe I could
ask you what's your preferred way to
smoke do you like joints bongs
vaporizers or something
else oh yeah is that your dab rig yes
sir um yeah I'm I'm I I I I am the
weirdest person on the face planet that
lik cannabis I
hate tast never liked it day one um I've
always been a bong guy I I don't roll
blunt play do even though I I
make my my boy
love you know keep quite a bit of them
around
but I I
prefered or hold on I don't know where
the it's at mine
and I got the pack with silicone
adter I put it because I haven't smoked
at it for a
while but yeah I like a three through
the same rig oh nice yeah I uh I I did
really I've never been a [ __ ] dab
[ __ ] really much but recently my
friend he he showed me how to do cold
starts because back when I learned about
dabs growing up these [ __ ]
would torch this [ __ ] and I was like
that's not me bro and uh recently my
buddy he showed me how to do cold starts
and uh I actually really enjoy that I
will say this though that a vaporiz the
the dabs don't have [ __ ] on a vrp dude I
got to use a vrp last summer at the
party bro and that dude that was
[ __ ] it depends on your temperature so
when you're doing cold you're kind
of and
what and I do
them is I'll put the booger on
the the bottom of it and the bottom I
give it either the of one Mississippi
two Mississippi or
three and let it bubble and I know it's
not
gonna
but two three at one to three
seconds gives it to the point where you
can actually tast to turpy when you T
the out of that and it's so damn hot
that
[ __ ] smoke and everything in the rig
and everything else like [ __ ] are you
baked out of your mind yeah but you're
also
probably I can't enjoy it right you're
probably also giving yourself throat
cancer dude [ __ ] [ __ ] burn it my
buddy I don't know that really but my
buddy uh
back home he [ __ ] he would Chaz a
dude like every time and I'm telling him
like dude that can't be good for you bro
and he every night I'm listening to him
when I used to be his roommate I'm of
course he smokes cigarettes too but
coughing a storm up just coughing
coughing I'm like dude you probably burn
in your he's always like my throat hurts
I'm like yeah dude because you're
[ __ ] intaking like thousand degree uh
what you know concentr trades but but
yeah man U I got a couple more things
out here we could go through through uh
okay
any um went through that one let's see
okay you said you're not much into the
breeding but um if you could have a
dream strain if you could create your
own strain um what which ones would you
what two plants would you cross together
or if you could have any cut maybe any
kind of
hypothetical I wish I wish my bubble gum
cres would have
worked um I I I got pollen facts on my
bubble gum reason I did that is what we
talking about earlier the
humidity and that's the one thing I mean
I'm I'm gonna take everything Caleb said
as and he says that bubble gun not
outside and that's the only reason now I
would cross train Rack
or something that's going to the bubble
I don't give a [ __ ] train wreck train
wacks com to the like [ __ ] get out of
the way yeah yeah I mean you put that
train wreck in there it's going to
[ __ ] ramp it up dude that all the
crosses uh in the atw I've had of pox
have been great dude I had uh you know
we make fun of cookie [ __ ] all the time
dude but he has the what is it the blue
is it blue garlic cookies or blue
cookies or something anyways at the
party somebody gave me
somebody gave me some of that dude and
even that was [ __ ] awesome dude it
Blow blew away anything you get from
like a a dispensary you know it's runchy
and you know it wasn't my favorite thing
that I got from the party because a lot
H&amp;L and a few of the other guys let me
have all their stuff I mean the pH Haze
was phenomenal uh the electric mango the
Rank Stranger from h&amp; there's a bunch of
[ __ ] that was great uh but just I ran
out of all that stuff and I had like a
half ounce of that blue cookies or
whatever the [ __ ] it was uh and it
actually you know I was surprised I
really ended up enjoying it dude it's
real runchy kind of real pretty had the
had really pretty blue you could see
where like some of the fan leaves were
blue like an actual blue hue it was
really beautiful uh nugs real dense
chunky nugs like it was grown well uh
and it smoked great dude it kind of
surprised me so um I got a bunch of [ __ ]
of Po I got going right now I got the
sleep
disturbance uh what's the other four
dude I'm too high right now I blank bro
I got sleep disturbance of course I got
some more of his atws ones going I got
the turp Queen the Kim dream and then
what was the shoreline or the dog [ __ ]
one I always forget the names bro
anyways another one of those I for I me
we don't need to know the names we just
need to respect the men and
that's yeah I forget it yeah dude I I
got so many little thing little
seedlings popped right now it's hard for
me to remember all the [ __ ] I got but um
but anyways I got a bunch of that [ __ ]
going and I'm hyped for it dude uh pox
stuff especially the stuff with the
p91 uh in anything with p91 and I've
Loved dude even the penic kushes from
konzo another breeder from the breeder
Syndicate Discord dude that was [ __ ]
good weed dude I loved it see I've not
I've not privilege yet of any of the PE
stuff now I do have something from has
sweet yeah and can't wait to I think
it's the sweet PE and the blue green
possibly and I'm stok about that and Old
besy Times um blue dream and I'm Blue
Dream what a beautiful PL and you want
to talk about
the blue dream s1's apox
that the tricomes were blue that's wild
that's wild
dude the only thing I can either that or
it was a plant material
but I don't know if it the actual
material but it was such beautiful
beautiful well the turp queen have you
seen pictures of that the real purple
beautiful uh there's a picture excuse me
he burping um on the mat Matt Matt site
there's a picture called uh I'll put
maybe I'll slice some of these pictures
in this video um but there's a real
pretty PL on there called turp Queen and
dude I got some of those going I'm
hoping to get one of those purple ones
like that I'm not a big purple weed guy
but that plant in particular I was like
wow it's beautiful and something to be
said about all those dream uh Blue Dream
crosses is even at this tall bro in if
you break off broke off a couple little
leaves you can smell that blue dream bro
and I know it because I I've grown uh
dryer sheets in the previous uh Pock
mystery grow uh like a year and a half
ago or something like that U or year ago
uh that was the most that particular
cross I mean I remember drying in this
tent I cleaned the tent out and then I
did a whole another dry on a whole
another run like three months later and
that [ __ ] tent still smelled like
that uh dryer sheets is the The Strain
or the cross that it was uh but yeah
dude just the Blue Dream Is Awesome from
Pac dude I love it I I think he said he
I don't I think the s1's are sold out
right now on Matt site but I think he
said he's working on getting some more
up but I'm not sure but um yeah man uh
if you had a dream grow setup what would
you
have uh a shed that was 10 by 20
yeah umon I say that is because I would
put at least
byes because then I would have a
dedicated 5 by nothing bed but then I
would do two by fours on the side so you
could do a mom room you could do a clone
you could have your individual T
so be because
don't so there's my gorilla there's
my and then the the two by right there
so I mean I keep everything in here
regulated by
dehumidified and that's the mistake a
lot of people make is when you run your
deidier don't let it go into the tread
you're never going to keep up with that
tread not
no a
sec good so just
run the side of your
thing it doesn't have to be I mean
that's
but you can you can not worry about it
as much
right here well hell you know all
the we had a sh R the humidity is you
can cut through it
yep humidifier dumps into that 5 gallon
bucket and there's no way that's Gonna
Fill Up by the time I get home from work
yeah [ __ ] dude uh I I'm I'm about to rig
my my drain for my dehumidifier out the
window bro I'm tired of [ __ ] even the
five gallon bucket I'm tired of it it's
it's that five gallon bucket of Ro or
that five gallon
of dehumidified water is no different
than your water system you're trying to
set up it's nothing in
it yeah I thought I was I'm just so
weary about about uh I got a cheaper
dehumidifier bro and you know I could
probably obviously you know check check
what's in it and [ __ ] like that but I
use that [ __ ] for outside like I'll take
it out to like uh you know like plants
outside or whatever and also we're we're
on a whale too so it's like dude I just
dump it on the ground it's going back
into the [ __ ] [ __ ] well at some point
you know well have to worry about C mag
yeah well actually you do here bro it's
kind of weird uh so here it's more iron
and dissolved like Metals uh that are in
the water so
because yeah
so right so back home bro I didn't
realize how good I had it you know
there's been some people that will [ __ ]
on Kentucky about growing but the water
and the temperature and everything for
me even in the winter time was perfect
never really got PM never really had
pest problems nothing dude but here bro
uh the water's different like there the
water had tons of calcium and different
different things in it and I knew it
You' see it build up on your fish tanks
and [ __ ] you know whereas here it's iron
and different Metals you see it just
building up and you could smell it and
so you know a lot of people say well
just you know I'm running like two to
300 ppms coming out the faucet so I I
personally don't know what's in it uh I
know obviously you get up to like 4 500
you're you can go all the way up to like
4 500 to the point where it's not safe
to drink probably but hey I'm just I
want to start at a base level with the
RO that way I can put in even it's I got
to spend a little bit more money I don't
mind because I know what's in it I know
how you know exactly what my inputs are
and uh that's kind of where I'm at if I
had a dream grow setup I would probably
have rooms but still like individual
sealed rooms but still have tents but
maybe bigger bigger rooms bigger tents
but just individual sealed rooms because
you know I I don't know I a big building
outside like a big [ __ ] Warehouse or
a building would be great dude with a me
with what I know I can afford eventually
in a 10 by2 sh I grow up my damn self
I'm going to put in either 2 by6 walls
or honestly I might go crazy is put in 2
by1 building it once for me for my I put
in 2 by 12s with spray and put pressure
treated wood on the very bottom with a
regular plywood on the top because then
you don't have to worry
about and then spray the
Walls 2 by1 dude you're going to look at
an R35 or an R40 dude it could be 20 Dam
outside
inside the damnn room and it's gonna
warm it up y you know if I could have my
next spot and I'll be moving not not
I'll be moving here pretty soon uh my
next spot I want to find uh a drain on
the floor I want it to be concrete with
the drain on the floor I want a [ __ ]
sink right there uh I want at least a
few I got a few finally got a couple 55
gallon reservoirs up here that I'm going
to start I've just now I've been [ __ ]
around with this RO system and I'm
dialing it in I'm dialing it in but it's
not where I want it to be just yet but I
would have a big Reservoir or a few and
uh yeah man more power bro that's
another thing more power bro because you
could never have enough [ __ ] power I
feel like dude you know and preferably a
really nice uh some kind of well that
would be good enough a sink and a drain
and and a door bro I'm on the second
floor so carrying soil and [ __ ] dude
it's a [ __ ] it's fun
bro there you
go I don't have a shed door there you
go my shed door is great stuff I mean I
know that was a major problem so now I
came across a freaking weather from my
next my dad's next door neighbor for
free
I mean I just put it on the the shed and
it has made all the difference in the
world by airflow because you're never
going to seal a shed door no but as you
can see behind me that white is
literally the stuff that you put under
metaling on top of
RC so you know I'm getting double
insation great and I'm not paying too
much I've got a window unit it's one of
those sheds that had two windows on it
AC and a small heater but as long as I
run my
life it stays pretty good yeah that's I
mean dude redneck Ingenuity
brother hopefully one of these days I
can get a 3D printer and I mean I know
I've talked it that nauseum on the
Discord but I want to make my bucket
system I mean you know and you know it
blue mats meets redneck basically yeah
yeah dude hey it's an individual blue
mat it's something each buget has it own
res it works literally [ __ ] away from
this gr you know when I asked my miss
when we went to Q I mean for four days
and I didn't have to I didn't
worry I right they just as smid heavier
than I may normally do but soil not wet
right added water resir below
yeah man I uh we were maybe before I
forget I we were talking about grow uh
dream Grow rooms earlier
um I there's a point where you get to
where you got too many plants I mean I
know you can always make it better and
um more efficient but that's something I
learned last year dude just like there's
a limit where it becomes not fun anymore
at least for me U and maybe like maybe
that would be too big if I could just
have a nice little spot uh a room or to
that has a sink and a drain that would
be great but uh and enough power but
yeah I mean dude I'm like you bro I I
grew up poor as [ __ ] so anytime I could
save a buck and if I got to put a a
little bit of work and some elbow grease
into something and to make it work uh
I'm going to do it it's like those drums
they were holding the brown rice syrup
so I think I paid five bucks a piece for
each one and I got yeah and I mean a
brand new one with the lid is like $160
Shi to you and I think at Tractor Supply
they're like a hundred bucks so I cut a
hole in it with the saws all bro and or
both of them I power washed them out you
know put some soap and bleach and stuff
cleaned them all out real good and dude
I got two 55 gallon reservoirs chilling
up here for [ __ ] 10 bucks bro I mean
it took me an hour to [ __ ] with them
cheap ass cheap ass freaking aquarium
pump and just literally put airstones in
both of them just yeah bit of
oy will keep it going
and that's you know and that's where
redneck freaking somebody like
bit know what the hell they're doing
yeah the actual guys yeah guys you know
but you know that's where you take the
information from guys we look up to like
that you know it's not like when I say
look up to it's not like I'm these guys
on some God pest right but learning from
them and I'm happy to say that I'm
learning from you know and I just don't
want that to be miscon that I'm like
guys way the hell up can do no wrong
anybody yeah yeah yeah I we're not
through the process of oh [ __ ] screw
that one up you know and and they're and
they're just like us talk it that one
up and and if anybody joins the
and and you're in there in the beginning
if anybody with a gold name gives you
any information listen to it because
these
are want to listen to because they've
proven that they deserve to have that
gold
man and and if you join Discord you
you well I think uh you know that's well
a good way to put it dudee uh I think
Denali it even better leave the egos in
the MAA tub no no I mean at the end of
the day this is a eg- driven uh Hobby
and or not ego driven but there's a lot
of ego uh a lot of egos in this in this
[ __ ] so I could get why you don't like
somebody thinks they know the best ways
but I I'm like you dude I'm want to
listen I'm want to be a sponge dude I
want to hear what you got to say because
hey I mean maybe I run into that problem
like right now I wish I would have
listened to about the sulfur when bitter
was talking about it the first 30
[ __ ] times then I wouldn't have had
to write them and be like hey how do you
do this how so do I need to dip my
clones do this that that so but's
another when you see these you're gonna
giggle because these have been mentioned
100 goddamn times
on every in a while even if you don't
even have to see anything get your
mosquit dunk put in the water water them
in I going admit I
am I'm the most generic General
hydropic with I mean so M
hydroponic
recharge and that's Sil a
supplement and I honest to God it is I
know they talk about a bunch of that's
non absorbent until eight years down the
road that that is bioavailable because
you get to the point where I know enough
about plants and and growth structure
just it's worth it because when you go
from a stem that's that big around to a
stem that's that damn big around it's
like oh [ __ ] okay yeah well what was it
something you yield if you I don't know
if you want to share this but there was
something that yielded for you was it
the blue dreams that was insane
something crazy was crazy and and so is
the train wreck the train was Unreal but
then come on I mean if you
Tok Tony
lomy George all those guys
come I'm just a participant behind those
guys they had beautiful
cloes and you know that's what's all
about learning I'm I'm I don't think I'm
gonna walk away with a but it is awesome
to get privileg grow with these guys oh
yeah it's all yeah I like that's myself
bro I don't think I'm anywhere near uh
the best grower or or the most
knowledgeable person if anything I'm I'm
the opposite but and that's why I do the
[ __ ] that I do and purs and in in the
Discord because I I want to learn I want
to be around these guys like I mean I
remember being 15 16 17 years old
thinking like watching some of these
shows and and downloading some of these
uh High Times cups and [ __ ] and yeah a
lot of that [ __ ] was crooked or whatever
but for me as a Kentucky kid like out on
an island by myself with nobody to look
up to really or talk to about marijuana
or weed or whatever uh and not knowing
you know I didn't you know when you when
you're you don't know that everybody's
[ __ ] out to get you or there's a lot
of scammers and [ __ ] you just want to be
a part of something I mean to be honest
I mean I I I probably got $4,000 worth
of sheets I'll never damn grow right
probably try to pop them I'll probably
try to pop him but because I went on the
Dick
Rider I mean it was whatever the old boy
said that bets every grower you know
getting too much prop or is to
much of my genetics in the very
beginning and then you start listening
to Matt telling you the true stories and
it wasn't the fact
that I was trying to prove a point the
reason I like M so much is he never
Li yeah he never lies Matt out false
information back in the day he instantly
corrected himself and I'm not saying it
happened a bunch but his pride never got
in the way of true
and always respected the hell out of
that right you know we're going back to
the what was it the third episode of the
podcast I was on right I know it's
pretty close for that I'll be honest I
never really W I'll be honest I watched
uh I watched a few uh panels with CSI
years ago Dude on YouTube and I
literally I think I
watched
maybe one episode it was the episode of
the origins of OG kush or something it
was the one on what they were talking
about from Florida or whatever and I
just that was the one time watched
something and then I literally saw Matt
and NATO talking about some one of their
podcasts and I just started watching
that so I got real lucky and didn't I
mean don't get me wrong I brought my
share of [ __ ] seeds but a lot of seeds
that I bought were like your um crop
kings in the beginning uh I love
marijuana [ __ ] like that you know
because I I was using Google because you
know you're thinking you know we use
Google for everything so you look first
thing you do is you go on Google you
know who best marijuana seeds in like
the [ __ ] top three pages are like the
dumbest shittiest scammy like websites
you could you could think of right
whatever not to give two props to him
but I mean like I said all the all the
ones that I bought from were [ __ ]
there sometime and you know who I'm
talking about I'm not giving the dude
prop because I'm not a big fan of the
dude whether he's a good guy or not he's
got a bunch of [ __ ]
[ __ ] yeah well you know that's that's
the weed world that's something I
learned and really surprised me you know
I'm so appreciative of having a living
out my sounds corny but being able to
live my dream of hanging out with other
people who love weed as much as I do
breeders Growers smokers just people who
enjoy it but also you know I didn't know
that there would be so much drama and
stuff in the Wei world as well too that
kind of was like caught me off guard but
I don't let that make my experience
though either you know that's why you
know look at the guys you got to hang
out with
D talking about
jealous well yeah I mean thanks to the
guys thanks to thousand and Denali and
Matt and uh and uh bitter not showing up
actually uh to the party I was able to
go to on that fishing trip with Rob
Clark and Denali and lo and Dan and and
all those guys and and uh man got come
on yeah it was a a dream come true and I
had to pinch myself it sounds kind of
fanboyish because I don't like I said
the the first time I ever got a [ __ ]
autograph bro was yeah Rob Clark in this
book come on you can't I can't knock you
for that bro I I am Never Gonna Knock
you for that that is the coolest [ __ ]
ever yeah yeah it
was I mean that would like that would be
like me and I know it's gonna happen I
know it's gonna happen and I don't give
a [ __ ] if take cards that I got and make
them the value that
which I
know what they were I want to sign his
name I want his signature on freaking I
can't that matters to me that's how much
I respect that dude I
want and I don't care and makes it worth
two it's worth the world to me and you
believe my boy already knows who D is
without ever being on the Discord
Y and he knows because I talk about
everybody so
so
positively and he sees the way I get
like when after after our Friday
Night YouTube and when you do the stage
now and I'm stilling the stage every
week dude props to you I mean major
props my boy sees the way that I come in
the I'm glowing even if I don't say work
he sees the way that I'm listen to
people that I look up to
and yeah yeah yeah I mean dude uh Denali
and a few other guys are I mean Denali
specifically he uh he's he's like my
grandfather passed away uh like three or
four years ago and he is an alcoholic
and he we weren't super close but the
times that he was around were were uh
really important and meaningful to me
and uh having D has been like having
like almost like another almost like a
dad or a grandpa he's been so good to me
and taught me a lot of [ __ ] and uh keeps
me on keeps my stick on Ice keeps me on
a straight and narrow path for a lot you
know I get a little wild sometimes but
uh you know and as far as the voice
chats that we do after the show um yeah
I mean dude I could be doing other [ __ ]
but I I know that that means something
to you guys and it's not about me it's
just bringing uh some sometimes the
community sometimes we need people to
just be that first person to get
something going and then you know other
people join and we all have a good time
because it is it's awkward getting on
the Internet especially sharing uh some
people are doing this uh still in the
gray area of legality so I get how it's
a little awkward but um yeah just
getting on there and uh I don't know how
many people want to listen to my dumbass
talk but uh getting on there and having
cutting up with you guys and um you know
sharing stories and getting to know you
guys guys uh uh believe it or not has
been one of the better uh and surprising
things that I've enjoyed about the
Discord for sure man well hell we're
turning this damn thing into Joe Rogan
episode man hey that's what I want to do
man not Joe Rogan but I wanted to uh
just have a podcast or a show that was
more um yeah just chill dude and just
hanging out we talk about
different yeah and feel very prived and
that you asked me to be on here I mean
and it means the world to well I was
going to say that uh you know you're the
first person I talked to Matt about
doing one of these little side shows or
and I don't know how often I'll do them
but maybe once a month maybe twice a
month we'll see uh uh I had a lot of fun
doing this one but my my thing I was
going to say was you were the first
person that came to my mind there's
there's tons of other people that are
just deserving and stuff too it don't
let me get it uh [ __ ] up I want to
bring on as many people as we came from
the Discord and highlight everybody but
you came to mind first because you're
one of the people that uh I see you
always have a positive attitude you're
growing the stuff uh you know it's not
that you I don't think anybody should
have to grow stuff that they don't want
to grow or no one's making you grow [ __ ]
in the Discord but it it's awesome that
you're growing the guys that we support
and that we rock with and also your
attitude about everything dude you're
you're always got a positive spirit and
I knew you would be a great uh guest to
do and plus you dude we're both rednecks
man gotta gotta get gotta gota get a
redneck on you know what I'm saying no
there you go I I was gonna say you got
the breeder Syndicate shirt on that's
awesome dude that's [ __ ] but I mean
it's it's just there's no falsehood that
I think that I'm doing a good job I mean
and that was my first interaction with d
is when I first came on the Discord I
think I had the sister
wife in three of TRS that I'm gonna
mention are be CSI so I sister
wife back now s wifey
was Wii and the three queens was
Bubba and then I had
the girl best friend which was the Forum
cookies
times and it was my third third ever in
their
grow Denali said I was doing a
good that somebody and now that I know
it's deep it's even more but you know
when you're first in there that you look
you
know the the chear and giving it felt
really good but now that I know it's me
help a lot more to me yeah D's the Og
man I mean d has been doing it for a
long time D's kind of like The Godfather
Discord and and usually he people don't
know this but a lot of times when
somebody new joins he'll reach out to
him and kind of uh you know talk to him
and and [ __ ] and he takes care of
everybody he did the same thing for me
and uh you know a lot of those guys have
taken good care of me and I can't ex uh
tell you how much I'm appreciative of
them and uh you know and that's why I
want to do the show to add value to
match Channel and and the breeder
Syndicate because you know I I think
this is this what we do in our Discord
I'm not saying that other discords
aren't doing it right either or whatever
but you know what we do and and focus on
in our Discord it means the world to me
so any way we can highlight that and put
that on on a a platform to where other
people can see it and enjoy it and learn
from it I mean it's a win-win dude and
there's not a guy on the
Discord and I I don't
give and you've mentioned some of them
like look and and and Gren and all these
guys and and Denali and and of course
pack and if you question and
mad sat there and I don't know bu the
sound out is so humble and will take any
question you have it's a legit question
and you're gonna be AAG about it like oh
I this you know
smoke a legit question all those guys
will take their time to try to help you
right because you know how it's your
genetic that you're growing or their
sorry their genetic that you are growing
that you know you're putting time and
effort into why the hell wouldn't a guy
that loves a
plan pass that and that's the one
beautiful thing about the disc I
mentioned enough everybody loves plan
and not trying to dippy about it but
everybody GS a [ __ ] about growing it
whether it's you know for whatever
motive it I'm not looking at
a you know I've mentioned
many come to me but it's
just it's nice to see people that give a
about what's going
on what they not just my bag on it open
my C we're doing this for our Lov
ones and the people close to us
yeah yeah I I couldn't I can't agree any
even you know I couldn't agree more bro
that's uh I I've I've this is going on I
think it'll be like two and a half years
in a couple months in the Discord dude
and and it's been uh the best thing
that's ever happened to me as far as
growing
uh was concerned and just knowledge and
uh you know I'm not the most
knowledgeable person when it comes to uh
history or strains or cultivars uh
things like that but I do that's why I'm
here is to learn and enjoy uh weed and
to talk with guys like you or girls
whatever shout out peaches shout out
Miss Gill no but uh but you know just
share share knowledge and have fun and
hang out and you know some I talk to you
guys more than I talked to some of my
childhood friends that I know uh for
Going on 30 plus years now with some of
them
so you know so but in all
honesty and and the reason I think that
I have so much more in the discords
especially when I get a couple minutes
at work you know there may not patience
there that day or I'm in between
patients and you know it it you take a
breath of fresh air and and get in there
and look at the see what's being talked
about if I can add my two cents I'll add
my two cents or make some offhanded dad
joke I mean 51 damn years old one of the
older guys you know and you know it's
just awesome to feel welcome and not
only that you know you're going to a
place that everybody's like like I said
hardless of the political view and
that's one thing I like about the
Discord we don't get too political
right you know and and that's that's one
thing I appreciate you know it's about
the you know there some guys in there
that are very opinionated that I love to
death and and you know it's fun I I love
list you know read more books than I
do you had to hold a gun to my head and
threaten my make me a book damn it I
hear you
yeah I mean dude I mean yeah I mean the
Discord is you can't for five bucks
especially bro I mean so nowadays that's
like a [ __ ] coffee or a piece of gum
or a pack of gum nowaday
it's y I mean I wish there was I wish
there was a way that it would be more
public on these
YouTube obviously not this
one does that they could get more people
could learn about the disc and
not that just left that you
know
controversy people are following the
[ __ ] out of because they can say the
right thing but that's one thing
I about breeder
Syndicate it's never sto the hyp [ __ ]
try to get
out it's one of those if you know you
know and it's like you know when people
ask about if I'm perfectly honest with
you I know he's part of The Syndicate
but if I were to tell brand new grow the
first place I'm gonna site's gonna be
the first
I because if you can't pick out of Cale
site screw it don't grow yeah CSI is the
goat dude uh I mean I
mean he he I know he's can Illuminati
and One Max but when you're talking
about something that can bring somebody
into the Discord that's the guy I would
send them to First here I want to ready
come on the Discord you can try some
really good [ __ ] too not saying it's
better than Caleb stuff it's just that
you may not have heard
of you know when you get you start when
you and I start talking about talk and
and high and Lear what people may
not eight
restraint you're looking at a minimum
minimum of 10 on the and then when you
start talking you're looking at the
14 but is it it is exponentially so much
better than this [ __ ] that
is
weeks Yeah well yeah especially like the
market like the modern Market uh you
know runs and dumb [ __ ] like that I mean
I I think I think what's cool too is a
lot of those guys offer some kind
of cross of some H some Modern stuff too
like I know excuse me I know pox got
like the train W cross the um ice cream
uh ice cream cake or he's got a couple
other things that are more modern and
Matt does too he's got some of his ex
cross to the
[Music]
I mean and it was fun I mean not as good
as the blueberry I but it bigger it's
little son of a [ __ ] I like that runchy
[ __ ] bro no fruity stuff for me now the
the blueberries are good the blueberry
shit's good but I like I like that
runchy [ __ ] bro like something like like
cot cheese fermented something I mean
I'm right there with you brother I'm I'm
talking lot lizards that ain't showered
in two weeks I want a smell fermentation
brother
stink no but but no I mean that being
said uh I have tried I want to say was
it
the forbidden fruit punch from
CSI that was awesome dude that was one
of the more fruer things that I actually
the potency wasn't like crazy by any
means but the flavor uh that was one at
the party one of the guys grew that and
that that was pretty good fruit like if
you wan that kind of [ __ ] but uh yeah
man I'm more of in that Kim Kim
Bubba uh I don't know just runchy
[ __ ]
skank Beyond yeah um I guess we're
getting at the point this is the free
version I couldn't figure out I should
have asked for Matt's uh log into to his
stream yard
so we're getting to the point where this
going to cut us off so uh do you got any
shout outs that you or any you want to
plug yourself you got anything you want
to shout out or plug or absolutely join
the Discord guys I mean the Discord I
mean not trying to be you know a dead
rer or anything that to put it I
mean one of the most places you'll ever
go
to I I care what you go to I don't care
what go to it's humble nobody has Uber
ego and when Uber OS come out those are
the with us after a
month I you know where can you find the
real
OG yeah well brother happy it was been a
pleasure having you on here bro and I
think what we're going to do is
obviously we get to a point where I I
run out of guests so probably what we'll
do is catch back up here uh down the
road at some point and do another little
episode and kind of see where see where
you're at and have we have more stuff to
talk about obviously uh since we we'll
be growing more stuff and uh that's it
brother I appreciate you big time man
for coming on today it's been an
absolute honor and PIV man all right man
well anybody watching thanks for
watching go to Riot seeds.com pick up
some of Matts H&amp;L the other guys
genetics join the Discord join the
patreon what am I missing bro anything
else if you can't find it on Matt site
go to lifted genetics lftd genetics
lifted seeds man I mean another sight
and and part of the Discord I mean and
if you're Australia ger by seeds and if
you're in Europe I think it's Riot
seedco Europe or I forget I forget EX
exactly maybe one I know ger by seeds
but I'm not sure about the other one
well it's it's gold cut that runs it so
gold cut in the Discord or in the
breeder Syndicate Discord I'll put links
and everything down in the the bottom
for everybody and uh like I said I
appreciate you appy well thank you for
having me on man you too bro talk to you
later
bye what do you mean you want Oreo
cookies I might be able to slide them
down through the little ducking one
second
second did y'all enjoy the
show it was fun I apologize for the
audio quality but I had a good time
doing it we're going to step the game up
next time on that department it is what
it is do yourself a favor while I got
you here go over to Riot seeds.com pick
up some blueberry's if you like
blueberry turps pick up some H&amp;L seeds
pick up some Pac pick up all the good
[ __ ] get you some PE crosses you know
what I'm saying saying if you know if
you know I appreciate y'all like comment
and subscribe let me know what you think
about the show down below unless you a
dab ho then be a dab ho later