let's see
okay here we go
back in action all right how's everyone
doing
welcome to live feed
i finally got instagram and youtube up
it sucks because i have to use two whole
different things and keep switching back
and forth
can you guys hear any sound
any sound
connection good
before i start jumping into this like
last time
any of you guys could give me some
feedback yep
perfect thank you
thank you guys
party is on
party wolf i only know about the dc
muscle if i don't know about no party
wolves
if you google that google it at your own
risk and don't do it at work
let's see
good now that's all that matters all
right welcome everyone today i was going
to talk about
uh
some some breeders that you you should
check out
you know
um
a lot of people spend a lot of time
asking about [ __ ] dumb asses and
people that like
really haven't earned their place in the
community not and by earning i mean just
by being good people knowing what
they're talking about
able to [ __ ] have a decent
conversation about breeding you know
what what
we all kind of hope for
normally spend a lot of time talking
about that [ __ ] so today i wanted to
spend time talking about people who
deserve it
um
so yeah
let me get my little black book here
first off i want to start off with some
housekeeping so
um
be sure to join our patreon some of you
have some of you haven't
on our patreon we have our discord
that's the main part of the patreon that
that most people utilize but you also
get discounts you get a 10 discount on
my store and if you're also part of uh
speakeasy's
patreon you get 20
at both stores so it it stacks up and
adds up really cool so you don't just
get my [ __ ] you also get other people
who are who are the homies on there
um
see right now i'm posting a lot of the
northern lights progress um
the progress working with northern
lights are about a foot tall right now
everything's gonna be cloned and flipped
pretty soon it's it's some of the most
beautiful broad leaf stuff i've ever
seen in the nl5 and hawaiian lights not
seen a lot of narrow leaf anything in
any of that
sometimes
but when there are fights you know i
watch them and sometimes if you're if
you're cool maybe you can watch them
with me if you're a part of our patreon
discord it really really makes it work
so and
uh yeah we have we have special events
and movies and all kinds of stuff like
that we haven't been doing them lately
but we're going to start doing them
and also i do some or i'm going to start
doing some breeding posts
just little lectures written lectures
stuff you can take back to your homies
and sound super smart
and of course i'm just regurgitating it
because i'm not smart at all so
sound is a mess is the sound a mess for
everyone
is the sound a mess
perhaps a blooper scope for me i was
wondering how many before i hit the
skunky pino that's not how it really
works
uh
in any kind of
genetic
equation
um it could be the first one it could be
left
constantly lag
that's not good you guys good there
sound good over on instagram
let me see
yeah i don't have any
different thing i can switch to for a
connection
all right crashing the stream jesus
christ
one second i gotta sign out the uh
youtube
it sounds like a fan right oh it's
probably the goddamn
computer but yeah over on youtube i
gotta sign it out hold on
connection is unstable
i think we know how to sign it out
in-stream
okay hold on a second guys
well i can't even go grab the stuff that
has my
internet thing on it so youtube is just
[ __ ] for tonight that's it for youtube
oh well we tried with youtube
people can come back over here if they
want
all right
yeah youtube youtube epically failed
um
yeah sometimes the internet connection
really [ __ ] sucks and it's been
really bad on my computer so i guess i
just [ __ ] for youtube
um
what else we got is it doing okay on
here so far or is it choppy
i know last time the sound cut out and
that was even worse
yeah it's always some [ __ ] i tried
to do it beforehand but youtube doesn't
really let you not go live and just
test it out
anyway so we're going to be talking
about
breeders that you should like right
people that you should go support
um
and this this is more more important
than ever it's not on it's not on
youtube anymore
so anybody that asks about youtube can
you guys
keep them on it and help me out with
that so that i don't have to keep going
saying it's not on youtube anymore
yeah
hopefully people will jump on over here
from youtube
sucks youtube's such a better platform
but this computer has been
not running so smooth with its uh
internet connection
anyway
so
it's more important than ever now to
support
the people that matter
because you have to use your money like
swords yeah dude these these shirts are
real nice nice and comfy it's one of my
favorites um you have to use your money
like swords that's it
there's a lot of bad folk in this
industry and right now that pie has
gotten very very very teensy
because of corporate [ __ ]
and corporate box really it is people
want cheaper weed that aren't growers
gypsy i'm gonna slap you
[ __ ] um
yeah so
vote with your dollars exactly
the problem is the problem is prop 64
passed we all knew we all knew that was
gonna happen
and uh it was only a matter of time till
the market crashed and it crashed it
crashed hard not just for for seeds but
for wheat in general and i think now
that the unemployment has stopped
running in in um california and
nationwide as far as like the extra
payments that people are getting during
kovid
no one's spending any money
so
if you do not want to see your favorite
mom and pop shops sink you have to
support these guys all of them i mean
some of these people i'm not even
necessarily friends with
but um
they're they're still the the people
that help build this industry
don't worry about that [ __ ] in my head
don't you worry about that [ __ ] [ __ ]
in my hand i didn't have nothing in my
hands anyway
so of course i'm going to start with
with a lot of the the the homies you
know csi csi humboldt makes some of the
best [ __ ] on earth um
one of the first guys to to really do
heavy heavy feminizing in the us along
with og rascal um
you got archive
707 seed bank
uh my buddy hyatt lonesome
you got
founding fathers genetics which is with
csi's one of his best friends and a
friend of mine tygard
everybody loves gene
right
um
bitter i could i can uh
i can vouch for him because because i
know that dude i know that dude's heart
uh
working man's been doing great
cb's been doing great with the the
diesel stuff
bodhi
bodhi has saved my career more times
than i can count and that's that's just
the honest truth he's when i when i've
been down and out when i've had whole
whole
um
mother rooms just [ __ ] he was the one
who really came and swung in both times
um elite cannabis matt from elite
cannabis has done some amazing work he
rarely sells it hopefully he will be
selling it soon hopefully hopefully
hopefully
um
i'd like to see that we got thunder
fudge
he's a homie and he's always done cool
[ __ ]
melting pot i saw him come in here he's
been doing some great stuff
radical genetics they don't get talked
about a lot but they've been around a
long long time
phenomenal work especially with cbd
stuff
skunk va skunky is the homie he's a
[ __ ] really really really cool dude
most people know him because the chem 91
cut
um his mentor was where the virginia
super skunk came from that is in sour
um
green body i don't know really well so i
can't comment on that one
um
i do know a lot of people
that that i'm listening are not friends
with him
um
let's see
uh swamp boys i can't forget the swamp
boys
i mean just two classic dudes that have
been in it forever
i saw top dog got his account taken down
so try to give him a follow on top dog
genetics
um it's it's unreal how many how many
people are just ratting each other's
accounts out just because there's that's
how tight the competition is and um
i'm concerned it'll be much worse than
that over the next coming few months um
but that that is what it is yeah
freeborn like i said jeans up there
bloom bloom seed co with hairy palms
and uh the homie pip he has this stuff
over on um
speakeasy as well so check out his stuff
i know that they have some neon flamingo
purple midnight and shock collar which
are all kbg
uh seeds so go check those out
but if you any of you guys have any
questions about oh you know what um
rich
rich that made dog walker og the other
dog walker um
amazing dude uh heroes of the farm as
well
um yeah
of clear buddy who's clear boat yeah is
there a clear boaty is there a
red boaty
dot d is great croc and family could
suck a dick but dot needs a good one too
dark d is a great one any of the people
i mentioned if you if you have any
questions about them one eye thank you i
always comb bridge but yeah cbf has made
amazing [ __ ] i owe a lot of my career to
him um same as organ kid um
a lot of a lot of what i've been able to
do has been because of guys like that
you know uh
it
they don't get enough shine
they don't
already already talked about crybaby um
any questions on any of that
any questions
dynasty yeah i mentioned relic but
dynasty is a part of relic relic is
dynasty
i'm really pissed off at this uh
this
[ __ ] [ __ ] just [ __ ] out yeah seattle
chronics great dude great great dude um
he's tried to to be super friendly and
helpful too
uh big timers
yeah everyone you just named arctic or a
bunch of [ __ ] but that's okay
i get along with brandon from third gen
i mean the clown she thing's always
gonna be there that was funny but like
yeah i don't know
um he's been cool to me
we already did archive okay can you tell
us about the pbo gmail what did it pass
on reliably in the crosses how did you
what what did you like about how does it
compare to the blue bonnet mill so
when picking that male what i wanted to
do with with most banana ogs which
you're going to find is
it out crosses a lot of amazing banana
type stuff nog stuff
but it then shits out a lot of boof like
a lot of skunk one type stuff um
blando
type stuff that probably came from the
sega math s6040
so i wanted to improve that
aspect of the breeding with it and keep
it more to higher resin production
and um keeping the banana tones more um
dominant
because you know yeah yes youtube is
down yes
um
where am i at sorry it's hard to read
and answer questions and do all this
right now
but yeah so so that was the difference
in in just the platinum bananog versus
banana og youtube is down
youtube is down
um
as far as the bonnet i mean it's it's
two different uh
it's two different
whole different projects
like
i don't just choose a male based on one
set of characteristics jaws is a [ __ ]
don't you know what
anybody who
i'm gonna give you a pass ufo i'm gonna
give you a pass but don't put don't type
[ __ ] scammers in here you're gonna
get the boot guys
you know how that works because people
think if i don't say anything
that i'm [ __ ] vouching for it because
people are stupid so don't start putting
[ __ ] scammers in here
or or you'll just be removed please
don't i don't want to remove anyone um
i you don't i don't just look for one
set of structure or one look for a mill
i
i choose a male based on what i want to
create and then i also choose its
partners based on what i want to
accomplish as well that's how it should
always be it should always be that way
with anyone making anything right so
the reason i did the banana was because
i wanted to
i love i i loved banana og growing up
and i've made a lot of cool [ __ ] with
this especially the platinum banana og
uh my boy hugo [ __ ] yourself that was
the name that he really used uh he
handed me off that cut and it was called
platinum banana when i got it
uh it wasn't my name for it
but um
yeah i always had a love affair with it
um organ kid was always super cool to me
too so i thought it would be a cool
project to just banana up everything and
see where it went um
i didn't have all the plants in the room
during the last platinum banana ogbx one
mil thing
and we actually ended up doing a
platinum banana og bx2 to the male so we
kept back crossing to the male as
opposed to back crossing to the female
which isn't done very often but that was
to see how we bred and he bred very
consistent um
there was a certain look that he had
i'm trying to think of where you can see
that look i know denali put up pictures
of
the
platinum alien orange cookies somewhere
and that has the distinct look almost
all those came out looking like what the
mail passes on
now with uh
the blue bonnet
my main intention was to find a male
that would bring the blueberry terps
not decrease resin production and not
decrease potency and as you guys as some
of you know that have worked a blueberry
a lot or grown a lot of blueberry um
that's not something you see very much
of you know like blueberry doesn't tend
to add potency blueberry itself isn't a
super resinous plant when you compare it
to modern day lines
so it was very fortunate that
the first male that i ended up using
from the blue bonnet did all of that and
then some um
his structure you can kind of see has
has a little bit of um
he can pass on a little bit of
foxtailing if if there's too much light
or too much heat
but most of it is like a nipple type bud
top and tons of resin production it's
it's mostly afghani as opposed to what
most people think of as blueberry sativa
stuff blueberry sativa stuff hey what's
up jax how you doing
um with the blueberry sativa stuff
uh so
i actually thought most of this time
that what i was looking for was gonna be
in the blueberry sativa stuff uh
blue moonshine blue velvet
moonshine rocket fuel all the other ones
that we were popping at the time but
what i ended up finding was pretty
amazing stuff in the afghani end so
yeah and that was that was because the
lone stars work he gets all the credit
for that [ __ ] absol another good dude
glad someone brought him up um
sub rob he's another badass you don't
get enough cred
smoking some white blood how you liking
it huey how you liking it
alien sour apple that you've had in the
ball yeah um
uh
yeah um
you wanted to hear me say what
let's see trip let's see what i miss
uh
how many blue bonnet did you pop to find
a male i popped the 10 pack that i got
didn't think i'd find anything in that
but during the blueberry hunt we popped
several hundred seeds
several hundred seeds were popped of
different blueberry lines flow blueberry
we had just gotten done with the rose
flow selections right before that
um
god
different lots of different blueberry
like from different people different f
gens and all that so yeah it's it's wild
it was a wild lucky lucky lucky pick and
the only reason i picked that male as
opposed to the others was because he
kept raising his hands up like even in
veg as he was growing up it you know
plants pray when they're happy this one
just was his families would be like this
almost 90 degrees just parallel to the
stem and i'd be like is that
[ __ ] raising his hands i bet
he's raising his hands for me and that's
uh that's really what i went with
something as easy as that because in the
end when you pick a male
unless you're unless you're
used to a line and really really
experience with that specific line it's
all a shotgun method
you're never going to know how a male
truly breeds until you rent off spring
so you have to start somewhere
my somewhere was
there
and you can see it in offspring
sometimes which is really cool um the
purple stripe stock so i thought he
would actually pass a lot more purple
traits than he does he can pass some
purple traits but it's not like a main
trait which is usually from the orbiting
purple tie end of blueberry
uh
usually bx does differ from land to line
it it just depends
um at what generation did you bx what
are you talking about for which
usually i only bx if i have a certain
line that i really like and i want to
use a male from that line and i don't
want to just reverse then i'll be x
but it's not my it's not a
i've done it a lot but it's not
it's not necessary all the time
unless you're trying to get work a clone
only line into mail form
like a perfect example would be bubba
above a bx to use as a male would be a
great breeding line or um
something else that's not available
in
seed form you know something like that i
don't know
put that mail and have to see some resin
pop out yeah um
resin popping out of males is one of
those things that's that's real
debatable on whether it's showing
intersex traits by having a lot of resin
or not um
still on the fence bring back face melt
and clockwork orange you know we did
face melt and that was really popular um
some jackass stole the name and stuck it
on his lines and marketed in high time
so i just never
never thought to redo it are you
familiar with heirloom varieties
from southern appalachia appalachia no
i'm not i'm not from that area and
unless you're from that area it's kind
of hard to break into it but that would
be cool to know more about
i did a lot of clockwork orange work um
we kept that line going
and and tried to keep it mostly in stock
but it was a little hard it's hard to
reverse
um
but i i ended up passing it on and i
think crybaby works with it now
so
there's only so much i can do with it
um it's kind of like an art piece like
if you if you have a certain character
you draw
and you you get stuck in that character
and it's hard to see outside that
character sometimes it's best to pass it
on to someone else to make something new
um
mention that you like cherry pie what do
you like about it when you did you get
actual cherry terps no
how did the high hit you um
cherry pie i got a lot of gas out of but
i liked how it hit me it gave me in a
similar anti-anxiety high that i got
from something like a blueberry but with
a little more potency a lot of people
have complaints about cherry pie because
of the intersex traits i didn't have a
lot of problems with that
um
but i don't like flood nitrogen and
flower which i think is one of the main
problems with that
um top three favorite blue bonnet
crosses oh that's a hard one
one's going to be punchy blooster just
because the turfs were so next level
like a like
like a slurpee syrup types
if you were if you were vaping it you
would actually taste blueberries with
sugar and
and all that in it it's it's very
exceptional in that way um
bubble berry was also an amazing breeder
and amazingly uniform um for being a a
simple
one-step hybrid i don't want to call an
f1 because it was not a it was you know
not a true f1 but um a one-step hybrid
it offered a lot of uniformity being
that they were both
somewhat afghani bases
um
a third god damn
the blooper skunk is still up there um
because it's a great super skunk regular
line um not necessarily because it was
great for letting the blue terps pass
through but because i love super skunk
so much it seemed to be one of my
favorites
yeah the resino g blue bonnet the the
kush cross to the blue bonnet is is
gnarly potent and it let some of the
berry come through which a lot of the
og's didn't necessarily the louis blue
bonnet also let those come through
what's up big red
well i thought bryn would be here to say
hi but she just walked out
run the bubble bonnet again really want
to dive into cherry aka i love that
cherry ak cut um i know csi's using it
in some of his stuff too
that water pipe's gonna be so loud it
always is um
yeah i can't wait to see what we do what
else we do with the cherry ak stuff
we miss you too red
what's up straight fox
no it's okay uh can you guys hear that i
think it's okay
are you getting more head band phenos in
that matchup
which one the banana headband yeah it's
it's it's sticking mainly to og and
headband styles like with the um
the 56 day cut
yeah dude who's responsible for bringing
the cherry a cake i think is what you're
asking i don't know man that cherry ak
cut i first found in san diego and i had
seen other cherry ak cuts that weren't
super resinous but were super purple i
know there was a cherry liqueur cut that
naboo used so he hates anybody calling
anything cherry aka even though his was
the cherry liqueur cut um i never never
got to run his but it did make some
amazing stuff in black russian
um
but yeah first time i saw it was in san
diego never saw it after i left san
diego and then it happened to come
across in a
two year long trade that it took for
this person to follow through and most
of what he sent me was incorrect but
the one thing he did send correct was
that
cherry aka cut and he had a friend in
san diego so he probably got in san
diego as well what's up with the rainbow
i did never use it because he was still
uh a small boat was still doing stuff
with it so i didn't
jump on it but yeah
and now i mean it's it's very much like
a really nice og kbb type so i've done a
lot of those so you know it was his
project and hopefully he'll bring it
back how many males would you test
before picking one for a project like
bluebonnet
what do you mean by test
we ran him out to see how he flowered
out for his general structure before we
used him
um
but as far as hitting a line first you
hit everything with it you see if it
works you run the progeny and if it all
sucks on the next on to the next you
know that's how it always works um
usually if if i don't find something i
like in the first two males then i'm not
gonna i'm not gonna keep pursuing it
because it's a lot of lost money in that
case
yeah that's with a project like
bluebonnet literally that was all luck
um and all work from lone star it had
very little to do with me or anything i
did special i can't take much credit for
it that was already a worked blue line
from someone and rest in peace lone star
um you can still find some of lone star
stuff as well from aka texas kid i do
believe he has some
um
i don't know who else is putting out
yeah
[Music]
that was coo
that was a cool line
lone star was putting it out at the same
time i was putting out my riot berry so
i didn't give it a chance back then
because i was a [ __ ] and i kind of
thought like i had the best [ __ ] ever
the best blueberry ever so i don't need
to see anybody else's blueberries but
you know i could have uh done some magic
[ __ ] just crossing right very to it back
then if they were both around at the
same time
no i haven't pharo i haven't at all
what you got what you got straight
what you what you holding on
see what else i wanted to touch on too
run them run them and use them
what size container do you typically use
tofino hunt
look through for large numbers of seeds
you know usually if i'm looking through
large numbers of seeds i don't go over
half gallon and i pop it
bam like that well [ __ ] yesterday thank
you
thank you
what's your most flavorful available
with a powerful effect now
powerful is subjective because there are
certain things
that like um
urkel for example will hit me super hard
because my brain chemistry whereas other
people like think it's one of the
weakest strains on earth you know um
that's subjective
let's see
flavorful
right now uh even the blue resin super
flavorful um
some of the um banana og stuff like the
sour apple platinum banana og is really
flavorful too i know that that's still i
think available
um
banana thai was super flavorful
there's so much that i did in the blue
bonnet stuff that i'd love to list like
the the bubble berry v2
was super flavorful almost anything with
the blue bonnet mail was super flavorful
so if you have a specific like you want
something gassy with berry the way you
do it
brindies it was very flavorful skittles
is good [ __ ]
for flavor
um
cherry berry cherry berry's super
flavorful and i think that's from some
of the trapinoline in it that
trapinoline makes everything more
flavorful if you cross it out outcross
it did you cross the bonnet with any of
your strawberry stuff i did not but
hopefully in the near future we can do
some of that i'm pretty excited about
that
you're going to be re-releasing any
bonnet stuff
i haven't needed to re-release much
because i have all of it
and i mean there's some stuff that sold
out and some of those i plan on
um but we'll see we'll see
what freebies came with the pink and
blue i don't know
i don't know
so i hit black triangle with two sky
cuddler males also made a forest guy
chloe handing out
i don't know who you are but that's cool
nice to meet you are you going to be
okay so i answered that one
next big sea dropping project next big
sea drop is going to be the um
northern lights work northern lights
works coming up and that's going to be
open pollination of the hawaiian lights
and the nl5 it's
all being documented um
if you're part of the patreon you'll be
able to see that and
follow csi humble you can see some of
his um
todd says try chrome oh yes
try chrome
um
when
well
they still need to be
cloned and flipped so it's no we don't
really rush it you know um not in a rush
to get anything to market like that even
though probably with the seed market now
we should be rushing to do everything
but that's not how you make good [ __ ]
also
and this is for real
like everybody in the in our in our
industry people making seeds what not
pay really close attention to to your
mental health during this time and
that's coming from someone who has all
you know i'm a [ __ ]
[ __ ] show when it comes to mental stuff
but
everyone needs to be taking care of each
other um
it's gonna be tough times coming up
for all of us in the cannabis industry
and and and all you with passion take
care of each other
it's it's gonna be very [ __ ] scary
and hard
um we've all kind of waited for that
ball to drop from
um
corporate [ __ ]
so it's going to take extra work extra
dedication
to make it through this
uh you know
why do you think everything is going
retro with the nl5 it was because at the
time uh seattle greg sent seeds to me
his son
and todd
and some people rushed to pop like five
seats and
do something special with that so
yeah it just happened to be the timing
on when todd passed him out
dog man what's up brother how's the
how's the uh the toy world going is it
is it is it crashing to like most the
other other [ __ ] in the in the us
thanks for the kind words pharaoh what's
up jb
so last time i let you guys see some
guitar stuff and because [ __ ] i'm a
man and men like show-and-tell i'm gonna
do that [ __ ] again
um show off some of my other pretty ones
you guys already saw the blueberry
gibson
or the the les paul traditional
so i thought i'd show off a different
one this time
i guess i don't need my [ __ ] computer
since we're not doing any of that [ __ ]
right now right
no youtube
i've seen the updated oh yeah the
hawaiian lights are looking good along
with the nl5 hawaiian lights is the bat
cross of so nl5 is um steve murphy
afghani times hawaiian right so the
hawaiian lights
is about cross to the hawaiian in
northern lights
toys are going wacky resin supply chain
as [ __ ] yeah
prices went way up though oh that's good
to know i need to sell some of my [ __ ]
then
so this
is a very special model i'm a big fan of
purple
and this is a purple
gibson les paul this was only uh
released in the robot form but as you
can see i don't have the robot
on it anymore
i don't know
i thought about putting them on just for
shits and gigs but the robot the robot
[ __ ] sucked which is this button right
here that's how you tuned it it was
supposed to auto tune and all this [ __ ]
but it really didn't do a great job of
it
but yeah this one when i got it it was
on sale
um on guitar center back in the day and
i've always wanted a purple les paul
that was a gibson and i finally found it
yeah purple's my favorite color too
yeah the robo self tuners were kind of
[ __ ] whack i didn't really love those
ones but this is one of my babies this
is my first gibson i ever owned
um i have another one that i'm
rebuilding before i can show it but it's
a uh
what is that one it was a les paul
special
so it looks
uh a double cut les paul special so it
looks more like a
les paul jr kind of but it has two
humbuckers
so yeah
and then i'll show you my other baby the
other one was a special gift from a
friend
no no
my other was a special gift from a
friend
ah damn it's not closing right
stupid [ __ ] cases
skbs i like my gibson cases better okay
you have a junior robo-tuner growers
yeah these are grovers on this one um
yeah i want a real les paul jr
eventually from the
50s or 60s but you know
yeah not anytime soon
um
but this one is a real special one
so when i was given this guitar
i i had uh
i had i had stopped playing
i didn't really ever play at that time
and a friend
and i just gone through some
emotional [ __ ] so a friend
wanted me to start playing guitar again
and sent me
this beautiful american jazz master from
the custom shop
it isn't marked custom shop but
this person worked dirt farmer worked at
the custom shop
at the time and um yeah it's a beautiful
beautiful jazz master with some
beautiful p90s
yeah this is one of my
favorite playing guitars especially for
surf [ __ ] or even
reggae it holds a [ __ ] tune like
nothing else
but yeah i also have a few um i have a
jaguar
uh or jaguar
um
a jack stain that we're working on a
mustang that we're working on um
a few telecasters there's one specific
telecast it's called an fmt that's
really beautiful and has humbuckers but
it's like a flame to maple and it's
actually pretty cheap when they sold it
so if you guys can still get a hold of
an fmt cheap they're so [ __ ] worth it
um when i got it i bought the body by
itself and
uh picked up
the pickups and everything else
separately
but yeah no i don't have any seven or
eight strings i can barely play the
[ __ ] things i don't need that
many strings i also have a [ __ ]
really cool four string um
it's a telecaster what is it tenor
telecaster i think that shit's [ __ ]
awesome i i'd be happy with four strings
that's all i need i don't play no
[ __ ] metal solos
you don't need no [ __ ]
extra strings
all that [ __ ]
anyway
huh
okay be safe
yeah this this one
this one was a
it was just special because of of
the gift factor of it someone went way
out of their way to give me this
beautiful nice very expensive
custom shop jazz master
um it was originally for blink 182 or
and it was either angels and airway i
think it was blink had ordered it and
they're just so rich they didn't have to
go pick it up and we're like [ __ ] it we
don't need that guitar so
went to matt
anyway
props to dirt or dirt farmer um
one of the nicest things anybody's ever
done for me it really was
okay let me put this back
i gotta shut this off because this is
[ __ ] cool
a really badass old mod [ __ ]
guitar strap that's from couch
couch guitar straps with the [ __ ]
[ __ ] i own so many of those just because
the the quality
i've got strap locks on that [ __ ]
so break things because i like to break
things
anyway
anyway so there was one funny event that
happened today that i wasn't going to be
able to share because you know a lot of
people are on youtube and they won't be
able to see this if they're just on
youtube
but
now that i'm just i'm doing this let's
see if we can put it on
i guess at the
mj biz con
aka the chad con
um
some people got in a fight
some security guards started whooping
ass i don't know the story behind it
hopefully one of you got it so you could
tell me because that [ __ ] was funny as
[ __ ]
but i i do have the video
oh i thought i put the
other one away i'll show this one real
quick too for those that didn't see it
the first time
this is the sg blueberry burst um modern
so it's got like [ __ ] clear
uh
i think some of these pop yeah it's got
modern
modern ways to it different neck
yeah
i love this guitar too it's really fast
to play
um you know if i sang i'd probably play
for you guys but i don't so it'll look
dumb me sitting here and playing guitar
like a [ __ ] 15 year old but i will
show it off i will show it off
and i suck i mean i can play punk and
reggae and that's about it
60s reggae not
not like bob later bob [ __ ] steel
drum reggae anyway back to the video let
me find this
yeah no that security guard was an
absolute [ __ ] for doing that i think
it's let's see
this one
[Music]
look at that throwing them slow-ass
punches
dude i'll go through all my pickups and
[ __ ] mainline i'll do all that [ __ ] i've
got a lot of pickups and stuff i haven't
even put into the cars
i have a beautiful black beauty episode
then he starts [ __ ] beating this
dude's ass
the funny thing was this dude on the
ground that this guy is is hitting for
no reason um right before he got stuck
in the face he's like oh knock this cool
out and then got punched on the ground
so yeah
i don't know i'll play it one more time
look at this slow punch
oh you totally missed
this guy's just clinching up
trying to hip top that big old dude just
trying to hip thoughts in
just throws him and then he starts
walking this way
that dude's like stop
knock your ass out boom
on the ground so this is this is the
chad con
yeah i like how that lady yells
the security's beating the dude's hands
anyway
um there was a fight earlier mj biz kind
of cat fight
i thought it was [ __ ] funny as [ __ ]
play it again i just played it twice
yeah you can have to uh
i would rewind the show and watch it
when i put it up on youtube or leave it
up on instagram
first guys tony vasquez who does he work
for do you know who are these people
and that right there if you guys don't
use your money right
that is the industry
that is gonna be what's left of this
[ __ ] industry
dumbass [ __ ] like that
who have no business in our [ __ ]
industry and not because they fight i
mean whatever people are going to beat
each other's ass but those are guys with
some [ __ ] chads yeah you would have
been out real quick
i don't fight i'm not like that [ __ ]
these people are crazy
so what do you guys say there's only 97
people here i don't know if it's worth
doing a p91 auction
um
there's only a few packs of these left
of the originals
i don't know if it's worth doing it
maybe i'll do something else though that
isn't as expensive or i wouldn't be so
bummed if it doesn't go for a shitload
of money what do you guys say
um
what do you guys say auction time or not
you guys you guys decide
you want to auction off the parrot let's
auction off the parrot
first big gets her yep
first big gets a parrot oh three oh look
i have some banana split blade here
someone someone just showed a picture of
these let me see if i can find it let me
see if i can find the banana split blade
picture here from modern day milk i
believe it was had some pictures of her
it was looking pretty cool let's see
i need to put those up
somewhere sometime
mm-hmm
[Music]
damn it i don't think i
saved him i should have
oh yeah maybe these are them
not i wish i could throw easily show all
three
let's see
let's see let me find you some more
pictures
choose a different asset there we go
got that
now these are all sold out everywhere
they've been sold out for a long time
but
i did have some packs that i kept back i
don't know if this is a good picture now
it's not a great picture but you get an
idea you get an idea it's uh there's a
lot of strawberry in it there's a lot of
banana and because a lot of people don't
know
bubble gum smells are made up of
strawberry and banana you can actually
get really bubble gummy smelling stuff
this is in our old um
our old packs the brass knuckle packs
um i haven't i haven't used these in a
while
okay
so
you guys want it yeah maybe i won't do
that so there's only one pack of those
left
um
do you guys want a bonnet or do you guys
want to do
a banana og wine
plant banana og or a bonnet line you
guys choose
i'll just whatever you guys choose we'll
do it
you want to do 300 on you want to do the
p91 you can do it so starting 300 on p91
and then we'll just wait like
two minutes after the last bid then that
gives everyone plenty of time to do it
so this is p91 s1 for those of you who
don't know what p91 is p91 is an old uh
cut from san diego before og kush was
big before
you know bubba was down there floating
hard p91 was the [ __ ] p91 hogg's breath
cat piss
bull rider were all flowing around um
godziki
uh
rob can name some more he's a [ __ ]
the san diego king
so this is the p91s one
and um
lost this cut shortly after this i gave
it to canorado and i think uh colli
grown i don't know what if they ever did
anything with it it was in such bad
shape when i got it and the reason the
guy gave it to me because he didn't
think he could save it
so yeah
p91 s1 300
let me go uh
mark that
419ers
pin comment
hey yeah oh betsy's another great one
uh sister of bull rider oh betsy
but this is the special the special san
diego one and and if you miss out on
this my homie bittersweet's gonna be
making some more i believe of the either
the s2s or even take it to s3 and his
s2s have been phenomenal phenomenal if i
was going to pass anyone this line to
work like that it would be him and i'm
super stoked he took it on super stoked
um
since this is a 300 i'm gonna throw in
something special extra
and some special let's do something
see
i thought i saw
something in here
it would make a good extra
we've been talking about cherry berry
tonight let's throw in cherry berry on
the extra
p91 again is an old
an old cut from san diego i would say
it's a super scout type but i think
maybe some silver pearl in it possibly
um i know some of the other san diego
dudes think that that's a definite
possibility and
i mean a super silver pearl is uh
phenomenal
a pika p91 i don't know if i have any on
the phone right now so it really
wouldn't do any good let me take this
pic off though so people don't think
that's what i'm showing there we go
uh so i'm going to throw in cherry berry
with this p91 and it looks like 419ers
are probably going to get it for 300.
we go
with the cherry berry
we're not throwing something else for
him too
because that's how we do
a bunch of cherry perry backs in here
um
blue garrick let's throw in the louie
13 og
are you bidding that local or are you
just
asking i don't want to pin your comment
if you're not bidding it
i'll throw in the the louis the 13th
blue bonnet as well for him
or whoever wins smoked herb what's up
buddy
king of irene
maybe i'll throw in some um colorado
cough across the platinum banana oh gee
i'm gonna do that
is that something you guys are into
i don't know
i'll wait on that i don't think anybody
wants any coffee stuff in one nl five
eight let me get a [ __ ]
nl5 haze
okay 366 66 matt b man what do you think
should i throw in some some cough
platinum banana og is that something
you'd run 4019ers you get an opinion too
afghani or skunky [ __ ] in there i do
have bloopers i have a big breeder's
pack of blooper skunk 100 seed pack matt
beaming it's ready on
yeah the p is it's just one of those
things if he never got pumped anywhere
he never he never got hyped outside of
san diego or so
it and it died out so hard
you know that it just never really got
it's just desserts outside of outside of
the crew
um
og kush really really killed
that
you got three packs of bloopers yeah i'm
not gonna put the bloopers gunk in
um but i do have the blue garrig
which is the louis xiii blue bonnet
um
cherry berry yeah the punchy's been sold
out for a while and i didn't really ever
sell that i used it to give away with
some [ __ ] for stupid ass bdsc so it was
all pretty much wasted and then he
popped a shitload of them never saw any
of those
um
way to hold good to your word isaac
[ __ ] cops [ __ ]
um
yeah
that's how it goes dude
don't trust people especially in this
industry people suck
the lineage on blooper skunk is uh
diesel crossed a blue bonnet and diesel
is the mass super s1 now super v2 tech
for being super technical
but it was the the only only mass super
that people saw outside of the va super
which was a different cut
obviously a different cut
ooh just found some strawberry roadkill
too it goes up maybe i'll throw in a
pack of those that's the uh uh what was
that
east coast sour diesel
what's the strawberry roadkill
was that the strawberry switchblade on
afghani or was that the east coast of z
diesel strawberry cream
i think that was more strawberry easter
salad diesel strawberry cream across the
blue bun i do have that in there
i think matt beeman's going to win this
i haven't really been counting but let
me see
if you get if you if you want a bid get
it in
because uh we're going to end it right
there if not
nazar's doing good nacho's doing good i
think we're gonna um maybe do something
with bodhi very soon
um the three of us which would be i mean
we've been waiting for
a long time
a long time for a good body episode
brentos freshmaker at 400
clock starts again is cult classic no
cult classic doesn't even grow but i
don't know i'm not going to be too mean
on marcus i kind of like marcus but i i
don't know if he's grown in the past few
years and i know other people were
making the seeds for a while
um
he's a trip dude's a trip
dude is a trip that's all i'm going to
say i shouldn't even comment on that
[ __ ] because he's a trip
god bless him
since farmer ho burnt you on the diesel
cut you like to get my hands on some
yeah right
[ __ ] farmer ho
he thinks he knows some [ __ ] about some
[ __ ] little dachshund [ __ ]
i think body and burner got something no
they i mean i don't i don't want to say
no they don't i highly doubt it what's
up big worm
i highly doubt that
me i'm
hey things are weird in the community
right now so if he wants to work with
burner i ain't gonna [ __ ] on him but
he's been around so long he can do what
the [ __ ] you want and i'd [ __ ] have
his back
i would have his back on anything
because that's my boy
so we're at 420.
hold on
hold on someone had to do it
someone had to do it
all right um we're at 440 brentos
freshmaker
since it's at 4 40 i'm gonna put
something else in
let's see what do i put in
for the people that are bidding to be
enticed how about some ryeberry v4 so
this is going to be the um
what's it called the mob cut across the
blue bonnet which is just this is just
straight up blueberry straight up
[ __ ] blueberry um
this and the blueberry ix which was a dj
short blueberry um
yeah those those are the two tops for if
you just want a pure blueberry line a
breeding blueberry line uh nothing else
but blueberry
and some endo perps actually is in there
too
matt beeman ain't giving up so right now
we have the
the mob blue bonnet
cherry berry which is the cherry gate
cable bonnet
blue garrett louis blue bonnet louie
13th og blue bonnet which is one of the
og's that lets the berry come through so
if you want a really super berry og it's
phenomenal and then the p91s ones one of
the last packs of those in existence
most people pop that [ __ ]
matt beaming at 466. thank you for
keeping the number pure
anybody else have any questions while
we're doing this [ __ ]
counting down the minutes
see if matt beeman's gonna get it
local botanist comes in at 470. he's
getting nickel and dime here
he's win a victory
thanks for being local
for brentos
if it gets to five i'll throw in some
else something else
all kinds of weird [ __ ] in here that i
didn't remember i had i thought there
was a uh
breeders pack of the trinity bonnet in
here the 50 pack
cookie berry v3 too
let's see what we have 54 minutes
this one
is okay i'll do it again
right berry v4 which is the mother of
berry blue bonnet
cherry berry cherry aka blue bonnet
luio g blue bonnet 3 13 og
lube on it and the p91 s1 one of the
very last packs of that one right now
we're at 480. brentos is ruling the
ruling the game
ruling that [ __ ] gang
so i'm gonna count down 30 seconds if
you have if you have a bid get it in if
not we're going to call it
oh local comes in at 500.
so now i got to throw some melts in
cookie berry v3
so this one's you know what let's not do
a cookies one this
that's tuesday i'm gonna throw in the
trinity blue bonnet so this is the
trinity cut that goes around now is
trinity it's not been verified but
pretty much everybody says that
it's the one but you know i'm just i
like to be very oh [ __ ]
let's see i like to be very specific so
unless it's been verified by the actual
um
old trinity trinity crew at oregon then
i'm not gonna say it's it and half of
them think it's it and half of them
don't
yeah p91 was special
it's the pink comment
so we have the the 50 pack this is five
packs
of the trinity blue bonnet and not a lot
of those are out there
along with the riot berry v4
which is the mother of berry blue bonnet
mother of berry um is probably mendo
perps blueberry
cross to blue bonnet so you're getting
basically a blueberry bx with mendo
perps bringing in a lot of perps with it
and for those who are chasing skunk
mento perps is one of those places you
can find skunky terps a lot of people
don't know that
you can find them in urcol you can find
them in
in men of perps you can find them in
good old afghanis
but we got the cherry ak blue bonnet as
well
louis the 13th og blue bonnet
trinity crossed a blue bonnet trent tren
as according to my buddy uh big worm
that's a nickname he gave it and that's
a nickname i keep with it the trend
trend p91 s1 which is the the grand
prize
see where we're at 57
give it till um
58 minutes on the on the button
so yeah
the mendo s ones that's where you're
gonna find that's where you if you run
enough of those you will find the skunky
ones um they're gonna be some of the
ugliest because that tends to happen
even with the diesel and the super
skunks and stuff like that the more
skunky they are usually the uglier they
are
um and the more prone to herm they are
but if you want those terps or thiols i
should say that's how you got to go
if you want those cannabinoids i think
that's the proper term
if you're a real botanist but i'm i'm
not i just play one on tv
um
yeah
outdoor urkel is really scary dude urkel
urkel and like um i lonesome he did uh
um
dog waltz the poodle nuts cut that thing
um will you do
what's pp will i do a pee pee
for canada
i mean yeah i don't care where you're at
if you're in canada and you can pay then
yes
absolutely
um
but yeah yeah the poodle nuts cut you if
you when you you take cuts of that thing
it would be skunk smells everywhere it
is so skunky in flower it changes a lot
oh paypal
um
we'll talk we'll talk yeah yeah if
you're in canada we can work something
out
um
let's see
why are all skunky ones all
knobby and leafy with dog tongues
because that's what scooper super skunk
looks like
brento's freshmaker just came in i was
about to call it
getting your uh
getting your last bids
do you have success using s-ones as
mothers absolutely absolutely
is herming and potency relation just
expressions of hyper vigor or more
likely to will to live uh hermaphroditic
expressions could be all kinds of things
555 for local botanists
the hermaphroditic expression could be
all kinds of things depends on the line
as far as the super skunk goes it just
seems to be a what we call link trait um
link trait to the files for whatever
that thiallic stuff it tends to be quick
to herm indoors it seems to do well
outdoor
but not a lot of people want to be
growing skunky stuff outdoor for many
reasons
onycd and urkel would be a good
combination to bring some of that stuff
out
i found that like diesel and sours
combined can also complement each other
really well to bring that out
there's buster i've been that's someone
i didn't remember earlier to to list but
boston roots has been doing some amazing
stuff for quite a while and i'm always
really impressed by his stuff
i'm always liking his pictures and
drooling
5.75 you guys can make me have more [ __ ]
to this
let's do bitter chocolate
now let's do
let's do
pacific northwest hash plant
crustal blue bonnet so the pnw hash
plant across the blue bonnet not a lot
of these have been out not a lot of
people have seen these
um traditional old hatch plant maybe
maybe the old original hash plant that
made the scentsy hash plant line um
crossed a blue bonnet
yeah
575 gonna call it soon
yeah this is this is fun i haven't had a
good one pop off soon and i don't mind
adding in all the packs because it's you
know what the [ __ ] dude money's tight
for everyone right now i might as well
make it worth it for everyone right
get your bids in anybody else
where's 6105.
marty according denali reminded me this
is marty which is why i called it martin
short because you know tj short marty
martin short
sue me no don't
just kidding allegedly
so we're going to call it
30 seconds once this hit 62 on my screen
i'm calling it
oh there's a lot people are bitten on a
lot it starts with the p91 s1
and stash
at 580. anybody does it pay
anybody that doesn't pay it'll go to the
next bid or down so um
people watch on your stuff guys
keep a watch let me start taking some
screenshots so i remember who bid what
right under that one's that one and
right under that is
just me
because i've had people come in here and
bid last minute and just do it just to
ruin options
so
brentos is back in at 590.
what's up michigan thc how you doing
dude long time no see
now i can wave at people look at that
dude
can of pot i never forget you i'll never
forget you
all right gonna call it brentos
i think i think i think uh old bruntos
is going to get this one
calling it
boom
is g13 and g13 hash plant the same
cultivar no one is a hybrid of the other
g13 doesn't exist brentos you are the
winner
boom
brentos gets
pnw hash plant costa blue bonnet
cherry a cave blue bonnet
louis xiii og blue bonnet
rye berry v4 which is the mother of
berry blue bonnet we got a 50 pack of
the trinity blue bonnet and of course
p91 s1 is one of the last packs of these
uh i hope you enjoy it dude um hit me up
after after the live feed and we'll
square up
g13 is g13 yeah so g13 died a while ago
a long while ago so if you see if you
see g13 pure ever across to anything
other than hash plant haze
um
nl2
skunk one
i think there's one more that i'm
forgetting i always forget it um
hash plant
haze
nl2 skunk one
i think that's it i think that's it
there might be one more but if you see
it cross to anything other
of those
anything other than those four
it's not real
it didn't happen
88 don't exist right so
it shouldn't exist there was no 1988 g13
hash plan but there is an old pack that
swampy had the indian guy made his name
off of that was a
g13 hash plan
what's it do with the cut joe holds it
you know it's it's up in the air but as
far as anybody knew it was killed jill
might have it i know that there are
people interested in it it would be nice
to know but other than that um
until we're sure we don't really we
can't really say
it is not
uh indian guy stuff el tata go it is
swampy stuff swampy past indian guy was
his friend india guy was responsible for
passing it to a very few people
um
yeah but it was swampy stuff
but you know when people die and other
people pass it around people's names get
stuck with it
make sure i took a screenshot of that
for brentos thank you brentos and
everyone else who bid
um
yeah thank you
uh gruesome g13 skunk from shanti yeah
back in the day you know what's funny is
shanti also sells g13 widow and this is
one of our big like
points of contention was on his forum i
was like how the [ __ ] did you get a g13
widow g13 was dead by that time
and i ended up getting banned from the
forum for a while for asking that
question
the answer was that it's really g13
skunk one
crossed a white widow
so yeah
i mean you know people are going to sell
short names they're going to do all
kinds of stuff not everybody's a [ __ ]
nerd like me and my boys are
when it comes to names he was swampy
that's way before my time yeah even
indian guys before my time yes swampy
was just another dude on overgrow and
cannabis world and he he made uh the
free leonard which is the g13 hash plant
butterscotch hawaiian and he was the one
who fgend um the g13 hash plan and then
indian guy gave it out to some people
some more people fgend it um yeah
it's a very nice line the stuff buddy
did with it was probably my favorite by
far
by far the g13 hash plan stuff but he
did was [ __ ] phenomenal he had a he
had a killer male i think that he called
deadly g or that might have been the
female i think it was the male
he'll have to correct me if i'm wrong
but yeah he did some phenomenal [ __ ]
with it what's your testing protocol how
many testers do you run of a new release
it just depends um usually i'll run 10
to 20 whatever someone's gonna uh
whatever a normal person would pack or
pop from a pack is what i'll run but
i'll run a lot of different strains
because i make a lot so we'll run
through that um i mostly do all the
testing in-house with the blue bonnet
stuff i did in-house and out of the
house so a lot of other people were
testing it along
along the same time um
but usually most of the years it's been
me testing it myself because there's
nothing more
uh important than a breeder knowing what
he's got in front of him because you
really don't know what kind of melt you
have unless you're doing it yourself
uh you too tent flow freeland is still
around so
yes and no i know that for a while bc
blood depot ripped off the strain and
called it the big for a while but they
never sell the same thing twice as the
same strain so who knows
um butterscotch hawaiian still around
and um
and g13 hash plants still around so i i
would imagine that it could be remade
not the same obviously as uh swampy
intended
but it could be
made to be something similar at least
the butterscotch hawaiian seems to be
very consistent for reading
butterscotchy terps
yeah when making seeds is a good idea to
start a male into flower a week or two
before the donor plants flower
when i'm doing regular seeds i'll fly
them at the same time if i'm reversing
seeds that's a big difference if i'm
reversing i'll usually stagger some at
uh one week before
trigger for the rest some i'll do two
weeks a trigger for the rest so i'll do
three
uh in the case of hemp i learned at
least with the hemp lines i was working
you trigger them at the same time it
just instantly reverses so well
and so fast that you don't have to
stagger the trigger
he had a couple miles i recall correctly
one was a little too dominant the ones
he had very the first was deadly g there
you go there you go
never mind your wife is snoring
do you stress test before breeding um i
don't do a lot of stress testing because
i think that people should grow weed
right
you know but if something is showing any
kind of hermaphroditic traits in a
normally good grown room then there's a
[ __ ] problem you know you just don't
use it
orange crush oh the orange dreams are so
old hopefully you kept them in a fridge
that's a really old line how old was the
orange crust i think he said oh my god
that whole line was um 2007
2006 right in there so it's a really old
line it's a lean forward i want to see
something
get a red toupee
notice your femmes being better resin
producers but generally lower yields i
don't i don't notice anything consistent
like that um
yeah it's just [ __ ] in [ __ ] out i always
say that like it whether it's with uh
red seeds femme seeds hash
the more better quality parents have
better quality results and and
feminization doesn't make things be any
more hermaphroditic it doesn't make any
things be more
stretchy or anything like that it just
it's it just everything is very
dependent on what you choose
specifically
skittles is apparently what grape
grapefruit no people say it's a green
sherb s1 um
joe what was it jodrey sherb s1 i think
maybe i think that's what the the
consensus is what would you recommend
for your cancer treatment symptoms
something that is more on the indica
side that will help you with your
appetite so
um
what people normally consider
sativas help my appetite but if if you
think that uh afghanistan everybody has
a different brain chemistry if afghanis
are what help your um
you know whatever is going on with your
nausea and your in your appetite um
stuff like my pacific northwest hash
plant bluebonnet does great the white
blue bonnet
the silver pearl blue bonnet would
probably do the nausea thing too i know
silver pearl helped brain a lot and
that's a that is a hearty strong indica
uh do you remember throw growing the
orange crush was that across a
california orange yes it was a it was an
old cut of cali orange across the
blueberry and it was phenomenal it's my
favorite orange strain ever
yeah it would have probably been the
same one that you would have seen alt
ago there was there was a main orange
crush going around a cut
ncga used it a bit
i know jojo used it a bit we had it down
to san diego and james hogg used it a
bit um
yeah
[ __ ] was phenomenal
if you're breeding for a thc cbd variety
or thcg variety would you use a hint
male or female
okay let me think in my head if i of a
specific project
i if i was breeding for
more cbd than thc i would probably
first start with the female as the hemp
and and uh a strong thc
uh plant is the male
and
see how that went but it's not there's
no certain specific surefire way to do
that it genetics depend on it's so plant
specific
there's no surefire way but that's how i
would start it
dreamsicle i believe that was the name
for um orange creamsicle was the orange
dream sandstorm that we made back in the
day when we crossed that orange
dreamline to sandstorm it was called
orange dreamsicle
yeah i'm a total nerd on names when it
comes to to names i you know and in the
history of lines and provenance and
getting sourcing stuff from actual
breeders and then checking to see if
that breeder even knows what the [ __ ]
they're talking about checking to see if
they understood pollen contamination or
pollen control i mean and that affects
all of us that affects
all of us
i don't care who you are
paul and control is a damn
[ __ ]
and um if you're not super careful it
will affect you so
yeah
yeah that's that's important to know how
was it made what was it made in was it a
tank did you clean your tent between
x y and z you know um that's my biggest
warning on the on the mccormick stuff
the northern lights stuff is that
what the [ __ ] was that
i thought you just [ __ ] shocked
yourself
good lord
woman's playing with a stun gun over
there
well it's a flashlight and if you push
it the wrong direction
i don't think she did that just to [ __ ]
with me
yeah sure you did that [ __ ] to [ __ ] with
me no i didn't
she wanted to jumpstart my heart
i'm fat i can't have you do that [ __ ]
jesus christ
let's see
we just indicate podcasts have been a
gold mine well good dude i'm glad you
enjoy them we're gonna um
we're gonna be
doing some more very very soon expect
more from breeder syndicate we already
have some in the can and hopefully
there's a lot going on like with with
trying to get the right side up the
spray site going and all that stuff so
keep posted we'll have that edited soon
um we interviewed legend seed company uh
red
and chimera and it was it was one of my
favorite interviews um both of those
guys uh chimera
add him to the list two of amazing
[ __ ] breeders that have done amazing
[ __ ] um he's he's one of the biggest
wealth of knowledge that that i've ever
met when it comes to science when it
comes to old lines he's as much of a
dork as i am on this stuff so
and read it red as well red's been there
done that when it comes to the bc stuff
and um it was an absolute [ __ ] honor
it to interview those two dudes and i
know they've been waiting for it so i'm
excited to bring it all to you because
it was really that [ __ ] good
what do we got what can you tell me
about bubble gum that secret matha used
and serious eats bubble gum is different
i see the indians
indiana being more indica but sirius
says their bubblegum is more sativa so i
believe adam dunn tried to go over that
whole thing we were going to do a
bubblegum show with all the bubblegum
guys but
um
my friend never got back to me on it
that was going to set it up so i don't
know if we'll ever get to it
the indiana bubblegum cut that's over
here is from sirius seeds
it was a selection from the year that
serious seeds won the cup
with that said there was
i know a lot of people had a lot of
there was a lot of phenos in it
and people didn't always find some
amazing stuff in it that was super
bubble gummy but that cut is phenomenal
for bubble gum however it's not super
bubblegum tasting and i think that
personally i think you need to add in
some terpenoline so if if any of you
guys see csi's durbin cross to the
indiana bubblegum grab it
grab it yeah i heard him say it comes
from illinois adam [ __ ] dumb it
didn't even come from him it came from
someone else so i don't know what the
[ __ ] he's talking about um on one of the
shows he had all the guys on and he
couldn't [ __ ] that illinois stuff so
um
is what it is you guys a douchebag but
you know whatever sells for him god
bless him for doing that
um
yeah i it would be cool to have like
the bubble gum guys i'll sit down and
and we can we can talk to him and really
put the story together in one place that
people can trust because they know how
much of a stickler we all for that [ __ ]
but heavy terpenelline with bubblegum
will give you bubblegum flavors that's
what happened with the um scentsy star
95 centistar bubblegum fino
uh that came out of superstar from delta
nine labs which was
what ed bohr got as testers from
um luke or i'm sorry from simon early on
that was he got that from simon early on
he took it to more sativa direction and
in there was the the i used to call it
menthol bubble gum but it really it's
it's it's our penalty bubble gum and it
just made everything taste super pink
bubble gummy
um
yeah so turpinelli helps carry some
flavors that's why a lot of people like
to trademark chad with the terpinoline
and blueberry
um
bogs was the real deal yeah
i don't know what bob used i do not i
mean the the
the um sour bubble was a sour diesel
uh bubba
which is not bubble gum but yeah what
strain have you made that has very
citrusy terps and hash
oh i did a lot of orange stuff over the
years i haven't really been [ __ ] with
orange lately
um
any of the orange oh there was there
wasn't orange in the blue bonnet stuff
that did have citrusy chirps but also
had og type chirps
so it really took in a different
direction i'm not a big fan of
tangy stuff
for um
i'm not a big fan of tangy stuff for any
orange chips because to me it also
smells like
like
spaghetti sauce i don't know i'm [ __ ]
weird
hog's breath is still around um
it had nothing to do with th seeds at
all he never had hogs breath or the real
hob's breath that was our old crew
um it is still around uh jimbo passed it
to his sister the cut after after he
passed the sister and and brother-in-law
got it
and they've passed it to a few people um
it was tightly held in a crew for a long
time and we did not pass it uh per for
jim's recommendations
but now like
some other people have it like mad
farter has it
um
brandon rush has nothing to do with
anything stop plant based you're [ __ ]
around you're [ __ ] around with that
[ __ ] that dude has nothing to do with
anything a motherfucker's a toothless
tweaker ain't nobody trusts that
[ __ ] and he's a little kid he's
a little kid he's a toothless tweaker
why does it think he had anything to do
with anything i can't believe people
would even buy that
um yeah the original hogs is still down
there
his bubble was a uh yeah i don't know
enough about bob's bubble gum that he
used i do know the one in sour bubble
was a bubba you trolling my ass
uh is the wrinkle cut agent orange a
gunner i never had a wrinkle cut of
agent orange um
i did have one of clockwork orange which
was nothing related to agent orange and
it is a goner it hasn't gone it's been
gone for a long time
i used to get so mad when people would
call it agent orange because i
[ __ ] couldn't [ __ ] stand that [ __ ]
man i couldn't stand sub so i was like
oh not agent orange don't call it that
it's not even an orange smelling strain
it was back when we used to call it uh
call strains by like their hair color
and [ __ ] you know like it was an orange
haired strain um
yeah
and it was like it was orange hair
strain and it was very golden when it
cured so it just really made sense it
was super potent people were like
talking about how their legs would go
numb when they smoked it um so i thought
that's kind of ultra violent right
is mad farter's urkel really special as
people have made it sound um
mad farter has nothing to do with urkel
he never has he's a [ __ ] fresno dork
he's always been a fresno dork um
urkel's from up and i want to say
laytonville
um
he may have the same cut that all of us
have had over all the years i mean urkel
was in everybody's garden for a long
time he may have that cut i'm not saying
his cut's fake but yeah [ __ ] had
nothing to do with it so um it's a good
cut some of us love irkle i do not like
herkle to smoke but i like i like our
coal
to grow i like it to breed because it
makes some beautiful stuff has some
beautiful terps but i can't smoke it
because it gives me anxiety panic
attacks brandon russ i don't know what
that dude said he used to come in the
live feeds and just just spit [ __ ]
myth meth mouth [ __ ] [ __ ] in here
[ __ ] what is he saying i made [ __ ]
bull rider he didn't even know that he
was talking about [ __ ] afghani bull
rider he was trying to say that he made
afghani bull rider but you didn't know
afghani bull rider and bull rider were
different he was just so full of [ __ ] so
i booted him out of the live feed now
apparently some people are taking him
seriously because gene would
just put a stamp on him or something i
don't know gene likes a lot of dorks i
love gene but gene likes a lot of dorks
and i think that's how that [ __ ]
happened he's not i don't say i
shouldn't even say he likes dorks he's
nice to everyone
i'm an [ __ ] so i'm not nice to
everyone he's nice to everyone and wants
and wants to see good in everyone and
that's a good trait and i'm i just don't
have that trait if someone's a [ __ ]
[ __ ] bag and i see them live then i'm
going to [ __ ]
pop them
um
is grape vape just mental purpose
probably not it's closer to an oracle
hybrid pretty erica hybrid favorite
dosey crosses um
i'm going to be partial and say
dos skittles and um those bananas those
are my two favorite
chimer's most notable release um i would
say mental floss is one of his best
there was um he did that the highland
mexican blueberry he had the vision type
blueberry from vision creator which is
cool
um
what else did camera had this great
schnazzle berry
uh fighting buddha he had all kinds of
[ __ ] c4
calizar
dude's been around forever
so hopefully hopefully we will have
chimera back too just to talk about some
of his strains that he made um
but i'm sure he's gonna wait till we
actually have the other one up
uh dose bananas terp description little
bit of dosy dose a little bit of
platinum banana og
somewhere in the middle
i'm sorry i just do that all the time
because that's really the best answer
anybody could give um hogsbreath what
can you tell me about that once um
kind of foot funky cheesy sometimes you
could get some some fruity terps out of
it but not it was mostly known for its
foot funky almost cheesy type funk um it
could have been a williams wonder cross
it could have been a lot of things jimbo
told a lot of people a lot of different
things because he wanted to keep it
proprietary but yeah
i'm not gonna say anything mean about
old flunk tech anymore he's just a
[ __ ] that's it um
your top three sativas for strength and
flavor i really like to draw chocolate
thai stuff
um potency flavor flavor less so but for
potency for sure
um i liked the colombian black that
brazilian zitco had back in the day but
don't trust them because he [ __ ]
everyone now
um
the colombian gold that was in the
colombian camdee was really good and
colombian kim d was a great line too um
some of the urban stuff that csi's done
pretty [ __ ] amazing yeah
what were neville's dwarves made of
magic
i don't know neville's dwarves what are
you talking about i don't know i don't
know about his dwarves uh if you're
talking about rudoralis
um i'm not sure
anyway yeah what's up luche what's up
mike diesel
uh anybody else got anything else or
are we good
it's a friday night
i think is it friday or is it saturday
friday so yeah you cut out during the
sativa recap what was the top three oh
jesus um
chocolate tie from draw
um
those other ones
uh colombian black from brazilian seed
co
um
who's the third one
i can't remember now see
dwarf sativas i don't remember his dwarf
sativa's green punk i don't remember
that
i talked to the dude a lot and [ __ ]
don't remember that but i mean it's very
positive i'm not saying it didn't happen
but yeah
blue wrecker what's up dr lean you guys
want to see some blue wrecker
i was i was really stoked to see all
these because um this dude uh ran
through all i think four finos that he
ended up picking from um female
there were some really beautiful
pictures of it the blue wreckers and and
he found
most of the ones that were
uh it had a pretty good grading scale of
of um
purely original diesel dominant to
very blue bonnet dominant so it was
really cool to see those um here's one
of them let me see
choose a different asset let's see
some cool pictures in here i really like
the way this one looks it reminds me a
lot of old like blueberry hybrids even
like old-time moonshine hybrids he said
that it was the led light was very very
intense so he uh
he was it caused some foxtailing in this
pheno
that's a beautiful phenom i love i love
stuff like that um i like unique looks
personally see what else we got
another one
boom you can't really see the resin
production on it some had great resin
production like the original diesel the
girth and thickness and density of the
original diesel and blue bonnet has a
lot of great density in resin but um
yeah it was it was a mostly original
diesel is going to dominate most stuff
it is a super skunk
probably with some og type in it or
maybe even chem 91 which is a super
skunk og type but it tends to dominate
the berry terps but we did get some with
some berry terps up in here for him so
yeah
yeah um we do have some blue cheese left
the uk cheese blue bonnet which
like
if i i that was one that i made the
second round of the blue bonnet runs
because people had such a high demand
for it that i had to do it i know you
don't like swerve that is true very true
dude's a [ __ ] cuck uh but could you
tell me what you think of his deadhead
og
i think he buys seeds from other people
without them knowing in bulk and sells
them as his own so god knows i mean it
just depends on when you got it from him
what it would have been you know
would you ever do a great bait blue
bonnet if i had grape in the stable i
know i know um csi still has it unstable
and probably buddy might uh maybe but
yeah blue cheese uk cheese bluebonnet
yes one of the terps on that one all
over the place but there are some hella
hella cheesy berry [ __ ] beauties in
there
beauties
let's see what else we got
um choose different assets sorry i'm
getting new to this
changing thing they changed it up on me
there's another picture this one's a
different one
it had a really weird like uneven
structure
but i if i remember correctly this might
have been the most blueberry i don't
know
favorite strain i'm currently running uh
i just moved so not running anything
we're about to start running a bunch
first time i've been down like totally
down in a few years
so
getting restocked and about to start
running stuff again um
right now we have a project going with
csi humboldt at his his location which
is the nl5 and the hawaiian lights
uh interesting stuff to come out of
texas that's not well known blue bonnet
everything that the texas resin company
did the shoreline cut that high and
lonesome has in runs um
and you know maybe maybe expect to see
some of that green crack green ribbon
the same thing
i don't know anything about green ribbon
that was
after i stopped paying attention um
green crack
skunk one super skunk a sweet super
skunk maybe
what's your take on fat he seems like a
really nice guy i mean he's just trying
to make his way through the [ __ ] he's
very respectful and nice so i have
nothing bad to say about the dude
haven't run his stuff he takes a lot of
pictures so you know check his [ __ ] out
any more questions before i wind this
[ __ ] down
thank you to everyone who participated
in the
the bids i want to be careful what i say
in the beats i want to thank everyone
who participated in that it was a good
time um
go join patreon again i was trying to
remember what to say go join patreon um
tomorrow nights the fights
tomorrow night is the [ __ ] fights
there should be some good ones you have
paula costa like not wanting to make
weight and knocking it up like to what
was it light heavyweight now
um
yeah jeff from weiss is a friend
definitely
most lemon pine soul og
lemon you know i don't smell a lot of
lemon and og but that's just how
people's noses work i'm not real hip to
lemon uh take on barney's farm they're
they're totally a bunk company that
makes fake i mean they put like they put
if you've seen their purple punch it's
nothing like purple punch no it went for
tent flow it went to a 205 [ __ ] catch
weight he moved it up to [ __ ] light
heavyweight catch weight 205.
[ __ ] pathetic um
high and lonesome and texas resin
company or breeders haya lonesome is a
breeder and texas resident company is no
longer around lone star passed away
um yeah so the fights are going to be on
tomorrow join our patreon it's only five
dollars a month and you get access to
all kinds of [ __ ] updates um personal
insights you can hit me up
privately all the time we all [ __ ]
hang out kick it on the discord chat um
so yeah all you have to do is go to
google type in patreon breeders
syndicate
you'll have first access to all the
episodes when they drop and a new one is
about to drop
um
you get 10 off at our store and if you
join patreon for
uh speakeasy you get 20 off at both
stores so which is a big advantage you
know
um
yeah that's it
i hope you all have a
wonderful night wonderful wonderful
night and
um i should be back i think next
wednesday i'm trying to do and ask me
anything about
um the reversal spray so people can get
in their reversal questions and and and
the feminize seed questions i know
there's a lot of them we're trying to
get back on the the reversal spray train
to get it out there because for a long
we've been down for a long time during
the move
um
yeah so if you want your reversal spray
you want the the
you want the the juice
the one that everybody tries to imitate
but never can do because we've been
working on it for over a decade now to
perfect this [ __ ] um
then then keep your eyes peeled we'll
have it for you soon
lots of love everyone