[Music]
thank you
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived it I'm Matthew owner of Red seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not so dog breeder and grower
from Mendocino
welcome to the underground
hello I think this is working I think
we're live so I think we're good you
think we're good yeah I think we're good
we can rock it so tonight we're going to
do
um the Diesels A to Z I know we've
covered it before sometimes Ad nauseam
we cover Super Skunk stuff however I
think this is going to be a good way to
do it with our new platform being able
to illustrate with pictures and whatnot
so I wanted to be able to do kind of
like a documentary style thing with uh
pretty much not so narrating as we go
along and covering what we can of the
diesel story which means we're not going
to touch as much on the uh oh we lost
the not so which means we're not gonna
touch on as much of the
chem story I think am I still here
is this still live everyone
all right
oh there he is okay just making sure I
have no idea what happened I think that
was my fat thumb to be honest
we'll put that up to a fat thumb mistake
where I hit the wrong button that's all
right
um
yeah see we're live again see now you
guys know we're live this time
um so yeah we wanted to cover it all
we're not going to jump as much into the
chems because we've you know we've
covered a lot of the chems but we do
want to do a serious diesel presentation
so without much further Ado where you
want to start
I mean I uh you know
we're we're gonna rehash this obviously
or whatever so there's and maybe we
decided that since it's the Thanksgiving
holiday that we could pick a subject
that everybody likes to argue about yeah
um because it's one of those ones where
uh you know whenever you talk about it
some people are happy some people are
are I think you're wrong on some parts
of it and some people are offended
yeah right yeah definitely whenever we
do this every there is definitely going
to be people offended it just is what it
is so you know it's just as like a
disclaimer this is like everything that
we're saying is like the best as we know
it yeah you know new information pops up
at different times sometimes it's good
sometimes not
um but you know it's uh it's it you know
it's all wrapped up in one of those
things where it became one of the most
famous strains in America for a while
yes
um and then so how it originated uh gets
battled about and because it happened in
the 90s when there was a lot of secrecy
it took relatively speaking a long time
yeah for the story to come out and
for which people involved decided to
speak when
yeah there's a lot of claimants to the
throne of uh diesel there there's no
shortage to that that's for sure and
which cut is the original
you know and so from like so there's
different perspectives on it right any
obviously anytime one of the ways that
people get rep in the Cannabis Community
or whatever is having some kind of tie
or even responsibility perhaps for like
a famous cut or a famous line
it's one of the best ways to get like
Canna longevity and fame I guess you
could say the best way to start a seed
company to kick off a seed company yes
definitely that for sure especially if
you're offering a clone that like other
people don't have very much right so
um you know so there's that aspect of it
but then there's also the aspect is like
sour and diesels became popular uh in
the pre-marketing era of cannabis
um they sort of became organically
popular and then the more popular they
became uh the more people hunted them
out to like you know to find more of it
and then the more it got grown and then
it sort of became a self-fulfilling
prophecy yeah where eventually sour
became popular enough that like
literally you know people talked about
diesel as gas yeah and gas operated like
a whole section of the market
it still does it's still the huge I mean
every day I get emails asking what do
you got that's gas I need the gas you
know almost more than anything people
still demand gas you know and I think
it's I think it's a number of factors so
it's interesting you can you can hit
sour from all these different angles and
as Matt said
um you know we're we'll eventually get
to the point where we start chatting
about like specific cuts and things like
that but like maybe even like a more
General start right so
you know uh diesel
um and it's beginning and this is some
confusion out there but diesel was slang
for good weed in New York in that era
yeah right like so just so people know
there wasn't like a specific cut or a
specific something that came out where
before that name had never been
associated with wheat
right because that's what happens a lot
of times with famous strains yeah you
know is they is uh
um so you know so diesel came out and
Diesel was just slang for good weed and
then
Sour Diesel came out and you know these
diesel cuts and it became so famous that
it pretty much swamped anything that had
been called diesel before
right yep it became the diesel
right and so you know there was there's
other things out there that were you
know that people call diesel back in the
day and it eventually got swamped by
this one family
this is the family now do you want to
start about to talk about
um what the original thoughts were that
the diesel was I mean I remember when we
first got on the forums it was uh a lot
of people were saying it was just you
know bag seed and that was it
you know well that's pretty much held up
self-chem 91. you know that I don't
think is held up
um just because now we've gotten a
chance to look through a whole bunch of
chem 91 s1s yeah
um and and so it's definitely got other
influences to it but I do think it's
true that it it was it was some Bag seed
um it just it there's a little bit more
to the story than that obviously and
that's where the confusion comes in yeah
um but it seems relatively safe to say
that it's some combination of
um you know uh chem and you know Cam and
skunk there we go so here's the dog your
your old favorite right indeed this is
an old High Times photo I I assume it
was taken of maybe from G's You Know
Places yeah not a hundred but I assume
so
and then you know I mean it's not the
most photogenic plant ever
um it has a lot of traits that are very
distinctive you know we've talked about
them before the the leaf cannibalism
trait it's not uh everyone's favorite it
doesn't make for a great finish Bud
either no
it doesn't yeah I have a few more uh
good shots of 91. I want to mostly give
people an idea of
how it will breed so looking at the
traits of the dog here's some more
um this is I think
Jimmy knits grow oh we're seeing in 2007
seven thumbnails right now so you're not
actually giving us very much
let me see what's going on here okay so
it's not sharing it again
I gotta get good at this let's see share
screen window where there we go chair
there we go so this is Jimmy knits
pictures of it
and this is the dog so we're looking at
some of the traits of the dog here and
you will see some of these pass on to
what we see later on so if you go back a
second that pick right there right yep
uh especially with the with what the
leaf does you know I can see that in
sour
yeah you can see it in sauer's progeny
too
you know and people if people want to
take note you can kind of take note of
like the dark leaves
right and some of the structure it's
obviously not exact by any means dog is
much more of kind of a stouter afghan
um it is a little bit leggy but nothing
like the diesel
um but it does I do think some of that
bud structure and some of those dark
leaves and some of the way the leaves
yellow and brown uh is pretty
characteristic of uh the chem dog
and here's an old cam dog picture from
high times as well in the upper right
corner
you know a different way of growing it
obviously
different style
yeah I mean it's she certainly comes out
in different ways and so just so people
know
um what's generally agreed upon uh is
that sour is some combination of chem 91
and skunk
and to illustrate that
I will bring this up let's see
and that's kind of where the uh some of
the some of the Guff comes in I think in
terms of like what people say it is
right
um yeah there's a there's a Polaroid
from skunk VA about some of the old
Super Skunk
I also think you can see Sour Diesel
traits in in that pick yeah you know
um so to me uh it's basically a chem
skunk I've grown a lot of Kemp's Gunk
hybrids uh I'm not saying it's it's
exactly that nothing else it could even
have a couple of Herms in between but I
mean the general story is that these
guys got
um you know they were getting some they
were getting some uh some supposed chem
dog either that or a hybrid from uh this
dude and they found seeds in it and they
collected those seeds and they popped
them in the summer in 95 and they got a
couple cuts that they kept and they
called them diesel one and diesel two
right yep uh and then and then they gave
some weed of that uh marked our diesel
to their homie who grew it out and uh he
found some seed
and he thought that the hour diesel had
an s in front of it and so he thought he
it was called Saudis
right so we know the mom of Sour Diesel
because we know the bud that the uh the
weed came out of the seeds yeah yeah
that we know that we know the weed that
the seeds came out of yes sorry so we
know the mom for sure it was this it was
this cut and oh and it's also just so
people know because it started another
Legend
um the mom of it they called diesel 2
but some people called it headband
and so because there was this mystery of
the what the New York headband actually
was there's a whole field of headband
cuts that claim to be that one yeah the
first original you know uh New York City
headband
right there's some these are some really
early picks ones from High Times ones
from Canada Bible of different Sour
Diesel cuts and then in the bottom right
corner here you should you could
probably be able to see the headband
as it was stated in the Canna Bible
which is yeah so there's nothing there's
different ones and then there was a few
there's a few OG strains that got their
name changed a headband which added to
the confusion yeah
um you know then there's names bandied
about like day wrecker which man is more
this headband looks pretty cushy in this
picture yeah you know and so and so it
added to a bunch of confusion because
outside of a really small circle there
wasn't really any confirmation on
exactly what the famous New York City
headband was yeah nor did people know
that it was Mom of Sour Diesel
that's great for a long time for a long
time that was not known yeah that was a
tidbit that came out pretty much in
recent years I think that was confirmed
yeah you know and so as a result of that
like Matt knows a little this better
than me but like in terms of the forums
wasn't it like there was a bunch of
stuff like it came out of the RH the RFK
skunk yeah and there was
uh there was all these theories bandied
about about a much more complicated
lineage right yeah Hawaiian RFK skunk
uh uh Northern Lights yeah
that was the theory JJ put forward for
it and and it was a decent Theory you
know
um I don't think it turned panned out
very well because our estate RFK skunk
was being passed around at the time it
was in the same kind of room so a lot of
the same Crews were growing it so it was
it was it was a decent Theory
no and I mean I also think too that like
much more so than theories it's like you
have different people that are that are
involved in the scene or whatever yeah
um that come along and they tell their
version of it and other people are
staying quiet
right yeah and so for you know for a lot
of times in a lot of cannabis Stories
the people that come out first with the
first story get get the most rep
yep that's why that um OG Kush story
about the lemon Pakistani and all that
still is passed down this day like like
biblical because people really but
that's real to be honest regardless of
all that before we get into it like a
discussion about like the various the
various versions of it sort of what
happened in my opinion is that
um you know the east coast is is a is a
big consumer area and they loved it and
I think that
um it worked really well uh it had a
really good Zippy up high
it got people super baked it tasted
great
it had a pungent and very distinctive
nose and I also think the nose lasted
for a while and didn't fade very fast so
yeah when people were bringing it
different places like that that
persisted
and so it just became something that
people knew when they bought was
consistent and good yeah and so
completely separate from the lineage the
vast majority of people that grew ever
grew Sour Diesel knew almost nothing of
what we just talked about yeah they got
this cut as sour diesel or sour or
whatever and people would buy it for for
a good month for a good chunk and they
like to smoke it and so all kinds of
people started growing yeah I mean on
the west coast in Mendo and Humboldt it
was a huge thing
you know because it was it was like
growing modern skunk weed
it got big it was Fluffy
um it took quite a while it wasn't the
easiest outdoor plant it did great in
depths
right yeah
um and it was it was kind of funny
inside depending it was temperature
dependent
um and a lot of times
um people you know it should go probably
like 10 or 11 12 weeks maybe even 13
depending on the Fino and most people
will take it would take it back in the
day as soon as they could get away with
getting the nose on it yeah so there was
a lot of sour that was that was
harvested between 60 and 65 days that
probably should have gone 70 or 75 yeah
in all honesty is this the uh the one
that I have up here do you are you
familiar with this one the super leafy
looking one
you know I think that's the way it was
grown
um and I don't I don't remember where he
took that one
so I can't really say I've seen people
put up pictures of a plant that looks
very similar to this one saying yeah I
got the original diesel one from the
camera Bible but I just never really
been able to confirm it just because it
looks so different than any of the uh
ways I've seen diesel grown I mean it
seems like the thing about the the thing
about the bag seed beginning is that it
uh which I don't know which way is the
best way to put it but it seems like
that multiple people got multiple bag
seeds even early on yeah yeah and so
there was probably you know at least
there was a couple things that were
diesel there was a thing that was
headband there was a couple sours I mean
even the people that tell the story say
the guy that found Sour Diesel he had a
couple of Finos but only one got out
yeah
you know I also um real quick for
anybody listening to the audio version
of this after we upload it later
um I highly recommend watching the
episode because there's a lot more to it
with visual aids and stuff so definitely
if you listen to it go back and re-watch
go ahead yeah so it got it got really
popular in the sense that it was uh it's
one in my mind it's one of the best
families of cannabis out there yeah it
has a really nice high it burns really
well it's not overly dense
um which is good in my opinion when it
comes to taking bong hits or smoking a
joint or anything like that I I think
burnability is like an overlooked
component yeah I I totally agree even
even breakup ability like it's it's
really obnoxious to have to try to break
up these big ass dense nugs I don't know
they don't break up that well I mean
this might be dumb or whatever but like
one of the things that I like to breed
for is like you know wheat is convenient
when it's like in the dark at a concert
and you can break off a chunk with your
hand and stuff it into a pipe and that's
all you need to do and you can then
smoke it yeah
right that's a good trait good good
quality it's a good well it also makes
this thing where there's a certain
amount when you're burning stuff there's
a certain amount of like air to air to
material ratio that helps it burn
yeah and then that makes you get a good
a good hit or not and so I think
Diesel's burned really well so they were
like a pretty effective delivery device
as far as getting buzzed
how do you think the Grateful Dead came
in to play with the popularity of diesel
I mean that's that comes into play
really early on yeah yeah well I mean
you know for one thing uh if if we're
correct in that uh you know chemdog is
the beginning of it or whatever that
like you know the seeds that came that
became chem dog uh were acquired at a
dead show yeah you know it was bag seed
there
um and you know I I do think and in in
terms of like the 90s especially it's
not so much like this anymore
but in terms of the 90s uh Grateful Dead
hippies were sort of the highway
epicenter of the American weed Market
yeah you know it's there's a lot of
different groups that grow now and I'm
not saying obviously they were the only
people but like you know uh kind bud
sort of started uh being regularly
spread about through Dead shows and
hippies
yeah there was a lot of them growing it
and so as a result of that like you know
uh the the people Sour Diesel came from
were essentially hippies yeah they like
to go see the Grateful Dead they like to
go see Fish
um you know it was the kids that like to
go party and have a good time and and
see some music
and that brought together people from
disparate parts of America yeah which
means that mixed strains and that mixed
seeds and people brought those things
home you know they brought it from
California to wherever it went to New
York it it moved around yeah it
definitely did so you know uh I think at
the time probably like the uh Grateful
Dead was like um sort of like America's
last nomadic tribe of people
it's an interesting way of looking at it
it's true yeah you know we were they
were kind of like the Roma you know they
were kind of like gypsies in a way yeah
like you know three quarters of the year
they tripped around the country yeah
and they and they had to figure out a
way to survive going from town to town
and one of the ways they survived was by
hustling wheat yeah
and you know so
um it was found at a dead show and then
it like and then they were growing it
and selling it to other hippies and then
it it harmed and then it harmed again
and
and so on and so forth I don't think
that's true anymore yeah um there's no
tour like that anymore and like you know
growing cannabis especially has gone
into all kinds of walks of life yeah for
sure you know uh you know so but for a
minute there it was kind of like it was
spread around by a lot of people that
were like that or connected to that yeah
so
which one did you want to cover next
um
which direction did you want to go so
really what we could do is I think let's
put it this way right there was two
different things going on uh there was a
scene in New York that was kind of small
and indoor based where people were
getting crazy digits for sour right
people like AJ and Manny various various
different groups and then it made its
way west because it was easier because
with 215 in California and other places
it was easier to grow more of it in the
west yeah but it was still it was still
supplying that initial demand back there
yeah right and I think for a while it
was just Sour Diesel
there was no other name or qualifier
given yeah and I would say maybe in me
you can correct me if you think I'm
wrong but I think that the forums is
where these all these other names
started to percolate around yeah I would
think so so from like let's say the mid
90s when it came out to like the early
2000s was their names or was it all just
Sour Diesel
I you know I wouldn't know that's prior
to my time so I think you guys all just
I think my you know I mean I got my cut
uh and it was helpful it was helpfully
called sourdie yeah
and pretty helpful yeah it was very
helpful uh and uh you know and then as
the forums happened that's the beginning
of like people needing to identify like
where strains come from yeah so then you
get like stuff like oh what is this this
is the choco yeah this is the East this
is the this is the shroomy
right yep um what were some of the other
early names of sour uh Amish was one I
mean I think that was one of the shroomy
other names for sharumi because they
were yeah because because because
shroomi was supposedly from Pennsylvania
so it was sometimes called his name or
Amish I called it uh Cobb sometimes
because Cobb did amazing grows of it
when people would ask me I'd be like ah
either look at Chacos he's got a great
grow of it or cause right look at
chocolate or like yeah why did you know
every there's a lot of people that call
the dog the the skunk Vie a cut yeah why
because he was online talking about it
and they were trying to figure out a way
to label the specific thing he was
talking about and so oh it's a so it's
this one yeah right
and so the same thing happened with sour
diesel and what's funny about that is
that Sour Diesel goes through phases
where
if it's good sour nobody gives a [ __ ]
and then it goes through a phase where
lineage is important and people try to
track down lineage and then it goes
through a phase where it's not important
and if it's good sour it's good sour and
now we're in a phase again where
um lineage is really important being the
first one is important and having the
real deal is important
um but there's probably like 15 or 20
different Sour Diesel names yeah even
more so now in the past
three years I'd say many more have
popped up so many more so many more
I mean so we've got like like just the
ones I think off off my head that people
talk about like you East Coast Sour
Diesel New York City Diesel
right Amish
choco
uh PTSD ecsd
um the dhk cut was one the devil's
Harvest crew cut dhk cut there was also
the dark heart Nursery cut the dhn cuts
lost
oh no
I think I'm still going I don't know if
he should outer
I did
let me know if you all see this
are you there yeah
yeah I'm alive I don't know what
happened but anyway all right uh I don't
know how far Matt got with me the dark
part Nursery cut
um so we have the dhn the dhk
uh
there's a lot more well yeah then a
little later came the res cut yep you
know because uh uh chem dog gave res a
cut of Sour Diesel and he started making
seeds with it you know and stuff like
that and so there was probably a number
of cuts that came from res seeds that
got repurposed yeah because everybody
just wanted to call like to the Brokers
or whatever it was Sour Diesel they
didn't really want to explain its origin
yeah so it got super confusing
um and it's almost a little bit like the
what happened with Haze
yeah where like in New York there's like
you know I'm in Florida there's like you
know 15 different 20 different Haze
names
that only a tiny percentage of people
really know where they originated from
yeah and then there's things that are
called you know that that are are named
that in recent ones it's like
um you know now there's like there's a
JP cut there's a skunk that cut some
people attach my name to a cut there's
an a cut the hunter mountain cut the cat
skills cut the one helpfully called the
real Sour Diesel yeah uh as if that
clears it all up you know the Manny cut
the AJ cut we left out AJ AJ's had his
name attached probably first yeah yeah
yeah yes
you know I mean There Was You know the
AJ cut uh and the AJ cut has probably
had like several Cuts yeah have been
called the AJ it's kind of like ghost OG
and that like what's the original AJ
isn't the current AJ yeah yeah the
original ghost isn't even the same ghost
from the forums it's [ __ ] weird how
that works yeah you know things so I
mean it's well it is weird how it works
but then we're talking about something
that was sprouted in 96 and it's 20 22.
yeah and so it's gone through like 26
years of clandestine shifting around
right
and it also was one of the most popular
Cuts in America for probably 10 years
yeah
at least I mean it goes through phases
you know like it's been the most popular
cut in America a few times for for long
spans of time
yeah I mean I think I think the only
reason why I said for 10 years is
probably because it probably took until
about
2005 2006.
for enough people to get a hold of it
that there was just so much of it that
it could become probably like the most
popular kind bud yeah because even
though it was popular before it's like
you can only get so popular if only so
many people are growing it yep so it did
take some time to spread and I think it
remained popular right up until probably
like this last wave of candy kitty
purpleweed yeah that took over and
everything had to be you know
yeah some kind of gelato or cookie
hybrid of some kite some it had to have
a specific look there was a lot of
variations on the theme and for the
first time in about 20 years kind of gas
fell off for a minute yeah you started
hearing if it's not purple it won't move
yeah you stop seeing a lot of the sour
beginnings of the names and stuff added
to different strand names yeah and now
and what's funny about that is then sour
had like a moment for two or three four
years where it wasn't very popular and
now it's had a resurgence
yeah which is really weird because then
you have a situation now where there's
like 15 or 18 different names and
everyone has the everyone has the
special rarest oldest bestest
yeah strongest mostest yeah the bestest
the grandmasest all of it yeah all of it
you know and there's a lot of certainty
in an uncertain World in that regard in
my opinion luckily most of them are
pretty good
yeah
you know in all honesty it's like
there's there's only there's only really
been one that I thought sucked terribly
which one was that
was the Joe B diesel oh yeah yeah the
the Kim 91 JB yeah I mean yeah the the I
don't know what I you know there's a
thing I I've told this story before but
uh there's a thing where I just had this
one Sour Diesel cut for a long time and
I never traded with anyone because I had
it
yeah and then people started asking me
which version I had and I had no idea I
still have no idea yeah so occasionally
I collect half a dozen of them or so and
I grow them all next to mine in the same
room at the same time in the same
environment to see like which which you
know what are the differences yeah right
um and you know there's there's a good
amount of cuts out there and their
Origins are mysterious
you know so I don't know what mine is I
still I kept at first I was like oh I'm
just gonna get this half a dozen or
whatever and I'm gonna grow them and
then whatever one mine is that's that's
what everyone calls it yeah only that
didn't happen
let me see here I'm gonna put up a
picture just so people can see what
we're talking about here
um where's the sours I think that's it
it's gonna be in this one and is it here
is that it no no no that's a Choco here
we go there we go
yeah I need a pot is it is it up does it
show up yeah I can see it yep yeah and
that just so people know I think Matt
can see comments the format I've got
right now it's like hard for me to read
at the same time so I apologize if I'm
missing stuff or if you see anything
super pertinent Matt just uh speak up
now it's just a black screen
huh is it back up it's back up there we
go okay
I don't know it's probably like four
weeks in uh there's a nug of it um that
looks so much like Choco's like it is
like at least this this this this
particular you know budget piece yeah I
mean yeah I got that we got we got that
cut around two thousand and we've never
lost it
and that's what I consider Sour Diesel
and if if you if you pause it for a
second you know when people were when we
when you showed those pictures of uh the
dog uh the chem dog earlier and I had
you pause at that other one where you
could see like the leaf rust and death
yeah the weird necrosis and stuff if you
look at that Sour Diesel right there you
can see that same kind of
of issue yeah right so the very huh yeah
go ahead so the very first sour I got
there's a lot of people that have sours
that variegate
mine doesn't variegate it does that yeah
whatever you whatever whatever technical
term you'd call that
it
um so that's not really like somebody
messing up on the nutrient or whatever
like the dog it does the thing where it
starts to eat its leaves about halfway
through sometimes and there's not a
whole hell of a lot you can do about it
yeah um sometimes it's more pronounced
than others but it almost always happens
and that one right there it never
variegates ever
it just does that
you know I was going to show this real
quick this is a pandas cut that keeps
being passed around his math super of
the jesel sour dub it also has that same
trait it also has that's yeah it has a
very similar trait in that regard so
that's and but then like my La cut my
headband
um you know and then other sours I see
people have have like more of that chemd
patterning variegation yeah that doesn't
do the the leaf rust Leaf death necrosis
type yellowing it has a it has its own
distinct thing that it does yeah
you know and I'm not saying mine's the
first I like you know I don't know I
don't know what hap I don't know what
mine is before I got it
but I can say I've had it
um since then and not lost it yeah right
um and it throws bats and you know more
importantly than that it's it's got like
just because it's the first one it's got
what I consider to have like the
distinct Sour Notes yeah you know and
can we talk about that a little bit
because like that's something that a lot
of people even to this day like I'll
hear oh it's got the sour nose you know
it's sour like like lemons you know I'll
get that a lot like it's sour like you
know uh like sour you know but when I
think of sour I think rubber skunky you
know with sour to you
so
um what I will say is like the diesel
family right uh that particular one uh
it smells it has I would say it has gas
but the gas is almost on the back end
right where a lot of diesels it's it's
on the Forefront it's like the fumes of
the first thing that hits your nose yeah
um that one has gas but it also has this
weird nose crinkle
uh in the sense that you know sometimes
you smell things that like should be
gross but it's weed so it smells
delicious somehow yeah
it's got kind of that it's got like a
nose crinkle gas that's a little bit
sour that's a little bit off yeah right
uh that's my perception of it at least
um and it tastes really much it the the
flavor carries over pretty strongly yes
that's a big big trait of sour I would
say uh you know the general yeah the
flavor itself of what you get on the
nose is what you get on the palette
right where I think uh a lot of
um a lot of the more modern stuff as far
as diesels and and sours go which I
still love a lot like the fuel knows the
gas nose is like very prevalent it's
like the it's like on the forward so
that right there
um though although I didn't tell you
that man when we were setting some of
these up but all those East Coast Sour
Diesel picks that I sent you yeah right
here these are all from the homie pip
yeah
um there I mean he didn't grow it but he
he's who gave me that version of East
Coast Sour Diesel yep and so I ran this
one next to the choco and they're
identical and so if you see that one
hold on go back one
if you see that one there it's got a to
me like that's a nice Cola it's got a
very delicate feathery
you know skunk kind of like overlaying
calyx's kind of approach right a little
bit of foxtailing going on
um where like if if that the actual sour
that I have was much more of a chunk
yeah right there was my chunky Bud it
was it was very chunky there was more
side buds to it that East Coast Sour
Diesel would throw bats but they were
delicate feathery looser bats I want to
say something real quick and for people
who don't aren't familiar with
greenhouse and outdoor and and that's
kind of like me I didn't do a lot of it
um so when you're looking at plants it's
they look very different indoor to
Greenhouse to outdoor so if you're
looking at this and thinking ah that
doesn't look anything like my my East
Coast allergies or my ecsd cut I don't
know a lot of it's going to have to do
with the morphology from it going to
indoor to outdoor greenhouse and all
that so I just wanted to make that clear
for people because a lot of people try
to you know make those associations by
looking at pictures of cuts and saying
this is this the same cut you know and
that's a major jump going outdoor to to
indoors so I do think and that's a good
point and maybe we could segue into that
for just a second sure which is there
are some strains that are very easy to
identify visually because they tend to
perform in different environments
whether it's indoor outdoor Greenhouse
they tend to perform similarly enough
that they're easy to identify the diesel
family in general is not that way uh it
can come out very different even in
people's indoors it's very sensitive to
light it's very sensitive to food and
and whether it's organic or salts or
whatever
and so to me the only real way to test
diesel really well
is to grow it side by side to itself in
the same environment at the same time
yeah so you can't see it in this
greenhouse right yet but in that
Greenhouse I had about seven types of
diesels all growing next to each other
same food same size pots same light
obviously it was the sun I've done the
same thing inside you know and so
um that's really where you get to see
the nuances yeah
um I am not good at and I don't think
anyone is really that good at looking at
Diesels or certain strains like that
online and being like looking at this
pick and being like Oh Yeah that's it
when it's being grown knf and under an
LED in somebody's environment that's not
yours and you don't grow it like that so
I think that you know I I really do
believe that you kind of have to like
compare same to same yeah I agree
um this right here I was I didn't load
up a picture of indoor sour for whatever
reason the ecsd but I did keep a picture
of Super Skunk candy which has a very
similar uh morphology mud structure to
What Sour looks indoor it's very similar
to the dcsd cut specifically I mean I'll
say you know I'll say that when I grow
diesel I see I see super skunk and I see
chem dog in it yeah I can't guarantee
it's the only thing in it but I I see
traits that pass down from both parents
yeah you know easily and I've known a
lot of all of them so you know it uh
take that and I also think that like
sour for everyone listening diesels in
general is our modern skunk
yeah I you know I I agree that sour you
know I think that fuel and gas and that
nose crinkle and all that weird I I
think that's all offshoots of like that
rank RFK like all that skunk stink yeah
I think it's just all plays on the same
nose
I put up pictures of chem 91 again so
people can get another idea for uh look
at you but if you go go back to one more
that one you you can see it on that one
and you had another one in there uh oh
one more back there you go that one you
can see that one you can see when I was
showing my picture of Sour Diesel and he
was showing that sour dub yeah right
that uh so that's three different cuts
you can see that same weird Leaf curl
Browning Leaf death
the whole bit yeah that's a trait that
passes in my opinion and another trait
that I see in super skunk a lot and and
I only ever see it in Super Skunk are
these little what we call them dog
tongues please and they're little
slightly rounded not very resinous
leaves and they're all over the the buds
in little tiny small parts and usually
uh any super skunk types whether it be
chem 91 in my opinion
um any of them sour usually you'll see
those little things and uh it's it's a
trait that runs through super skunk and
it's usually easily to tell Super Skunk
because of that trait
it's one of those identifying visual
traits
so you know I mean I guess there's um
so there's probably like a
there was the first wave of sour that
got passed around a bunch
and those were just labeled Sour Diesel
and they had basically no other monikers
yeah and then there was probably
something from I don't know would you
say like the mid-2000s on
where there was a whole batch that
started getting named on the internet
yeah
right yep
and then it fell out of popularity for a
minute and now there's another whole
batch that has gotten named on the
internet and again it's like I know you
know J plant speaker has asked people
not to not to name it after him because
it's not his
but what happens is you tend to name it
by the source that other people would
know it you need some kind of descriptor
yeah so it ends up being not so sour
or JP sour or skunk Tech sour or this
sour or you know yeah or whatever
um and uh you know
I don't know that you know I would have
to go get probably gather up another
half a dozen sours and grow them against
the ones that I know yeah because at one
point I think I had like nine or ten
that's a lot of them
I didn't keep all of them but I was
trying to collect them to see what the
hell was going on yeah
because for a long time I thought there
was just a couple of cuts
and then I realized there was a ton yeah
keep going my headphone broke real quick
your headphone broke yeah I gotta switch
headphones keep going so yeah I mean I
uh I um
all the people are talking in the
comments I'm gonna look at
you know the uh uh the thing about it
someone just asked something and I wish
I'd cry baby on right now to explain it
but somebody was asking what are the
main terpenes of of sour
and I don't think that terpenes uh tell
the whole story
um there's these volatile compounds I
hope I don't I don't uh mangle the word
but he would call it theols
files there's there's a number of
different scent compounds and I think
Sour Diesel and skunks in general have a
relatively complicated chain of those
yeah so it's a combination of terpenes
and you know uh volatile gases and other
types of things that combine to make
that aroma
yep right
um and uh so I think they're called so
far uh uh something sulfur compounds uh
it's on tip my tongue volatile sulfur
compounds BSC balls yeah so yeah because
you know the even with like the super
skunk that he's got posted up there
right now
um it smelled unbelievable the last two
weeks of flower and the first three or
four weeks of uh post-harvest and then
it faded and it didn't store that well
and it became kind of generic greenweed
yep so those terpenes were not long
lasting that was not the kind of weed
the super skunk itself that you would
want to store and let chill for a month
for best effect yeah that was the kind
of weed where like as soon as it was
smokable you wanted to start ripping it
yeah because it was gonna fade
where the chem dog was the reverse it
took almost a month for it to really
come into its own yeah and I think the
sour is a blend of the two the sour
tastes great right away and it also
holds it for a while
you know so
it holds it pretty well some of the
super skunks do not hold that skunkiness
super well past drying no I it's it
doesn't last long Super Skunk is best
fresh and becomes generic pretty fast
yeah yeah that's the hard part about it
it doesn't store well
you know it doesn't it it does not store
well no I wonder if that you know like
we always hear about people like
stopping growing skunky stuff because
like they didn't want to get popped or
whatever I wonder if that another aspect
would have been not storing well like
that is a major important part of you
know artists well yeah it didn't store
that well
um and it was only moderate potency yeah
that was the other component it's a
classic example of a strain that does a
couple of things really really well yeah
um but isn't is incomplete
I mean that was the whole point of this
of the Superdog project really yeah was
to sort of take the lime green color
from the super skunk and its flavor and
some of its visible Crystal formation
right
and add that to the frame of the chem
dog which was denser and much more
potent and longer lasting yeah so you
were trying to see can we get can we get
the good parts of both into each
yeah you know uh this what's weird
though is that if you made if you made
dry sift
um not water hash but if you made dry I
actually think some of the stuff was
water soluble but if you made dry sift
with the super skunk and you Jarred that
and treated it nice the the pro the
smell profile would stay for a long long
time in Kief yeah but in weed it would
oxidize and go away
that's weird
you know like
for all of the legendary [ __ ] people
talk about Super Skunk like six weeks
after you cut it down that [ __ ] was
generic greenweed yeah it didn't get you
that high
and I say that as like a big fan of it
you know yeah like it's it wasn't
something that like you were like oh you
know man two months from now this is
gonna be the fire
no you [ __ ] ripped it as soon as it
was dry enough to smoke you started
puffing it yeah and it would almost you
would almost ruin the dog if you smoked
it too soon it really benefited it was
denser and it took longer to cure its
flavor and its Buzz really benefited by
you kind of leaving it alone for a few
weeks
so they bonded well together because you
could smoke the [ __ ] out of Super Skunk
for a few weeks and then finally start
hitting your dog and then there would be
a time period where both were good and
then the super skunk would be bunk and
the dog would still be good and then
you'd Harvest again interesting and they
essentially might have been two
different types of Super Skunk but just
because they were two different
Expressions you could bounce between
them
yeah I mean I just I and it's what's
interesting too is that you know we joke
around about how like
um you know the most famous thing that
uh Sam's man ever did was breed the
skunk out of uh out of out of the skunk
yeah right yeah but
his point of view was that the skunky
[ __ ] didn't have the high he liked
okay
and so he bred away from it
it had a a muddled not that great a high
and the stuff that we all don't like as
much like the the Citrus and the floral
and all that that had the more up Buzz
that he enjoyed yeah
I'll believe it when he comes on the
shows and uh tells it to me I don't
really believe that story yeah I'd like
to hear it from him personally that's
the uh that's the thing about all the
old timers right is that there's like
very little there's it's it's all their
their remembrances yeah
you know there is someone though that
grew um a lot of night or a lot of skunk
one from uh Robin Sam in 1978 three are
gonna be interviewing soon and uh yeah
he actually has a he has a documentation
all of the pictures you can imagine was
even in High Times selling you know in
the thmq showing that he was growing it
selling it it was moving and uh he has
very good memories of it uh very
accurate he's really quick with it so
I'm looking forward to that he might
actually prove me wrong you know that
that would be dope Yeah the more the
more opinions you get to it I mean
that's kind of the getting back to sour
um that's kind of the Crux of like
people having one sour story is there's
probably like half a dozen people
loosely associated with the creation of
sour in one form or another right yeah
and two or three that are pretty Central
to it and they all don't agree on
exactly how it all went down yeah even
amongst themselves and publicly
so you know a certain point it's like
who do you trust yeah who do you talk to
it's hard it's hard
um yeah it is hard it is hard especially
because a lot of times and you know and
Matt and I deal with this all the time
um but a lot of times when you interview
people
their first goal is in historical
honesty yeah it's making themselves look
good yeah I mean that's kind of part of
Being Human yeah telling telling the
history in a way that suits them you
know so the more angles you can get on
the same subject at times
uh it can be better
but
um this is a picture from Rascal and the
reason I chose this picture was because
back in the day it was so hard to find
any good pictures of diesel but also
realistic pictures because there were a
lot of people growing stuff that wasn't
it his show the it's in my opinion how
it looks the best low resin production
um his wasn't his foxtaily but I mean it
gets pretty heavily fox tail and looks a
lot like super skunk in that old Scentsy
picture but for people to be able to to
see what diesel is it was again in my
opinion this is a uh uh Super Skunk S1
not a super skunk chem dog D hyper like
the candle Bible set but you see all
these wonderful expressions of Super
Skunk even little dog tongues in the in
the diesel
I was hoping that some of this genetic
testing that came out was going to start
revealing some of these connections and
lineages uh so we would have uh data
sets to go with the oral histories and
the stories yeah but so far that's been
Elusive and hasn't really happened
um so we're stuck with the stories but I
will say that
um this is just one guy's opinion but uh
diesel is probably up there with like my
all-time favorite family of weed you
know it's up there to me with Haze or
something along those lines in terms of
like it's definitely like you know take
it to the island type of Bud yeah um and
most of them are pretty nice I grew when
I realized that there was a bunch of
sours out there I took my sour the ecsd
from pip uh an NYC diesel uh the Joe B
the Amish clarify the NYC diesel
clarified that for people clarify the
NYC diesel for people that it was not
the Soma one it's definitely not the
Soma one no it wasn't even related it
was from
it was for bald eagle yeah yeah it was
from bald eagle and then
um and then I got a couple others and I
grew them all side by side indoors and
in a greenhouse uh two or three times in
a row yeah right and it was interesting
because they when you're growing like
the same family like that and you're
seeing sisters to each other or half
says whatever they might be related to
each other they're definitely all from
the same family yeah so some of them had
Dart had very dark green leaves
some of them had very light green leaves
um the yeah the some of them smelled
like the the choco uh I grew the choco
and the East Coast Sour Diesel from Pep
they were basically I think the same
yeah um and they have like to me what I
consider to be more like an LA or like a
headband smell oh interesting right yeah
um but the New York City Diesel from uh
bald eagle was like pure fuel yeah like
dipped in gasoline and then you smelled
it no other notes of anything just like
pure nose crinkling fuel some of them
had skunks some of them had a mix of
skunk and headband that one was fuel the
Amish was pretty nice but compared out
of all of them out of all that first
batch I think the the ecsd that pip gave
that supposedly half of Death Star uh
that particular cut the choco or
whatever was my favorite of the ones
that weren't mine yeah but they were all
different and other than the East Coast
Sour Diesel and the choco none of them
were the same
interesting and then I grew them again I
think the second year
and that year I remember at it was the
second can Illuminati party we had yeah
and I remember yeah I brought four or
five different types of those that year
you know yeah I remember the Amish real
well because that was my favorite for
flavor anyways yeah actually that year I
didn't actually bring any of my own sour
for some reason like it didn't end up in
the it didn't end up in the comparison
but
um I was growing all the numerals yeah
and seeing how they performed and some
of them were shorter and fatter and and
yielded you know a little nicer some of
them were taller and more feathery
um you know and their formation and
stuff and so but they were all
variations on the same theme
if that makes any sense no yeah totally
you know they were all they you know but
I did find it interesting like uh my
headband has kind of my La has kind of
lighter leaves the nycd from bald eagle
and another one both had very pale
leaves like that interesting where there
was a couple like all these different
expressions of similar stuff coming out
of the same lines but then there was one
that but then there was another one that
that uh mine and the dog and one other
diesel had very dark dark leaves yeah
like Olive colored not lime at all
and some of them stayed pure green all
the way through some of them variegated
and some of them did that weird Leaf
death thing like I was talking about it
makes sense all those different traits
from uh you know super skunks you know
so that was interesting too and so you
know I don't know I mean people get all
uptight about like everyone's everyone's
sour now like it goes back to the mid
90s it's the original it's the best one
it's the this people are attaching their
name to it and trying to sell them for
high dollar
um the good thing for me at least is
that despite all that chaos yeah
um it's better weed generally than
what's been popular lately yeah right so
it's only huh yeah I agree
so it's only an improvement
you know over all these other purples
and all these different things that have
been running nothing I'm against purple
by any means but just like the the
purple only era you know yeah
um it's is uh choco is not chocolate
diesel somebody just commented that
chocolate diesel is different choco is a
dude from the forums that got a cut of
Sour Diesel named after of him because
of how he traded it I believe
was that accurate though no he got it he
got named after him because it was the
one I kept referring people to go look
to and that was it it was just oh it was
you yeah I was my dumbass added another
name to sour you're welcome
you're welcome well anyway so yeah it
got he was the guy on icmag yeah right
and and
um you know he ended up getting a cut of
Sour Diesel named after him yeah
it's kind of is kind of the movie yeah I
saw someone said that Amish is a cross
of
sour and head banger that that come on
guys come on I mean there's a lot of
different stories about these different
I mean but that one Headbangers like
five years old Amish yes no the Amish I
will I will I'll agree with Matt on
there 100 yeah the name Amish from
shroomy Far Far precedes any headbanger
existence yeah it's a little bit off on
the years which is why I was giggling
you know and so
um yeah they they uh there's a there's a
whole bit of it where it's cool that
there's all this like renewed interest
in trying to figure it all out
yeah right
um and one of the things that's made
diesel cuts a lot more popular uh I
think and is because because that strain
became so popular for so long it's
almost like the nl5 hazes where there's
just more phenos of it than almost any
other type out there yeah there's not
like I mean I think you know gelato and
cookie has a bunch of Finos obviously
right but sour and sour is up there is
like there's a bunch of them
yeah you know and so it's pretty
widespread people have access to it I
think
and that helps something gain popularity
yeah definitely and then people want to
figure out oh well which one is it which
one is this which one is that because
everybody wants the original real one
just in the sense that they think that
that one has to be better than all the
ones that came after it but yeah it's
the original that's it starts out the
best and it just loses as it goes down
isn't that how breeding works it's just
you know sometimes but sometimes things
get better too you know so
um I I just wanted to this is uh another
Super Skunk cross this is my um blooper
skunk which is the diesel Blue Bonnet
but I just wanted to show this because
you can see a lot of the the sour traits
coming through very heavy in it very
obviously it breeds very dominant or the
super scum crates I should say uh which
you can see in sour and all the other
Super Skunk types
um yeah it you can go down grandchildren
great grandchildren when it comes to
Super Skunk and if someone's selecting
towards those traits you will still be
seeing those traits and often you'll be
seeing those same uh scent profiles and
whatnot
yeah we uh somebody was asking which
there's some spammers in our comments oh
yeah cool
um someone was asking which one has the
dark one uh the dark leaves uh the cut
that I have has dark leaves
um there's a depends on how much you
feed it nitrogen too and also yes and
the light source so that can that can be
like I said before visually they can be
very hard to tell apart in different
people's rooms yeah because they are
very environmentally and Spectrum
sensitive
so they perform very differently
depending on where they're at and how
they're fed
um and you know it's interesting like
when
um you know when Pip was at that party
and he smoked that ecsd he was like dude
that's some of the best I've ever seen
it grown right and it wasn't so much a
testament to Me Knocking it out of the
park or anything like that it's more of
a testament to like sours can be really
hard to nail yes they can you can make
sour super boofy super fast you know you
grow sour and you knock it out of the
park and you're so stoked in the next
three or four times you grow it it's not
nearly as good but you didn't change
much yeah and so you don't know why so
when you really knock it out of the park
and you get its full potential it's full
Buzz it's full nose everything you're
just like oh my God this is some of the
best weed on Earth yeah and even when
you miss it's still usually pretty good
um but you know that there was better
yeah especially you've already had
better you're like that's what I mean
yeah you know you know that you know
that there was better yeah
um
you know I don't know so let's get into
the LA
I'm gonna show off some of the headband
delay right now
all right so the LA is I told that story
before as well but just so people know
um the LA is the first headband that I
got we got it about a year after the
diesel so we got it in
um 01 or so and I've we've had it since
and it's we it used to get sold to sour
all over the place but as you can see
there's what Matt's throwing up that's
the same Greenhouse that that East Coast
Sour Diesel was in you can see that that
thing throws straight bats compared to
the ecsd is that the Malawi or a Durbin
in the back yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
there's some sativas in the back over
there uh some head stash along the wall
um there might be some nl5 haze there
might be a Malawi there's a Panama I
think on the far on the right there's a
Panama from uh CSI
the old Canada's Panama or yeah there's
there's some on that that those years
whenever I can I like to throw
experimental stuff out there and see
what happens you know yeah I like
putting plants in the sun if they if you
can do that so yeah
loves it
uh yeah I liked her penalty you know I
do I like it mixed in with other things
more than just straight pure yeah
astringent or penalene but
um especially if it comes with a buzz
that I like I can handle it yeah
you know
um but that's most things so yeah that's
my that's my headband right there again
I don't know lineage it's very
it's very sour it's very diesel like
um it's a little different in terms of
its buzz but it's obviously you can just
look at it it looks like it's from the
same family yeah it's bigger yielding
especially in the Sun
um and uh it's it's uh it's one of my
favorites
um for a lot of times a lot of people
can't tell the difference
um you know uh and a lot of growth hour
huh I can't tell the difference between
this and what sour yeah okay that makes
sense just like it's like to them it's
like in fact there was a bunch of people
that would just call it sour
and then they would come up looking for
that sour yeah and it's mostly because
of the buzz you know it has a really
great buzz and it has a really great
nose
um and so for a long time when it came
to diesel family I had that cut and I
had that Sour Diesel cut that you showed
way earlier and I was super happy with
those two things for a long time yeah
you know there are some of my I mean
I've grown them over and over and over
again in every situation imaginable
Outdoors greenhouses like that one
indoor
um Outdoors is the biggest pain in the
ass because you kind of have to go till
close to November
in there right I think those pictures
were taken probably like October 25th
something like that not this year it was
this is a number of years ago now but
that was late October right before
Halloween yeah
um and so they do better sometimes as as
as Greenhouse plants
um because
um you really have to get nice weather
to get them to their full end
they take a while to form out you know
so there's a lot of times where
um like like we just did like right uh
right after right after Halloween I'm
cutting it down yeah or I try to get as
close to Halloween as I can and even go
a little past it if the weather stays
nice
um and if you're in a greenhouse
um you're a little more protected from
the weather so you can inch out a few
more days
right yep because it doesn't get as cold
you don't get Dew and you don't get all
that other stuff but yeah that's the
um
you know that's the headband and those
weren't very big plants those were just
plants put in 15 gallon pots
vegged for probably three weeks four
weeks and then and then they got flipped
how did she change from um Greenhouse to
indoor what how does she vary
you know uh
she's changed a lot so in the beginning
it didn't really matter where you grew
her she was a champ in fact there's a
lot of old buddies of mine that
um changed their whole sense situation
by growing that inside because you get
basically one and a half to two per
light
um and that's back in like the old
single-ended hortiluxe days yeah
um you'd get one and a half to two per
light all the time no problem uh and it
was Fireweed
yeah and outside she was a little bit
more she like I said she was you get
good years and bad years right because
there's a potential on that if you don't
know the the bud to size ratio going on
you can get you can get a lot of larf
yeah you can get a lot of almost weed
right
um and so there was a long time when you
were growing weed where like there
wasn't this like modern hash market like
there is today so a ton of larf would
make your Tremors cry and was also
problematic yeah right so you had to
know how to trim that thing up and I'll
say now as she's aged she likes probably
greenhouses the best
she can still do really well inside but
she doesn't like bulb heat yeah if that
makes any sense
she's fine with like like like actual
nature Heat
but there's something about heat from a
lamp
that she just does not Vibe with at all
and one thing I should I should shout
out because I have some friends that
have tried to grow her she eats like a
champ
she is can be really hard the more she
variegates the hungrier she is
interesting so when she's perfectly
healthy it's actually really hard to
find the variegation on her anywhere
and if you bloom her when she's heavily
variegated she won't come out nearly as
nice a wheat
um and so she needs strong food and she
needs calcium not so much Cal Mag but
excess calcium
you know
um you can just put in straight cow
without without the mag and she does
good but uh but if she can be hard to
feed all the sours can be hard to feed
you over feed the sour at the wrong time
and you kind of ruined it the ecsd
doesn't like as much heavy feeding as
like that that one probably would like
it sounds
no and I I didn't I didn't actually like
send you those pics but from that from
that same Greenhouse but the following
year I have this picture of like uh
probably like 40 or 50 East Coast sour
diesels growing in front and then my
sour growing behind it and they're
almost done and there's like this sea of
green
with the ecsd and then as soon as it
hits mine it's all yellow and brown
because all those big fan leaves are
eating themselves and dying yeah before
before Harvest or whatever so it's like
it's like a line in the greenhouse you
can clearly see where it starts
um and that's one of the reasons why
like I think that side by sides are so
cool because to really assure that like
people all the time now on IG especially
they reach out and they want to like
identify Cuts based off a couple of
picks and something their Buddy says
yeah it's really hard to do that with a
lot of cuts
you know
um the best case scenario for proving
it's real is either getting it to
someone that you hope can identify it or
trying to get the cut from a different
source and growing them side by side and
seeing what you can see yeah
you know
so
um
you know they uh
I got distracted by the comments yeah me
too
because dude is convinced headbanger is
in that [ __ ] line I'm like oh [ __ ]
I was there when he was making that
stupid ass I mean come on so you know
but that's the thing is is that
as far as diesel goes it's been reborn
yep there's new Legends there's new
stuff going on there's new I mean even
like you know there's some that I didn't
name just because I don't even like the
people that that attach their name to it
so I haven't but there's other people
that
um offer seeds of it
yeah bx's of it you know yeah things
along those lines
huh oh no there's no ibls in the LA Kush
yet that's right no no but a but of but
of of of sour and stuff like that
there's not even any seed lines of La
out there other than What CSI is
released yeah um but the popularity of
me talking about it and the fact that he
released it and people found a bunch of
fire and especially in the in the
um La by chemd
it was fire too I gotta smoke a bunch of
that yeah has led to a bunch of people
on you know clone Sellers and various
breeders all claiming that they have it
because people like it yeah yeah
um but I don't think they have it
probably not but it's okay no it's okay
it's okay to to want
yeah I mean and there's also a thing too
where it's like it's not even like I'm
trying to sit on my high horse about it
or whatever it's just one of those
things where it's like when interest and
money comes along in something all of a
sudden it appears in places
yeah and especially the people that
aren't like particularly concerned about
history or lineage and they're just
trying to make a buck sure they're going
to offer it for 500 bucks a clone yeah
maybe 15 or 20 people bite on it they
make and they make a chunk of money
yeah and all they needed was a Sharpie
and a label
so
um but yeah I mean I think
honestly uh I don't have any idea if my
headband is the real headband or the
first headband or the one from New York
I know we got it as headband in 2001.
um we had it since and
um
just having grown it for that long I
would definitely say it's closely
related to sour
yeah
how whether it's a parent or a sister or
a half sister or some I couldn't tell
you
I don't have definitive proof but just
just looking at all those picks you can
obviously tell and then you know if you
had a bag of it or whatever it it is I
mean some people it's their favorite
wheat it could be diesel bag seed it
could be any of the number of any up and
down the line it could be the original
it could be next to the original it
could be 19. she she variegates uh like
the like the chemd yeah that's so weird
but it makes sense though because it's
just to me it's a super skunk trade I
see it through all different weird super
scones without having to even touch 10d
you know
um so I almost I am I've almost had this
thing that like I wondered like you know
I mean who knows but this is really
speculation but I was like what if what
if Kim D is like an Afghan expression of
of dog super skunk
and the headband is like a sativa
expression of dog super skunk
it's definitely possible definitely
impossible within the fan I'm not saying
it's the only thing in either one I'm
just throwing it out there is like when
I look at them and I look at how things
grow and I look at like Leaf
similarities and stuff like that
um they're obviously closely related in
some way it's just how yeah
um but the most important thing is to me
like though that sour and that LA are
two of my all-time favorite they're
probably in my top five
I could smoke them all year every day I
really enjoy them a whole bunch
um
and I like quite a few of the other
diesels too I'm not trying to put mine
on a pedestal or anything like that what
do you think about people who qualify
diesels as roadkill skunk do you think
that they are potentially in the same
scent profile do you think what are your
thoughts on that I I would agree
diesel I think I think when you get that
fuel nose I think that's only like a
couple degrees away from skunk nose yeah
it's got the same like it's got the same
like nose crinkle like is this offensive
you know bright strong
um I actually think that that sour and
Diesel family is modern
skunk yeah I think it's the modern skunk
family that survived and we just were
hunting for this thing that like mostly
exists and I'm gonna make you qualify
this again because you always say this
you say it's a modern skunk family do
you mean modern skunk one family do you
mean modern Afghan family by Skunk or do
you mean by the scent profile the
weather does it grow like I mean I mean
modern I think so to me like it I
actually probably think it like this
could get me in trouble too but I think
it's like
I think it's like I think Sour Diesel is
like ancient skunk
but improved and what I mean by that is
it's like imagine if instead of breeding
it towards Citrus and floral and grapes
and all that
you bread it towards gas and Fuel and
headband Aromas and weird nose crinkle
and sour right
and but we've never seen that in spunk
one
huh but we've never seen that definitely
not in pure no no I mean I think you
know I think he I think he intentionally
bred away from that and I also don't
think that this is pure skunk
um you know
it's it's obviously got some cheminic
and that's where and I think that's
where the power some of the power and
some of the added density and stuff like
that comes from
you tend to think it's more uh skunk one
based as opposed to the Afghan tea base
I mean I don't know I don't know if I
would say that I
but I also don't like qual I mean
to be I didn't I didn't send you this
pic either but that but our same friend
uh
um
bald eagle he had this Colombian strain
yeah remember I yeah I lost those in the
fire yeah I have a picture of the
headband right next to that Colombian
and they're not the same but man would
do they look related see to me when I
look at like Greenhouse plants and
outdoor plants they all kind of look the
same I don't have that train die so it's
hard for me you have a lot more
experience in the greenhouse seeing the
the variation between plants and stuff
so I think it would be hard for someone
who doesn't have that like me to to be
able to see that that similarity past it
all looks kind of similar yeah I mean
that's one of the benefits of growing in
Mendocino County in in the 215 era was
that you got to do indoor you got to do
light depths you got to do outdoor
Greenhouse you got to do all these
different kinds and so for someone like
me who keeps a lot of the same strains
around for a long time that means you
get a lot of different expressions of
the same strain and you really you
really get to see how it performs in
different conditions it's super
important to have that eye I think I I
lack that for uh greenhouse and outdoor
but it's one of those things that I'd
like to eventually at some point in my
life catch up on because it I think it's
super important to be able to have that
I almost feel bad now because I got
distracted and I could I could have dug
on my phone and given you various picks
from inside and different things and
shown you how many how many different
kooky ways they actually look yeah I
mean Expressions the most interesting
part to me as I learn more about it and
how plastic these uh these plants are so
if you want to take it a step back
though right yeah is that until I saw
those Colombians
right yeah it clicked something in me
because before there was this aspect of
like
um
you know of the Colombians that you
would see would be these big huge crazy
stretchy things I'd never really seen
like too many like somewhat bred
Colombians in a certain direction
and when I saw that I was like oh so
obviously in Skunk there's a Colombian
element
right what if sour diesels and this
headband and stuff like that are you
talking about skunk one
yeah 100 okay okay because when I think
skunk I think Afghan afghanist because
that's what the first term is gonna work
so I think to be to be fair right just
to take it even a further step back is
that it seems like no matter what story
of Sour Diesel or headband or anything
like that you believe that it was a
merger of the chem family
right with this with the skunk family
and whether you believe that was the MSS
cut or you believe it was the RFK cut or
you believe it was the the DNL cut right
uh yeah whatever whatever whatever tale
of origin you want to lean on they all
seem to agree that there was this
blending of chem family and some kind of
90s skunk family yeah
right and so what happens when you blend
those things
that's what I think all these different
diesels are showing us
okay
in a way if I had if I had to get get my
guess on it too
um and there's some that lean more
Afghan and there's some that lean more
sativa yeah because it's in there right
there's probably there's probably more
Afghan than sativa but like you look
it's there's a reason why really good
diesel takes you know and a lot of
people in a lot of cases 11 or 12 or 13
weeks
yeah right that's pretty there's a lot
of that there's a lot of Afghans that
run 11 to 12 weeks too though no that's
true yeah there's a lot but the reason I
was asking was because recently you know
I've been digging through the old High
Times a lot in the old yeah magazines
and all the homegrowns so what I've been
doing is going through the old THM cues
and I've been going through up until
about 1985 going through all those and
trying to figure out where was the first
time people were using the term skunk
for cannabis because like we kind of
know that like the term skunky started
hitting heavy in the afghanis but I
wanted to see if anybody was referring
to Mexicans or Colombians or any of that
other stuff at any point before the 80s
never happened never happened in any of
these magazines or any of that up until
they started referring to afghanis as
skunk you know then you started getting
red hair skunk and you know Afghani
skunk or that's skunk bud uh Kentucky
skunk but it took up until that so I
don't even know if any of the Colombians
or Mexicans truly had that kind of scent
profile to be adding to it
um to make a skull
I mean the thing is is that so if you
take let's say for instance that just
just for the sake of pure argument with
with speculation right
that the L the headband or the sour
diesel or something like that is a
combination of some blend of super skunk
and some blend of Cam yeah right
if you just take that right there then
from the super skunk side you have
Colombian Mexican some kind of Afghan
and then Afghan tea
yes right
and then from the chem dog side you have
no [ __ ] idea but you have some kind
of some kind of weird old Afghan mix
yeah probably
right yeah and so it's it's more Afghan
than it is than it is sativa but that
doesn't mean that some of them couldn't
have a tall leggy
growth rate from some of that Colombian
or some of that Mexican oh yeah yeah
that's all that's all I'm saying I was
more referring to the scent profile of
skunk that most people identify with
skunk like that but even if even if you
consider what I just said is true then
Sour Diesel would have the Afghan that
was in Skunk one
the Afghan tea the maple leaf that
Neville mixed it with
right and adding the Chemin
and the chem which to me and this is
what I'm bringing up right now so people
can see the illustration of it I think
is also Super Skunk so it'd be doubling
up on The Afghan T if that was the case
uh again I point to my little dog
tongues
um the fact that just a pure Super Skunk
without anything else no chem in it does
the same kind of leaf traits you know
um yeah
so that would be almost if that is the
case if I'm correct on that it would
almost be like a doubling up on that
Afghan T reinforcing that
and you know and as since we don't know
the origin of the chem at all
you know and yeah we're not even a
hundred percent sure uh what the
um you know we don't know anything about
the origin of the of the maple leaf
either other than it came to Neville
labeled maple leaf maple leaf and he
named some phenos yeah
so there's a lot of mystery in there
um but
I will say generally speaking about Sour
is that it seems like it has a sativa
frame most of them right and then it
stretches but then it has some more it
varies how much Indica influences in the
buds some of them are pretty chunky some
of them are a little bit more feathery
and a little bit more layered right yeah
um and it has some density and some
potency from the Afghan and it has you
know the the stretch and you know some
of the buzz from the sativa and it
Blends in all these different weird ways
yeah and it just depends on because
honestly that that New York City Diesel
I actually told you like when you when
you look at it growing it was very
similar in growth
um in terms of the way the plant looked
yeah to my headband cut except for it
was about three or four feet shorter
oh wow so it went like Squat and wide
right where mine kind of went big and
tall and floppy but like as far as Leaf
shape and and and you know serrations
and leaf color and the way the bud
formed there was quite a few
similarities yeah it just looked like a
much more Afghan version of the same
thing
it stayed shorter and squatter and wider
and mine wanted to get tall and throw
like big forearms everywhere yeah I want
to grow bald eagles someday that one
looked pretty cool yeah it did look I
don't know if he has it anymore and I
lost it in the fire
fires
kill him I mean starting in starting in
2017 on I mean I got evacuated three
times between 2017 and 2020.
three three different fires and so
obviously when you're and you're
evacuated it's really hard to care for
your mother room
yeah from a distance
yeah I'm losing my hair if that happened
laughs
could have had an effect there could be
some grain that went on or whatever else
I mean luckily I I share and I backed a
lot of stuff up from different people
but I did lose some things in that era
that I have not gotten back
um this is a good question that you can
actually comment on because I think
you're working on this how about
epigenetics affecting one cut to
acclimate into two different
environments over a period of time and
reunite to be judged as being different
or the same
I am doing that right now
um so we don't know
um but I will say that uh uh you know
um
CSI and I have a little experiment going
right where we gave each other our
oldest Sour Diesel cuts
and we gave each other our chem dog cuts
and we gave each other our chemd Cuts
uh and
um we're we're going to see a if we
think they're all the same
uh and B
um you know are there differences we're
actually we're absolutely positive
actually that the the chem dog cut is
the same but they've been separated for
you know I mean I think he got it in 06
yeah you know so they've been completely
separated and never exchanged for the
last 17 years between the two of us yeah
I'm fascinated by this because I've
always had that theory about acclimation
and stuff and um I'm very interested to
see how plastic the chem 91 cut is and
and I also have another theory because
chem 91 even in the s1s it's pretty
freaking uniform so it's probably you
know either bag seed bag seed
unintentionally self or a work line
whatever it is so
between the two
I have something interesting I could add
to that yeah uh which is not it's not
definitive by any level right
um but
um when him and I traded right
uh he runs a pretty simple uh organic
setup these days right yeah
um and it's it's you know a lot most of
his most of his blooms are geared
towards seed making which is obviously
different right
um but we obviously veg different we
were having a convo last week I think
and we were talking about different
methods and I do something right now
that I that uh some people call synganic
right which is that especially in my
mom's or whatever and I've been
traveling and stuff it's been easier for
me to blend some organic and some salt
together yeah and use that to grow my
plants right so huh heresy I know I know
I mean for you it's probably that I used
so much hate mail because yeah yeah you
know organic [ __ ] you're like oh my God
give me the salt you know Salt Life bro
but so I yeah I grew a blend of I grew a
blend of salt and and organic amendments
and stuff like that inside right and and
so I traded him some stuff and he hit me
up and he was like man
and I was like what he's like
your plants smell way stronger in veg
than mine do yep
that's cool which I found was pretty
interesting yeah we started so we
started chatting about what we were
feeding them you know
um and you know and when he was growing
flour for market right he used to do all
these different you know he's through
all these teas and all these amendments
and all these extra special things all
the time to get it just exactly perfect
and now he's you know he's got he's got
a decent amount of stuff going on so
he's like he tries to keep it simple
yeah and he grows really nice weed but
it's like he you know he's vegging
organically with a lot of dry amendments
and I'm using some of that and then some
salt and he was he he straight up was
like every plant you gave me is more
pungent in my mom room than my own [ __ ]
in veg
which I thought was kind of an
interesting observation yeah I don't
know what that's gonna lead to or
anything else but
it was uh
um
you know uh yeah it was interesting that
he already had that kind of feedback on
it without even blooming it
was like your plans smelled stronger
you know in veg I noticed it when I
brush him and when I touch him and when
I work with him and then I go and I work
on the same strain that's mine and it's
more muted
whatever that means
isn't that interesting so we haven't
yeah
well I mean what I think it means
personally is that the plant Wants What
It Wants
right and if you give the plant
everything that it wants as far as food
right then it's able to do all the
various processes it wants to do and
reach its potential yep and I think a
lot of times with Organic especially
indoor organic
um you're not actually giving the plant
everything that it wants all the time
yeah it's because because it's like I I
kind of look at it this like might be
blasphemy for people or whatever but I
kind of look at it like organic gives
the plant a lot of things that it likes
but sometimes it struggles to give the
plan exactly what it needs yeah because
when you give a plant really really high
quality and I don't mean Athena or
anything like that but like like
something like Canna or Cutting Edge or
somebody that's actually decent if you
give them really high quality salts
um the plant has to do nothing but
absorb those
and it's a lie that people talk about
where if you use any salt at all you'll
kill all of your beneficials yeah people
don't know this but like or some people
don't know this but the plant absorbs
salt through its roots
that's what it absorbs and you can't
tell the difference between assault from
like Cutting Edge or Canna and a salt
that's organically derived oh my God
you're going to make so many people so
upset and it is true it's true Superior
I'm not saying that one superior to the
other because no but it is true what I'm
saying is is that
what I'm saying is is that like when you
when you bathe a plant in in nutrient
that has salts in it it's almost like an
IV the plant has to do nothing it can
just as long as the ph and the
temperature is right it can just absorb
that food right up into it
where in Organics
oh man when in Organics uh he agrees
those same salts and those same things
are bound up in like more complicated
chains that have to be broken down by
microbes and bacteria and stuff to
release the salts yeah doesn't mean that
Organics not going to do other stuff
like enzymes and and you know a whole
like soil food web and you know mycelium
and different things that like so
there's all this complexity to it but
essentially
um it's really really really hard to get
a perfect organic mix indoors in pots
especially small pots yeah much easier
to do in beds it's much easier to do in
large amounts of soil than small so when
you have a bunch of moms you know like
uh CSI does you're a lot of times you're
growing them in anywhere from four inch
to two gallon pots yeah
I found in the in smaller pots it's
easier to be syngantic and have a bunch
of and have a your a bunch of organic
and then still feed a light PPM or EC
whatever you choose to use salt base
yeah and then that just kind of gives
and to me the goal of an old Mom
especially some of these things are 25
30 years old is like keeping them as
healthy as possible
yeah these are things that are annuals
that should be dying yeah well you know
as as Matt will tell you like once you
get a plant unhealthy sometimes it can
be a real struggle to get it back to
being fully healthy sometimes you can
see Cuts I've never seen bee go back to
what they were ever no matter how
healthy you try to get them you know now
you know what what happens too is that
when it is true that that salts will
kill some Organics but that's mostly at
like high ECS and stuff like that if
you're feeding really low or moderate
it's not going to really kill your
beneficial bacteria or do anything like
that because
the organic is producing salts too
and a lot of times when people go into
the store and they buy bottles of
organic nutrient like let's say you're
going to buy some kind of like some kind
of blend but the reason why that should
cause money the reason why that [ __ ]
costs money is because they already
brewed it and made some of those big
like organic chains break down and some
of those organically derived salts are
in the mix waiting to be used already
yeah it's not like you just have to like
you know dust bone meal or blood meal or
something like that and like wait for
them to break it down yeah most organic
liquid amendments are just people
breaking it down for you ahead of time
so that it's easier and more readily
available
yep and easier to apply
you know but some stuff you put in your
soil it might take two three months to
even break down
yeah and what rate does it break down
what if your plant wants more of it then
you have to offer
I'm not trying to get off on some kind
of nutrition tangent but I will say and
this can tie into Sour Diesel
that I'll tell you a funny story from my
friend John who runs Cutting Edge okay
uh there's this product he came out
which is a carbohydrate product which
has some potassium in it that's called
sugary
yeah right uh it's a carbohydrate-based
sugar product so he's got these clients
back in the east coast to grow a ton of
Sour Diesel and they call them up
Furious your [ __ ] ruined our diesel
yeah what do you mean it ruined our
diesel how did it ruin our diesel your
[ __ ] ruined our it made our diesel taste
sweet
right yeah so they're all pissed off
because to them they have to have the
nose yeah so he actually made a product
called sour d
right which is the exact same product as
sugary but instead of extracting the
carbohydrates and sugar from sweet
fruits yeah he extracted them from tart
Sour Apples
interesting and that made it and then
those and then those people grew it
using that and the sour flavor came back
so even even the development of the nose
could potentially be based on the type
of food you're using and what it
balances at didn't we just say that when
elements are analyzed whether organic or
salts
it will still be the same thing right
exactly but so those those that's very
true but that's the 17 macro and micro
elements
okay that's not all that's
getting two different types of
sugars that are just sugars
or two different carbs change maybe yeah
maybe maybe the sugars and the carbs
like feed different bacteria oh that's a
good point yeah you know that's a good
point who knows I don't know I'm not I'm
not saying I'm that that's not a story
that has a definitive ending yeah it's
just an anecdotal story of like he
changed up his nutrient a little bit and
it changed the flavor profile of the
same strain yeah
I remember Botanicare offered like grape
sweet like all these different kinds of
sweets I always wondered if that was
legit like Berry and
like yeah at the beginning it was just
and then they came out with Berry Sweet
and yeah they came out with a number of
different ones you know and so I I
haven't actually done that experiment
with the sugary or anything like that
myself but I will say that I have some
friends that grow in living soil
and they have some similar strains that
uh that other friends I have run that
grow in a very different style yeah and
the
um the living soil stuff is is overall
much sweeter
um and you know much more biology
uh just I'm not even talking about so I
just mean like the weed that comes out
of it okay you know like it's it's it
has like a it has like a sweeter like
some of those some of those like um
other flavor profiles aren't pronounced
and then I have a friend who grows the
exact same stuff in salt and they get a
much different flavor profile than the
living soil people yeah I definitely
believe that for sure so that's that's
kind of what I'm saying is like I'm I'm
not gonna sit here on this episode and
try to like tell you anything definitive
about why I'm just saying that certain
strains are sensitive enough
that even what style you're growing and
what you're feeding them could
potentially impact
the chain of things that occur that make
the nose that you perceive yeah
that's what I'm saying you recognize do
you recognize this cut yet
the one we haven't touched on that cut
this is the day wrecker which one you
haven't flowered yet wait
yeah crap is that is the day record
this is what she looks like yep yep I
have that
um I have I have had it for I don't know
yeah a number of years now right
and I've never actually made a little
dog tongue um so I don't have anything
I've noticed the little dog tongues in
the the foxtails very it has a lot of
sour traits
no it does that's interesting I have not
seen that picture of it I like a lot um
some of these are gray skulls and some
are
um um THC uh uh I'm sorry I forgetting
his name off top my head but he deserves
credit they're great pictures but yeah
so yeah that that one is uh that one's
also
um that one's been percolating in the
collection for a while I'm hoping gonna
Bloom it this winter
um that one you know Matt gave to me
helpfully labeled original diesel yes
yeah that's correct
I and I don't know any history behind it
by that some people call it the day
Wrecker
um it's hard it's a hard one to trace
back it really is I'm gonna grow it next
to my other diesel Family Cuts and see
what I think
um it certainly grows a little
differently
um it's a little bushier to me and I
think I think pip would pip agrees on
this one it's one of the more potent of
the diesel families one of the most
potent like it is it is for us it's it
is narcotic as [ __ ] it's a little strong
it's a little strong
um I would say it it draws a little
after the end
yeah that draws from that afghanian very
heavily how many in the high how many
days does it make I mean I know pip
would say 84 but how many days would you
take it
yes 70 77 right in between there 11
weeks right in that same range
yeah right in that same range so yeah no
that's one that's a great reader too
it's a great breeder yeah
I think not just catching a lag it's a
bunch of cool discussions going on I
might
yeah
am I here you go you're back
oh man
I'm back there's a bunch of cool
comments uh about nutrition I've thought
about doing like a solo show recording
about ju about like uh about nutrition
for a while I just haven't actually
pulled it together
um but it's like to me it's like a
fascinating topic because I've grown uh
for at different points in my career
I've grown
um the exact same strain side by side uh
under same same everything but feeding
them different what do you guys think
about a a not so Story Hour show too I
think it's a good I've been trying to
push him to do it because he's he's very
good like in audiobook voice like with
not being interrupted by me saying yeah
all the time and I know people get
annoyed by that but we're trying to you
know continue the conversation and make
it not you know but I I'm looking
forward to it so prod and poking it's uh
it's my it's my fault I should have done
it but uh I haven't done it yet he'll
get to it I mean I could say that but
but nutrition is something that is uh
it affects sour and Diesel cuts a bunch
yeah and it affects a lot of strains a
bunch and it's one of those things where
it's the closest thing to religion that
weed growers get where they're convinced
that whatever they're using whatever
they're feeding especially organic and K
F and living soil types that they have
stumbled upon the word of God absolutely
and so if you try to talk to them about
what you've what you've experienced
sometimes it can be here it can be
you know I mean they can't burn you at
the stake but they might want to they
definitely will want to that's for sure
yeah there could be some Salem Witch
Trials or something like that because
you know there's I think salts get a bad
name uh in certain regards and I think
Organics you know is poorly understood
in a lot of ways I'm not going to hijack
the whole show but it is it is
interesting more much more so than
almost any strain I've grown or any or
any family of strains that I've grown if
you start playing around with food and
light spectrum
you will get way different results with
diesels yeah definitely
you know you really will like I've grown
I you know I've grown them under
different light spectrums metal halides
high pressure sodiums double-ended
Ceramics you start changing the food
that's something that really responds to
changes
and that's what makes it so hard to
identify too
under uh ceramic metal halides I
remember it almost had like a a more
cushy type bun it wasn't foxtaily it
looked almost delicate small cushy it
was really weird for a sour the ecsd cut
choco
people somebody was just saying in the
comments all just the bottles are poison
uh that's a bunch of [ __ ]
um you know uh bottles are just uh
bottles are just a form to hold a liquid
right uh yeah and you know in if you get
like a really high quality hydroponic
nutrient right
um especially one that's made out of
high quality minerals those minerals are
just pure forms of like the what the
plant needs you know uh salts get a bad
name because cheap salts have heavy
metals and have other [ __ ] and are
derived from things that aren't that
nice yeah but really really high grade
salts it's literally just like you know
it's there's minerals that the plants
are absorbing and they have them in this
order and they get them from a really
clean source and there you go
it looks like we made it an hour and 45
minutes in talking about diesel
oh my God and it's lovely components
well there's also something so uh like I
said in the beginning uh nice argument
for your Thanksgiving weekend yeah you
know
people will probably hate me for saying
certain things about this evening
tonight sometimes they say the most
innocuous things about Diesel and I get
hate mail
um because I poked a hole in somebody's
story so it's not to tell anybody that
they're wrong it's just this is just our
opinion yeah and not so there's always
poking holes in someone so you know I
mean it's what you do
so I'm going to give a shout out real
quick to me let me stand up so I can get
this in the camera wake Brewing
go check them out great craft brewing
company they hooked it up for
Thanksgiving amazing Thanksgiving Brews
we have our sale going on at
riotsies.com
um we are restocking we just restocked
like tonight I should have had it up
earlier the Santa Cruz wreck which is
the Blue Dream Santa or Santa Cruz Blue
Dream cross to Arcata train wreck um we
just restocked that restocked some smell
boat stuff and um use coupon code Black
Friday 50 or I'm sorry 30 off or uh
coupon code I don't know FM 50 and you
get 50 off the fence spray uh you got
anything not so
no I just hope everyone had a Happy
Thanksgiving or at least is enjoying the
time off
um Harvest is mostly through for most
people and you know trimming is either
well underway or paused so I hope
everybody survived and uh I hope
everybody has a nice holiday we'll see
you next week thanks for showing up
everyone Thanks for to everyone who
threw in some super chats we appreciate
you
lots of love peace
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminizing
[Music]
foreign