what's up everyone
finally got somewhat of a backdrop
behind me
finally
i want to show it off because
britain put so much time into making it
pretty but yeah anyways waiting for
natso and then we'll
kick it off
shout outs to the syndicate crew
shout outs to everyone [ __ ] in the
patreon and our patreon discord
everybody [ __ ]
interacting over there it's been [ __ ]
awesome
it's been really awesome with me a lot
of supportive people
if i have side issues [ __ ] people
[ __ ]
hit me up and help like it's been crazy
it's been really cool so i appreciate
all you guys that are that are hanging
out and shooting the [ __ ] with us and
learning with us as uh
as we do a lot of this deep diving and
get ready for the shows and picking show
titles and
and [ __ ] to talk about
um one thing i do ask is that people
share the podcast we need people to
share them so much right now because of
i mean starting from scratch so
definitely need people to do that so the
more you share it the more reviews you
lead the likes on youtube
all that [ __ ] it helps it really does it
really it helps it build traction and
get seen and recommended to other people
if a lot of people are liking it and
leaving reviews and all that [ __ ]
are you [ __ ] up though because you're
not supposed to cuss within the first 35
seconds
yeah i need to um
i have ssl on the site but it's not
hooked up correctly so i need i need
someone who's good at domains to to set
that up but
i have my my old web check looking at it
right now
or going to this weekend
so
that's rad the person that i was with i
worked with for a long time on web stuff
i just went back to that
here we go
mr goat farm
yeah everybody check out um santa cruz i
don't know why it's not letting me have
naza yet let's see
there we go santa cruz goat farm on
riotsteads.com go check it out we have
all the stuff up tons of pictures
all that good stuff
i exist there you are
indeed
all right so uh how's your how's your uh
start of your week weekend
it's going good
good so far yeah
yeah it's going good
good deal
like fairs in town so my kids are all
excited
are they there right now yeah they go
at least some of them
some of them yeah
yes this these are my care bears behind
me of course
you like the backdrop it's better than
the prison wall it is better than the
prison wall
it's a lot
you know it just shows what you can uh
spend on yourself when you don't have
children
yeah you could buy yourself all kinds of
figurines
yeah someone asked about resin lung i i
have no clue i texted him two days ago
no response yet he he likes to to go
away and disappear for a long period of
time randomly one of the weirdest dudes
i've ever met
uh he does he does like to you know
hibernate
hibernate not not everyone has the
easiest time with uh socialization and
all that you know
yeah um and in fact i will say too that
uh
like a lot of breeders and growers and
all that kind of stuff like it
um
you know at some at sometimes like you
have to be somewhat used to isolation
yeah
you know you spend a lot of time kind of
alone
yeah you know what i mean yeah it's i
miss him dude he's so funny
i know we all miss him but yeah
hopefully he'll come back sometime
yeah it would be good it would i mean
but that a lot of times that's weed
people
yeah
you know they flow in and out you know
sometimes you only have so much energy
for socialization
yep you know the desire to be public
yeah you know yeah somebody said
pandemic same thing for me pandemic was
easy i'll spend a lot of time alone and
you know yeah
that was super easy for me
but for a lot of people that are super
social you know i mean there's a lot of
people that can't even be quiet yeah you
know they get they have to have music on
or they have to have someone talking
because it's like they're just not used
to yeah so
yeah looks like someone accidentally got
blocked sorry sorry whoever it was i
can't unblock you or i'd have to stop
the show to do it so
um yeah
yeah matt on the not only does he have a
quick block finger he has a fat
accidental block thumb i do i do and the
problem is like when people say [ __ ] in
here that i want to get rid of i go to
click it and i'll go to hit boot but
sometimes it'll scroll up when i go to
do it and i do it so fast that it's just
like boom and then i told i'm like well
i'm trying to remember stuff and answer
and then i'm like i don't even remember
who i did it too but before before uh um
like uh we jump into like what the show
is actually about well you know
maybe i'll add one comment onto that
which is that the whole thing about like
i see a lot of people commenting on like
how they kind of liked the coveted
lockdowns because it fit their lifestyle
you know or like they were prepared for
it um you know there's a lot of us
uh who are kind of involved in for a
long time that like the way you stayed
safe was like you had a tight group of
friends that knew what you're up to and
you stayed quiet you kept your head down
and you tried to be invisible right and
i actually do think that played a
massive and you know and then there's a
whole thing of like some people like the
plants more than people
uh you know and people had weird quirks
and you know one of the things that
cannabis allowed was like your weird
quirks to get bigger
yeah because you could self-sustain
whether it was seeds or flower or
hustling or whatever it might be
you know and a lot of times like you
know real jobs and stuff they sand those
edges
yeah they do and so we get a lot of
quirky people in weed and then when the
money came into weed
right so here's the here's the point i
wanted to make when the money came into
weed the vast majority of the like
slightly invisible suspicious we people
sort of hid and took like a waiting wait
and see kind of attitude towards what
was going on yeah right which meant like
all the super social hustler bullshitty
type people
they all ran to the capitol first
because that's what they wanted was
money yeah money and rap and all this
different stuff and all of a sudden
there was like minor weed celebrities
and you know and this and that and
everything else and so as a result like
a lot all the people that all the money
partnered with first
weren't like the deep breeders and the
people pulling off real [ __ ] and the and
the people that grew exceptional flower
and all that it was like all the people
that were like you know that they were
socially you know they just ran towards
it they're from cities they were
connected they have rich parents or rich
brother or you know some kind of media
whatever
and so it's kind of been [ __ ] up and
that like a lot of the like the faces of
cannabis like they're not the heart of
the scene
no no i mean that's that's a given like
a lot of these um corporate guys where
they made the mistake and investors they
made the mistakes in thinking that they
could walk into a black market and talk
to talk to the deepest dudes in the
deepest circles because obviously those
are the guys on high times covers and
winning cubs obviously those are the
guys that are the deep ones in the deep
circles i mean right you know they kind
of they kind of screwed each other and
in the process they lit a bunch of money
on fire because
a lot of the capital like sharky rich
people like you know partnering with
some of some terrible people in the
industry
each party was trying to screw the other
yeah like the weed hustlers were trying
to get a bunch of money from the rich
people and the rich people were trying
to like steal genetics and sop and then
kick the [ __ ] hustlers out
yeah only like the hustlers couldn't do
what they they couldn't they couldn't
set up
actual large scenes and run them
efficiently they had never heard for a
long time they didn't understand all
that different stuff and so they sort of
learned on the rich people's dime
yeah you know
and honestly like if if someone would
have came to me and said hey you know
what i know you've been doing this x
amount of time i want you to scale up
and i want you to run this [ __ ]
massive facility
i wouldn't have been able to do it like
i mean scaling up is a hard [ __ ]
thing it takes a certain kind of brain
to go from being able to blow up houses
to blowing up [ __ ] major facilities
it is not easy it's not the same thing
at all it's not it's not necessarily i
mean the one thing that does translate
is that if you're a good pot grower and
you're observant of the plant
that helps because that helps you fine
tune whatever the [ __ ] is going on with
your greenhouse or your outdoor or your
room or wherever you might be growing
weed you know but certainly scale and
you know and then the other part of it
too is like
like everybody agrees that there's craft
weed
but nobody agrees where craft stops
yeah
you know it's true like so so that way
everybody gets to claim craft yeah
you know you have people with a hundred
lighter claiming craft you have people
with acres claiming craft you have
people with a ten thousand squid you
know it's all they're all growing the
fire
yep
yeah i was i was watching a video
earlier today and i mentioned it to you
it was people growing aquaponics on a
large scale for a major
um
uh retailer in canada and they were just
they were growing dank in aquaponics it
was one of the first times i've ever
seen that so yeah actually
all that 20 years ago
um and it's it's because it's actually
like it fit what i was it it's hydro but
with fish yeah kind of
but it's organic you know so it's like
if you get it right it's pretty neat
you know it's very hard to find really
quality like exceptional quality
cannabis grown aquaponically because
it's so hard with the inputs you give
the fish what you want them to output
you know what i mean like it's hard to
get quality quality in that yeah i mean
it was it was just never the most
efficient thing for almost anyone no
matter who you were yeah as a result it
wasn't it what you know it's not like
you had a thriving fish business that
you sold tilapia and you sold cannabis
like it just didn't really mix
yeah but it's a cool like closed-loop
method in a way yeah you know that's for
sure i i admire it it's hard it's hard
stuff you have to be fastidious and very
attention detail orchid oriented i mean
i'll say something too like about craft
like even say 20 years ago or 25 years
ago like in the when a lot of people
were growing like generator scenes in
the woods around here right yeah um most
of the people that worked there that
were growing at 100 or 200 lighters
almost all of them bought their head
stash from people that had four to ten
lights yeah yeah yeah because it was
just nicer
yeah i mean even 10 000 square feet is
kind of a lot of weed
yeah
you know so like where is where is craft
where is the amount where and not just
like growing it but like
growing it and handling it and drying it
and curing it all the right way because
you can [ __ ] up at any of those steps
yep and then it's not as good see it's
not just about like growing it it's like
all the way to the end can you manage
that whole thing
yeah
at scale
you know
so
i don't know
it it's interesting on that regard where
where is craft you know where's crap
what's a craft size indoor what's a
craft sized greenhouse what's a craft
size outdoor that'd be a curious thing
to pose to the community
is is someone just typed in there do you
know ken blah blah blah isn't that kendo
i don't know blah blah i don't know
i'm pretty sure that that's kendo he's
talking about i don't know there's a
bunch of cans but uh
kendo you know kendo right i don't know
if i know kendall yeah kendall is funny
he's like the older me just talks mad
[ __ ] to er except he's tough
like a tough version of me
yeah you know yeah that's what's cool
that anyway just to close on that that's
what's cool about craft is that
everybody agrees that there is fire and
craft and really really excellent weed
just no one agrees what that exactly is
so it allows everyone to fight over it
and claim it
sure and now there's huge ass scenes
growing straight meds claiming craft
because it's just marketing
yeah it means it's losing its its value
in name like calling something craft is
going to lose its value like calling
something date you know or kind it
happens in any kind of thing it's like
people want to attach their not quality
onto quality yeah
is really what it comes down to
yeah um so we're gonna have we're gonna
have some guests coming up but it didn't
pop for this week so we're gonna do uh a
uh uh part two of clone list
where uh matt you know we go we're gonna
go back and maybe i'll give a little bit
background real quick again here so
we're mostly talking about 90s to
say like 2005 to 2010 clubs yeah right
and the reason for that is that
sort of before then
like there was this immense amount of
diversity because weed was rare enough
in most places that anybody that grew
quote-unquote kind bud it all sold yeah
and it was easy to sell which allowed
people to pop seeds get stuff from seed
banks trade with their local friends and
keep this random ass [ __ ] that worked
well for them yeah right and what
happened is
you know with the purple wave and then
the sour wave and the kush wave and then
the skittles and cookies and all that is
that every huge wave came along and
instead of a whole bunch of different
people growing
all these things lots of people started
growing similar families of stuff yeah
because that's what sold well and a lot
of those other things sort of went by
the wayside so there's this enormous
amount of cuttings from like i don't
want to say matt and i's childhood but
like you know a younger time a younger
time in cannabis or whatever that like a
lot of which have fallen by the wayside
and some of which are still around but a
lot of which were super famous at the
time
because it hadn't had to be so mono crop
yep right and so when when monocrop
didn't happen
uh before monocrop became a thing uh
this is what we all grew
and so that this is part two of that
what we grew before mono cropping yeah
pretty much is is pretty much it right
so that the cannabinoid clone list only
covered so many you know like it was
pretty comprehensive but it wasn't
all-encompassing there was a lot that
was not on there so i added a bunch um i
also
i don't know if i know not so you hadn't
seen these before or didn't have them or
whatever uh these are the old strain
books from green candy press my dad my
buddy jack
released these a while ago and it has
it's pretty much that era of 2006 to
breeders seed makers of all sorts
there's [ __ ] in here there's
excellent [ __ ] in here there's
everything in between good info bad info
but
it's a good resource for knowing what
was being at least being talked about
growing around these times yeah they did
the cannabis indica volume one through
three and then they did the um
the cannabis sativa volume
one through three and these are on
amazon still so grab them while they're
still around um it's a great question
for coming in hard and fast so i'll
throw something out there real quick
i'll interject
people are talking a ton about the white
family and white widow yeah and we've
mentioned this but you know uh when the
white family hit in the mid 90s it was
like a tidal wave in cannabis
uh it became the biggest one of the
biggest most popular cuts and lines in
weed for about five to eight years
perhaps
and so as a result it got crossed with
almost everything else good
right
and
it it is there everything white is in
this era that we're talking about all
the great white shark and white widow
and white rhino and blue widow and
all the numerous things because that was
one of the first strains that like lots
of people got and then were like i'm
gonna cross it to everything cool i have
yeah so white russian
uh you know there's a bunch of the white
family it was like an og kush
of its day
yeah where people got it and it was like
the thing
you know yes so
that's it it's definitely and it still
percolates around here and there it's
probably in more things than people
realize
yeah because the names just got changed
you know
so
um but we're gonna kind of do this thing
with uh
with matt where he's got a big
[ __ ] list and we're gonna rapid fire
off some stuff and do some off the head
what we think about it what we remember
experiences and so forth
and he's got the list so i don't know
what's coming but we'll see
yeah one second
i was gonna invite archive on but he's
uh hitting the airplane um
yeah so some of these on this list some
of them like i may have no knowledge
about it and
not so might not either but i put it on
the newsletter
because it was something going around at
the time so at least we can uh kind of
acknowledge it i mean there's there's so
many that didn't end up on this list
that that i mean there might be a
part three part four part thirty it can
grow yeah it's just the framework to
riff off of for the most part about
history and strains of old and their
impact
so i also didn't choose specific seed
lines
unless
they had a clone in it that was well
known so there's a lot of seed lines in
here like white rhino where
like in the us i don't remember a
specific white rhino clone going around
there wasn't there wasn't an elite that
like at least that made it onto the
national like forum and like traded
scene
yeah
okay so last week we left off with
matanuska valley [ __ ] and we did
indeed
and right after that comes og kush
so one of the things i was thinking when
covering og kush we could just do a
quick rundown of some of the og clones
that were some of the more early clones
that were named
okay
um
so as far as i know
uh i'll start with four and matt can
riff off that if he wants there's
obviously whatever you want to call the
og kush that uh uh matt bubba and josh
brought west to l.a
uh there's that that started the whole
la thing yeah um you know there's the tk
yep right um there's uh an old one
called the master that's not a bubba og
that i'm not sure where it came from and
there's supposedly the you know the
flowrider
okay um and then
from there from a bunch of bag seeds and
everything else it exploded into you
know uh and there's debate on that too
so like you know if i left off some
important thing or whatever don't get
all pissy it's like a hugely convoluted
family with a lot of weird origins
okay um yeah we have uh early on let me
see sfv
uh larry
um we have
tahoe
we have the solo assassin one through
three we have um so i have to close my
eyes to
see it sorry uh the souls has a one
through three we have um we have the
face offs i can't remember how many
there were the face offs uh archive can
say um then of course the 92 which who
knows when that's from there's a whole
like pure kush family yeah there's one
as far as i know there's one pure kush
and then everything else people called
pure kush which was a og cut um what
were some of the other ones uh louis of
course
um
they're they're like private reserve og
the weird ones that that could have been
anything the platinum og skywalker og
was early fire og thank you uh paris
paris for me was later i don't know that
came later there's uh the f-cut
i mean yeah so there's an aspect where
you could literally walk into a club in
la in 2009 or something or eight and it
would be like 25 listed ogs from
different people
yep like it took over southern
california and as a result of that some
of those are probably renamed some of
those are probably bag seeds
you know there was like i mean it was
literally went from like
we don't even know how many cuts and if
there were sisters to each other it does
seem a few different cushy things came
out of florida via different people yeah
and hit california and spread from there
yeah and then it exploded into its own
family but it's like a whole episode in
itself so if we want to keep to like the
the timeline or whatever of uh reading
off more plants we could probably talk
about og for an hour yeah those are the
ones like and and there were other ones
but uh that people are naming but those
were most of the early ones you know i
hear people constantly saying oh we got
that diamond og you know that old [ __ ]
and i'm like no
there was like a very small list of the
og's that were going around and then
everything after that was
shut off after that like you know the
planetary ogs that people mentioned were
later renamed and stuff but it was
during this time the planetarium g's
were going around
um p91
p91 um i'll let matt talk about this one
much more than me it's his it's his
wheelhouse
it's an old san diego strain there's a
lot of different stories behind it a lot
of different claims to who has made it
um everything from saying it was like
the g13 story strapped to a berkeley
story um
yeah there's all kinds of crazy crazy
different things it could be i think
it's some kind of like
uh
i could see silver pearls super skunks
some kind of afghani somethings
but yeah it's a what most people
consider a classic old indica pre-dating
the og craze in socal it was one of the
big ones like bull rider and all the
others um
yeah it's it's it's got its name p91
either from class of 91
or
peanut 91
we don't know there's just
endless arguments but it does have a a
weird nutty
profile uh nutty kind of
accurate it's weird man it's weird it's
a good cut though
um yeah so next
next we got pez i don't know pets very
well pez
you know uh csi has it yes it's a
northern lights type plant
it's one it's one of those ones where
you get frustrated because you wish that
is it five by two is it nl skunk one is
it this that whatever but it got renamed
but it looks like a classic
90s nl
yeah you know in that like it's bright
green and has those nice hairs that like
you know yeah it just looks like a
classic bag of 90s hydro to me
all right um here's one that's your
wheelhouse
perps
perps maybe talk about your perps and
other perps
um you know uh
yeah perps is just i mean perps has been
with us forever i think
in a way there's a lot of plants up in
my neck of the woods that
turn purple with fall
um but then sort of the ones that like
everybody is kind of familiar with
you know is the mendo p and then all the
stuff that got famous on the purple
cribs yeah right uh the urkel the great
babe we chatted about that a bunch and i
mentioned
most of the story of the mendo p but i
believe it's it's from the late 70s
grown in mendocino county and put in
this dude's closet for a couple decades
until i got it in the late 90s yeah um
and i have no idea what it is except for
he remembered where he grew it because
he said it was the only purple wheat he
ever grew and it was grown in kovalev in
the late 70s
uh and i tend to believe him just
because it tests like very within the
range of most 70s cannabis yeah uh and
you you breed with it and it's got just
an enormously wide gene pool so i
remember i had something i wanted to ask
you i thought about it earlier today
with the perps so
when you talk when you told the story
you were talking about how he gave you
some seeds in a bag of weed and the
seeds he gave you were from the 70s but
when you brought it back he said oh
that's that purple one do you think it
was from the same era
so the thing is is that he thought he
was giving me different seeds
yeah and i can't even remember what it
was supposed to be
um
and like i said i only there was only
two of them that popped one male and one
girl the boy died
and when i got this weed it was so royal
purple and smelled so crazy yeah i
didn't know what it was so i brought it
to him and i said this doesn't look like
you know what it was supposed to be and
the only reason why i know the year is
because he said
that's the only purple weed i ever grew
and i grew it here
okay and so that's really that's really
all i know he didn't know jack he just
said it was you know they were playing
around with with like afghans and stuff
that wasn't sativa that was faster
guys were starting to mix that in you
know or whatever yeah and so they were
trying stuff and he said he grew up one
year that's it that's all i know
oh no [ __ ] yeah so that's it that yeah
that's okay so he the you're applied to
the the purse not the other so i got it
and so i got it and yeah i got he didn't
he didn't tell me a year
until and he said the only reason why he
even remembered that year is because it
was the only time he grew weed that was
purple like that got it you know so
um so he remembered the year later when
i actually showed him flour
yeah
and you know uh csi's bred with it a
bunch i have other people have it it's
obviously it's it's super super terpy
low thc
and super wide band as far as diversity
yeah there's a lot in there
yeah you know so okay
and when i got it in 1998 so at the time
those seeds were 21 years old 22 years
old yeah 21 years old something like
that
you know and that was now that was 24
years ago
you got people obsessing over your
[ __ ] hair it's killing me all right
yeah
all right so um
purple i was going to do purple indica
but since fletch is getting on a plane i
don't want to cover purple window
because i've never grown pure purple
indica so i can't really comment on it
um but you can see our last
interview with archive and we covered
purple indica pretty well there so it's
a good uh call back to that episode
which is available
on youtube and spotify and all that
purple purple
what was your first experience with her
when's the first time you saw it and
smoked it and your your feelings on it
uh probably 2003 2000 2003
okay for sure easily 2003 um it started
getting passed around mendo as uh you
know the thing to grow
yeah it was super slow growing uh but
there was a huge demand for it yeah you
know i still think there's a fairly
mysterious origin of it or whatever
uh and uh you know yes so it's one of
the few strains that has gotten that
famous
that we don't know like a crew that came
out with it yeah we only have like some
certain claims that are
not
nobody's sure
nobody's really there's some claims to
it but nobody's really sure
um and you know the lavender and which i
think later got attributed to soma but
i'm not sure if it it the one that got
famous is yeah yeah
um but the lavender and the earth came
at the same time
yeah you know and my buddy that gave me
the tanjo um he got the lavender from
mckinleyville humble
uh
in humboldt and i had gotten the urkel
from a source in mendo and we showed
each other flour and they were pretty
similar
yeah they weren't exactly the same but
like we got the cuts those two cuts
within six months of each other
i remember my first experience with
urkel was something similar and i saw a
cut of lavender around the same time and
they were obviously related the the
oracle cut and lavender cut to me were
obviously related so from that point on
i always assumed that urkel must have
come from the lavender seedline you know
because i saw the clone that must be
real lavender but i don't know if if
that was just like an oracle bag seed
rename just being sold as lavender
because lavender was pop popular um yeah
my so my opinion is that the original
urkel and the original lavender were
were somewhat closely related
and they popped up on the scene and up
here in the basically at the exact same
time but then soma has a line that he
sold for years named lavender yes and so
anybody that pops seeds of that would
obviously call it lavender
and so there's different lavenders that
float around
there's also
someone from oregon that claims they
made that lavender i can't remember his
name off the top of my head but claims
he made it and that soma hijacked it
from him and the guy was known for
making other stuff too so it wasn't like
a just a random bold claim it was it was
something that might have merit it's
very interesting yeah and then it's so
it's like one of those things where um i
just think that
like the urkel is a little easier
because there was one irk
and you know and then the lavender it's
like there was the cut that i remember
and then there was
soma selling thousands of seeds of
something called lavender yeah
and so a lot of people think that the
lavender is somas
yeah a lot of people apparently think
it's mad farters too but that's uh
that's been
tantamount i mean it's been disproven
it's been smashed to the people but i i
the first lavender i saw was before soma
was selling seeds of it so yeah um i
don't i don't think you know
yeah
all right um so someone mentioned this
in here and i think it's it's a great
one to bring up do you have experience
with permafrost
permafrost yeah i actually don't but i
do think that that and like coral reef
or something are two things that homey
archive has been hunting for
yeah and i do remember permafrost from
smoking it from some of those uh ron
parties in the early 2000s
but i never grew it myself so i don't
have a bunch of comments on it
i only got it and passed it um
to an idiot but um it's a white widow
train wreck if i remember correctly
that's what people said it was that's
about all i had to comment on i never
got to grow it like that it was potent
it had a nice flavor it was super frosty
uh i just remember
snow yeah a little bit in my head well
you crossed white widow i mean train
wreck and white widow are both pretty
crystally things yeah in that era or
whatever so it had that half you know i
don't know it it was pretty
all right um let's see
purple effects
purple effects uh purple effects was uh
made by uh me if you can consider
accidents uh made by someone uh totally
oh
so i had i had this strain called
effects which was a garlic bud um yeah
that tim blatt one of tim blake's main
workers gave to me in the late 90s
and um
you know and so
i uh
i had this room going of a bunch of
different stuff and it was summer and an
air conditioner died and it got hot for
a couple of days until we repaired it
and the mendo p as it can sometimes do
um it hermed all over the purple effect
all of the effects
right so i ended up with these two
effects plants that had hundreds of
mendo p seeds
yeah right
um and out of that those seeds came what
we call the purple effects yes uh it's
in the can of bible uh a couple of them
i think i don't know we grew up yeah we
we grew it a bunch
uh it had
it was it's really killer weed uh the
the turpogs used it in rose and in
sprite and some stuff like that it's
been floating around laytonville
um it's the first it's the first
breeding that ever happened with the
mendo p
yeah uh it was it was feminized uh years
before i even knew what that meant
yeah in the era that we were even
suspect that using the seeds might be
[ __ ] [ __ ] up
yeah because they were all herm seed
but i did it anyway because i loved the
plants so much and all i had was two
females so yeah you know and it came out
so so yeah that's that's the purple
effects
yeah that's one of those like i don't
know if it's necessarily a myth because
it is true that if something hurts it
has that trait it may pass it on to the
progeny but it also might not it also
might not be triggered by something that
normally would trigger stuff so it it
you know it that was one of those things
for sure that i always heard was oh you
better not pop don't make with the herm
you're gonna get herms
somebody asked how did the accident
happen uh the mendo p
herms
right and if she undergoes uh
environmental stress
it often makes her throw bananas yeah so
uh like i said it was summertime the ac
broke it got hot for a couple of days
until we could get the ac repaired
um and she threw some bananas and just
happened to pollinate the plants that
were right next door on the tray
whenever you're mad you often throw
bananas too it's really weird you know
so yeah so that was that was the purple
effects it floated around it's in any
number of different things it's really
it's really terpe
uh and it's pretty potent
all right um
scentsy star i mean this is one of those
where there's pretty much one
main clone going around that a lot of
people had or at least one expression
that
commonly popped up enough to be passed
around as multiple clones maybe um did
you ever grow any scentsy star i grew it
for a little bit and to be perfectly
honest uh i got rid of it
um
and uh i didn't i just thought of it as
kind of a boring afghan oh my god one of
our friends is so mad at you right now
i know that doesn't mean that i grew the
one you know but that's true later on
later on one version at least became
pretty famous
um and uh luke is one of the people from
paradise seeds
he's refused to give any lineage or any
information about it
it wasn't offered for all that that long
i don't think
uh yeah it was not his regular seats but
his feminized seats i don't think he's
ever stopped offering it you don't think
he's ever stopped offering his family
yeah so i just meant i don't you know
the regular seeds was what like it was
like a four or five year period or
something not i don't even think it was
a four or five year period i think he
gave someone testers that was a friend
that person reproduced them which caused
him to say [ __ ] that i'm only doing
femmes from now on as i understand it
wow so
yeah and uh it it it gets claimed to be
so it's it's it seems to be a pretty
good breeder there's a cut that floats
around
um i mean there's a there's another cut
that floats around that was called
uh scentsy star but is actually like a
nirvana four-way something something oh
wow i could see that kind of translating
a little bit and confusing people though
yeah you know and so yeah there's
there's like a history to it but
unfortunately it uh it wasn't offered
for very long and um
you know there's a couple cuts that
float around
you know and that's the other thing too
it's like not everybody thinks
everything is elite
yeah so sometimes you might get
something and grow it and it's not for
you or it wasn't the right environment
for it and you have better things and
you just move on
and other people it's the bee's knees
yeah
um
i think we just recently did snow but
you can cover it again real quick just
to plug it in here
we did uh snow got famous in oregon
yep it was called it was often called
oregon snow or eugene snow even
uh it made its way down to humble and
got called humboldt snow yeah uh it was
cropped by a bunch of people uh csi used
to run it from he's had a cut of it
since the late 90s
um and it was brought out from florida
by a couple people i know and it was
called skunk five in florida yeah
and it's a low terp super frosty afghan
that occasionally can be absolutely
delicious and at other times can be a
little bland yeah uh but it's super
potent it's a great breeder
uh it seems anything you cross it to
makes nice plants
and it's a it's a heirloom
yeah
and it's pretty purple isn't it like
pretty it can purple up pretty good you
can get purple up at the end sure yeah
yeah okay
we've done whole episodes on sour but
might as well
go ahead i mean the the the cool part i
guess about sour is that more people in
the sauer family are starting to speak
up recently yeah that were involved um
you know vondo swell manny you know
people that really hadn't spoken up very
much
and so they've confirmed some things
um you know sour sour came according to
them came from diesel 2 which they
called headband so the first headband
was a very sour type
um skunk type plant
that they found some seeds in
yeah and they called it our diesel and
that led to sour diesel
it's been it's been covered but and that
is and that was something that you know
the headband story and the confusion
around that
a lot of tales spawned around it with
people claiming they had the real new
york city headband they had the real
this
you take a famous story that's light on
detail and you're going to get people to
fill in detail
sure right you sure will and so with
manny and some of those other guys
coming out and telling their side of the
story we actually have some stuff that
used to be just a version of the story
yeah be kind of become the story
yep so that's cool
and and someone was asking about the
original new york city diesel that's
exactly what we just talked about yeah
and there's there's a further
complication and that in that diesel was
slang for fireweed in new york city back
then yes which is why they called the
bag our diesel when they gave it to
homey
because they wanted to differentiate it
from all the other diesel coming around
and there's another cut named original
diesel
which may or may not be the cut matt has
but there's a different guy that has it
that's just the first diesel that he got
in vermont and he stuck that label on it
you know so
um
anyway yeah yeah uh and jesus was called
jesus because it was jesus diesel yeah
one of the people in the chem crew
yeah [ __ ] diesel yes the cop diesel
another great name that nazar calls it
um the cockney so there's all k so yeah
it's it's it's one of those things where
it could be an entire episode we're
trying to condense it
but and we've talked about it before so
yeah we have a whole episode about it um
shoreline did you ever get to try any of
the recent shoreline from our crew i did
not no
i'm not in the secret secret cool club
but apparently not so i will let i will
let matt describe the shoreline
so i i got to try outdoor versions and
indoor versions and
um the indoor was
like hot garbage very well done i don't
think it would it reminds me a lot of
lemon g in the way the bud is formed in
that it's not as pretty as modern weed
that people would love but it is very
it's resinous and it's it's not
airy airy but it's not super dense like
uh like cookies or any of those kinds um
it did smell like hot garbage i wouldn't
say roadkill skunk i would say hot
garbage but that's my nose someone else
might totally
smell something skunky as [ __ ] in it and
i could see how it could lean that way
because of the hot garbage not there's a
little sweetness to it there's a little
bit of terpenoline somewhere in the
background i think um now the outdoor
version had the hot garbage but it also
was loud as [ __ ] with piss with and when
i say cat piss or i mean like human piss
like not like terpinelli it was the
closest thing to catfish smelling that
actually smelled like urine
so what's funny about weed
is that there are aromas in weed that
are uh are strangely attractive yeah
that would be horrific in any other
context yep
um you know halitosis yeah
yeah i mean some people liking the chem
d to a dead body
you know and things of that things that
would be universally gross
yeah you know uh end up in weed because
that description is sounds horrible to
be honest yeah i mean it's not horrible
we have a bunch of friends that love it
it's good weed i'm not dissing it but i
just mean that like when matt was
speaking about it
yeah
you know it doesn't sound appealing i
don't know if you're ordering that on
the menu as the guy prevents the
specials you know
yeah yeah it smells like hot garbage and
human pee
yeah dead bodies actually smell like
sweet [ __ ] if you didn't know that sweet
sweet
rotten meat feces like when meat rots in
a trash can for too long and sweet
we have some good friends that run it uh
multiple good friends that run it and so
it's in our it's in our uh pretty close
circle of friends and it's a really good
cut
uh it has a pretty complicated lineage i
like the height too we had a very good
high i wouldn't say it's wickedly potent
it's not bad it's not bad at all it can
hold its own yeah i mean you know me the
uh good highs are our base one
yeah it's the most important thing so
what's next
strawberry cough
um i like the cough quite a bit
the strawberry cough i think grown grown
especially organically it's a really
nice tasting
up energetic buzz yeah
um i don't know how much i believe about
the story
i don't believe it you know i think the
story is pretty suspect i think the
person that tells it is pretty suspect
uh hi kyle um but uh you know but it is
but it's a great cut yeah it is a good
cut i don't i don't believe much about
the story but i i i like the weed quite
a bit
i've worked a lot with uh the erd beer
lime which is a swiss strawberry sativa
and i've worked a lot with strawberry
cough
expressions in the strawberry cream that
was from a strawberry cough s1
i was positive
absolutely positive that
that expression is just an herb beer
expression which is a super strawberry
resinous not necessarily mega potent but
it's not terrible very dense
um
the the old herb beer and strawberry
cough are damn near identical i i mean
it could be a hybrid of it of some sort
i don't even know if the years match up
but god damn if they're not identical in
every way so who knows who knows i would
agree with that assessment i think at
its best it tastes really nice it has a
good uplifting high it's not
overpowering and doesn't have any
paranoia and it's not knock you down
strong but it's not weak either
yeah it work it works pretty well it
burns nice when done well you know it's
a pretty nice little plant
yeah
um
train wreck
uh train wreck to me
is uh is famous for a couple reasons one
it was one of the first named clones
that got passed around
in humble and mendo as a named clone
yeah like i think caleb would even say
it's probably one of the first things
that he got
yes like that was that had a name to it
it wasn't just like seedlines or
whatever right
and it yielded big and it was frosty and
it looked good um and it uh so it got
grown a ton
and it uh you know it was strong
terpenoline so it was a lot of people's
first experience with a terpenoline bomb
type strain yeah
and it had its moment in the sun and now
there's a bunch of debate about the real
one or the fake ones we have a good
friend of ours uh we have several good
friends of ours actually that that do
work with with train wrecks
um and they're a cool plant
you know it flowers actually pretty fast
outside
yeah for all of its sativa
characteristics and all that
um it actually because i think it
triggers quick
yeah
like is what happens
i love train wreck i love the high from
it
the resin production it does breed
dominant for those the the heavy terpene
terps
but i i love the high from it for me
it's all ant anxiety some people it
[ __ ] spins them out so i don't
recommend it for everyone but uh yeah
our buddy um pack from santa cruz goat
farm has a bunch of train wreck
reversals fem lines right now on
rideseats.com so go check them out
yeah and it was it was it was nice buds
that got thrown on a big sativa frame
yep a lot of people would get two pounds
of light growing it
uh so it became popular
you know
i i see it coming back and and it's
going to come back strong i think in
hybrids i think
i think on its own it's very novel for
the first you know if it's new to you
it's novel and cool and different um if
if you've grown a lot of jack and a lot
of durban a lot of peddling stuff it may
not be as cool but in the hybrids it
[ __ ] it shines it shines
yeah and what's funny about it is in
that era people called terpenoline train
wrecked hers yeah and then that got
dethroned by jack terps it sure did
she did because jack came along and took
the title
yeah away
um and and train wreck never didn't get
talked about in that regard but in that
era it was so strong torpedoline
you would talk about train wreck terp
yeah train wreck it smells like train
wreck
it smells like the wreck here's one that
you have a lot more experience with
especially the original and that's the
trinity
the trend
yeah so it it is my introduction to the
trend was basically
um there's some people that know that
are more tied into it than i was but it
is one of these things where supposedly
it came out of a bag seed that came from
trinity county
that was traded to a glass blower um
that was traded to a glass blower for
some some pipes and they sprouted that
seed in the eugene glassblowing area
seen right
and it sort of started spreading around
that little group
yeah
you know um and it was kind of a
dinosaur leaf plant some people got
skunk off it some people got
burnt rubber some people got like a
sweet pine it seemed to vary
um and it got really popular in oregon
and then
everyone lost it and disappeared for a
long time
yeah um but it's a cool plant
and and people are asking about the goat
monkey one that's the same one that we
have all gotten and grown in our circle
too and uh i i don't i didn't have
experience with the original trinity so
i don't know i couldn't say if it's real
or not but i know um csi and inspector
and um and not so or
attempting to figure that out in some
way shape or form by reaching out to the
original dudes yeah and i mean part of
the part of the issue is too is that i
have a bunch of friends that had it
but then what is your 15 or 18 year old
memory yeah that's so that really does
play into it when you haven't seen
something in a super long time but you
had it in 98 or 99 can you absolutely
guarantee
yeah you know um and most people that
think it's not it uh think it's like uh
it's it's at the very least the hybrid
yeah
um half my friends think it's it the
other half are and most of the people
that aren't sure it's it is because they
people can grow it's so nice now it
doesn't look like it
yeah
in a way it gets a little bigger than
what they remember
yeah and that's the thing we grow so
much different than we used to and
people don't realize how vastly
different people grow than they used to
but you know what's funny about that is
so i got it back and then that was the
year that i got evacuated from my spot
due to a fire yeah and then it froze and
so i had some small trends out there and
they went through hell and almost died
but they came back and finished
yeah um and every person i showed that
jar it was like leafy and sparse buds
and all that everyone thought i had the
nose to the tee
yeah and
everyone was convinced it was it
and then the next year i grew it in
perfect conditions in a greenhouse and
fully organic and fed it really nice and
it came out with fat buds and then
people were like oh it looks too nice
yeah it can't be the trend
you got it to get nice buds yeah that's
impossible it's it's a leafy shitty
see-through
type of strain yeah so you know
the good part is is the one that's the
one that's floating around right now
yeah
it's strong weed and people are often
surprised when they smoke it how high
they get
oh interesting regardless so yeah it
knocked pip on his ass that's funny it
did it it surprised him how stoned he
got we didn't even finish the joint
when he was visiting one time um so
regardless of whether or not it's
actually the real one the one that
floats around is an excellent strain in
my opinion let's show i'll i'll clown on
myself to show how different people grew
at least me in 2006 than now this is a
picture of clockwork of me trying like
it's vastly different there's no resin
production on this thing you know what i
mean a lot of people are growing like
that going through these old books like
that is just what we looked like back
then
nobody
yeah there wasn't really a lot of
self-assessment going on and i have you
know i have friends
that talk about that where you know they
grew in five gallon pots with plain
water
and all in soil amendments
with metal halides in oregon in a
rudimentary 397 you know your 1997 setup
yeah
you know and you know you're obviously
25 years later if you're still growing
lead you're probably better at it
yeah and then i was growing in 100
degree rooms like no like no issues just
[ __ ]
um
so
i believe
oh williams wonder did you go to the mlb
or any of the williams winter cuts going
around i have grown williams wonder
the one i like it
it's not particularly potent but it is a
large yielding and to me like sweet and
very old-school stelling smelling
afghan that stacks yeah it's kind of
it's not brown it's a little tannish
maybe
in kind of the way that it grows yeah
like the the bud formation or whatever
um and there's still people in the
pacific northwest or at least was five
or six years ago that we're growing it
selling it to old people getting three
pounds of light
so it floats around
yeah um and then you know various
breeders have used it because anything
that has a tendency to throw donkey dick
style buds
they want to mix that into their seed
lines oh sure especially back then yeah
so
you know
um
but it's one of i think it's one of
those old seed lines that like
people get excited about and it would
probably occasionally throw a really
nice plant but it probably has a decent
propensity of junk
yeah
and if you want the truth you know a lot
of those 80s and 90s varieties had some
crazy elites in them
but they might have like a 20 of it
might be trash
that's the way i feel like going back
and looking at a lot of the different um
80s and 90s indicas that were being
pushed out from
um
uh amsterdam the their afghanis the
different afghani blends and stuff the
hash plants and stuff there was a lot of
uh [ __ ]
just subpar stuff it's hard looking
anyways you know cookies kind of changed
the game as far as requiring what weed
needs to look like yeah people were
certainly willing to accept much uglier
cannabis
as long as it worked well
yeah smoked good
you know
okay now we're going to enter the list
of things that we've added in or
what have you um do you want to start
with your list or mine uh you go for
yours okay
um first is going to be crystal chunk
since it's fresh on your memory crystal
chunk uh this one could also be for a
while uh so the crystal chunk i actually
found out a little bit more about just
this past couple weeks
so
how crystal chunk is important to me is
that it was the first clone that my
friend gave me
um to grow indoor with yeah in my one
lighter
right we all remember our first and so
it yeah i grew the crystal chunk and
then there was a number of people in
chicago that grew the crystal chunk it
made its way out to
colorado it made its way to montana
and there was various circles of people
that grew it it was uh
um it was an nl of some kind it was
popped in 88 or 89 in carbondale
illinois
um and it was a number of things these
guys used to go to to neville every year
and buy seats
and then they would come back to
carbondale which is in far southern
illinois it's a college town down there
and they would blow up indoors
and then in order to not get busted in
their college town
they would sell the weed in the huge
city of chicago like four hours north
right and that cat and that kept them
anonymous in their hometown
right and so that's the chunk the chunk
is some kind of nl from neville in 88 or
89. i don't know if it's still alive i
think not
yeah i have some friends that have
hybrids in it
um i brought it to california in 98 when
i moved out here
i lost it in o3 i think maybe so
um but it's a cool one
super potent
low odor low low smell low taste do we
know if that clone's still around i
don't
my buddies that i just my buddies that i
just went and visited said that it
existed as late as 2013.
oh wow so we're still kicking around
till then and there's c and they gave me
some seeds of it uh
not pure you know not river
but but but mixed with other [ __ ] so
we'll see
other cool [ __ ] yeah 100 yes other
questions
i'm excited to hear about that sometime
uh deep chunk somebody just said finally
hearing about crystal chunk first kind
but i experienced so interesting that's
i mean those guys down in carbon deli
grew a bunch they grew but they had more
than that um um but that the chunk kind
of got spread around a little bit and
became pretty famous in those little
circles
yeah you know uh
did you say deep chunk deep chunk
deep chunk is pretty famous in various
ways i would say uh
it floated around mendocino we were just
talking about this yesterday
it floated around mendocino uh because
that's kind of where one of the places
it was developed um
as monkey balls
yes
cabbage we all called it monkey balls
back then because it was like golf ball
size purplish super
you know chunky
uh some were frosty
uh and it was grown a lot on spy rock
yeah and so a lot of people i knew that
grew grew it grew it out that way then
it became famous in another way because
tom hill made it and he ended up
becoming pretty famous on the forums
yes
uh right and so he had he had a with vic
high and other he became very he was
sort of one of the big personalities
for a long time on on the forums i would
say yeah
right he was uh super intelligent super
knowledgeable super cantankerous
yeah uh you know didn't have a lot of
patience for idiocy
oh he suffered no fools no he didn't
have a lot of patience for idiocy and
then it might actually be
uh
it might actually be one of the only
ibl's out there
yeah that's i noticed someone was saying
that they just have seen people taking
it to f13
on
selling and selling seeds of it like
deep chunk was already as close to ibos
you're going to get if people keep
taking that inwards generations i'm not
sure what they're trying to achieve
other than making more seed maybe um but
eventually you're gonna suffer from some
heavy heavy inbred depression no matter
what you do with it at that point it was
already
it was already where it needed to be
yeah there's people saying purple monkey
balls monkey balls was pretty common in
mendo like if you got cold october
nights
yeah most of the plant would purple up
you know yeah and and in that regard and
so it was like that's how i got
introduced to it it's just one of those
old-time hill strains
yeah
um and the problem with purple chunk in
my or you know deep chunk in my opinion
is that it is what it is
and it breeds very much like itself
yeah and you're not going to be
surprised
yeah
yeah so if you like that and that's what
you want to add in and you want to add
in some of those qualities
um you can
yeah um i've seen very good
um
seedlines of deep chunk i know uh csi
inspector has some
and uh kos the rev has an amazing one
but i've seen very very
bad resin less
just
terrible deep chunks which a resin this
deep chunk is a disappointing thing yeah
so it can you know on the right the
right hybrid the right outcross
it can pop yeah and it can lend
qualities to it that make it overall
amazing
uh and it can also just kind of be a
very boring leafy
not fun high afghan yeah
someone asked it's a good question and
and it'll be uh good to answer something
a lot of people probably don't
understand this if plants get inbreeding
depression
how do you get land races so land races
are constant
big populations wild populations and
there is some inbreeding that goes on
but because it's a wild diverse
population it's always going to be a
little bit diverse as it goes you know
some do get inbreeding depression some
and lots of land races are just pure
like cbd heavy low thc you know herm
machines and that's just what cannabis
wants to be another another way to
describe the scale of it
is that um
when we talk about inbreeding depression
mostly we're talking about small indoor
greenhouse style selections with maybe
you know like you know anywhere from one
to a few males perhaps and you know
certain amount of females where what
matt was describing
if you're in mexico or
thailand or whatever is fields of weed
yes with thousands of brothers and
sisters
right yeah and that's where the seeded
comes from and so as a result of that
you're going to get like a much wider
population it's when we start messing
with them in much smaller non-field size
environments yeah that you can get
inbred pretty quick
oh yeah
somebody was asking him if we can speak
on tom hill's haze
yeah i mean there's not a clone that
goes around to that so um but yeah it's
a it's a famous strain of his
um if it was
pretty notorious for the fact that like
dog would tell people you know you need
a good 10 packs to find a keeper it just
is what it is on that um it was from
positronics um their haze 19
is is
from sam's haze if i remember correctly
yeah so yeah he positronics is one of
the three people besides sam that sam
gave hayes to when he went to
um amsterdam yeah he gave it to neville
he gave it to corel from uh super sativa
seed club and he gave it to pozzi yeah
and he actually worked at pozzi for a
bit uh as far as like just helping
making breeding selections and things of
that nature so tom hill's haze is from
um the haze that sam gave to pozzi yeah
and it's i saw a lot of hey hey
would be a great name for it because
it's very hay and carroty and
lots of hay
lots of carrot
hay
but
i did see some really beautiful um
uh examples of it from hazy lady over on
mr nice and i'm not sure she deleted her
account after key play attacked her but
um their those pictures might still be
up there and if you want to see a
beautiful haze look for hazy ladies
h-a-z-y-l-a-d-y or uh grove tom hill's
hayes and there's an aspect too where
like even when even when like the flying
dutchman or whatever was selling sam's
haze yes his ohays or whatever you know
um they even said that like only 10 of
them are gonna be
you kind of have to hunt a lot and
there's a lot of junk in that haze
and the problem with haze is that since
most of it goes 16 to 24 weeks
you know searching for the needle in a
haystack and having the space to run a
hundred of them
yeah and then smoke test them and figure
out which one or two are the ones that
are good and the rest are mostly bunk
yeah that's hard
yeah it's time consuming and jungle weed
and a lot of space
okay uh silver pearl did you get to try
uh pipsque
oh yeah
what do you think
it reminded me of the silver pearl i
knew in the 90s
um in the sense that uh this is gonna
sound gross again but
it has this like there's this thing when
babies are first born
and all they drink is milk and they're
getting a lot of their mom's like
colostrum or whatever yeah and baby poo
kind of has this like sweet
like it's
it's just it's not really all that gross
yeah right and then they start eating
real different foods and it's like then
it's just [ __ ] you know but yeah but the
silver pearl has this kind of like sweet
young young baby poo
type smell
um and i smelled that in his cut
so wild i got pick out like bubble gummy
but not pink bubble gum like some kind
of sweet
and then
not skunky but somewhere along that
direction it was so hard to describe but
it's one of my favorite smells i mean
the other thing is that like you know i
i had kids and you didn't so
there's a point when you have aromas
that what reminds you of what you have
like we talk about how there's no skunks
in europe you have to be actually
exposed
to the smell
to have smelling something else trigger
that memory yes i i've not got my nose a
baby [ __ ] yeah yeah
so you know
the silver pearl was to get a little bit
more specific
um i believe silver pearl is a mix of
early girls skunk one and nl5 yes
um and it is a pretty leafy
frosty nice smelling
you know uh uh
you know
it was an early poly hybrid from neville
it was it's a great uh resin dumper for
like dry sift and [ __ ] too it is so
frosty but it is so leafy
it's leafy and very frosty
and you know back then especially like
most things were most things that were
getting released were f1s yeah and so
that was that was sort of in the first
wave of poly hybrids of different
crosses he'd made and then combining
those into into different things yeah
so that's silver pearl it's a cool old
it's a cool old line from um both the
seed bank in the 80s from neville and
from the years of scentsy yep okay uh
amnesia [ __ ] haze
it wasn't this big in the u.s obviously
but i mean you can't really talk about
that era of clones with in the world
without mentioning amnesia hayes i mean
i think i think
amnesia hayes is sort of like uh
you know i don't want to be wrong here
but i associate amnesia haze with after
neville put out super silver haze and
mango haze and and neville's haze and
sort of stopped contributing yeah and
greenhouse sort of reconstituted their
seed company right yeah
that was one of the that was the thing
that came out after that right
yeah for the most part yeah yeah yeah
and some sort of super silver haze
and so there's an aspect where there's
this is highly disputed so no one take
this the wrong way
but if you listen to neville and shanti
they claim that after neville's
experience at scentsy um they didn't
want to give arjun all the clones and
seeds and and all that
um so they controlled all that and they
just gave greenhouse flour and seeds for
sale yeah so when they left to do their
own thing arjun had probably the most
famous at the time between him and
scentsy he had the most famous
award-winning
uh
seed bank
and he is his breeders left yeah
and so he brought on franco and rumor is
is that he bought 20 or 30 000 euros
worth of his own seed stock yeah
and they started breeding and doing
various things trying to come up with
seed for their seed company yeah and i
think that's where like arjun's haze one
through five and amnesia haze and you
know lemon this and all that started
happening
yeah you know um and that's that's
amnesia haze to me yeah i don't remember
who did i think it was like high pro or
order lab or one of them made amnesia or
amnesia i can't remember the [ __ ]
story but it's it's not um it's not soma
or uh
or whoever else people are saying yeah
and i think it's i think it's one of
those things too that like it's one of
those renames that like they took some
other haze in amsterdam to sell at
coffee shops and like we did in cush in
la and just gave it a new name
that one's it's good it's a it's a
almost fruity floral that's the best way
i can describe it's for penalty but it's
it's nice it's resinous it's potent i
see why it was passed around for so long
it's consistently a a great haze i think
i like it i like haze so yeah
it's good um did you ever run any blue
cheese
yeah
yeah did you have a cut you liked or
they would pass around um so when we
were chatting about those those ron's
parties and where a lot of us were
gathering in those years
um there was a lot of cool things
crossed of the blue family
and while uh i didn't really like a lot
of the straight blue stuff
yeah a lot of the outcrosses were really
good yeah um and blue cheese there was
blue widow blue cheese
um blue rhino blue rhino there was a
bunch of different blue hybrids out
crosses that i actually preferred the
straight blue lines yeah and blue cheese
was one of those ones yeah you know so
um i didn't grow it a bunch or anything
like that but it was a it was a pretty
sweet floral
you know
slightly skunk one-ish type plant yeah
you know i mean there was there was a
bunch of seeds passed around by friends
too
oh yeah
it wasn't just a cut i mean it was like
you know there was there was people that
had crosses and there was f2s
yeah so
did you ever have any experience with it
uh no but i did make a blue cheese with
the blue bonnet that i really enjoy and
that was just because so many people
over the years asked me if i had a good
blue cheese that i would recommend i'm
like blue [ __ ] cheese i did not want
anything to do with cheese in the first
place it was everywhere it was a british
thing so during those years like
whenever blue cheese doesn't [ __ ] that
what the [ __ ]
i'm not regressive but i did find that
it is a [ __ ] amazing combo and i was
just being announced
you cross cool things to skunk one and
nice things come out of it that's why
it's been a breeder standard for decades
here's one that's a little self-serving
but it was so huge in san diego that
um i think it was pretty huge everywhere
actually uh bubble berry
bubble berry
yeah
yeah did you have any of those cuts up
there
yeah we had some bubble berry
uh i believe it was it was first offered
by sag martha
yeah i think right yep yep that was a
total stream
um you know dj short sent a bunch of
blue family seeds to sag martha for them
to retail them through their their
business
and tony crossed
some blue work um
you know to some bubble gum
yep and the bubble berry was born and
the and the bubble gum is famously mold
resistant
and uh throws a very consistent type
afghan
beautiful plant yeah and the above the
blueberry added terps and color
and some frost and some attractiveness
and some other weird stuff
and so there was a good cut that floated
around that everybody kind of loved yeah
yeah
it was it was well loved in san diego
too it was one of my favorite strains
the the the bigly chew pink bubble gum
with heavy heavy like blueberry jam it's
insane and and
what's funny is
i look at the old pictures of bubble
berry from tony back in the day and he
obviously used
the same line of bubble gum that we used
however
it wasn't the same clone and and the
blue mill we used was blue bonnet and
they used a blueberry mill which similar
lines however
they look uncannily similar when crossed
and i it might be because bubble gum
breeds so true you know like
but it looks damn similar even all these
years separated different parentage but
similar to similar lineage uh it is it's
a cool looking plant and it's very
consistent when crossed even even in the
same family yeah and it's it there's
cool pictures of it from olden times
from the 90s matt the various breeders
have done work with it yep um you did
work with it
um bob did stuff with it right
you know um
bog bubble
yeah that based on it in a way
yeah like oh he was that was uh bubble
gum i don't think it was bubble berry
you don't think it was bubble berry no
it was bubble gum yeah
now or something yeah anyway it was it
was it was a cool line
it's it's a good example of how
uh when two things that are very
different from each other come together
for the first time yeah uh you can pop
some cool plants yeah
absolutely
yeah people are still talking about blue
rhino blue this blue that blue the blue
outcrosses i'll say this too there was a
very limited number of people outside
the amsterdam seed banks in the late 90s
and early 2000s that got famous on the
forums
and there were certain forums of
watching of some blueberry groves that
got everybody hyped on blueberry yep and
so people started getting blueberry and
since it was obviously red seeds they
started crossing it to other lines
and that's when all those cool hybrids
came out so like in the early 2000s blue
and blue and white hybrids what the
white widow family and the blue family
they were crossed to all kinds of things
including each other yep
all right um um maui wowie
i this is kind of a weird one because
it's one of those ones where i a lot of
people don't see the same maui wowie
twice
i think maui wowie is a lot like the
alaskan thunder [ __ ] or crippy or
diesel or you know fire
yeah you know it was probably it was
probably a sativa afghan grown on maui
yeah um and it rhymes
and that makes it easy to sell and so it
was probably applied to a bunch of
different types of hawaiian weed
yeah
i think that's probably the most
accurate thing to say about it yeah i
think that's that's that's fair how
about lamb's bread or lamb's breath
or
whatever you know i don't have any
personal experience with that one but it
was supposed to be a wild sativa like 20
25 weeks yeah that came out of jamaica
yep
and was supposed to be pretty famous it
was before
jamaica got inundated with uh your
european uh weed strains yeah and
started growing mostly dutch [ __ ]
yep um
and as a result of that it's a little
bit before my time and i don't even know
that i ever saw one that i believe was
true this is the only one that i
remember seeing and i'm like okay that
makes sense for a long flowering indian
sativa type this was the pictures from
jason king in the canada bible when he
went to jamaica and had to pay them
[ __ ] a shitload of money to take
pictures of their crops yeah i mean i'll
say the more fun you know the the the
expression on that one i could see that
thing taking 24 weeks yeah easily easily
yeah that thing's a a
calixi mess
okay um
let's move on to malawi i know there are
certain clones in malawi past i've been
oh [ __ ] my whole thing almost all over
certain clones of malawi passed around
up in humboldt right or
cal i should say um i had a malawi
uh that its biggest issue was that it it
never wanted to finish for me yeah uh
which is not a convenient tree
um
you know and uh um you know malawi is
one of those things where there's a lot
africa is probably
the continent with the most weed that we
have the least amount of its genetics
that like fresh genetics over here yeah
it seems like there was an initial
seeding during like the slave trade era
when there was an enormous amount of
ships coming from africa to the
caribbean and stuff like that yeah so a
lot of like maybe mexican and caribbean
weed
ancient origins tied to there
um but you talk about the congo and the
malawi and this and that and everything
else and
um
you know maybe durbin is the most common
thing that we have from africa swazi and
urban lots of southeastern stuff there's
this there's stuff that roll that all
that a lot of that african weed rolls
right through the equatorial region
which means that it takes forever which
means that it's a ginormous pain in the
ass for anyone in america unless it's
crossed to
something afghan that makes it yeah
yep and by manageable we usually mean
like 12 or 14 or 15 weeks or something
there's a red congolese that's pretty
tightly held by some people that they
love
yeah but that's that's kind of like that
it was crossed to some very afghan thing
to get it i remember that red congo is
like a congo afghani oaxacan or
something like it's not yeah i mean
the malawi or the com like there's you
got to do some [ __ ] to tame it
yeah you live in america you don't live
in the tropics
yeah super hard to get those to flower
under
like reasonable times indoors too yeah
you know
you have like uh
24 weeks something and it's like unless
you start light dipping it in june
you're not making your season
yeah you're screwed
you know and then you grow it inside and
it's like this jungle weed that's leafy
and takes like six months like you know
it's hard yeah
it's hard
apollo let's just say
let's let's call this the uh the the
brothers grim when i see brothers grimm
i mean sly and it with
uh some assistance from soul and
marketing let me throw in one more thing
here as we chat about this stuff there's
tons of cool comments and various
questions popping up but at the rate
we're talking about stuff there's no
chance i have to answer even most of
them so i apologize yeah
yeah i mean we're going through a like a
categorized list this time so it's
really hard to answer questions at rapid
fire you know so but if they're
important to you remember them and you
can hit me up about them later so yeah i
just wanted to throw that out there join
us on the patreon discord like she
talked about this [ __ ] all the time so
you can ask us anything all the time
and get multiple responses mostly yeah
people smarter than myself you know
um so we're going to call this the the
brothers brim selection of clones which
is princess cafe girl [ __ ] um
ginger ale cut um we got uh what else we
got uh princess cafe girl blah blah blah
there's another one oh genius genius
which leads to the apollo 13s the the
special cuts of that the apollo 11's
all that good stuff all that good stuff
c99 pineapple um what what which of
those do you have experience with them
this this ties into a bunch of stuff i
already said but um i would say that
just like dj
um the original brothers grim crew
came out at a time when there wasn't
very many non-dutch breeders doing
things publicly
so a lot of their work got heavily
spread amongst the community yeah
especially the early forum community
yeah just like dj short i just said
became famous uh brothers grim became
pretty famous there was endless posts on
[ __ ] cubing
and how he took the the original seed he
got from the jack herrera and turned it
into c99
um and you know the apollo 11 the apollo
13 the genius
um there was a whole bunch of stuff so
again when i was going to those parties
uh of bronze um a lot of the things that
were was the stuff that was the most
common to be crossed with
was the blue family the white family
um
breeder steve's work and a lot of
brothers grim
yeah um i love the genius i grew the i
had the apollo and the genius in that
era i got them from friends that i met
through there yeah they were both nice
smoke yeah
you know uh i thought i've always
thought this cinderella 99 was a little
bullshit-ish
yeah i loved absolutely loved the
pineapple fino c99 i was a sucker for it
torpedoing and pineapple together make
it taste like pineapple
i was [ __ ] fire but brothers garum
was really famous
yeah in that era
yeah so a lot of their stuff was getting
passed around a lot of their straight
clones
that people found that got names and
hybrids yeah
um i i did a lot of work with apollo 13.
that's when i chose between the 11 and
um
the 13 i chose the 13. had a lot of
really nice great phenos come out of
that
uh there was some good lemon pinots that
were more uh dense and afghani looking
than the the grape super sativa purple
looking pretty [ __ ] but um
yeah
maybe we should i know
that what we're talking about is the
original
uh
um organization of brothers grimm yeah i
don't know anything about the second
iteration
the second one where where the sly
wasn't involved and mr soul and
and
you know duke had something going on
like that was i mean there was like a
15-year break or something where there
was no seat yeah
so we're talking about the early late
early 2000s first when they first got
famous yeah not and they were
reconstituted uh decades later not when
the marketing guy tried to put it back
together put the team back together
without the team um
let's see let's skip through those we
did shoreline
here's one that i i have some
interesting info on but i can't say who
or where rfk skunk
rfk skunk yeah
you know i don't know i mean rfk skunk
was uh supposedly
um you know skunk uh
it's got a lot of things right so it's
uh rfk is is where the uh the washington
uh redskins played
right uh the the grateful dead there was
a bunch of dead shows um they was on the
when they would do their summer tour
rfk was was one of the big stadiums that
they would always play in
yeah um you know and and all that and
supposedly that rfk
uh came out of bud from rfk
i am beating myself up right now because
i just realized that
rfk is probably going to pop up tomorrow
in some lemurs list of stuff that
they're claiming to have but
yeah nonetheless
yeah it got mixed it's like so there's a
there's a whole series of like
mysterious east coast skunks from the
same area some might be renamed
right yeah um it's been rumored to be in
a bunch of different things
um but proof is low
yeah
perhaps yeah um
yeah we'll see we'll see
one might be out there of this and it'd
be growing and gonna see about it so i'm
pretty stoked because it's one that
there's very little info about out there
as far as what it was like and blah blah
blah like i mentioned with the headband
story before manny and those others
cleared it up where there's very little
info but it's still fairly famous
it allows a lot of room for people to
say
whatever they like about it yeah because
there's very little verifiable info
so maybe that is the verifiable info
yeah you don't know you know
um
romulan
romulan is another one that uh
is weird
in the sense that there's a lot of funky
stories about it
um and and they keep getting earlier and
earlier yeah um what we know for sure is
that it's canadian
um you know that's where it got famous
and when
it be i believe it basically got first
like nationally or internationally
famous
when the canadian seed companies um
started jumping into the seed game and
there was a lot of hybrids across to
romulan yeah
um and there's some stories about that
it came from mendo and like and
mendo joe and it was brought to british
columbia and it was this and this and it
came back in these crazy early years
i don't know what you think of that matt
but um
um i
from everything that i've researched on
it talking to people in bc and
other parts of canada who were around
during that time and had interaction
with those crews mendocino joe was a
hundred thousand percent not rhyming and
joe
rongolin was also not from the 40s it
sounds like it was from the [ __ ] 90s
and
if i remember correctly and i'm only i'm
only repeating because i i i'm not from
canada obviously um port alberni pine
bud was one of its first names and there
was another name something blue indica
was and then later on um
it was made popular in the 90s with a
different name change but yeah it's not
a there's no such thing as a 1940s
afghani hybrid so it's one of those
things when i hear it it just makes my
eyes cross
and it's also it's also kind of kind of
a cool thing in the sense that a lot of
cannabis names were very much
tongue-in-cheek about like pop culture
yeah and so romulan is actually you know
obviously it's a race of aliens from
star trek
yes
you know yeah yeah it's nice star trek
uh so star trek yeah so uh the romulan
did you ever have the grapefruit romulan
or the grommulin no no yeah it was it
was okay it was a weird one that went
around san diego a bunch and like no
matter what clones you were trying to
chase you'd always end up
right back at square one with grommulin
how about just grapefruit
grapefruit um there was a uh
you know there's a there's a pretty
famous pheno of uh
soma's diesel
that had grapefruit flavor yeah and some
people bred with it and
loved it a ton
and it had really strong grapefruit
terps yeah which is about as far from uh
sour turps as you can imagine but yes
yes nonetheless they really loved it
um and that's the only like and that's
the only real grapefruit i have ever
i've ever experienced there's a real
popular uh well most phenos of c99 that
are popped from seed come out very grape
fruity um to me it smells what's weird
when people explain grapefruit and give
me grapefruit but i thought super
grapefruity i always smell [ __ ]
perfume it's weird it's one of those
things where i just smell it so much
different yeah
people are talking about all kinds of
skunks and stuff like that and
i'll say something real quick i do think
in the 90s skunk was a much more
prevalent odor i do think it popped up
in hybrids a lot more frequently um
but you know uh
skunk bud tended to not be quite as
potent as some other weed uh and it had
really uh noticeable terps that got you
in trouble um and so i think it just got
selected away from too much
uh and by various people and then as as
clones changed and names changed people
went to different stuff and everyone
assumed that people would be holding it
and now it seems like a lost terp
yeah
you know and it's also possible it could
be a little bit of a recessive terp now
where it needs other genes from another
partner to like make it pop yeah and
they're buried double up double up
where in the 90s maybe it was an easy
double up and now 30 years later it's
like a rarer double up yeah
because you've talked you've talked
about i can't remember who made it but
you were telling me what was the sour
dub fino yeah it was a diesel uh
sourdough cross to reverse chisel
sour dub by diesel so you know you
matt's cross diesel to all kinds of
things and one time this one hybrid
all of a sudden throws
you know a much more
skunky [ __ ]
yeah yeah so i think that's probably
where it'll pop back up again is it will
be it'll be a lucky recessive combo yeah
i know crybaby did a gmo diesel that i
thought would probably hold it pretty
well or even a d diesel or any of those
things any any combination of the the
the like sour version of super skunk and
the short squat version of super skunk
to me seems to just kind of bring it up
uh
quite well quite well yeah i mean i
think if you start crossing i mean we've
talked about that a bunch we start
crossing different skunky things and
large enough numbers yeah and you'll
find some stuff
yeah you know um it's just not going to
be across the skunk one will take you
farther away from your goal than closer
yeah there's see a lot of people that
have had sour dub some people look at me
like silly when i say sour dub you can
grow up very [ __ ] skunky if you know
how to how to bring out skunkiness out
of strains
but some people are just like oh i never
never see it i don't know some people
have had really loud sourdough and some
people have it i'm never sure if it's
the same clone or just way different
growth styles
i mean there's definitely i you know my
friend that i visited he grows a lot of
living soil yeah and i definitely
noticed like a pretty extreme sweetness
to a lot of things you know so i
definitely think you know room
temperature and feeding and you know
type of feeding and stuff like that can
certainly different plants can
definitely bring out different aspects
yeah
so
so one that was big around the forums
during um overgrow era i believe was
jackie o did you ever see jackie oh
it was a i believe jack flash fino
crosstalk calio
indeed that was a naboo one if i
remember correctly it was pretty good it
was it was a good calio hybrid
did it taste like citrus or did it go
beyond that oh it was super citrus and
super pineally uh oh yeah yeah yeah two
extreme flavors combined in one
yes super citrus and super terpene
so then we all since we're bringing up
callio bring up calio in the melton did
you have any callio
i had calio
um
you know it was one of those things
where
maybe the funniest thing i could tell
about calio is when tangi came out and
got popular and people were lining up to
buy tons of seeds from dna and tangy
hybrids
a lot of us up here in mendo were
shocked because you know five or ten
years before
trying to give away
pure citrus smelling pounds was a tough
sell yeah it was that was there was a
there was a limited limited market and
you would get told no a lot
headache weed
a lot of the pure citrus stuff whether
it was the lemon g or the cali o or this
or that
if it's just one note
um citrus terp
a lot of people will get old on it fast
so we were amazed when tangi came out to
such
it was like citrus had gotten so
unpopular that it got it had a
resurgence because no one had smoked it
yeah because no one none of the brokers
would buy it
yeah that and that's kind of how i
looked at cheese too like when it
started getting a big resurgence i was
like gee really you [ __ ] have cheese
but i did it when i was down south i did
get to grow out a lot of caleb's calio
hybrids yeah and you can really see its
sativa origins
pop through in various and various
things especially if you cross it to
other things that like to stretch
um and uh
you know i'm not exactly sure what it is
but it's one of those original clones
that um you know went over to uh
amsterdam uh and it sounds like it came
through uh rob clark
oh interesting
you know uh he wrote about it he wrote
about it uh in the first can of bible
and that big
you know um but it people get over
people get over it because it's just
it's oranges
yep yeah i'm not a fan um spirit of 76
did you ever see that up there just in
the can of bible no yeah yeah i i see
pinkleberry that looks pretty identical
to it and that that super specific pink
pistol trait but that doesn't mean
they're necessarily related but that was
what i always wanted to see and i was
wondering if it passed around uh norcal
back then so the thing that i'll say
about that and it has nothing to do with
the spirit of 76 but it's that
growing a lot of the same strains over
the years indoor versus outdoor
yeah uh there are strains that will give
me magenta or hot pink or
crazy colored
you know those hues pistols outdoor
yeah but we'll never ever do it
inside
yeah and they don't dry to that color
yeah but there's a period of time during
their flowering cycle where you can get
i have i mean i have a bunch on my phone
um
you can get some really amazing
different stuff
yeah but only in the sun
yeah it's weird yeah it is weird and
maybe it's i wonder i wonder if one day
that leds will somehow be able to
capture that range that pushes it out
indoors
so someone just asked a pretty good
question when we said what does double
up mean and what i what i mean by that
and just like a super quick genetics
lesson and i'll use humans as the
because that's easier than plants is
like
having blue eyes
green eyes hazel eyes gray eyes that's
recessive right yeah so the only way
your kids can get it is if both parents
have the gene
yes right
if they don't um like for instance you
know i have i have i have multiple kids
i have hazel eyes my wife has green eyes
so we both have the gene
we got two brown eyes and one blue-eyed
kid
yeah
right and three tries so
you know um what i mean by double what
we mean by doubling up is
i think that that particular skunk aroma
is probably recessive now
and you'd have to find a different
parent that had that recessive trait and
grow enough of them that those two
recessives met in one plant yeah lined
up that's what we mean by doubling up
because if you don't have two parents
with the blue eye gene you can't have a
blue-eyed kid
yeah
same thing with blonde hair actually
um same thing with any number of traits
they think that humans eventually will
all be some kind of brown eyed just
because it's so dominant in so many
cultures that you know
and i think that's kind of what what
happened to skunk it just got lost
and now it'll pop out on rare cases
mr toad does not have a strain that
produces pink pistol inside mr toad is
full of [ __ ] and let's see we got the
white from chrome
uh you know you might remember more of
the history about it than i do
um i classify it in in the same way as
the snow and maybe some other things one
of those low
terpene low flavor
chunky
frosty
plants that tend to transfer that when
you breed yeah so it got mixed into a
bunch of stuff yeah it was the white
because of how frosty it was yeah it was
from from chrome from swamp boys was the
one that brought it online i i don't
remember where he said he sourced it
from somewhere in florida um
i remember there was some talk around
the time too that it was called
a white triangle or just triangle but
not triangle kush remember there was
some speculation on that i don't know
how accurate that is uh i wish we could
have chrome on to talk about a little
bit um i was associated with like
in my head with the hash plant meaning
that it's a plant that is solely for
producing hash or adding tons of resin
but it also adds earth and dirt
and mushrooms terps
so
it might be one of those things like i
neville used to talk about the nl5 yeah
how it added frost and structure and
improved lee you know caleb's the leaf
ratio yeah but it didn't taste like much
or smell like much which he liked
because it let the other side of the
breeding shine through yes so it added
and that's kind of how i think of the
white
yeah it did it did amazing with the blue
bonnet and let the blue bonnet dominate
it which is really weird for like that
recessive blue
terp in the first place that blue smell
and um that's the one thing that i found
that really married with the white well
in a single f1 hybrid usually it takes
some back crossing to
to get rid of those chirps to the white
and that's kind of a common old school
way of breeding where you take something
that's
frosty and dense with nice structure and
potent but maybe doesn't have a lot of
smell or flavor and you throw that on
something wilder growing with better
terps and better this and better that
you see if you can get
both qualities in one plant yeah
you know so
let's see it's [ __ ] incredible
not me
yeah no i i i threw it once and called
it [ __ ] awful but it was a
uh i actually have to say let me let me
add this in too is that someone just
someone mentioned that they think that
the citrus terps took off with dabs
and i do think that tangy came out at
the perfect time because a lot of that
citrus weed is pretty low potency to
moderate at best
yeah but if you make bho of it and you
make it 78 thc you're gonna get high if
you take a dab yep so in the flour form
years before it would just get it would
just be weaker and wouldn't stay around
long
yeah but you could put it through bho
and that citrus terp would come through
whether it was lemon or orange or
tangerine or whatever your brain picked
up on
and it would work yeah so for it for it
was perfect timing for extract
yeah
anyway
uh black russian
i don't really have any experience black
russian
cherry aka blackberry
uh beautiful beautiful magenta colors it
was before chitrali was super popular so
people weren't used to seeing those
beautiful magenta colors it's
responsible for like double purple doja
and sputnik and a few other things
mostly just like the blackberry but with
better cherry
nicer
uh terps and a little bit more resonance
than blackberry but still overall pretty
low potency and
mids um pretty low potency in mids
yeah unfortunately i i spent a lot of
time on on black brush a lot because i
was convinced i could pull something
good out of it and i never was able to
doesn't mean it can't be done i was just
not able to and i tried a lot
i mean we were yeah i mean it was kind
of this like that the blackberry kush
that we had in mendo was kind of the
same
yeah it was incredible looking and
people loved to grow it and it would be
absolutely gorgeous
and then sometime you just realized that
you didn't really get very high from
from smoking it
um some
i just seen the same thing up over and
over about 20 times asian fantasy we're
not talking about asian fantasy only
because that was a clone that was
supposedly never passed ever yeah and
that's it so there's no nobody has any
experience with it except for jason king
and the guy that wouldn't give it out
there was scammers that claimed to have
it and traded it out for a long time and
they still claim to have it and it's
stupid yeah it's ridiculous it's one of
those strains like
um i i don't know like creepy people
just make [ __ ] up just is what it is um
west coast dog do you have experience
with it
um i you know
i wish we have we have some friends that
have more experience with it that are
chatting on here than i do
i never really grew it it did seem like
it was one of those big yielding
you know that they could pass as chem
um so it got grown in a lot of
greenhouses and a lot of outdoor yeah um
but i don't remember its origin story
off the top of my head and i that didn't
think can and if you've never smoked him
or smoked
smelled kim you'd be like what it's a
it's it's above a hybrid probably of
some sort um it does real well outdoors
because people could move it out as
indoors it just was one of those plants
that could
one of those transitory plants that you
could pass off is indoor and that's
about it that's like i mean brokers
there's always been a history of brokers
where if they could make depths look
like ins
or they could they thought that outs
looked like depths then they could get a
higher price
for from their customers and then their
margin would be bigger which is the
point of their existence
yes exactly you know so it was like a
big i don't know i think it was one of
those ones that it was like a big
growing afghan that was kind of boring
but yeah it got cam attached to it
um let's see what else we got here
purple mr nice i know that went up in
your area did you did you grow any of
that yeah purple mr nice is a little
weird um in the sense that uh
it
it's got g3 it's supposedly got g13 in
it yeah you know and it's one of those
things that when
when neville lost women never went to
jail for 11 months and then scentsy got
him out of since he gave him a bunch of
money and got him out of jail and bought
his seed company
um
some of the things that were common in
neville seed catalog didn't port over
yeah to scentsy like any of the g13
hybrids any of the hash plant hybrids um
the maple leaf all disappeared yeah and
then in the late 90s after neville left
the maple leaf the g13 the afghani one
all those things started popping back up
yeah and i don't know if they pulled
them from seed but i think that's where
it came from
yeah is mr it's scentsy offering first
yeah right and it was it g13 by hash
plant yeah
you know hash planet one yeah it's uh
yeah it just it was like every single
g13 hash plant that was purple to me it
was it was it was narcotic enough it was
okay you know it yielded really well and
the better it yielded the worse it was
yeah that's about it yeah i mean so it's
one of those things where i always
question is like why did it disappear
the whole time neville was there
yeah and then after he left got brought
back like why didn't it stay i've never
gotten answers to that why didn't the
hash plans and the g13s and the maples
and some of those other things why did
they go off the menu yeah and then ten
years later pop off back on the menu
yeah it's a weird one um
any mangoes that you can remember
there's a ginormous mango uh
old school seed line that floats around
mendo
um because people used to be able to get
eight or ten pounds of plant off it yeah
um and they called it the mango around
here and then obviously there's the
mango haze
um but i don't know which one he's
referring to
yeah i'm not sure
um i'm just just mango in general mango
harawana
um you know i don't really i i've heard
various tales
uh about that type of stuff uh you know
uh it was supposedly grown a lot in
trinity county um
you know and um
you know extremely potent
i had a friend that used to move a lot
of it but i never had i never grew it
okay
um yeah heroin i grew a bunch of the
seedlings it was
the name was a total to me it was a a
misnomer i tried tucks i tried motor
rolls tried sanis which was motor rebels
i didn't have anything i liked it was
very low potency
some of it was resinous smelled like a
leather which is just not my my gig how
about the puck
the puck
um
you know i we we both have some
experience with the puck
uh the puck is supposedly
a
a hash plant you know
from neville from the neville seed bank
era in the late 80s
yeah it came out of uh you know it got
famous in colorado and leadville and
various places like that
some old schoolers used to carry it
around in a hockey puck
hard case
um and that's kind of how it got the
name the puck
and it's around and people breed with it
um i never had very much luck with it
because when i had it i was primarily
using the sun
yeah and it grew worthless weed in the
sun that was some worthless looking weed
about either outdoor or greenhouse
i'd written like my head stash beds
which produced a whole bunch of gorgeous
weed
uh and that stuff was leafy took forever
almost restless
but you know inside people get better
better results off it
um
you know it's kind of another one of
those like old afghans that's really
ugly by today's standards
yeah
um and probably is best in a breeding
project
probably its best trait is that it's got
very old genetics in it
yeah but it's not like a one hybrid and
you're done
no i you know i
anybody working with it more power to
them for trying that's all i'll say on
that
it's probably a multi-stage process to
get what you want
and this is it for the list right now
you got me on yours you got anybody uh
no i didn't write me down
i just saw you had such a huge list yeah
um
you know there's uh yum bolt
i never grew the yum bolt but i actually
used it strangely enough i used to get
yum bolt from humboldt
and whoever had the yum bolt in humboldt
was doing a good job and it was frosty
and burned good and i enjoyed smoking it
yeah
you know
uh people are talking about you know
yeah there's people out there that are
doing some extensive puck work and i
think that's probably what it would take
yeah yeah it would it would take i'm not
saying it's bad or i'm not dissing it
i'm just saying that like to get the
qualities you want out of it
you're gonna have to work with it for a
while and do three four
you know five stages of breeding and
you'll probably get it to somewhere
where you want to go
if i was being optimistic i would say
cross once to the puck and then cross to
anything else for like nine generations
no i'm just kidding there's i'm sure
people are doing great work with it i
just haven't run any and that's that's
the main thing
um island sweet skunk i could talk about
that for a second it
um it's canadian there's uh stories
around about it um
supposedly it uh wasn't [ __ ] this up
again don't [ __ ] it up again well then
you say it so won't i can't [ __ ] it up
well i don't remember so but i think
it's cotton candy was the rename of iss
or something like that well no there's
an aspect where the sweet skunk the
sweet skunk was supposedly um an nl5
haze maybe mixed with something from uh
from breeder steve
and then the island sweet skunk uh
you know was uh
i don't know like
it kind of got like [ __ ] up with mark
emery and he decided to like rename
something because he wanted something
different sounding on his menu
so i don't know but apparently it still
lives in canada so there's people that
know the real story and have an original
one it's been held around for a long
time
um and it's likely an nl5 haze or hybrid
yeah
irene we're not going to talk about just
because we might have
some people on eventually that uh it's
kind of their story to tell and they can
give an enormous amount of depth on it
so hopefully that'll be soon
you know
yep
casey jones was that it was a similar
era um there was a cut from joe schmoe
that was pretty good at casey jones
um
that's about all i got on that anything
else you want to cover before we uh wrap
this one up and if we missed any again
send us messages some of the ones people
were mentioning you guys missed it
earlier in the episode summer and other
episodes we have all episodes about so
go check them out um anything else you
want to cover before i start doing a
[ __ ] what about that time 8 50 or
something like that yeah oh i'll see
some somebody just asked about champagne
um champagne was a canadian strain
and there was this picture i can't
remember if it was in the in
emery's magazine cannabis culture or
whatever but there was there was these
vid there was these pictures of
champagne that were just like three foot
tall colas
with very little branching on like a
hydroponic setup and it just looked like
there was like five pounds of weed yeah
on this table and it was very it was
very delicious looking and i think there
was some really attractive pictures of
champagne taken
that got a lot of people's interest in
it
um and it was seed lines that was
crossed into stuff
it's kind of one of those things i don't
know that we ever saw the real one down
in america i can't say um but it
definitely was passed around those 90s
beaster circles
yeah
you know
yeah um
someone was talking about what was in it
the king and champagne a funny story
about the king i almost popped the last
of those seeds and then i agreed to do a
collab with y east and
when he was with compound um the seeds
got given to his partner of king and i
never saw them again so you look at him
i'm sure compound might have a king
hybrid somewhere and i think maybe
there's a good chance like we have some
canadian friends and stuff yeah um you
know i think it still survives up there
yeah it could very well yeah it's mostly
it's most the history on it is mostly
canadian yeah and a lot of things people
are asking about like the canadian stuff
i'd love to talk about but i just don't
have
any experience with canadian stuff other
than what we could buy from seed up
there and it was still minimal you know
yeah um we had this we had this line
from my friends in color we had the hong
kong i don't know if that's what people
are talking about or they're talking
about a different kong but yeah we had
this thing called the hong kong that uh
still exists in various hybrids
so
the kong if i remember correctly had
this reputation for being sold for some
ridiculous amount of money like twenty
thousand dollars for a cut yeah
and soul assassin was not just og solo
assassins were all uh hybrids of og we
still have the number one in our circle
number three was an oracle hybrid and it
is gone as far as i know
um yeah so
we've been doing a lot of updates to the
podcasts we're on every single platform
now that you can imagine for podcasting
and we put these videos up on youtube
pretty shortly after we do these and
record these i'm going to get the the
episode up pretty pretty quickly maybe
four or five hours uh on the the
podcasting software please go like and
share because like
we don't we don't ask for anything other
than to just like and share with the
podcast that's it you guys now that
we're up on youtube uh and stuff like
that it's an easy way to recommend to
friends that can't sit for the live
yeah to be able to listen to it on audio
or video
yeah
yep and uh we have our breeders nice
patreon you can join us gonna be some
fights tomorrow that we're all watching
good ones and uh we shoot the [ __ ] in
there all the time come join discord go
[ __ ] yourself on say not saying discord
and um yeah uh what else do we have uh
riots.com is up and running do not use
the right seedcode.com use
riotsteads.com or write seco gives
errors uh
breederpodcast.com is our new domain for
breeder syndicate since we could not get
our domain back
um so breederpodcast.com
and we have the whole every podcast
episode is up on there on the front page
super easy to work go sign up and like i
said please like share subscribe all
that um that helps
there was a lot of good questions
tonight
if you didn't get your questions
answered you can always reach out to
myself or whatever and i'll try to
answer them for you i saw a bunch scroll
past and it just wasn't easy to stop
what we were talking about and tangent
but that doesn't mean it wasn't a good
one
yeah okay
all right well thank you everyone for
showing up hope you guys have a
wonderful weekend and we'll see you next
week same bat time same bat channel