ready go
[Music]
welcome to breeder syndicate
so yeah let's kick it off dude we're
gonna have to go over some very basic
breeding
um terminology just so you can
understand when we move on move forward
some of the people who haven't quite
gotten there yet can understand what
we're going to be talking about
all right so uh as far as terms go
probably one of the more
misused terms is f1 right we'll just
start there yeah start with f1 because
this has a lot of this is used
incorrectly in the cannabis world daily
even by myself like i mean there's not
really another term to switch it out
with as we use it so sadly uh there's
almost no f1s
um and the reason being is that like
what an f1 means is when you take two
parents
that are pretty much true breeding okay
and you cross them together
right
um let's you know that would result in
what was called an f1 where
basically all the dominant genes from
both parents
will be dominant right and so you'll get
what's called hybrid vigor because
you're not going to get any weird
recessives you're not going to get
anything like that you
basically end up with
whatever the dominant genes are on both
sides that's what pops
yeah right so you know an example of
that for instance would be
you know say something like you know for
our purposes like skunk one by hates or
something like that like or or skunk one
by an nl or something something along
those lines part of the reason why they
use skunk one so much was simply because
it was it was an easy way to f1
something right well even even
technically you want to get more basic
if you're doing f1s it's like afghani
across the tie right sure
because it has to be the definition is
two
crossing two parental lines with
distinctively different genotypes the
most important which makes it more rare
so it's one of the most incorrect terms
um because a lot of times it's used just
to say this is the first time someone's
crossed these two things and my
cushman's by skittles f1
yeah right and that and that and that's
not right because yeah those aren't like
parental stock from region of origin
you know um
type of thing so f2
would be if you take that f1 seed and
you grow up males and females and you
cross them together
that's when with a line you should see
all the dominance all the recessives all
the various permutations of what's in
that line can pop up
so instead of getting like all the
dominant traits combined
you get every trait imaginable combining
in every way imaginable and most
importantly you'll see stuff that you
would not see in the f1 line stuff
cannot show up there are things that
will never show up in the f1 line that
will only show up f2 and f3 yeah to give
to give a really easy example for people
like in humans
brown eyes is a dominant gene and so in
order to have blue eyes gray eyes green
eyes hazel eyes both parents have to
have that gene and they have to line up
to two recessives
right so if one parent doesn't have the
gene it'll never pop
yeah you know so exactly so anyway so
that's that's f1 f2 s1 is is a
relatively
modern thing uh in terms of people being
able to do it but that's basically it's
a self one
um either through hermaphrodism
naturally or something human induced
from some kind of spray that's used in
modern terms you s1 the line it used to
be sort of frowned upon
but in in recent years because we have a
lot of cuts that we don't have the line
anymore we just have the specific cut it
might be the only way to look through
genetics in that line besides
you know besides an outcross or a hybrid
of it right so it's not as good as as
doing uh because you'll get a lot of
weirdness when you inbreed you could get
some undesirable things but at the very
least it gives you an idea to like
look through something like
chem d or
you know trinity or you know something
that's old that's an elite clone only
right yeah
um and then there's a thing called
and also it when in adding on to it was
looked down on it was only looked down
on in the cannabis sphere in normal
agriculture selfing is the normal way to
breed uniform crops that's how they do
it they don't use filial generations
they go through selfie
yes so that's so is a cannabis kind of
old wives tale as it were and one of the
one of the things that happens with
cannabis too is that you know in modern
agriculture when you're developing a
seedline you might want a whole bunch of
like butter lettuce for instance that
comes out extremely similar and you
might want a bunch of seeds of whatever
cucumbers or zucchini or what what have
you that comes out extremely dependable
and so they will s1 that until they get
you know a very dependable very narrow
breeding uniform uniform
not a lot to look not you know that's
part of the reason why like you know and
so ibl maybe we'll shift it yeah this
segways into it because ibl is another
like super mis misused terms and it
stands essentially for inbred line
yeah um
but
hold on let me add this in because this
is the point where most people lose it
because it says inbred line it does not
mean that if you line breed that you
have an ibl it is a very specific term
and it is a basically don't look at it
like okay well i crossed this f1 made
f2s that's ibl right it's line bread
it's inbred line it it basically what it
means is uniformity in a line and that's
it it's not something that can always be
achieved at f6 or f8 it only means when
you're popping those seeds you have a
homogeneous line meaning uniform like
clones
so for us um for you know for like
large-scale agriculture something like
that might be useful for cannabis it's
not that useful for the most part unless
you get something amazing because what
you see is what you get
if you breed with an ibl it'll throw
what you see
it's very valuable in hemp farms i i
know that that's one place where they're
liking seeing uniformity in self lines
because they just it's more vigorous
it's faster they can pop all those seeds
and if they come out uniform that's even
more that you it takes the the cloning
out of the you know the picture and
stuff so in in hemp i can see that being
more useful but in modern cannabis
people want to find that that keeper
yeah they want they want a little bit of
variety so there's new paths
yeah for a breeder for somebody like you
know um for a breeder or anything like
that and uh
all that
getting something where like there's
nowhere to go within the gene pool
itself
because it's an ibl and it already is
what it is the traits you see are the
traits you get
unless you really want to add those
traits to another line specifically
there's not a lot of room for places to
go
yeah because it's already been all that
variety has been bred out of it
yeah so that's another thing with
breeding where it's like a lot of
breeding depends on what your goals are
yeah you know
some depends on goals some people might
want consistency some people might want
like the same three to six phenos to
regularly pop
some people might want to breed an ibl
some people might want to do an open
pollination or an f2 and have the widest
possible
gene pool to hunt through depending on
what your what your goals are you trying
to find like a random elite cutting to
hold on to are you trying to actually
breed a line like matt was saying where
you could like put it in a hemp field
and start thousands of seeds and get the
same consistent you know size bush type
of thing
so
that's kind of the thing um
so uh we have ix in cross in cross is
the last one we have left so in cross is
the last one so can't this is another
weird term because uh
in um
we call it a bx
right yes um but in most other breeding
they call it a bc
a back cross is actually like the
technical term that you would use but
for for most cannabis people they're
mostly familiar with a bx
and a bx is simply
you take a cut um you know and you
use an outside pollen donor
uh to make a male
line of it and then you take the
children of that and you back cross it
onto the origin that initial female so
we've talked about it on the previous on
the previous podcast we talked about how
um you know uh
you know neville used um seattle greg's
nl1
and uh you know we'd use that as a
pollen donor and would back cross to
make a pure hash plant to make a pure
big bud to make a pure nor uh hawaiian
indica
that type of thing uh jj from top dog
you know he took
uh
an afghani one and used that to cross
into um chem d and did that a few times
and made double dog and trace dog and so
on and so forth so that's basically what
a bx is is you find a pollen donor
and you cross it to a clone only for the
most part and then you back cross you
keep back crossing
so on and so forth so those are kind of
like the lockdown single trades when
it's back crossing and and then ix is
going to be
similar to a bx but going further down
the line and crossing back to a previous
generation so like maybe an f6 cross to
an f1 of the same line that would be an
in cross because you're crossing in
between the same line
but sure
yeah so that it is essentially still a
back cross though so those yeah those
things are and it's only it's only a bx
or a bc
if you back cross it to the exact same
parent exactly that's super saiyan
cutting like if you for instance had
like a line of chem d for instance and
you and you crossed your children of
that to a different chem d parent it
wouldn't be a bx it has to go directly
back to the original genetic
stock that started the process otherwise
it's it's not a bx
um those are some basic terms i think
that covers like most that cannabis
people deal with