so i decided to do a quick video
about the cosmic boogie poster i know
there is a website out there
that goes over each individual little
thing on it
but a lot of people have not been able
to find really good
you know images about it or of it
um it's really hard to find it's
impossible to find an original
this is an original um but i want to go
over it with you for all you haze
fanatics and strain [ __ ] out there
so you can see what what makes this
poster so special
so first we have the signs of the zodiac
if you look
scorpio that's all i know because i mean
leo
the [ __ ] or whatever that is some
scales and weed
yeah so they have the constellations up
here i'm not sure let's see what that is
not quite sure what that is i can't tell
oh it's just a bud
it's just a tall but i forget that's how
hayes looked
um yeah so we got that
it references the silver and the blue
haze
it references magenta and gold those are
the four original types of haze
the original haze connoisseur's choice
cultivated california cannabis
let's see what it says right here let's
get it to
focus for you i can't quite get it to
focus
in nature we trust americana
1976 no seeds
my favorite part
honest weight there's the scales
because you know back then people would
[ __ ] [ __ ] with the weights
warning in some states cannabis is
illegal
all right here we go the cosmic boogie
1976 now the cosmic boogie this is where
it gets its uh
name from the poster in clandestine
location sparsely scattered throughout
california a few dedicated farmers
cultivate the herb cannabis
as a way of life anyone can grow weeds
and see the virgin greens but to
cultivate the exotic queens beyond your
dreams
you should have dedication sensitivity
to plant life consistency and a little
basic knowledge
good karma and a great desire to find
harmony with mama nature
the basis for any strong healthy plant
is the soil it grows in
resin producing herbs grow best in soil
that is neutral to semi-sweet
uh larger the bush or tree whatever it
may be the larger the root structure
needed to support it
roots develop mostly freely in a loose
rich soil makes one yard of soil
compound
of 30 mushroom compost 30 redwood
sawdust
40 sandy loam topsoil mix organic
nutrients three pounds of
what does that say boof three pounds of
hoof and horn meal three pounds of boof
hoof and horn mill five pounds of rock
phosphate four pounds of kelp one pound
natural compost
one pound soil iron uh five pounds
gypsum and five pounds of dolomite
this is supposed to be the recipe they
use to grow the haze
who knows mix soil and minerals
thoroughly and let sit for at least one
week
then check the soil with the soil
testing kit for ph and add
agricultural lime to bring ph to 7.5 to
8.5
spring arrives and with it comes new
life fresh spirit and a great hope for
the new crop
plant your favorite seeds on the 6th or
7th of april the moon is in cancer best
signed for planting above ground herbs
in may the 3rd 4th and 5th are good
if you're still not together try june
8th and 9th while the moon is in scorpio
when you irrigate make sure that the
moon is in one of these signs
when possible cancer is the most
excellent time to irrigate
taurus scorpio and pisces are also good
for irrigation
pruning should be done only in the third
quarter patience is the real secret and
the true test
try to make it until december 10th or
11th when the moon is in leo and harvest
conditions are perfect so you can dig it
in nature we trust the spirit of 76 and
it says right here copyright
1975 robert lund
and this is signed by uh grantedy mike
he raffled this off uh
i think a seattle hempfest or something
that's where this got loosened from his
grips
um and ended up with me lots of love
everyone hope you enjoyed