[Music]
thank you
welcome to breeders Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not so Dawn breeder and grower
from Mendocino welcome to the
underground
so we're here with heavy days from the
podcast and um we wanted to talk with
him about his journey through cannabis
where he started how he got into
podcasting period not only that but
taking that journey into breeding into
making seeds and um and and the whole
political climate in Australia and
however how he's grown throughout this
journey so I want to start from the
beginning with you do this kind of um A
to Z how did you get started where did
you get that that spark for cannabis in
Australia
yeah great question
um I guess first off I'll just say you
know huge thanks for having me on guys
it's a pleasure to be joined by some of
my my favorite podcasts so super stoked
and um yeah to your question good good
question right because the Australians
seen historically has been just very
fledgling and very much in the shadows
of the US
um sort of wasn't a lot of notable
figures doing much when I first started
getting interested in cannabis which
would have been around
2013-ish yeah that was when I started
getting really serious
and I think initially the thing that
like really was the light bulb moment
for me was
um I actually tried some imported
Californian weed and I was like wow you
can like weed can be this good and prior
to that all I'd had was like the
Australian equivalent of beasters
so
for a long time I was like yeah cannabis
is cool but whatever and um yeah then
you try this Californian stuff and I
remember specifically it was it was said
that it was Granddaddy Purple but
looking back with what I know now it
definitely was not Grandpa
it was uh it was very green and it had a
very generic sweet smell not that sort
of Earthly yeah you'd expect
um but it it was nonetheless a light
bulb moment and then the next batch I
got
uh there was a few things that there was
like some Jack Herer which wasn't Jack
Herer there was some Girl Scout cookies
that wasn't Girl Scout cookies but there
was purple kush and I think it is the
Purple Kush that sort of goes around a
bit and that one made a very lasting
impact on me and I think the ball got
rolling from there and I had I had done
a grow before that but I got mediocre
results and it was my first gross you
know it was going to be a bit dog [ __ ]
anyway and yeah you end up growing out
you know like DNA or whatever because
always yeah like it's it's a given your
first grow you don't know who's a good
breeder so you're just gonna get lost in
the marketing so so yes I came back to
it and um I just started getting
interested in it and at the time I was
applying for graduate school and part of
the entry requirement was um there was
like this essay component and I wasn't
good at writing so I started um writing
these largely speaking sort of opinion
pieces on cannabis and sort of the state
of the scene in Australia and I would
talk about how I was sort of a bit let
down
um I would talk about how I was sort of
a bit let down by the Australian scene
because from my perspective the
penalties for growing cannabis were far
less than the states and so there was a
huge incentive to get at it like why not
the penalties are pretty minimal and yet
no one had really done it and so I I
sort of wrote this opinion piece saying
you know I think the Australian scene is
pretty apathetic compared to the
American scene you know like during the
Reagan Administration like people going
to jail for just for incredible periods
of time and I just don't think the same
legalities were at play in Australia for
a long time and so yeah I was just
writing these opinion pieces and saying
like you know if you want to
um help get things legal in Australia we
need to be more open because at the time
I knew a bunch of like white collar
professional guys who grew but they were
totally in the closet they wouldn't tell
anyone about it and I sort of tried to
encourage people and I was like the more
you put this out there the more people
accept that you can be like you know a
family man with a job and and still grow
on the side you know yeah you don't have
to be a criminal like in a criminal
organization you can you can have a
normal family life anger yeah unlike the
way I look right now
[Laughter]
but uh but yeah so so I think that was
sort of how I got my um my feet wet was
I was writing these opinion pieces and I
got to admit it was all sort of guys
just an experiment for me to get better
at writing and it was just subject
matter that I was somewhat familiar with
and then
um I guess the and this is probably the
part that I haven't really spoken to
people much about I then got the idea of
like well let's do a podcast and what
you find is if you're like a no-name
person like I was at the time and you
ask people hey would you like to come on
this podcast the first thing they'll say
is can you like send me something to
listen to so like I have an idea of like
what it's going to be and if you're then
like oh you know you're actually the
first person yeah people just stop
people stop replying very quickly okay
so I remember specifically I um at the
time Brothers Grim was like just
announced they were Reinventing
themselves I didn't know who who Duke
was yet I just knew Mr soul from like
reading online and stuff and so I
reached out to him and I was like do you
want to come on and he was like yeah
we'll do it send me some questions I
sent him some questions and then like
after a few replies he's like what like
um organization do you work for
and I was like oh it's like it's just
sort of me just
and and he abruptly stopped replying
sounds about right that's about right
it's uh yeah anyone who's met Mr soul
will know that's pretty par for the
course yeah
um so then again being a bit of a newbie
I reached out to Swerve of caliphon and
um a very similar thing he expressed
interest and then after one or two
replies just completely ghosted me so at
that point I was sort of a bit like I
don't know if this is gonna actually
happen
and I just started following Duke
because I'd seen on The Brothers Grimm
website that um you know he was pairing
up with Mr Soul yeah and I I just asked
a few questions in the comments I think
he had posted about some 88 G13 crosses
he had done and I just sort of said oh
you know I read this Line's pretty old
and it's a bit inbred do you find like
it dominates the crosses yeah and um I
think just a few questions like that he
was sort of like oh you know you seem to
be interested in the genetics yeah and
so yeah I just I floated the idea by him
and I think I even linked him some of
those opinion pieces and I think that
might have been what sort of got him
over the line a bit thinking like oh
this guy seems to you know it's not just
like haphazard you want to do it he
seems to be sort of passionate yeah so
yeah then we did that and that went
really well and I ended up we chatted
for a couple of hours and then we
actually ended up probably staying on
the chat for probably an equal amount I
think we chatted for like three hours on
the episodes then we'd probably spent
another three hours just chatting
afterwards about General stuff yeah and
you know we sort of developed a rapport
and at the end of it he was like I'm
gonna do you a favor and I didn't really
know what he meant I thought coming on
the episode was the fact that I was very
thankful
um but so I just went to bed thinking
that was great you know what a once in a
lifetime experience to talk to like a
professional because like at the time I
like you know I was just a nobody yeah
yeah and um yeah so I was really
grateful and then the next morning I
woke up and I had an inbox from skunk VA
and I'd never spoken to him at the time
and um in my mind you know he's this
mythological figure in a chemist story
very and he was also very inaccessible
at the time he wasn't online he wasn't
talking and he just basically said hey
you know um Duke said I should message
you and that was all it said yeah and
and uh and um so then we ended up lining
up the episode but a hundred percent
without a doubt those two things
happening was definitely the momentum
which allowed the show to continue in my
opinion yeah yeah I think that it was it
was a big get to get uh uh skunk VA on
for sure and you know that time yeah and
you know he He Turned he's a good he's a
pretty good Storyteller
um and he also told the truth about a
about a you know a lot of aspects of Kim
that were that people didn't wanted to
know so it probably sort of launched it
a bit I would imagine
yeah yeah hugely and I I think
um uh not so dog you said this in one of
the Breeders Syndicate episodes not so
long ago but you said listening to that
episode he was he was pretty honest
about a lot of things and as the years
have gone by and I've learned more about
you know the behind the scenes of the
various incidents he maybe spoke about
yeah I did sort of start to gain a bit
of an appreciation that like yeah it did
sound like he gave a pretty honest
recount and
um you know like there's a lot of funny
things not funny but um how can I put it
like people and you know not so you
probably deal with this a lot too people
still constantly ask me you know who's
the Staten Island guy yeah oh my God
yeah
yeah and you know what's a what's a
what's a bummer about that for me is
that because he shunned the spotlight on
the forums and anywhere else
um he's probably the single biggest
person responsible for keeping the chems
alive
right at least for that period of time
until he spread them out a little bit to
his friend group
um and he doesn't and he brought the
super skunk West
uh and he doesn't really get talked
about and he doesn't want us to say his
name
so I asked if Staten Island was like an
acceptable you know Among The Flume yeah
you know and he was like okay you can
call me that you know so
that's funny
yeah yeah you definitely and and as and
as I learned more about the story and
sort of the interplay between
um you know skunk ba not so dog some of
the other characters in the scene the
Staten Island guy I started to like
realize the story a bit more on the back
end and I was like oh okay this is
actually like really interesting and
yeah um I can understand the Staten
Island guys perspective and he's he he
always like you know obviously I've
never met him or spoke to him and
whatnot and I I know not so dog you're
you're very close with him but um yeah
they're smoking to him
yeah there you go but I just I just sort
of understood that he was from that Old
Guard which was like you know I keep to
the Shadows I do my thing
um so yeah that that was definitely
really interesting but I think that was
largely speaking how I got into it all
and then um you know it all sort of just
started to gain a bit of momentum from
there and we just sort of branched out a
bit really because everyone you know I I
owe a huge amount of um you know
appreciation and gratitude to to
everyone in the first ten because as
much as you know the first two I
referenced gave me some momentum I think
I have to be honest I think there was a
bit of a lull between episodes sort of
four to seven where I had some people
that I was interested in but maybe
weren't super super big
um right yeah definitely so sometimes
the interesting people aren't who who
like necessarily everybody wants to hear
about that moment but it's who we want
to talk to you know I feel you yeah but
yeah definitely people like yourself
um mean Jane and Bodhi and you know some
of the big name guys in the first sort
of 10 to 12 episodes which is hugely
impactful and I I honestly all the time
think about how different it would have
been if like I didn't have those people
including yourself you know I I imagine
I I look at a lot of other podcasts and
I see it takes a long time to get a big
following and I just think I was very
lucky to to get that sort of push
initially yeah you got some people that
the community uh likes a lot and some
people that were interesting and stories
that they wanted to hear
and I think that that probably had a lot
to do with it too
um I've always been super interested to
be frank and that the fact that you like
because our world is so underground
right there's like layers of what people
know about each other you know from like
Insider information that I'm sure like
as you've been in the scene now a while
you've heard a lot but when you're first
getting involved you typically only know
like Legends or public personas right
yeah and so even figuring out like who's
who
um can be I you know I always looked at
that because it's like it happened for
me like organically or Matt just being
around the forums being in the scene
living in California for so many years
like I knew a lot of these people in
real life yeah yeah you know but you're
on the other side of the planet you know
and you're trying to determine who to
talk to
um and uh you know we're a quirky Bunch
yeah how did that work for you like like
trying to slowly figure out like maybe
not necessarily who's full of [ __ ] but
who is more who's who's perspective
aligned most with how you see the
history going how did you start figuring
that out what was what were some of the
the
steps in stepping stones in that process
yeah what a great question I I have to
be honest I I'll I'm probably I haven't
actually super thought about that so I'm
just going to give you the ideas that
are coming to my head right now and yeah
yeah
um but basically I think that um I'll be
honest it probably wasn't until like
episode 40 or so that I actually was
able to stop viewing every episode as
like this real Fanboy thing in a sense
like I feel like before every episode I
would get nervous and it was like [ __ ]
I'm about to deal with this big name
dude and you know what I mean yeah so I
think um I just want to put that out
there that um yeah that that definitely
was the case I was a bit Star Struck
initially because you know as you guys
said you know these
um really Infamous figures online who
you just get little tidbits about here
and there I think largely speaking I
didn't have too many people messaging me
saying hey stay away from this guy there
actually wasn't too much of that except
except for my my name I believe that was
one of them you got a lot about nah not
at all not at all I I mean like maybe
but like [ __ ] those guys like
um like I I always view it as like I've
always said you know consistently that
your episodes are some of my favorite
because
I think that a lot of guests are very
diplomatic when they come on the show
and I liked the fact that it didn't feel
like that with you it always felt very
free-flowing
um but to jump back to the question
quickly for a second I think generally
speaking I just picked a few people in
the scene who I thought were really
stand out and then I thought if if the
guest I'm thinking about is sort of
friends or cool with these people then
they must be okay so I think that
probably would have been the guiding
sort of uh feature but also I have to
reference I was lucky enough to come
visit the states probably within the
first six months of starting the show so
I got to hang out with a lot of people
in person
um and I think that helped guide the
guest selection a little more but like
I'll be the first to admit you know
there are there are some episodes that I
think haven't aged as well as others
um and and there is a number of episodes
that are just not available anymore and
that's for a variety of reasons and
sometimes the guest has requested it to
be taken down other times we just viewed
it as inappropriate to keep it up
um so yeah I think that the selection
has gotten better over time I hope and I
certainly also think that I like to chat
to people a little bit before I get them
on the show and the other guiding
principle I have is that I don't really
take requests so much like people will
message me and say hey can I get on the
show and they might be like a decent
size following but I have always said
you know in order to get a good episode
I think I have to genuinely be curious
about you sure yeah yeah and if you're
not it's just like a stale conversation
you know yeah yeah I mean it's it's
really hard when it comes to to guess
like I mean
even with just doing the live streams
for a long time there are so many of
those that I look back on that did not
age well in my brain like I'm like wow I
was really friendly with that person and
later on I'm like wow I don't really
like how that went looking back but you
can't you know I mean you can only do
what you do at the time and and how it
goes at the time and how you're feeling
at the time and and I think like over
years and years and years you it's
easier to go easier on yourself about
the [ __ ] cops when it comes to stuff
like that because it's just so it's it's
possible to control other people's
actions and then I think I think my
opinion on it actually has dramatically
changed in the last few years
um I used to think about it where like
to be honest there was some people that
you you've had on I don't need to name
names or anything like that because
that's irrelevant where I was like ah
that person oh no but then
over time I think I've thought about it
and like I actually think to let people
really judge someone
it's really hard to [ __ ] for two or
three hours yeah like your interviews
are pretty long and like you give pretty
open-ended questions and you let people
talk
you know and when you talk that gives
the public a chance to see do I Vibe
with this person do I like what they
have to say do I get a sense of who they
are and in some cases people can't talk
the talk
yeah I remember it yeah and so that and
so that allows and I'm not you know good
or bad or whatever and so it just it
just allows like
um because our our our
scene is full of characters
you know there's definitely reasons why
people like to be isolated and growing
weed and not dealing with humans yeah
and you have to have a certain risk
profile and people get into cannabis for
all kinds of reasons
sure you know
um and so yeah like you give nice long
interviews
and you let people speak you know
um I'll I'll say this I I was one of the
people that gave you I think this is the
first time we butted heads was during
and I'll say it the sub cool interview I
was super pissed at the time and I've
told you recently like looking back on
that because Monty's no longer with us
like I am so glad you didn't listen to
any of us I'm I'm because because
regardless of whether me and him got
along or what happened
it none of that matters because he did
work it was it was important it was in a
lot of people's Gardens and those those
stories need to be there we need to
whether they're accurate or not or
whether you know he was right or not
doesn't really matter we need to have
those stories regardless and he was a
major part of the scene for a long time
so
on that yeah he he did and I was pissed
at the time but I mean
yeah I I just wanted to you know I like
now it's like even if even if it's not
somebody I prefer like I like to hear
what they have to say
sure you know because I'm always curious
about people's perspectives you know and
um you know and then there's an also
thing where like there's this huge
there's this huge gig to like
um you know when you were saying before
it's like there's a lot of people that
come on to be diplomatic
you know there's a lot of people that
are coming on that are trying to project
an image
and so it's probably really relaxing for
you sometimes when you get somebody on
and you just get a sense oh this
person's just being themselves
yeah hugely and it's I don't want to say
it's rare but I can understand like I do
it myself you know sometimes you've got
your own personal thoughts and then
you've got more public thoughts you're
happy to put out there but it is super
refreshing when someone's very upfront
and
um to sort of reference the the the
Monty interview you talked about Matt
that was actually a very interesting
moment for me because I didn't actually
I knew there would be some people
unhappy with it but I didn't anticipate
it would be to that level and I remember
uh old CSI left the comment
it's not like over a hundred likes I
think our whole crew probably said
something yeah oh it was it was yeah
I've never seen anything like that and
it was like to the effect of like this
ain't it buddy and um yeah I guess you
know sort of a related Point I've been
thinking about recently is that um you
know it's it's it's it's kind of scary
to think that three of the people had on
the show have passed away now yeah
you're not being Monty bog and Jaime
Chiba oh yeah great I forgot about I
forgot about part two yeah yeah and so
sometimes you lose sight of the fact
that like um yeah some of these guys are
a bit older and like you know
um as you said for better or worse it is
good to get their perspective on some
things and sometimes it's tough if
you're feeling like some of the things
they're saying might not be a hundred
percent true sure but um if nothing else
you know it's I I am grateful that I got
to speak to sub and interestingly you
know I never put this out there but it
but like from a technical level it was a
very interesting interview
um uh you know sub got a bit mad at me
throughout it and actually hung up the
call at one point
and then I think his friend told him
that that probably wasn't a good PR move
and he yeah he called me back and said
that there was internet issues
but
but like it was it was good to get his
take and you know I obviously you know
don't want to speak negative
um because you know I think we all can
sort of look at the last few years of
Subs life and and draw our own
conclusions but sure sub cool definitely
was the person who got me into growing
organically with super soil I don't
think Super soil is the best nowadays
but it was a great stepping stone for
someone who just never done Organics
yeah so so yeah for that reason I had a
bit of a personal like thing with sub
because I was like you're the dude who
got me in him and actually um you know
it was the Rev him and the Rev So I
listened to your episode the other day
yeah yeah yeah the Rev he was he was
great and I tried TLO and I had pretty
decent success with it and then I tried
super soil and I had pretty good success
with that and then I ultimately
um just moved on to sort of the more
general no-till you know it's it's it's
such a mindful these days but like yeah
um I I felt an obligation to sub for
that reason because he uh yeah he showed
me the Organics
you know anybody who came in during my
era like 2006 to you know all the way up
to
2013. like even me like Subways people
that I entered in seeing it was DNA but
once you got past like the DNA
Greenhouse like you know Spanish bait
and switchers you get into the Americans
sub was at the top of the game then you
know like all of us got into that even I
was inspired by him young um I have his
first book Bank you know like I still
have it so it was it was an odd fault it
was an odd Fallout when we when we had
our Fallout because
um I did respect him and I did look up
to him at the time and it was just like
I was I was his antithesis I guess you
know sometimes what I've heard is I've
gotten older sometimes just do people's
energies just don't match it doesn't
have to be a hate person or I hate that
dude or anything it's just sometimes
energies just don't Jive you know and
that's I definitely know what it was a
slight digression but they're connected
when I first started going over to
Amsterdam in the mid 90s and buying
seeds right and after I'd been there a
number of times I started getting
introduced to people okay and what I
realized was that everyone had their own
version of History some of these
Old-Timers didn't like each other and
there was significant beefs and it was
really Illuminating compared to today
because you know Matt and I talk about
all the time how you can pick any hero
from Neville to Shanti to Art to all
these different folks and you can kind
of tear them apart if you want right and
so people have their favorites or
whatever but there's a difference
between like lasting contributions to
the scene
and uh and and you know and being a good
person and someone you get along with
and someone who you agree with their
decisions
yeah
you know because those two things are
totally different you could make lasting
contributions to the cannabis seed game
and the Clones into the gene pool into
the knowledge and you could kind of have
a variety of of you know personality
quirks that aren't that cool yeah yeah
those things exist
yeah yeah yeah hugely and I think it's
only as I get more deep into knowing
people do you realize how deep some of
those uh divides actually run and um
something that's always lasted with me
is sort of this quote which was I you
know I can't tell you who said it but it
was like you know considering we all
smoke this plant that chills you out
there's a lot of aggressive unhappy
people in our community yeah I always
thought that was interesting you know
because it's you know maybe it's like
that with every Ultra you know maybe in
like the 0.01 of the craft brewing
Community maybe it's like that too I
don't know but like it is an interesting
point
I think you know some of it is because
we come from a
a subculture of like the cowboy attitude
of just like [ __ ] it we're here bring
what you brung like it's different now
it's there's obviously a big culture
Clash going on we have we have the dudes
who are isolated like to stick to
themselves move weight we don't want to
deal with tax stuff or anything like
that we don't want to deal with the
normal business [ __ ] it's why we're
doing what we're doing so we don't have
to do that kind of work and um now we're
merging with the the realistic climate
of legalization and it is a hard clash
of personalities plus we have two
different Generations uh maybe even
three or four in some cases apart trying
to work together or not work together
but it coexists in this same sphere and
it's it's definitely going to cause some
Strife
um I'd love to know how you navigate
that when you're doing a lot of these
interviews when when you hear when you
hear something that maybe you don't love
so much and you and you want to push
back but like what what what what is
that dividing lying for you
yeah great question and brings us to
something I definitely wanted to touch
on with the audience if it's okay with
you maybe I could chat a little bit
about our falling out and how that sort
of guided my view on um sort of the
question you just asked yeah it goes
with what we were talking about the
heavy beefs everything yeah yeah yeah of
course you know and and I can completely
appreciate
um that there may be some people
listening to this right now going why is
this guy on here I'm not a fan of him
and I can understand why you would have
that view so I guess
um the first thing I would just say is
like I didn't like so you know we had a
falling out probably about two years ago
and I want to take 100 responsibility
for that and the first thing I would say
is that I never wanted to really discuss
this publicly until I was able to do it
with you because I just didn't feel it
was appropriate and
um so I just sort of wanted to do it
with your permission so to speak so yeah
I think historically I always viewed the
interviews as like my goal is to get the
guests comfortable enough that they
share their inner monologue and then you
listen to it and then you decide so what
that would mean is sometimes people
would say things that I didn't agree
with or that I didn't like
but if I push back in the past they
would get cagey they would close up and
I sort of didn't know how to handle that
at the time and as a result I just felt
like it was better to just try to keep
them comfortable keep them happy let
them Express their inner monologue if
they say something that's really weird
hopefully the listener picks up on that
that was really weird sure yeah and um
we sort of go from there so sometime
about two years ago I had Gage green on
the show and I asked them specifically
in one of our prior episodes we'd spoken
about the Colombian black from JoJo
Rizzo yes yeah and I had said uh I know
that you and Matt both had those seeds
um he has said something to the effect
of you guys put them out cheap just to
you know sort of get it out there so it
wasn't valuable you know what's your
take on that and they initially started
out by giving this sort of long-winded
answer about how largely they try not to
focus on the negatives in their life and
it was sort of a diplomatic answer at
first and I was sort of thinking okay
this isn't too bad and then at the end
he just went off really left of field
and essentially made an extremely
inappropriate comment relating to you
and your childhood yeah and
honestly in the moment I was taken back
and I thought to myself this guy's a
scumbag and it's crazy he just said that
and in the moment I tried to voice some
opposition to that and looking back I
wish I had given a much stronger
rebuttal I believe I said something to
the effect of I can agree with most of
what you just said yeah yeah
um but I I want to acknowledge that it
actually it wasn't a strong enough
response on my part to what he said and
more importantly
um I just I didn't I thought that people
would listen to that moment and
basically go this guy's a scumbag you
know what I mean
um and I also thought that largely
speaking you and him had had you know um
conflicts in the past and it was sort of
just two people flinging insults at each
other however as time went by I realized
I had made not only a grave mistake but
one that I was deeply apologetic and
sorry about and I think the reality is
the simple truth is that there's no
place for comments like that on a
cannabis podcast it's just it's just not
appropriate and so I definitely want to
take responsibility for that going to
air I think that you know as the editor
of the show the buck stops with me so
even if I didn't say the comments myself
I have a responsibility because they
went to Air and that's under my sort of
leadership so to speak and I was
actually really grateful because it was
actually not so dog who messaged me and
he let me know some info that allowed me
to sort of reflect on the situation and
realize just how inappropriate it was
that those comments had gone to Air and
I specifically wanted to say you know
thanks not so dog because I always have
felt grateful in the manner in which you
approached me it was very humanistic it
wasn't like coming in hardcore like
you're a [ __ ] it was like hey just
want you to know it would be cool you
know and I I've always been very
grateful for that response and I thought
it was very telling of you as a person
that even though you know I I'd
essentially done something bad so to
speak to your buddy you were still um
you know kind enough to come in and give
me the sort of that gentle influence so
that I was very grateful for so since
that time I have been applying a much
more active level of moderation to the
show and this is sort of getting to the
Crux of your original question sure sure
which is that I realize that there just
is some things that get said that you
have to give push back to because the
reality is there's going to be some
listeners who just don't find what the
guest has said to be acceptable or like
maybe it's like insulting to them and so
you need to provide some amount of
feedback so these days I tried to I try
to provide some degree of feedback so if
someone says something I don't like I'll
try to come in and say yeah but like
what about this angle it doesn't seem
like you're considering that and I try
to give some degree of feedback but I
also
um apply like a sort of more active
level of moderation in that in the past
I literally would not take anything out
the guest said unless they asked for it
to be taken out sure whereas nowadays
there may be some things I'm like you
know what we're just we're a bit off
topic here maybe not appropriate or
relevant and so you get rid of it so I
think overall it's definitely a
continual learning process and you know
again I I sincerely apologize for any
um you know harm or distress that that
caused and I take full responsibility
and I I view it as a very big learning
experience in my life one that I'm not
proud of but I'm glad that I hopefully
have you know grown as a person and can
recognize that that wasn't right and I'm
not going to make that mistake again I'm
not going to let you eat crow totally
because you did try to reach out to me
and I just totally blew it off and I
think you know it took me a long time
over over because I I can't hold the
grudge if people that know me and have
known me over years know that I've been
all the [ __ ] Grudge like no one's
business but there were certain things
about that that I took very personal but
it wasn't necessarily from you it was
from it was because the dude knew me
personally and had personal info about
me and and the thing was that not
everybody listening knew that he because
it could have just sounded like a
[ __ ] mean slander at the time you
know but um yeah so it took me a long
time but when we finally spoke I was
very glad because it was it you know
that was heavy on me we were friends
like I had you out to our canaluma
naughty party because I liked you you
know so I'm stoked that that we moved
past it but I was mainly asking you
because I am learning that process now
myself you know like you had the podcast
I we started this way after and I'm
slowly learning like okay there's going
to be people that like I might have to
edit what they [ __ ] say like I don't
know where to draw this line and I don't
know like is it is it different between
each person like do you just try to draw
a line based on that person and how
accepting they are of certain it's hard
man it's hard and I've come to
appreciate what you've put together a
lot more a lot more being on the other
side and and so you you know I
appreciate the the apology but I
apologize as well because you know you
were reaching out you were trying to
communicate and I didn't communicate
back and really that's all it took so it
was always the The Shining Star trying
to like be cool with everyone and I you
know I I appreciate it for that I do
think it was very effective for a lot of
people it's showing them exactly the
kind of person that Gage green was yeah
you know um that's why I never asked you
to take it down to uh so so I mean it
obviously sucks you know in that regard
but I mean it and you know as far as
like me reaching out to you or whatever
like I mean Matt knows this very well
like one of the reasons why I'm even
public is I'm trying to build community
and culture
you know as sort of like a bulwark
against all the changes that are coming
and so like I try to like in on IG and
all that like you know when you
mentioned about like not just like
flaming you or something like that like
there's a lot of there's a lot of of
that kind of like like snippy back and
forth thing that goes on in public and I
don't think that's like particularly you
know conducive to anything positive so
you know I I always try like you know to
reach out and see if there's like common
ground or to like show someone your
point of view and maybe you can bring
them along and I always try to be open
to that as well you know
um because to me like being a good
person doesn't mean you don't make
mistakes or [ __ ] up it just means that
you try to learn from it and you try to
you know make amends when you do and
you've like being a good person is a
work in progress
and you know and and that kind of and
and so it's not like you never make
mistakes so you never look back and be
like oh man I wish I would have handled
that differently because that's asking
for Perfection Which is far different
you know yeah and I don't think you ever
did anything out of maliciousness that
was a whole nother thing too it was like
there's nothing mean like you didn't do
it to be mean to me ever and I always
appreciated that even when I was [ __ ]
mean you're never [ __ ] mean back so I
appreciate that dude because like I'm
pretty goddamn mean look in all honesty
I I think during that time period where
we weren't chatting I just tried to
appreciate that anything you said uh the
feelings were essentially warranted and
I I couldn't I couldn't deny you know
that this person is understandably
probably not happy with me and um I
think that was part of the learning
process and and to speak to not so dog's
point I definitely
um am a big Advocate and I try to tell
everyone that you know that like before
you go and rip someone's head off drop
them a line and and because one thing I
know for sure having had a bit of
experience in like sort of the mental
health field I've realized that there's
a very common saying you're hearing that
which is like always assume ignorance
before like um maliciousness which is
like chances are when someone does
something to piss you off they probably
didn't think about it hard enough to
wreck you know what I mean it probably
wasn't like any and and I've certainly
learned a lot from that and that's not
to try to you know take any um onus of
what happened no no I definitely could
resonate with that that sentiment that
you know I I think our community would
be a much more hospitable and friendly
place if everyone just sort of tried to
yeah exactly what not so dog said you
know just message someone in private you
know chances are they'll respond
positively and say hey thanks for
letting me know I'm sorry about that how
can we make it better you know what I
mean like generally speaking I've had
that response from people yeah you know
and I hadn't I had just completely
blacked it out you know after that I was
just like I'm not going to deal with it
not going to deal with it and then a
timehill episode happened I was like wow
this is a good episode he knocked it out
of the park so you know I mean you I I
finally got to hear how much you've
grown and listened to several other
episodes since and I'm really proud of
you man how far you've come dude it's
it's pretty exceptional and the the Tom
Hillman was a massive get and a huge I I
think a huge achievement for the the
whole Community because nobody had
really ever talked to him for a long
time and had him put all that down on
record and you asked him some of the
most amazing questions that anybody
could have asked him so mad props on
that if anybody hasn't listened to it
yet go check it out
uh you're too kind honestly if if any
episode is strikes you as particularly
good it's because of the guess not me so
um you know all props to Tom for
everything he's done in the scene and
for being willing to share that
knowledge and more importantly I've been
I've been very adamant about this from
the start I I wholeheartedly believe
that you know you guys will be able to
coax a whole different library of
information out because you you can
probably relate to this right when
you're doing an interview often you know
they say something and you're like oh
that's interesting let's follow that
trail of thought yeah and and like you
forget to ask something else so like I
think that there's so much stuff that we
didn't get out of Tom that we do need to
get out and I think that it's going to
come out when you guys go and visit him
oh Lord
oh Lord I will I will disagree with you
a little bit there in the sense I think
you're being too humble and that
interviewing people I think and talking
publicly is a skill yeah you know and I
definitely think that you know you do
something more and more and more you
probably learn what questions to ask you
know you probably got better at
researching the your subjects and trying
to think of good questions that your
your listeners might want to know
um you know I mean I personally when we
started doing the podcast I started
listening for all the weird verbal tics
that I had that I didn't realize because
you don't realize you have them in
normal conversation and you listen to
yourself and you're like oh man I need
to get rid of that yeah right and so
talking talking in public is hard even
if it's pre-recorded or whatever else
it's like it's definitely a skill and
being entertaining you know not even
that like with cannabis there's so much
like especially I mean you can interview
a lot of people in cannabis that make
seeds and it's even if you have no
knowledge about reading it doesn't
really matter because odds are either
well go in and interview someone like
Tom Hill is a whole nother a whole
nother aspect because he's going to tell
you you're [ __ ] stupid if you ask him
a stupid question that makes no sense so
yeah I know I mean there is there is you
know it's guests are great and all that
there's a big part of it if you don't
know yet and you get the wrong guess
that can be really catastrophic and
that's one of those guests that could
have gone really catastrophic if you
didn't know your [ __ ] because he will
call your ass out so I'm proud of you
for that one dude it came out good it
came out good and you and you remember
to ask about the chemist and stuff like
that
so thank you thank you in all honesty
um yeah Tom Tom's a great guy he'll let
you know when you're wrong which is um
uh a good trait I I enjoyed our chats
with him and um you know he's a he's a
cool guy I'm glad that we're able to get
that some of that info out from him and
and hopefully at some point someone can
touch base with the chemist right that
would be really cool yeah well there is
there is a chance uh that you know he
doesn't he doesn't live too far from me
um yeah he lives he lives you know he
never mentioned exactly where he lived
on your show uh but he lives probably
like uh on one of the most famous roads
in Mendocino uh for cannabis growing uh
I would literally call where he lives
sort of like the Beating Heart of of the
Trump of the Emerald Triangle
um and he's lived there since the 80s so
you could literally like I actually
thought you did a good enough job uh um
on a lot of the genetic stuff I was like
man maybe we'll just talk about life in
Mendo and growing up like in a
subculture because like I live in a
bubble but where he lives that's like a
bubble within a bubble within a bubble
it is it really is like I it people
don't know how much that little that
area that he lives in and what kind of
world he comes out so the chemist is
supposedly his neighbors so maybe if I
end up going up there and chatting with
him in person which he says he prefers
like who knows
um but there are a lot of old-time
breeders up here
um and that's that's one of the
interesting things is because you know
you you have a tendency which is very
obvious like to interview people that
are currently selling seats
right like to be like a commercial seed
seller right because those are the
people that get their name out there but
a lot of those people got their start
from people that have never been
commercial seed sellers
right they took a bunch of that work
even when you talked to Tom he was like
you know most of Tom's most famous stuff
is the stuff that he liked the best from
the chemist stash
and he just improved except with the
exception of the haze you know um but
the rest of it was pretty much just
stuff that was he got from older people
in the neighborhood
um yeah you know and I think that's a
big thing that a lot of people Miss
where a lot of people think current
breeders kind of come out of nowhere and
they created all this stuff for
themselves but they all had a starting
material as well and a lot of times that
we all stand on the shoulders of those
who came before us
and we just popularized certain things
you know yeah
I was just going to say something I've
certainly learned which resonates with
that is that as time goes by you realize
a lot of the people with the big reps it
may have been just because they were
particularly vocal or loud you know what
I mean like you're referencing they just
they weren't putting it out there you
know
uh yeah I mean I will say that the skill
set required to survive in cannabis
during the prohibition era
was very different than like the show my
face you know burner publicity this is
who I am this is putting your name on a
strain yeah you know was crazy
like trying wanting to know people
people to know who you were and that you
were responsible or associated with this
and so in America a lot of people that
didn't actually create the strain just
became associated with it because they
were the first people to become famous
around it yeah
you know and a lot of people got scared
and like you know you know hide in the
shadows
you know uh for a variety of reasons
you know unlike uh the king of cannabis
we saw Matt hoed up too long ago where
is he where's our guy
did you say that um they put out the
like you know cookies is opening their
own seed bank oh yeah you see greenhouse
seeds in the tag yeah makes sense what's
he gonna add like I really I genuinely
want to know what's going to be on the
menu that's his contribution well you
know
I I think like Ariane is is the
Prototype burner for in the Netherlands
so I'm sure burner could learn a lot
from him when it comes to seed banking I
mean
for one thing uh cookies opened up a
smoking Lounge I believe in one of
greenhouses coffee shops in Amsterdam oh
boy
um and so the collab the collab if you
will started early
um and you know Arjun for all all of you
could there there was a and it's going
on in America now
there was two camps in Amsterdam and one
of them was uh sort of like the the weed
history and the weed nerd camp
and the other Camp was like straight
businessmen who were looking to Market
and and and and and make a lot of money
and Arjun was extremely successful at
the second
he was an he is an extremely successful
businessman he's probably the wealthiest
dude in cannabis that's what I mean I
mean he can teach Berner how to go get
Spanish seed too to everyone to
introduce him to you no longer have to
use these front men like you know
whoever they're using that for the
smaller companies that are repping
cookie stuff you can just buy direct
from the Spaniards and here's the I'm
sure they have a beautiful business I I
bet I bet arjun's angle is that for 25
years uh his town was the center of the
cannabis seed universe and it's shifted
to California so probably Greenhouse
getting promoted by Cookie in California
will probably Drive sales oh I'm sure
and I'm sure their sales are far far
down from what they used to be when they
were the primary place you went to get
seeds sure and then you know the
attitude is popping up in the U.S now
right you know who's running that
I mean I uh yeah I I uh Greenhouse
probably Greenhouse coffee shop is
probably the Prototype cookie
yeah and look something that sort of
jumps to mind when we're talking about
this is that I I did want to try to slip
it in at some point in our chat is that
I uh I really wanted to encourage people
to consider their own personal
weaknesses and and try to address that
so as we've been talking right like
we've just said you know Aryan and
burner both great businessmen and we all
know that there's a lot of great
cannabis
um people in our community who are maybe
good at cultivating but not so good at
the business side or maybe vice versa
and I think that one of the ways we can
stop everything going to [ __ ] long term
is through yeah trying to encourage
people who are like the heads the you
know the guys who we align ourselves
with to try to get a bit more business
savvy you know it's always beneficial to
try to improve your deficits and this is
something I'm learning myself all the
time is that you know it's easy to
assume that like you know yeah I'll
start the company and like I don't I can
just do it you know you just make a
website and you just you know what I
mean and then when you start to really
get into the business World a bit more
you realize like hey you know I was
actually selling those guys short
they've got a whole unique skill set
that I don't have at the moment and it's
probably beneficial if I try to
cultivate some of those skills myself so
highly encourage people to like be
self-reflective and consider your own
personal weaknesses in terms of you know
are you just limiting yourself to one
thing and and you know listen to some
audio books look at people who are doing
it successfully like what we've just
said you know plenty of people have
walked this path before us and they can
show you maybe some of the areas you
could do things better in and that's
certainly where I'm at in my life now is
trying to recognize all of the areas
where I might be a little deficit
compared to others and trying to become
a more well-rounded person because I
think there's only advantages to that
sure so here's a good spot for this when
you when you got in into the idea of
wanting to start making seeds and see
your own creations and and see all this
stuff you obviously were working with
you know what you're working with at the
time based on your your education level
how has that changed now like what what
where are you at in your your seed
career now as far as what you're working
with what direction do you want to go
and how has it changed where it started
yeah that's actually a brilliant
question
um because I think the answer is going
to be a little counter-intuitive
um when I first started making seeds so
this is actually before I started the
podcast or anything I was just you know
some dude in Australia just making seeds
for him and his friends yeah and at the
time I had already completed my
undergraduate degree I had a dual major
one in organic chemistry the other in
molecular biology and genetics so I
actually have a degree in genetics one
of the few people making seeds that do
but what I found was that besides the
most basic principles it actually wasn't
that applicable and I started to realize
that I I didn't I didn't actually think
it was a real credential after a while
because for me for example the majority
of people who have a degree in genetics
or molecular biology it'll largely be
focusing on human biology like you
eukaryotic biology not plant biology so
I think if largely speaking if you
understand the principles of like you
know Punnett squares and mendelian
genetics you don't need to go too much
further because when you do a degree in
this sort of stuff you then move to
humans and you start talking about you
know proto-oncogenes and tumor
suppressing genes and these things just
don't exist yeah it's not applicable in
bunny yeah for sure totally so I came
into it thinking I've got this
background let's see if I can use it and
what I basically found as time went by
is that like I don't feel like that
specific quickly has made me any better
I think that largely speaking the the
things you hear our community commonly
talking about are true I think that
empirical observation is like hugely
important just having experience making
seeds looking at different plants and
that's what I try to stress to people in
Australia is you're limited by your
exposure I have lots of people who
message me in Australia and they say hey
man I've got this super killer clone and
I'm like have you ever tried a USA clone
only because you might and be like oh my
my client's actually not very good
compared to this so and I say to people
you know if you're growing your first
ever plant you take a cutting of it by
definition that's a keeper like you've
got nothing else right so yeah yeah so
as you get more exposure you get better
so for me the thing that's helped me
specifically is to just have had time
making seeds popping them just sort of
seeing what comes out but then obvious
there's also the side of it which is
like the the podcast and what people say
how does that play into it I think
honestly as time's gone by more and more
I've become more in line with the
sentiment that Bodhi expressed on the
show which is basically that the proof's
in the pudding don't judge anyone until
you've grown their work and if it's good
work then like what are you going to
criticize you know make like I like to
think of it as though we've got all
these tools and the the reality is the
more of those tools you incorporate into
your repertoire it's probably more
likely you'll have success but at the
same time that's not to say you can't
haphazardly make the next cookies
because we can all point to various bag
seed that have gone on to become clone
onlys and they take the World by storm
absolutely I think yeah it's great to
have all those tools in your toolkit but
I also think that you shouldn't limit
yourself because you don't have a
genetics degree or whatever you know
like make some seeds like do something
that you're passionate about and you'll
probably find you get better results if
you're Crossing stuff together just
because you're like gel and Aid cross
whatever is going to sell well like you
you probably won't get too much out of
that in terms of like fulfillment or
experience like doing things you're
passionate about going through the
numbers and tying it back to What DJ
Short said
um you know the real way to tell if a
male is good is to pop the seeds and
find out you know that's the only way
the only way that's to actually run the
project yeah and and I think you know
obviously you can be a good breeder it's
not all like random or anything like
that but I think that people shouldn't
like trick themselves into thinking that
they can't make something really cool
because they don't have a degree in
genetics or they don't understand this
certain thing they don't have actual
access to tissue cultured Cuts so yeah I
just would really want to encourage
people to get on board because as time
goes by the more I myself encouraged the
people around me to make seeds get into
it it's fun it's it's what's going to
keep you passionate over the long term
and the more people do it with like
honesty and and passion the better it'll
help combat
um you know stuff which maybe is
produced from a more financial point of
view absolutely yeah I mean one comment
I'll add to that other than I basically
totally agree with it is I you know I
talk all the time about
um there's kind of two sides to breeding
one of it one of it is some like basic
information but then the other is the I
right and I kind of look at the eye as
like the artistic side of it where you
don't have to have an immense amount of
technical knowledge to create something
great you just have to have enough of a
sense and enough of the eye and enough
of being able to smoke and tell you know
and and also on that you know it's like
read what you like
and you know the the best way to breed
in my opinion isn't to grow what you
think other people will be hot on it's
more to like be like here's these two
strains can I get things I like about
each one of them in the same thing
or maybe it'll give me something
unexpected you know
um and then on top of that too the most
important part of weed the high is
invisible
yeah right so you can't actually see it
you have to test it and you can't really
test it with with testing you have to
test it the old-fashioned way by
consuming and then get feedback on it
um and so I like that you came around to
that side of things because uh you know
when I when in Out Here in uh as
cannabis is becoming legal you're
starting to meet with a bunch of big AG
people
and they just can't believe how
you know I don't even know the term to
use they probably think that the
Cannabis gene pool is just nuts
because they're used to Growing these
strains of vegetables or fruits or
whatever that have Decades of breeding
out of all these universities that they
bred them to be extremely like reliable
to these certain traits there's all
kinds of ibls all over the place and
then comes this big crazy manic very
poorly documented cannabis gene pool
that doesn't do anything they think it's
going to do and they're like what is
this this is a mess right but to us it's
beautiful It's A Beautiful Mess
yeah you know but to them they're like
how do I make an IBL out of this does
the exact same thing in the whole field
and that's what we're about
it's funny you mentioned that because
the Australian uh legal medical scene is
is really starting to take off it's sort
of only occurred in the past two three
years but it's really starting to take
off and I'm really fortunate that I've
been able to be involved with a few
facilities be it like consulting or even
looking at maybe trying to get some of
my genetics into the facilities and the
most crazy thing which relates to what
you just said is that one of the
facilities told me that they had spent
Millions like literally 10 million
dollars from the moment they started the
company until the end of their first
year of operation and it was because
they hadn't been able to put out a
single successful crop in that first
year and they're paying overheads for
this huge facility whatnot and it was
basically because they said the first
six months we had to teach our Growers
to grow and the second six months we had
to finohan and it was just mind-blowing
it was like like you guys didn't know
this is what to expect like they didn't
under they thought like what you said
they'd pop a seed it would be the exact
plant they wanted and they were like oh
you gotta hunt through this and then
propagate the keeper up and then get you
know what I mean it was it was very
eye-opening that the big AG who had all
this money
seemingly had so little insight into the
very foundational practicalities of like
growing plants I saw that when I worked
at the grapery and I was doing that big
um them reversal on hipster and they I
mean some of these are some of the best
great growers in California that have
been doing it 50 years plus you know
like growing some of the best most
expensive grapes uh sold in California
and um they were shocked they they had
no idea what to expect from Cannabis
they didn't understand that the the the
the lack of sex control that we have
over the cannabis plant in the first
place that is totally baffling to them
that we can't control the sex very well
through environment or spray I mean we
can reverse it sure but like as far as
keeping it female and 100 non-staminant
like they don't understand that because
that's the sex sexual stuff isn't as
plastic in a lot of their their the
plants that they work with so yeah it is
a whole different ballpark it's a weird
plant it's a very weird plant among
plants even you know it's not just weird
uh from humans to plants but actually
plants to plants it's a very weird plant
hugely hugely it's a different game down
here and um yeah it's cool to see the
medical Market opening up in Australia I
would actually love to see like there's
no surprisingly no one from America has
come over here and like
like just set up something that works
because as it stands all of the
Australian producers are not really
producing a good quality product it's
all sort of Mitzi and the only decent
herb you can buy is imported from Canada
and so you can already tell that it's
not the best of the best right like yeah
it's um so yeah it's very interesting I
hope that someone comes and sets up a
facility in Australia and just crushes
it but um it's sort of yet to happen
that's wild I mean there I mean the
second Thailand to open up cookies was
there so I'm kind of surprised that
Australia just
has been a I used to have a dream of uh
being wealthy enough to avoid winter
and so I would spend half the year in
Australia avoiding winter and then I
used to see these grows posted from
Northern Australia by people growing
Neville's Haze outside and they actually
had a climate that they could grow like
these beautiful sativa plants and finish
them without getting cold and getting
ruined and so it's I I never really did
anything serious about it but I always
kind of had in this back in my mind oh
maybe I could go to Australia one day
and grow all these different plants in
my backyard that I could never do in
NorCal
yeah please come on over
so so I know I know the Aussie fans are
going to be super bummed if we don't
talk about some of the the heroes from
over there
um yeah sure
and Where Do We Begin where do you want
to start with you have a much better
grasp of it but please sure so I mean I
think for a lot of people the obvious
thing would be like wanting to talk
about like Neville or Shanti or any of
that but I think in all honesty
um I actually actually listened to your
episode talking about some of the older
European guys and I think people should
just listen to that if they're
interested like there is so much
information about the seed bank that I
just didn't know that I got out of
listening to you guys hash that one out
so I don't think we'll touch on them but
I'd love to touch on some people who the
international audience may not be quite
as familiar with but were like pretty
focal people so
um I think it might in fact be the
people you're referencing not so dog but
there's this crew called the Wizards of
Oz and it was made up of two dudes
largely speaking Wally duck who goes
online by the name um Donald Mallard
he's on icmag he's one of the moderators
he's a very well-known dude and then
another guy called Moon Unit
yeah and then the third guy you're
probably familiar with or heard the name
of is kangativa so oh yeah yeah so those
three guys are what I would consider to
be like the
the dudes who are sort of like me but a
few years ago where it was like a a sort
of notable guy you could point to from
the Australian scene and largely
speaking there hasn't been too many
others but what they did that I love was
not only were they growing like cool
Thai stuff and the mum bimby Madness and
all that but they're actually working on
trying to make some unique hybrids so
Donald Mallard is the guy who brought
the duck's foot to the scene yeah and
that's how he got that name and I've
done an interview with him it's a sort
of interesting story how it came about
but he sort of it's not too dissimilar
to ABC in fact sure he just sort of got
it given to him and he was like wow this
is a real mutant plant and
um it sort of went from there but
they're they're notable for doing the
z99 hybrid so that's a cross of Zoid
Fuel and an F4 c99 from the original
Heavens stairway stock so what was
interesting about that was is that the
Zoid fuel is a super interesting strain
it's made by Moon Unit on his own and he
basically did what Neville said he could
never do which was he he spun together
three land races to make something that
is like very representative or akin to
Modern cannabis he basically took a
Chinese Yuan a PNG gold and an
Australian heirloom sativa so probably
like an acclimatized tie yeah yeah like
that he spun those together to make
something which to me looks very similar
to like an Amnesia Haze or something
like that
except the high is like a hundred
percent anxiety from that PNG goal
you know why when he was a homie he told
me that was like the white whale the PNG
gold
yeah yeah you know what I've got a buddy
who reckons he might have some I'll send
it over because he he wants me to send
some stuff to the states so we might
look into doing that because I'd love to
see people grow it out it's going to be
a big plant man a big let's do a group
project on it between the two podcasts
anxiety isn't my favorite Buzz no not
mine either but it's one that everybody
misses and it usually ends
it exists in weed and it is strange
sometimes what different strains give
people anxiety and others it relaxes
them I find that very interesting but
yeah the 100 anxiety crawl out of your
chair
uh that's always an interesting
description did you ever run into
smoking moose much in your in your
research in the Australian stuff I know
the name I I do remember the name from I
see mag did you have much history with
him yeah he was on uh Mr Nice forums he
was friends with me Wally and and uh
Moon Unit and he was one of the guys
that a lot of us like looked up to as an
elder in the scene but I don't know much
more about like his actual history in
Australia but I know him and Tony
mullaway and a few others are real big
out there
yeah do you have much info on Tony
yeah he's he's still doing his thing
he's been providing
um like so I I've I've met him I think
two or three times over the past few
years just haphazardly not not at like
events just randomly bumping into him
he's um he's a he's a big dude in the
underground medical scene in the sense
that
um he he would give medicine to really
sick people yeah before like before you
could really get it so yeah yeah he's
definitely like an OG in terms of having
provided a lot of like um RSO type
medicine for people who are really sick
over the past 20 or so years yeah and he
definitely gives out a lot of seed that
um he says you know if you grow this and
you want to make RSO it's it's going to
be good genetics I'm actually not
familiar with what the genetics he gives
out but he is he is definitely a known
dude he hasn't got online unfortunately
there's a few guys like that yeah um and
he's more of a like a a local Legend in
like nimbin that sort of thing oh yeah
nimbin's a bit is that like you're
Humboldt out there
it it is and it isn't so the the
Australian scene is very interesting
because there's a huge divide between
the Old Guard and the sort of younger
generation the old guys largely speaking
they like smoking
but they're they're also equally driven
by
um Financial motivation so like things
have to yield well those sort of factors
yeah yeah the younger generation is more
indoor cookies hype that sort of thing
so in nimbin you can get lots of outdoor
stuff it'll be sort of
thai-esque it's not unfortunately it's
not like the tie you would hope you
would get where if I said oh hey I found
some tie and you'd be like oh [ __ ] Are
we about to yeah a once in a lifetime
experience yeah unfortunately it's not
that yeah
um but it's just like what we would call
Australian bushweed so the acclimatase
tie yeah exactly it's Gonna Get huge the
high is not as unique
um but the yield's good it's generally
uplifting and it's generally grown by
guys who only ever had exposure to
sativa in their life you know like they
wouldn't have got Indica until like you
know probably the mid 90s yeah yeah
right yeah like like even way after
California sort of thing when it was
just super commercially available that
was when they would have got it so a lot
of those guys are just like die hard
sativa dudes so you can definitely get
that at nimbin these days if I if
someone came to me and said how can I
get good weed in Australia or like they
were like I want to come to Australia
for a holiday
um I just want to make sure I got like
some good weed when I get there yeah I
would say it's actually very easy to
just find a good grower on Instagram
from Australia and just be like can I
buy a bag
um yeah yeah
let me interject something before I
forget right
um so one of the things I was thinking
of when uh when you were talking about
the the differences in you know in
Indica uh in America versus there is
um you know because I bet most of our
listeners don't know like in a place
like nimbin or different places like
that that had some weed culture
um how intense was the police pressure
uh in that area because really what I
think what started the huge wave of
outdoor sativa to Indica in California
was helicopters
before the helicopters it was all sativa
and then as police pressure became
incredibly intense they wanted bigger
yielding thicker and most importantly
earlier stuff
but I don't know if that that would have
would have happened without that outside
pressure you know
um so you know if you're if you're a
bush grower as you were talking about
um what's it like for those people
yeah great question I I think there are
some people who could tell you they've
had to battle with helicopters but I
don't think it was on the scale of like
Camp yeah and some of those notable
campaigns in California I think that uh
largely speaking a lot of those outdoor
Growers
uh that if I had to go out on a limb I'd
say their primary consideration is yield
and so I think the the acclimatized ties
always just sort of out yielded
everything honestly because if you're
like where Wally duck is which is like
the northern part of Australia you're
basically at the equator and stuff will
flower all year round that's amazing and
so it was sort of hard to compare yields
if you've got like a tire that goes for
21 weeks and it's just growing that
whole time and that's where you'd see
those crazy photos of kangativa posting
the Mullen man never forget them never
the old mother sativa oh yeah oh yeah
yeah yeah old mother City's a good one
and um yeah it's it's interesting there
are definitely some guys outside who who
grow um indicas and I and I suspect that
they would have had luck with that but I
think that like a lot of people who I
speak to are interested in like sort of
what Wally duck has to offer which is
like I've got this z99 hybrid so like
the c99 tames the anxiety of the Zoid
fuels because they didn't want to get
rid of the sativa Edge they still wanted
it to be like an uplifting effect but
not so like [ __ ] yourself so the d99 is
sort of what you're alluding to not so
dog it's that shorter plant but it's
still got that sativa high that they're
used to because they grew up smoking
Thai so I think that was sort of the
middle ground and I think that is in
fact why they made the z99 because it
was like hey this is like an indoor
friendly really uplifting sativa strain
that is a just a little bit more
versatile I want to modernize Australia
and start pushing Appalachia over there
it's like to me to me it's like the the
like what c99 kind of always pushed for
an early flowering something that had
that really nice almost what people
would typify as a sativa Taipei and um
but fast flowering good density all the
looks but just lacking a lot of the
paranoia but still with the potency you
know I'd love to get that over there I'm
always fascinated by uh things and
breeding that occur because of where
you're at not necessarily what you're
after you know and and so I think like
for people like Sam Skunk Man or
something like that or Rob Clark or
whoever like breeding Colombians in in
California in the 70s they probably
would have stuck with them but they
wouldn't finish yeah so then they're
like oh I'll add this Mexican that's a
little faster you know and then oh this
is a little faster oh and then I'll add
in this Indica that's a little faster
now I have skunk one you know type of
thing
um and and you know in Australia like I
you know it like I said like I can't I
can't grow a 20 week in the Emerald
Triangle you can't grow a 20-22 week
stream unless you light depth it
starting months earlier it just won't
finish it gets too cold the Sun goes
away sometimes it rains sometimes it
freezes it just doesn't have the weather
um and you know so without with with
tropical weather and no police pressure
like California might be a vast sativa
land still
um yeah because you know it it it's
interesting how those things shift and
it sounds like Australia didn't have the
same intense pressures to shift
yeah well I guess like the one thing I
could say in relation to that point is I
think another reason why the like the
old mother sativa and those things fared
so well was because for the longest time
people weren't growing indoors so you
were really limited by the conditions
outdoors and if you're up like North
like where Wally is the humidity and the
temperatures are off the chart year
round and so I think that lended itself
to why they just kept growing the tire
for so long because it would never mold
even though the humidity is like 80 plus
percent all year round yeah and um
during summer the heat can get pretty I
mean this is the funny thing
historically people are like oh
Australia gets hot it like the hottest
it gets in California is the same as
here it's just maybe we get a few more
days of that here it's it's not
particularly more but yeah just endless
weeks of heat and humidity I think the
time lends itself to that
yeah I could see that
I don't think people from America
realize how different the climate is
from say like Sydney and Adelaide and
those places down there up through Byron
Bay and and nimbin and then up into like
the tropical North and then you have
this vast hot dry desert in the middle
um that's very uncomfortable and then
you get over to like you know I don't
even know what the weather's like in
Perth or like that kind of like isolated
part of Australia
um but yeah it's essentially Northern
Australia is tropical right that yeah
that continent is massive so yeah it's
it's got a quite a diverse uh climate
between it yeah so there's a guy in
Australia he's an American dude he's
from Oregon his name's Steve Solomon he
um is one of the guys who sort of taught
coot and then like so he was like one of
Coots gurus anyway he um he moved to
Tasmania because the climate is the
exact same as Oregon so if you look at
Tasmania and start going up so like you
know you'd say Melbourne would be sort
of the next thing above Tasmania which
is at the bottom of the Continental
Australia
um that might be somewhat equivalent to
like Northern California so as you go up
Australia you're sort of going down from
Oregon and there is some a degree of
overlap in the climates not not 100
obviously you know Oregon's like very
humid and wet sort of place and maybe
Tasmania is a little less wet but it's
still largely speaking very similar so
you can try to replicate some of the
sort of micro climates but I think
Humboldt and Mendocino you know they're
their own special little egg I don't
know if we have anything like that in
Australia
um and the only reason I I saw recently
something that really helped me with
that was that it was this map of
Australia that made the weather patterns
in relationship to places I knew from my
from America
yeah right and like you could be like oh
this area is like this weather and this
area is like that weather and this area
is and I think that was like really
helpful actually for me to like
understand
um you know the climate differences yeah
and all that because I do think like
maybe down south uh you know where most
of the population is probably is more
like California
right
um and
um so you're saying like in uh in
Tasmania maybe does the 45th parallel go
through Tasmania I think it's pretty
close hey yeah I think it's it's very
similar and I know some dudes who do try
to grow similar stuff Outdoors like I've
got a mate who got some Jaeger s ones
off Caleb yeah and he said they did
really well so it's like okay I'm sure
yeah I mean the the 45th parallel in in
America goes through like Portland
Oregon right yeah
um and and uh but obviously it would be
the 45th North and you would be the 45th
South
you know yeah um so you know probably
like probably for you guys like Northern
Australia is probably like something a
little bit like Mexico but more humid
and it's funny you mentioned that
because I I did sort of wonder how did
nimbin become this hot spot of Australia
because it's it's not geographically
quite in the right spot it's a little
too North it rains a little too much
for it to be like
real like a lot of the guys who grow in
that nimbing area like they're always
battling like the first reign of the
season and stuff like that so it is
really interesting that it got set up
there I think maybe the reason is that
um it was a the police's priorities were
a little less there but um yeah I'd have
to imagine that somewhere down near
Melbourne would theoretically be the
better spot to have your cannabis Mecca
of Australia because it's just colder
the humidity is more manageable and you
just don't have these prolonged hot
periods you know
yeah I mean I I think one of the you
know I I uh one of the things that that
um when I first read like for instance
uh This is Gonna sound but DJ shorts
book right
um which is an interesting one but it
had some tidbits that always stuck with
me
um was he talked about how in different
parts of the world there's just there's
these cannabis regions that are ideal
for certain types of ranges of varieties
right and it just so happens in America
that Humboldt uh and Mendocino County
um and some of Lake County and some of
Trinity are in this like sweet spot
right where the temperature is nice and
um like it's it's also like remote and
hilly and away from authorities so you
could kind of get away with it you know
and it was dry as well
um or at least dry and you know it
doesn't rain in the summertime in
California very very frequently so
um it's interesting how now that we see
legalization going on you see all this
gear being put towards growing cannabis
in all these places that aren't very
well suited for it
yeah uh it is you know there's lots of
places that it's not very well suited
and but a lot of times you grow where
you can get away with it
yeah you know right and so a lot of the
most famous cannabis zones in the world
are places that a are suitable and B you
could get away with it
because you kind of have to have both
you know yeah that's a hugely valid
point I I definitely get that and I I
have to imagine that there will be some
new hot spots coming out of Australia as
more time goes by and you know what's
interesting as you said that you made me
realize all of the facilities largely
speaking that I interact with the legal
ones they are down in Victoria and so I
guess they've made the decision that
like now it's legal like why why
wouldn't you set up in the place that
has the best environment for it you know
so I guess there's some four thoughts
there there is one or two operations in
that far Northern rivers that nimbin
area and I think they're just having to
try to brute force their way through bad
conditions with uh yeah you end up
spending more money
in order to grow the same kind of
cannabis I mean uh one of the
interesting things is that when I first
started going to Amsterdam in the 90s
almost all indoor technology is like
trickle-down technology from their
professional greenhouses that they have
in Holland and in Belgium and in Germany
because their climate sucks right so you
know they grow vegetables like they'll
have like a hundred thousand lights of
cucumbers and tomatoes right and almost
all of our indoor technology that we
have that we use to grow cannabis all
descends from that happening you know
um where Australia
or America is the same way they're both
big enough that you can probably grow
various crops where the climate just
suits it
right
um and you know and and you know some
some places indoors the only viable
thing because the climate sucks some
places you can grow maybe in a
greenhouse but you'd have to have huge
dehumidifiers and lights and all kinds
of climate control because you're
fighting the weather isn't isn't as
ideal as you want
yeah it's so interesting you mentioned
that because that's literally all I've
been thinking about in regards to
Thailand it's like it's so humid and hot
over there you I I don't even know if
you could produce high quality outdoor
crops I think you'd have to do it indoor
and like yeah I is it I I have questions
about whether the logical answer for
them will just be to try to import it
because like it's just so costly to try
to overcome this just strangling
humidity part of the reason I think that
uh part of the reason when you see some
of those like Thai sativas and they end
up being like wispy calyxes that are
just like you know a Tremors Nightmare
and most people would just want to
eliminate because of what modern
cannabis is supposed to look like but
it's probably with that level of
humidity that's the kind of buds you
need to grow to not have it all rot
yeah right and like the effect is like I
also like the um I can't remember who
said it but someone was like you know
life at the equator it's sort of a
little easier because it's warm than
like up north and so it's interesting
how equatorial plants tend to be more
like sativa and fun and uplifting and as
you get North or South you get these
more Indica varieties that are sort of a
bit more medicinal and maybe it's
because Life's a bit harder in those
environments I've always been interested
in like sort of what you're talking
about like the environment as well as
like how that maybe affected the type of
high that was selected over thousands of
years
that that's a huge subject too and I I
think that
um one of the reasons is that uh you
know a lot of those sativas were bred
for smoking the flower
where all those indicas were bred for
harvesting the hash the trichomes they
were they were resin farmers and so
Americans and Australia others you know
it's it's basically you know when we
started getting those indicas that we
started blending them with what we had
and smoking them
um you know there uh there's a there's a
funny story uh that uh uh Kamara tells
about you know one of Sam's stories or
whatever
um about trying to get seeds in
Afghanistan and he wanted flour to get
the seeds and the warlord or whatever
looked at him and was literally like you
know women and slaves smoke flower men
smoke hashish
right uh and so yeah you know like uh
the there they they didn't breed for
smoking flour yeah you know yeah uh we
did
you know so it's it's an interesting
divide the parts of the world that breed
for resin and only smoke hashish and the
parts of the world that breed for flower
it's very different very different
selection pressure in my opinion hugely
can I um actually take this somewhere a
little unexpected because these thoughts
here I need my mind I want to ask you
specifically not so dog what's your
thoughts on Mendo breath because it's
such a hugely popular strain and I think
largely speaking the popularity comes
from the Mendo perps that's utilized in
it and I'd be interested to know like do
you look at Australian like that knowing
it's got Mendo perps in it and that if
you actually look at the Mendo flower
now there's a good few characteristics
that are actually you could say oh
that's actually from the Mendo perps
like the smell and the flavor
specifically I um I'd be interested to
hear like do you ever do you get
invested do you like sort of track it or
are you just like it's it's not really
my thing anymore
I mean I uh you know there's
I'm all I'm I'm like you know super
interested in genetics and what passes
down and what think and what things
breed for right uh and one of the
interesting things is because you know
I'll be I'll be totally honest I don't
think Mendo perps by itself is like an
elite complete strain like it's THC
content and it's high it's like people
that don't smoke weed a lot really
really like it but if you smoke heavy
Indica all day long you try to go from
like you know uh pure kush or something
to a a Mendo mom uh it's lighter yeah um
but it breeds really well and it adds
color and it adds all these unique
flavors and I will say that anytime I
ever smell anything that I think oh that
smells like Mendo perps
I turns out that it has Mendo perps in
it
right and not to say not to say that
Mendo perps has that unique and nothing
else does but there are things that are
older that had smell profiles like
people hunting for Super Skunk Aromas
that have been lost right and are either
rare or only found in one or two lines
these days
um and so you know I think uh I think
Mendo breath got popular because I think
with IG
um IG made everything that was going to
be popular it had to be photogenic
it became very hard in the Instagram era
to have ugly weed because you couldn't
tell what it smelled like and you
couldn't tell what it what's its high
was like but you could tell what it
looked like
and Mendo breath is very pretty
it's thick it's juicy huh I remember
when it came out a lot of the popularity
for it was because of the looks and a
lot of the looks for ogkb at the time I
think the staying popularity and the
reason people used it was because of the
Mendo perks to be honest there was a lot
of other ogkb offerings at the time like
it was one of the later ones that that
came out and one of the the last ones
from the original era of the ogkv
hybrids and it had some of the best
pictures of it but I think it's staying
power in lines was Mendo pervs because
of the the terp content stuff like that
that adds uniqueness to lines for sure
that's a good question
heavy days one of the things about that
that for like someone who likes to know
like lineage and history
um is that a lot of breeders like to
obscure what where they got the sauce
that they got to make what they made and
so people generally speaking are not
super honest about origin stories it's
it's more rare than you would like
um because they want to be like oh I
made this famous thing and it's all my
my gig
they don't want to be like oh I took a
piece from here and a piece from there
and a piece from there and it blended it
together and Bam I got lucky there it is
right yeah and maybe they don't even
like the person that the that one of the
we the strains came from so they don't
want to credit that person yeah yeah
um and uh you know and so
um but you know good weed is good weed
and so I do think that um Mendo perps
isn't a lot more things than people give
it credit for uh it's a shame that
philos and others were unable to do what
they promised which is reveal family
lineages and ancestry genetically like
that
um but
it is uh it is in a lot of things
uh and it Blends well with a lot of
things and um it adds color and a lot of
Terps we're about to crack the F1 derb
um whole whole thing around that right
now and I I'm I'm putting my odds on
Mendo purpose being an F1 derp I haven't
really told him that but I'm putting my
money on it there's there's there's
there's been an aspect of uh people ask
me sometimes on the lives to talk about
the cookie story and I kind of held off
because there's such a there's such a
juggernaut of money and they have these
various intentions about being the
biggest cannabis thing in America
obviously so poking around at their
story you know like they don't really
care about the truth as much as they
care about the pr of developing their
brand they have like a massive brand
right and so
um you know things that add to that
brand are positive things that take away
or or whatever maybe not so much so the
cookie story is a hard one to tell
yeah um
you know uh you know money gets involved
in things uh and you know who created
what who's responsible for what
right yeah
um when you interview him make him break
it down for you
we'll do that we'll do that I have to
admit the reason why I was curious about
the the Mendo purse question was because
um it's it's exactly what you guys said
um I like a lot of the work I'm doing
now relates to this very special jelly
breath clone I found and largely
speaking it's just a very Mendo breath
dominant clone and so I've always been
very interested in asking you about that
because I like through trying this jelly
breath I'm like man this stuff's amazing
but I can tell a lot of it's coming from
the Mendo breath and I can tell a lot of
that's coming from the Mendo perps
um yeah it's interesting that's that's
cool to hear the backstory and I
definitely think that the Mendo breath
performed the best out of the OG KBS
because a lot of people are going to put
up an argument say Dosey does better I
just don't think doci does better
especially considering jelly breath is a
cross of Mendo breath and do-sido
um I'm very grateful it came out leaning
towards the Mendo breath side the
particular cut that I kept and um you
know the other stuff like Grandpa's
breath from um dungeon bolts like he's a
cool guy it's a cool strain I just don't
think it's quite in that same category
as dosido or Mendo breath but yeah it's
it's beautiful stuff man and and like
I've done a BX on it and I see more of
those sort of Mendo Finos coming out
where I think they're a little less
cookies looking a little more magenta
and um a bit more cerebral high it's
really enjoyable yeah how much of the
train wrecks leaking through in that
from the crystal locomotive that's what
I always wondered and I have to imagine
that the majority of the Mendo breath
flavor you get is just from the Mendo
perks because it doesn't strike me to
train wreck at all I've never tried it
the the Mendo I think that I think the
train wreck gives the structure and some
of the density and some of the crystal
content and visible Frost
um and I think the color and the perps
and the and the Terps and the flavor
profiles get dominated by the Mendo
here's one for you
um the original line that was said to be
used in the Mendo breath was supposedly
key place that he created it but
somewhere in my seat I have the original
pack from JoJo of Mendo perps Crystal
Locum so it did exist prior to key play
playing with it that did exist and if I
have it that means a lot of people that
knew JoJo had it wow so it does still
exist the original mother stock does
still exist and is out there of that
leading back to the Mendo perch Crystal
locomotive pre-blackberry pie or
whatever the age called it or keep play
wow that's rad that's super cool man
would you ever want to pop him or are
you just like nah I
the last time I tried popping some of
Jojo stuff was um a friend of ours
working man gave me some um pure Crystal
locomotive that he had and I was like
yeah I'm gonna pop these right now and
then I like right after popping him it's
just screwed everything up and I was
like [ __ ] I'm just never gonna pop these
things because every time I do something
screws up but yeah if you're ever if you
ever want to run through them I know you
like that line I'll send you out some of
that stuff to try
uh you're too kind you're too kind maybe
I could spend a second or two just
talking about
um some of the stuff I'm doing but also
some of the stuff in Australia
go for it yes
yeah like something I'm trying to do is
sort of help grow the scene and whether
that be like um you know trying to
Mentor some up-and-coming people just
you know help avoid make the mistakes
and pitfalls I did or just more
importantly trying to help put Australia
on the map a little bit and just
highlight the thing that I think is the
real selling point for Australia is that
and and you could say this about many
countries
um we don't have any USA clone only is
in Australia no one has successfully
brought them over and these days I
actively tell people don't do it we
don't want the markets the whole plating
virus like you don't want to be the dude
who brought that to Australia exactly so
what I say is that the selling point is
that there's a little bit less of that
same sameness about the offerings
because everyone has to hunt seeds fine
killer moms and I'm now at the point
where I am confident that there are a
few cuttings in Australia that could
stand up to some of the cuts in the
states sure of course you know there are
some cuts that you know the chems the
TKS like it you know I'm not talking
about that that's the next level right
but like a lot of the stuff that's
commonly passed around is clone only is
like we've got stuff that stands up to
that and the cool part is it's from
people you know like you know there's a
there's a Bodhi cutting the chemical
easy so that's chem 91 cross 2 the 88g13
hash plant there's a beautiful cutting
of that that goes around Australia it
won uh one of the smaller cannabis cups
one year so really beautiful stuff I
think it tends to tap a bit more into
the hash plant components yeah yeah yeah
and it dominates yeah
so also you know what's what's good
about that though is that the chem 91
and I've talked about this uh before but
um out of anything you know uh my uh our
buddy CSI is one of the most prolific
breeders I know and he said there's
nothing in his collection that passes
potency as consistently as the chem 91
cut which chem 91 was in that one yeah
do you know which one was in the Kim
kisi
uh is the 91 the real one because I
remember there was two different
releases at the cam 91 G13 hash plant
and that's why I was asking I can't
remember which one was named witch that
one had one had the Joe brand cut that
was a diesel and one had the skunk VA
the skunk yeah yeah so I mean I just so
you know if it adds potency and the G13
hash plan is pretty and Frosty and dense
and more modern looking you know in a
way then
um you know chem 91 is some like ancient
looking
ugly Afghan weed that's [ __ ] ugly I
don't care it's legitimately ugly you
know I mean I think it's beautiful but
like you know it's kind of ugly compared
to Modern weed
um
leaves during stuff like yeah grows it
beautiful I have no complaints about the
way it's going he grows it beautiful but
I could never get it to perform like he
does at all I just couldn't I mean
Staten Island he used to joke about like
you know some some of the best runs that
we had with it every fan Leaf would do
that and die before Harvest
and the bud the bud would still be
beautiful but it would like you would
just be like oh my God for the last two
weeks of Bloom it's dying it's done yeah
it's eating itself oh no you know but
then it would come out fire
so it's funny you mention that because I
think most people I know say oh if you
want like a real Benchmark for the chem
91 like try some from skunk VA but I
think in his mind he would say those
early Staten Island guy harvests were
probably The Benchmark for him in a
sense you know what I mean so it's
interesting you mentioned that
what's funny to me about even though the
chems aren't uh they weren't named that
because they were they were grown chem
it
um they really do uh respond well like
my uh Statin used to joke he's like it
really likes GH you know it really likes
General Hydroponics three-part you know
you can try all this organic this and
that and everything else and it comes
out pretty nice and then you grow it in
three part and you're like oh my God
it's out of the park
um and you know what's funny about that
is he was organic for so long the reason
why we all started calling it dog was
because he wouldn't call it chem because
he didn't grow chem wheat he didn't grow
candy weed he grew organic in dirt weed
so he couldn't call his organic weed
chem so he called it you know he called
it dog chem dog you know and that's and
it's stuck in our little crew in Skunk
VA and I see Collective and me and
Staten Island I mean forever until the
until really the forums it was just dog
someone gave Joe brand according to Joe
brand his story is that someone gave him
[ __ ] because they didn't want to give
him the real [ __ ] and he started passing
it and didn't know that's his from his
point of view that's how it was and it
sounds like from talking to some of the
other guys that maybe it was more
intentional because Joe Brown's a little
harder to deal with for most people I
like the guy he's a great guy no no
offense from my angle but like they they
had some troubles you know yeah yeah
yeah I mean some of that stuff people
want history and uh knowing a decent
amount of those people pretty well I can
say that like what's a lot of what's
been publicly told is true but then
there's some interplay between various
friends and falling in and out of
friendships and different things that
happen to different times and some of
that has been I think withheld
um you know but uh you know and people
miss people mislabeling Cuts people
going through some bad times in their
life maybe and partying a little too
hard and letting Cuts get out that you
know
um and so it never got lost in the crew
itself but there's different individuals
at different times that you know
um may or may not have intentionally or
not passed out things that ended up
being quote unquote fakes it's how we
ended up with seven kmds is what he's
trying to say oh no I'm not going to hit
that his mouth but that's what I'm
saying
yeah no I mean it you know Joe you know
it's it's Joe Brand's a big partier you
know
um there was some chaos and and I see
collective's Life at that point in time
and like that's where my that's where my
not so dog even came from was
um him selling a a bunch of dog to
Staten Island and he couldn't believe
what it looked like and I was like oh
it's not so dog
um and so it's been it's been lost a few
it's been lost a few times amongst it
but no but no no none of the four of us
ever all lost it at once yeah let's put
it that way you know so it's been
refurbished
yeah yeah and and you know and honestly
too it's like it took we all had it for
so long before anyone even cared yeah
to you know to be to be clear about it
too it's like before the forums and the
internet and all that like it wasn't
famous
you know you know it just kind of
touches back on the on the the tale of
like you know there are some people who
intentionally obscure stuff there are
some people who you know whatever but
there are also some people who genuinely
are trying to get it right that just
can't for whatever reason because of
past Stories being muddled and that's
just that and that's where it's left and
you can only correct what you can at the
end you know but there there are people
that are genuinely you know try to get
it right and nail it and then something
comes out where it's like oh my God and
and it's how they take responsibility
for it and how they act with it like you
know at the Kim 91 thing a lot of us had
different chem 91 cuts at the time and
none of us knew we were all passing them
to each other and we all thought it was
the same thing you know it's different I
mean it can be hard like you want to be
historically accurate right sure but
then you also because we come from a
clan design society and like not
everyone you know it wants to show their
face or be Associated or have their real
name no known with it and so in some
cases
um you you know you're protecting
someone's wishes you know for the larger
point of their life or in another case
you might be glossing over some things
that aren't absolutely critical to the
history because it might paint them in a
bad light or be personally embarrassing
or not the greatest you know not the
greatest time in their life when they
were struggling with something or
whatever and so you don't want to just
put out gnarly details for the public to
consume that might like hurt someone's
feelings or something like that so
you're trying to stay as accurate to the
story and as and history as you can
without it necessarily being a grimy
tell-all
let's talk about what you're what you're
working on now like what where what's
brought you to now what interests you
now genetically yeah great question I'd
love to delve into that so
um
historically I was really and I mean
even still now but I'll quickly cover
the backstory on it but historically I
was working with this strain that I
called raspberry Mama it's essentially a
phantom Kush F2 which is uh an offering
from Ken's GDP okay and it was a cross
of Pink Champagne to Ken's cush Ken's
cush is essentially OG cross to sour I
don't know how they got a mail out of
that but somehow they did manage them
they managed and um so yeah so Crossing
that OG sour thing to the pink champagne
and then from that I bred it to the F2
and tried to just steer it a hundred
percent to the Pink Champagne because
when I smelt that turf I was like man
this is real interesting champagne
Pink Champagne is an unknown clone from
the NorCal area it came out largely
around the time of About Cherry Pie
probably because cherry pie came out at
the same time it stole the Limelight
yeah it's very it's a very similar plant
in the sense that it's a very sort of
different Turpin profile like cherry pie
in my mind is is quite a unique smell
there wasn't too much at that time that
smelt like it and it's got for me Pink
Champagne obviously has this sort of
champagne component to it so like this
sweet fizzy effervescent quality but
there's but there's also like this
really nice
um feminine perfume aspect to it nice so
and and I think to me cherry pie is I'll
describe it similar right like there's
like this perfumey component and um
anyway so I'm working with that and a
few people from like um the Bay Area
remember it and they're like oh yeah I
remember you know Pink Champagne that
was cool anyway so I'm working with that
it's an F2 and I'm doing my thing
making seeds at that time I wasn't
really putting out much I was still just
you know doing my own thing figuring out
the ropes and I eventually reversed it
made some Femmes gave those out and they
did okay but then I had to move and I
lost the plan I I didn't have it the two
guys who I had backing it up they both
lost it thinking someone else had it
yeah yeah
cannabis stuff right and um and so that
was what then stimulated a bit of move
on and start looking at the jelly breath
stuff I mentioned however
about a year ago a good buddy of mine
and another breeder in Australia his
name is feral genetics he's a cool dude
he works with like land race Thai and
Crosses it to like uh elephant stomper
and stuff like that like cool stuff and
um he hit me up and he's like bro you
probably don't remember but you gave me
a pack of the s1s you made and
um I hunted through them and I found
something that I think you should take a
look at and so I went to his house and
um it was like the original the the
plant I thought I had lost but it was
actually better because the original it
would just stay green it wouldn't budge
but this one went purple so I was like
yeah this is like this is even better
and so I've been working with that more
recently because it's come back and I
guess what's interesting is from a
genetics point of view it's like an F2
S1 so that's a bit that's a bit
interesting in itself sure
um and then I recently did some
feminized crosses with that and so that
then made the F2 S2 yeah so again from a
genetics point of view a little bit
different to what you might see I think
it's I think it's very interesting for
especially like speeding up
stabilization
yeah well what was interesting was the
majority of the original s1s did not
come out like the mum so I'm like all
right the mum is a recessive feed
exactly most plants aren't coming out
like that so when this one was the same
I'm like oh [ __ ] that means both
recessives have lined up in this one
yeah and it can only possibly pass on
the recessive trait which means
theoretically most of The Offspring
should come out with these sort of
traits and not be like like the s1s
exactly so yeah so I've definitely been
interested by that and then at the same
time I'm also working
um the the JB clone into a seed line and
what I did was I initially made so I got
this jelly breath clone and and you just
may as well think about it as a cookies
thing right it's just easy but it's
cookies
um so I crossed that to this strain I
got from duke which was chem D his chemd
I know there's discussion around that
but I'll just quickly move on
um his chemd across to Local H and the
Local H is is um Sour Diesel cross to
diesel slash cuttlefish hash plants so
this I remember a cuttlefish I remember
that one I made s1s of it a long time
ago oh actually it was a Black Russian
cuttlefish
that's cool man because like no one
really worked with it right no so sunny
and me
yeah so yeah so I crossed this chemd
Sour Diesel sort of hybridy plant to the
the cookies and I ended up like there
was clear like I'm not going to take
credit for it it was clearly just
something about those two strains which
just really clicked yeah like it's it's
not it's not me I'm not taking credit
these two lines were just meant to cross
together because I did a 40 female hunt
of these seeds and I found like eight
Keepers I was so surprised and I was
like man I've got to whittle these down
to just like two or something yeah and
for the life of me I ended up just sort
of being like you know what these these
plants are different and they really do
stand on their own feet so that's been
really cool recently to be really trying
actively to disseminate those clones out
into Australia yeah and a lot of people
come back to me and say dude this is the
first thing I grow where I feel like
it's on par with Cal California and
stuff in terms of like just it's just
the genetics it's not like me it's like
just that's how it happens sometimes
where like that zipper lines up
perfectly and everything just matches
it's just how it works it's great yeah
totally so I used that strain which I
call dog jelly
um and I cross that and I use that as
the initial mail stock to then start
doing the back cross onto the jelly
breath so I then did the bx1 and that
was great it came out very potent it
fixed up a number of the issues that I
had with my jelly breath clone which was
like all Cookie strains it's a little
less urine than you'd like and um a
little more prone to mold than you might
like because you know those little golf
ball dense nugs anyway
yeah so it fixed up that and um as a
result I'm now just about finished I
don't know if you can see it that's my
little tent there I uh I have a bunch of
seeded plants in there it's just the
little tent for seeded pollinations and
um yeah I got the bx2s being they're in
the oven you know the plants are seated
they're just developing so that's sort
of largely what I'm doing at the moment
and I think it's interesting because
it's a pretty stable seed line as far as
like a high quality cookies sort of
offering because in the past when I had
bought cookies hybrids admittedly
probably from some less than reputable
breeders
um I just they're all all over the place
you know I could never get like a
cookies type plan until I had this jelly
breath really so that's sort of what I'm
doing at the moment but the next cycle I
do because I'm about to head over to the
states come hang out with y'all yeah and
um when I get back I want to do a big
sativa hunt that's where my pumpkin lies
so Keen to do some sativa work and um
one of the strains I'm going to be
chucking in there not super sativa but
um I've got a pack of
Matt riots foreplay oh wow oh wow dude
that so not many people got those that
was the um the the Fairfax four-way cut
by the elite guys that is a special
[ __ ] clone dude like I only got to
see it expressed really well once
because it it definitely had some kind
of something but
um we never saw it past any progeny and
those things that was a skunky plant
dude uh hempaling those guys are right
that is a very special plant that's cool
Yeah man so I'm excited to do that when
I get back get some um some fun stuff in
the um in the ring but but other than
that I think I think Australian stands
doing really well we're growing there's
a number of cool breeders popping their
heads up
um I I wouldn't want to do any Miss
justice but like some of them that jump
to mind immediately are like you know
we've already mentioned Wally duck who's
like you know a bit of a an older legend
of the scene but there's some new cool
upcoming guys I'd say check out like my
buddy Farrell who I mentioned earlier
who does like that land race Thai versus
modern stuff like a cool sort of clash
of the worlds
um another guy who sees I've got
recently uh stinky Jones he's done some
cool work another guy bootleg and then
another guy
um finally who I'd give a shout out to
is local bird seed gotta love that name
I love that name
but yeah so there are some cool
Australian dudes if you're interested in
just sort of seeing what's going on in
Australia I highly recommend you check
some of those guys out oh another guy uh
called uh easty's treats
um again I don't want to miss anyone out
I'm sorry if I don't do it yeah it's
hard because like you don't miss anyone
and but yeah no I think it's awesome you
get some names out there if you can
but yeah there's cool stuff going down
in Australia and um I think yeah largely
speaking you'll see me working the
raspberry and the jelly breath stuff but
the one cool little thing I can tell you
guys about is where my buddy Farrell
messaged me and said hey you know I got
this S1 you've got to come see it he
also said
what do you think the chances are that
you had pollen contamination and I said
I I don't think so the tent was on its
own you know blah blah and he said I
found a male in the s1s and I was like
okay I've heard of this but like
probably more likely pollen
contamination than because I think Sam
said you get like three and a thousand
or something like it depends on how the
genetics line up but yeah it's it's
usually very small yeah so in the back
of my mind I'm like it could be that but
it could probably more likely pollen
contamination anyway so I've got this
male raspberry mama and so we thought
the first thing to do is try to flower
it like let's just see and um this thing
like you you can't make it flour unless
you fully put it into flour like I put
it in the tiniest pot I could I made it
root bound I put it under 24 hours of
light I tried my last try to stress
induce flour yeah it would not budge
it's the only plan I have that like
basically won't even show you it's a
male in veg yeah yeah that's a good
thing for a male because males usually
just flour at the first sign of root
restriction
I mean to me
um you know you guys there are males
that appear in in reversals yeah um the
way to really know is like if you used
any pollen from that mail on anything
um and you remember up the seeds uh if
it was a regular if it was regular
pollen then you'd get anywhere from 20
to 80 percent male female ratio and if
it's you know feminized then you'd only
get female seeds or it wouldn't even
take I mean it might not even be volunt
I'm not 100 sure that's really accurate
because we don't understand the whole
sexual chromosome nature like the uh I
don't even remember the proper term I'm
gonna make myself sound stupid but we
don't understand
um the whole the whole nature of not
just the sex chromosomes but the what is
it autosomes that that aren't related to
sex chromosomes a lot of those are
something is having an effect on the sex
chromosomes aside from just the natural
genetics X chromosomes so I'm not sure
if that really plays out that way I
think what we found out most is that
when there are males and feminized stock
they tend to be males or females only
expressing male for whatever reason
but wow yeah I hadn't I hadn't actually
thought about that I thought yeah that's
great so so they should test female when
you test yeah so what my plan initially
is I'm thinking well I've done the
reversal with like the The Proven female
that we really like so I was like why
don't I just try to make the regular
versions of those Femme crosses and and
if this thing is in fact you know a male
or a female show like I should get some
similarities between those two seeds
right see the parents in there right
yeah or I thought alternatively I could
try to do F2 S2 F2
so that would be yeah that'd be
interesting oh yeah so just crossed that
mail to keep the thing now and just see
what it so yeah it's going to be
interesting to dive down this rabbit
hole because it starts to get a bit
confusing with the um the lineage but it
should be interesting and I'm sort of
keen to see where it goes you know DJ
shorts the king of playing with weird
lineages like Crossing making F1 like
technically what would be f1s within the
same line each gender successor
generation without ever like breeding
for this specific path or that specific
it's interesting I think it's
fascinating and it made some of like my
favorite stuff regardless if it was like
considered uh
technical or correct it ended up making
some really fascinating stuff that I
have no end inside of ever stopping
working with
yeah yeah DJ's stuff is is killer and
he's he's definitely done more wild
stuff than any of us which is cool yeah
um so what like if people wanted to get
the Australian guy stuff where would
they go like online where is there a
place they can get this stuff yeah good
question
um probably about half of those guys I
mentioned uh I stocked at maybe like
Little Australian seed banks so that
might be one Avenue to go down my my
work is stocked at a seed bank in
Australia called top shelf seed bank I
know that feral is also stopped there
and some of those other guys might pop
up on there but I would always encourage
you
um if you were interested drop drop the
guy directly a message Australia you
know these these guys aren't big
breeders they're going to be very stoked
that you're interested in maybe learning
a little bit about what they're doing
and um I think they would be very
receptive to anyone who dropped him a
line and said hey I'm in the states and
uh maybe I could try some of your seeds
um yeah I think they would be receptive
to that so by all means listen to the
names I mentioned
um and and just type them into Instagram
or or just like go to my
um Instagram and look at who I follow
and they'll they'll be in there and um
yeah drop them a line for sure because
as I mentioned earlier if nothing else
you probably have a little bit of a
better chance of finding something that
just feels a little bit different
because we just don't have access to all
of those clones and so things inherently
have to be a little different and um
I love it I love I loved it that you
that like I've I've pretty much thought
about just dropping every single clone
from here on out and only working with
what I've made out of seed from here on
out
um I've lost a lot of that love for
finding other people's Keepers or
messing with other things people other
people call Keepers and really really
just looking at what's out there in seed
and just trying to enjoy that some more
because as Americans we it's really easy
to get trapped in the Clone on the game
and constantly chasing that next clone
only and that and when you don't have
when you when you have a constant access
to stuff like that
it it's it's easy to fall into it
permanently and I've kind of tried to
push myself out of that when I when I
lost my whole collection
um I I was bummed man that was that was
a long time of collecting and it and it
pushed me into uncomfortable zone of
having to pop seeds and it made me find
that love and all that again so I kind
of Envy a little bit some of that out
there in Australia that that they they
still have that love for C at night I'm
glad I get to find that again you know
I think it goes in phases you know uh to
what heavy days was talking about
earlier when people were like breeding
for what they like
um I think it's we've had a massive
explosion of American breeding going on
but a lot of it has been profit-based
and so it's been crossing a lot of the
same 30 to 60 Cuts in innumerable ways
right and you know if you don't care to
sell seed and you're just doing it for
yourself and your friends you can
literally pick any weird thing you want
and go in any direction you want you're
not limited by anything in that regard a
lot of times people are like I want this
drop to sell well therefore I'm going to
use things that have name recognition
and I'm going to walk down this path
that's been walked before you know yeah
um but if you don't care about that then
the world is your oyster and there's a
lot of weird [ __ ] out there that you
there's a lot of directions you can go
um if you know and sometimes you know
maybe you change the game who knows you
know uh it it it uh you know things
aren't new and you know it's like it's
just like new genres of music right it's
not Popular until it is
right
yeah hugely and and I can hugely relate
to everything you just said because if
if someone said to me like right now
do you think you could base a whole
breeding program off something you found
in a pack of Kenneth seeds I'd say [ __ ]
no yeah you know what I mean so it was
the fact that I wasn't thinking about
that which allowed me to try something
that I just thought is a bit weird and
different and then all of a sudden you
find something really cool in there and
I I try to encourage people to do that
I'm like grow what interests you because
you never know what'll jump out and it
could be as you just alluded to the
start of something which goes on to be
changes the whole scene
I mean in the worst case scenario if you
do a bunch of breeding and doesn't make
any money and a lot of people don't like
it as long as you can fall back on I
like it yeah right
you know I like it I like all this
matters
right it's so valuable to just have said
you know I went through the process of
selecting it making the seeds testing
them and then having the foresight to
say you know what maybe this is a dead
end but at least I got experience out of
it you know what I mean it's interesting
and being able to say the things that
did end is a valuable tool too that is a
valuable tool I mean everybody should do
everybody should realize that most
breeding is failure yeah but I don't
think that's a comment I don't think
that's common sense to most people
though
um at least into seed making because
seed making failure isn't making money
and most of it's about making money so
if they're seeds you can sell them as
long as you can Market them so it's not
I mean never any sense as you think
Neville used to have this joke right
that everything he did with the haze
passed F1 he made it worse yeah yeah you
know he was never able to make it better
like the nl5 hazes and the first crosses
that they made and did those were all
better than all the later stuff in his
opinion even though he tried really hard
you know so sometimes and there's luck
in it you know you could find you could
not find it in a ton of seeds or you
could find it in the first 10 or 15 you
pop yeah
hugely hugely and it's um it's
interesting you say that because I I try
to encourage people to also not
um buy into any paradigms about having
to pop any certain number of seeds like
of course the more you pop the more you
likely but I talk to people who
don't pop seeds because they're like
well I can't pop 40. so what's the point
exactly yeah and I'd just say most of my
favorite like my the jelly breath I I
reference right I try to I try to make
this clear that jelly breath I I you
know you could say it's biased but I
genuinely believe it's the best cutting
in Australia and I will be fully upfront
in saying that I got those as three
feminized freebie seeds that's cool you
know what I mean it's like the the best
[ __ ] can come from who knows where and
it could be one or two yeah the Mendo
perps right that was like two seeds
right
two yeah yeah literally two and uh one
of them was a male so it's the lowest
possible Fino hunt you could ever have
you know when is that girl one of the
best blueberries I had found in all of
the years of searching for blueberry was
a freaking freebie from dynafin
blueberry hash plant like of all the odd
things out there that you think you you
know it had some of the best blueberry
smells up until you know the Bonnet
during that run so yeah it could come
from anywhere it's so crazy you just
mentioned that because one of the
earliest strains I grew that was
impressive was a dynafem strain we call
it was called Blue strawberry I think
whatever the blue component like maybe
the blueberry was the pollen donor part
in this one as well because I
specifically remembered oh blue
strawberries world of seeds
uh it mustn't have been blue strawberry
then it was definitely dynafin but maybe
they did maybe they made a couple of
hybrids with them pollen but yeah but I
also remembered like looking back I'm
like man how did dinosaur produce that
like it was pretty good so the Spanish
breeders what I've learned like knowing
some of them they're [ __ ] good like
that like my buddy um
Ernesto from from Buddha seeds he was
one of the first doing making a lot of
seeds for a greenhouse and Nirvana doing
the big massive productions for these
major Dutch companies but in the
meantime he was also doing Auto flower
breeding and moving Pakistani to trolley
into an Autoflower Forum into like a
reliably true breeding autoflowering
magenta plant and he did it and I got to
watch him you know go through this
process and they have some serious good
breeders over there and and I think it's
very easy to dismiss it because what
they sell isn't necessarily what ends up
in the packages of greenhouse meaning if
they're selling in Neville's Haze to
Greenhouse it doesn't mean Greenhouse is
going to stop get his Neville's Haze it
just means that they bought it and
they're going to put it in one of the
most likely one of those sativa packages
that best that best fits it you know
that's how it goes so when people know
that they make this stuff they might not
understand that it's being
misrepresented what's being made but
they have some fascinating or fantastic
breeders out there fantastic breeders in
the Spanish that are heavily under for
what they for sure
yeah man I I it's interesting how like
the real heads in the Spanish scene are
not particularly well known in the USA
scene and I think like not at all yeah
and and some of the Clones like um
what's that that one um the queen mother
oh yeah yeah Reina Madre yeah yeah yeah
like like there's a whole bunch of
clones that are just absolutely prolific
over there and people who are like in
both USA they're like oh yeah that's a
good clone it's it's not just like the
Spanish think it's good but it's not
yeah and and I think there's another one
called Lily
I'm not familiar with that one but yeah
okay yeah I think it's from that same
crew it uses that zamo slash Queen
Mother stuff anyway yeah um yeah really
interesting stuff for sure it'd be Keen
to get in there and the more I hear
about La Mano Negros work the more I'm
like damn I wish we had more clear info
about his life
he was an excellent breeder but he did
inject a lot of Dutch [ __ ] into his
stuff and left that out and that's why
it's so pretty because it is very
dutified and he did not keep that very
clear he was a good Storyteller and he
made some amazing stuff but for a
preservationist you wouldn't I think a
lot of the people that were around him
that liked him a lot were were more
saddened to find out that it was very
injected with Dutch stuff and left out
for someone who was such a serious
preservationist but he did make some
amazing stuff for sure I mean it it goes
to to your previous point in which you
were sort of happy that uh clones from
America weren't making their way to
Australia because you were avoiding the
whole viroid and you know super mites
and all the various uh things that we
struggle with but to the Spain Point
um you know International borders and
customs and oceans are a real barrier uh
no they're not genetics Spain is murder
like Spain Amsterdam all of them have
been murdered by the hlb now all of them
they've been taken out
so right well not any there's no good
barrier there that's all I've been
hearing about lately is the Spanish but
I just mentioned in a sense I I actually
meant more in the sense of like you know
in America like we don't get very we
don't it's not like you get Spanish
strength oh no no you're right it's not
like you're getting you know like like
things that he was just talking about
that might be very famous in Spain and
amazing Cuts you know um it took you
know there's a couple of the Neville's
uh not Neville's Hayes but like a couple
of Neville's f1s that have made their
way to America now but it took like 30
years
and most of them aren't over here you
know and so Australia Spain Europe
America even Canada which like America
and Canada share a border there's
there's that border and you know is a
real barrier to free exchange of
genetics and there's really good things
in Canada that don't really exist in
America and vice versa because of that
barrier I'm not so sure they don't make
it over here I'm not so sure that it's
that they don't pick up because they're
not popular strains because we've had a
lot of the the Dutch stuff even the
quays was over here I had it but I was
too stupid to keep it you know like
stuff makes it over but because it's not
popular it doesn't necessarily spread to
a lot of those Spanish strains have
weird name like the critical Bilbo like
over here that would sound like critical
dildo like No One's Gonna grow critical
dildo over here right so I mean some of
it is an Aiming convention for sure
um
but yeah it is it is kind of crazy that
there isn't more exchange between the
countries even with tissue culture being
more prevalent and stuff that we're not
seeing more of an exchange I don't know
I don't know what that is other than
naming conventions
and you know what that Segways nicely
into like something I wanted to ask you
guys which is that there's I mean not
not just now but in recent years there's
been quite a focal discussion around
um the nomenclature or cannabis and like
how we really need to get with the times
but there's a part of me that thinks
that may never actually change because
it's just so widely disseminated the
current language I'd love to hear you
guys thoughts like do you think we'll
ever have a global reset or do you think
it'll just continue on and the squeaky
wheel will keep letting us know we're
doing it wrong and that sort of vibe
I it could change over time I mean I do
think that you know like for instance
like how in cannabis we use BX
uh and it's not ever used outside of
cannabis it's always BC back cross right
um but I don't know even though it might
like scientists and stuff might look at
it and laugh at us
we're still conv we're still using that
word BX to convey the right information
like people understand what the word
means you know and so some of that is
you know I mean I guess like you know uh
you know they they misnamed and you know
Indica should be afghanika and uh and
you know sativa should be Indica because
it comes from India and sativa should
really be rude you know ruderalis should
really you know all that I don't think
that'll ever catch on no I think it's I
think sativa Indica is too ingrained in
in the in in our subculture
um and I don't think it'll I don't think
that'll shift even people that are anal
about it like me still use Indica sativa
so I I think you know and then there's
also this thing where you look at some
you look at some stupid seat seed bank
or whatever and it's like oh this is 72
indica and 18 sativa and you're like all
that's made up yeah I have no idea you
know like whatsoever so like it it is it
is misleading in a sense because I I
definitely think percentages they mostly
just pull out of their ass
for sure yeah hugely hugely and I
definitely have noticed a lot of
breeders these days just list everything
as 60 40 Indica dominant that's a way
man and you know the confusion the
confusion around phenotype versus
genotype
um you know some of that kind of kind of
stuff is you know that probably should
change over time
um you know I think uh be pretty well
established it we got it right
um on the last episode I did with uh the
PHD lady I was like hey you know what
like I want to know am I am I using this
word correctly because I'm not a
scientist I'm not a botanist by trade
you know like phenotype like as I
learned it genotype are the genes behind
the expressible traits right what you're
visually seeing are the phenotype the
visual traits that are expressed this is
the phenotype the genotype are the genes
behind it you're not you know so I think
we're using it correctly according to
her anyways I hope so folks I hate being
wrong but yeah I mean I guess my general
point is that like we uh but you know
that that's what cannabis does right
like we take we take these like real
world terms and then we like
create our own use with them and it's
like what made you know legalization so
hard in some ways is like in Colorado
when it first went legal they went in
and took all these suggestive children
names and candy names and trademark
names off the cookies as cookies because
the Girl Scouts sued them yeah yeah
right
um you know and and so we had all this
Counter Culture tongue-in-cheek funny
names that played off things that people
knew I don't see any reason why that's
not going to continue to some degree in
science I mean we're a pretty subversive
group
um and our opinion is you should bend
towards us yeah yeah
I think it like I I totally agree with
what you're saying and I think it speaks
to the point of that
um the purpose of language is not
necessarily to be a hundred percent
technically correct but to facilitate an
exchange of ideas where we both know
we're talking about the same thing and
that's what you're alluding to it's like
we say sativa because we both know that
we are thinking of the same thing when
we say sativa and I think that's almost
in a sense the manifestation of language
evolving in front of your eyes it's like
maybe it's not technically correct but
we know what we're saying to each other
and that's almost more important to
facilitate ideas being exchanged but you
know I almost wondered with the the
continuation of the sativa Indica thing
though if it really takes away from the
effect of the high because I think
that's where it genuinely confuses
people when they go into collectives and
they say I would like a sativa because I
know because this the I'm Jim Belushi
show it told me that sativas give me
energy and I need to go work in the
garden and that's where you run into to
the problems because just because maybe
it is a narrow leaf type plant doesn't
necessarily mean it's going to have a
specific type high so maybe maybe that's
where the education needs to be not in a
new whole new terminology but in in
explaining High types and that's because
sativa Indica traits don't necessarily
mean high-type
I don't necessarily know if that is
gonna be it because I think now that
consumerism and legality is involved
what you see like in in food and stuff
like that is people will use like the
word natural
like if things don't have a specific
legal meaning but they convey an idea or
an image then marketers are going to use
them to their advantage sure yeah right
so you can't say for instance in America
this is a hundred percent organic unless
it's actually 100 organic because
there's like a federal Rule and you have
to but you can say it's all natural yeah
right and so I think that's the naming
thing that's going to go on unless
there's some rule against it people are
going to call [ __ ] whatever they think
makes them money
it's why I like to to some degree it's
why almost all these strains are candy
and dessert names now yeah right nobody
would name a strain in 2022 the dog [ __ ]
they would very unlikely name it you
know Candy Apple something right yeah or
strawberry or strawberry switch you know
whatever yeah they would they would
evoke some image it wouldn't be cat piss
it wouldn't be dog [ __ ] it wouldn't be
it you know so
um you know it uh indicate sativa that's
as long as these as long as these
perceptions persist about what the
effect is going to be
some of these companies they would name
you know they would names weed strains
emotion
yeah you know like relaxation calm you
know I think you just gave everyone more
ideas God damn it but you know that's
that's what happens right like that's
what it's there's there's a capitalism
part of it
um and we us weed nerds can argue about
it sure you know and then Berner is
going to be out there being like you
don't want to smoke some relaxation
yeah all right because you know it's
what sells
that is
that's interesting can I actually make a
really random comment I think you guys
will be interested in talking about it
but I wanted to push myself to express
at least one personal opinion that I've
never expressed before because I was
thinking about a whole diplomatic thing
before the show and I was like yeah I
shouldn't be Diplomat I should say
something
anyway it ties into what you were just
saying like about like what we can say
and what we can't say and sort of
Industry versus standard but basically
in Australia like I I work in um like
generally speaking the healthcare
profession and I used to work in
Pharmacy and I experienced it there and
I experienced it now where I currently
work and what I would really love to do
is encourage people to be what I would
call academically honest about cannabis
and its effect on people because I speak
to a lot of people in the healthcare
industry who are not particularly
interested in hearing about the benefits
of cannabis because for a long time
they've heard people quote incorrect
things like Mantra and like the real
specific one that I sort of have a bit
of a pet peeve with is that cannabis
doesn't kill people yeah yeah the thing
that I would say is
first of all I I have a family member
who has um bipolar and when he has
cannabis he goes Manic and becomes very
unwell sure and so I think we need to be
honest with ourselves and acknowledge
that cannabis actually maybe isn't for
everyone and that's okay because I think
that the people I speak to they take his
shoe that they're told you know it's
it's better than anything it doesn't
kill anyone blah blah blah and I think
there's stronger arguments we could use
it's it's not dishonest to say cannabis
causes less damage both health-wise and
societally than any other drug that's a
very strong argument and it's a hundred
percent correct however my my buddy is a
doctor and he has literally seen people
die from getting high and walking in
front of a car accidentally and getting
hit by sure he's seen people who present
who have only smoked green their whole
life and they have emphysema sure and so
you have to be honest with yourselves
that like there are trade-offs I still
think it's the best choice by far don't
get me wrong I'm I'm sitting here heavy
smoker myself but I just think that we
just need to be a little more mindful
about whether we're like a bit whether
the claims we're making are 100 genuine
and as I said I think they're a really
strong arguments to make that are true
saying it's you know it's less hard yeah
really but I think that we just need to
get out of this space of like it causes
zero harm because the reality is any
smoke in your lungs long term will cause
damage it's just that simple yeah and um
I think a lot of people think well it's
better than tobacco and I'd say 100 150
better than tobacco but that's not the
conversation the conversation is that a
lot of people say cannabis has zero
negative effects and I just think yeah
it would be cool if we could all be a
little more honest with ourselves about
like it's not perfect but it's far
better than the other things no question
but um that's my little edgy point that
I wanted to get out there because I do
unfortunately see the negative impact of
those statements that you get these old
school you know doctors who are like
well I don't really listen to what the
community says because they they say it
doesn't cause harm and I can tell you
clearly yeah yeah and so I did want to
get that out there that we can still do
a great job advocating for cannabis and
promoting how it's better than some of
the other alternative recreational
sources of relaxation however I just
think we have to be a little more honest
and recognize that it does have some
health effects it's not necessarily for
everyone but it is far better than
alcohol or tobacco or any of the harder
ones you know and I just think being
mindful of the language we use will
probably help that longer term to get
some of the more professional white
collared people to listen to us because
the reality is we know for a fact that
the underground Community was ahead of
the medical community yeah the way CBD
has helped people clearly shows that the
medical community was wrong they were
like not no benefit and then like for
epilepsy Clear Proof undeniable it's
beneficial so I think we want to try to
maintain that moral High ground and not
seed it by making this sort of
Ambiguously incorrect statements and say
look there's value we've got we've got
proof of it
um but you know there are pros and cons
like anything sure I I I I love that
I think it's probably a reaction at
least in America but probably elsewhere
too to where it was so demonized by
society and the government that you felt
that like talking about it in a nuanced
way
any anything you admitted would be used
as a club to beat you over keeping it
right where they wanted it to be which
was totally illegal and as dangerous and
in America it's schedule one so it's
right up there with you know
um you know the worst drugs
methamphetamine it's not even it's worse
than Coke they use cocaine in uh in nose
surgeries so cocaine is actually
scheduled two in in America because it
has legitimate medical uses right uh and
uh not that I'm advocating for that but
by any means but I mean you know there's
an aspect there where
um it hasn't really been properly
studied
for a long time
um and you know when they did study it
they were looking for harm
right and so I think we're kind of in
the infancy of balancing out cannabis uh
one thing you didn't mention you know I
actually don't think that like you know
Canada I don't think cannabis has ever
killed anyone although I do think that
you're probably right cannabis has has
made people do stupid things and they
died while high that's probably true
right um but I have one of my really
close friends has cannabis hypermissive
syndrome right where he gets the
vomiting and he's had to quit cannabis
um and it's it's pretty rare you know
but it does exist and everyone thinks
it's name or this or that or whatever
but he grows his own
um and he had to give it up and you know
it's kind of like shellfish is amazing
for most people but some people die
peanut butter is amazing for most people
but some people no not not so much you
know people have allergies people have
different physical makeups and different
genes
um that react to certain things and so I
agree with you I think it's mostly
beneficial
but there's it's rare in in the world
that everything is a perfect good or a
perfect bad yeah I mean anything
carcinogenic is going to kill someone I
mean if you smoke it it's going to kill
you not necessarily it being cannabis
being the the thing killing you but the
carcinogenic factor from smoking
cannabis is probably what's really
pepper is supposed to be slightly uh
carcinogenic but I'm not sure yeah but
I'm not sure it says carcinogenic is
burning up uh you know flour or
something like that but the one thing
I'll say about that is that I don't know
about the carcinogenic aspect of weed
simply because we know that tens of
millions of Americans have smoked it
every day and plenty of other countries
right and in America we lose like half a
million people a year to Tobacco illness
and they haven't been able to pin cancer
on cannabis despite trying extremely
hard
um and so I think that one is still up
for debate
um I agree it has a lot of tar I agree
it has a lot of carcinogens uh in it
yeah
but you know you would think that if
tens of millions of Americans have
smoked it daily for years that you would
have a lot of them would get sick and
die
and we haven't seen that yet so I think
it remains to be seen
because it isn't necessarily a proven
correlation doesn't mean it hasn't been
seen oh I agree you know and I also
think I'll throw this out there to to go
on to heavy dazes Point
um I think that smoking flour itself out
of the traditional ways and bongs or
bowls or joints or whatever has been
well studied for a long time
um and I think that it's generally
pretty safe I don't know if all of the
modern dab and extracts and all these
other Goos that people are smoking all
the time I don't know if those are going
to end up being as safe
um and I think that you know people are
saying oh it's cannabis so it's all safe
right but we also haven't had years and
years and years of people using it yet
to see what the effects might be later
on I think this is a great example three
different eras right here of of the
modern era the mid-era and the old era
of like I mean different pushbacks to
use a perfect example I remember when
all my I'm not that into hash but I
remember when a lot of my friends would
smoke their Dabs out of glowing Cherry
bangers yeah we now know if you're
smoking hash at 800 and 900 Degrees it's
creating cyanide it's creating various
carcinogens it's really unhealthy and no
one does that anymore because that [ __ ]
is [ __ ] yeah but yet yeah
but everyone I knew back then was like
heating a torch until that thing was
glowing red and then dropping goo in it
and taking big hits and coughing until
they couldn't breathe
it's probably not the best
yeah no look I'm so I'm so stoked you
guys brought those points out because I
think I could probably add a few little
tidbits of info so in terms of when
you're smoking green plant matter like
there's no tobacco in there they've
actually shown that across the board
most plant matter when you combust it it
turns into this molecule called 44 by
pyridine which is basically a relatively
benign molecule and this is why cannabis
doesn't appear to increase your rate of
cancer per se because the molecules it
turns into is pretty benign
um what's interesting is when you smoke
cannabis as you mentioned it produces
more tar than the equivalent volume of
tobacco so that one gram of cannabis
actually makes more tar the difference
is is that when you smoke cannabis in
your throat you have this thing called
the mucousillery elevator it's basically
like the little hairs that brush the
dust up out of your lungs and stops your
lungs from getting filled with Gunk and
what happens is when you smell my
cannabis that become those hairs they
become paralyzed but after a few hours
they start back up and you can clear
that tar out so it's not actually a big
deal even though people do like to point
out that cannabis produces more tar your
body can get rid of it it sweeps it up
you don't recognize it goes down your
esophagus and you just swallow it and it
comes out the other end what's
interesting though is with tobacco it
actually kills those hairs and the hairs
take at least two weeks to grow back so
as a result unless you abstain from
smoking tobacco for two weeks that tar
will accumulate in your lungs and even
though it's less than cannabis your body
can't get rid of it so that's an
interesting sort of thing to keep in
your stash because people love to [ __ ]
on cannabis and say there's more tar and
it's like yeah a bit sort of not
actually an issue interestingly when we
look at
the carcinogen aspect of cannabis that
you're right there's no proven
carcinogen like it's it's not going to
give you lung cancer per se but what is
interesting is that when you inhale any
smoke it essentially causes the
breakdown of the alveoli which long term
is what we would call emphysema and
emphysema long term will turn into
chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
COPD
so the way I try to explain it to people
is you might think of um being exposed
to Asbestos and you and you could say
well it's not actually the asbestos that
kills you asbestos causes mesothelioma
and it is the mesothelioma that kills
you and so I actually view it the same
way with cannabis cannabis doesn't kill
you but it causes COPD and COPD will
kill you so I think it's just about like
sort of keeping it in perspective sort
of because a lot of people yeah it's
it's hard to understand that it can kill
you but I because I myself used to say
well I've never met anyone who smoked
pure green their whole life so it's sort
of hard to know because most people have
smoked a decent amount of tobacco so
it's just like it's just muddled and
it's like well how do you know by the
correlation thing because yeah yeah but
but I have bumped into a few British
guys who reckon they've just smoked
green their whole life and and they do
have emphysema so so it is interesting
but but like I guess on this point I
I've cut my usage back so that I tend to
just consume in the evening and I think
this has actually been really beneficial
for just my own personal health maybe
this is a very specific thing to me but
but I feel like
um you know not having brekki bongs so
to speak for me personally has been
quite beneficial and I feel like my
respiratory
um capacity essentially has been better
for that and I would just encourage
people to to just be mindful of this in
the long term because you know
unfortunately COPD is a bit of a rough
one and um you know it would be it'd be
better to avoid it if possible but it is
interesting yeah the 4-4 by pyridine
thing I'd encourage people to look into
it it's pretty benign
um and and yeah overall clearly smoking
weed is way better than tobacco right
like there's just no question about it
is it the Nicki or tobacco that's
causing the um the stuff in your lungs
to freeze we don't know yet probably
because it has its Vapes are so young
nicotine and tobacco are always mixed in
the same thing right yeah I mean yes I
saw this big study and I can't say what
it is right now I apologize but I did
see this thing where it was like they
studied a huge amount of non-smokers
weed smokers only weed and tobacco and
just tobacco and the highest rate of
lung cancer was tobacco followed by weed
and tobacco but then strangely the
control group the normal lung cancer was
third and the people that had the least
amount of lung cancer were the people
that smoked cannabis only
yeah um but as heavy days says you know
just because it protects you from one
thing doesn't mean it doesn't increase
your risk for something else to come
along and harm you
um you know uh and so a lot of times we
oversimplify things by being like see it
prevents this so it's all good I've seen
that it causes this so it's so it's all
bad I've seen that with CBD in the USA
it's it's a literal snake oil show here
with CBD literally it is being sold in
every gas station now like in at least
in my area every gas station carries
some sort of CBD Contraption or uh CBD
flower even they sell everywhere you
know and it's being sold like if you
talk to like you know my chicks parents
or whoever they really have this idea
that CBD cures everything every last
thing there's this weird thing that we
won't know for probably decades but like
since you're in the in the medical
profession maybe some you know people
are going to push it along but you know
these guys in Israel we legitimate
definitely have a cannabinoid system
right
um in our body and CBD and THC interacts
with that cannabinoid system and it's
pretty unstudied and we don't exactly
know
um what how you know what it affects you
know it's it's one of the body systems
that I think is the most poorly
understood because they only discovered
it in the late 80s early 90s and they
don't know how cannabis and CBD
interacts with your you know your
cannabinoid system or even what your
cannabinoid system totally does in
relationship to the rest of your body
um so I think people uh forget that you
know we know a lot
but that you know we only figured out
what bacteria was like 130 years ago or
something and we still have a vast
amount of of things to learn and we're
going to be surprised
you know yeah when I was when I was a
kid heavy days
um they they told everyone that that
margarine was clearly Superior to butter
now they have a much different opinion
of trans fatty acids you know
um you know people have things change
new evidence comes in and it changes
people's perspectives so you know I
don't know where it's gonna lead but I
do think it's it's being studied now
more than in any time in our history so
I would imagine over the next 20 or 30
years will probably be a golden era of
discovering how cannabis interacts with
human beings
yeah hugely hugely and I I totally agree
with you I am 100 on the fence and
almost anticipating the worst with these
long-term bait studies coming out
because I I agree we totally do not it
like I'll be honest I switched from
bongs to Vapes like a bit over two years
ago thinking I was you know doing it for
my health and as time goes by I'm like
man am I about to like get cancer and
they find out like oh it turns out
vaping's like Wayward like you know what
I mean like something really concerning
but just to add one little extra little
study Tibet in there they they did a
different study where they tried to
assess the lung function of um just pure
cannabis smokers and what they basically
found was if you look at lung function
we tend to use these two measures one's
called fev1 which stands for how quickly
can you push all the air out of your
lungs so forced expiratory volume yeah
and we tend to look at it over one
second so how much can you push out in
one second and then the other one is how
much can you hold in total which is your
Force by model capacity basically what
they found was is that the people who
had like older and had smoked cannabis
their whole lives they had slightly
smaller overall capacity which meant
like there was some degree of emphysema
there but they actually had a better
fev-1 which is sort of the more one
you're interested in actually because
what they basically found was a lifetime
of ripping bongs actually strengthens
your lungs that's [ __ ] hilarious I'm
not even kidding and like they were
basically like they found it a lifetime
of ripping cones gave you the same
benefits as someone who was like a diver
their whole life who worked at holding
their breath and like there's real
benefits associated with it and they
basically were like yeah like a little
bit less total volume but like your use
of the space is superior to someone who
hasn't smoked that's might be my
favorite part of the whole interview uh
that I've been I've been training my
whole life just dedicated
I I smoke you know bongs or what that's
my primary delivery system
it's the one I find the most convenient
mm-hmm yeah I see the shape the shapes
of his bunks are very phallic
they tend to be that way they do they
tend to be phallic you know they tend to
be a tube with a bass you know so so it
ergonomically fits in the mouth yeah
ergonomically just slides right in
you'll see it you'll see it when you
come when coming you have to know heavy
days that once every episode
Matt tries to get me to Break by
throwing out usually some kind of
phallic reference and tries to get me to
crack better arrests throw me off my
train of thought so he was running out
of time and he probably realized he
needed to get it in uh I love that I I'm
trying to be cognizant of the time
we could do I always remembered um when
I interviewed Bodhi he did something
very different and he was like I would
love to give people some um book
recommendations is there any chance I
might be able to do that do that let's
do it yeah yes please cool cool so I've
always thought if I could recommend a
few books to people like not necessarily
cannabis specific but just no just
things that are good reads
um so I think one of the most
influential books in my life
um is definitely one called the body
keeps the score by Bessel Van Der cook
it's a book largely speaking about
um people who have trauma and how you
can help them overcome that and I think
that it's very interesting because it
speaks about how a lot of psychological
problems manifest physically you hear
people talking about tents in the
shoulders and anyway it was a seminal
literature when it came out the body
keeps the score Bessel Vandercook very
good book
um likewise the 48 Laws of Power and the
50th law by Robert Greene absolute yeah
gotta check them out great books
um meditations by Marcus Aurelius you
know an absolute staple yeah please
consider that one I've recently really
gotten into rum Das and I like walking
each other home and becoming nobody uh
me and Bodie have had some really nice
chats about those books so I think you
would vibe those if you like that
um Oliver Sacks the man who mistook his
wife for a heart and Awakenings are two
very interesting books if you like
neurology and how things can go wrong I
do have that one now I was trying to
remember what that was yeah yeah
um and then uh the extreme ownership and
the dichotomy of leadership by Jocko
willink are both very good books if you
like that sort of accountability style
of things which I'm I'm pretty into
myself yeah and then finally uh my two
final ones not gonna hurt me by David
Goggins is possibly my favorite book
ever so check that out but likewise if
you want to learn a little bit about
Australian history I strongly recommend
you to check out a book called Dark emu
by Brooke Bruce Pasco I I doubt anyone
listening has heard of it it's a book
that largely speaking when people came
and colonized Australia they very much
whitewashed the Aboriginal history and
said that they were a very primitive
people and violent and blah blah blah
and this book really outlines how in
many aspects of their society they were
far more advanced than us and so I'd
highly recommend check out dark emu by
Bruce Pascoe it's amazing how that
happened to the Native American culture
here over there just to any native
culture that were you know terrorized by
European
kids I generally think as far as humans
go to be fair uh any group that comes in
that's that's uh more technical
technologically advanced especially with
weapons
um that tends to be bad for the local
population
um you know uh the uh the Mongols
weren't European but you sure probably
didn't want them showing up to your city
you know
um and you know Europeans we get we get
a we get a wrap because we colonized
everywhere and it's a lot more recent
and it's very well documented
um but it's certainly it's a human
failing unfortunately where uh lots of
cultures I mean they used the first
thing they used to do when they took
over a culture was burn the libraries
and burn the knowledge
you know um and so you know there's uh
there's aspects to that
you know uh that uh that suck but it's
part of the human experience I think
nothing recommendations
I'm gonna throw out some book
recommendations uh do it uh that some of
the I'll start with some like some uh I
don't know necessarily they're not
weed-based necessarily but they they
they maybe inform your experience uh one
of them is called uh the NAT the the
natural mind right and it's a book by
Andrew Weil
and it's kind of a a study on why people
like to change their headspace why
people like Altered States Of
Consciousness how normal it is for
people to want to alter their
Consciousness and how many different
creative things come out of them putting
yourself in a different perspective
um and I'll just I'll move on but one of
the coolest things he says usually the
first time that people get high is these
like little kids spinning around in
circles until they get so dizzy they
can't stand up and they fall over
and that's usually the first change in
Consciousness that people actually
experience and it's almost Universal
right
um so he got really famous for like
writing a bunch of self-help books and
stuff like that but
um that book came out in the 70s when he
was still a researcher uh you know and
and it's really interesting take on why
our mind likes having a change in
Consciousness right uh two would be uh
another book by Andrew Weil called from
Chocolate to Morphine
and it is a book it's probably a little
dated now but it is basically every drug
that affects humans
um and the most up-to-date knowledge
good and bad on what it does to you
without all the governmental politics
just like he's a you know Harvard
trained physician so he just looked at
it like well what is the medical say
about caffeine or chocolate or heroin or
marijuana or you know whatever it might
be and so if people want to read about
what things do to you without a bunch of
[ __ ] like we were discussing with
weed
um it's you know it's a little older now
but it's probably a pretty good start
uh getting on to the metaphysics side of
things like he was mentioning with ram
Das
um there's a book by the Dalai Lama that
really affected me uh that I read when I
was locked up which was the art of
happiness
and I don't think many people think
about
um happiness
and what happiness means in their own
lives right and what feeling good means
people chase all these things that their
parents want or their society wants or
what they think they want and they don't
think about like what kind of life or
what kind of mental state leads to
calmness and peace and happiness and
enjoying life right and so since we all
only know that we get this one shot
maybe maybe not maybe not you know we
might as well enjoy it while we're here
uh and the mind is a funny thing
um so books that help you explore your
mind and explore why your mind does what
it does is pretty cool
you know
um and then you know speaking to the
aboriginey side of things there's a book
by Howard Zinn that's kind of
controversial it's called a people's
History of the United States
um but it was basically written about
all the people you know mostly we write
about like powerful white people that
had all these big effects on the world
and they sort of take it from like a
native's perspective or a woman's
perspective or a black person's
perspective or an immigrant's
perspective like what was America like
for them
right
um and so just you know any book that
that gets you out of your comfort zone a
little bit or teaches you something
um about the world uh books are how we
pass knowledge down and so I'm a big fan
so it's super cool that you brought up
some of your favorites
and I'll show them yeah I'm gonna I'm
gonna download those to the out of
happiness and the people's History of
the United States I'm gonna get the
audiobook going I'm about to go for a
bike ride all right right yeah I'm gonna
go I'm gonna get the trauma one that you
mentioned too that sounds amazing yeah
it's a pretty interesting book
there's uh there's there's a lot of
knowledge out there and it's good so we
actually ran this thing about 50 minutes
longer than we almost ever do so for
that you are probably our longest chat
yeah uh which is pretty awesome
what a blessing thanks for having me
guys I really appreciate it am I able to
give a quick shout out or two yeah
please do yeah 100 and everything nail
it all out
um yeah
yeah I guess just off the top of my head
I would say like you know shout out to
anyone who's ever been on the show
um and you know everyone who's been on
the show has helped uh steer me in some
form or another and I'm very grateful
for that hopefully whether the steering
was positive or negative I've hopefully
come out a bit better the other side
um and a huge shout out to everyone in
the Australian scene who's trying hard
to help promote it I know that things
are still very fledgling and it's easy
to look at the states and to feel like
we're so far behind but I genuinely
believe there's a lot of people in
Australia who are both passionate and
are really putting their mind to it to
try to progress things along and that's
cool and furthermore
um you know like a shout out to all the
people who you know we stand on the
shoulder of giants you know to anyone
who's ever given me any work that I've
used for everyone who's just been a part
of the scene before me
um I certainly couldn't be here without
all of the knowledge from those who have
walked the path before us and so I try
to always be very grateful for that and
um my my final little thing would be um
if you're if you're interested in my
seeds you can you can check out seeds
here now
um we have a UK distributor simply
souvenirs who's about to have a drop
soon and if you're in Australia just
just drop me a message or check out top
shelf seed bank but um yeah super
grateful to have been invited on the
show guys it's it's an honor to be with
uh my contemporaries like yourself who I
view is such high regard uh we're happy
to have you dude I mean our audiences
are are pretty similar I think I think
it's people that are seeking like some
kind of path to history and cannabis so
there's no reason that we shouldn't be
working together and I'm glad we finally
spoke and like hashed our way through
shits that's the only way people grow so
I appreciate you for reaching out and
like you did that big Mia culpa but it
wasn't necessary because like it was
just as much me as it was you and I
genuinely feel that so thank you for for
coming and and being the bigger man and
actually emailing me and and reaching
out like that
uh look I had to make things right and
I'm very grateful that you're uh willing
to be open to my apology ah dude we're
gonna hang soon
my friend I'm gonna be in the states in
December guys um if you yeah drop me a
message I might be in an area near you
but um yeah excited yeah we appreciate
it very much we always we appreciate
anyone's listening's time anybody who
likes to nerd out on history and culture
related to weed
um you know we try to keep it
interesting and we try to cover
different topics at different times so
um yeah it's uh thank you all for your
time wonderful we we got not so back how
about that guys Cheers Cheers
[Music]
foreign