[Music]
hey what's up everyone just getting
ready for everything hold on
i should have put on the headphones
first
too late
hopefully it's not too bad
the subject for today is going to be uh
eric from hbk farms gonna come talk with
us there's one of my old friends and uh
he's been around forever he's made some
killer strains won some awards
done some cool [ __ ] so we're gonna bring
him on
what am i smoking on like uh professor p
sent me some stuff i've been smoking on
some blue power from a buddy lots of
good stuff lots of good stuff
all right hold on
here
see how we're doing on volume okay
yo
what's the haps amigo
how goes it
all right how's the connection there
yeah that seems like it's good so far
alden
oh we're good what is that good what is
that couch chair you're on it's a it's a
rocking chair oh lord you get to chill
while you're doing it i do a little bit
a little bit that's cool that's cool all
right waiting for hbk right now um so
for everyone just coming in we're going
to have on hbk farms he's an old friend
of mine
he's been in the scene forever won
awards at the emerald cup um when i
first met him he was making a killer
killer topical one of the best and and
he won many awards for his topicals as
well but one of the most one of the best
and most effective um cbd creams that
were at the time
i'm not sure if he still does it i know
he he put a pause on for a while but he
was winning awards and one of the
the earliest guys to be doing stuff like
that and really make effective cbd uh
crave
so we'll be bringing him on tonight
let's see if he's in here yet
hpk any hpk's in here there he is invite
there we
go
so he should be joining us in a second
he's still your pop pops lazy boy yeah
no doubt right it's pretty funny it's
okay what's up brother
hey what's going on guys good to see you
dude
good thank you sorry for the smoky
screen but my phone's kind of a piece of
crap it's all good as long as we can
hear you we're good so be sure to speak
up
okay
all right so um who is hvk farms and
where are you from brother
uh originally southern california i grew
up in san diego on the border east
county
um
yeah
campo area yeah and then
for the last
25 30 years i've been in the central
valley
um near fresno yeah and then
um
for the last 10 years i spend half the
year in southern humboldt in half the
year down here
very cool and and
when you started hbk farms was that when
you were in san diego or was that when
you moved up to the central valley
no central valley yeah i didn't really
brand myself until
god almost like 2014 2015 and that was
when i
got online and started talking to people
and i realized i needed a name and
i was trying to get into the cannabis
industry and
so yeah i came up with hbk that was
actually a name that came
prior when i was playing paintball yeah
back in the day actually kind of before
that and it was just for half-baked kids
is that what this dance floor
yeah that's funny i didn't know that
until right now
yeah i had a foreman at one point um and
he didn't really like me and
used to be like oh that stoner guy he's
[ __ ] half
and it just kind of stuck and then when
i was playing paintball for about 10
years
i was
doing a lot of um tournament level ball
and we started some teams and yeah half
bait was the name of our team that's
awesome i didn't even know that all
these years
yeah thank you
what were you smoking in city like what
years in san diego were you were you
puffing back in san diego when you were
there
yeah so i grew up in east county um and
i think when i was in about 10th grade i
started smoking
what kind of stuff did you see around
then
uh brick weed yeah yeah the experience
of the brick weed
yeah and then every great once in a
while we would see some kind bud come
through and that was usually we'd have
to go down into like el cajon or maybe
like mission beach
track that down but that was so
expensive back then that i couldn't like
that's why i started growing yeah my my
dad was a grower
he was kind of a hobbyist grower when i
was a kid
and his
best friend who lived on our property
was like legit grower he was a gorilla
grower yeah and so when i started
growing my dad kind of shut me down real
quick but then daryl my dad's best
friend took me under his wing
and then there were some other people in
our town that were pretty heavy growers
and
so yeah i learned pretty early on that
would have been like 89
88.89 i started growing yeah and in 1991
i was already producing speeds because
back then we couldn't find any seeds
yeah
i got lucky and had some pretty good
strains and was already finding some
males and so i started making seed
and i had a um
growing up on the border in tecate
i grew up with kids that parents were
cartel growers yeah and they were like
can you get a seed like bags of seed and
i was like well yeah and so i
realized that it was easier to grow seed
for sale
and not risk as much than trying to grow
pounds yeah and so that's what i started
doing early on but then
um
i took a break from like 97
98 to
2004 or 5.
i had a daughter
and my life changed and
kind of got out of it for a little while
and then came back
and been here ever since
yeah so when you um when i first met you
you were heavy heavy heavy into the
topical scene and
i remember like our first exchange uh
you gave me some of your cream like hey
try it out like real generous it was i
knew it it sold for good money but you
gave it to me that's right
and i've tried so many different creams
over the years and i i really genuinely
dismissed every cream that i tried after
that but when i tried yours and handed
it off to my chick and my my mom at the
time they were blown away absolutely
blown away and you started winning some
big awards for your work um can you tell
us how you got into that i'm very
interested in that
yes so my daughter when she was born um
she was born with a rare skin condition
called epidermolysis bullosa
um
it's like
so they're missing a skin tissue layer
and
it's called the butterfly disease i
think is what they call it or something
like that and it's kind of like
being burned every day
without being burned and so blisters
sores the blisters once they start they
don't stop they just keep like she would
get a little blister on her knuckle and
by the next morning it would take up her
whole hand oh god and you'd have to stop
you'd have to lance it to stop it but
you're not supposed to do but yeah
because of the tissue layer issue
um she would get these infections so in
96 95 96
there were some local
hippies um a lady named marion who was
uh one of my elementary teachers and her
husband were holistic
old-school hippie growers at that time
and
she was like oh you know you got to make
these cannabis sad
and you start teaching me about cannabis
salves and creams
and then
god i
kind of dabbled around with it for a
little bit but then when i came back
into
to growing again i started trying to
pick it up but
i wasn't getting the effects that i
really wanted it wasn't really working
for her
but then
i came across cbd and him and working
with ringo lawrence
and he was like hey you know we got this
stuff you should check it out i've got a
friend that's making these creams and
it's really helping
and i was like oh okay and so i got into
it
and yeah i just decided i'm gonna make a
good cream you know like i wanted
something that because with my
daughter's skin condition
it couldn't be too greasy it couldn't
get oily
and it couldn't be too rough
so a lot of the people that were making
cannabis sods or bombs it was like
beeswax and
coconut oil and
gonzo and that just made her skin
problem worse so i came up with the
cocoa cream
with seven ingredients and it started
working for her and so i started kind of
selling it on the side a little bit yeah
i started getting instant feedback
everybody's like dude this is amazing
and so yeah i started getting it on the
market and i started winning awards
and then
um the cbd craze hit
yeah and all of a sudden it went from
like 10 or 20 of us that were making cbd
creams or topicals to like thousands
and big companies that were like dumping
[ __ ] on the market and garbage yeah all
of a sudden i went from everybody being
like oh wow who are you what's this too
all of a sudden everybody's like oh
you're a cbd company [ __ ] you
yeah
for a while
and i kind of just
kept it available for people who wanted
it needed it but i stopped trying to go
big with it because um
i didn't have a million dollars to go up
against these cbd companies that started
coming out
and so yeah i still make it i still have
it available um yeah so yeah i just
don't i just don't market it like i used
to because
it's just the people who know know and
and
anybody that wants to know it's still
there
that's good to know i mean like it's
people don't understand like with that
market there was only a few people that
were doing it right like really right
and when cbd hit big and and the farm
bill passed and [ __ ] like people started
licensing
uh
hemp products from from china that would
and they grow they are paid to grow hemp
over there to leech toxins from the soil
like it's used to do that it's garbage
and
they know they can pass that out off at
cheaply super cheap on dumb ass
americans
and that pretty much wrecked the whole
industry for the few people who were
doing this [ __ ] right and now you see it
in gas stations everywhere you don't
know how it's sourced you don't know how
it's made and there's no regulation so
nobody gets a [ __ ]
it's it's sad that's sad
it's one of those things that people
don't seem to know very much about so
when i went fully legal it seems to me
like all those products you were talking
about most of them don't have like the
amount you would want
right they just want to splash cbd
cream or lip balm or this or that or
whatever or gels and they don't really
have a bunch of science behind what
actually works what i was thinking when
you were talking about all that stuff is
like how interesting like your
weed path is because most people
who start making seeds have been growing
flower for a while before they get like
the know-how and the knowledge and the
itch
to make you know to like sell seed not
to like make seed every year to grow
flour but actually to like sell seed
right and then to get into cream cream
has got to be one of the rarest things
that anybody ever figured out how to do
like that like like pretty much nobody
was
nobody was really making that kind of
stuff it wasn't common
i never met anyone
really it was like
and
because i was dedicated to making seed i
didn't have a lot of flour so i have a
lot of by-product from the plant that i
was breaking down for the seed and i'm
like what am i going to do with this
let's make hash or let's like let's
figure out what we're going to do with
this let's make edibles i wasn't a good
edible maker and i wasn't a great great
hashmaker
and i didn't have a lot of material so
yeah the topicals were like it instantly
all just fell into place it was like oh
yeah okay this is what we're gonna do
and yeah those are the two things i
focused on
yeah it was it was it was wild times and
and i'm glad to hear you're still making
it and i know like instantly everybody
in chat was like where did we buy it is
it available on a website is it
available on our website anywhere
it is i have my own website it's um
www.hbktopicals.com
all right i'm gonna pin it in the um
in the chat room so people can see it
while we're doing this
and go grab it and and i i'm there are
very few things that i will uh put my
name behind but
the eric's uh
topicals have been always always been
awesome always always been awesome so i
highly recommend it checking it out
i have the cocoa cream which is designed
for skin restoration or skin condition
issues it works great for like bug bites
takes the itch away but then i also have
um a cinnamon fire bomb which is based
off of like a traditional tiger bomb
and that's for
muscle ligament you know it's a menthol
type based smells like cinnamon fire
nice
that available
um i do have tinctures up from time to
time and
i've been trying to get the chopsticks
back but i just haven't had the money
for the labels
yeah yeah
my girlfriend loved the chapstick that's
the one she likes the most is the
chapstick
dude that the chapsticks were like a big
thing for a long time when i was doing
the emerald cup yeah
sell out i would go through like 500
containers and every year people would
go back over the booth and pull their
their stick out and be like oh this is
the best i still got it i'm glad you're
here yeah
i think it's because it's like super
it's affordable and it's it's something
everybody can afford but it's highly
effective at the same time
i know
so people are going to want me to ask
more about ringo and your interactions i
didn't know ringo so i didn't have any
interactions with him or his crew can
you talk about him a little bit
yeah so i knew rango kind of um
i would go up and see him every once in
a while we had kind of like a phone
conversation
um relationship
in 2010
or 11
i can't remember when it was i wasn't
doing too well i decided i was going to
leave the valley
i was going to move to humboldt i went
up there looking for work
it wasn't like i got lotted in with all
the
immigrants and the homeless people and
this dude pulled in you know and i kind
of looked at him and i'm like man i
wonder if this guy can help me out i
walked over started talking to him
we kind of took a bond and he's like hey
you know i got some work
but if you can move some units for me
and i'm like okay
and so yeah i started talking with him
and
kind of formed a bond and i would just
call him and go and see him every now
and then and then when the cbd thing hit
for him
he was kind of like the godfather of the
cbd
um
and then he got sick and passed away
before i could really get a chance to
spend a lot of time with him
um
we were doing a little bit of cbd
breeding work when i was doing all that
testing for [ __ ] with the well i wasn't
really doing testing for hymen i got a
lot of the early cantatonic seeds yeah
yeah
stuff
and then when ringo had all his sioux
lines
i started going through those and
um
and then we started working on the
lavender project and then yeah he passed
away
and i tried to reach out to his kids but
his kids didn't really know me and they
were doing their own thing and so yeah i
just kind of lost track of all that and
unfortunately i'm not sure
if any of his lines are still around
from the family if they're still
focusing on any of that or not i
honestly don't know
yeah
his daughter danielle
and levi were the ones that kind of took
over and i think they still have some
stuff going on but i'm not sure but i
still see harold sue crosses everywhere
oh yeah yeah
so that's that's his legacy that'll live
on forever
yeah that's cool when you get to to work
with some of those guys who are maybe
like
underground like legends like that you
know you get to just briefly rub elbows
with them and have some of their magic
rub off on you a little bit that's
that's special stuff and it sounds like
he's a special dude
yeah yeah he was the one that got me to
like start growing again um
i was still kind of like oh i'll grow a
couple little plants in my backyard
and he was like no man you know like
you live in a great area
you can go incognito like let's do this
and i'm like okay yeah okay let's do
this
and so yeah i miss that guy he was
he was really cool he had a lot of
great stuff going on he grew a lot of
really big plants and yeah i missed him
so
well that's cool you have anything you
want to ask nathan
i mean the the weird i do i was just
thinking about like the whole
the whole cbd thing because i think like
for the probably the first 20 or for
most people when they first encountered
cbd
like they didn't know what it was and so
they felt like it didn't work like i
come from the midwest right and we used
to get really beautiful ditchweed
sometimes we'd call it pretendica and it
would look like unbelievably juicy so
much better you were talking about
mexican we all started on you know there
was two kinds of weed there was brown
mexican and green mexican
and then every once in a while you'd
find kind bud but then sometimes people
would take that that gorgeous weed and
dry it and it would look so amazing and
we'd spend all this money and we'd smoke
and smoke and smoke and smoke and like
oh i'm like man i'm not getting high
you know and so it's interesting it's
just interesting how like
how for a long time we had like this
relationship with hemp and cbd and then
we went like 50 60 years with nothing
and so even a lot of even a lot of like
you know like people on the thc side
that are pretty knowledgeable like
you know
t cbd is supposed to do you know stuff
everything from like miracle cures to
like make nothing
yeah right like
it's really odd in that regard you know
and so
you know it's kind of like in its i
think it's kind of like in its infancy
and it seems like it got all big all
quick like you were saying and so all
these sharks jumped in
and kind of like diluted the scene
is really realised you know just well
yeah everyone just jumped in and nobody
knew anything and then you get to sell
something cool and holistic to people
that don't know anything and they don't
know how much doses are supposed to be
in there
yeah they don't know what an effective
dose is
right and so it's kind of like yeah it's
weird it's it's weird and that like it
as soon as it went legal it like got
doused in a sea of like ineffective cbd
yeah the difference between the textile
hemp style plants that are more for
fiber
which is also carries some cbd
which is hemp versus the more
traditional like cbd lines that we know
now like catatonic there was a big
difference
um so when i first started smoking some
of the early con pentatonic i picked up
on on a euphoric feeling from it and i
was like oh yeah okay there's something
here and then when we made the creams
for it i made some really hot batches
and i could feel my hands get numb and i
was like oh wow okay
you know yeah
i've gotten i've gotten textiles type
hemp
extraction and tried to use it and it's
completely useless because you know
what's interesting about that is like
catatonic and stuff it seems like
there's a there's not that much cbd
that's like bred from drug cultivars
towards the cbd side and that's kind of
what i was getting on what you were
saying is like cantatonic was sort of
bred from
smoking weed
not from the other side of like hemp
fiber or anything like that which might
have a bunch in it but if you remember
when jaime first sent those tester seeds
out like we didn't know it was a cbd
line it was just catatonic and they just
made the cry it wasn't ever advertised
they didn't breed it as a cbd line
originally it just ended up that way
yeah yeah and if you look at the
genetics behind catatonic you would
think oh this is going to be some fire
weed like
thc weed because it's
the genetics behind it but then yeah
it's primarily
cbd only now when i was going through
all those packs and i was having them
tested i found one pheno that was a
primarily thc carrier pheno it was like
a 14 or 16 percent thc
with very little thc or cbd yeah that
was still one of my favorite plants that
i ever smoked it was like real cheesy
and it got me so high and then when i
was doing that work with plant speaker
jay i lost that cut i was trying to get
it to jay and while i was gone up there
i lost that cut and
but there are
some very rare thc phenos of cantatonic
out there yeah
yeah i just i think it's funny because a
lot of people weren't around when resin
seeds came out and all their i remember
they had the the fake hp 13 sour diesel
so i remember thinking [ __ ] they got the
sour [ __ ] and they're selling it hell
yeah i want to try that and it turned
out not to be anything and they admitted
it later on they're like yeah this isn't
what we thought it was which is cool of
them um yeah we have a catatonic i
remember remember when that came out too
and it was not a cbd like it was like
what mk ultra g13 haze
yep yeah there was probably honestly in
the in the prohibition days there was
probably an enormous amount of cbd
in
uh various cannabis strains that got
selected away from
because we weren't we were only testing
by smoking
and so you you know you're passing
around different phenotypes and your
friends are like no that one i don't
think let's go with this one yeah you
know because without testing it's really
hard like something that's one to one
you know like 10 12 thc and 10 12 like
cbd or something that's high in that
like without
you know i mean when was the first time
you saw results like actual testing when
do you remember
oh that would have been 2011.
i was just gonna say like 11 12
somewhere in there so basically what you
guys are saying is that we've had
testing for a little longer than a
decade
right where it's like before that like
we really weren't able to select for cbd
very well
no and once i got my first few tests
that came back i was hooked on getting
tests remember matt i was just like
every week i was testing testing testing
all my money it was so [ __ ] expensive
back then too and i remember every time
i'm like how does he [ __ ] afford to
test all this [ __ ] i can't test one
thing and he's got like [ __ ] 20. yeah
i was doing literally like between two
and five thousand dollars every other
week on testing just trying to go
through all these and that's why i
gained a lot of respect early on because
i was actually doing the work to find
these these cultivars yeah you for sure
were you were doing real testing
at a time when it was totally just not
advantageous financially to do it and it
was it was very very cool it was very
cool to watch and luckily you used some
of my [ __ ] so i was like yeah i can see
the tesla's on my [ __ ] too because i'm
cheap i'm cheap fellas
so let's let's uh talk about some of
these um strains you've seen over the
years some of the ones you've worked
with let's start from the beginning what
was one of some of the first strains you
were crossing at hbk
um at hpk or the first strings i was
crossing let's say first you mentioned
that you were crossing like different
mexicans right at the beginning
yeah i was doing just like like the very
first stuff was just like some regular
old brick weed seed and
um
there was some a guy in pine valley that
i was growing up with named chris balman
and he was
like
going out and finding all the kind bud
he was a truck fun kid and he had the
money and he was bringing all this weed
back and he was getting really good bad
feet he was collecting it and he was
giving me some of that and i was popping
those and out of those i had gotten this
purple hair afghani these little short
plants super dark purple hairs and my
buddies in the area and campo there were
like damn like that's bomb yeah and then
one of our our friends in the
neighborhood
that hippie couple
they traveled to amsterdam met up with
neville
brought back most of his seed bank and
this was in
i want to say
my daughter
wasn't born yet so it would have been
they brought back a bunch of genetics
and my best friend jeff at the time was
working with his people and he pulled a
few cuts away from them and then got a
few seeds from them after they had made
some crosses
and that's what i was working with and
then there was another guy over in
verona
by the indian reservation they were
working with some jamaicans
yeah jamaican lions and we got a little
bit of that and that's what i was
working with early on
and
then
when my
wife at the time got busted for
international trafficking we lost
everything we moved and then i had to
start over again
in mid-2000
and in mid-2000
when you started working with making uh
strings again what were you what were
you growing
what were some of your selection
criteria
the first few things i started working
with was i was moving some weight for
some um mom growers in your valley and i
got some heated pounds of some really
great wheat
and
i then got some bag seed from some kids
that i was playing paintball with
and that's when i was making that candy
candy crack was what i was calling it
and i ran that for a long time
for a few years and then i got into the
cbd thing hard
i was running some of your stuff and um
people been asking about that candy
crack green in the in the comments
repeatedly
yeah
that was something that
is kind of this convoluted [ __ ] up
story that i i got tired of arguing with
everybody about you know i made that
stuff back in like 2005 or six i was
dumping clones
just some kids in san jose that were
distributing them
and
i didn't realize
like
what it really was until about 2014
when i started seeing some of the
flowers come back and everybody's like
yeah it's crap
and i'm like man i think that's my
stream you know so i reached out to you
yeah and so it kind of came up with the
name and
then later on god like
2018 or 1911
started by losing everything and so i
threw in a philos
run and it came back as green ribbon but
also green crack it was also related to
skunk
hemp
colombian gold dream queen
yeah all this [ __ ] so
i don't [ __ ] know like i honestly
don't know i just kind of was like
whatever
like
if if
if it is it is cool you know like i knew
i had some really good stuff but it was
such a small run and i wasn't really
shooting for anything at that point but
it turned out to be a [ __ ] and strain
um
and yeah there's it it violences back to
a bunch of stuff so
you know
whether yeah
it's a tough one you never know like
their their results were so
inconsistent like some of the times i'd
see him and be like okay that makes
sense genetically this related to that
blah blah blah and then you go and see
like that that i don't know for example
um
let's say someone submitted a bubba
mendo perps and then they submitted
bubba and then they submitted mendo
perps that they made it with and then
all of a sudden it's like oh none of
these are related well that's right
weird you know yeah
right so yeah i kind of just stopped
arguing that point
but then the next thing that came up was
the chili birdie the chili verde was
part of the the lavender project with
ringo yeah
rango had called me one night and he's
like hey he's like you're running that's
that
lavender right and i'm like yeah i had
gotten a cut here locally it was the
scent like the san jose cut or whatever
it was the lavender that everybody had
in mid 2000 a little short stocky super
dense was it the early lavender
yeah yes yeah yeah
and um he's like hey he's like i got all
these seeds that i bought from soma
he goes i don't
want to work this project to get
straight lavender but he's like if i
give you the seeds
and go through it
can you
come up with something i'm like yeah and
he said that he had a male already so i
went up got the speech got the mail
got some more lavender cuts from him
brought them all back
and i started trying to make because he
wanted straight lavender yeah and so i
made the straight lavender but while i
was doing that i had a whole depth full
of other stuff yeah i hit it through
e-line pie i hit the girl scout
i hit it to
um
pineapple cheese
from ringo yeah i hit it called horror
stew
i hit it to um
a
um
what was the other one the craft baby it
was oh the
the green candy
and there was another one that i did
and
harvested all that stuff took all the
seeds back up to ringo came to him and
then he passed away
and then the next season
was a year when those kids ripped me off
and yes a lot of that
got all that breeder stock from me so i
lost the lavender stock basically i um
kept one little i had one little shitty
clone left
and but i had all the other seeds and
then i started dropping those chili
verdes and when i dropped the chili
birthday
i got kind of a lot of pushback people
were actually talking [ __ ] to me when i
dropped them and they were like you use
key lime pie
they're like that is the studious
[ __ ] plant in the world yeah you're
not a breeder and i'm like
well i liked it it was okay you know
none of them had even tried it that's
the [ __ ] far like it was it was in so
few hands at the time yeah
yeah and so
didn't i
kind of perceived it as oh well maybe i
made a mistake
and so i didn't really push it that hard
and i sold some packs and then um kind
of just set it aside
and she was like two years later two
years later it popped a few more seeds
and i had
um
a through f cuts is what i was calling
him yeah and i was hanging out with with
john
and we were doing the breeder series
with kev
which one
yeah yeah and so
i took a bunch oh i took some cuts up
with me and i was like john like check
this stuff out
and he looked at the flower and he was
like he's like wow he's like what is
this i'm like key lime pie lavender he's
like
he's like this is legit he's like
he's like you have touching this i'm
like yep i brought you one i gave him
one and he was like he's like man he's
like we're gonna do some stuff with this
he's like we've got something here man
he's like you're on to something i'm
like okay cool
and
that was when i met not so dog i think
at the same exact event
that's a nice cut i got to i agree that
cut that you gave him multiple years in
greenhouses
in mendocino
um it it
it was it was i liked it sun grown quite
a bit
was that was that the the super verde
cup
yeah yeah we we had this chili very i
have pictures of it on my phone uh we
had a bunch of them um we did probably
a couple years in a row probably half of
like a 30 by 100 greenhouse of it
there was one a good one
huh there was one when eric first
brought it up that smelled like to a tea
chili verde like just
the wildest greasy meat chili verde
smell yeah it does kind of seem to like
that weed came out like a few years
before the the like modern purple wave
sort of swamped everything yeah you know
it really was like purple had not been
popular for the most part for quite a
long time so
um you know it it was one of the first
cuts i remember seeing
that like you know kind of started that
way like that and the gelato and
different things like that like but it
reminded me
it definitely you can definitely taste
the lavender in it
yeah it's it's you know but i think it's
maybe a little bit more potent
so the cut that matt's referring to is
one of the other cuts that i had it was
more of that the straight chili now the
super chili which was coined by
um lion bolt i think which is the d cut
that's the cut that i gave john the one
that won the emerald cup that one was
heavy lavender it was really gravy but
it still had like this og overtone to it
yeah
it was really different than the the cut
that i smelled from you it was
like the one i smelled from using like
meat like
chili verde on the the barbecue it was
good yeah the one i had was sweet so
much sweeter
you know the one the one that that won
the emerald cup was the one the reason i
gave it out was because it had better
uniformity looking structure it had more
tighter nugs and it was a little bit
easier to run in depth or outdoor but it
was really finicky indoors especially if
you were running the old-school shitty
leds the pink ones yeah it [ __ ] does
not like those like chili just doesn't
like leds for some reason i'm not sure
why
but
um yeah so those were the two that i had
a couple different cuts and then
um
john had the fire the cut got out got to
a few different people and then yeah it
took off and it won and
i was a little bummed because i wasn't
in position to be able to capitalize on
getting cuts out to the population when
it won yeah and all the other people
instantly jumped on it and maybe oh sure
made a lot of money yeah and i was just
like hey
[ __ ] you know
how am i going to deal with this how do
i
how do i direct this in my direction
yeah so i started dropping seeds like i
got seeds i got seeds like i don't have
cuts but i got seeds and so
i kind of tried to stay on top of it
and
yeah still kind of
pushing that run you know it's turned
out to be a really good breeder
um i've gotten up into the f5 f6s now oh
awesome
i got
the last batch of chili crosses that i
did i did like
i think it was seven crosses with an f5
and they turned out phenomenal every
single jar you open is just so bomb
[ __ ] in color
because you get that red from the hairs
and the purples and some of the greens
um
and i kind of did some hypey crosses a
couple years ago before i went to work
for emerald and i still haven't released
them i'm trying to get them out in the
next couple weeks but there was a brunch
chili
wedding crashers chili wedding cake
chili josh d chili
uh dosie dough chili and sweeties chili
yeah and every one of them turned out
just amazing i was really happy with
every single one of them
okay one of the things i like about the
chili verde is that a lot of cookie
hybrids
uh seem to not like the sun and not like
food very much
you know like so there it i don't know i
felt like that one especially like you
put it out in the sun and it thrived
you fed it well and it thrived like it
could eat it could grow there's certain
aspects where like you know i i think
sometimes like some of these some of
some cookie selections were designed for
like rock woolen to be two feet tall in
an indoor situation and like the chili
verde can grow
you know like it can be a healthy happy
vigorous plant
um and a lot of cookie hybrids aren't
that way in my opinion you know that one
was one that was you know you could put
it in the sun and it would you know you
could put it in a greenhouse you could
dep it like you said it did well as like
a medium-sized plant like something you
want to get a half pound to a pound per
plant off of and it gave you a lot of
very very pretty weed like you were
saying the formation on it it's
extremely attractive when it's dry it
has a really nice aroma
you know and it gets me hot
it um i always thought because of the
lavender it wasn't going to be a big
yielder
but when i was working for ben
um up in mendo we ran about
25 or 30 phenoes of the f5s
two they were we were pulling
like between three to seven pounds off
some of them plants and they were just
monsters you know arm size colas from
bottom to top
um they're a little pm prone if you're
in a pretty nasty area which can kind of
be a bummer but if you're in a dry hot
climate
like here in the valley they thrive
they've got really good root structure
really good nutrient water uptake to
them they have a good root they have a
good root system yeah they're a little
dangerous
if you get some fog for sure because
it's such thick buds
you know
they're not like big buds but they're
very dense you know it's one of those
things when it dries when you put it on
there you're surprised at how much it
weighs
so it but it it both of them they are a
little they are a little like uh pm and
and uh and grey mold sensitive but
that's like any
i think all that lavender urkel all
those super dense lines
have that you know plants have pluses
and minuses but that was it was a good
grower i enjoyed growing it
you know it's like okay if you're if
you're in a hot air conditioned area
like especially like here in arizona or
colorado they do they do really well
here in the valley they can be like
108 today and they're just like yep
bring it come on
so
yeah it's brutal right now dude in the
valley
yeah where are we going on like over 40
to 45 days of over a hundred and i think
we still got
like probably another 10 days at least
that [ __ ] starts making me question my
life choices
you know it really is when it hits i
mean it it's get it's a little much like
plants
i don't know but it is interesting in
the sense that like
the the hard part is you can get with
like you're right in dry airy conditions
you can get some monsters
it's just about like keeping them
hydrated and like and making sure they
don't go b grade because it's too hot at
night
yeah and you know
shade cloth is you got to have some
shade cloth on them
they can't take
110 degree direct
light for hours on end that just they
just don't like it it's way more light
than they need
yeah and so you get like a good
thirty to forty or fifty percent grade
class i like the 30s
just keep that over them the whole
summer and they
they do fine they thrive
hydration is the key man
so
since you're growing in the valley and
you have a lot of experience with it
yeah someone asked a good question
are some uh terps volatile to heat like
are there some terps like some strange
you cannot grow in the valley because it
gets so [ __ ] hot during the summer
there's no point because it gets surplus
is that possible
the terps will the terps will die you'll
get that
kind of
like not hay but it smells like old weed
almost
and what also happened that i've seen is
i've actually seen trichome heads melt
out here
yeah the heads will just literally be
like
and then you're left with a [ __ ]
stalk of like
like a dead tree kind of thing yeah and
then it's like you can see it where it's
oozed down
and then you start getting like the
titus type situation where it starts to
rot kind of yeah i have seen that before
i actually think
one of the one of the reasons why a
bunch of mendo and southern humboldt got
so legendary for growing outdoor
is that even though it might be blazing
hot in the daytime that ocean comes in
and it cools it down at night and when
that plant gets to cool down
like it preserves terps like if it's 105
in the day but it gets down to 55
degrees at night that makes an enormous
difference in the quality of your plant
and if you get too far inland like say
grass valley grass valley you grow like
some 10 or 15 pounders or the desert but
that's what it's all about is trying to
preserve your terps
because if it's 108 in the daytime and
85 at night
you you run big risk of not like i said
not quite hay
but like not anything what your plant
could be potential of you can definitely
burn your terps off
and i and and uh yeah makes it makes a
big difference
the key the key to growing in the
central valley between like bakersfield
and
sacramento is
realistically knowing your times of when
to grow
i always tell people
if you're in fresno i don't grow outdoor
in between like
july and the end of september
it's just unless you're gonna run a
cooled
depth it's not it's not [ __ ] worth it
it's just no it's a battle
you have to you have to run a water wall
and like yeah like in like a greenhouse
and add a bunch of moisture and cool it
down
yeah and they're like whoa it's it's
it's warm and it's dry and i'm like yeah
but you have the whole rest of the year
you can get away with growing in the
valley yeah you know you can grow from
september all the way through until june
yeah but you don't really need to stop
growing in a central valley from that
time but
july august september
take that time off like
i even started taking summers off
indoors because it was just such a
[ __ ] battle like even trying to
battle the air conditioner with indoors
and all it was a [ __ ] nightmare every
year in summer no matter indoor or
outdoor that's why people call it summer
bud
yeah
you know it's like a lot of times people
have a hard time
growing the best weed that they can in
the middle of the summer
they really do they you struggle with
i conditions
know if you've ever made seeds in that
kind of condition
but when you make seeds in over 100
degree weather those [ __ ] are
almost impossible to crack yes yeah
it's still like
like a rock yeah it's you need a lot of
hand cracking with those too because
they they they develop so thick and
everything because they know that it's
hot and they want to keep their their
embryo alive that's crazy yeah yeah i
mean now that now that we're like
um
you know things are getting
whether you want to call legal or more
acceptable or whatever it might be
it's like we all used to grow weed where
we could get away with it
for the most part and
there's not been a lot of thought of
like which type of strains grow well
where
yeah you know because like in america
it's like we grow citrus in florida
right or winter wheat montana or
potatoes in idaho or corn in illinois
like you figure out where it works
and we haven't really done that with
weed no you know but there's so there's
certain like i was even in mendo there's
so many microclimates i'd have strains
where like they did amazing in one part
of the county and i'd get a different
spot and i'd put them out and i'd be all
and like stoked that i was gonna crush
it and they wouldn't do that good
but then there were some other strains i
had that did really well so there's
aspects where i'm sure
there's some strains that like acclimate
just like growing in british columbia or
canada or something right there's
probably some desert weed that's like
more acclimated uh but we don't really
think of things that way anymore
right like it's names and popularity and
maybe it's runts and maybe it's this and
so
you know um
i think sativas deal with the heat
better than indicas
personally yeah yeah yeah i think so
it's and they have they have better
water absorption abilities they can hold
water longer they got thinner leaves you
know they're not they don't have as much
exposure like and they and they come
from places that are hot as [ __ ]
yeah
a lot of them
you know
so one one thing i noticed this year was
um
people who are moving clones from one
end of the state to the other
are
experiencing
like it's almost like culture shock for
the plants because they're used to one
environment and then you're moving them
all the way to another environment in
the state and they're like
but some are like yeah they love it so
it kind of falls into the same
category g with the clone stock
it's a serious thing people don't take
into account but some strains definitely
are more picky than others when
acclimatizing even from one grow room to
the next in the same city it just that
difference can really flip it you would
like to think that like you can work
with most nurseries and like get a cl
you know like tough and hardened off
plants that are going to be suited for
your environment but a lot of cases
you know clone companies are you know
nurseries nowadays
they have these plants under 24 7 light
and they're just trying to keep them
rooted and healthy until somebody buys
them yeah and then they get taken from
like 24 7 light under fluorescence they
get boxed up in the dark like he said
they get shipped down from northern
california to your desert they get
opened up and then bam they're in the
desert
and they're flowering and it's and
and the light drops by eight hours in
one night yeah
yeah right because you used to be able
to like if you grew in mendo or southern
humboldt or somewhere like that like
most people would acclimate their clones
and plants for their own season yeah
nowadays you buy you know people just
want to buy them from somewhere but it's
like i mean when i was working in
southern california you would go
the the longest day of the year down
there is maybe 14 or 15 hours
so you're getting you're going from 24
hours to 14.
it's a 10 hour drop in one day you could
have a plant trigger
just from the shock of the light cycle
yeah well that's kind of what happened
to me this year is i had
some clone stock that i had in southern
humble
spent two days three days
making the trip down here and i got here
put them out here and everything was
like
oh
no we don't like this
so yeah i kind of had a little bit of a
rough transition this this last couple
months and so i just kind of gave up and
just
that bucket i'll just wait until i can
get back into another good position to
be able to do some real work you know
yeah
you know it's also one of those things
too where it's like a lot of the some of
the stuff that's getting really popular
right now
um indica style is probably best for
like being grown more northern climate
right
where you get way far south like where
you guys are and you almost need some
sativa mixed into your work if you want
it to grow outdoor and stretch
right because it's far enough south that
it'll trigger fast
that's kind of that's kind of one of the
things that i've seen and so people
think that like oh you know like
figuring out what works well in your
area is huge
in uh
you know it really is it's big
yeah for sure
i wanted to i wanted to keep going over
a little bit more of the green craft
stuff because i know that's probably
what people want to hear the most about
because it's it's a strain like when we
were working with it it was it was the
clone was a lot of places and then
it was nowhere all of a sudden
it's become a lot it's become a lost
legend and misnamed and all kinds of
stuff you know
lots of imposters lots of seed lines
that weren't real and right there with
the lavender you don't see the lavender
around anymore either not that miracle
lavender you really don't not anymore
no these were all strains that that
so we had that
we had that push for strains that were
um like the blue dream yeah everybody
was like [ __ ] blue dream buck the
[ __ ] lavender [ __ ] you know these
these strains that just hit a wall all
of a sudden and we're gone nobody wanted
them so nobody kept him there might be
some random dude around that has a cut
of it but
yeah it's a little healthy or not he
[ __ ] knows you know
yeah so yeah
that is one of the biggest things is
trying to be a collector and trying to
keep genetics alive
is that everybody will help you back it
up when it's flying out the door is
flower and it's easy to sell
and then as soon as the mood changes
your most of your best friends don't
even want unless they can sell it to
market and it's working for them right
now they only want to keep
clones of like what's currently popular
yeah and so i mean i mean everyone and i
mean everyone that was growing a decent
amount of weed in humboldt and mendo
in the 2004 0506 era they had one of
those urkel or one of those lavender or
one of those grape ape or one of those
cuts you know and you know green crack
green crack's a great plant
if you grow it small to medium sized
it's got really nice terps you know
it's got a nice buzz it burns well um
but people got burnt out on it because
just like blue dreams someone's like oh
i can grow a 12
plant of this in grass valley and it's
gonna be bee weed and i'm gonna ship it
off and it's gonna be endless amounts of
boofy green crack the one that the green
crack two was like
half the plant was larv
yeah and so and then that part that was
trimmable
was usually the trimmers [ __ ] hated
it they were like walk this plant and so
yeah it kind of just went by the wayside
pretty quick
but what's funny about that one is that
you think about like the eras
imagine if that had had like its moment
in the sun now
when everyone's extracting and all that
laffy stuff probably would dump
well it was a great so
from my experience it was a great
um like you could blow it it would blow
great but if you tried to wash it it was
um it was almost too greasy like you
didn't
yeah it was just kind of fell into that
category of it was just too hard to work
with
um and so yeah that's kind of why that's
kind of why i got away from it
i i've been trying to figure out what
green crack is for a long time years and
years and years and over the years as my
experience gets better with different
strains you know my opinion kind of
changes on what i think it might be
early on i was like this has got to be
some kind of so mango because it's so
purple and it's super mango so i was
like okay the mango purple it's got to
be that
and as i went on okay i see some skunk
one in this okay you know with the mango
over time and and and the more i look at
it and the more
i figure it out the more i realize i bet
it might even be a mendo purp something
yeah
okay so that's where the story kind of
gets convoluted because
a lot of people associate purple
with green crack
now
what i was running what i what i was
calling the candy crack does not get
purple i don't care you can get it down
to 20 degrees it does not get purple
yeah at all and it's more watermelon
skunk than mango interesting interesting
that that lends more towards the skunk
one side than that
if it's a skunk i mean you can look at
it and just the way that it forms its
its spear buds all over itself you can
definitely see some skunk influence in
it
i will say that if it is a skunk one
fino it's definitely my favorite tasting
pheno of skunk one yeah
you know it has at night it has no when
it's done right it has nice terps
yeah the original seeds i used to make
the uh the green craft stuff that like
uh what were they called
that company that made green crack s1s
but a spanish company
yeah they used they used our s1s to make
the s2s and sold them as swans but um
it was heavy purple like and it wasn't
always purple but it was like the like
three degrees of cold change it would
just flip black almost like mental
purpose does and um yeah it was super
super overripe mangoes
purple not not frosty like a cookie's
cut but it was good resin for its time
it was good present it was it was an
attractive weed done right yeah and
really sure fiery orange hairs and yeah
and i see people mentioning cecil like
me and cecil when we first met each
other we tried to figure out if he had
anything to do with it what we
determined he had nothing to do with san
diego west coast green crab nothing at
all it was just that when we received
the cut uh but it was it was c-u-s-h
and he sent a cut west that was also
spelled wrong c-u-s-h and that was it
somebody said better keeper than cheese
i would rather have real green crack
than cheese but that's like a personal
preference yeah personal preference for
sure personal preference but my personal
preference was i would rather smoke and
you know what's interesting is that we
were talking about how
you know uh unreliable uh philos was
earlier which is a bummer because all of
us have these like great desires to know
how things are related yeah and i
remember caleb telling me that like
uh when
uh
dna submitted their las vegas lemon
skunk
that it came in exactly the same cut as
green crack
yeah it doesn't surprise me those guys
are the worst for that but like dnas
their their cantaloupe pays was just the
c99 i mean but i just mean in the sense
that it was a it was a good enough cut
that they used it and all kinds of
things yeah they just got rid of like
the name connotation you know like oh we
won't call it green crack it'll be las
vegas lemon skunk
right yeah and it is kind of lemon
skunky
that's why i was kind of leaning like
when they start talking about the green
ribbon
what i know is my candy has more leans
towards that i believe than the green
crack i always kind of was wondering if
the green crack was just an offshoot
from that or maybe i had an offshoot of
the original green crack that's where i
don't know
yeah that's where it got completed and
that's
people will start hitting me up and it
turns into an argument and i just
started being like [ __ ] it i don't know
anymore oh my god dude somebody's mind
just got blown in the comments and they
just realized that cantaloupe hayes was
c99
so the story was soma and this this came
from uh i won't say what came from but
it came from the amsterdam dudes that
were friends with all these guys and a
part of the same group and soma gave
them a pack of c99 to start their
company and sure enough that c99 became
the eight week haze magical eight-week
case magical 95 sativa and comes in in
eight weeks
yeah yeah no i just thought that comment
just
that just that's just yeah that's funny
well because that they were they were
some of the first people
that they went around california and
they took a bunch of famous cuts and
they gave them different names and they
started a seed company with it yeah and
they did really well
isn't like brothers graham try to take
the credit for his b99 isn't he like 99
guy or something like that well his
partner was his partner was and now he's
here so that's what we're left with
after meeting him and then you're
learning how to partner everything it's
like oh that makes sense then okay you
know
yeah okay
but yeah i mean green crack kids have
got in my opinion got a bad reputation
because most of the time
you could you could grow an eight or ten
pound plant of green crack
and it would kind of suck
but if you grew like a four or five
pound plant of green crack it was really
nice and if you grew a one or two pound
plant of it it was killer yeah so most
people just tried to blow it up into
these like i'm going to grow 99 green
cracks
and get just boucou weed and i'm not
going to dry it that nice and then
people are like oh i don't like green
crack
yeah
and so that's what happens to a lot of
big yielding cuts like blue dream green
crack uh you know barry white these
various ones that run through they get
blown out by people that don't care
chili verdes got kind of a bad rap
through the distros in california
because of the dark heart cut so dark
heart [ __ ] jumped on a cut of chili
verde they got
um
from a friend of mine named moongazer
moongazer kind of did a quick little
final hunt dropped a chili cut on them
real fast
and it wasn't the greatest chili and it
wasn't producing the best flour so all
these growers that jumped on it right
away took all this flower to the distros
and the distros were like oh we can't
[ __ ] do anything with this
so it kind of
like
it's like depends on who you talk to and
like who really liked the chili and
because of which cut they had now
the purple city cut or if they were
running a cut for me
um yeah
the distros take it but if you're
running like a dark heart cut they might
not take it
what's nice about that is that
you know it seems like in chile verde
that there's a number of people that
found a number of cuts that had like a
range of terps and effects that they
liked
well that's that's because of the fact
that i dumped all the seeds on the
market i didn't leave it to be just a
single clone only
cut right
being just one or two cuts out there i
made sure that i got enough seeds out to
the farmers
that there was some diversity that
people could start actually pheno
hunting out some good stuff because
there are there's a lot of good phenos
in it you know there's a few duds here
and there but there's [ __ ] some fire
in it especially as you start working
the line depending on which way you go
um i started going with this like a
pineapple there's a pineapple pheno in
there that i've been working
i really like that one the terpenes
profile is super high
and then there's the grape you know
that kind of everybody knows that
grapefino is really good
and then there's kind of more of an
unknown cheese pinot that floats in
there too
and that cheese pinot is bomb like it's
really good i gave um the humboldt local
joey i gave him some of the cheese ones
and he was like
they turned out funny
cheese
chili verde sweet lavender cheese
yeah where the cheese comes out of it
i'm not really sure but so in like the
key lime pie the key lime pie
i was told originally it was durbin
poison
og kush
cherry pie
but i'm not sure that does that sound
like that still hold true to it or not i
mean key lime pie is also like it was
also going around as the green sherb the
original sherb um also stardust sherb
for a while as well
um
i if i remember correctly it's the mom
of what became skittles is is what
people mostly tend to think that have
been growing a bunch of it so you can
find like the skittles type phenos in in
the out crosses and and in the s-ones um
but yeah as far as what it actually is
it's kind of like trying to peg down
what cherry pie actually is it's just
like wow [ __ ] they said a thousand
things i think i think it's likely that
all those things you mentioned are in
there in some form or another
yeah you know that's like the cheese is
the only one that kind of throws me off
because there is a very distinctive
cheese pinot that i did find in the f1
um
and yeah it was
like i didn't know if it came out of the
durbin side or maybe the og fight or the
cherry yeah just wasn't really like
okay
so
the the durbin that those dudes used was
it was so different from like the norcal
derb or the the colorado derb it was
nothing like it it was it was it was it
was not terrifying
yeah it wasn't the terpentaline stuff at
all no
and then you know we're just in the
infancy of figuring out how these
different things flavor combined
yeah
you know so i you know maybe it maybe it
uh yeah and then i also think too like
when people smell
it's like they related to things in
their life so it's really weird like
someone might get strong cheese and
somebody else might like get a totally
different impression
yeah you know
totally i i see that all the time like
almost like when you go to shows and
you're showing people jars and they're
you'll show maybe like 100 people the
jar and you'll hear like 20 different
comments of what they smell and they're
all different you know i actually really
like that a lot i used to do that with
my trimmers where i would ask them away
from the rest of the trimmers what they
were smelling with what they were
working on because i liked unvarnished
like opinions and then if i heard the
same thing four or five times
i'd start to accept that people got that
terp or that aroma they didn't call it
terps then or whatever i just wanted to
know what they related it to
you know because because the language of
it is so hard and so if somebody said
you know and a lot of strains i grew
over and over and over again and so i
would ask different trimmers over the
years like what do you think the maui
smells like what do you think this this
smells like and
sometimes their answers would be pretty
surprising
you know and you wouldn't have seen that
before they said it but then when they
say it it clicks
so i do i do think asking people's
opinions like a show would be a really
cool place to get a bunch of
quick
back you know like feedback on what
something smells like
yeah yeah somebody was telling me
recently that uh zometical farmer
he's got a chili that's like
i think he said it was papaya or guava
something like that i forget exactly
what it was
but yeah i was like i've never i've
never smelled that in it but then we
were going through some jars recently
and somebody was like
oh yeah i smell it totally i was like oh
okay yeah i get it now
i think i think flan nailed it on the
head there might be some skunk one and
cherry pie and key lime pie and all that
it sounds like it's just the whole gamut
of skunk one smells the grape the
[ __ ] cheese the all that is in there
i mean there's there's an aspect too
where you know it is possible
that um
you know a lot of durbin
you know had skunk one in it because it
came through sam
yeah you know and and a lot of durbin
came through dutch passion later on they
sold the durbin poison and that had more
skunk one in it evident so it was like
yeah so it's definitely it's definitely
possible
i'm thinking that that the uh the f1
derb is probably a hybrid of the dutch
passion one because it looks like some
of the old pictures of the old but just
grown much better in now today times
yeah
i mean durbin's one of those strains
that like is so old
that most people don't have experience
with what durbin was like in the 80s and
90s
yeah
you know and then what survived too you
know and then
yeah the black versus
associated with durban
yes and but then that colorado cut and
some of those other ones that got famous
later were super terpenolene yeah
you know and once you've got your
penduline in a line it hangs out
yeah it's hard to shake it out it's hard
to shake it out but i do like you know
we i worked with a durbin in the early
2000s and it was definitely more on that
anise black licorice type of aroma and
we didn't really get like this the type
of terpenoline
that seems to huh did you say it was
more like your black anis
is that what she just said
you know
so you know it's
indeed
so what are you working on now eric
what's cracking now
okay so
for the last few years i've been pushing
a couple
couple lines my durbin or excuse me
durbin my diamond master i've got an
orange creamsicle um hell's angel cross
it's really good
um
i have some peanut butter stuff but
right now currently what i'm working on
is actually some femmes
so okay
i've never really released femmes i did
one little fam run a couple years
got six years ago i thought it was like
10 pounds
years ago
it was
a blue dream
blue dream to blueberry hash plant
awesome what i'm working on now
is
doing kind of a hypey run just for the
market um
everybody's been just
inundating me for femmes
and so
i did a collaboration with a buddy of
mine uh wyatt terp 710
he did a chili birdie skittles cross
and so i'm feminized that and then i hit
that to
like
10 or 15 hypey strings like
mule fuel sunset cider chemistry one
apple tarts
orange diesel
[Music]
bubba kush
um
dirty skittles sfv
and la kushcake
very cool
very cool um hoping
like the normal market that comes to me
may not be interested in that but the
market that i haven't been tapping into
because i only sell regs i'm hoping
they'll be like yeah we're on them you
know
i've been trying
i've been trying to explain this to
people that um
what's going on with our market and that
and and a lot of people [ __ ] on when i
say it but it's true like if to have a
viable seat company you have to tap into
that market or it just doesn't work
there's not enough people to support
uh the niche market of rare strains old
strains unique strength it's just not
there anymore nobody gives a [ __ ]
yeah it's weird that in the last
you know
i mean we went from four or five people
doing feminized stuff 12 or 14 years ago
to 99 of the market or more being
feminized stuff
and reg seeds which was the standard for
forever
are now like a a tiny little corner
yeah
um is the kiddos and crybaby's right
this girl's rarity crosses will take off
people give him a chance especially
because it's almost like a
uh uh a back rock in a sense a back
cross to the
the key lime pie by the skittles it
probably be a terp explosion and it
would probably grow better and look
better than skittles
it's not hard you know no no skills is
not
it's got chilly structure so it holds
itself up it doesn't want to fall over
and [ __ ] be like
yeah you can smell you can smell the
skittles in there but chili's there too
it's like
and it's um i don't know if you run the
dirty skills or if you're familiar with
that it's a new one from i think micah
up at um
peace and meds he's got that farm um
i think he has that lamborghini or
whatever it is yeah
i know exactly what you're talking about
yeah
it's really similar to that
but yeah i'm i really dug it i went
through it my buddy
uh wyatt chirps made it and i was kind
of
had three phenos to kind of select
through and i was like wow these are
[ __ ] bombs you were talking like you
were talking like lampire farms right
yes i think that's who did the dirty
skittle yeah empire farms micah has a he
has a dispensary in my town
very cool in ukiah and stuff like that
and he's you know he's got a bunch of
seeds that he's been making but
that someone wants you to mention um
electric boogaloo dog [ __ ] eric are you
doing any work with that
the dog [ __ ] so um i have some of the
last dog [ __ ] speeds that were given out
i guess uh cora genetics gave me some
dog [ __ ] but i haven't had a chance to
get to them
i'm just kind of sitting on them at the
moment
oh that sounds cool is that who's
supposedly writing
uh no a guy out of oregon no a gentleman
out of oregon i can't remember the name
of the person who who bred the dog [ __ ]
yeah yeah i was at an event um we did a
sesh up in southern humble a few months
back
uh joey from humboldt local and i ran
into to eric
from forever flowering
oh yeah uh light depth eric and eric and
poor genetics and
he was like hey take these they got the
last dog [ __ ] like these
formal breeders
and i wanted to get into him but i just
i'm not
in a spot right now where i can do
anything i'm just
like yeah i'm sure that gives not so a
major boner he's a he's a electric
boogaloo dog [ __ ] [ __ ]
that kind of meat i like that it's got
it's got nice flavor it's pretty it's
got an up high
you know yeah lonesome loves that one
too that's one of his face too yeah i
know it's
a nice sativa
and i think
i think a lot of people are in that same
boat there's a lot of breeders
right now that are looking around at
like what should i like what what would
i like to do and then they're trying to
figure out well what should i do to make
it
you know like and it's it's kind of a
hard thing to navigate like you were
talking about growing hypey things and
trying to figure out where you fit in
and all that so
um
you know there's a lot of breeders in
the game right now but it's it takes
it's kind of a lot
there's a lot of seed makers in the game
right there's a lot of scenes a lot of
raiders it's very real i can't even put
myself in the breeding category anymore
i can't remember the last time i've
worked like worked a line several
generations it's just
it's hard to it's hard to do that
nowadays and know that
it's probably not going to sell you know
yeah it's crazy there's there's two
distinct markets that have broken out
that you kind of like if you're making
seeds you have to be making washers
something that washes yeah
the hash guys are gonna want cause the
extract thing that's where it's all
seemed to be going to
or
your hypey market
because the hypey market once the hypey
guys get a hold of that [ __ ] they're the
ones that find that cut
and then that cut gets taken over to the
commercial growers and then the
commercial growers blow it up yeah and
so if you're not tapping into those two
you're you're kind of like
oh well what am i like what the [ __ ] am
i gonna do you know because i was stuck
in the middle for the longest time where
i had these dedicated lines of regulars
that i was making
i have
certain growers that like to run those
lines and they're willing to to go
through my stuff but
the hype market which is the general
consumer who grows six or ten plants who
doesn't want anything to do with
males they don't want anything to do
with pinot hunting stuff that they don't
know
and so if they recognize it and they can
pop it and they can grow it real quick
and smoke it and they like it that seems
to be where it's at so
washers
yeah
yeah that's for real i mean people
people only see what we present like out
front and i always talk about this like
a lot of it is smoking mirrors like
there's a few of us who don't care to
front like we're rich or famous you know
that are just farmers
but a lot of people it's all smoke and
mirrors and they present like they're
[ __ ] flexing [ __ ]
blinging chains and [ __ ] if you're
wearing a gold chain and like going to
all these events everywhere you're
probably not doing much growing because
most of us are tied to the [ __ ] row
you know what i mean um
yeah smoke and mirrors is a lot and
behind the scenes ever since covet there
are there are seed makers and breeders
alike you know they'll message me and
tell me that this is they're scared for
their future and they don't know who to
talk to and it's it's hard so i don't
have any answers because i [ __ ] i i'm
the same spot as all them you know um
but it is what it is and people get the
market that they pay for and eventually
the people that that have that small
niche market of the the two percent that
want something unique that like running
seeds to find their own unique thing
that's not enough to hold over the whole
market so eventually some something's
gonna have to change or or we have to
change to
yeah reflect the market
yeah no i know i'm i'm struggling like
really bad right now like yeah
i'm kind of worried like if i'll have
enough money for my bills next month
kind of thing you know
there's there's a lot going on in the
world
there's a lot of potential in the world
right now what's going on with all these
countries coming online
and i'm just like man i hope i can just
get by long enough to where i can get to
a spot where i can be okay but yeah i
don't even know if i'll ever make it to
that you know
yeah there's definitely a lot of soul
searching going on
in the weed community right now
you know about what what works and you
know i think there's a natural human
instinct to like get good at a certain
niche or a certain aspect of something
and keep doing it and you just want that
to continue
right because it works for you and
you're good at it and then life throws
you curveballs and
you know um one of the cool things about
like the 215 era was how diverse it was
how many different people could be
involved on different levels and make a
living
and now it's getting consolidated and
you know
the amount of people that used to make a
living off it are probably not going to
make a living off at that that time
so how do you fit in how do you work how
do you survive how do you make it happen
you know and that's the thing is i'm
noticing that i don't fit into the new
world like i've tried to get jobs
numerous times at these new
facilities or these new operations that
are licensed and
i'm either not getting hired or i'm
getting ghosted once i get there
or i show up and it's so [ __ ] up i
leave
yeah
and so
yeah i i'm to the point now where
i'm like i'm gonna go take a job doing
delivery or doing something else and
just grow my hobby weed on my own and
just be like [ __ ] the weed world
but i'm still like still trying to hold
on you know i i've retired from the fact
that
i will not be a licensed company
yeah walton's cannabis company
that's what that video a few months back
was i'm i'm retiring i'm getting the
[ __ ] out of this i'm done with it
and i kind of
misled people in the fact that i was
getting out of the weed world i was just
saying i'm retiring from trying to be a
company like a licensed company
um yeah
it it sounded great like early on you
know like oh the wheat people can
finally they would have been ones who've
been fighting for this to make it legal
fighting for legalization
finally get to grow we finally get to
grow safely not get guns put to our head
not end up in prison and that's rad and
then that was all just
yanked out from under us i mean there's
a there's an aspect too with that where
you know i mean maybe some of the
pricing was risk factor
and a willingness to take risks and a
willingness to have some balls to do
some of that stuff and yeah you know and
so as the risk goes out so does some of
the probability and then the margins get
tighter on things and you know the other
part of it is you know when we were
talking about hype things is
part of it for
older growers is that all of the skill
sets that kept us alive and safe for a
long time are starting to change
so we wanted to be invisible we wanted
to be low-key i mean when you when we
were talking earlier on the beginning of
the show i mean he's he basically you
crawled out from under your rock like
2014 2015
right not that long you know like so you
were growing a long time and hiding
and staying quiet and now the people
that are doing you know somewhat better
are really loud
and really out there and really
promoting themselves and that's not the
skill set most of us had
yeah right self-promotion like we wanted
the work to speak for you
and then people were like well [ __ ] the
work i'll just say i have it
yeah and then i'll get people believing
it's i do
right and you see my gold chain right
you see my gold chain shows i did the
work but you know honestly that type of
thing where you go to like a cookies
opening or something like that and
there's various people standing there
and like they you know they want to
think like they want their breeder hero
to be a baller
yeah there's an aspect of that people do
that because they're making money off
the image of being a baller breeder
yeah
it's the car salesman mentality is most
people want to be sold on something and
be convinced that it's going to change
their life
and that way they can go then do the
kardashian thing and show it the [ __ ]
off and be like look what i [ __ ] got
you know you know what you know it's
fine i'll give you guys a good story
that i heard the other day so one of our
close friends um his his property almost
burned down up in humble area and
he he's
he's a he's more rotund like me shorter
and uh that [ __ ] was swimming
across lakes to water his plants yeah
rivers like a madman like and and this
is probably one of the most successful
people in our in our industry and he
didn't think twice about going and
jumping in a [ __ ] river to go water
his plants daily just because it was all
you know sectioned off he couldn't drive
up there now that's and like i heard you
say too like yeah if it's all done then
i'll just grow my hobby girl and that's
that like
we don't stop but the
people who love weed but it's not gonna
stop ever the thing is
is on that level right it's that the
part that annoys the [ __ ] out of me
is like the the way that they've
you know it almost makes me like talk
about like maybe i'll get on my soapbox
here for a second and get pissed off but
there's an aspect where it's to me it's
not really been made legal
it's been made like taxed and regulated
right yes because
like if it was fully legal then
you know theoretically speaking let's
say like all the money went out of it
okay for whatever reason and all three
of us on this podcast tonight i had to
go out and get different jobs
but if i could grow half my backyard
with a bunch of different things from my
seeds and make seeds and trade amongst
other friends and enthusiasts and share
cuttings and all that
not commercially but just because we
cared right yeah
now you're talking about like the
heirloom vegetable market before it got
popular
yeah
when it was just a bunch of enthusiasts
with going to like weird shows that
nobody went to
about wheat about about tomatoes or
about zucchinis or about squash now it's
all the rage heirlooms yeah but then you
know think about how many decades those
people kept all of those old heirloom
you know varieties
before the popularity came back
so
you know the way i look at it is like
six plants is an insult because that
means that you can't breed at home
that's exactly what that means you need
a license to breed weed you can't be
real i mean if you're going to be a
hobby breeder you can probably get away
with it realistically speaking but like
it's not legal
where you can just like you know control
the sale of it if you want
yeah right but think about how much cool
[ __ ] you could do there's a lot of
there's a lot of weed people that just
love wheat
and they would grow weed even if it
didn't have a financial benefit
like a summer garden
yeah
you know for for real but you can't
because you can only have six [ __ ]
plants so they want you to go to a
dispensary and buy them
yeah
you know any breeder knows you can't
crack six seeds and get anywhere on any
kind of project you want to do
no not really not if you really care not
to make progress yeah not if you really
care want to make progress no so it's
not really like i've gotten to the point
where i don't even really like
discussing it is legal weed
because i look there's no i'm i can go
to the liquor store and how much money i
have in my pocket i can buy as much
liquor as i want
yeah right i can buy
booze beer i can buy dom perry on i can
buy kegs and kegs kegs and kegs i can
fill a whole garage in my house with it
i can give it out to friends i can share
i can throw a party in my backyard and
have a hundred people over and give it
away for free
so like when weed it gets treated like
alcohol or vegetables i'll start
thinking of it as legal
yeah i like what ring said right here he
said the lack of cash has only
reinforced how much everyone who is
getting out of it was into it to begin
with yeah we him and i have been joking
about it actually because we don't we
don't live very far from each other at
all and we both moved to mendo when it
was kind of like depressed and weird
and so you saw this enormous green rush
rush in for the money
yeah and now as the money's been really
hard the last two or three years you see
like the reverse green rush
where
most of them didn't want to live there
unless they could make a bunch of easy
money
yeah
yeah for sure
you know so
humble oh my god southern humble isn't
like in such bad shape right it is it
makes me nervous like for the first time
ever
like i think the the triangle might get
has been cut off to the point where it
could actually suffocate
yeah it's coming together right there
trinity southern humble mendo the way
that everything got built up the
structure of how people cut deals with
each other and grew weed and all the
various aspects it's an enormous danger
anybody see the dark horse breeding
facility what the [ __ ] are they gonna do
with that he buys all his seeds from
breeders
sorry i mean people might people might
not want to know this or whatever and
this might be dissing them or whatnot
but i'll say it anyway darkheart is one
of them and
but there was a number of early
nurseries that became nurseries because
they were so bad at growing flower that
their flower even in the 215 era was
hard to move through anywhere
and so when you're when you're growing a
bunch of warehouses in the bay of b and
c grade indoor
like a few of these companies flipped
into clones because that was just easier
right because they couldn't grow good
bud and then they take bad health
practices
and they spread
viruses and diseases all over california
before anybody had an idea of what was
going on
yeah speaking of which speaking of which
let me plug this in real quick on
september 9th we are going to be having
um
the people i'm not going to say their
name because people just snipe everyone
on shows i guess but
um the the the foremost experts on the
hopslate and viroid um doing studies out
of peru and they're [ __ ] killing it
so we're gonna have them on to cover
and try to
figure out all this [ __ ] and it's gonna
happen it's gonna be a really cool show
because there's a lot of of uh
maybe we'll call it we've called it bro
science yes uh there's a lot of
ineffective sterilization ideas out
there and there's a lot of ways that
people don't understand how it moves
around and how clean practices work and
you know when we all got started in the
90s you could have one razor blade it
was like the most unprotected like
carefree you basically use the razor
blade until it got dull
yeah and now it's almost like you want
to be like a tattoo artist
where you've got clean clean tools for
every single every single tattoo you're
giving so every single plant
right if you really don't want to spread
things
you have to kind of take that sort of
like
that new approach
yeah and we're still learning a bunch
about it honestly
yeah so i just wanted to put that in
there it's it'll be an excellent episode
and
we'll try to uncover some of the myths
going around like it being transmissible
in seed if that's a fact if it's not you
know there's all kinds of stuff
i was working with a
plant scientist from brazil
on at a nursery in redwood valley last
year and she was
working on hops thyroid
and other plants for quite a few years
prior to getting into cannabis and she
was saying that it was a 20
transmissible
through
breeding into seeds
in other
varieties of plant species and so she
was assuming that it would also transfer
over into cannabis as well
from what they've seen there's been zero
transmission in cannabis as far as uh
the cannabis species it was and and with
hemp it was eight percent
transmissibility or six or something
something very low but in cannabis for
some reason it's not they're not seeing
any so we can hope that it's gonna stay
that way or maybe it's just undetectable
with what our tools are currently but i
guess we're gonna see i mean a viroid is
even tinier than a virus
yes but you're really that's what makes
it so hard to kill you're really talking
hard it's not even like a living thing
it's almost like a cult it's like a
collection of it's like a little piece
of data floating around waiting to
attach to the right thing
yeah um a district i just watched it
this morning and the experts and they
said eight percent so somebody
did i hear correctly that um
dark dark heart nurse or a dark
horse yeah and not so trans drag dark
horse for dark heart i did i did i said
i was slow i i don't know what happened
but that's where i went i'm getting i'm
getting the facts from scientists
district that's
uh
i heard they're going out of business is
that correct oh i i did hear that but
i'm not sure but yeah i did hear that
okay yeah i wasn't sure i didn't know if
that was a rumor or if that was for real
or not they said they came up
they said they came up with a cure uh or
a treatment program yes um and then
other you know other opposing nurseries
bought plants from them and still had
and still had the viroid
well i mean they supplied the viroid and
passed the vibroid massively so they had
to come up with the solution so they
could make money off it again and then
it got [ __ ] yeah well then promoting
that new um
non-breedable clone stock
yeah they're yeah
kind of like like corn where
all the corn farmers you can't breed
that corn you gotta buy seed every year
yeah because it's not readable and i
heard that's what darkheart was doing
they just announced that like a month
ago well there's a yeah there's an
aspect right now and i think this is
probably going to be like a big deal in
the next 10 to 20 years
where like if you're gonna have this
industry that's gonna be worth billions
and billions of dollars nationwide
they just can't accept that like
all of these strains right now are
basically open source
people are going to want to lock that
[ __ ] in
and you're going to want to control
things
and they're going because you guys know
everybody every breeder knows right you
can make chili verde or nl5 haze or
punchy blue whatever you know any any
strange name as soon as you sell it it's
out
right and you don't control it anymore
people can buy it from you people can
make their own seeds people can sell
their own seeds you know people could he
you know he could make a deal with a
nursery to like have verified chili
verde and another nursery could buy a
hundred of clones and grow up all those
moms and start selling them and he has
nothing to do with it
so once you release things into the into
the world they're gone
oh yeah you know in that regard and so
people don't like you know corporations
and and big companies they don't like
that they like like uh you know uh
intellectual property if you will
and so it's really weird because you
know
you know there's an argument where it's
like there's companies going around
right now trying to make like uh
marketing deals with various collectors
and breeders to get old stock
yeah right and then that person would
get kickbacks but who should get a
kickback for it
a lot of that time
i've never seen anybody really be paid a
kickback yet
but i'm just saying like
people are kicking around ideas but all
that is all that's coming all that's
going to try to be more standardized
you know you know maybe i would've
offered royalties on chili birdie
through
like dark heart a few other places
and but it was on the stipulation that i
had a
state license
and that i was then going to sell them
the one clone first and then
from then they could give me royalties
back on everything yeah but you better
be licensed you better be licensed huh
but that's what i mean right so let's
say they make a deal with you and every
clone
that they sell of that thing they give
you a percentage
but i buy 500 clones from them and i
take it to my nursery and i don't have
any deal with that and i start selling
thousands of clones of chili bear day a
month and none of that residual goes to
him
yeah because i don't have a deal with
him i just bought this thing from a
nursery i don't owe anybody anything i
own it now it's mine
yeah you can suck it
so that's been a problem the whole time
and it actually is like
back in the day it's it's to some degree
why one of the reasons why a lot of
breeders started not wanting to tell you
what's in their work
because they didn't want people to know
that it's like they wanted it to be
secret sauce because they didn't have
any control over it
once you release it
it's out there it's gone
you know in the last few seed sessions
that we've had
seat swaps up in southern humble
um i've seen an influx of people coming
in
that are from out of the area and they
literally go and buy seed from every
single [ __ ] person at the whole
entire place
and they buy
everything of what that person has and
then they walk out with a whole box full
of seeds and i'm like
that's not what you normally see
yeah like you know what i mean
yeah um because we've been running those
swaps up there for a couple yeah that's
an anomaly dude yeah three or four years
we were doing these flops and then there
was always locals coming in doing a
little bit of trading maybe buying a few
speeds here and there but nothing like
that and then yeah last this last six
months or so i was just watching these
people come in and i'm like
they're they're collecting for
somebody big
yeah what the [ __ ] you know one of these
big farms out there that are just
getting geared up to go to you know go
public
yeah
but it's that it's that thing where it's
like it we've got decades of i hope it
all stays open source
i hope it's pretty punk rock in that
regard and it's like
i'm not saying that like in the future
they might not lock things in where they
can put like genetic markers into
certain breeding lines where you can
tell it's from that but i basically
think that like everything from the
beginning of cannabis to 2018 or 19
should be it's it's just out there
yeah but
honestly you know and it might be shitty
for some people but it's like
otherwise everyone's going to lock it in
and control it and then people are going
to that's that's what will happen is
people get sued like monsanto you know
right now the us is
like gonna be one of the last like we're
way behind because like if you look at
like colombia right now columbia is
already on the move to do that they're
already looking at licensing and holding
on to these genetics and calling them
there and being set up for worldwide
distribution
and so
the us is lagging and yeah in one regard
um
of
being on top of licensing these genetics
and we are we will stay open sourced
here for a long time because of the lack
of
the government
wanting to really
open up ganja here i think the entire
market in colombia
is just kind of kicking around getting
started hoping that america opens up
that that's real i think i think that a
lot of these people that are going to
third world countries right now and
these other places trying to set up shop
are trying to have their roots in
if it goes federal so they can im they
can export from this place that doesn't
have osha and doesn't have this and
doesn't have that i think that's really
what it is is that they're not down
there to try to make a bunch of money in
colombia
like that's cool if it happens but
they're hoping that our market opens
yeah you know thailand's kind of
interesting right now to see what's
going on there because they've just
opened up hemp
and
um they're letting everybody sell it
just open them anywhere and there's no
age limit on it
but everybody's already growing ganja
they're using like kind of how we did
with the cbd thing
they're selling weed
as hemp
and so
but it's supposed to be for export only
you're really not supposed to be
consuming it and yeah so i'm kind of
curious to see how that's going to go
but i'm already seeing
i've already seen
two or three u.s companies
feed companies that are already there
and i'm like
how does how did that work out like how
did you do that
so well get get us there buddy get us
there
yeah you know
um
if i can make some money over the next
two months or so i want to go to
thailand for a while my wife or my
fiance is there waiting for me
and um
yeah that could be something big for me
you know
i'm looking forward to that i haven't
seen it so everyone watching let's
support our homeboy and get him to
thailand see what's up there i mean this
is one of the dudes who will actually go
chase down land races and stuff so it's
beneficial for all of us to get in there
yeah yeah i'm looking at getting over
there um
my so i have a fiancee that's from
thailand
a couple years ago
she lost her visa
mostly because of what i do and who i am
yeah
and so they sent her back and i haven't
seen her in almost three years but
that's sad
yeah and getting my passport was a
nightmare
um
i had some problems when i was younger
living on the border yeah and the first
time i applied for my passport they
denied me
then they gave me coveted [ __ ] they
got lost and so it took me almost two
years to get my passport and i finally
got it and now i'm ready to go
but yeah now i just have to make a
little bit of money so i can afford to
go
yeah finances moving up moving in in
state moving in cities expensive as [ __ ]
i can't even imagine moving out of the
country how expensive that is
yeah um i'm not sure if i can actually
move full time because i have to go over
there
we'll get married
then i can apply for a marriage visa
yeah she'll open it up for trying to get
dual citizenship
and then i could move there but i
wouldn't be able to stay there full time
unless the thai government approved it
and i heard that's kind of really
difficult
yeah
yeah we'll see how it goes
yeah i i dude i watched 90 day fiance
man that shit's crazy with the the
passports and immigration and all that
stuff between countries it's insane dude
yeah you know everybody keeps telling me
i need to watch that show but i don't
dude
but i'm like i'm living it so yeah dude
yeah
a lot of it on that show is sex tourism
so it's just like the craziest
[ __ ] doing the crazy [ __ ] but
every once in a while there's good
people on there and it's it's crazy what
they put them through yeah awesome cool
cool yeah you know my my fiance she's
amazing um i look forward to getting
over there she's she's a good woman
yeah she sounds like especially if you
took such a big hit for you like that's
that's a partner man that's part of it
yeah yeah we made the mistake of um
i sent her some pictures on her phone of
the farm when she was gonna come stay
with me when she got the customs they
went through her phone and found the
pictures and were like uh yeah no
oh no
something that small really oh yeah yeah
i had i i've had i've had trimmers that
would fly in that work that that worked
a long time that worked for me for years
and sometimes when the smartphone era
happened
um they can absolutely look through
everything they want uh and then see if
they want to let you in
yeah not so used to flying men in from
amsterdam constantly and they would
check their phones man
horrible horrible
but yeah they do they will look i mean
it's it's uh
uh
you know american is sort of like the
gold standard passport to travel around
but we're not the easiest most welcoming
place to get into for lots of countries
especially in the last two three years
it's gotten to where they don't
they don't want to let anybody in
it's really difficult yeah so free free
movement of people hasn't been the
easiest
yeah
but was there anything else you want to
want to cover tonight like is there any
projects uh we haven't talked about that
you want to talk about
um
i've been doing some collaborations with
uh ryan over at wallflower nursery uh
radio
ryan's been helping me out tremendously
him and eva are amazing people
um they're kind of basically holding my
my stock my genetics for me because i
yeah they got all our [ __ ] man i love
them i do love them
ryan is a good person they are yes they
they're they're good people
and this is radio ridge that i i refer
to often while flower radio rich right
yeah wall flower
wildflower is radio ridge yes yes yeah
so
so yeah i've been working with ryan he
um helping me on this collaboration with
the spams and
so yeah it's been really good um but
like i said just the last few months
have been really difficult um
financially
so
yeah it is what it is i try not to get
down too much but i'm one of those
depressed kind of people already so it's
like
dude this far into the weed game if
you're not jaded then you're not
realistic with yourself i mean
you know it's positive failure
no matter what you do well you know if i
was if i was
more into being self-promoting and being
one of these guys who who's on the
internet
like just blowing myself up and
constantly
being there
i'd be way better off but i'm one of
those guys that like
i haven't been online and when people
come at me i'm like it is what it is
this is buy it or don't buy it i don't
give a [ __ ] yeah so that's not the
greatest sales technique yeah
i have that issue too yeah like trying
to trying to like push yourself you feel
like you use car salesmen like these
seats are great uh i felt like a [ __ ]
slime ball so what's a [ __ ] point
yeah it's hard man it's hard
yeah
and then um yeah so
but yeah that's that's pretty much
what's going on with me i'm just focused
on trying to to get to thailand and then
um
after that [ __ ] i don't i don't know
do you after that it's kind of up in the
air so
um someone real quick someone asked if
your uh cream is good for eczema his son
has eczema it is it's very good for
eczema um depending on the condition of
the eczema it can take
anywhere from
a couple weeks to a couple months to see
improvement
um but uh yeah i've had very good
success with eczema
very cool very cool hopefully that helps
us uh yeah the cocoa cream not not the
tiger not the not the cinnamon there you
go cocoa cream cocoa remember that
you want to do you want to do your end
of the night spiel mat
yeah um and you can find all that at hpk
topgolf.com is there a good place for
people to find your seeds
uh seeds yeah so there's a couple
couple seed banks that sell my stuff um
or you can go through me directly but if
you want to go through a bank there's
immaculate seeds there's penal paradise
um there's dagus dagalov
and then
um neptune some of neptune's
sub banks carry my stuff but i'm not
sure exactly which ones
okay
and so yeah or just contact me directly
and from time to time i'll throw some
stuff up on my website as well
um
you're more more likely to get cool
extras and [ __ ] if you buy from breeders
direct like breeders directly like they
you know so hit him up
yeah yeah i'm always pretty good about
throwing in a bunch of extras and yeah
about it but i'm old school like
it's still
you gotta
call me
yeah indeed indeed all right and we have
our breeder syndicate patreon where we
all hang out uh come join us uh we have
three different chairs we have like a 5
15 and 50. they all come with different
stuff the five gets you into the discord
and that's where we all hang out and
shoot the [ __ ] i think there's some
fights we're watching tomorrow um he has
the instagram handle it's hpk genetics
isn't that right
yes
hbk genetics on instagram everybody give
the man a follow he's been a good friend
of mine for a long time um i appreciate
having him here uh it's good to see you
eric and thank you for spending time
with everyone yeah and we we appreciate
everybody's friday night we appreciate
everybody chatting come chat with us on
the discord uh you can always dm and
reach out to us uh and we're always
appreciative for listening
yep that's about it yeah uh
check you guys later thanks for coming
eric you guys have a good night