[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
ER Syndicate where we explore the
history of a clan destined scene Through
The Eyes of the folks who lived it I'm
Matthew owner of Riot seeds I'll
occasionally be joined by my co-host not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
welcome to the underground
hello everyone welcome to breeder
Syndicate
um where we cover strain history my
guest today is the Rev from Kingdom of
organic seeds welcome brother nice to
see you
thanks man good to be here a long time
we haven't talked so we're going to
catch up a lot on uh everything you've
been doing everything that you've done
for the people who are new to you and
where we're going from there so let's
start off dude like what started the The
Rev on his cannabis Adventure
well I guess I was about this has been
about 1975 I guess you know I planted my
first weed ever and my mom ended up
killing it right right
me out you know
so I was so pissed that my beautiful
plants got killed I had about a half a
pound baggie about a quarter full of
seeds yeah I went out in the backyard
the next day and I just spread them
everywhere right so so a dichondra lawn
of cannabis came up I bet germs freaked
out and we eventually struck a deal
where I could grow four plants oh wow
they they gave in yeah well I just
overrode them you know yeah dude and uh
so I was jazzed about that so I grew up
my mom's backyard for a couple years
after that just you know I was an idiot
I didn't know what I was doing but I
grew some giant freaking plants you know
I bet and uh then you know my dad he was
a hydroponic experiment scientist guy he
loved Hydroponics oh wow one was on the
other end of the scale she's fully
organic I mean you know as organic as
you could be back in 1970s yeah now so
they each had their own input to me so I
learned Hydroponics really well really
fast the whole dynamic of it and my mom
taught me Organics and the first thing I
did of course was I flopped into
Hydroponics and you know started uh
Building Systems and designing them and
uh that worked out really good and I
look back now at that and I think man we
really sure thought we had some great
buds back then but I won't even touch a
synthetic grown Bud these days I mean do
you remember those old catalogs from
Scentsy seeds like the pictures the buds
back then just all chewed up and rotten
yeah
yeah dude it was a different time man
well I hope there's no difference
because of my organ my uh hydroponic
knowledge right I had met these guys in
Northern California and uh they were
super interested in Hydroponics they
didn't know anything about Hydroponics
and they wanted to know big time oh I
bet so it was kind of a marriage made in
heaven right there I got together with
them they agreed to teach me their ways
and they were breeders and Growers and
uh if I would teach them Hydroponics so
I mean that couldn't have worked out
better yeah no kidding apprenticeship
made in heaven yeah
so what kind of stuff were you seeing
around then was it mostly Mexican stuff
that was coming in import no no these
guys had connection with uh the Surfers
right around the world like a several
Pro Surfers so they were hooked up with
some really Prime genetics that's why
when people nowadays tell me
um you know the weed now is so much more
strong well as a whole yeah but not if
you're a selector and you find a a clone
of something like Blue Mountain Jamaican
or something you know something from
Hawaii something picked and selected it
was just it was incredible weed Ty oh my
God yeah see I always hear these stories
about the old ties and that's why I've
always kind of chased them I looked up
to you and I was you know getting into
breeding and growing up and I was like
wow this dude's super into Thai I want
to see what this is about I love Thai
yeah yeah it's a special it's a special
region that produce just I don't know if
it was the region that produced the
incredibly special plants or the farmers
were just better at it or how it worked
plants from different regions are kind
of similar sometimes it's like Central
Americans are kind kind of close to
Southeast Asians you know they have a
lot in common yeah where like Colombians
and South Americans are have some
similarities with South Africans and
Africans like the rui BART right from
South Africa and uh like a Colombian red
a good a good strong real Colombian red
they're very similar it would be tough
to tell them apart by high time and I've
always tripped out about that you know I
thought well there must have been some
boats going around exchanging genetics
way back then yeah you wonder about like
maybe they were just you know similar
equator similar elevation [ __ ] like that
yeah yeah and I think the genes are
similar too because I mean you can grow
you can have something like a Durban
Poison from South Africa that is Miles
different than a rui Bard or a Colombian
oh sure you know but but there are there
are strange similarities across the
table that always make me wonder what
happened in the past how they got there
yeah no kidding man that I've seen some
pretty weird ones like uh there's a lot
of that terpinoline in a lot of
Colombians but in a lot of Mexicans
there's skunkiness and you think there
would have been a lot of trade going up
and down through there but they did keep
their own little separate divisions too
it's wild and they're you know they're
they're those like the Mexicans
especially they're uh they're like the
South Africans too in a way is that at
first you know when people are looking
for all the terpenes that looking for
the smells and the flavors they're
always like oh this smells like lemon oh
well that's super common at the early
stages of flowering right yeah a lot of
sativas to smell that way they don't
really start to put their real smelly
legs on until at least halfway through
so what were some of the first lines
that you were um making crosses of what
were some of the first crosses even
before braiding just to first like
oh my God
let's see God you know what I
the first ones I find it hard to
remember I remember I had a uh I
remember I had a tackle box oh yeah the
cops got that I haven't I had a tackle
box just full of a big one labeled just
full of all kinds of I wish I could
remember some of them now but damn I
just I just can't it's mostly Regional
varieties yeah some of them are
reasonable some of them I got from
France some of them I got you know
online having to read the catalog and
mail and go yeah yeah and then uh let's
see when was it that when sea Bay came
online around that time okay
yeah yeah when they came online I
started really digging on the
availability of online stuff and of
course you know you run the risk of crap
but oh yeah I found some real gems back
then just popping around talking to
people there was crap too but still I
mean is that is that the error that you
got the metal Haze
yeah that wasn't from Dutch Flowers yeah
it was and in fact you know you and I
were talking about the having to select
things Southeast Asians like Hayes is
right yes and uh that that metal Haze it
was funny because if I recall I got uh I
think I got six or eight females out of
a ten pack and pretty much most of them
were average and okay yeah a couple of
them were better than okay and then that
one they're like oh my God you know I
mean it just it stood out like a beacon
so yeah that was lucky really that was
lucky because really you usually have to
go through a lot more than that yeah
yeah
yeah especially in Haze varieties
because it's just so much any any
sativa that has like mostly a land race
history is going to be a real good
selection because wild plants keep their
options open you know yeah they sure do
big genotype on reserve to tap so they
they don't really unless they're super
super old like like the Deep chunk or
Panama Red or Thai some things like that
yeah they're just they're set in their
ways just like old people they aren't
changing yeah yeah deep chunks perfect
for that yeah you know they're just
they're real they're real acclimated to
whatever environment they were inbred
500 times into or whatever exactly deep
chunk just loves the Mendo and that's it
you know like the Mendo outdoor is
perfect for it people have big problems
with it when their pH usually runs low
oh really you know yeah because uh you
know it won't tolerate a normal pH if
your pH runs six eight six seven you're
gonna have small issues with it your pH
has to be up around seven for it to
really kick ass that's awesome I didn't
even know that part I've had trouble
with it on and off in the past yeah I
guess it's because it's from the desert
basically yeah that makes sense so it's
used to a lot of minerals probably a
super high soil PH with pretty low
organic content so yeah it makes a
little bit of sense yeah it sure does
um so what was let's let's let's talk
about the first strain that you actually
started breeding breeding a line you
started working
damn I think I used
I think I had a
damn I really just can't remember yeah
how old are you son I'm 62. I've been
doing this for half a century I know I
guess it gets harder over time you know
over the years it's gotten a lot harder
for me to remember some of the earlier
years it used to be just like damn bam
no just just wait till you pass 55
brother I know I can't I'm already I'm
all about walking in the kitchen and
going what am I doing
[Laughter]
it's like a mad scientist thing around
here I got
I got sticky notes at my Google
Calendars busy all day long you know oh
you know that's [ __ ] to remind me of
what the [ __ ] I'm doing all the time see
I haven't even gotten to the point of
utilizing that so I just forget and say
[ __ ] it and go smoke again I just I give
up oh man I can't do that because you
know when I'm when I'm so especially if
I'm selecting like I am now yeah if I
screw up even once man now I have now I
have a whole new set of variables I have
to take into account that's true you
know I mean it's like I can't tell you
how many people I visit they're trying
to select a clone that'll have like a
closet or a small area of plants right
and they'll be like yeah well I'm gonna
kill these three because they're not
doing well and I'll be like wait a
minute
you know your fan is blowing extra
strong on those three back plants so
really happening is they're dehydrating
faster they're needing water sooner so
the reason they look shitty isn't
genetics you got to understand the
environment around them right yeah
that's like selecting in veg like
culling in veg like oh it doesn't grow
well it could be the one that's the most
potent we're going for effect not for
structure in veg you know if you're
super familiar with the line like I am
with most of that one yeah because I'm
like the embodiment of Tasmania or uh
the Galapagos Islands right I have a
pretty sealed gene pool yeah you do I
don't walk outside of my gene pool very
often so it works out really good for me
yeah I mean that's that's one of the
best ways to truly learn your lines and
to master a line to really really get it
into I mean for lack of better word to
master it to get that bug grown to its
best Expressions to where you're
familiar and you know I use marker
Expressions on lines I'm real familiar
with like my own lines I've worked with
a lot I know if uh if I have a square
petiole right on this one I know that
that that is a link Gene to something I
either want or don't want as an example
right okay so I can select early I can
wipe out a lot of planets I know I don't
want early write in veg with things I'm
familiar with so for people listening
like a linked trait could be like you
see at least certain Leaf mutations so
you know that in that line it happens to
also denote another trait right and a
lot of times a lot of times it gets a
lot deeper than that like patterns of
leaf hairs the patterns that they form
in certain places on the plants one of
my one of my favorite things to do to be
able to check plants early is uh I look
at those you know the little round I
forget what they're called coital zones
or whatever
on the Sprouts right yeah those are uh
those are some of my favorites when I
catch the plants about a week up above
ground I always take a 30 times scope
and look really close at those those
leaves and look at the density of the
leaf hairs now what that does is since
Leaf hairs and trichomes are pretty much
exactly the same just a little tiny move
on the planet different I then know
which is most dense which can have the
most dense trichomes right from go this
helps me a ton for males so if I'm
selecting a male from something I'm a
little familiar with or not that
familiar with I can get a good grip on
how what my potential is in my males to
to pass off heavy resin production with
the female for The Offspring right yeah
that gives me my first little marker so
I can you know do that hang on I'm gonna
grab all right okay all right
that reminds me I got one too
there we go
that's something I can never never even
considered that's amazing
I'm glad you like it yeah the leader the
leafer things are big I use them to
judge a lot of things and it's like um
most people go right to the leaves they
look at like leave formations Leaf
whatever some some aspect expression of
the leaf yeah those work good those were
good for a lot of things but the problem
is with different environments and with
any strain especially a hybrid if it's
not an IBL yeah it'll throw out just on
the notch it'll throw out different
morphologies different resin values you
know because it's still testing the
water it's a hybrid yeah right that's
what it's doing it's getting a grip on
the world
yeah and and in today's society we know
like almost everything's a poly poly
poly poly hybrid in the cookie worlds
unless you're yeah unless you have a a
nice sealed environment away from that
kind of BS like yours well you know My
worry is I it's not that I think
anything is particularly bad or
particularly good in in the recent 20
years or so but the problem I have is is
it's is it's useless for me to try to
run down the origin of some type of
genetics that I get because I'm involved
with two or three people at least with
one or two of them at least have just
gotten it decide to rename it something
else and maybe embellish on the history
so I just I just don't trust anything I
hear now so I have my uh my Galapagos
Islands gene pool that I went man I got
a lot of seeds from a long time ago I'm
just working through them now like I
told you recently I just got a g I just
got some G13 haze from Soma to pop
30 years old oh yeah I bet those are
that's a really good line too I think
that's where they found the the CBD
stuff a lot of the the CBD bases is for
cannotonic and stuff like that was in
someone's G13 Haze well the haze would
definitely have some CBD yeah yeah right
but yeah because it's not just the resin
production you know I mean a lot like
with uh let me think of it oh like let's
take a Congo for example okay several
times I've seen Congos that suck right
yeah several times I've seen Congos that
look like they'd be okay you know it's
like a real dark spooky looking bud but
you don't see much resin you know just
and it will kick your ah I mean bad
right yeah and if you were to chop that
butt in half and look at it you would
see that it forms this different it's
resin different than an Indica would you
know a lot of the indicas were bred to
make hash right yeah so they always
wanted the resin spread out all over the
whole plant so they could all extract it
with hash yep sativas are a lot
different especially some of the really
Wild Ones yeah it's their resin
production as you get closer to the core
of the flower to protect it from the
weather basically is what they do for
but that's why you can have a sativa
that to your naked eye you can go oh
yeah that looks alright and it will lay
you out yeah I mean you look at a lot of
these old sativas I was looking at some
Highland Thai bud I had from Bodhi save
and if you look at it like if I guess if
a modern person that like in the that
started growing in the
2020s looked at it they wouldn't even
understand what to smoke on it because
it's almost all Leaf you know there's no
floral density to it whatsoever yeah
yeah no we had those a matter of fact
when I went to Northern California they
had just gotten pretty flush with those
exactly yeah right those the ones from
Afghanistan and the Mideast that were
not really buds right they were just
like Leaf bud
florets or something yeah yeah yeah and
uh and they were just covered in resin
you know just these big non-dense
flowers just soaked with resin
Jesus
so let's talk about some of your lines I
mean you've made a lot of I mean so many
lines over the years what are your
flagships is the uh what is it the Blue
Rhino 1947 love it let's talk about that
one it's one of your Staples when I when
we first started talking I think that
was one of the big ones you were working
with man I still love it it's one of my
favorite go-to smokes of all time it's
it's kind of heavy on the Indica side
but you wouldn't know it by smoking it
because it doesn't really relate that
kind of sleepy side too much yeah it
doesn't give you munchies too much but
what it does do is it reminds me a lot I
I've mentioned Bhutan earlier as it
reminds me of some boots and knees right
that have this this resin profile where
the high type is like I don't know how
to describe it other than it's golden
and happy right everything is like
golden and you're happy and that's what
the Blue Rhino does the blue Ryan 1947
does for me but its most unique property
that I have found in nothing else is
that I have some I have a lot of damage
actually but one of my major damage
zones is in my leg right and I took some
really bad nerve damage yeah the problem
is is when I'm up and walking around
because of all that damage along with
bone damage and other stuff but when I'm
up and walking around I have to hold my
muscles in that leg tight right yeah
because any loose if I step down a step
that's not there or something man I'm
done I'm on I'm on a cane for a week I
know what you mean yeah it's bad right
yeah so
the Blue Rhino 1947 after a day when I
lay down to go to sleep of if I'm up and
around right my leg will get spasms when
it relaxes right and that hurts the hell
out of me oh I'm sure if so the Blue
Rhino 1947 I could just puff some of
that and those spasms are just reduced
to a tiny tiny little Rumble that
doesn't hurt at all so while I don't use
it for pain relief directly it
absolutely cures me from the pain I
would be suffering so I always have Blue
Rhino 1947 always also do you think
that's from the blueberry side or what's
in the Blue Rhino it's a blueberry white
rhino and Peak 19 and AK-47 19 and AK-47
that's right right I got the I got the
peak 19 AK-47 from sea Bay many many
many many moons ago do you remember
pardon me do you remember who made that
one I know it's a hybrid Sega math and
something else I do not know who made
that one yeah about you but I use the
Irish Rose version of Blue Rhino very
cool and uh I just crossed them up and
you know
it's a it's an impactive line anyway I
mean the high is impressive but beyond
that I started noticing that stuff with
the Tremors in my leg I went oh there
really is medical marijuana yeah you
know the first time I realized that was
when I had a um uh for myself anyways I
had a uh abscessed tooth an abscess
molar and it was just it was one of
those ones where it was like tears
running down your face it's the only
thing you can feel in your body is that
pain just throbbing and nothing was
working dabs nothing and then I smoked
some very weak blueberry just because I
happen to have it and it completely took
away the nerve pain and I realized oh
this this for me helps with nerve pain
insanely like a whole bunch so I was
wondering if that maybe helped you any
of the blue stuff at first I really
thought it was the blueberry I did for
several years I thought was the
blueberry but then as I started to
inbreed them and mess with them and look
at different ones that were better at
exactly that nerve damage stuff yeah I
noticed that the ones I would select
that would be the best would
morphologically they would look the most
like the peak 19. oh interesting not the
blueberry so I just kind of naturally
made the leap and thought it must be the
peak 19 that's doing it but I could I
could be wrong yeah yeah I don't know I
mean the the blueberries that I've had
usually smell like blueberry the ones
that helps my nerve pain because I have
neuropathy bad and that tends to help me
a lot but I also like when you mentioned
White Rhino like one of my white whales
is White Rhino like a very good White
Rhino cut because I had one it's just
the one time ever that we just made me
see tracers and hallucinate like LSD and
it was White Rhino so man that's a
special line
yeah yeah we used to smoke a ton of
White Rhino when we were out taking care
of stuff outdoors and white rhino works
really good Outdoors because it's also
hardly smelly at all when you grow it
yeah
Let's see we have your Riff Raff tie
which I know is a popular one that's
that's a real great great fruity baby
right there man oh some people are
hunting grapefruit right now people keep
talking about it too oh [ __ ] the
riffraff ties like
you could call it grapefruit I mean you
know I just want people to know that
there was Thai in it yeah but uh and
then it's you know kind of muggled up
not pure tie but I mean damn you talk
about grapefruit that that baby is full
on grass with a cure it just gets ten
times stronger it's radical what's in
the what's in it Riff Raff tie is uh
deep chunk and let's see which tie did I
use
I can't remember if it was the I had
gotten sent from my cousin in Vietnam
and when he sent it to me the the paper
or whatever it was wrapped in said bat
damn bang on it right so I just called
that bad damn bang time that's a good
name too all right and then the other
tie I had that I worked with was from a
breeder that I hooked up with that was
in uh Denmark or Amsterdam and he wanted
to trade me some juicy for a tie oh yeah
for uh something I had I forget what it
was but I was like oh hell yeah
and uh that was legit juicy for a time I
mean it was long flowering smelled just
like Juicy Fruit gum was kick ass so in
the Riff Raff tie I forget which one it
was but it was one of those one of those
two it'll say so in the description yeah
so check this only I had a photographic
memory yeah yeah I see I need one of
those too mine's just damaged damage
damage like Memento me too
so
um if anybody's interested in the
website it's
kingdomorganicsseeds.com definitely go
out go check those out there we want to
talk about some more of your stuff let's
see I know my friend smell boat would
kill me if I didn't ask about the Cherry
tie the chunky Cherry tie yeah now you
know something this I love that for so
many reasons but the the first thing I
really liked about was when I saw The
Offspring I knew because sometimes when
you're working with like it usually
happens with the land race or or an
heirloom long IBL when you pop it into a
hybrid usually what will happen is they
will just merge right it'll the
resulting will be uniform and it will
blend yeah it's pretty uniform in the F1
times that doesn't happen sometimes it's
like they resist each other a little and
you definitely get lots of different
recombinations that's what happened with
the chunky Cherry tie so as soon as I
saw saw some starting to finish at about
10 or 11 weeks and I saw others that had
two more weeks to go I was like oh yeah
I knew and then oh my god when I smoked
them there was one I had that was a
14-week finisher and it was uh so close
to just Thai I mean it was just like
smoking Thai it was slightly different
but not very and so I treasure that one
I still have deep stash buds of that
that's awesome you came in the freezer
it's incredibly like time I mean it's
almost spot on
that's really cool I know um my friend
smell boat used just the Cherry tie part
in his uh rainbow and it's one of his
favorite lines yeah the Cherry Pie yeah
that's one you need a little selection
there but there are one out of four of
those females are just Stellar they're
all good you know you don't have any bad
ones but there's like you know out of
like four females you would probably get
two average ones one really good one and
one Epic one if it spread the if it
spread the bandwidth you know yeah yeah
it's an even distribution of the
Expressions yeah
yeah let's see what else we got we have
um let's talk about
do you remember a string called Uncle
Lucius lemonade I still have Uncle
Lucius lemonade I remember that was a
big hit on skunk Magazine's uh forums
back in the day the Uncle Lucius lemony
all my friends were grabbing them
popping them loving it what was that one
about I've almost popped it here in the
last uh six months I've almost popped it
twice I mean I've had it out and ready
to roll yeah something else came up and
I went oh it had to go a different
direction yeah but I'm definitely going
to rework that again the only problem is
it takes a lot of work like I was
talking to you earlier about if I'm
working with things I'm really familiar
with right like you know blew around a
1947 website I can pop eight if I want
to continue the line I can usually get
away with one wave of eight Sprouts I
can select from there and be good find
everybody I'm looking for yeah maybe I
might have to do that twice but usually
not because I'm familiar with it I know
what I'm looking for exactly so that
works out really good but the Uncle
Lucius lemonade now that's made from
a lemon rack that a friend of mine
brought me in about 2004 I think a lemon
rack clone up from Northern California
up from Willits
um it uh it was an intense train wreck
super lemony it must have developed a
sport mutation or something and it had
become super lemony
okay there we go so but it also had
another couple other weaknesses that may
have come along with the lemony flavor
was it was real weak it had no
structural integrity and stuff yeah so
I crossed it with another heavy hard
hitter the iron Cindy which is a lot
like a train wreck yeah and um so I
crossed it with that to make Uncle
Lucius lemonade now the problem with the
original
uh Uncle Lucius was or with the original
lemon uh lemon wreck was that it had
some Hermes in it right yeah you had to
weed those out and they weren't the easy
kind to weed out they weren't true
Hermes they were the kind you don't find
out until two weeks before yeah those
brutal just just weak breeding right
yeah so uh so I have to fish through
them so now in order to run those and
then breed them I'm gonna need to run 16
Sprouts to start with and and cross my
fingers that I can find what I need in
that run because those are particularly
dangerous first I have to find true
males for sure yeah then I have to find
a female that can take some stress I
have to beat the [ __ ] out of them to
find out who has the least tolerance for
stress so once I find that I will do it
because that is some of the most lemony
stuff man ever I think people run into
that a lot with the train wreck stuff a
lot of um intersex traits and a lot of
like there's even auto flowering traits
in the line somewhere and but man for me
there's not a much better height than
train wreck stuff it's one of those ones
just that I associate with Thai Thai
pies kind of in there that that kind of
make me happy energetic just
yeah time makes me happy and energetic
for sure sometimes it's totally spaced
out depends on how much I smoke but uh
but the train wrecks any train wreck
I've ever smoked I'm not a big fan uh oh
they're potent that's for sure yeah but
they have uh they have a quality to me
that is not dissimilar than when you uh
take something two weeks late you know
how the resin changes yeah yeah that's
that's how they always remind me of I've
even tried taking them a little early
and that doesn't change yeah but you
know it's just it's a personal thing
like you and millions of people love
train wreck yeah they have nothing
against other than the fact that it just
kind of makes me feel yeah like it's
like it's weed that was taken too late I
always get that vibe from it you know
what train wreck people either and it's
kind of like that with Jack hair or two
a little bit maybe it's because of the
Terps maybe it's because of the high too
but it's either people love it or
they're just like man and some people it
makes speedy and paranoid like crazy
paranoid and it just never does it to me
but a lot of afghanis do it to me and
skunk one does it to me but yeah it's
weird oh man you want to see the queen
of paranoid that black forest I have
yeah let's talk about some of the Black
Forest let's talk about that one oh man
I can't tell you how many people I've
sent running for the hills with that
where they go yeah well I do get a
little paranoid I go well I wouldn't
smoke it if I was you if that's the case
right yeah yeah and you know they don't
listen and uh you know they run for the
hills because that thing's just a pure
jungle black Vietnamese who knows how
many
bazillion years old it is across with my
old Cherry Bomb male which God I love
that cross because what was the cherry
bomb that was an F3 out of Hawaii that
was uh it was a combination of about
three or four Hawaiian sativas elephant
ear Puna butter a couple others and it
was crossed with a cherry ak-47. oh wow
that it was inbred a few times to F3 and
it was shared with me under some kind of
top secret you know how the Hawaiians do
they they do they are tight with their
stuff top secret so anyway when I got it
the first thing I noticed the first
couple things I crossed it with is it
was sort of uh it was sort of submissive
you know it would impart larger yields
and it would impart added resin but it
wouldn't really contribute too much to
Terps or or high type or morphology to
any big degree so I really liked it
because I could blend it with almost
anything and it would come out mostly
whatever else was in the hybrid you know
would always be like 80 20 instead of a
50 50. yeah so yeah I love that so
anyway I bled I've read that with the
the with the Vietnamese black which I
got from my cousin back in I don't know
I think it was like maybe the late 80s
or something so you've kept the
Vietnamese blackout law uh line around
that long yeah I still have it I just
popped three a few months ago because I
just inbred the uh I just inbred the uh
Black Forest by getting a mail from the
original V black line oh not using him
to do a soft back cross yeah to to the
Black Forest so now it's like the black
forest runs over anything it crosses
anyway you know ones that flower
16 weeks oh I bet that's got to be so
killer though oh my God but you know
peeps have problems with it because yeah
if you never have flowered a 16 week
plant in a container you may have some
issues yeah yeah people that aren't used
to used to land races and heirloom lines
and long flowering lines indoors you've
really gotta do your homework before you
start flattering them puppies oh yeah
yeah yeah because you know [ __ ] not only
do you have to select the [ __ ] out of
them and keep them over loving them is
the death sentence to them you know yeah
you start trying to pour food on them or
switch their pH faster your bone over
watering all kinds of [ __ ] plus people
people will take them as a common
mistake with a black forest or anything
that's like up 14 weeks or something is
they'll get to about the 10 11 week Mark
and they'll be oh [ __ ] my plant's dying
yeah I need to transplant it well that's
like the worst possible thing you could
do in flowering because suddenly the
plant gets this dose of all kinds of
available nitrogen and [ __ ] so it says
yay time to veg and what that means is
time to reduce resin production yes so
if you're in flowering and you're
reducing resin production well that's
not right yeah counterintuitive as [ __ ]
that's that's how that's why I tell
people you're feeding cannabis not
tomatoes because tomatoes like some
nitrogen in calcium and veg and stuff
but cannabis nitrogen kills resin
production and flour yeah I mean sure
your plant will get really happy and
will start to grow really fast maybe
even mutate growth a little bit but
well it's like with tomatoes like if if
you were overdosing your tomatoes with
nitrogen at the end if you weren't sort
of fading your Tomatoes you'll get
really big gnarly Tomatoes but they'll
have a thick skin yes right yeah super
thick robust thick skin yeah yeah
so one of the lines that I probably
associate with you the most and that I
get asked about the most when people ask
about your lines is iron Cindy
it's basically a haze for my money you
know it's like it's just like a faster
flowering Haze it's a slightly longer
flowering Cindy because Cindy and Haze
have a lot in common Cindy and Southeast
Asian have a lot in common yeah so the
iron the
so that I the metal Haze was kind of a
no-brainer that I wanted to cross with
it you know
it kind of makes a really nice outdoor
plant too for the for the metal Haze a
better frame for it and everything else
so what kind of what kind of Terps are
you seeing in the the iron Cindy is it
did you use a pineapple c99 a grapefruit
what kind do you use it no no I just
used uh I just selected some I think I
used a couple of females for that maybe
more than a couple but I just took some
good cindies and crusted it's hard to
get a bad Cindy yeah the only the only
bad Cindy or every once in a while I
would say one in eight are super small
yielding yeah that's the only really bad
Cindy I've ever seen and that's not bad
it just yields really small yeah but it
probably has heavy resin production yeah
yeah that's funny that's funny too
because you know something in any line
I've ever seen yeah if you have you know
usually they're big fat plants usually
if you get one a a phenotype that has
like let's say 25 percent less yield
yeah it will also have about 25 percent
more potency yeah and resin production
it puts all that energy Elsewhere for
the plant I love I love cannabis I love
how how
just intuitive it is as a as a plant and
how how quickly it adapts everything
everything about the plant it evolves
um a lot of times we talk about on our
show about like expressions and clonal
expression meaning you know a lot of
people used to call it genetic drift but
it's not necessarily a thing but taking
a clone from one environment to another
and watching how quickly it adapts how
quickly it will
change its form even
you my man know the important stuff if
you ask me because that is it now I call
it adaptability as a general yeah
but yeah one of the first things I do to
my plans to check them out is back in
the day we used to call it the breeders
in Northern California used to call it
growth hormone okay and what it is is
basically when you take a plant you top
it right yeah you see how fast it comes
back with the axial branches yeah and
then you top it again see how fast it
comes back with the abstra branches top
all those and you see how many times
before you actually slow the process
yeah now of course you got to keep the
resources all in line here during this
sure you know you gotta have container
size and food and water because you know
it's now putting up 20 leads yeah
exactly whatever but but that's how you
could tell a plant has like the superior
Vigor from hell if it can come back four
times and still be just the Hemingway
one of the ones I worked with a long
time ago Terry Hemingway well before it
was the Cherry Hemingway it was the
Hemingway oh okay and it's a bhutanese
mad plant
that thing man my friends would tell me
it's broken out of the grow room window
and ate the neighbor's dog
I mean you talk about bigger you could
just you prune the [ __ ] out of that
plant you just make it mad I mean it
comes back that's adaptability right
there is it the pure Boonies that's one
of the things I always look for with all
my breeders is I test them that way you
know I always yeah I took the crap out
of them and see how fast they come back
and also I take advantage of any
incidents I might have where if my tent
were way all of a sudden it's 110 in
there I'm like oh [ __ ] then I watch
those plants very closely for the next
two weeks I see who handled that best or
or if something happens where I I I
drowned them all out and they all hurt
from drought's Death that's a really
good opportunity to see what's up yeah
yeah it's a great way to see what's up
with your plants and their ability to
test for stress and yeah
they got to be they got to be
strong first and foremost you know yeah
when I'm selecting them I don't want any
weaknesses in there at all once I've got
it down to all the strongest plants then
I go to work on resin production Terps I
see what's up with all that
so aside from your breeding work which
is is completely prolific it's really
well known and like you said it's its
own kind of ecosystem where you've kept
it very pure in its own form and rarely
do you bring anything in you're also
very well known for your true living
Organics you have a book out from Green
candy press called true living Organics
let's talk about it let's talk about
let's let's do a a step-by-step quick
basic organic introduction like you
would you would teach a beginner give
them your your best advice that you
would give a beginner starting into
Organics
okay
TLO
simply an all-natural Style
okay
when I say all natural style
I do mean organic yeah but all organic
Styles aren't all natural that's right
yeah I could be growing organic with my
Earth Juice bottles and it would not be
all natural exactly it would be organic
yes so that's the first difference there
TLO is an all-natural style there's no
liquid anything no synthetics we don't
cram
organic acids in there to force feed
them yada yada no synthetic processes in
any of it or even any hot or organic
acids in any prolific amounts okay and
um then the next thing you need to know
about TLO is we leverage Mother Nature
right we take some advantage of the
plants being in containers like higher
root temperatures yeah that means
there's more you know you've seen an ant
hill on a sunny day compared to an ant
hill on a cloudy day yeah you know
they're moving like lightning on the
sunny day and they're all just screwed
all right same with your plants when the
roots are the temperature around the
roots in the container are warm like
that that's pretty alien to the plant
but Mother Nature comes to the rescue
takes advantage of that but we can
leverage all those things right yeah it
goes warmer temperatures and the right
balance the right pH the right food the
right aeration the right container
Dynamics you put the right water you put
all those together and not only is it
all natural growing it's freaking
Supernatural right and I mean literally
not just a tagline yeah yeah
natural yeah
so we were getting into
um the second part the second question
of uh best advice you would give a tll
grower
right right the second part is
from the movie Ghostbusters do not cross
the streams
okay
this is one of the most important things
and what [ __ ] up the most people most
often right is they have their grow
going really good everything's cranking
along and they decide to add some sweet
or some you know super Thrive or some
kind of Elixir or yes you know because
that just does once you get how the
all-natural process works it's all about
consistency right yes it's all about the
plant and the soil all getting used to
their environment the changes don't come
rapidly they come slowly the plant loves
it like that because it grows super
slowly right exactly you can't just
blast in a bunch of phosphorus or or
some kind of radical fulvic acid
solution in there and think everything's
gonna be okay because the first thing
it's going to do is change the ph and
the soil radically yeah now if you're a
human you might go cool more food but if
you're microlife in the soil you die
yeah and it takes a whole two weeks for
that to come back to where it should be
after a mistake like that and if that
two weeks is during flowering well as we
discussed before you're taking the way
from resin production yeah yeah
instantly instantly you're you're
boofing your bud
um yeah I mean I don't get why anybody
would go through all that process of
having this beautiful organic living
soil and add in just a little thing but
I guess that temptation is always there
though right like for for people that
are used to bottles grabbing that bottle
real quick to make a quick adjustment
for sure I understand it my god when I
was making the transformation myself I
boned that one many times myself
I bet I bet it's got to be a common
habit so well right out of the gate the
problem the problem is it's right out of
the gate when you pour some of that on
on your plant oh your plant looks wicked
happy for a week maybe 10 day oh yeah it
loves it you go man I made a great move
then all of a sudden it starts going to
hell and you're like what's wrong well
it's because it catches up in time yeah
so if you're going to go TLO stay till
low do not mix yeah give it a fair give
it a fair shot you know don't don't
decide when you've got you know a couple
or a few weeks left to go before Harvest
that you need a phosphorus boost yeah
yeah okay no kidding yeah so when when
did you start your writing career I mean
this is a big part of your career is
writing not just growing and writing
about growing but actually being an
author when did that kind of come about
um I uh
met up with a guy who was a writer his
name was gooey he just met with him
online right
I didn't know [ __ ] about writing yeah I
mean I could I couldn't even spell the
word the word article consistently yeah
right I would spell it wrong I spelled
all kinds of things wrong my sentence
structure sucked anyway so he proposed
an idea where he wrote for skunk
magazine at that time so he proposed an
idea where we would collaborate right
and we would just do some stuff together
yeah so I stuck with him for probably I
don't know it was like a year but what
we would do is I would write then I
would send it to him
then he would he would fix it and then
he would send it back to me and then I
would say yeah yeah because sometimes if
you don't know how to grow and you're
editing somebody's writing you screw it
all up because you don't know what
you're saying absolutely so along with
correcting those kind of things I also
took really careful note on the writing
Corrections he made yeah I started to
get a grip on how he wrote how he
structured his sentences blah blah blah
so after about two years I guess a year
and a half of that I uh broke out on my
own and just started writing and I did
okay for a while and slowly came up more
and more and more
you know in my skills of writing sure
and then uh at uh at one point when
skunk went digital they got the new I
forgot what it's called but the program
that you uh submit articles in right
it's okay it's got all its own little
rules right
excuse me like how many you know words
can be in a paragraph how many
paragraphs can be how many words and
paragraphs can be under a heading
all this stuff that I wasn't really that
familiar with so that trained me a
little further so so now I can write
pretty good you know standard issue
pretty good I still have my own
signature moves that I pull off that
aren't you know classic writing skills
but yeah for sure you know it's it's
like whenever I'm writing I'm always
imagining that I'm just sitting there
talking to somebody at a pub or
something and I'm explaining whatever
I'm writing to them and it's funny
because a lot of the people who email me
they say exactly that they go I swear
man I feel like I'm just sitting next to
you in a pub and you're just telling me
stuff yeah that's what I enjoy that's
what that's why early your writing
resonated with me as I was growing up
and reading skunk and doing all that
like it always resonated with me because
it's how I speak when I'm talking to
someone it's just familiar you don't
feel like someone's above you talking
down to you just feel like it's a broke
talking about growing you know no I mean
everybody has their own likes and
dislikes I respect that totally you know
it's uh it's like music or anything else
or your favorite food you know you have
your favorites right now your favorites
change sometimes that's just the way it
is I go through I go through periods
where I'm just like uh oh God yeah I
made some sash from some Cinderella 99
recently oh that's a good move
that's a really good move so anyway I
just got obliterate I don't really you
know for uh for a writer of cannabis an
author and a grower and a breeder I
don't really smoke as much weed as a lot
of the people I know yeah probably
because I'm older now because I sure
used to yeah but when I get something
that's really fine in my hands like that
Cindy hash I tend to go for you know
maybe a week just being the stoner from
hell
all the time
that's me when I start when I fire up
the puffco
you know there's a good week or two
where I'm just stuck on stupid you know
for a while and then I go back to flower
and kind of get you can do it slowly but
yeah yeah that always yeah we go hash
also blows your whole ability to smoke
flowers too because it brings it raises
your tolerance to a really high level
super fast super fast yeah and that and
that that's no fun when you can't really
enjoy the fine complexities of a high in
a flower right because exactly exactly
because I I test stuff out you know
where where sometimes the route I take
for breeding is I will use uh since I'm
really good and fast at making hash I'll
take four plants four females that I've
never seen all the way through flowering
right and I'll have my male or two or
three however many I'm using in there
then since I've seen this so many times
and especially if I'm using something I
know I can look at the plants as they
seat up watch them very closely under
magnification as they finish and I can
tell who's got the most resin production
and of course the turpins become obvious
to me yeah yeah and uh so what I do is
is I make separate hash balls from each
female because beyond the resin count
the resin production you have the resin
coating right the profile itself yeah so
and that's what I'm really all about I
love that so I just take days where for
three days I smoke just hash from one
you know in the morning noon night then
the next day or the next set of days I
smoke and it takes me you know a week or
two to go through four or five different
females sure but by the end of that I
damn sure know which ones I like best
yeah you have a good idea how it gets
you because a lot of people like I mean
I'm sure people realize this but I don't
know that they consciously realize it
a strain doesn't always affect the same
person the same way at the same time of
the day when you smoke in the morning in
fact nor will it affect you the same way
under two different situations exactly
right it's it's it's so variant how a
high will make you feel it could you
could be smoking the exact same Terps
cannabinoid content everything but time
of day mood everything matters when it
comes to cannabis everything I agree 100
it's like uh one of my favorite things
to do to test out especially sativas
ones are sativa dominant they're all
just blaze of doobie or a couple hits or
whatever and I'll but I'll Blaze out on
my bicycle and go riding around see see
what's up yeah dude I'll see what kind
of energy motivations weed it really is
a lot of times I don't even get to
really truly experience a high until I
get up and move around and start you
know getting some getting some action
going that's usually when I figure out a
house truly stoned I am exactly and you
can take note of things along the away
like some things stay consistent like oh
this is well I ate that whole box of
cookies so I guess it gives you the
munchies pretty hardcore exactly yeah
yeah exactly yeah yeah so you could tell
some things stay the same but as far as
your attitude as far as how it hits you
mentally when you're on it there's some
that are just like I say those bhutanese
or the Blue Rhino 1947 there's a few
others I have that just make me have
that golden the life is beautiful thing
yeah and then there's then there's those
strains where a stupid joke will make
you laugh to where you almost choke to
death yeah I mean it's just there's so
many different kinds out there and you
know I run across somebody a couple
years ago and man I'll always remember
this guy he comes up to me wants to
smoke a doobie with me and I'm like dude
is it organic or whatever he goes I
don't know it's pot
he goes but it's really really powerful
and and I said all right well let me
have a hit of it I smell it it smelled
good you know I was like okay my first
hit I could see it was gnarly synthetic
grown like so bad it was like Miracle
Grow yeah right it was like oh [ __ ] I'm
sorry don't want to piss you off but
that sucks right yeah yeah and uh he
goes dude you won't believe how high it
gets you and I go let me let you in on a
little secret here I could spray the bud
with raid
and if you smoked it you would get so
[ __ ] up yes so it's not just about
that right you know that they actually
um I've talked about this before on the
show back when I was in my teens in
Bakersfield most of the time we were
getting in Mexican compressed during
that during the 90s we're getting
Mexican compressed and we're young we
didn't have access to dank up and
Humboldt we'd have cars to drive around
we were young poor kids but in a certain
area of town you could go get Mexican
and it always had this weird floral
perfumey smell to it later on I found
out they were spraying it with raid
because they would they would sell it
and they'd call it nade so I thought
that was the Stray name but later on I
found out they're spraying it literally
with raid well it will get you really
really high it sure will [ __ ] just just
take a shortcut and inhale some rain if
that's it right up on some raid yeah
don't have fun right no no no if I'm
right kids
but yeah I know I I it's shocking what
people will do to their weed just to
to give an effect even if it has nothing
to do with the natural processes of the
plant or the high of cannabis right
right I've converted many many people
just by giving them some weed right
because they'll hit me with a weed and
they'll go oh this is the best weed and
and I say compared to what yeah not
compared to this yeah this little number
and I'll give them like a quarter ounce
of it or something right and within the
time of no more than a few days it never
takes more than a few days
next thing they're doing man they're
asking me how to do this they want
details they're selling all their other
[ __ ] they think it's crap now because
especially synthetics I mean if you're
someone who can't tell the difference
between synthetic grown weed and organic
or all natural grown weed
you need to solve that problem first
because there is a hell of a difference
it means you're not smoking enough
different good Growers if you don't know
the difference absolutely because man
that's synthetic weed I could take one
hit of real shitty synthetic weed oh
yeah and my throat's through for the
rest of the day yeah yeah you're blowing
out blowing out coughs out the throat
all day yeah it's all hot and shitty
yeah yeah
it's pretty typical for it
so I mean you know if that's your gig if
that's what you like and that's yeah
right fine you know but don't don't
throw it on me and try to tell me it's
organic I don't tell me it's the best
you know like if you haven't smoked a
good sampling of all that's out there
and a lot of different types of growing
stuff you really don't truly know until
you have that experience and if got the
breadth until you can tell the
difference between organic you know
shitty synthetic and the and the
difference in between it's not just
looking at the ash you know it's just
that yeah but and that's just the
Elegance of the smoke you know how
elegant and smooth it is yeah when
you're organic or all natural your your
miles above anything synthetic all all
the way yeah but from you know I've
never smoked really organically grown
bottle weed I call it soup style
organically grown weed with bottles that
has been really offensive unless the
person has decided to Goose their plants
at the end with a bunch of potassium and
phosphorus you know yeah if they don't
fade an organic bottle grow well it can
be harsh nothing like synthetics can be
yeah but still you can pick it up there
you know I'm sure you've smoked those
dummies where the the Cherry will Sizzle
like a sparkler a little bit yes that's
Mega potassium still in there yeah yeah
I love Mega potassium
yeah and yeah I mean if you're gonna
pour like heavy potassium or like
phospho load on your plants at the end
of an organ or a TLO grow just just
don't just don't you're not going to
fool anyone just you're not I mean
potassium and phosphorus are both
elements that you absolutely do not want
to Goose your plants with pretty much
ever if you're in soil no matter what
you're doing yeah exactly in nature
potassium and phosphorus don't come in
highly available forms they're taken in
very slowly stored and that's another
thing with breeding that I also notice
is along with like what we were talking
about before with how vigorous and what
I used to call the growth hormone right
yeah how how adaptable they are another
thing with it what was I just talking
about see how I am
see how I am
um this is the curse of the old person
it's okay Mr Magoo what am I doing where
did I go
oh okay what was I talking about oh yeah
so yeah so it's potassium and phosphorus
are just meant to be taken up super
slowly over time right like I said and
stored in the plant and along with
certain abilities of certain plants over
other plants one of those abilities is
to be able to store and acquire
nutrients like potassium calcium
phosphorus something about a breeding
trait here yeah yeah yeah when you're
selecting some plants can store a lot of
those nutrients yeah some plants have a
hard time getting it some plants don't
you know it's just how well they work in
synchronicity with the soil life it's
how how adaptable I guess it's kind of
their more Wilder side coming back to
them yeah so one thing I noticed going
through your stuff I don't think you
have any OG cush in your lines do you no
I do not I love that I love that I mean
I like OG Kush but at the same time the
past
20 years has been bombarded everything
has OG in it now so you always yeah
profile somewhere in it and I just
realizing wait a minute this is this is
an enigma this is a a thing you don't
find very often a breeder that's still
going didn't work OG Kush in their lines
in a still successful making great lines
I mean that's special I like OG Kush
right yeah it kicks my ass I think it's
that the guys who first made that were
guys from Northern California who went
down to LA right yeah
those are the guys who built that so uh
that was uh that was a devastating
that's that's a that's a not a day
record because the legs aren't super
long but I mean it would be a day
wrecker if the legs were longer yeah
because it's just disabling I mean it
just if if I'm in bed and I feel like
[ __ ] OG Kush would be perfect you know
just
because I'm not gonna be doing much else
besides maybe get a haircut and watch a
movie and and not follow it yeah exactly
exactly I mean there's a time and place
for that weed but that's not usually my
go-to type so I didn't want to use it
because I mostly breed with stuff I like
and even though I'm not the usual I'm
not the regular I'm not the majority
most people like strains and and
varieties that are different than the
ones I like the most I tend to lean a
little more sativa in my likes or most
people lean a little more Indica in
their likes and it's not that I don't
like it because it's just if I'm gonna
have a go-to weed that I'm gonna I'm a
busy guy I do a lot of [ __ ] all the time
yeah we don't need something to hammer
me down and make me eat some pancakes
and go to sleep yeah no that don't help
nothing I want something where I could
be high and happy still functional and
I'm stoned as hell but I'm still good to
operate it's not like da right yeah I I
just I I admired that I admire that
because it's so easy to go with the
crowd I you know push oh geez uh things
are going a little bit slower let's push
some OG in there that's what's hip now
you know you just never did it and I and
I admire that that's that punk rock
ethos that I love about the Rev thank
you I sure got offered enough of it you
know I guarantee you did yeah for sure I
mean you were there for the beginning of
it the you know all of it and you just I
love that you stuck to your guns that's
what makes you special oh
what's the revs white whale what's a
strain that you that you either you've
had and lost or a strain that you're
hunting a strain that you just always
wanted or a terp profile that you've
always wanted well I'm pretty good with
making terp profiles I mean I'm usually
pretty close I've seen enough of them
blend so I know
close to where they're gonna go and then
individuals in that batch I can usually
find it you know yeah but as far as the
The Strain I would love to have back
that the police got from me
after I first moved here was my Panama
Red Clone oh I bet one of the craziest
[ __ ] plants you've ever seen a jungle
sativa right this thing would grow roots
that would shoot straight up out of the
ground for a couple inches then they
would turn around and go straight back
into the ground so you'd have all these
root loops
and then new plants would start growing
off of those of the what that's crazy
all right do you think that's weird let
me tell you something else you know how
the male plants in some strange some
rare varieties they're usually land race
heirloom types they have those Nubs at
the base of the stem I don't mean it
from being too humid yeah I mean they
actually have little Nubs like they
reinforce the bottom third of their
steps these like armor Nubs right sure
the Panama Red had spikes on those Nubs
still a pointy little like thorns on
those Nubs I mean you talk about a
dinosaur freaking plant and DJ Short
absolutely described it to a t it is the
tequila of weed
what makes you say that right it is
psychoactive man it is it is it is off
your rock or down the rabbit hole
complete takeover of everything this is
like it it warms you so thoroughly you
were like it's almost like mushrooms it
really is wow yeah I mean it just your
auto Tory or your visual everything is
affected hardcore your brain is just
going 20 directions at once it's like
it's like your head is zooming through
space really fast you know you're just
like whoa like that ad for those
speakers that time yeah oh yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah just like that you're
like whoa It's just kicking your ass and
like a Durban Poison it has waves right
then it's creeper so the first 10
minutes after you smoke it you go damn
damn and then five minutes left there
you go oh whoa it's not done 10 minutes
after that holy [ __ ]
it it just keeps bumping and you just go
deeper and deeper it's a great great
I've never seen the true clone of it or
what looks to me like a true offspring
of it anywhere yeah so I haven't dabbled
but I never gave the Clone to anybody so
I don't have any backup so yeah the cops
the cops have gotten a lot of really
good strains where did you source that
one
from a friend of mine down in uh
Nicaragua oh why yeah him and I did well
a long time ago
I used to get this hash right from
Jamaica
this is red hash and we used to take the
boat and go down to the uh one of those
islands just off just off in Mexican not
Catalina
you know that I was just south of San
Diego across the border the ones that
are named after the squid
Coronado Islands Coronado oh Coronado
yeah yeah yeah yeah not Coronado San
Diego but yeah
well we used to Rendezvous there and I'd
I'd always get the hash there well he
was the one who was always talking about
this so yeah blah blah Panama Red and
Susie said that of course I was like
yeah I bet you know Panama Red and he
goes yeah yeah he goes yeah I have a
clone so I was like well can you bring
that with you next time yeah and he was
like yeah yeah sure I'll do that he was
real nonchalant about it for such a whoa
yeah what year was this uh
uh
82 oh my gosh that's awesome yeah legit
[ __ ] legit time for Panama Red to be
going around and everything oh well you
know the closest thing to it now that if
you could source as far as I know would
be what was that stuff the Big Sir
hollyweed remember this movie yeah yeah
yeah that has real Panama red in it okay
nice [ __ ] potent potent old sativa
type oh yeah
yeah Panama Red The way you describe it
reminds me of how Tom Hill talks about
his Haze a specific Vino in his Haze uh
it is a lot like killer hazes right it's
got same psychoactive just blo I mean
blow your mind High yeah yeah that's
when he was talking to her he's like I
don't even know why anybody grows
anything but that he's like I don't care
if it's if it takes 10 and 500 to find
one of them because it's better than any
weed you'll ever smoke he's like
everybody's an idiot for not working
with it and I I was like wow really but
I mean it sounds like that this High
truly does exist in cannabis in some
forms it's incredibly impressive and I
say that
as an understatement I mean yeah if you
ever smoke it it will I I hope it's
still right I hope somebody has a hybrid
of it somewhere or something you know
yeah or somebody resources the real deal
because it legit comes from the edges of
the Panamanian jungle yeah you know I
mean just right there they don't go in
too deep to have to get it he told me a
lot about it but again I'm old and I
forget a lot of the details but he had a
lot of details about it but just looking
at the plan it was crazy first of all it
was red purple I mean
was it a purple flower plant bottoms of
the leaves were purple all the veins
were purple purple the buds were purple
and the buds were dark purple you know
but everything else was kind of a
reddish purple and those roots that
would go back in the ground start new
plants it was just crazy
that sounds a lot like the Dolores
strain too that was around a long time
ago I think that um who talks about
Dolores
uh Robert Clark maybe one of those guys
they know about it and it's it's an old
uh I don't know if it's South American
or Mexican hybrid but um similar very
similar in how the the looks
a lot of it and it's I think it's in Big
Sur Holy Week the Dolores like is a
portion of it so that's interesting it
would be interesting to see if we could
find a way to find a strain similar to
that well well well a haze a really good
Haze is very similar very similar so Tom
was nailing it on the head with his Haze
maybe oh yeah I mean yeah if you find a
good Haze some are easier than others
it's like yeah we went through some uh
the first Haze I remember
it was like 18 weeks flowering indoors
it's crazy but remember where it was
sourced from that one no that came from
the Surfers in Northern California so it
wasn't a good source those came from my
buddy's Surfer connection they had those
but uh that one was just even and just
the seeds from like any hybrid of that
one you know they never inbred it but
they hybridized it a lot but like the
the like the Vietnam Black the jungle
sativa yeah it walks all over anything
you would cross it with like 90 percent
yes something would have to be an IBL 10
or 15 or greater to even have a chance
to play a little bit in The Offspring
recombination yeah yeah that makes sense
um so this is a personal question just
for me did you keep seeds pure of the
Vietnam Black
yes I did that's awesome that's what I
just that's what I just did the soft
back cross I just released the uh Black
Forest F2 right yeah I think brackets it
says bx1 small bx1 yeah because I didn't
take it back to the original individual
uh Vietnam Black then I took it back to
uh super superior male that had all the
good signs on them so I back crossed it
to the line not the individual such a
generation of black forest that I just
released right it's gonna be wamping
wamping Vietnam Black sativa so you're
it's going to require not much looking
through because again I've never seen a
bad one of those they're all they're all
decent but there are probably three out
of ten two out of ten in our
extreme I mean extreme that is so cool I
because I know most of the people have
only been sourcing Vietnam Black via I
can't remember who brought it to the
scene but I know JoJo passed it
um the Vietnam Black that was in Willie
Nelson and Billy Goat also used one but
the fact that there's a whole nother
separate Vietnam black line from back in
the day like that super interesting and
I think a lot of people are going to be
interested to know that yeah that came
from my cousin in Vietnam he sent those
to me that's that is sick that is super
sick I always assumed it was the same
one as the billy goat one knowing that
just has me a thousand times more
interested to see more of what Vietnam
has to hold oh God Vietnamese the some
of the the cambodians there's just so
many Southeast Asians I Love Actually
bhutanese is the Southeast Asian but
they're far from Hayes like you know
they're just of course that that is a
unique one Bhutan was a closed Kingdom
for a long time yeah yeah I got those I
have a buddy of mine in China well he's
he's kind of a buddy we email back and
forth about stuff and he gets me stuff
sent out of there he's done it twice and
one of the things he sent me was this uh
what was it it was Bhutan he called it
gold Bhutan
anyway it was it was right from the uh
that that it was at the base of the
potato of the Tibetan Mountain there
right that's where it was harvested at
and it smelled just like fuel right oh
wow like strong honey oil fuel it was so
accurate and gnarly but we called it uh
butane gas you know boots on gas because
it smelled like fuel yeah so we called
it butane gas that that line yeah and
that's what I crossed with the Hemingway
and then I crossed that with the Cherry
Bomb and made the Cherry Hemi
so the Cherry Hemi is a real cool
collaboration of a lot of strange exotic
[ __ ] but there's a real wild side to
that boots and knees if you piss off
that boots and knees or anything with
boots and knees in it yeah she's gonna
hurt me and get pissed on you yeah I
would I would imagine so it's a wild
jungly place with her I've seen their
strains like because I
um in in Bhutan I know that like they're
they're wild cannabis growing at
literally all over randomly and and
different little even from house to
house you know 100 meters apart might
have different little cultivars or
strains or whatever they have going on
but they tend to be pretty jungly wild
stuff yeah yeah same same with South
Africa from Farm to farm or Jamaica from
yeah you know you can have slight
variations on stuff because of whatever
their breeding practices are you know
yeah and elevation all of it especially
in some of those Island places where
elevation goes from see Florida you know
High super fast more UV is always good
up to a point Point yeah right so too
much Evie it's like if you grow plants
in all day full sunshine
and then you grow the set a clone of
that plant under all day laughing
sunshine or dappled Sunshine you're
probably gonna get a 10 bigger yield or
15 bigger yield on your all-day Sunshine
plant yeah but that 10 or 15 percent is
just pure vegetable fiber from the UV
yeah it just makes everything bigger not
better yeah it actually reduces the
potency of the resin because it swells
up everything so gnarly you know all the
UV is just promoting that vegetable
growth so we used to take for our
commercial interest we would grow full
sun yeah but for our plants that we
smoked we would either we build
laughings over them or we kept them we
kept them positioned around trees so
they would only get half a day of full
sunshine and then half a day of dappled
Sunshine that's really good advice too
um for some of these longer flowering
indoor streams that you have would you
recommend
um a Different Light hour time for
indoors on some of your longer flying
strings a different what light flowering
time you know how most people go to 12
hours as a standard do you ever
recommend different flowering times for
any of your strains well if it comes
from the the equator anywhere around the
equator what I will always do to it is
during the second half of flowering I'll
either drop my photo period to 12 5 11 5
or 13 11. you know there you go yeah or
11 13 I mean 13 hours of Darkness right
yeah because they grow pretty much year
round with very slight photo period
changes yeah so sometimes I've had
people have long flowering sativas all
day many times that have told me it
won't stop flowering yeah yeah yeah okay
you just cut your cut your legs from 12
to 11 and that'll fix that in two weeks
I remember I ran into a Malawi this is
the first time I ever ran into something
like this and I had it in 12 hours of
light and this is the first time I ever
learned about light out hours moving
them or fluctuating them and I thought
it was like three months in nothing no
no flower formations and I I hit a body
I'm like Bodhi what is going on what do
I not know and he's like reduce your
light hours dummy you know it's like
reduce them watch it watch and then you
know start reducing and we ended up
moving down to eight and by the end of
eight it would finish eight hours of
light and it doesn't seem like it's
enough it's counterintuitive you think
it won't yield enough but it was perfect
for that Malawi it wasn't and you only
really have to do it for the last few
weeks right just so if you know about
that that's why I like sourcing
geographical varieties and strains
because
I know a lot about different strains
from different locales yeah so if I know
where it's from or where it's
constituents of the hybrid or from I can
assess all kinds of things right off the
bat I can assume a lot of things yeah
yeah you know so that helps me a lot but
if I'm just
if somebody's offered me some seeds I'm
like well where is this from where where
do the genetics come from and they go
well it's blue pups blue Boingo and
gorilla Funk cookie mask and you know
that tells me nothing zero because you
know nothing about anything about it you
don't even know if it's in Afghani if
it's if you don't know those specific
names for those strains you have no clue
at all nor do I really trust people who
I don't know to tell me what's real and
they may in fact not know shade on them
they may believe it's true because
somebody told them that they believed
that it and it wasn't true like I've
heard I've heard some good fantastic
stories that I just don't think are true
yeah yeah and yeah the road to hell is
paved with good intentions there's a lot
of people who are great people just
warm-hearted people that will tell you
information that isn't correct because
they truly believe it to be true and
they trusted the person who gave it to
them and that person might be a great
trustworthy person but the person that
you know just got it wrong once we
didn't
I'm just going to use an example here or
something let's say a Cinderella 99
right yeah they'll grow Cinderella 99
and they'll end up with yeah I don't
know let's say five females right so one
of the females will be outstanding like
in my c99 line now if you want to look
for something really outstanding what
you're looking for is an extra beefy
female okay she is vigorous and extra
beefy to the max she yields about 20
percent more than any other Cindy and
she is the most great or the most uh
pineappley delicious resin so killer
ever okay that's my favorite cut right
so let's say somebody grows them and
they find that that female right yeah
well that's special right so they name
her
Griselda yeah right yeah so then they
decide [ __ ] I need to breed this so then
what is the hybrid X cross with
griselves not c99 no so you lose a bunch
of the strain limits you don't know
it kills the anthropology of it all
right
you have to you know I mean I run it
backwards in my head and go oh it's
probably gonna be like this but you know
there's a lot of stuff I can assess with
you tell me it's gooey cookie Funk and I
don't know yeah I mean with with if we
know that a c99 we can go okay Jack
error type uh skunk one Haze Northern
Lights five okay we can you know you can
easily break it down but yeah once they
start playing around past the bass lines
and it's just random names and they
aren't really there's not a lot you can
get from that and to be honest if I see
something
um a line that is like eight things in
it like some people get all excited the
more hype strains are it the more
excited they get because it but I me I
walk away this the second I see too many
because I'm like I don't even know what
I'm gonna get from this nor would I want
to breathe with that because it's going
to be completely unpredictable
you know unpredictable is an
understatement right yeah
it's just it's a totally different way
if you look on my site you'll see that I
do have poly hybrids for sure but I have
a lot that are true two-way f1s true
three-way f1s and true four-way F1 yes
once you have a five way or above of an
F1 then it starts to become a poly but a
lot of the ones these days are like 10.
yeah I remember if not more someone
showed me the seed finder page for
animal mints and I went and looked at
like because you can do the strain map
and see all the stuff in it listed it
was like four pages long of of
everything laid out because it's just
poly hybrid polyhybrid polyhybrid
cookies
right it all ends up being OG Kush in
the end but none of that really matters
because they've crammed OG cushion to
itself and all of its Expressions 90
times over you know right and you know I
like to keep everything separate too I
like to know when I'm not double dip it
in some Gene pools so if I if I have a a
c99 cross with an OG Kush and a c99
crossed with a metal Haze okay I have
those two strains
now
oh I did it again
c99 metal Haze c99 and I was gonna say
you see what happens when you have resin
on your brain I do I'm seeing my future
right here
because I was such a such a forgetful
person oh yeah okay now
all right so if you have those two those
two varieties those two hybrids right
right now you smoke one oh yeah this is
really good oh it gets me hot then you
go to smoke the other one you go yeah
that's pretty good well it could be
every bit as good as the first one but
you've already built up some tolerance
to the c99 in the first one yeah the
second c99 hybrid is going to be a
little less impressive to you yeah so
when I'm testing things or sampling them
and want to know really more about them
I got to make sure that I'm not cross
cross encountering some things in two
different ones because then I have to
adjust that into my whole deal yeah
that's not an obvious thing to think of
either like uh building tolerance to a
specific strainer type when you're doing
testing so would you recommend like
maybe the next day the following day
maybe smoking one in the morning and one
at night and vice versa the next day or
or you can or you can clean your palette
if you've got if you've got a couple of
hybrids that have a common P1 right then
you could just clean your palate in
between right yeah you could sample one
check it out and then go for something
way out of the bandwidth
then come back to the second one and
then
that makes sense that makes a lot of
sense give your give your receptors time
to change a little bit
yeah one of my favorites to clean my
palette with is Congo right yeah why is
that the Cindy Kong go super well
because it's one of those you know you
know the strains that you could be
smoking different weed all day you can
be kind of baked you know hanging around
it and then you smoke that weed where
you take a few hits and it just wipes
Out All the Rest of anything you've ever
smoked and capacity just takes over with
a new high that's combo yeah the
Breakthrough highs I always call this
breakthroughs and everything else it
just Stomps out any kind of mild effects
what kind of smells come out of the
Congo that you work with
they are real uh like kind of rotten
meat with uh like a sickening sweet
background interesting it's uh it's
acrid but it's not Fury you know what I
mean it's like it's like rotting meat is
the best way I could do it it's sweet
but in a kind of a sickeningly sweet way
kind of like the matinees could Thunder
[ __ ] it's weird that they smell a lot
alike but they do I wonder I mean does
it smell like a dead body Maybe
because sweet like I remember yeah yeah
yeah but yeah but you have to imagine
what I mean when I say that there's a
sweet component to it it's not like oh
yeah I mean it's like it's like ooh but
it's strangely compelling someone I knew
that worked in a in a funeral home
always describe the debt and they
described this to me before I smelled it
because I I would do I would help them
in the in the funeral home but um they
said bodies dead bodies smell like sweet
[ __ ] sweet running meat it's there's a
sweetness to it though that's really
freaking weird
it's sort of like sugar cookies you know
oh wow oh my gosh so it's almost wow
that would be a really weird but
attractive smell I mean I've smelled
body odor smells in um cannabis like uh
what was it bodies he had a string
called hippie Slayer 33 I think and it
smelled like straight Bo but it tasted
it smelled yummy like I wanted to eat it
like why would you want to eat human
beer but I did I'm with you I'm with you
the metal Haze was pure cat piss I mean
just just pissy bit you would think if
you opened a bag of that anyone who
walked in would think well did the cat
just pee in here yeah it was pure pests
but again strangely attractive and
compelling
yeah do you still keep that little Haze
cut
no I lost the metal Haze cut to police
metal Hayes
[ __ ] police
[ __ ] pigs they always get them I mean
that cut was really special I got to
work with it a few times and I it
reminded me of a um maybe a more in the
structure NL skunk one dominant because
it wasn't super super super like lanky
Haze but it had a good structure to it
right it did good bud structure and
stuff that was such a cool line man that
was such I loved it well the reason the
re one of the main reasons I crossed it
to the uh
iron Cindy was to preserve it to some
extent because they're very similar yeah
right they're very yeah yeah yeah
definitely it's that skunk one or like
five Haze combo that you can see in both
of them well I could yeah because I did
it to make the iron Cindy I combined the
metal Haze and the c99 because the c99
is like a little metal Haze kind of a
faster uh c99 is really unique I really
love it I mean it has a kind of a it's
like a poor man's Haze definitely a lot
of hazy sativa qualities to it not all
but a surprising amount for a eight or
nine week plan you know I think that's
why c99 c99 gained such popularity
because people want that type of high in
the same kind of flowering time they
could get from some of these afghanis
and it's one of the few lines other than
like high in lonesome's Appalachia that
I found that really captured the ability
to capture sativity short flowering time
like that it's like c99 is the only one
I've ever seen that did it that's why I
grabbed it up so fast I was like oh my
God this is this is really like a fast
sativa with some definite longer satima
flowering qualities yeah yeah especially
in the eye I love the c99 I think she's
fantastic especially now that I found
that buku grapefruit Mama yeah no
kidding I see I'm a sucker for that Pine
all right not grapefruit I'm sorry
pineapple oh yeah the pineapple one man
that's your penalene that that that what
you would refer to as like cat pissy
smell but like mixed with the pineapple
makes the flavor translate so well like
it actually tastes like pineapple sharp
Citrus pineapple Sharps Citrus pineapple
right yeah it would it would it would be
so hard for someone to intentionally
make that again from scratch I think it
is one of the most pineappley things
there are in cannabis super cool it it
really really is pineapple I mean
especially with a little cure on it two
weeks of a cure and you open the jar and
it's like damn yeah yeah that's one that
I I do miss a lot and I've actually been
trying to look for it I think CSI
Humboldt might have grabbed it recently
so hopefully that that one's going to
come back in rotation soon
you can always get the pineapple I mean
I'm not sure I don't know what the
ratios are the percentages of chance
that she pops up but I did find her
within uh probably
15 females okay I found one and I've had
friends of mine that have found them so
they're not super hard to find no no
they're in there definitely they're
probably one we're probably one in eight
maybe one in 12 something like that so
if if people are interested do you still
carry that line in seed form and sell it
on your site absolutely awesome awesome
c99 they're still like the F5s yeah that
I have made and what happened was last
time I made them I made a shitload and I
put most of them in deep freeze cryo
good good so now I just tap from a
smaller Source once they run out I bust
into the deep freeze cry I'll bring a
bunch out and do it again it can stay
the same I don't have to keep in
bringing them and inbreeding them and
you don't have to keep yanking them in
and out of the cryo constantly every
time you want to take out pack and
fluctuating right right and I love this
pie I love a couple of the Finos but the
pineapple Beast is my favorite and I'll
always want to be able to get her so I
didn't want to risk it on the off chance
that because sometimes it's like with
the skunk man sometimes it's just
cannabis Mother Nature just goes
yeah there's just nothing you could do
you try to combine what you think is
going to work in a certain way and it
comes out almost opposite yeah I can't
tell you now twice now I've combined
roadkill skunk mail with Road skill kill
skunk female and I get all the same
spread that I would have if I would have
pretty much crossed anything any other
two yeah you know it always comes out
spreading the spread I can't get to
isolate it down what I what I just did
recently for uh just because that pisses
me off yeah yeah as I took uh the
Vietnam Black jungle sativa since I had
the male flowering right yeah and I had
a roadkill skunk candy it was only a
little clone right I had a little clone
I was like yeah yeah okay I popped it in
the flowering tent you know yeah made a
flower and it only ended up about this
big but it got pollinated with that
gnarly
if you've never smelled the V black
before let me tell you it's it's not
like anything else ever I've smelled in
my life it's it's sort of like nag
Champa incense yeah and it's real sharp
oh it's just god-awful exotic and
delicious but I mean so I crossed it
with that right it's a sharp acrid
terpene profile right yeah so I brought
the the roadkill skunk up against it now
I'm gonna end up with a long flowering
son of a [ __ ] it's gonna be 12 weeks at
least yeah but
If I Grow these out and I get a high
percentage of roadkill skunks you can
bet I'll be waiting them down to Shorter
flowering and be able to keep that
roadkill scone because I'm sure that'd
be black will rule dominant in many of
the things especially the terp combo
right yeah yeah I should be able to in
theory inbreed days yes with the right
combo and get all roadkill skunk they
might be 11 weeks they might be 10 weeks
but I should be able to do it because I
can't I can't get my skunk line to come
all roadkill it just it won't I've tried
three different ways and I always get
the same spread no matter what I do I've
tried two different ways with a few
different lines and it is very hard
especially once the butt is dry to lock
in that smell once the bud dries it's
like that smells gone sometimes it's the
case yeah sometimes you know it depends
on a lot of things it's like what I do
now more recently only for the last I
don't know three years maybe four years
or so is I used to never dry my weed too
dry because I like to smoke it when it
has just a scose of moisture still in it
right yeah yeah it's much much smoother
absolutely you smoke super super dry
weed it's a little hot right yeah man so
I always like my weed like that so it's
hard to store weed like that without
consistently burping it exactly or else
it loses the smells faster right yeah so
what what I do now is oh and this works
good buddy I take and I mummify it right
I mean I dry it so [ __ ] bad you touch
it it'll just crumble okay that's how
dry I dried yeah I very carefully put it
in big jars and put it in a big
insulated cooler and I store it right
yeah when I want to hit that weed or
check it out or smoke it or whatever I
just open the jar up my humidity around
here is usually around 50 percent which
is fine 50 60 that's fine and I take
some very carefully out of the jar I set
it in an open Bowl close the jar put it
back and then I let it just set out in
my room for about a few hours usually
check the moisture level because fast
it'll start soaking that up
moisture from there right yeah and then
it gets to that perfect consistency
within several hours sometimes it takes
overnight it depends if the humidity is
low yeah but uh but by the next day or
within a few hours boom you not only
have the perfect moisture level in your
buds but the smells just come out with a
Vengeance then right there because it
all starts processing again yeah once
you mummified it you've stopped it yeah
you've stopped everything it's doing
there's no moisture in there right yeah
so it preserves your buds for a super
long time so I take them all I put them
in all smaller containers like like
either pint jars or what are they quart
jars yeah I save them all in that so
that I never have to bust One open and
keep opening it you know that way I can
burn through one in a relatively short
amount of time and now you have to keep
opening it and close it having more
moisture get in there yeah
I opened up some Blue Rhino 1947 a few
days ago that was five years old it's
been in storage for five years I did
that to it
five years and it wasn't Frozen or
anything it perfect no no it was just
now understand I store them in a big
gnarly insulated cooler okay this cooler
is in a place that is pretty cool never
gets really warm gotcha so the real key
to the long-term storage is having your
degree variance be very small in any
24-hour period right that makes sense
well you only want that to change like a
degree or two Max Max and then that will
store it as long as it's cool for a
super long time all by itself so mine
stays like that in the cooler Five Years
buddy five years I broke it up left it
let the moisture absorber I squeezed in
one mama
you know who else is is blown my mind is
Bodhi he has like this this barn with um
buds hanging in it and
for years you can have buds in here and
and just of all different land racing
stuff and go ahead and pick it off but
because Santa Cruz's humidity is so
perfect it's just like a humidor for bud
in the last years it's crazy absolutely
crazy that is nice you know if you've
got like here
it's really a lot of times here in
Oregon it's too wet to really I mean I
can pop them in the room since I don't
trim the plant at Harvest now I just
take the whole plant right yeah yeah all
the big leaves will come down and
protect most of the buds from the light
sometimes man I just have to hang them
in the grow room to let them dry you
know and they're not in any direct light
but there's a lot of reflected light
which is not my favorite but I sometimes
have to do it because my humidity is 90
Plus for a week yeah I mean and I can't
dry anything like that if I put it in
the jars I'll be mold City fast oh yeah
yes my girl who I have uh I have uh Kai
found this tool of hers she had a uh a
dehydrator right
right when I pull them down I take them
on a little buds I stack them on that
dehydrator I let that [ __ ] roll for
about an hour to get a mummy dry yeah
very carefully put them in the jars and
put them away and that works like a
champ but during the summer I don't need
it I can I can mummy dry them just
hanging them out in the closet you know
yeah
so you have a new book coming out
um we we have the TLO uh version one and
two correct yes is this the V3 or is
this a whole new book whole new book
what do we got tell us about that man
it's uh
I've leaned away from the whole tease
thing right I don't like teas anymore
all right what I like is a Perpetual tea
I call it the churn right okay it's a
constant addition to your water that you
back off when it's near harvest the
whole book will explain it but it is the
[ __ ] bomb right okay that's how I
keep I adjust my water and uh I give in
the new book there's like I don't know
probably 10 soil recipes for any
situation no matter what you can get and
what you can't get with tons of options
for what you can sub in that was a point
of problem for some people where they
would not be able to get something in
the original recipes and they would sub
in something else that's not good right
or or they would just leave it out
completely and with some things you can
leave out it's no big deal with other
things that's not the case you know yeah
yeah
so it's all these new soil recipes it's
all the new Dynamics around growing in
general it shows new microphone style
right which is essentially using the
catch trays as little micro ponds yeah
yeah where the water sits in for a while
you have some Alfalfa and whatnot in
there all the microlife Bros and then
get stuck back into the plant and
everything is beautiful that method
works like unbelievably good I'll have
to check that out I've never heard that
oh it's so Kick-Ass man it's so easy
it's like it's like top dressing but
it's probably but it's like top dressing
that works much faster right it's like
you get results with it within days you
can see the effects of what you've done
and so that's a that's a new component
to the book what else are you adding in
what else are we covering oh my god I've
got so many new things about lighting
and sprouting and vegging and some
detailed information about the lighting
and photo periods like you said how to
do Sprouts clones uh all keeping with
the TLO methodology you know yeah I have
an extensive troubleshooting section
that I believe will handle any freaking
problem anybody can have that's killer
I'm pretty sure because I've seen for
the first two books I've seen a lot of
specific issues people have yeah it's
their own fault it's usually because of
they can't Source something you know
along those lines yeah well or they use
something that's not what I said to use
like a couple of people have really
boned themselves using kelp extract to
mix with their soil mix instead of kelp
meal ah yep do and that's a synthetic
process to make the extract right no no
no no no no kelp extract is it's all not
it's fine it's just
highly yeah obviously highly
concentrated okay you start adding four
cups of that to your soil you're done
potassium overdose is one of the ugliest
most horrible ways to lose your plants
because yeah it is it is an ugly ugly
death so now I know people are going to
kick my ass if I don't ask you about
your roadkill skunk you mentioned it
briefly where did you Source it uh what
was it like can you describe it a little
bit okay long ago in Northern California
I made lots of friends yeah when I went
to the uh
uh what was the cup the emerald Cup in
2013. yeah I uh got a hold of an old
friend of mine in Willits that I knew
had the skunk I knew he was a gatekeeper
of it I knew yeah
so he was you know paranoid skeptical he
kept calling me worldwide rev why is
that you know he just didn't dig the
fact that I was uh
uh so out of hiding yeah oh yeah yeah
for sure you know so he so there was
that aspect so anyway I worked on him
for a while about six months and we
finally made a deal I would trade him
some of my mohawken for some of his
skunk right
so we finally got together and he
finally did it he assured me that he
hadn't bastardized it you know it was
the original skunk line which I remember
when it was first before it was skunk it
was called red Russian right red Russian
okay that's what it was before everybody
realized how skunky it was and the rest
is history was there a Russian River up
there in North Carolina yeah that's
where that's part of why it was named
that yeah right off the Russian River
and uh and it was very red yeah makes
sense so uh so anyway so it's always had
from seeds from it it's always had kind
of a spread there's always some sweeter
some like body odor stinky feet ones and
then there's like really skunk you have
roadkill skunky ones there's pissier
ones there's even some with a little bit
of a sweet component to them although
those were very rare yeah with this plan
I've I've grown some of these out
several times now and I've get I'd get a
nice spread I get roadkill pretty often
I would say one in eight maybe yeah
but but I don't have enough of a numbers
of those spreads really say that for
sure yet yeah I've gotten it about one
and eight so far from three runs right
yeah so the roadkills the problem with
the skunk is that there's no way to tell
it's roadkill until two weeks before
Harvest yeah I know of no way yeah right
because there's no indicators nothing
else the all the turpents Stay Stay
changing oh I'm gonna have to plug this
in
that's all right I'm running a low
battery hang on we'll keep it going
let me see if I can
do this and not screw things up
I'm sure it'll be cool oh I'm a techno
wizard it'll be fine don't worry I got
this handled
come on baby
okay how's my audio perfect
all right because sometimes when you
plug it in the audio goes to hell yeah I
know you're good so let's talk about the
morphology of this skunk was it a a pure
Afghani was it a hybrid what did you see
from it I've heard three what I consider
to be legit stories for people I
consider to be trustworthy yeah so I'm
not really sure what it is yeah I the
one consistency that I have heard a lot
is that it was a South American cross to
the original Indica that came to
Northern California okay there was that
kind remember with the leafy florets yes
yeah right yeah that was all over
suddenly everybody had it right
and it was real purple and real gnarly
but uh somebody now the best I know is
that was crossed with a South American
okay that's what that's what originally
brought up the skunk line which was when
it was red Russian it was I hadn't even
skunk it was very resistant to things
like mold and Pottery mildew it didn't
have a problem with any of that stuff
and uh as it now that it's an IBL I
don't know 13 or 15 or 20. now it's got
some of those standard weaknesses that
go with it it's not so not so resistant
to everything anymore but it's still
pretty much the plant I remember you
know I mean granted that was a long time
ago and I am Mr Magoo yeah but from what
I remember it I would my best my best
estimate and feeling is that he did give
me the true one that he has inbred
himself yeah but like I said the skunk
has a thing where
it just won't it won't go where you
think it will go when you breed it it
won't yes it'll just do its standard
it'll just whip out bandwidths of the
different Terps the different
morphologies you know all of the
morphologies are close yeah Terps are
wide ranging you know there's there's a
lot the two killers are the body odor
stinky feet and the skunk yeah they are
soup now there's another one that I
remember that is also in these a Piney
one right yeah people love Pine super
Pine resin I mean really sharp it's
almost skunk yeah but Pine yeah yeah and
those are probably the most potent in
the bunch do you do you notice any
intersex traits specifically in that
line or any of the skunky stuff do you
ever notice that like for example
um so a lot of the the the lines that
we're seeing that have a lot of the
skunky traits whether it's me or CSI
we've been doing a lot of stuff almost
all of them are freaking full intersex
every time we run into that same terpene
profile a lot of the times it comes with
intersex traits heavy
I'm not sure I understand what you mean
by intersections
oh oh no no there no no there's no
there's my skunk is sexually healthy but
that's good to know that would not
surprise me because
when the skunk came out of course you
had to have it yeah of course yeah yeah
you had to have it yeah so everybody had
it and while I was associated with some
pretty damn decent breeders who were
teaching me stuff yeah that wasn't the
same for everyone right yeah of course
and so everybody and their mom was
breeding it I mean it just everybody did
so tons of it tons of the seeds of skunk
yeah flooded the market but you know you
got people who just uh they just can't
uh seem to
put in the work it takes to make sure
that you're not blowing Hermes or you
know any of it testing the line and
seeing what you've made any of it yeah
that's a lost art [ __ ] I do I do the
most deep inspection on unknown plants
if I have anything that I don't that I'm
not already totally familiar with man
I'm in there with my 30 times super
light magnifying glass every day
you know I'm looking close I'm seeing
because I can recognize what Hermes are
about to happen but right before they do
you know there's a little mutant growth
that occurs down at the axial intersects
you could see it's like a mutant growth
a mutant Leaf growth kind of
because it's not it it's different than
how a female typically grows when you
can see that yeah sort of like it's
trying to re-vege a little
so I for the viewers watching this I
want I want people to take note because
I often talk about like different things
you learn only through experience and
breeding and one of those if you'll
notice when when I'm sitting here
talking with my friend the rep he's
talking about you know I know this line
it's because I know the line I know what
I can see from it and it for someone who
isn't super experienced running a bunch
of different lines not only a bunch of
different lines but a bunch of the
different bass lines meaning Northern
Lights skunk one Haze a lot of these
land races it's hard to truly understand
until you've run them what it is when
you can truly start predicting and
that's what breeding is when you're able
to predict you know uh to to run your
lines and then to see it in action and
to realize okay I was either right or
wrong at this and make the next move
that's that's all breeding is and and
when you get to this point in your
career when you've been breeding 40 you
know 30 years a lot of this stuff comes
second hand and a lot of it becomes a
natural instinct as you're going through
these these things and there's there's
even stuff you're telling me about
different traits of the of the leaf
hairs on the cotyledons and stuff like
that I have never even thought of and I
spend all of my time looking at the
plants you know just constantly
observing and that's how you learn it's
constantly observing you don't want to
just let your plants you know leave them
in a room let it auto run for a week or
whatever if you're really into it learn
your plants every freaking stage that's
how you know and uh where rev is a great
example of that everything you've been
saying about that just reinforces that
100 right it's like when I was telling
you about my little hash trick earlier
it's like if you are a breeder who
doesn't really know your [ __ ] yet and
you're dealing with lines that you're
not really familiar with yet
the easiest way to do it is to pick
let's say four of the strongest best
vigorous females right yep grab a couple
of the strongest biggest best males
throw them all in and let them breed now
when they're about two weeks from
finishing
just go over them all with a magnifying
glass see who has the most resin get a
grip on them smell them you'll know the
smells by then right yeah everything
will be less because they'll be full of
seeds but you could take that into
consideration you
then go in and check them out then you
get a really good idea of what you're
dealing with who's better than who who's
likely to be the king who sucks right
yeah
you just recycle the plants that suck or
make hash or do whatever you want right
exactly make cash from those plants that
turn out good that I don't know anything
about but they're killer yeah I'll make
cash from so that I can further dissect
the exact resin profile relating to the
high type itself which is which is what
I cherish over everything else because
some weed just it makes me aggro train
wreck do that uh you know there's
different hash plants that can do that
for me the the the really super fast
flowering plants the ones that flower in
like six or seven weeks yeah yeah
those all have the exact same quality
for me of what I call aggro Weed right
yeah it's like I smoke them I get really
high really baked I'm all whoa this it
doesn't last long it only lasts like an
hour or something right yeah yeah then
you come out of it and man I'm like [ __ ]
I just said he mood yeah you know it's
like oh I just I don't like that yeah no
that's why we feel super fast flowering
ones man I just do do you think it's
maybe like it just hasn't had enough
time for the resin glands to mature in
different oils obviously because they're
afghanis they'll have different oils
than than these longer flowering sativas
but maybe that's what has something to
do with the high just not enough time
well certainly it has to do with uh you
know the type of high generally speaking
sure you know you have that to high I
just described that super up super fast
really [ __ ] up and then you're down
there I hate that yeah yeah it just bugs
me butts on a longer flowering Divas you
have much more different kinds of highs
yeah a lot of them come across much
different some are very evil some are
very happy you know some are very you
can't read a book because you have to
keep rereading the first paragraph 100
times that's my life
you know some are just like that so yeah
I like to get a grip on those smaller
assets of it I agree with you you
accidentally you absolutely I think it's
impossible to get a sativa
10 week plus high from anything that's
below seven weeks yeah no I could
believe you could do it in eight I can't
believe that yeah
the closest thing I've ever seen is a
Cindy right yeah yeah but so it would be
rare but yeah in order to get the kind
of highs I really like and I really look
for it's got to be a 10 weaker nine week
nine week exceptions I've seen twice in
my life
almost every single breeder or someone I
would consider a connoisseur weed that
has the experience has smoked a lot of
different strains like and knows what
they've been smoking they all tend to
lean to that 10 to 11 week high
everybody seems to kind of as we get
older I think also our bodies mature the
chemicals in our brains change and I
think we all tend to just kind of
navigate to that certain kind of high
typing and it's really really bizarre
but I've noticed it it's the best of
both worlds it's really where the
entertains meet you can it can go either
way that way yeah you can find anything
you like Plus
at 10 weeks you generally speaking
almost always have much longer legs
right yeah yeah the legs will be much
longer you get that six that via that V
black I'm telling you about not only
does that take 20 minutes to set in oh I
bet yeah 20 minutes that's wow it's
gonna be 20 minutes before you're like
holy [ __ ] before the rights like truly
starts yeah right yeah but then you're
gonna stay exactly that high there's no
wobbling it's gonna be like a freight
train it's going to go up slow and then
man you're not going to get off of that
for maybe five hours that's crazy yeah
cook you all day long
that is awesome it is it's one of my
favorites for going you know out on bike
rides or something you know oh I bet I
love that super long flowering sativa
tie V black anything like that the metal
Haze was killer for that the chunky
Cherry tie oh yes
so what's what's some of the current
work you're working on what is what's
some stuff you're really excited about
right now right now I'm just kind of in
a blurb where I'm just bringing up some
stuff to look at yeah I just I just
switched over my lights for winter so
I'm all back to my eye blue 6500 Kelvin
metal halide lamps yeah so once I once I
get those in I have to do a little
adjusting to my environment to make sure
I can run everything right because
they're freaking hot right yeah yeah and
I run tents so yeah so anyway I'm Donald
in so what I thought I would do was pop
up a few I've got uh right now just my
ones to have a look at right now that I
have up are some Afghani orange that's
so old I'm not sure if it's a hybrid of
Afghani oranges something else and I'm
not sure who gave it to me but I had it
in my four star can oh wow but it's so
old that the label wore off and all I
can read is Afghani orange was part of
it so I had to see what those were yeah
yeah and they look they look cool they
look good and then of course the G13
Haze right yeah oh yeah and I ended up I
planted like six I still got two more
seeds yeah if I had six I got four to
come up two died just you know how they
are with super super old seeds yeah it
just kind of came up and went in no yep
and then the other two which are a male
and a female and you know I don't wanna
jinx myself or any but they both look
really good yeah
so I'm testing though now I just popped
that G13 of flowering oh you bet I did
oh that's awesome I need to be I need to
be looking at that right and then on the
uh in the other 10 I started up some
cherry Thunder [ __ ] oh nice and some uh
Cindy black
which with the screen yeah nice yeah so
it so with my so here's what why because
in my head if my Vietnam Black skunk
doesn't work out how I think yeah then
I'm gonna try the Cindy black skunk and
see if I can lock in those [ __ ] skunk
turbines because something will do it
eventually we'll do it
I just have to find a gene that goes in
there and knocks them all cattywampus
and gets them to line up more uniform
for me yeah or a gene that somehow in
one strain makes that link trait to the
skunk smell have something you know what
I mean like a link trait that's good
with it brings it out
something that'll just stick right to it
and make it so I can recognize when it's
there exactly something visual a visual
marker visual early on a
marker expression is what I call them
and that would be super nice to have
because with the skunks at present
the Phoenix the morphology is you know
pretty random they're not they don't
have a wide range but there's a lot
different ones it's not an indicator if
nothing is locked to the roadkill and as
far as any patterns Leaf patterns
petiole patterns root size root density
root I cannot find anything that is only
visible with the roadkill skunk right
nothing so I'm like that pisses me off
because
as much as I don't mind flowering some
plants yeah I am used to and I do like
knowing early at least having a grip on
what I'm dealing with you know yeah yeah
yeah it's it I mean as a breeder and as
someone who has goals in their breeding
that's like that's the main part it's
never seen enough to know if I have to
take up 10 if I have to flower 10
females to find my my roadkill skunk
every time well that's not how I do
things yeah yeah that's it the whole
idea of becoming better and getting to
know what you're doing is to be able to
take shortcuts right right yeah yeah
yeah and that's that's the whole point
of the experience yeah
as I mean if you if you don't know
anything about breeding you can probably
do really well if you're just willing to
do the work flour out all the plants
first harvest them all sample them all
and then bring house save clones and
then just breed with those and you'll
probably have learned more than any most
other breeders out there in just that
one experience by going through taking
good notes smoking everything and
testing you'll you'll be more advanced
than 99 of seed makers I should say out
there I agree I agree and I I tell
people a million times you know you're
going to start out it's going to seem
like allow you know maybe take a lot of
notes to be able to but pretty soon
you're going to start to know a lot of
things just intuitively from what yes
you know it's you know it becomes much
easier especially like I said with mine
that I'm familiar with you know I can
tell when they're a month old a lot of
things I need to know right then
no I know which expressions are linked I
know which markers I'm looking for I
know which markers equal something I
don't want you know yeah and that's a
cool thing about keeping your little
Galapagos Island of gene pool it really
is because you've had all this time to
learn these specific strains to learn
how they breed and um when I tell people
to note your breeder this is what I'm
talking about you should be able to have
a competent conversation with your
breeder about their lines about the
history of their lines and if they're
passionate breeders if this is what they
love you should be able to have a
conversation like this and and this has
been an exceptional exceptional
conversation with you is there anything
else you want to get in and plug or talk
pardon me now is there anything else you
want to get in before the end of the
show and unplug or
well let's see with the new book I
should be able I should be submitting
the manuscript around I'm thinking first
half of December okay so that should be
able to put it in print by the spring I
think that's awesome so that would be
super cool if you want to get copy that
I mean with this book I you know in the
first two books one of the first things
I start out by saying is this is not a
girl book this is not to teach you how
to grow weed yes yes right this is
assuming you already know how to grow
weed and you want to grow it all
naturally and you want to grow up better
yeah yeah so but now in this book
I was able to not only organize it
better so after you've read it
as you're growing you can go wait a
minute what was you can actually find
what you're looking for because I kept
it all very Iceland to Chapters now good
so you can go and look and reference it
which is something the first two were
lacking because you know I'm kind of a
bozo I've never written a book before oh
it's hard man like whoa I can't even
imagine where you started but you think
it's going to be too you know together
yeah and the saddest part the saddest
part is that the easiest part is
actually writing the book yeah
billions and millions of times you have
to go back through it and rewrite
recheck update everything gets make sure
everything's you know you on track
because with TLO I mean I'm learning
things new things a couple times a month
I learned whoa the new you know because
I try new stuff all the time well you're
a pioneer of TLO
yeah and so so you know I'll be in the
book like I was halfway through the book
and I discovered something and I was
like oh [ __ ] so that's like that huh I
go oh so now I have to go through the
whole book read it front to halfway and
correct every reference I've made that's
relative to that and any spin-off
references that are relative to that
yeah so it becomes a lot of tedious work
but now it's I'm in my favorite part now
I love this part this is the home run
right here this is this is where I'm
just rolling through it from front to
back I'm correct in punctuation adding
photos just making sure everything is
you know paragraphs are good my
Punctuation is good I've said clearly
what I want to say yada yada so this is
the fun times this is all fun work now
do you have to do all the formatting
when writing your books and like where
the pictures go and formatting of the
text and everything or does someone else
do that I give a general format location
excuse me like a lot of times you know
when I'm talking about something and I'm
showing a picture reference to it yeah
yeah in the manuscript I note the photo
at that point yeah you know so that they
know I want to be somewhere real close
to that statement gotcha okay so so yeah
that works out good but they're they're
pretty good about just keeping it my way
you know they they try to work out
things what I do is I I give them like a
bunch of extra like bud shots that are
just I don't have any place for them I
just put them in an extra folder for
them and I go if you need to make space
to you know say so my paragraphs are
closer to my pictures I put in there
just use one of these bud shots to even
it all out you know yeah yeah yeah so so
that works out good for both of us shout
out to Green candy press they're they're
my favorite cannabis publisher they
publish your books um they did the The
Strain uh cannabis indica and Cannabis
sativa volumes yeah and the cannabis
grow guide and yep they do a lot of
stuff like that I mean they've always
they've always done me right they've
always treated me right they've always
done what they said and when they said
they'd do it they do it and uh I I first
got hooked up with them through John
over at skunk you know yeah yeah yeah
she was he was buddies with Andrew over
at Green candy so I just uh hooked up
with Andrew and I couldn't be happier
man he's a great guy everybody who works
there is great it's it's a lot it's it's
good working with those people you know
yeah I met them through you and when I
worked with them in the Cannabis indica
and sativa stuff they were fascinating I
mean they were just so kind and generous
and if I ever work with the book
publisher that's going to be the number
one one I go through because it's just
they're they're great people so I wanted
to give them a plug super easy to work
with and you know like he knows that I
would uh I've been struggling with
trying to finish the book you know I
just got my last hit from coven not too
long ago and uh [ __ ] it spun me hard I
didn't even get I just got like flu from
the first one you know but this one man
this last one and it gave me kind of
long covet I'm like extra fuzzy and
sleepy all right let's cover
um let's go over the the website before
we're done kingdomorganicseats.com can
you talk about it
okay yeah so something when you go to
Kingdom organic seeds there's a wide
variety of stuff there right yeah we
read closely because you know I'm
telling you the real deal here uh when
you read this take them seriously it's
not just a bunch of [ __ ] I've written on
there to make it sound good yeah it's
just it's the real deal so when you get
to the site you'll notice that up on the
top bar there'll be the strains right
that's all the strains well right next
to that is a button called Gambler
section yeah in this section is where
you can get basically untestedish stuff
that I know because I'm familiar with
it's probably gonna work out I don't
think I've ever had a bad Gambler so far
and there's been a lot of them yeah so
so you can get really good deals on
stuff before I really know what it's
what it's about you know whether it's a
a full head or a Miss but there's
nothing bad on there and you can get
some really good stuff on there a lot of
people just exclusive possibly hunt that
zone to get stuff for a good deal before
it comes in at the real price later down
the road so make sure and check that out
I bet I mean the thing is a gambler
section the way you word it is going to
be totally different from like a person
getting their clone their first time
Crossing it not testing it releasing it
these are clones you've worked with for
a long time so you have a pretty good
idea with these lights these are ones I
have high confidence are going to be
great they're going to be fine they're
going to be excellent and I have like I
said I have I haven't thrown a dud into
the Gambler section yet and I've thrown
I don't know 30 yeah
that's killer so um are you gonna
Venture into feminized seeds at all I
haven't asked you that let me see how do
I put this hell no oh no
no no no
hell hell no because
feminized seeds to me are sexually
unhealthy genetics there you go that's
that's all it's about to me and besides
Femme seeds are are bad because of their
sexual health to me yeah as a breeder
especially but I'm not a big fan of them
anyway they grow that's probably a
unfair bias because it was 15 or 20
years ago when I grew up and they sucked
pretty bad yeah they did so they've come
a long ways now but the one thing that I
really don't like and I have never liked
are Auto flowers oh Jesus yeah it's just
it's you know why because no matter what
it is all the ones I've ever tried
anyway remember when I told you about
those six or seven week plants yeah yeah
yeah flower six they all have the same
high type yep all auto flowers I don't
care if it's Thai Autoflower it all has
that exact same high to it so I just
think those are a great option for
somebody who needs them and just needs
to grow a little weed I could totally
see it but as a breeder or a connoisseur
I poo poo those yeah for sure yeah you
know I remember Neville said the same
thing that he just couldn't do anything
good with ruderalis everything just
turned into [ __ ] and I found this I
don't want to see [ __ ] because it would
be offensive to the people whose stuff I
used but it wasn't as good as the stuff
I was able to do with regular photo
period lines it is always subpar yeah
right it's always just below what it
should be it's like it reminds me of
back about a decade ago there was a
bunch of sativa that was suddenly
released from Sweden or something right
yeah yeah it was uh Acapulco Gold and
all this stuff right I got a pack of
that right away yeah and I grew it and I
thought you know this stuff looks pretty
legit to me but it's all watered down
yeah right whoever made it either was
hideous at selecting lazy at selecting
or just didn't care and just yeah
floured and bread whatever they grew you
know without really ever looking at it
because if you do it that way your resin
production will go down because you'll
be selecting for the strongest best
plants and the two don't really mix
right you're right yeah seldom have a
super vigorous wickedly beast-like plant
that is also incredibly potent yeah
exactly right usually they're they're
the medium or you know they're very
vigorous very uh and they're very very
potent you know yeah it's that energy on
the other end of the scale I run across
plants fairly often that are
psychopotent insane resin production but
[ __ ] talk about hard to grow they have
problems with everything just like with
anything people cows dogs you have you
have offspring that just suck yeah they
just they have problems you know
genetically heart defects nutrient
defects you know just the same with
plants you have individuals that just
never make the grade but a lot of times
those ones that [ __ ] them up are the
same ones that make them have massive
resin production yeah
well it's been an absolute pleasure
having you on here like I said you were
one of the people I looked up when I
looked up to when I got into this and I
still look up to and learn from you and
and it's an absolute privilege and a
pleasure to have you on I know people
will be begging to have you back and
again do we have the name of your new
book coming out and where it will be
available yeah it'll be true living
Organics it'll be the Druid guy the
Druid guy yeah it shows along with your
basic stuff like I said teaches you how
to grow in a lot more ways than the last
one did
it also shows
very high order High connoisseur High
Artisan value methods yeah ones that you
probably don't want to start out trying
to do to jump right into yeah basic the
basic lessons I show you in the book it
will come much easier like you said to
be a breeder isn't nearly as hard as you
think it's going to be reading about it
as when you actually get down and start
to do it you can actually you're like oh
that but you look at it on paper you're
like holy [ __ ] I'll never be able to do
this exactly yeah no you just got to
jump in and and learn and experience and
screw up and keep screwing up because
that's a lot of breeding is screw-ups
and if you're not screwing up then
you're not really breeding you're not
really doing real selections and then a
lot of people can't handle that they
screw up that they're human so they
blame the seeds or or the white or or
you know what they'll blame something
else anything yeah anything but them
right anything we've seen these emails
for years we know we're eye on the other
hand when I see something [ __ ] up I go
all right what have I done yeah yeah
that's my first instinct what have I
done yeah it's a different mindset it's
a different mindset well you learn
faster that way take example take
responsibility you're going to make
mistakes take responsibility and go how
can I not make this mistake again
exactly exactly that's what it's all
about these are the lessons from the
wise absolutely for sure if you want to
learn faster and actually learn stuff
that's the way to go [ __ ] it up don't be
scared to [ __ ] up don't be scared to
[ __ ] it up take responsibility learn how
not to [ __ ] it up next time and don't
cross the streams and don't cross the
stream
this is advice from the Rev thank you
from all of us at the breeder Syndicate
and uh we look forward to seeing you
again soon my friend I'll be happy to
come on again man it's been super fun
thanks a lot for having me all right
privilege and a pleasure thank you
everyone Cheers Cheers
right
[Music]