door so it's not sold out
all right
what's up everyone
waiting for not to go to join this uh
manscaping talk
he's really a master of pijazzling i
don't know if you guys are familiar with
pijazzling you might want to google it
but that's really naza's main talent is
uh the pijazzle
it's got to be past your bedtime hnl old
man
oh man
i think it's past nazos too
how's everyone doing
i'm in my undies too
i almost always am [ __ ] hate wearing
shorts on camera you know
so i'd keep it up here
keep it up this area
this
region
he always ignores him huh that's why i
gotta keep doing him
my goal is to make him [ __ ] die
laughing what's up curbside how you
doing dude
yeah the flannel backdrop yeah i haven't
even i haven't gotten the new podcast
room up it is now just full of [ __ ]
boxes after box after box after box
after box
so hopefully it'll be um
hopefully
it'll be up soon
i don't know about lazy where is he
there he is
technical difficulties testicle
difficulties over there something
alright actually
when you first started the video i was
like what if we did a whole live like
this
like that that'd be something that's how
you were like it was like the very top
of your head and like two eyes popping
out i could do it like this you just see
my [ __ ] wrinkles
hmm yeah i try to keep
it's hard too because i can't really
like wear my glasses and focus on
something this close yeah i can't even
but it makes it hard to like read
comments
yeah i try to wear glasses to read the
comments because that's what they're for
but it doesn't really help much anymore
it just [ __ ] me up i can't like see far
and super close at the same time yeah i
don't know what it is
so and then yeah i tried to join the
live but i think matt wanted to get his
bejazzling talk out of the way i did i
did i wanted to let them know that
without he wanted that as a monologue
where i didn't have any chance to object
or change the subject so
uh that was all that was all it was
either technical difficulties or
intentional on matt's part yeah i don't
know what it was um but yeah i know i
mean i was just talking about your new
hobby the the where you put your gems
and you just get nice adhesive and stick
it real hard and take pictures it was
[ __ ] it's pretty cool
i mean the people that can make a living
doing that
you know
i mean i got to make a living somehow
you know i would i you know i mean they
probably played they probably paid marky
mark a lot to pose on those calvin
kleins right yeah i would think so you
know okay so you would imagine so
yeah he's not packing heat like i am
though that's for sure no i mean i think
there was an unripe avocado involved or
something like that so it's all that's
for our leaf avocado colored
that's for artistic impressions
all right so what did we want to cover
today where do you want to start
uh well we we thought about it i did
that
we thought about uh
we thought about putting out like a few
different things people were requesting
certain stuff so
uh we'll pay attention to comments if we
can and we'll take questions and then
people were asking
about like uh because it's it's like a
big name like what what's some of the
super dog which i'm kind of tied into
story is about
and then what some of the kush story is
about yeah and it's like not to be we
probably won't get like massively in
depth in some kind of step by step
because there's a lot of
uh i don't know what would you do a lot
of toes to step on a lot of people with
money tied to their story about oj kush
so yeah but so so there's there's some
legends and there's competing tales and
there's stories that you kind of have to
choose who to believe again yeah um it's
it's one of the more complicated ones
and uh
but we can talk about like how it
impacted california which is kind of
really where it got famous
yeah you know
and uh you know kush
uh
i wow that's an interesting one i did
know chris oh yeah he has been uh he's
been missing for a super long time uh
his and his family still pays like
there's like hundreds of thousands of
dollars
yeah
i mean it's
one of those it's one of those things
that uh
someone asked weeks ago to do some
missing person stories or whatever and
it's like yeah there's people have
families and friends and loved ones and
stuff and
all that so yeah
it's probably not the most like
the coolest thing to chat about you know
the sensitive nature of that i'm sure
yeah kids and stuff left behind well no
i mean it's just more like you know
people you know it's like someone goes
missing you got friends and family that
love yeah yeah for sure and they don't
have any and and the reason why there's
a huge reward is they don't have closure
yeah yeah it's pretty horrible you know
and so that kind of stuff that kind of
stuff happens up here
yeah you know it's isolated and so yeah
i don't know but did you catch the
obsolete um posting pictures of hlv
infected seeds
you know i didn't but
uh you know i was actually strangely
enough we could talk about that for a
second because
uh it was probably two nights ago or
something i had a pretty long chat with
uh uh csi yeah and we were talking about
a bunch of different things and one of
the things that it's interesting is you
know as you know he's got a couple of
plants
uh that have dudding yeah right that are
just really old
and irreplaceable
yeah and so he keeps them but he keeps
them in a totally separate spot and all
that yeah right well anyway one of them
is uh one of them is calio yeah right
and so there's this rumor you know i
don't know if it's a rumor but there's a
there's uh tails going around that the
viroid uh duding viroid hl whatever the
[ __ ] you call it hplv or whatever yeah
past not only does it stay alive in
plants but it passes on to a certain
percentage of seed yeah it's i think the
the number is
from the hops people it was eight
percent of seeds it can be passed to but
that doesn't necessarily what people
don't understand is that doesn't
necessarily mean that eight percent of
your seeds that you pop are gonna
absolutely show it i mean
that it gives it eight percent chance
and it could be eight percent of the
seeds you didn't pop that you had you
know oh yeah i mean chances is like so
over a huge number of seeds
you're you know all things being equal
your seeds somewhere between like 50 50
male female or 60 40 yeah right over
over like a large lot like on a big
average but i mean i've popped like 26
seeds two packs of like mangoes haze and
got three girls yeah
yeah i have the same same stuff where
you get like zero females all males yeah
or vice versa you know the law of
averages on like a very small amount is
not that great but i will say the point
before i get to too distracted is
he grew out some of those hybrids
yeah
uh and he didn't see any he didn't he
didn't find any evidence of it yet
yes that's correct so i don't know i
don't know that
that's i don't want to say true but i
don't know how proven that is yeah i
don't know how proven that that eight
percent is and is that just hops is it
not necessarily cannabis which is a hops
you know relation
um
there's not enough science on it yet on
uh as it relates to just cannabis
yeah no one no one looks cool smoking
their vape so i try to hide it sometimes
sorry guys
yeah no no one looks cool
it is interesting um because
you know there's an aspect
him and i were also chatting about which
is like
there was an era where you didn't really
worry about uh disease or bugs too much
right powdery mildew was unheard of
there was no dudding there was anything
like that and there was this thing where
most people either
did their own clothes
yeah or only supplied their small little
tiny group of friends yeah right and so
a lot of times diseases or issues or
something like that were fairly
localized and didn't really you never
really heard about them to be honest
and then in like the 215 era uh when
people when lots of clubs started
selling racks of cuttings for like uh
for profit yeah a lot of people stopped
running their own veggies
stopped the cake taking care of their
own mother stock and their own clones
and everything like that yeah and just
decided [ __ ] that power in space i'm
just going to buy
clones
yeah for my next rip from you know my
friend at this shop
yeah
at smart cart yeah
yeah and you know and and certain
companies
you know and so that so in a way it's
like
those diseases made their way to like
certain like
nurseries and clearing houses that were
supplying a lot of clubs
yeah and they spread it all over and
they spread it to thousands of different
gardens yeah
and so then it kind of became this thing
where now
you see it on ig and all this there's
advertisements for viroid tests like
crazy yeah people are taking all kinds
of precautions we've had buddies that it
came in
and uh ripped through their rooms
um
there seems to be different different
strengths and different ones
uh most people don't understand uh what
a viroid even is
i think we've all everyone in our crew
has at least seen one dud over time to
be able to experience what that was and
now we all kind of [ __ ] know it sucks
yeah but i mean there was even a thing
where i was listening to a different and
an excerpt from a different podcast and
they were interviewing someone who uh
scientifically studied it right and they
were talking about the different methods
um because it's a it's not even a virus
it's a viroid it's like little bits of
rna or whatever yeah uh and it's like
for the most part it's like it's totally
fine and 99
isopropyl yeah
it's it doesn't kill it
yeah uh you know we've been i some a
couple of good friends of ours they had
some tech at their nurseries where they
had like the
the uh propane canister and the torch
that attaches to it yeah and they would
torch their their you know their
equipment plant to plant yep that
doesn't kill it no
you know [ __ ] i mean root to like like
what i saw was root uh like if they're
if you have a tray of clones and you've
taken all these different strains some
are more susceptible to catching it by
the roots and the water or it's the
[ __ ] razor blade or whatever you're
doing it spreads pretty [ __ ] bad
and so and so then there's an aspect
where it's like basically what they
found is that like
you know 10 or 15 percent bleach for 10
minutes does kill it
really yeah
but like uh uh h2o2 hydrogen peroxide
the strong [ __ ] yeah that doesn't kill
it alcohol doesn't kill it fire doesn't
kill it
uh there's something about the chemical
composition of uh
of bleach i wonder if the vine oxide
works there's this other stuff uh yeah
there's a few other things that that
cause that kill it but some of those
things are like really harsh on tools
yeah or you
you know so
uh but then the interesting thing about
bleach is if you buy like store bleach
uh yeah uh uh our buddies skunk just
said vicrons um if you buy if you buy
like uh clothing bleach
like sodium hypochloride that stuff only
stays good once you mix it for like i
don't know five to eight hours yeah and
then if it gets too dirty it goes inert
yeah
i remember like jungle boys jungle boys
was saying they were using i don't want
to get it wrong but it was um something
like sanidate or oxidate yeah it was
like one from that company xerox hall or
i remember yeah zero tall i remember i
spilled that [ __ ] pure on my [ __ ] leg
once oh
[ __ ] yeah
but you know for people now that we've
gone this far into it or whatever but
if you want to use a bleach solution
that stays a lot more lasting and
doesn't get [ __ ] up super fast like
your laundry bleach yeah uh get bleach
for pools
because that way that's calcium
hypochlorite
right and calcium hypochlorite is you
know pools are dirty you know they get
[ __ ] in them and stuff like that like as
far as you know dirt and leaves and
whatnot so it doesn't go inert the same
way sodium hypochlorite does yeah
but now people i mean i go i go to the
store and i buy
uh you know like a hundred pack of of
blades yeah and i just i i just add you
know yep every plant gets a new every
plant gets a new blade yeah it's a good
habit to make and you you know you uh
yeah and so
there's an act there's aspect to it
where it's like so what sucks is that
you know you go somewhere and you see
some really cool tech that somebody's
doing and you're like oh i'm going to
incorporate that into my own thing
and then you find out that it actually
doesn't work yeah
yeah yeah i tried with i tried with the
sanitate and oxidate on the
four-way and trinity cut because both of
those have the hlv and
not no dice hey natto
yes
i just want to wish you a happy pride
indeed
happy breakfast
that right there before i lose it
because it'll go off my screen every
plant gets its own rooting hormone yeah
taking all the precautions to actually
like
separate and not cross-contaminate
um it's a pain in the ass yeah it is and
it's basically like dipping in
you having a separate like thing a
clonex for every [ __ ] thing or
whatever yeah and then on top of that
then you're then you got to use rockwool
or you got to use the earth plugs or
something like an easy cloner yeah it's
like that's everywhere yeah that's if
you're done at that yeah that's like
making out with people with the flu yeah
you know and uh
you know and and so it's hard because
there's like real science and bro
science yes and for a long time we only
had bro science because real science
couldn't touch wheat i i can't tell you
how long i have heard that powdery
mildew plastic passes to seedlings like
that's bro science it's been bro science
for a long time so when i first heard
about the hlv thing i was very skeptical
you know because i'd seen a lot of
people breed with duds over the years
and never seen the duds pop up in seed
porn but apparently the hops people do
say it happen so
yeah and i mean that that obviously
still has to be checked and and proven
over time and that's how science is
right is it like it's the best
information you have and and you know
we'll we'll see i don't know where that
originates from yeah i know that's
stupidity i think uh you know
and uh well you know it
people to have to understand the life
cycle of things and like a viroid isn't
even a virus it's like little bits of
rna
yeah and so to have something so small
like that be able to just [ __ ] us up so
hard the skunk van knows i don't even
know what trans laminar means and i
probably should but i think that sounds
correct so translaminer
is there's two things right there's
vascular where it's moving through your
vascular system yeah yeah and then
there's translaminer which is
essentially like uh the the leaf surface
okay yeah that means right
so in some for for instance like to give
you an example of you could use a
certain kind of poison
yeah and it would be a contact killer or
maybe it would form a relationship and
be trans laminar and go on the leaf okay
and we're not systemic
that could be systemic though it could
it could have systemic translaminer and
you can have systemic vascular i know i
know systemic vascular but i never heard
i wouldn't think systemic would be just
leaf touching but i guess that makes
sense yeah you know well i mean it just
depends there's people humans have
figured out all kinds of different [ __ ]
yeah you know um but he's right in the
sense that pm is
you know it's like pm the hardest thing
is to break its life cycle yeah
you know um and that's what people don't
do
yeah you know they mostly break its life
cycle but then it like
you know i don't know i mean when you
live in mendo and you're surrounded by
vineyards and everything else and
everybody grows uh you know we got a
crash course 20 years ago in p.m
yeah you know i i wanted to make some
eagle 20 jokes but i can't even joke
about that [ __ ] anymore because people
take that [ __ ] soon yeah they said avid
is a uh avid is we used to call avid the
death
uh avid is a trans laminar yeah
systemic or whatever um
and you know 20 25 years ago someone is
systemic
yeah
because i last i i do remember that
spider mites are not susceptible to
things that are systemic because of how
deep they go into the leaf
no they're susceptible
i mean the issue the issue becomes
really with spider mites specifically
is that
20 25 30 years ago there was there's a
bunch of poisons for spider mites uh
that are you know all from pretty
natural to pretty toxic that worked
really well
and you know people overused these
toxins over and over and over again and
would dip their clones in it every time
and would just yeah they were trying to
take precautions
but what they bred was super mites yeah
i was pretty sure avid wasn't systemic
yeah it's one of the ones it's not um
just because it's not it's not systemic
doesn't work necessarily with spider
mites you don't need systemic so they
don't go that far so maybe people are
there's there's vascular systemic and
there's trans laminar
right and so
like when you think about it like if
something's a contact killer it means
that the bug has to come into contact to
kill it yeah right if there's something
that's trans laminar and like and uh um
and and persists within the leaf for a
period of time
it'll kill the bug for that length of
time that it persists if that's not
necessarily systemic if it stays in the
plant that's not a definition of
systemic
well i mean it's also one of those
things though that it's systemic in the
sense that uh your plant will test
positive for it for a long time
yeah yeah but i think there's something
specific about it not being systemic
like
what it what it actually is avid um yeah
i mean someone's amacloropid which is
the people used for root aphids or
whatever that stuff you can test like
that stuff will test dirty one to two
years later yeah that's crazy [ __ ] so
that's kind of maybe i mean maybe i'm
getting it wrong what i consider to be
systemic yeah is that if you apply it
and then weeks or months later you can
still test for it
yeah it's around
it's in the plant system somehow whether
that's the leaf system or the the you
know and maybe we can look it up and
maybe i'm totally [ __ ] yeah i don't
know i don't know it's always possible
but that's kind of how i that's kind of
how i view things is like things that
persist yeah i don't i have no clue to
be honest with you i just remember that
that the the old saying that systemic
stuff doesn't work on mites because they
don't go deep enough into the leaf yeah
someone just asked if you spray avid and
veg it will absolutely
um it will absolutely persist for some
time yeah and there used to be 80 to 90
days is right i should say i should say
this thing there used to be this thing
where
not to call anybody out or anything like
that but there was a lot of people that
supplied clubs
that knew exactly how many weeks you had
to go not spraying it to test totally
clean at the club oh yeah
and so they would do this thing where
like this gentleman just just asked can
you spray it and veg they would spray
the [ __ ] and veg
yeah
and veg for x amount of weeks and then
bloom for x amount of weeks and then
know that it would be clean
and then in order to in order to get
around that yeah uh the legal testing it
went from ppm to ppb
oh oh yeah that's right from parts per
million to parts per billion
and once it went to parts per billion it
[ __ ] every all those people's math and
all the rates they were using it and
everybody was hiding using it and
getting away with it
um you know and so now what's happened
is is that
a lot of these mites have survived
decades of people
spraying them with all kinds of funky
[ __ ] yeah yeah and so they're a lot
they're a lot stronger and they're a lot
more resistant in california than your
average might would be in the wild that
[ __ ] in san diego back in the day dude
they would drink out of it they'd take a
shot and say [ __ ] you you know like they
were they're brutal yeah i mean there's
there there's uh it's it's not
you know and then everything gets
overused
and just like anything else if you don't
actually eliminate the problem if you
just knock the problem down to low
levels
and you keep doing that over and over
and over again
eventually the ones that survive are
going to be better at resisting whatever
you're using yeah and it could be
totally organic it could be evil like uh
avid or forbid or kantos or
you know there's those aren't evil i
don't like being sued there's a
just in the sense of you know i mean
everything has its place i suppose but
yeah
and i don't want to be sad
but
well you know i mean all that stuff
comes from the only reason why that [ __ ]
exists is because it's all over your
[ __ ] food yeah yep
you know it doesn't exist for weed
people
all those all those crazy chemicals and
stuff eagle 20 and all that stuff it all
exists because it gets used all the time
in commercial food production yeah
that's why you could even buy it i
remember back in the day the big mix in
our old cruise i shouldn't even admit
this but it was a long time ago before
before you know a lot of the information
was available even though you could
smell it you could smell the toxicity
but it was a
phyton 27 and
spectrocyte immunox
yeah for some reason seemed to just
knock pm out but it would also murder
your [ __ ] plants you know yeah emunox
is kind of like a derivative it's like
another brand name for eagle 20. yep you
know
and uh yeah the eagle 20 gets sprayed
for grapes uh avid a lot of these things
are designed for ornamentals too yeah
yep you know uh you know points that
like the like the [ __ ] pgr [ __ ]
yeah right where everybody you know for
a while where if you were super
unethical and you wanted to get two or
three pounds of light and you didn't
care about quality you would pgr your
weed and it was
it had it had a bunch of names right
phospholoed or
you know there was there was a number of
companies that would all hide what it
actually was
and it's the same [ __ ] that makes like
when you walk into a grocery store
around christmas and all the poinsettias
are the same [ __ ] height to the inch
yeah that's because they got treated
with a pgr
yeah i mean i think i think the term pgr
has been demonized just like uh gmo or
anything like that whether it has sure
yeah i mean there are great pgrs and
you don't even know what you're talking
about because there are actually pgrs
that we all use that are decent i will
say
that uh a lot of the companies would
hide the
the
[ __ ]
uh what was on the label oh for sure
right sure and then eventually they they
got caught onto and they all got pulled
off the shelf or whatever
and uh uh sunlight supply came out with
one that they called dr nodes
and it was fully vetted through all the
all the various agencies right yep so
i uh my my buddy had a shop and they got
all these samples and one of the samples
was this bottle of dr notes
right
and i'm looking at it and it was a
bottle and it came in its own plastic
sheath that you kind of like almost like
a medicine thing that you had to rip
open and do that right yeah and one of
its warnings was
pregnant women should not touch the
bottle
right
that's safe
that's pretty heavy but like on the same
on the same tip
uh a natural pgr is kelp
yeah you apply too strong a kelp you'll
plan or do some weird [ __ ]
yeah so you're right in the sense that
it's just a term that exists yeah
what most people are thinking of when
they think of pgrs and weed is like
exactly like possible and like the name
is this long and it's methyl ethyl and
it has a bunch of parentheses and
hyphens
yeah yeah it's it's it's all it's all
kinds of bad [ __ ]
paclo you know i think it's the other
one
terrible
yeah uh and in addition to in addition
to um making your weeds super dense uh
it [ __ ] with your crystal content and
uh made your weed uh b grade yeah
definitely and there's a lot of
companies and this is even [ __ ] up
even if you weren't evil
uh and use the [ __ ] sorry if you used it
and i just called you evil but
they didn't put it on the label on lots
of things and then there's other
companies that would put it into like
bud blasters and things like that and
they would just put small amounts for
that extra oomph
yep
it's all part of that [ __ ] nutrient
game which yeah i mean after making the
spray um and and learning about
different nutrients how they're sold how
you get regulated how you get you know
omri listed all that stuff it's just
like to me like it was like learning
about the the vitamin
like like
what do they call it like when you go to
those muscle stores or whatever you can
buy all their supplements supplements
it's like stuff i'm sorry i have to i
have to interject too yeah uh you know
someone's couples couple people said uh
gravity and [ __ ] like that which is
definitely one of the things and then
someone was like yes it's illegal to not
have everything on the label yes
and you'll be shocked to know that
people making products for cannabis
people were willing to do something
illegal
and that not all of them had the highest
of ethical standards yeah but they got
that purple max though i mean that
gravity [ __ ] or whatever i i had a
friend uh
who literally was like an early
proponent of you know you'd probably
call living soil today yeah i was super
anal about inputs and all this different
stuff and so he comes in and he buys
some of that uh and all it says on the
label is kelp
yeah
but it had the full paclo in it oh sure
and so he goes out there and he makes a
whole resi and he waters all his beds
and he'd had those beds for like five
six years and had been developing them
every year and then he went and sprayed
him with paclo because it wasn't on the
it wasn't on the label he thought it was
killed and nobody knew to tell him
yeah you know
so
um yeah that some of that stuff was
insidious they were trying to sell you a
product that you'd buy again
yeah
yeah i mean and it's just like
i look at it like drug dealers who press
their pills and like you know double the
strength of their xanax of course people
are going to go back to that [ __ ]
dude if they want to get all super
[ __ ] up and die so i mean there's even
there's even pesticides that have gotten
caught
right that have gotten pulled from the
shelves in california uh because they
listed you know clove oil and this and
that whatever to kill bugs and then they
test it and it's got avid it's got
abimectin in there yeah yeah it's got tr
it's got low amounts of something that
really works
yeah
you know and then they just figure is
someone actually going to analyze my
secret sauce
probably especially people do
you know eventually people do i mean
there was a there's there's been times
where
like uh weights and measures has come
into growth stores yeah i bet
and by law you know if it says it's 40
ounces it better be 40 ounces if it says
it's x amount of pounds it better be
that
yeah and they'll pull all their [ __ ] off
the shelves
oh yeah because it doesn't weigh right
yeah i think people are asking about
powers i know that's a um
ortho solicitor or monosolicit um
acid it's it's it's uh it's a
silic basically what it is is it's
silica in a form that's a lot more
absorbable for the plant yeah there's a
lot of [ __ ]
there's a lot of silica out there that
is not that easily plant absorbable yeah
it's not available for cannabis unless
you reuse your soil for you yeah and so
and so as a result uh
there's there's a number cutting edge
has one um power c is one there's a
bunch of them that put it basically in a
different in a different suspension yeah
lack of a better way to put it uh that
makes it uh that makes silicoic acid
that makes it a little bit easier for
the roots and the plant to actually
uptake
yeah that's one of the few products like
that that i really actually visually can
see change within 24 hours of using it i
i was a big fan of it
it's expensive as [ __ ] but yeah people
are talking about and there's enzyme
products the market a lot longer right
now
uh enzyme enzyme products are uh
um i use them a bunch actually there's
nukem and and dr zimes and all these and
they're all basically this this their
enzymes that [ __ ] with the sh the
ecoskeleton of the pl of the bug
and there's citric acid in there yeah
right and they're really gentle and a
lot of more organic and they test clean
and they absolutely annihilate
uh powdery mildew
uh and they do a pretty good job killing
mites too
yeah i'm still i'm still a big proponent
now because of you of the um
what's that [ __ ] called the micro
sulfur micronized sulfur micronized
sulfur yeah yeah that's a truth
i mean micronized sulfur if you don't
use oils
yeah and you spray micronized sulfur i
learned that way you'll never uh you'll
never have russet mites uh or pm in your
veg ever yeah it was beautiful except
when i used them both together in the
same bottle like a absolute fool and
burped up every plant that i had
and well yeah they'll burn hairs though
that's why i said in veg yeah yeah for
sure you know you'll definitely uh
sulfur is a really uh distinctive aroma
and you definitely don't want to be
using sulfur for any reason much past
the first week
yeah once you start sand to me
uh it's it's not a good idea but in veg
when it's just all sticks and stems
you know and leaves it's organic it's
safe it's you know yeah
it uh it works really well
um i
totally got away from oils simply
because i like sulfur in the rotation as
a safety measure in the veg and plants
tend to like it a lot and i don't so i
don't use oils at all
because
god help you if you got russets or
something like that
um you know it'll it'll annihilate those
yeah it's i think it's safe to use
indoor but i don't like put on masks
when i spray either so what the [ __ ] do
i know it is safe to use indoor
um but i put i would put on masks
you know yeah even smart people put the
shipping on that there's a lot of stuff
quote-unquote that's safe
um that i might only put on like a
uh like a a snowboarding shell or
something to spray but i have a full
face mask with a visor and the whole bit
right yeah because it might be safe for
your plants but that doesn't mean your
lungs want it
yeah no i don't want to breathe in
wettables so i don't want to breathe in
anything
like on that level you know so i always
wear a mat i don't want in my eyes
either
yeah it's probably not good it's
probably why i'm [ __ ] blind to be
honest with you yeah i mean uh you know
it's uh
it
i just i you know did i always do that
no as i got older
yes as i've gotten older i've tried to
to be more i have a real nice i don't
know it's a two or three hundred dollar
full face mask or whatnot and even for
the most basic stuff i put it on
someone said they started using sulfur
because that guy who said sulfur is how
to get our gas turbs
i mean it'll definitely make your weed
smell and taste like a tire fire
yeah i mean if you use it wrong yeah if
you feed it
to the roots it does you know increase
terpenes whatever it has it's not going
to change somebody said yeah nukem nukem
and sulfur or nukem and dr zymes and
sulfur or whatever you can use them back
to back
there's not oil in there so you could
use it i've done it a bunch it's
completely safe the only thing something
happens when you combine oil and sulfur
it changes the ph on the plant and it
burns them to [ __ ] yeah it murders them
so
do you
uh sulfur is sulfur is very
uh very very safe
as long as no don't mix it with oil i
never usually do lines of um pure weight
if it's over 90 degrees sulfur can
really hurt your plants yeah for sure so
uh don't if you know uh
we me me and uh our buddy and i we uh
one of the fires in 2019 i think it was
2018 maybe
uh we had sprayed sulfur the night
before
and then the next day one of the biggest
fires in california history started a
couple hills over from us
and the first thing it did was burn out
a bunch of power poles
right
it was 108 degrees
and the lighting went out but so did the
air conditioning and all the fans and
everything we had because the power
poles bent and fell
yeah and it got real hot and we lost a
bunch of moms
um to sulphur
yeah from the day before
that's uh
there's a lot of things that's sucked
about that fire but yeah um i mean we
didn't have power at that spot for
almost two weeks
you know and it was june and you have a
debt and i mean there was problems there
was issues you know
yeah um so
but yeah i mean
uh people uh trying to read and talk or
whatever but
i didn't even think we actually
bullshitted for on a totally different
direction yeah that's all right yeah
don't get don't get sulfur on your
lights
you know um
but yeah sulfur sulfur works better than
anything i've ever seen against russet
mites
yeah it absolutely annihilates them and
it annihilates powdery mildew yeah i
never had rusted mites in my life so i
should knock on wood somewhere but
powdery mildew i you know was it's even
a problem in bakersfield where it's
super dry and i mean do you know that do
you know that they consider uh russet
mites ariel plankton
no that's weird you ever heard that word
aerial plankton no but
so area so obviously plankton in the
ocean yeah they just get carried around
by the currents
yeah right
russets are so small they can get just
carried by wind currents for long
distances
yeah they're that's why they call them
aerial plankton because it's like living
things that are just getting carried
along by current in this case wind
current
so you could have a neighbor a couple
hills over
and the wind could be going the wrong
way and they could definitely start
blowing off their plants and right up
the hill and right up into your ship
yeah
and that's how a lot of people got them
in mendo actually was they spread
neighbor to neighbor farm to farm
you'd be you'd be downwind from someone
and about july august their garden would
[ __ ] you
yeah
and so you could take all the
precautions in the world about
quarantine and bringing in clean stuff
and not allowing pests in you know
and then they came in on the wind
ain't that a [ __ ]
so somebody just said uh spin assad i'm
sure there's there's uh
i'm sure there is
spinosad is a cool story actually i
don't know if you've ever heard it but
spinozad is like a uh
is basically a bug killing uh fungus
yeah right
and they discovered it in the caribbean
right
uh there was an old uh rum mill
and they went into this big old factory
you know rum factory
and they noticed there was no bugs
yeah although there was like zero no
spiders no bugs of any kind so they took
soil samples and they found spinosad a
and d
yeah and uh that's what that's what when
you buy spinosad that's what that's what
it comes from it comes from them
discovering this thing right yeah
um but
the reason why you shouldn't [ __ ] use
it is that it is
rel it is terrible first beats
yeah it is one of the most toxic things
for bees
um so it's safe for you and it's safe
for people and and animals and all that
type of stuff but
it'll take out a whole beehive that
sucks
um so it's not it's not uh
you know i mean i guess if you were
indoor
you could safely use it on your plants
yeah um and you really wouldn't have too
much risk or be or you know be an
[ __ ] about it but yeah uh if you're
gonna spray it on a bunch of your um
your depths or your outdoors or
something like that you'll put you might
kill
the natural bees all in your area
you might just take them off
yeah and they they have their own they
have they have enough struggles going on
right now bee populations with a lot of
things that are [ __ ] with them so
yeah um
i would definitely i i could never in
in good conscience recommend somebody
use it in their depth or their outside
yeah you know i don't want to hear some
[ __ ] on og when we can get to that sucka
we're there i mean i don't know we just
we just took it and we just took it in
that direction uh but you know there's a
bunch of people listening so if if we
talked about certain things and and why
not to use them that's cool too yeah uh
and that's the reason when people say
oklahoma or california there's testing
for it it's not because it's harmful to
humans
it's because bees pollinate half of our
food sources yeah and so we really
really don't want them to die
yeah
and they are dying at a rapid rate and
they're dying at a rapid rate from a
bunch of different issues and from a
bunch of exposure to toxins and
pesticides and herbicides
and other and other stresses or whatever
and literally there's an immense amount
of stuff that you eat that wouldn't get
pollinated if it wasn't for bees yeah so
spraying a [ __ ] ton of
bee killer
you know yeah it's a little rough
so
um
all right so we can we can talk we can
talk about kush uh oh this already just
i just totally changed my mind and don't
want to talk about it at all from oh my
god i'm just kidding yeah i know but
yeah so but yeah but i mean it it there
could be there could be now that we've
been chatting about it for a while yeah
you know not right now but like our
experiences in the future or people want
to know about pesticide or or tech or
how to beat certain things or what works
or what doesn't um living up here
surrounded by growers i mean i've kind
of seen about just about everything
tried
yeah and you start to poke around and
what works and what doesn't what what
are the downsides to this thing
yeah because most things have downsides
you know so you got to pick which ones
you're okay with yeah you know
definitely but
if people want to hear about og
yeah like a lot of things or like a lot
of famous stories
um it's not mine or matt's story no
i have nothing to do with og
by any means
you know but we you know what we thought
like
so
there's there's like the the most
mysterious part about it is the is the
florida history
right it starts getting a little bit
more definitive and understood once it
got to california yeah yeah right so
what we thought is like obviously this
is like i mean there's been whole shows
where people
confidently talk about the origins of og
and this and that and everything else
and there's a bunch of stories because
it's so famous
of various people trying to like claim
yes
right there's somebody in hawaii hawaii
who says his dad did it
you know uh that's my favorite there's
no no my favorite was was
was the underground bunker frank giga
story that frankie gax said is not true
that was my personal favorite so there's
there's there's the like there's a story
that it's neville work that got sent to
hawaii
yeah and made his way to florida from
there neville did have apparently many
backups everywhere yeah there's uh
there's uh
you know there's a story like he just
said that you know frank is a guy that
had a bunch of
uh basically undergrounds and warehouses
and big grows
uh in the southwest uh you know uh
united states arizona arizona and new
mexico issue and all that and um
there's rumor that it came from there
uh it certainly seems guaranteed to have
come from florida people
coming out this way
me and fatty did meet uh old dave
richards he was there when when i met
that guy and he was still he he had a
circle around him telling the tales of
og and how he [ __ ] made it
i mean i i've met i've met uh dave
richards he's a character did you meet
him yeah i met him he's he smokes black
and milds on one of those [ __ ] things
yeah yeah he's i liked him in person
like there's i'm not even gonna lie like
he's a funny dude like he's he's
personable yeah he's personable it's
hard not to like him but when i first
realized how much he was lying to me i
was like okay
come on dude like it was so easy to snap
he's personable and so there's a there's
an aspect where
mark's castle yes that's another claim
that's right
anyway there's
basically what it boils down to is that
kush became
one of those things that ended up being
so famous and made so many people money
that there's a lot of people invested in
trying to be like
you should give me rep because my crew
or my family or my whatever my friends
are the ones that brought this to the
world yes
and so people come out of the woodwork
you know i mean uh and i'm not trying to
call individuals out but it's like
there's everything from those crazy
stories we told you
to the one that matt and i tend to
believe which there was like an accident
and a closet and it came out of some bag
seed
you know to
uh ever-changing story from tk origins
uh with different years and different
plants and different certainties
you know um and you know it's also
possible too that like it's
you know it's it went it was it was
strained by a different name
and now we just know it is kush yes
you know i mean we we you know neville
told uh neville told matt that he
thought that most of the american cush
stuff was based off his kush 4 and l2
yes yeah you know and it was all just it
was all just phenos of that he just
thought it was nl2 expression out of
that yeah you thought this is nl2 this
is mine obvious
right and so you know and then you know
there's
so there's all these different things
but what regardless of all that uh
you know
um yeah someone you know uh there's uh
there's a bunch of rumor
yeah and since we don't know any of the
parents
right it allows basically anyone to step
in and say
[ __ ] this is the story
well i mean i also think because the way
og expresses being long and lanky with
dense snug so it looks like what we
would just consider traditionally as
like a sativa because it's so long and
lenky but then it has these dense
nugs and resin like an afghani so it's
really easy to just make up [ __ ] and
be like that's a [ __ ] nepalese and
just some random sativa and some random
afghani you know so maybe we'll go way
the [ __ ] back for a second okay right
start start at the back we'll start at
the very beginning
okay so
the very beginning of kush in america
and we have no idea if this relates to
the cush that everyone is familiar with
but people would bring back seed from
the hindu kush mountain region of
afghanistan and pakistan
and those mountain valleys had the kush
yes right and that was the first term
sam skunk man had a hindu kush
that was the hindu kush mountain region
yeah the hindu kush mountain region uh
the indian supposedly gave seattle greg
a kush that got put into nl2
um you know uh there's various ones
right and
so
it used to be a generalized term for a
region
yes right where now if you fast forward
40 years today
it basically goes back to
you know uh the kush that went to la
the tk
that type of thing is like that's what
everyone thinks of as kush yeah so it
went from like a region and all these
different afghans within that region yes
to like a very specific phenoexpression
and look
yes was kush and so now if you talk
about kush today you're not talking
about the region anymore with anyone
right yeah they're specifically talking
about
a specific phenotypic expression and a
look and there's variance within that
look but it's got some key
characteristics and one second i just
for everyone that keeps mentioning the
packy lemon tie i will tell the actual
story behind how that how that came to
be and you it you'll laugh your ass off
so let's continue so so anyway so it
started off as it started off as a
region
right
and maybe we should talk about the
region for just a second because it
might interest people right okay so
i i have this theory and i've and i've
seen it in some different places and all
that and
like
and we've bounced it around and i would
so i wouldn't say it's like a a theory
that's like you know you couldn't poke
holes in but i think it can hold
generally true
where if you look at afghanistan there
is parts of afghanistan that are
anywhere from sea level all the way up
to 10 000 feet yeah
right there's a lot of different
elevations so like mazar uh that region
that's maybe only 800 feet above sea
level
yes but there's areas in the hindu kush
valleys that are five six seven thousand
feet where they grow vegetables and
wheat yeah and so what tends to be is
that when you get the lowland afghans
that are in the foothills or the plains
or sea level in pakistan or afghanistan
they tend to be these squat
bigger
like fluffier
plants with much wider leaves
right they're not as dense
um they're growing in more humid areas
right a little bit um and they're lower
to the ground and they have these big
fat wide leaves and then you get up into
these high mountain regions
okay which also has afghans and those
afghans kind of sound a lot like what
matt described with the kush that
everyone's familiar with yeah skinny
leaves but indica
right not not big fat wide leaves but
skinny leaves
golf ball type much tighter type nugs
right yeah and you think about the
environment that they're in very cold
colder drier a lot more uv
right yeah and so the leaves are smaller
because catching all that uv is bad
yes the intensity is more i think i
think well i was talking about this with
csi because i don't have a lot of uh
experience with outdoor other than a few
you know like uh depth runs in san diego
but
i noticed that even with the nl5s
they're expressing way more narrow
outdoors and it's just a trait that
outdoors because of humidity and other
other things and transpiration they're
just naturally more narrow there's gonna
be there's the plant's gonna have a
range of expressions based on all kinds
of factors yeah uh and you know uh homie
just said you know uv protection the
higher up you go in elevation the less
atmosphere there is the less uv is
filtered out
yeah right
and so obviously even though the plant
might come from afghanistan if it
developed in a valley that's six or
seven thousand feet above sea level
and it's a mountain region that kind of
cold and day night temperatures and a
lot of things it's going to have
different breeding pressures and
different plants that are successful
yeah versus a lowland plant from the
plain that gets you know moisture off
the ocean
that's going to be a different kind of
plan
yeah and i think there's a lot of
misconception where people think all
thin leaf is sativa
and the broader and fatter it is the
more indica it is yeah you can have
narrow leaf pure indica
yeah
you know it just happens to it's just
usually highland weed
yeah
not lowland weed
you know and i think that's a big
misconception
yeah for a lot of people
yeah i think right as a major
misconception yeah is is all indica and
all afghan the broader the broader is
the more afghan
and the narrowers the more sativa yeah
you know and maybe if you a broad leaf
afghan to a narrow leaf sativa that
would be true in the children
yeah
you know um and so now so so anyway so
there's
highland afghan there's a lot of there's
a lot of mountain valley weed
yeah and there was a lot there was a
bunch of weed coming over to america
called hindu kush
because that was the big mountain range
and all the valleys that uh that it came
from yeah and dirty old sag is saying
there's hash plants because those were
all hash plants all those i love
lebanese my red leaf that i had was also
a narrow leaf but it grew like a a big
afghan sideways it was real [ __ ]
weird yeah yeah and so there's just you
know like a lot of times and it makes
sense like you read books and you see
what you're familiar with in america
right and there's certain assumptions
that get made but they're not always the
true ones
yeah
you know um and
you know and and you know narrow it and
and what i mean by narrow leaf is just
like obviously there's a range
yeah bodhi has a lot of really good
narrow leaf afghanis and pakis he's put
out if people are interested
yeah and so it's just and and so a lot
of times i
i believe very strongly i can't say it's
a hundred percent fact but i believe
very strongly that almost all those
narrow leaf indica types
developed in high altitude regions
of those mountain ranges where they
didn't need as much leaf to capture
light
they needed less of it right because
each leaf has a job right yeah it's
there to transpire water and it's there
to catch sunlight pet trees and water
transportation
yeah if it if it uh
um
on my buddy i was visiting my friend
yesterday and he was showing me an
afghan and it was thin leafed and fluffy
as hell yeah yeah so you know the leaf
has a job and if it's way up there in
the mountain valleys and it can do its
job on a skinny leaf then it's not going
to put a bunch of effort into growing a
big fat
thick leaf yeah
is there no narrow leaf indica type or
hybrid oracle expresses many different
ways i've seen it be narrow and i've
seen it be broad
so one of those that it depends on the
room the environment how
narrow or broad it is so just as a
general thing um a lot of times people
you know people judge narrow or wide
based on and and make guesses based on
how sativa or how indica but that's not
the whole story yeah and i honestly
think that can tell the story about the
[ __ ] and the tie
yeah i honestly think some of the some
of the
the kush that we're familiar with some
of its narrow leaf characteristics
um led people to believe there was
sativa in it
yeah i think i think the stretchiness
and all that [ __ ]
and definitely it wasn't as broad as a
lot of afghans despite the density
but the story
originated from
there were two brothers back in the day
that went by brothel brothers
and one would call himself kailua kid
and the other called himself nyc kid
both i think are still around i know nyc
kid is still
but back then
uh kailua kid who also went later on to
start trichome kings and a few other
things and paradise seeds mod was
another name of his
he made the claim that he brought og and
that it was pakistani crossed a lemon
tie
lemon thai was a dutch flower string and
i mean there are ties that are lemony
but the one he was referring to was a
dutch flower strain and he's not in
[ __ ] og kush um is this that's one of
the oldest stories that's been shot down
more than almost any og kush origin
story but to this day
to this day people still [ __ ] repeat
that [ __ ]
ad nauseam because they don't know that
the guy was a major scammer that started
the story he's [ __ ] all of us all of
us back in the day um and he made a lot
of claims about asian fantasy and all
kinds of other stupid [ __ ] it was just
what he did uh i remember at one point
he was selling seeds he called
dog dog bud s ones and then i kind of
called him out on he's like well [ __ ] i
don't know man i got him in a bag
labeled dog doggy doggy bud weed you
know close enough
so this is the guy that they're relying
on for that story uh the the second
story that we were talking about the
frank giga story it was started by a guy
named dave richards um and he told the
story on adam dunn he came out he
actually i believe adam dunn at one of
the adam dunn cups gave him a lifetime
achievement award for breeding and and
bringing og kush to the masses
um unfortunately dave richards made a
lot of mistakes one of the first ones
was that it was a it was a hash plant
thai afghani which he kept referring to
as htf now htaf is an old term from dj
short referring to highland thai afghani
so he was confabulating different stuff
to make his story he also said that
frank gigaax left a book behind
with the breeding tips on og kush and
everything about it when i spoke to
frank gigaax directly and his daughter i
went to lunch with his daughter and
breakfast we went to a few different
things but um i talked to frank g gax
over the phone and he said that he wrote
that book as a grow book for dummies in
prison because he had nothing else to do
so
dave's store and also frankie got said
they never bred there it was only
commercial production and it was he gave
a few different lines i want to say it
was like nl
for something weird that i i don't think
you probably had um big budge skunk one
and something else he said we did no
breeding there whatsoever and he
completely smashed that story to
smithereens um but still people again
repeat it constantly to this day as
truth because it was aired once on a
show you know um but those are the
probably two of the biggest ones the the
third being
uh the creepy story and that's just
silly like i mean i i don't think
anybody that's been around a long time
even gives that dude any kind of
credit yeah it's not even worth the
dressing to be honest with you on the
creepy thing
i mean what you know and then there's
there's there's the story of how
you know there was accidental
pollinations in florida
um and so really what what it seems like
it does seem
to me at least
is that
i do believe that there was multiple
people that brought kush from florida to
california
yeah
i think that's factual
right yeah um
you know we're you know because
obviously people know about cornbread
ricky and tk
yes right he sent that out before he
came out physically himself to the state
yeah um people know about
uh
uh matt bubba and uh and uh bubba kush
and uh josh d
i'll say i'll say
flat out when i when i first talked to
matt i thought he was full of [ __ ]
because he comes off like a little bit
of a used car salesman when you talk to
him he's very friendly but it's his it's
like his nature so i didn't believe him
but everything that i've ever
researched and found is he has not been
wrong once and and as much as i was
biased against him i've told him dude
like i can't poke holes in your story
unfortunately like i don't believe you
but i can't poke holes in it so i'm left
with a truth
so
so there's an aspect where
and bubba bubba and that kush that went
to la became very famous tk became very
famous uh there's a strain that got sent
to the bay uh that we called the florida
uh that i've chatted about before and i
posted about um that went into cookie uh
and so
what we don't know for sure
uh uh irene irene comes a little bit
later but that's another beautiful cush
strain um but
there are there were multiple people
that got pushed to california to
different people at different years we
don't know huh let's slow down real
quick because i think i think people
would be interested in the irene story a
little bit don't you think
sure 100 yeah well so irene i'll let you
tell it because yeah go for it so the
original irene is as as best i can
remember i wish rude boy was here right
now but um the original irene was picked
from a bag of weed that went from
california to atlanta and what was kind
of cool was that we were able to link up
resin lung and his crew with the atlanta
crew and how they were shipped
i'm not going to say it i think we said
it a few times but you can figure it out
anyway they shipped it a certain way and
it was so unique that when they were
both telling the story it was like holy
[ __ ] there's no way they just made that
one up it was something that nobody
would think of um it was originally from
a bag of wheat and i want to say
either the first irene was from a bag of
larry og or the second irene that they
picked after they lost the first irene
they picked another selection that was
the most similar to the first one and
that came out of larioge if i remember
correctly but that's the rough story the
irene that we have now is what we would
consider irene ii
and that's the one almost everyone has
grown only a few people like smoked a
herb and rude boy
really experienced the first diary
so yeah so there's so basically
if you move past the uh the the origin
stories
right right of who's responsible for it
or where it came from yeah of which
there are many
um there was it does seem like the stuff
that we know of
uh made its way from
florida to california yeah and we don't
know
exactly if all those things were the
same cut
or there was multiple cuts that came out
or there is possibility that there's a
cut that shared a name
and was called different things by
different crews those are totally
possible right yeah but
uh what really happened is
you know uh
bubba kush matt bubba he brought he him
and josh d brought out bubba and that
and a couple other strains from florida
to uh uh
a neighborhood out in l.a right
and um they started growing some rooms
of it
yeah right and
what happened i think in la is that
la is such a is such a hype town
and it's it's it's so about flash and
it's so about like who has what
whether it's alcohol or cars or watches
or clothes or
whatever
that yeah kush caught on with a certain
clientele
and then everybody had to have it
yeah and then so demand went through the
roof
and
you know there was only so much of it
being grown
uh and so wholesale became crazy
right yeah and then so it became worth a
lot i mean what was what was uh
you know what what was it going for back
like 7200 yeah it was wholesale okay 68k
yeah
you know
yeah six six to eight k right yeah and
so and if and it gave you status if you
had it
right and so it just became this craze
yeah in a sense and in the beginning
there wasn't very many
right yeah and
the nature of la we've talked about this
before with seed companies but the
nature of la
uh to everybody
to pop up with their own [ __ ] nobody
down there wanted to give anybody else
credit for how they got theirs yeah of
course so
the [ __ ] and the and the stories
started happening immediately yeah you
know and the bubba just so everybody
knows the bubba that that matt bubba
brought out
it died by 98.
yeah the bubba that everybody has now is
not the first bubba that came to
came out there
uh luckily bubba is is such a specific
type and breed's so true it's probably
something similar but yeah
so i mean they found the i believe the
story is it might even be somebody like
rascal or somebody like that someone
found someone tied in found
bag seat
in original bubba
huh i don't know not shaw no i
uh
they
well i think the thing is is that and i
think that's why i got named bubba kush
because they thought kush pollinated the
bubba
yeah i think matt bubba's story if i
remember correctly
he can correct me on this is that bubba
is a hybrid bubba kush is a hybrid of
bubba and og nog kush yes yeah so the
original order lights so the original
bubba that came out is no more yeah
everybody has like everybody regardless
of how you want to believe the story
according to matt who brought it out
they lost the first plant that they
called bubba yes and bubba kush is a
hybrid of that plant yeah
right yeah
yeah it's a hybrid that's kind of it and
so to get really confusing
within five or ten years of this plant
hitting la
there was a whole family of what you
call purecush
right yep uh malibu purekush to pancake
canyon pure kush i don't know about all
that i only knew of one pure kush in
southern california and it was called
pure kush it wasn't like
it wasn't [ __ ] there was no hollywood
no malibu no malibu no
no
it was called purekush and it was a
linky sog and then there was og and then
there was and then there was kush and
then there's og kush and then then all
of a sudden there's a there's a there's
a valley cut there's the sfv
there's a larry there's this there's
that there's
all of a sudden the names start
proliferating right yep to the point
where i don't know by
you know 0.050607
um there was probably mo the clubs and
it was so popular that probably most of
what club sold in los angeles was kush
yeah and there was probably 20 or 30
different kush's on the menu
yeah
and so we really don't know how many
original things these things started
from
i mean we have a buddy uh that uh that
came to uh
um came to our one of our canned
illuminati parties right remember and he
was telling the story about about how
he had bought a couple of pounds of kush
for 8 000 bucks
right
and he brought it home and he starts
breaking up the weed and a couple of
seeds fall out yeah and then he's
looking at two seeds
from an eight thousand dollar pound that
nobody can get
yeah and so he spent the next two days
looking at every bud for a seat
and that became i think the poison o.g
oh yeah casas yeah yeah yeah poison but
that's what he said he said he bought
two pounds for sixteen thousand bucks
yes yeah and he goes dude i'm just
rolling my first joint at home and i
hear a seed hit the table and roll and
i'm looking at this seed and i'm like i
just spent
eight grand a pound
yeah wonder if there's more seeds
what if the weed looks like this yeah
and so every every seed you know and we
have a good buddy
um who got the kush
in 99 we think right yeah yeah he's 99
somewhere between 99. he's tied into
some of the first people outside of
outside of matt and josh d that got it
yeah in los angeles and it was one of
the guys mansion craze yeah and one of
the guy and one one of the people
intimately involved in running it very
early on
um and uh so we heard a lot of a lot of
tales from him
about uh
sort of like how it spread and how it
started and what it was like and
the politics and the clubs
right a lot of times clubs would name
something
because they wanted to be the only club
with the louie
or the only club with this and he has
this funny story i can't tell it like
him and he has a great accent i could
never tell anything like that there was
someone there was some armenian that you
know he would always joke about and like
he would be like let me give him a hug
and he would be like 250
that's what he wanted for one rooted
snip of his og that he had yeah right
and uh
you know and so
um you know it's uh uh yeah but imagine
paying eight thousand dollars a pound
and you find it seated to him that just
meant he was going to be able to grow
some of those seeds yeah and grow his
own 8 000 pounds yeah he was excited as
all [ __ ] get out
yeah you know he was stoked
because that gave him away where it's
like before it was like there was you
think about the demand of l.a and how
many people live in los angeles
yeah and how much wealth there is and
when there's only a few garages or a few
rooms of these things cracking
it goes [ __ ] lickety-split
yeah
yeah there's there's way more demand and
so changed weed for from then on
and so maybe we should maybe we should
take a step back from the story because
you know there's lots of people that
like to talk specifics about the origins
and how they're tied into it and all
that [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah whatever
specific cuts
but what happened is is because that
weed was worth so much money
and because it became so popular in this
area that had like 25 million humans
yeah and it's sort of like a pop culture
like you know melting pot for lack of a
better term right yeah um
[ __ ] blew up
and then all of a sudden all these
different names popped up and everyone
wanted to have their own and then what
that also started doing was because
brokers could make more money off kush
they started pushing all these people
800 miles away in mendocino and humboldt
and stuff county right yes to grow weed
that they could make more money off
yep and they didn't want
i mean you know like my buddy who gave
me the flowrider
he didn't do it out of generosity
he did it because i was giving him the
superdog and the dog and the maui and
the super skunk and different things
and he had this kush that he could make
way better margin on
yeah
so he was like give me that grow this he
didn't tell me he was gonna make way
more money
yeah i didn't even know that that was
the rake down there
right yeah but what it did is it pushed
a lot of people to start growing similar
stuff to feed the market
yeah and the purple the purple craze
that we talked about before with caleb
and all that that sort of started like
the do you have this clone only and you
better have it and if you have this
specific clone only i'll buy all your
wheat
and if you don't it's going to be less
and maybe maybe i will maybe i won't
yeah right and kush was another wave
just like that
yeah you could sell every gram of kush
you had
and so brokers started going around and
started trying to giving their i mean
like who [ __ ] ghost
right there was people that sold
cuts of kush for thirty to fifty
thousand hundred thousand two hundred
thousand dollars
yeah and people
yeah because they could then they could
fill rooms with it and it was like an
investment
yep there was violence over cush
which is how the you know i mean i don't
we don't really like to tell that story
too much but it does seem like the what
i call the 56 day headband
yep
started out name named something else in
the cush crew yeah and there was some
stress and some violence and some
whatever and they fled the they fled to
the bay
and they wanted to call it something
else so they didn't get in trouble for
it
yep and they chose the name headband
right
uh you know and then
you know there's a lot of people that oh
well what what cut we should talk about
this too
i firmly believe that the cut that josh
brought to
la first with matt
it's really hard to figure out the
lineage
what do you mean as far as like what's
actually in it yeah there's a bunch of
people that think when they get ghost
that that's it
yeah oh yeah yeah there's a bunch of
people that think when they get 92 og
that that's it there's a bunch of people
that think that they pop josh d og seeds
that it's but forget about that one for
a minute i'm just saying
some people think sfv
some people think josh some people think
ghost some people think 92 right someone
mentioned that earlier again you know
um and our buddy said he doesn't think
any of those are it
yeah
right yeah so what happened in la is
everybody came up with all these
different names it's not even like
there's one sfe there's a few that float
around oh yeah
there's not just one there's not one top
oh not one larry yeah for sure there's
multiples so what you consider is like
sfv is it
there might have been one time when when
it was called it but a lot of what's
currently circulated right now is that
isn't it yeah
and some of the people that bought ghost
off ghosts like 20 years ago for high
dollar they don't think the ghost cut is
it
let's get passed around that's not what
they got 20 years ago
well the guy that goes around his ghost
now that people talk about is not the
same ghost that had the cut and traded
with oregon kid from michigan most
people confused this cali guy with the
original guy yeah there's a lot of first
go
the ghost cut right now isn't the first
ghost cut and what everybody knows is
ghost grow isn't the first ghost that
passed the ghost cut who now lives in
the midwest again
yeah i don't even know if ghost grows
the same one as the one that was going
around calling himself callie kush farms
that wasn't the michigan ghost the
michigan ghost
i talked to one of his buddies and he
has to be put back in touch with oregon
kid and that's the first time i realized
that the ghost that was kind of hanging
around oregon kid wasn't the same ghost
that passed the cut so i put him back in
touch but i don't know what happened
from there so people are people are
ripping through the stories or whatever
right and it's because
the first people that the first people
that brought it out sometimes with
certain strains you lose chain of
custody
yeah you know i mean there was an issue
where
freaking uh you know
i don't think josh will get too mad if i
say this but like josh lost the cut in
an accident and none of his friends in
l.a wanted to give it back to him
and he had another story and he had to
go to a friend in the bay that he had
stashed it with to get it back
yeah
right yeah and that's typical weed yeah
because people were like oh it didn't
even matter that he was the guy that
they got it from it was profit
yeah oh a lot of these original guys
that had it they lost it right
and
um and there's an aspect where it's like
and i don't mean i'm not saying that
like people have fake ghosts what i'm
saying is is that there's four or five
cuts out there that all claim to be
the cut
that matt and josh brought to l.a that's
yeah exactly and they're different and
those cuts if you grow them side by side
they're not the same cut
yeah
like i don't and i don't mean like not
the same cut that they first brought i
mean not the same cut to each other in
the same room at the same time yeah
so then how do you know how do you know
what you know and nobody called 92 92
yeah that that's a more recent
adaptation to the name that's a more
recent adaptation the first name there
was no going back to like when it was
first around for a number of years no
one called it 92. yeah
that came later
yeah you know
and so
you know we don't people don't know i
don't know if the 92 hollywood hills cut
is the same as the flowrider
could the flowrider be the exact same
cut that josh brought out to california
to la it could
i don't know
yeah you know i got that one early but i
didn't get the josh cut early
and i didn't get it with provenance that
i would know for sure
yeah
huh i see people keep asking about the
suge knight and the kush war that story
is a bag of worms that no one wants to
touch because nobody has any facts
really around it so i'll leave it alone
but yeah
there's rumors going around that they
might have some relation and one
the one that you think would came first
might not be the one that actually
is the first one between the two yeah
you know so so there's a lot there's
basically
i bet there's a bunch of people that
have different named ogs out there that
are the same og
and
one guys one guy's larry could be
another guy's sfv could be another guy
yeah right because these names became
interchangeable and then you start
adding names and then you start getting
louie and fire and
you know diablo and yeah and da da da da
then there's all the pure cush names and
all those riffs and then there's the
master cushes and two or three of the
master cushes look like bubba kush's
yeah and one of them that i used to have
was tall and lanky and dark and very
stringy
i still think
two dogs i still think two dog has the
[ __ ] socal master every time i see it
it looks exactly like it hell's angels
and then people say that
you know that yeah you could you could
probably name and there was probably a
10-year period where like you could walk
into a club and they would have 20 25
different names on the menu of cush
yeah
right oh
yeah some some collectors out here were
only ogs and that was their [ __ ] like we
only carry og's it would be a [ __ ]
list of like 40 different og's yeah and
what's funny is that you know [ __ ]
dude ghost girl or whatever he rages
because there's people in la that their
entire career has just been learning how
to grow kush
yeah and selling it for high dollar
yeah and it had such a long successful
popular run before things changed
that some people's entire careers have
just been cropping kush
yeah
you know um but there's no like there's
so there's this aspect where because
it's one of the most famous families of
weed out there
yeah there's a bunch of origin stories
and there's a bunch of claims and
probably most of the cuts that came out
of la are bad seat
yeah
one would think
and then sometimes that's what i've
always thought and then sometimes a
different crew would get it and they'd
throw a different name on it yeah or
just renames in bag seeds yeah
yeah and then you know i mean i like
josh or whatever but josh did the stupid
[ __ ] thing where he took
he took like
uh what
h-a-o-g and something else and something
and crossed it all together and then
called it original josh d
no that was karma who did that
that was karma yeah it was karma's doing
not not just yeah oh god well then yeah
karma can suck it uh yeah because
because there's an obvious play to tie
it to
yeah you know yeah use like triangle
kush and oh yeah oh g and and h-a-o-g
and something else and d-obs yeah yeah
you know but yeah and so we never heard
when was the first time you even heard
the word 90 did you even hear the term
92 og the first 10 years you heard about
og i didn't really hear that until like
four or five years ago the 92 attachment
that specific year
yeah and so now people are like oh well
is this this should be the first one
right it's the 92 it's the one that
started it yeah
and it's like one of the more recent og
names
yeah
you know how did the louie get started
how did the fire get started how did
this get started like it's hard to find
these stories
yeah because people don't have a a
interest in honesty what they were
trying to do
is
sell a different kush for a high dollar
oh there you go yeah here you go nature
farm has all those old something and
they aren't dutted there you go so now
you know now you know yeah he's have to
battle he's got k f cures duds i've seen
his movie yeah we've seen his movie he's
got everything you want
you know he doesn't do any like negative
testing or anything like that but
you know
he just knows he's just got the sense
um
but yeah fire og is rascal sfv or maybe
fire og to somebody else is something
different
fire og is a clone
um
it came out of a tray of clones
and it wasn't i don't know which
specific og it was but and i don't think
he was told anything more than og and it
was fire so he called it fire og that
was it and then later on um swerve made
a cross of fire og and something else
more correctly and called it raskology
yeah and so it's one of those things
that one of the biggest things about og
is that og og and sauer but especially
og
are is probably one of the first strains
that like it just dominated breeding and
hybrids for so long
yeah
you know and what's interesting is like
for a long time
maybe we should talk about this for a
second but for a long time
um people would work ogs and they would
breed with ogs that they would s one
them
and
kind of the best pheno would be the one
that looked like mom
yeah
right yep it was really weird it was
like you wouldn't find a bunch of [ __ ]
and uh the good ones would be the ones
that look exactly like the parent
and then caleb uh reversed the tk
and he got a much wider variety of cool
phenos
yeah and he found ghost in there and he
found he found ones that looked like a
lot of popular ones and that's that's
like one of those ways for a breeder if
you're a breeder to know that you have
like uh you have a mother type situation
of a bunch of other cuts is when you s1
it and you're seeing all those sister
and brother phenos popping out of what
you just
made and that's how you kind of get the
idea that triangle might be the
predecessor
so it's it's interesting because if if
you know if there was bag seed and there
was multiple
cush strains found in that bag seed
yeah then the initial bag seed would
probably be a hybrid maybe
right uh and you know it seems like
there's there's at least one maybe a few
cushions out there that throw much wider
phenos than most of them yeah so it
almost leads it it almost leads you to
believe that a lot of these cushes are
lucky bag seats
yeah that people found and named but
because it's an s-1 of kush already
it kind of looks like itself for the
most part
yeah it's one of the it's one of the
reasons why caleb and i believe that the
chem dog the 91 itself might be an s1
yeah because it throws such a narrow
band
yeah of phenos
like there's a bunch of there's a bunch
of physically it doesn't look very
different
um potency-wise it can vary
quite a bit in some flavor
but there's a really narrow band of
physical expression
yeah and a lot of cushions are like that
yeah probably because they're backseat
yeah
you know and it's also interesting too
that like um you know i mean the
the two of the most famous strains out
there um the kush and the sour diesel
neither one of them reversed very easily
yeah
a lot of failure with those
right
yep yeah they suck they suck so a lot of
times a lot of times things get reversed
onto them
yeah
you know that's that's usually how it
goes the only
the only real ogs i'm seeing people like
regularly reverse or og hybrids and they
they have to get lucky and find
something that'll reverse well but most
of these old og cuts be it you know bad
seats and back seats and we're finding
that like s2s s3s [ __ ] like that doesn't
reverse well for whatever reason it's
really hard to reverse like a multiple
self or multiple backseat generations
and that makes sense for og it makes
sense for a lot of these ogs
you know so it's like yeah they they
ended up getting outcrossed
and then people would would reverse some
of them looking for better [ __ ] and the
best [ __ ] that they would find was the
[ __ ] that looked like the [ __ ] they
already had
yeah
and i got kind of over og because while
i think it is an amazing strain and i'm
not here trying to dis it or anything
like that i don't think that its genetic
expression is wide enough that you would
need to keep 20 different ones yeah and
you're like this one's earthy this one's
lemony this one has a slight hint of
this this one's more tennis balls this
one's darker
you know yeah uh look at that matt
someone wants you to s1 the hogs breath
yeah i've done it before i'll do it
again i haven't i haven't i haven't run
it again once it started getting past i
dropped it so somebody asked an
interesting question why does s2 and s3
and all that get harder um because what
happens is is you're selfing so there's
only one set of genes and so every time
you self you increase the propensity of
recessive traits that are negative to be
able to pop
yeah right and so the deeper you go into
selfing the more narrower you're putting
the genetic pool
yeah and that's when issues start
happening
that's why there's rules against injury
for humans you're not allowed to bang
your sister or your first cousin doesn't
go well or your mom or your uncle or you
let me tell you from personal experience
yeah that [ __ ] sucks bro yeah i mean it
took out the whole royal families of
europe
yeah
they needed some outcrossing
yeah they kept selfing essentially
almost yeah so that's why and then and
then you know as things get as things
get more narrow a lot of times s3 s4
it starts getting a lot weaker
it starts getting a lot more prone to
lack of vigor
stress other aspects
and there's a lot of regular breeding
um
there's a lot of regular breeding that
uses selfing successfully but it does
in normal agriculture absolutely selfing
is a massively used technique with great
success
yeah in cannabis it seems to have
negative connotations taken
maybe maybe people have a different idea
but for me at least
what it seems like selfing the biggest
thing is is because most of the things
that we have are our
individual cuts and not seed lines
anymore yeah it allows you to see what
else is in the genetics besides that one
expression yes
you know if if if you had you know a
hundred seeds of what og kush came out
of and it was males and females you'd
have a line
yeah but if you have a cut
then how do you how do you see what it
is pure not outcrossed
yeah
so a lot of times i mean caleb talks all
the time like if people are looking for
consistency in
in um
in seed then the way to go is some of
his outcrosses
yeah a lot of the um
the the feminized hybrids yeah well
feminized hybrids
if you're looking for specific phenos
but you're willing to tolerate more junk
yeah go to the s once
yeah but the s1s are going to have a
certain amount of recessive stuff in
there that's undesirable
yeah does it bread with itself
so the outcrosses you know urkel
reversed onto kush would will be more
consistent than urkel onto urkel
that's why again why like when i talk
about the blue bonnet and despite what
was said about it that it was a pure
blueberry line i still think to this day
that it's hybrid because all those
recessive traits that blueberry usually
carries
when you further inbreed it are gone
completely erased
and i talked before about how i didn't
like the the pure blue lines very much
at all yeah yeah um but then you
outcross them to different other amazing
things and those kids
came out way better than the parent in
my opinion exactly and i think it just
it's i think it was massive inbreeding
going on in such a small environment and
the constant crossing of two uh two
distinctly different
expressions like crossing indica to
sativa or whatever
most people don't breathe like that they
breed in a direction most people don't
keep constantly in crossing two
different types through generations and
that that caused a weird inbreeding to
go on and and
and not all the best traits to be a
parent dj is really unusual dude
because if you believe in what he says
he basically took four plants
and never added anything else yeah yeah
and everything that he has comes from
those four plants
yeah right it was like a
oregon purple tie and a juicy fruit tie
and an anime and an afghani yeah and
maybe something else or that's it
the the the oregon purple thai was
chocolate thai wahawk and gold so
yeah
yeah okay count those two
if you count those two it's four
yeah exactly you know and then a lot of
times all those things were only used
once
according to him
never never back crossed to again or
reintroduced and he just lied and he
just worked within the lines yeah and so
you know
uh camara has talked about how he kind
of views all of dj's stuff as this big
mangled
inbred specific thing
yeah but at least that's cool because
you never mixed anything else into it
yeah but that's really unusual
it is it's everything about how he made
[Laughter]
i i agree like i spent i spent several
thousand dollars on those specific seeds
and i had to really work to find
things that were good blueberry terps
because that just wasn't what i was
seeing in the line i told you i ran 400
and 450 of four of his lines yeah you
know and uh i wish i was bragging about
keepers
yeah but you know like i wouldn't have
loop on it without those lines so
there's great potential in those lines
but i think like you said it's it's in
the hybridization i really do it's in
the hybridization you know it's kind of
like that thing with like you know the
closest thing that we have to uh to an
actual ibl people throw around ibl all
the time it drives yeah nine nuts yeah
ibl's
yeah right because an ibl is essentially
something that's been bred so
consistently that it just is what it is
yeah it is what it is everything's
looking like clones of each other from
science and everything looks like clones
of each other so if you have some kind
of ideal where you're trying to grow
fields of exact replicas it might be a
good tech
if you want to breed all of the genetic
diversity out of your [ __ ] and
everything that you cross with it is
going to look like it
yeah
then you know [ __ ]
yeah you know but i mean that that that
88 g13 hash plant kind of throws
phenols that are just like it
yeah
junk you cross things the jeep chunk and
it's very deep chunkish
yeah yeah well though gene did point out
that like there are so
i when i refer to ibl's i do think a
deep chunk because visually it is it is
very uniform i mean there's like two
phenos like two uh uh
visually
expressive phenos that look
distinct but when you smoke it some have
a much better hive than the others so
true
and that i i when i was speaking about
it i was only speaking visually when it
when in fact a true ibl would be for all
traits across the board but that's why
it drives matt and i nuts because there
are no ibl's in cannabis yeah you just
can't but
and so an ibl is basically something
that breeds true for all traits
yeah and all the seeds are going to be
very narrow within that tiny little band
yeah you can have a true breeding stream
that's only true breeding for one trait
yeah like the bonnet it's true breeding
for blueberry terps and that's it
right or you know you could have you
could have something like skunk one
that's true breeding for
you know improving calyx to leaf ratio
or you know bud structure or this or
that but it has a variety of terps or
you know things in it
you know so true breeding
and ibl is like the furthest example of
true breeding it's like when all the
characteristics are the same
yeah
and true breeding is just one or more of
the characteristics you can count on
seeing in the progeny
yeah so when someone the other day i
can't recall who it was it was i think
it was a lady was saying that um
that they have an f2 ibl and people are
like what the [ __ ] that doesn't make any
sense and that lady was like no it makes
sense it doesn't make sense to have an
f2 ibo it's not possible no and so
there's a lot of terms that are thrown
around ibl is the worst one because yeah
um you should be able to buy a hundred
seeds of an ibl and see less than two
percent variation
yeah and i think i think uh what where
the miscommunication is is that a line
being inbred is not the same thing as an
inbred line and line breeding is not the
same thing as an ibl
you know ibl so specific and line
breeding and in breeding in a line
don't denote an ivl it is a process to
getting towards an ivl but i think
that's where a lot of confusion lies
yeah if there's if there's a bunch of
variation of of any traits at all in
your lead it's not an ibl
yeah
you know
ibl's is basically a way to in
agriculture to grow clones of each other
from seed stock
yeah that's its goal
yeah so you know if you're gonna grow an
ibl for weed it's like you're gonna
breed
all the cool [ __ ] out of it and it's not
going to be worth breeding with once
it's an ibl
for the most part because it's going to
have such a narrow range it's going to
make everything look like itself
yeah and so hope you know so if you made
an ibl maybe it would be just you know
if it was something that was just so
incredible but it'd probably be a bunch
of words
yeah it'd probably be a bunch of work
and it would suck
yeah
you know realistically speaking and it's
in in cannabis another reason it's very
hard to to make ibl's is because males
express different than females even if
they are the same expression males are
even if they're the same
uh general phenotype they the male
always grows taller than the female so
they don't look identical so trying to
choose
the male expression of a female line
that you want to find is very [ __ ]
hard to do you know that's why it's much
easier and faster to do it through
selfing
and there's an aspect too where someone
was like well what if you just picked a
really good plant to ibl
that's assuming that all those traits
will be the dominant trait yeah the more
that you breathe and breed into itself
and you're not going to lose them
by inbreeding yeah
you know um
you know so so there's an aspect there
where it's like it someone just said
that's a good question i missed whatever
the question was yeah i was trying to
look for it just now i don't know if
matt if you can find it or someone wants
to uh
you know um
the whole thing there is no cubed term
the only [ __ ] that ever used the
term cute like like the c99 really cube
that was a mr soul thing yeah that was
sort of his his own terminology for he
still has his and he even after this
like he still has his [ __ ] training
wheels he needs to slow down oh my god
but yeah there's no cubing was just like
he found some bag seed and he started
inbreeding it to itself a bunch
you know
um which was already probably inbred but
yeah
it's like
you know
one of the reasons why they don't want
you to bang your sister
um is because the [ __ ] that happens to
you when you start breeding humans too
close is a lot of
mental issues physical issues various
kinds of things start popping up that in
normal humans are never dominant
yeah but if you inbreed enough you can
combine those two not dominant genes and
it'll pop dominant
oh you
that question he said what about this
isn't a real question what about
recombinant and red line like tony green
and gg4rio
i can't even answer that like without
laughing stop guys please
you know and i think that's a guy who
who is talking [ __ ] about uh caleb and
said he was at like f12 or something
[ __ ] nothing
there's an aspect where it's like let's
let's let's be honest it's like there's
a lot of there's a lot of terms that get
loosely applied to cannabis yeah and
they're not that well understood and
it's not anybody's fault because it's
not like there's seminars on this [ __ ]
and a lot of information gets passed
through friendships
and a lot of times some of those
friendships like aren't passing the most
reliable information about things
yeah
right
yeah you know that's what it is
they're hoping that people don't know
what the term means and it sounds like
they've done work if they put stupid-ass
terms at the end of it f12 like if you
really think that some dude that's been
around not that long is it f12 then you
do not understand breeding or how long
it takes to make it through generations
and to do real breeding to make sure
that generation is correct and if you've
made an error to go back to the previous
generation keep working because you're
never going to hit it right 12 times in
a row guaranteed so implying that he has
worked something like 12 generations is
asinine to people actually do that and
there's friends of ours that are
breeders that are like dude i had this
awesome line
and then i did this thing to it and i
didn't end up keeping enough seed from
before i did that thing
yeah and then i [ __ ] it up yeah i
didn't
get rid of it to get rid of that seed
and go one to two gens back and go in a
different direction but i didn't keep
the seed and i [ __ ] it up and it's not
as good as it was before and i can't
make it the way it was before because i
didn't keep that gem
so it's basically like a misstep
yeah right you can make a mistake
if you don't save if you don't save seed
from every single rip
you know and when people say f2 f3 f4 i
mean what that means is that you're
supposed to grow up a bunch of seed
pick males and females
right that exhibit traits that you want
cross them and then breed them
okay here's a question and i'm going to
address it just because me and me and
csi were talking about like an hour ago
right right before we started this
anyways um but is crossing an elite to
an elite breeding or pollen chucking
i
consider regular breeding like using a
male i consider that vacation and taking
days off like that is the easiest [ __ ]
to do you don't have to do anything you
just they they make their seeds
themselves you don't have you have to
shake it around that's about it um
breeding using
reversal techniques is a lot more
involved
it's it's a lot more unpredictable um
you can make a lot more errors a lot
real fast i mean you could you could
take something and isolate it and and
make it
more true breeding really fast but you
can also make huge errors right away and
very rarely does a pollination go where
you can just like hit something and
shake it in a reversal and the seeds
make themselves that just doesn't really
happen that often a lot of times you
have to get in there with
[ __ ] tweezers tweeze out each one
shake the [ __ ] pollen out half of
that [ __ ] won't be good and it's just
because that's
that's how it goes you know so there's
an aspect too which i should mention uh
and that's the reason why matt said
you're not gonna do 12
12 readings that all make sense
and what he means by that is that let's
say you're at f3 and you grew up a bunch
of f3s and you're ready to make your f4s
and then you realize that you don't like
that combo
yeah and you want to go back one
generation earlier and try again
yeah because you didn't like
that selection so yeah you're like in
order to get to f12 that means 12 times
you would have to grow up seeds
like what you see pick
females and males of each one
cross them together
grow up their children and just keep
doing that and every single time every
single f gen you're like [ __ ] yeah i won
yeah [ __ ] yeah i'm good where a lot of
times you're gonna get somewhere and be
like oh that went in direction i don't
like that nearly as much as the f4
this f5 sucks i gotta go back to f4
again i i did a green craft bx1
and i i you know i was one of the early
growers and breeders with green crack i
love that [ __ ] strain i don't know
why it's just nice and mangoey and it
was really beautiful purple and i'm
sucker for purples
but um in the bx1 i had crossed it to
and actually done a few but the one that
i ran with was the platinum banana og
as the male from it and out cross to
that back to the green crack and
all i found was a lot of platinum banana
og plants and not many green cracks and
i didn't expect that because usually
green crack breeds dominant but that was
one of those cases where it's like okay
even though it's a bx1 and it sounds
like it should be super green crappy
that's not how it played out in
in practice it was only in theory so it
kind of was an epic fail and this is why
breeding is such a [ __ ]
because you spend all this time and
energy doing it and then you're like oh
i don't like that that choice
backstage go back go back you know go
you know slide slide back down and start
over
yeah
uh and so there's a lot of missteps and
there's a lot of things that you hope
will happen like i'm gonna take this and
cross it to this and i'm hoping these
traits come together and you and then
you're like oh that's a horrible
yeah i gotta back up
uh and that's why so many people just
like to make one one-off outcrosses to
different things
not test it and just release it and just
move on to something else yeah
because you can spend a bunch of time
[ __ ] around
and that spit so much time i mean there
was there's an aspect where bodhi was
telling me when when he first got the 88
g13 hash plant right
from uh ndn guy seeds
yeah
he didn't realize that they were already
f4
yeah so
he kept
the first he kept males and females of
the first round
and didn't lose him
but then he took it three more gens
yeah right
and it got shittier and shittier every
gem
yeah and what he ended up using
was the very first seeds that he popped
from the initial seeds that he got
yeah and that's what and that's what's
in all those hybrids that people buy
from him
is because those those moms and dads
made way better crosses
yeah than any of the intentional work he
did after because he thought he was
getting it kind of raw so he's like oh
open pollinated a couple times
yeah you know and he spent all this time
three doing going three gens that's a
lot of time that is a lot of time a lot
of effort and it's not rewarded yeah and
then you're like and then he's like each
one of these gems sucks ass and i'm not
gonna use them yeah i'm just gonna stick
with this first [ __ ] i have over here
yeah i could have saved myself a year
yeah
you know and so that [ __ ] happens
and i can guarantee you
after being in this business this long
that
what's what's sad and what a lot of
people have noticed that that are in
this business is that they're the how
quickly things sell
it how much work you put into it has no
reliance on that it's all in the name
it's all in the hype it's all in that
kind of stuff so there's no real reward
to putting in all that extra work
to then fail
and spend a lot of money doing it or to
then succeed and still
not be able to outsell something else
that's being hyped so
when people when people make comments
about like i don't see braiders doing
long work anymore there's a reason it's
just not financially viable uh anymore
and as as bad as it sucks to hear that
as bad as it sucks to say it that's
where it's at and that's why most
breeders
if you were to ask them
like you know to like
people breed and they put in a bunch of
crosses and then they make a bunch of
packaging and stuff and i'm not dissing
it by any means but i'm just saying that
they don't have time
to test every round of everything
you just can't anymore before release
you know it's not it's not it's not
feasible you know you can you might look
through the things that you're the most
interested in
always but yeah and see and be like oh i
really want to see what's in this hybrid
you know
even that is the minimum i can think of
like
seven people that do even that much you
know what i mean it's very it's very
difficult and then there's an aspect
where
you know i mean matt and i when we were
researching like uh i guess you'd call
it last season's podcast that we were
doing and we were doing a bunch of
neville work you could go through the
scentsy catalog from 91 to 95
and it barely changed
yeah
barely at all just little tiny things
barely changed you know some some names
here and there one or two things but
maybe in five years they added three or
four things to the catalog yeah
right
and
now
it's like people come out with 20 or 25
new strains every crop ev every time
they make make a drop
yeah a lot of the times and then when
they make another drop six months later
it's a totally different set of [ __ ]
yeah
so it's become vastly different people
used to be able to get away with simon
from serious seeds
for 20 years he sold six things
yeah right that don't work no more no
white russian
chronic ak
collie missed a bubble gum
and uh
one more
one more than i'm forgetting yeah anyway
he sold he sold six lines
yeah and he made those six lines over
and over hey now i said ak i think but
we could look it up but there maybe i i
named it was six though i named five off
the top of my head it was six for sure
but it was six but
you know 15 years of just making i'm
gonna make these same hybrids again
yeah i'm gonna make them i'm gonna make
them i'm gonna make them i'm gonna make
them and it was like they didn't have to
change that much since these catalog the
first five or six years was pretty
consistent and then the last three or
four years in the 90s they added four
five or six more things yeah
but then it stayed consistent after that
yeah
and now it's like that's not
what breeders or growers or anyone
expects it's got to be all new [ __ ]
yep
yeah i mean even with me early on i
would like to do clock the clockwork
orange i'd always keep that in stock and
like the white russian
big
i think you didn't say that maybe i
still like russian i don't know yeah i
don't know but it kept it in stock man
over the years you realize that's not
even viable to do anymore because people
want new and now and new and now at all
times and not everyone
obviously but the the majority of the
seed people buying seeds that's how it
goes and if you don't do that you it's
not a viable company anymore and so matt
and i laugh because we read
all this stuff about what people think
breeders act most a lot of breeders are
actually doing
yeah
versus what they actually do
yeah and they're like oh these guys are
testing this and that and they're
looking for herms and they're looking
for this and they're doing this and that
and they're making choices and
selections and they're
not most of them
yeah because the the most profitable way
right now to make seeds is just to like
blow off a room
d you know collect the seeds
i think it's even worse than that i
think the most profitable way to make
seeds like with compound and guys like
that they buy seeds from other people
already made and label them something
they're hyping there's a bunch of stuff
that goes on with like people would be
shocked to know
you know how many how many of their like
some of their favorite cali people got
their seeds made in spain
yeah yeah
you know or had some dude that they know
that has a tent make seeds and act like
they're blowing up their facilities yeah
yeah and so there's a lot of there's a
lot of fakery there you know and people
eat it up and they realize that they
with ig and with these things they can
control the narrative and hype
and people never see behind the screen
door
yep and so the amount that they think
that they're
uh yeah people most aren't even germ
testing most aren't even taking 100 or
200 seeds and spending two or three days
and making sure they get a good pop rate
yeah no and that's what [ __ ] candy
rain
they didn't even pop you know and he
sold them they sold them for like 800
bucks a piece
or 800 bucks a pack or something like
that you know
um and but so there's all these things
that they think their breeders are like
these mad scientists like really putting
in the work
and most and that's how they present
themselves yeah and then the people that
do put in work and but don't show it
that much for various reasons they get
called out for being the big guys that
aren't doing the work yeah
all the time and you're like dude your
hero
is like paying some kids to do the work
while doing photo ops
while while ordering half of it from
dean of them in spain
right
yeah and you think he's been carefully
working on it for the past 12 12 months
yeah
you know and he's just putting his name
on it
it's literally a re-label
yeah that's how it goes it's how it goes
you know and and there's not a lot of
pressure so i'm not it's just and so
what matt was basically saying is that
there's not incentive
or for financial survival for most
people to do
what the customer base would like them
to do
yeah
in my opinion
yeah no there isn't
it's just not there it's not there
anymore unfortunately it used to be
there and i think a lot of us would
rather just quit than
join the stupid [ __ ] parade
yeah i mean think about it for a minute
you know think about how many people out
there
can do what our buddy csi does
yeah which is show pictures of rooms
regularly of what was running and show
pictures of seeds that he made
that there's 200 phenols growing in a
room
yep
you know and you can go years and years
and years back of he hasn't he hasn't
popped everything he's made that's crazy
yeah but he's constantly popping stuff
that he's made
and looking through it and that kind of
dedication is like uber rare
you know
um it's like him and a few other and
you know a few other people
and some hobbyists who are doing it for
love
uh and most of the famous people no
yeah
no
definitely not because it's just not
financially feasible and they don't have
the space and they don't really have any
goals either they're trying to just make
much money off a seed drop
yeah caleb caleb i can guarantee you
will
spend every time doing it right because
he's so ocd and autistic about how he
gets it done and well he's very
admirable he also his favorite part of
the whole process is seeing what's in
the hybrids he makes oh yeah yeah that's
actually testing that's actually the
part that keeps him going the rest of it
is kind of a soul-drenching grind
yeah but that he gets excited about
yeah
so that's cool i've never met a man more
excited about genetics and seeds than
that man
and it's it's [ __ ] awesome because
he's one of the him and not so and a few
of our other friends those are the only
people that i've ever met that i can sit
there and nerd out with like that and
dork out for hours on the phone and just
talk about genetics and and our wives
all hate it i'm sure yeah
i actually have a buddy i just mentioned
it me too he's i have a buddy who's like
as old of a seed weird
breeder interested in the process as
you'd ever meet
um there are people scattered throughout
mendo and humboldt here and there
uh they've never been a majority
anywhere
yeah it's definitely a weird offshoot
yeah i want to have i want to have
uranus come on sometime and talk to you
because i know he's a big [ __ ] nerd
like us
he he is you know so a bunch of my
friends it's like even [ __ ] caleb
it's like there's people that aren't
comfortable talking
in public as much
yeah it's a hard thing kind of
yeah i i do believe you know because
you're live like in person just sitting
around with a couple buddies smoking
joints and shooting the [ __ ]
if you could capture that
it's amazingly conversational
oh yeah yeah that's why like the parties
like even even for me to sit back and
watch everyone like
talk genetics and it's like like even
some of the people like everybody that
was involved with og kush except for
uh big ricky was it one of them you know
like everybody with him was there and
you could
listen to all of them talk all at once
everybody part of that people should
know the guy that's famous for irene
rudeboy you know he came out with his
whole crew one night
yeah that was [ __ ] cool
and brought his herb and we had our you
know we sat around and we saw we shot
the [ __ ] you know and exchanged a bunch
of stories and you know confirmed a
bunch of things and
you know so yeah not so does not need to
grow mustache dude i mean the thing is
about mustaches right i'll just say this
okay and this this is no prejudice
whatsoever i'm 46 okay
yeah when i was in my 20s and 30s i
would say the only people that had
mustaches were like police firemen and
gays
yeah
there was no dudes just now it's back in
style and there's a bunch of like 20
somethings or whatever just rocking
massive
70s stashes and [ __ ] but it was like
it went out of style like the station
wagon
yeah for a while yeah and he looks like
a he literally looks like a tom of
finland character when he has the full
stache rocky
[ __ ]
oh do you super dog let's do super dog
before we're done
super dog okay uh we are getting close
to being done
um but i will people but we're bugging
so i will give a brief synopsis of super
dog so yeah let's do it matt sent me
some stuff that like blew my head off
about super dog
in in some forum posts and stuff like
that that we won't get into
yeah but
needless to say
um
i i think what happened is is that
there's a
there's a few versions and there's a few
things that happened over time
right and
my buddy who i never mentioned uh i just
call him staten island uh it's mostly
it's it's a it's a bunch of it's it's a
bunch of his story really but yeah
um
you know uh the story starts i guess
with he gave the super skunk to
uh chem dog to greg yeah right
and in 93-ish i think and um
94-ish greg calls him up and he's super
excited because
the super skunk had permed onto the chem
dock
right and he got a bunch of seed and he
grew this seed up and he said
this seed is so amazing
i'm growing this stuff instead of the
cam dock
it's unbelievable right yeah and so
there was this aspect where gat where my
buddy staten island thought
okay
maybe we could blend these two things
together
yeah but we didn't know [ __ ] he didn't
know [ __ ] about sts or reversals or
anything like that back there right
yeah this is so pre-pre that it's
unbelievable so yeah
homie
3 000 miles away just had an accident
and got some seat
yeah and so homie out here thought oh
maybe i'll have an accident maybe it'll
do this but he basically started the
project and he took a a a hawaiian plant
and crossed it to the super skunk cut
yeah and then he got he got like a super
skunk line for lack of a better term
right bred that a couple of times
and then
he took uh he took some males of that
and tossed it on the
we tossed it on the the chem 91
yeah and the super dog was born
right
um and i was helping him a little bit in
the middle of that and then him and i
worked together on hunting through a
bunch of super dog itself
right and doing further outcrosses
so
there was some stuff on the east coast
that might have had a similar name that
came about in a very different fashion
you know but no
get the [ __ ] out of here yes you know
what i'm going to tell i'm going to tell
one real quick story and
so
i i was obsessed with finding that super
dog cut because i was a big fan of
diesel and supposedly they were similar
genetics one was cam 91 super skunk
supposedly one was supposedly chem d
super skunk according to the canon bible
at the time so i i had already had
diesel and i loved it and the superdog
really interest me and and i wasn't sure
if maybe they got it wrong and it's the
same cut so i remember asking greg back
then chem dog
about it and he kind of inferred that he
had read it and then i saw another post
today where he again inferred he read it
so
the fact that it was the same genetics
as your guys's
out in the west coast
and there's still no pictures no
provenance nothing for it and every time
i ask for any info about it all i get
even and with diesel as well all still
all i get is let me check my notes
and and i like to do a lot i like kim
dog a lot he's a good dude i've met his
wife she's really cool um but yeah
that's that's as far as i can get with
it i do think in my opinion
i think
they didn't know much about super dog
they heard about it and that he may have
taken credit for it back then and it was
probably what was going on with gabby
and you yeah okay so
so
we did a bunch of work on it and it took
us a night we and you know it's like
there's a lot of projects like that
where when you don't have some specific
goal
in terms of like timing or anything it's
like we popped off a rip here and then
four months later six months later we
did another stage of it over here and
then you know it's kind of like that
you're doing it along while you're
growing and yeah um we ended up what
happened is what most people what most
people know of is we started picking
phenos like the seven the three the
thirty
um there's some pictures of it in the
can of bible yeah i started spreading it
around i started giving out uh selected
cuttings to friends and we crossed it
uh there was a time when we did you know
we were trying to do
um
i don't know what you'd call it it's not
quite open pollination okay but we
basically took out of out of hundreds of
seeds we took like our four or five
favorite males yeah combined with about
seven or eight of our favorite females
yeah and we put them in a room and we
bloomed them
and then we threw in literally
every good
cutting that we had at the time
so
actual chem 91 actual super skunk the
warlock my black domina cut the maui
uh the the mendo perps
yeah
the crippy no no we didn't have this was
before i didn't have a kush um yeah i
didn't have a kush quite yet or anything
like that but uh but we so we did
basically just like it was like bread
amongst itself
yeah and then we bred it to like every
fire cut we had at the time
and yeah
okay go ahead go ahead oh my gosh um
so
you know i uh
uh
that one totally distracted me but i um
i did that herbalist i did do that one
that's the uh what i call the skunk
spray cam line and that's the only other
one besides um
the heirloom afghani line that i
consistently can can make skunky [ __ ]
come out of really easily so
i mean you know uh he doesn't really
like to chat in public or whatever but
he probably uh
um
my buddy from staten island is probably
should get the most credit for the
superdog because he put the most time
into it uh him and i did do projects
with it together and then it was the
projects that him and i were doing
together that ended up getting spread
out and getting photographed and getting
traded to people and that's kind of i
think where it started popping up on the
forums
yeah and people started talking about it
and seeing it i gave a bunch of superdog
hybrids
to mandelbrot uh and that's kind of the
basis of the males that he started with
his uh emerald emerald mountain seed
company and all that
um so that so it started it got it got
mixed into some other things that are
pretty famous too
um but we won't go into that right here
but it what we were trying to do
is we were trying to get the density and
the potency
of the chem 91
yeah combined with
the the color and the crystal content
and the nose of the skunk
yeah so we wanted potency and density
from over here
and we wanted a little bit better looks
and frost and terp from over here
yeah
and it worked pretty well
it was killer you know and honestly it
probably would have it probably would
have taken off a bunch more if
the
purple and then kush
and diesel craze hadn't started
where everyone wanted to grow the exact
same strains to get the dollar
yeah for sure
you know um
yes the super dog would have been in in
dispose in 2001 in the bay 100
uh that would definitely be an era that
uh
there would definitely be an era where
you could have gotten uh a lot of super
dog went to the bay
a whole bunch
you know
um and you know
uh
uh you know i've talked before about how
we lost it and some of the different
things and been hunting for it for a
long time
um it uh
you know it exists in a bunch of
children
um and you know
skunk and chem seem to be a great combo
yeah
in general i know i know that at least
in 2000 let's say 11 or 12
that maui superdog was still being grown
up north that weird i don't know if you
know karnak the weirdo oh dude so
there's there's phenos i have friends
from trinity county that grew for years
and their boss his favorite strain was a
maui super dog yeah uh a maui super dog
hybrid um
you know some of the maui super dog uh
mandelbrot wrote about it a bunch but he
found out of seeds that i gave him
something he ended up calling the truth
yeah yeah which was maui by super dog
that's just a straight maui by super dog
so i think bitter is still holding that
cut for you too by the way and so
there's there's a number there's a
number of phenos of that that float
around
yeah and there's some other stuff we
won't get into right now because that's
a whole nother movie where it's in
um so it's it's it's blended into
different things
um but it's one of those gigs where it's
like weed reinvents itself every five or
ten years
and people only like to grow what's easy
and popular and it would probably knock
people's socks off today but it came out
at a time when it wasn't able to get as
famous
you know because it was coming out in
2000 2001 2002 2003 you know it's just
that was just like a different era
yeah things didn't get like naturally
hyped very easily well it just couldn't
spread
yeah people that couldn't communicate as
much uh clones didn't spread as much
there wasn't clone trading going on very
much there wasn't clone mailing
anything like that you know so
um so there's an aspect to that that
someone's asking if you uh what did you
all find out did you find a line on
anything that you thought was lost
recently not so
that i thought was lost
yeah i mean i uh there's you know
we did get something that i considered
to be the trinity or at least
you know extremely extremely close to
the the right cut
you know um so and we that was lost for
15 or 18 years to us
and i'm still not sure if it's the exact
right thing
um but if it's even the people that seem
to think it might be not
think it's incredibly closely related
yeah like it on s1 or you know something
like that but i think it's the real one
um and now what gets hard is that uh
because old things are becoming popular
again everyone's coming out of the
woodwork with old things
yeah
that goes back to the [ __ ]
question that dude had about a smear
campaign i absolutely
consider diesel chem skunk weed
yes
yes 100
yeah
super to me diesel and sour diesel and
all that is is kemp is is chem skunk
blend
okay and
before we close it down i want uh
someone wanted you to talk about
francine they kept they kept mentioning
it
so francine was an extremely tasty
indica
um
and obviously that's that's the cut that
facilitated the the trade for the super
skunk
um and uh
my buddy ended up we ended up letting it
go
because like a lot of
amazing afghans uh it had horrific raw
issues
yeah
and it could it could grow all these big
beautiful colas
and then there'd be gray rot running up
the center stem
yeah and a lot of people had fine had
had issues with breeding a lot of early
afghans because afghans bred in rot
yeah because they grew up in a in a dry
cold afghan environment and then they
get brought to like moderate sort of
humid california at times and they just
they just couldn't handle it yeah so it
was it's one of those things where it's
part of the lore but it was
intentionally dropped for issues
and it was dropped long before any of us
thought that any of this weed that we
were growing would matter
yeah i'm sure
too you know
so
um so yeah i mean we've now been talking
two hours and six minutes
yeah
probably we try to keep it two hours
every friday you know yeah so maybe now
it's a good time if matt if you want to
do any plugs or anything like that oh
yeah so uh
go to google type in reader syndicate
patreon if you want to go join us on
their patreon um we'll probably be
watching fights tomorrow
um
and yeah we're always on there shooting
[ __ ] ask us questions there join in
and we
probably gonna have some contests coming
up that'll be fun um check out speakeasy
they help us produce the podcast and the
audio version so go check them out show
them support uh all my stuffs were at
seatco.com
um we didn't get to not says manscaping
so i'm kind of bummed about that indeed
yeah
it's probably a it's probably a two or a
three part show you know at least at
least it needs props and pictures all
kinds of stuff
and just in general in general
yeah two or three parts yeah so anyway
thank you all for your friday night as
always as always for me give suggestions
give give ideas reach out to us dm
things you want to hear about
um yeah this is all about us chatting
and interacting and stuff so
uh but again thanks for the friday night
have a great day
night