all right
take you in a bit
what's up everyone
slowly
waking up
okay i guess we wait for natso
we have um
some kind of stuff planned a little
planned as much as we
plan
i don't plan too well so my apologies in
advance
how's everyone doing
slowly waiting for people to show up get
it started so i was thinking of doing a
giveaway today you know at some point of
this [ __ ] so
we'll probably do that
i got a better idea so naza didn't have
to come up with it
yo yo yo
what's the habs jack adjusting the
height of my little thing here
yeah that's what she said oh man
all right you're good
i am good you're good haircut
seems good you get a haircut i do
yeah no not really no i got a haircut
last week i think
it looks good until it mushrooms out it
doesn't really go long it goes wide and
then it gives you a [ __ ] so just
like it just expands outward and you can
wait for it to fall but
i don't have enough hair left to really
make that work whenever my hair grows
out like it starts doing this thing
where it flips and curls right here on
the sideburn area
really really awesome looks cool peter
pan
all right so what do we want to start
off with um what did you want to kick it
off with
well uh we've been doing uh so
again what we're gonna do is we've done
a bunch of shows that are that are like
somewhat like uh
themed you know um and then the last few
that we've been doing have kind of been
more a bit more like uh
some loose subject matter that we
discussed and then we riff off and then
we answer some questions and such and it
seems like people uh
people are into that as well so uh we're
gonna do one of those where
um we're gonna touch on some different
stuff that people asked about during the
week on our discord and then uh we'll
riff off that a bit and people can
answer questions or ask questions
um matt's a little bit better at reading
the screen than i am but i'll try i can
feel some for you you can field some if
you see anything that pops up that looks
normal yeah so
i don't know normally we wait until
it's 150ish people or something like
that but we'll yeah we could start we
could start in a second so
um a couple of things that that people
wanted to chat about a little bit was uh
um some stuff that i'll mostly talk
about which is sort of like the some
traditional hash aspects right
and then there's some stuff that's a
little bit more matte where people were
asking about like
you know what's like the international
seed scene like
uh today how does that all work uh what
is you know what is what's changing in
the in the in this in the seed world or
whatever
um and matt's a lot more uh uh can speak
a lot more eloquently on that than i can
really um
but you can speak on the hash because i
i i
have never smoked like afghan lebanese
blonde i mean i had a chunk of
silk road hash that was like
i was i didn't smoke it was too scary to
smoke so i just didn't
so it's it's interesting and like the
hash thing um
you know the hash thing is is kind of
cool because you can we can widen it out
a little bit
in the sense of um you know and talk
about like some traditional weed
cultures yeah because there is a real
divide in weed cultures between cultures
that grew weed primarily to make hashish
sure uh and cultures that grew weed
primarily to smoke weed
you know yeah um and you know that that
aspect and those choices made
um made a lot of differences for people
and now for a long time
america
one of the benefits of america is that
we're isolated from everywhere we have
like big oceans
yeah on either side and all that but
we're very far away from the hash
culture
yeah right so traditionally
uh all the best hash sort of stays local
uh and then some small amount of it
would go to europe right yeah uh and
what america typically got
was uh the b and c grade yeah you know
so a lot of times americans especially
canadians are a little different
canadians had some better connections
and some better smuggling that happened
up there yeah so they sometimes saw a
little bit better of a grade but
americans especially
um
you know they uh we got the shaft as far
as high grade
so a lot of people think of
um imagine if your view of kind bud was
like beasters
yeah and that's what you thought it was
because that's the only thing you've
experienced a lot of people if you
haven't been to europe and you haven't
and you haven't and you haven't been
tied into those communities right yeah
you probably haven't smoked the best of
the best
and so there's a lot of hash people in
america that think like the last 10 or
14 years of sort of like the hash
revolution that's happened over here
that they have the best hash by far that
they blow away all the traditional
cultures by far and that they're kind of
on the cutting edge and they've changed
the game
and they figured it out nobody else did
yeah
right which is pretty far from the case
yeah you know so it's like a lot of
those things where
um
you know we can we can kind of riff on
that for a little bit um so maybe you
can kind of talk we can we can start
like maybe we'll we'll we'll start from
the beginning where it's like
the hash culture sort of comes from
the
i would say the the near east and the
middle east yeah i would say indian
indian culture india
chinese maybe yeah i mean and and
probably the old probably the oldest way
to smoke cannabis
uh before they even figured out how to
smoke flour besides like burning flowers
on braziers or something is the hand rub
yeah you know um
and that india pakistan afghanistan iran
the middle east you can go into like
lebanon and israel in those areas and
you can go through north africa all the
way to morocco and that's sort of hash
culture yeah
right um in in terms of like people grew
weed just make to turn weed into hash
yeah
where
you start getting into like
um southeast asia
uh and you know and especially the new
world like mexico and colombia and
panama and these type of places in
africa
they mostly smoke wheat
yeah and you know um one that that
caught me off guard was nepal
i always think of like nepalese temple
balls and that kind of hash culture but
if i remember correctly when i was
studying it most of it was a flower
culture it was most it was it was a
little bit of both yeah you know um but
you know and so
to be to perfectly honest like when i
started going to amsterdam um i i went
there in search of seats
yeah you know and then i started getting
introduced to hash and uh you know i
smoked a bunch of stuff but in the
coffee shops uh it's a lot like you know
it's a lot like dispensaries or whatever
there's a wide variety yeah of mids and
junk and really good and pretty decent
and stuff and it wasn't until i met
collectors
yeah um that started explaining to me
like how it all worked yeah right
um and so
there's an aspect maybe we maybe i could
talk for a minute about before we talk
about the regional differences for a
second yeah maybe i could talk about
like
uh something that we chat about often
which is the vast difference between how
traditional hash is made
um and how
american hash is made yeah right so the
american hash
uh the way it's made um in most cases
is you it's it's you know a lot of times
it's called single source right
it's a single clone
right um grown in either depths or
outdoor or indoor or whatever and that
single clone is usually you know dried
or fresh frozen and then it's you know
it's processed um and then it's usually
refrigerated or frozen right away or
stored well until use and it's used
pretty quickly yeah right
where in traditional hash culture
you're harvesting a field of seeds
yeah
right so you know in america it's like
oh i'm gonna pull down this greenhouse
and it's all for lack of a better it's
all gmo yeah it's all the same cut you
know same terpene profile same cbd cbn
thc all that it's the same thing
yeah but if you're if you're harvesting
it from any other region you're going to
get the full range of expression of that
wine
yeah because they're harvesting
thousands of sisters yeah
and then they're processing those
sisters and unlike
unlike mo if you're if you're talking
about like dry sift and stuff like that
they tend to let that hash age
yeah
on the plant for a number of months
and then when it's cold and bone dry
they start a sifting process yeah
right and then from that sifting process
um you know then they make it into
various grades
and then they press it right so that's
not done in america at all
all of your all of your terp [ __ ] all of
your whether it's fresh frozen or it's
you know bho or it's it's uh
you know uh whatever extraction you're
doing it's usually single source yeah
and it's not aged usually the plan is
taken down fresh
and as soon as they can make the hash
they make the hash yeah right and so you
know i'm not exactly the expert on the
science or whatever but definitely aging
it creates you know it it transfers
things
from one to the other right certain
amounts of cbn or cbd or this or that or
whatever is converted into other
bioactives what not and then on top of
that when
uh we've wanted to get uh
our buddy bodie on here for a long time
to do like a hippie hashish trail kind
of episode yeah and so we might get more
in depth with that but
when
essentially when europeans and white
people first started going to the hash
regions and looking for export
most hash there was a lot of hash that
was one two three years old
yeah you know a lot of the best hashish
uh wasn't smoked until it was over a
year or two years old
yikes right i guess it's just different
climate though you know so it was
different climate it was stored it was
stored very differently you know and
they just thought that it was it was not
like it wasn't ready yet
yeah
you know and so um and what's
interesting about this is that if you go
to amsterdam
and you have all these people that have
all the same access to all the same tech
that we do here yeah as far as
extracting modern cultivars for hashish
and all the hash heads over there
will tell you that the best hash that
they smoke is the top import
they can use pollinators they can use
tumblers they can fresh froze and freeze
dry and microplane and do all the tricks
that people win awards with over here
and they still think that hash is
inferior in quality and effect
to the best of the best import
right
and
you know but in america we all think
that our [ __ ] is the best [ __ ] ever
of course
basically as soon as we invented the
nail and we invented some modern ways of
hash smoking and 09 you know 2010 2011
yeah that that was the revolution
and hash went from shitty to amazing
yeah right now it's true that most
americans got shitty hash and it's also
true that when all these white people
and all these europeans and all these
americans and and brotherhood of eternal
love and all these [ __ ] started
coming to these regions to look for hash
and started offering crazy amounts of
money
yeah the quality went way down yeah
people started adulterating it people
started middlemen started making it
worse people wanted volume because there
was so much demand
right so a lot of times the best stuff
never leaves
yeah even like even my friends in
amsterdam who are very tied in
them getting the best of the best is
really hard
i would imagine so and they and they
savor it
right they absolutely savor it and they
hold on to it and it never makes the you
know i almost said clubs it never it
almost never makes the the coffee shops
yeah because it's all traded amongst
each other
yeah right it's all bought and sold that
kind of grade you kind of have to know
someone yeah it's no different than like
if you if for to mention him again if
bodhi gave out some like 14 week amazing
sativa you probably wouldn't be able to
buy it from the cookie store
yeah well you'd have to have a you'd
have to have a homie well well maybe now
maybe but but even someone even
something that takes that long yeah yeah
for sure you know what i mean like in
europe you know there's there's still
like i have a buddy over there right now
that was texting me on what to get matt
i didn't tell you this but he just
bought some cg13
and some c5 and some and some a5 from
over there you know
um and those you know those are 15 16
weak strings
yeah that's you that's unheard of to get
yeah
in a dispensary over here yeah that's
wild
but over there it's their bread and
butter
yeah you know so you can find that stuff
so the biggest just to reiterate before
we get too off track
um
the biggest differences between
american hash and like the best
traditional
is
uh
you know the what i was told by the the
amsterdam cruise is like the best stuff
is made in traditional regions but
westerners help them
to make sure that the purity and the
process is amazing
okay does that make sense so making
their technique more purifying making
making sure that the cl the cleanliness
you know and the technique and all that
is good screens and everything like that
and you know people one of the reasons
why people ask this is people asked
about temple balls right these nepalese
temple balls
and i will say that these nepalese
temple balls that i smoked from my buddy
was some of the best hash i've ever
smoked in my life
okay and it's interesting because a lot
of people over there feel that way yeah
right
and they feel that like there's
something to the fact that like a lot of
this stuff is being grown at six or
seven or eight thousand feet
yeah
right where the air is thinner
and there's more uv
and maybe that leads to a different type
of psychoactive or a different type of
thc production i'm sure
you know and so they would say that like
you know uh our buddy yo sammy
you know would say i don't care what
modern cultivar you have i don't care
what amazing cut you think you have or
how pure you make it
you know it shits the bed next to the
best typical
yeah like if you can get the best of the
best he's like just in flavor and effect
yeah right an effect is hard to say
because it's invisible right yeah so
we got used to making all these modern
cultivars and thinking that like
thousands of years of hash culture
we just beat
yeah because we're a little cleaner
yeah because we gotta have a little bit
better and we have a little bit we have
some machinery and we're a little bit
better processed but like old timers
will tell you that like they think that
putting your hash in the in the in the
fridge ruins it
yeah
and you know what what what's weird
about the nepalese stuff is i will say
that
this isn't a plug on it or whatever but
anything i've ever smelled
that smelled like the mendo perps that i
cracked
yeah had the mendo perps in it
yeah in the sense that like i've never
smelled that terpene profile
from any other plant that wasn't it
yeah
unless it was related to it in the sense
that like someone bred with it or it was
it was an ancestor of that right yeah
except these temple balls that i smoked
and they smelled when you were burning
them they smelled like you were burning
mendo perps
that's interesting now you know does
that mean that like the mendo p is
nepalese i don't know you know but or
does it mean that it just evoked that
terpene profile yeah you know
i i can't say um but all those guys over
there what's crazy is that um
all those hash heads over there they
grow all kinds of phenomenal weed
and they sell all that weed to buy the
best hash they can get
yeah
you know like somebody like somebody
like you know uh when you were
interviewing uh
uh camara and and red you know yeah
i mean he was saying that like you know
he's never even seen sam skunk man smoke
weed yeah
that you know the the top people over
there are hershey's
yeah you know they smoke hatch
they're resin farmers makes sense you
know that's what they're after they're
after a resin yeah
and so you know we could widen that out
for a little bit
and talk about how
um
you know this is like a totally
different tangent or whatever but
um
when
americans started smoking weed
we were a flower culture
we were getting weed from mexico and
panama and jamaica and colombia and all
these things and we were getting bricked
um and we were getting you know we were
getting bricked of this stuff
and we started blending them with
afghans because of prohibition right
and it's super common and matt can speak
on this too but um
most of the weed smokers back then
were very disappointed in the smoke of
the afghans
yeah
they didn't really like the high and
they didn't really like the way it
burned
yeah i mean it was so vastly different
than what they were used to
compared to compared to sativas because
those sativas
have been have been bred for smoking
yeah they were bred for they were bred
to be burned as flower yeah you know
where i mean i i told this before but
there's this funny story of when sam
skunk man was in
um was in afghanistan and he was
searching for seeds
right
and so he was asking these warlords for
seeds
for flower
you know
and they looked at him
and they said you know smoking flowers
for women and slaves
right are you a woman or a slave yeah
and he had to convince them
that he was a man and he just wanted
them so he could grow his own
flower at home and make resin
i wonder if he pulled out his wiener
you know
uh and let me prove it you know but to
them it was like that that was that was
the thing the flower was a waste product
yeah
you know peasants and women slaves and
women's smoked smoked flour real men
smoked hash
that was their culture so obviously you
don't care how flower burns and you
don't care how the flower affects you
because you never smoke it in that
culture yeah so americans were the first
people taking all these hash plants and
and afghans
and actually wanting to smoke them yeah
it hadn't happened before because none
of those people back back home where
they were from gave a [ __ ]
yes
and you can kind of draw a line from
morocco
on the the western part of africa all
throughout north africa all the way up
through
um lebanon and israel
all the way over iran and into
afghanistan and that's all hash
yeah right
but then once you get to like cambodia
thailand
that all kind of got lost
yeah and it flipped into weed smoking
and exporting actual wheat
you know
huh i wonder why
i don't know why that one became so
separate
you know i don't know
you know
um you know and you know it's like i i
prefer flour too to be honest and i
don't think that we need to like base
what what what we think of on what
afghans think um
but uh
you know
definitely they um you know they just
thought that because that was the
culture that they were raised men smoke
ash
yeah you know and women smoke flour and
slaves
i like they weren't good they weren't
good enough
women were puffing tough on the flower
over there
and you know and so there's this thing
where when i first went over to
amsterdam i met this guy he's still over
there steve the nose or whatever and i
got introduced to some of this hashish
culture
and they would show me the best moroccan
the best lebanese these are amazing
temple balls this is from afghanistan
this is from the pakistani highlands
and you smoke all this stuff and it's
unbelievable yeah like he had the best
hash collection i've ever seen in my
life and these guys
they didn't even really smoke weed very
much they had it
you know but they mostly cared about
hashish
that's so funny you know and they
thought they didn't care what method you
used they didn't care what extraction
technique you had
uh did all all those cuts that you could
make hash off of they were inferior yeah
they were it was inferior hashish
interesting you know
yeah and
you know and so we we
huh
my mother knew you there i'm here so you
know they um
so
it's really a big it's really
interesting because americans like until
things open up
um i would say that 99 of americans have
probably never smoked
the top import grade of hash that you
can get
yeah
they just haven't seen it yeah it
doesn't it doesn't show up it gets it
barely gets to europe
yeah before it gets absorbed i see a lot
of people asking about the the opium
thing
and i can comment on that real quick
what they're referring to is an old
story
and it wasn't hash it wasn't a weed
thing it was necessarily it wasn't
necessary we think the story was that
tie sticks were dipped in something
called pasta water which was uh the
water used when you produce heroin so
when you're when you're doing the
conversion from opium to heroin the
leftover water is called passive water
so there was theories and or people
would spread stories that you know all
thai sticks were dipped in pasta water
and that's why they were so strong when
in reality it probably wasn't the case
that's not really how how the the water
works drying on the to weed you know
but it that that is stuck forever so
that a lot of people think that thai
sticks have heroin in them and that's
yeah that's where that came from
and you know they don't mostly because
yeah i think if it happened it would
have been very rare
i mean the re the reason why is because
cartels like that
um
they don't put more expensive drugs on
cheaper ones yeah never free that's not
how that's not how they operate you know
yeah i mean uh you know now with like
the whole fentanyl thing and all that
there are people are cutting all kinds
of stuff with highly dangerous
substances
yeah uh back in the day if anything got
cut with anything it was by something
cheaper and weaker
yeah i still am very skeptical on on
street fentanyl being cut into normal
things because it's still more expensive
i would imagine then
most of the drugs are saying that it's
cut with it doesn't really make sense
unless people are trying to buy fentanyl
and they're cutting it with [ __ ] but
cheaper i'm gonna i'm gonna reiterate it
one more time just because i think it's
really important which is that almost
all traditional hash regardless of grade
or quality
is made out of thousands and thousands
and thousands of sister plants
grown from seed
and so you get a very wide range of that
that strains profile thc
cbd cbn terpenes all that kind of stuff
it all gets blended together
right yeah and so it's
vastly different
than
growing a room or growing a greenhouse
of gmo or skittles yeah or something
along those lines and taking the exact
same genetic cut
right yep and
that exact same genetic cut and uh
and and extracting that
right
it's just very different and the way
they process it is different and how
long that it takes them before they
think it's cured into something that
they want to smoke
is also different so american hash
culture is very new
and it goes against the grain as far as
like any other kinds of
uh hashish culture that you would that
you would you would see now it is true
of course that with with demand
right they're going to mix all kind
brokers and and and people looking for
profit are going to mix all kinds of of
cut into hash yeah i'm talking about the
nicest stuff i'm talking about the pure
grade
right and hash in these regions was a
lot better
before all these white people showed up
demanding tons oh i'm sure
and then once all these europeans and
all these english and all these
americans started showing up on the
hippie hashish trail in the 70s and they
wanted just enormous amounts of it they
blew through all the best
and then of course just like any other
humans you're going to get a bunch of
people that are trying to meet demand
yeah so the quality on average is going
to go way down
and you're going to get a bunch of b and
c grade
and then you're going to get
you know and then you're going to get um
you know the the top end is gonna be a
lot more rare
yeah
you know
um and you know
like i said all those old-timers that
smokehash they all swear
that the best traditional hash is still
the best
yeah now whether that's because of the
strains they use whether that's because
it they dry farm it you know i mean i'm
sure there's a bunch of different
reasons
but the process itself is very different
yeah
and the effect is very different and
they
they all they all swear by it and that's
what they take the best of what they
grow
um
you know and that and people say that
too people say i see that all the time i
have a buddy of mine that was like oh
yeah yeah yeah they know what they're
[ __ ] talking about they [ __ ] make
hash with the same hat the hand they
[ __ ] wipe their [ __ ] on
yeah right and it's basically like
these people these humans that have
spent thousands of years refining their
hash culture don't know [ __ ]
yeah from what we've learned since oh
wait on
yeah right
right and different cultures we've gone
we've gone through everybody dabbed with
a [ __ ] thousand degree glowing cherry
red hot nail or banger yeah
unpurged bho
every two or three years we're like
improving our technique and you only
have to go back five or six or seven
years to techniques and [ __ ] that people
wouldn't do again
yeah it already get out of style that we
learned that a bunch of these terpenes
are like carcinogenic
yeah at the heat that most of these
people were dabbing them
yeah with right and then the other thing
too is when you watch you know you can
get on ig right and you can watch some
of these hash cultures work and how they
heat the hash and how they work the hash
you know and how they get the hash
malleable and how they get the the resin
to be warm before they use it you know
all that different types of stuff and
like and so there's a lot to learn from
those people
you know because they've been smoking
hash for a long time
yeah you know and like we you know we
stumble upon all this stuff and we think
we're doing amazing because you can see
through you know we want to put it on a
piece of parchment paper and be able to
see through it yeah we want to make it
off fresh frozen
harvested fresh frozen put into this
thing put through a freezer dryer all
this different stuff and
you know um you know frenchy people
talking about frenchie and stuff like
that and he did bring a little bit of
the
of
of of that different culture into all
this you know but there's an aspect of
um you know the the old-timers will tell
you
that you would store the hash in like in
loose bags right
in a cold spot and they said if you
wanted to ruin your hash you put it in
the fridge
yeah
and and the fridge and the humidity and
the [ __ ] would ruin your [ __ ]
hash
they were like if you wanted to ruin it
just just do that to it but if you put
it into a cold dry cellar and you let it
age for a while
boom
it would get better
yeah you know and
you know and so and they also grow with
a bunch of different cultivars that
we're not used to
yeah that's very true too
you know um and you know and they you
know they grow from seed every year
yeah right and we don't we grow from
clones
you know yeah um and so we've gotten
really especially on the west coast you
know um
we've gotten really egotistical
about our hash making yes and about our
extracts and we are you know we are
doing better i'm not i'm not saying that
like what we do isn't viable
i'm just saying that like from the
people in amsterdam that have vast
experience with both
yeah
they all prefer
the traditional [ __ ] if they can get the
grade they want oh i'm sure so that
should say something
okay people are asking the title of the
book and and someone did point out the
attorney app maybe isn't so well liked
but um this is with uh lawrence cherniak
and allen dronkers it's called
uh how she used the joy of making and
curing it's i was just putting up some
pictures to illustrate as we were
talking about how she used the different
styles looks
techniques in here but yeah people used
to sit there and i don't know if you can
see my hand or whatever um but like you
can they would sit there and rub and rub
and work and work and work and really
get the hash warm and malleable
sometimes people would put it into a
plastic bag and they would put it in the
heel of their shoe yeah and they would
walk on it to like work and work and
work and they wouldn't just sit there
and you'll see videos on ig now because
there's people that are going around
afghanistan and pakistan and some of
these hash cultures
of how before they use it they heat it
up
they work it they get it to be they get
it to be a certain way so there's a lot
of there's a lot of uh
there's a lot of old techniques that i
think are kind of being ignored
yeah that
um
you know it's almost like this [ __ ]
where like in california in the 70s
people knew about red and white wine
yeah
you know that was that was the level of
knowledge that like red went with
with prime rib and meat you know and
white was for their wife
and went with fish or chicken or
something and that's about all they knew
yeah and now you fast forward 30 years
or 40 years or whatever and now it's
like they're like oh merlot and this
appalachian and the pinot gris that's
that um you know that uh
that's all going on
and and whatnot and you know i think the
same thing is going to happen with hash
yeah we're a baby hash culture in
america
and we don't know [ __ ] and we're
learning stuff and every few years you
can see hash culture and you can see
people's techniques improve
yeah right
um but we could learn a lot from
you know and maybe they'll get to a
point like with the legality of things
or whatnot where you could grow a field
yeah like it would be cool for seed
makers right where you could grow a
field
of uh
of seeds
yeah and then harvest the whole thing
for hash
yeah that would be awesome and then you
get the full range of whatever you know
matt's bubble berry or or yeah you know
a skittles hybrid or a gmo hybrid or
whatever the case may be you'd get the
full range in the hash
uh instead of just like this one cut i'm
going to concentrate what's in this one
cut
yeah because that's never been done
before right yeah so that's telling me
how it's done over there it's not
typically how it's done over there and
so we have we have our own thing and
it's not bad or anything like that i'm
not saying that but
it it's very different
yeah it's very different now
we could expand it out a little bit
and talk about
um when
when they first started bringing afghans
you know we all started growing sativa
in america right yeah
because
sativa seeds came free with the [ __ ]
wheat
yeah you get kilos of you know headstash
brought in and everyone's selling it
your weed came with
free seeds yeah we used to sit there in
high school leaning back against the
chair and we'd have a we'd have a tray
and you'd break up the weed up here and
you let all the seeds and stems roll
down
and yep keep and you keep your weed up
there right but
hash didn't come with free seeds
yeah yeah
so i was just watching someone tell a
joke about bubble man
so we don't have we don't we don't we
didn't get very many seeds so
you know
sativas were all everywhere everywhere
in the 70s and 80s and that was
primarily what it all was how do you
think puck washes
how do i think like man you know
if you wanna if you wanna if if there's
people out there that don't like me and
you wanna think of me as a shitty grower
i should show you some pictures of uh my
puck grows
uh because i did some i did some depths
and i did some greenhouse outdoors with
it and uh
boy was it not impressive
no i wouldn't wash it because there
would be no reason to wash off of it i
got it was it was a really ugly i mean i
can't say what it looked like in the 80s
or in the 90s when it was a little
younger
um but you know when i got it it hated
sunlight and food
yeah
and you know strangely enough those were
two things that i liked to give my
plants sunlight and food at the time so
yeah yeah it was uh it was really
unusual um
you know and uh
you know they uh
so there's you know bubble hash and
there's another aspect of it too where
it's like maybe we should we could talk
about this for a second is that
most people
most most americans i was going to say
white people but most americans will say
it that way right yeah like we don't
like our time is our time is money
you know so you look at the way
traditional people sift sifting is an
amazing product
but it's the most time consuming
yeah and it gets the least yield
so
it's the rarest
so americans are constantly looking for
can i wash this
can i bho it can i co2 what what way can
i do it that's efficient
and i can get an extraction that yields
what how can i get yield
right well most of the time you have to
put that through a solvent
it's not just knocking the flowers
yeah over a screen and getting and
getting dry sift and then putting that
dry sip through a series of screens and
cleaning it up like bubble man as shown
right even water is the salt water is
the original solvent
that's why it's so funny that people
call water solventless
water hash is solventless like look
put in is water a solvent into google
and see what comes up yeah
it's a solvent yeah sure is the original
and what's crazy about that is if you
read now granted
there's a lot of there's a there's some
thc and terpenes and stuff like that
aren't soluble in water
yeah
but there is if you read like uh rob
clark's book hashish about 25 of
terpenes are water soluble
yeah
so you can so there's times when we did
stuff with water hash right where
you run something like some kind of
tangy cross
yeah
and that and that citrus that citrus
comes through super strong
right yeah but then you run something
like the 56 day headband and it comes
out smelling like axle grease
yeah it's super potent
but it's like chemical process didn't
like it's it the chain that makes up the
the aroma and the taste
didn't make it through the hash making
process
right so most of the stuff we do today
whether it's bho or whether it's water
hash and then frozen or this or that a
lot of these things affect the flavor
and a lot of what becomes popular
is what keeps its flavor
with the time saving techniques that we
use to make hash extraction easier
yeah
you know i mean you watch you watch
these guys like on ig or whatever then
you see them do their traditional hash
thing no american wants to be sitting
there with a face mask on for eight
hours a day over a thing
shaking
flour and knocking off the crystals and
then carefully you know like refining it
it doesn't get you enough weight for
your time
yeah
people we want to use machines
well that changes it too
yeah
right
and part of the reason why i think like
the tangy and the whole to mention that
again the tangy and the whole citrus
craze happened
is because when
like you know in the mid 2000s you
couldn't give away calio
no
if you had citrus weed that was a great
way for your broker to look at you and
say nah dog
yeah not a dog i don't need that
headache weed
i'm not taking your weed you know but
then and it was also citrus weed tends
to not be that potent yeah
so it's it's you know you could call it
i don't want to say minzy but you could
say moderately potent at best
yeah where the flavor people did blank
lacking recreational potency yeah but
then
you start extracting it with bho or this
or that or whatever and all of a sudden
that that citrus terpene came through
super solid and now the shit's 70
percent thc
yeah and it actually gets you high
yeah and so a lot of the popular strains
in america that got made into hash um
got made into hash because after you put
them through the the processes that we
do to make life easy
yeah still tasted and worked good
you know but the but the old like the
old static tech and the old like and the
old sifting tech that was like used
forever that wasn't abandoned because it
sucked it was abandoned because it was
lower yield and took a lot more time
yeah
and amer and you know most hash guys
like to make their money quick right
yeah turn it over i want to turn it over
you know and so you get like what you
think is the world's most amazing hash
the hash collectors in europe don't
think you're smoking the world's most
amazing hash yeah that's not that it's
not good
and everybody can have their opinion you
know
yeah they just have a different
perspective on it and
more
man it's hard to say a bit more cultured
at some points when it comes to hash
specifically
i mean it's one of those things like
like that's why you can compare it to
wine
yeah you know it's like
now in california you can have all these
wine nerds that are extremely
intelligent about the different grapes
and the different grades and the
different appellations and where certain
varieties do better than others because
of climate
yeah in the 70s it was red and white
and that's kind of where we are hashish
wise right now we're just learning and
like anybody who's listening right now
like you know who's made hash for the
last 10 or 15 years think about how much
your techniques and what you've been
doing has been changing
every year or two this whole time it's
not like you've reached the mountaintop
you know it's like people figure out a
way to do it better and then people are
like oh [ __ ] i'm going to do it that way
yeah and a lot of the traditional ash
people tell me that most of the modern
cultivars that we grow with suck as far
as hash extraction
where you get some yeah where you get
some lebanese [ __ ] you get some nepalese
stuff that for generations has been
grown just for that
and that [ __ ] dumps
yeah
you know because that's what they
designed it to do
and when when the hash revolution hit 10
12 years ago you know um
people started looking around for all
the elites that had been kept around and
do any of these also dump hash yeah
they weren't bred for that
no one ever thought of it
hash was like uh you know hash was like
a personal product
yeah maybe you could get some key for
the club maybe you should get some water
hash at a club you know um people would
get scissor hash
you know if you were working or people
would get finger hash when they were
bucking down stuff and all that but it
wasn't like commoditized
right
did you ever use an iso too oh god yeah
i want i want one of those to try out if
any of you guys out there have an iso 2
i will trade you some seeds for one uh i
used to use my dad's as like a he-man
castle along with my group
castle grayskull and [ __ ] but i'd really
like to see how it works today you know
we could probably do a we could probably
do a whole show one time on just the
different eras of like oh that sounds
cool
yeah oh i'm gonna go on an octagon oh
i'm gonna grow areaponics oh i'm gonna
grow nft oh i'm gonna grow this way oh
i'm gonna extract that way oh yeah you
know coliseums yeah colosseums i mean
dude i had to call it i had two coliseum
i mean we could go through all that of
just all like whatever is the most
cutting-edge [ __ ] imaginable you know do
you remember the v tables the the they
were like that yeah yeah i remember one
of those popped up there's a pencil and
so it's funny right because a lot of my
friends are egotistical or whatever you
know but it's like the the main you talk
to hash people in california and the
west coast now and they think they're
the best hash people that have ever
lived sure
that they dominate
you know and i'm not dissing them
because they are figuring stuff out and
they are making nice hash
yeah right most of them are failed
growers [ __ ] them
they're also turning their back on
thousands of years of humans learning
[ __ ]
yeah
you know and and it's it's like it's
like when you're shocked when old people
have something to teach you
yeah
you know yeah uh you know there's
there's there's techniques and there's
things and there's aspects
um you know that uh you know i mean
think about all those classes that
frenchie did
yeah
just
are you supposed to be
you know and he was and he all he was
doing was just
teaching some people
how
different cultures over there made some
hatch
yeah
you know
and people ate it up
yeah they did
you know and there's different flavor
profiles and there might be a way where
you take a cultivar and you extract it
one way and it fights potent but it
sucks
and then you do it another way and it's
amazing
so it's not like all strains react the
same like something like i said some
things go through water like a champ
right i even did [ __ ] where i would have
like a a greenhouse
full of the same strains and then i
would have outdoor
yeah and like sometimes like the sour
diesels and certain things like that if
they got rained on a bunch in october
their terpene profile wouldn't be
exactly what i was after yeah but the
sour diesel grown 30 feet away in a
greenhouse that never got rained on once
was fed with the same food and the same
everything would be bomb
you know but like the super silver haze
or certain citrus stuff it wasn't
affected by the rain at all
yeah it just kept its profile but
sometimes the rain enough rain would
[ __ ] up the flavor on my weed
yeah
you know
um and uh well you know someone just
said it's potent but it sucks that's the
biggest oxymoron ever not really it
depends because it depends on how
it depends on how you
what the high is like
yeah right i mean quality of high you
can read old high times right and not to
bring up high times but
uh a lot of people's opinion of the old
afghani one
was that it was uncomfortable anxiety
inducing body high that gave you heart
palpitations and it was one of the least
enjoyable smokes out there yeah and they
way preferred sativas or normal or nl's
or there was lots of other highs that
they liked
yeah they thought it was potent but they
didn't like it
yeah you know some people like some some
people the
that sativa buzz that nl5 haze buzz or
that neville's haze buzz it's super
potent it makes them want to crawl out
of their skin and jump off a bridge and
die and they'd never smoke it again if
you know they hate it yeah that's like
me with skunk one types they [ __ ]
hate it it's super potent it's amazing
it's the nicest sativa i've ever smoked
but there's people that are smoking a
couple of times and they'll be like i no
that's a bad time for me
so
you know potency is just one aspect it
just means it's strong it doesn't mean
that it's going to affect you in a
pleasant way
yeah you know i personally i don't like
edibles
yeah oh no you can't control the high
you can't you're just strapped in
because and the reason why i don't like
edibles and i'll be perfectly honest is
that they [ __ ] with my equilibrium
oh really they give me this like you
know when you're drunk and you're like
if i put a foot on the ground i'll stop
the spins yeah yeah they can give me the
spins
that's enough and i don't like that
feeling yeah and i'll have friends
that'll be like oh you just got to eat
enough and blow past it
yeah and for me i'm like well how how
many hours of uncomfortable do i have to
feel before i start feeling good yeah
because
i don't feel good
yeah you know i like weed a whole bunch
and i don't feel good at all
you know so how many hours of my life do
i want to not feel good
yeah you know that happens to me enough
you know so i don't do edibles because
like i got kids and [ __ ] you know so
you know one of my kids could break
their toe or whatever and yeah
it doesn't matter how much weed i've
smoked i can hop in the car i can take
him to the hospital i can do whatever i
need to do yeah but if i just ate a
couple hundred milligrams of edibles
i might need to like call a lifeline you
know or yeah for sure
i'm not you know
and then yeah i have all kinds of people
are going to start commenting oh you
just need to take these you just need to
ate these i'm just saying that for me
the way my body works
sometimes it gives me the spins
yeah
and i don't like the spins i think a lot
of people don't understand that though
how how variable the everybody's brain
chemistry is and how each individual
cannabinoid or what have you interacts
differently with everyone not everybody
gets the same effect from the same clone
though you know i mean collectives
that's the way people are tied i'll all
indicates do this all sativas do this
all hybrids do right in the middle you
know it's just yeah it's just it's just
not that way i mean i i chem 91 is one
of my all-time favorite highs
yeah it makes me feel like i'm a
teenager
watching a mel book mel brooks movie and
i got a big thing of popcorn and i'm
happy and content and life is great
yeah and we have good friends
that are like meh
i mean i love what it i love what it
what it breeds like and i understand
that a lot of other people like it but i
wouldn't like to smoke it on a regular
basis yeah but i love it
you know so there's that aspect too
you know and that's that's one of the
main things that
um all the hash guys the experience tell
me is that they can't they just simply
can't find the same effect
yeah how have you tried suppositories
buddy have you tried any of those no i
can assist you if you need help i know
you've got you've got all those you got
to all those extra jumbo i got that
extra long attachment on the thing to
get it really release no yeah i don't i
don't i don't need any of that kind of
stuff i mean i'm sure that
for people that have a hard time and a
bunch of nausea you know um i'm not
trying to make foot fun off it or
whatever that might be the best way for
them to absorb
yeah
i got a pretty funny pretty funny story
about boofing stuff so i had a friend
named brian he's dead now but he had
heard that if you boof oxycontin and
granted that we were like 17 18. you
heard that if you boof oxycontin you get
really [ __ ] up and this is the early
days of oxycontin
so he stuck the oxycontin up his ass and
waited and waited and then he realized
that there's a coating on the outside
that it really won't penetrate through
your [ __ ]
so he had to crush it up and reinsert it
into his ass
that's my boofing story you're welcome
everyone
i i do joke with uh my friends that are
younger than me you know
that their contribution to drug culture
is boofing
yeah really that is that really that's
what they that's what they're going to
be remembered for that's their
innovation
yeah you know
all that different types of stuff and
you know whatever it uh
like i have seen
people
making suppositories for very sick
cancer patients and aids patients and
other various aspects
and i'm sure
that uh they do a great job
um but what people also should know too
is that when you eat when you eat weed
yeah or you take it you know a
suppository style it turns into thc 11.
okay did you know that no i didn't it
converts into something when you smoke
it it's it's delta 11 thc delta 11.
that's right
and uh it's much longer lasting
you know um and so that's kind of why
you get [ __ ] like in the sense of like
if if it hits you the wrong way
yeah you're sort of stuck with that
feeling for a while
yeah and so me and delta nine are real
good friends
yeah
nine in me we get along we see we see
eye to eye on things
i can smoke whatever format even you
know i don't i'm more of a flower person
than hash but i can smoke a bunch of
hash and i can still accomplish whatever
i need to do
11 hydroxy not delta that makes sense
okay yeah 11 i maybe i misspoke but um
but yeah it it converts in your gut into
something different
okay and it's longer lasting and it has
a
some different effects
well yeah doesn't it um bind with your
fat cells too which makes it more potent
in your stomach now we're getting into
into areas i'm not familiar with
yeah you know it's one of those things
where i don't care about edibles that
much because i don't
um i don't uh i don't use them they're
not that important to me you know i i do
think that they're a great way for some
people to get medicine
yeah you know
but i i got [ __ ] to do and i got kids
and i can't take myself out
yeah yeah it's a good way to take
yourself out and you know to be honest
like in the 90s and stuff like that you
know uh
now you can go to the you can go to the
store and you can be like oh i'm going
to get a 5 milligram or a 10 milligram
or a 50 or 100 milligram you know yeah
um and back in the day
you know and you know when i was doing
edibles more it was like is this ganja
goo ball am i gonna feel anything
yeah
all the way up to i'm in my tent and i
can't move
yeah and i'm missing the festival
because i'm horizontal
you know yeah okay
just chimera just answered he said no it
crosses the blood-brain barrier more
easily makes sense it converts in the
liver not the gut which totally makes
sense yeah yeah i knew i was gonna i
knew i was gonna misspeak i knew that it
affected you differently and it
converted differently yeah um i was
nervous to talk about the various
science of it because i i wasn't i
probably wasn't gonna get there yeah see
i'm very um adventuresome and i'll talk
about the science of it know exactly
nothing what i'm talking about so i'm
good at that part i just knew that it
converted differently
and it and it and it it lasted longer
and it has a different series of effects
uh than inhaling than smoking
yeah i know someone said that um people
with diabetes can't feel edibles and i
can
absolutely disprove that
because i'm diabetic and i can feel
animals
yeah i mean i i've been on you know i've
eaten some ganja goo balls at times and
stuff and i i definitely i'm not i'm
speaking more experience when
i was like i'm in the tent and i can't
move i can't stand up i need to pee am i
gonna pee myself
can i move yeah you know that's the good
[ __ ] yeah because you know it's just
like it's just bad dosing
yeah these six kinds of goo balls are
almost worthless and you wasted your
money and this one is like catatonic
yeah you know do you really want to be
catatonic at a festival you know yeah i
know that's how you get raised happens
well no i mean not that i mean but it's
but it's just yeah you paid money to be
there and now you're laying on rocks on
in a tent
spinning
you know
um
but it's just one of those things where
it's like uh
you know and actually too it's like it's
interesting in the sense that i don't
even know if i should bring this up but
i have a i have a daughter that's i have
a couple daughters in middle school
right
and it's one of their big issues right
now
is edibles
really
think about it it's taking animals to
school yeah they're easy to mask
an older brother an older sister or
someone that's willing to go and buy
them and kick them down
yeah they're sour patch kids they're
made in a bunch of attractive ways now
like when we were kids the only way you
got edibles is if some degenerate older
brother made some brownies yeah exactly
off some shake or something like that
was able to stink up their whole house
or some [ __ ] yeah now they can get like
these really attractive much more
controllable packages
right there you're not going to get
caught with a lighter or a pipe or
stinking like weed or anything like that
you can just eat like a 10 milligram
yeah right and so they're a lot more
prevalent makes sense nerds ropes sour
patch kids rice crispy treats all kinds
of there's an immense amount of of of
baking
and candy
and [ __ ] and much more controllable
amounts
um that uh i just don't like it
and i'm not what you're saying is kids
are good customers
no you know i just mean that kids kids
are going to get access to whatever is
cool that's available in their local
area and it's easy to smuggle in i mean
i remember back in high school they
would do like locker raids and all kinds
of [ __ ] trying to catch us dealing drugs
and uh we didn't have things like you
know gummy bears and [ __ ] like that yeah
if you if you if you took out some of
those gummy bears if you took out some
sour patch kids from a from a an edible
thing you got and you put them in a real
sour patch kids thing and took them in
your lunch box or your thing or backpack
how would they [ __ ] know exactly yeah
visible at that point you know
um
but you know so
i just uh i just i just don't like
edibles
you know
i just don't like edibles um but
um we kind of got off we kind of got off
track there or whatever but it's like a
big thing
you know and some people are into them
but they steal they steal my they steal
my equilibrium i don't know if they
steal other people's equilibrium
but i start
not feeling the right way and then i get
hot
yeah and when you get hot and you have
the spins i mean how fun is that yeah
you end up puking that's enough it's not
fun for me
no you know
but
you know and i i think it'll probably
take like it would probably take like
international
freedom
where weed really becomes opened up
you know yeah for americans
over here at least to really start
trying like the finest grades
of imported hashish
i just don't see i i see the
the world opening up and it being so
super corporate and hyper illegal that
nobody's gonna be [ __ ] with [ __ ] like
that
you know it's gonna be in afghanistan
they'll have
those small clubs and all that [ __ ]
it'll be just that culture infiltrating
everywhere as opposed to letting the
cultures that are there stay there being
able to try each other's cultures
uh
who knows there's money to be made off
this [ __ ] you know right now you know
you can get you can get greek olive oil
you know you can get those iberian hams
that cost eighteen hundred dollars for
the leg that have been dry aged x amount
you know there's a lot to get
you know what you can't get
thai land races anymore it's very very
hard things are disappearing not just
the not just the strains but the
cultures are disappearing with them in
some senses and granted that's not a
hash culture necessarily but it's just
like just like those strains
disappearing i mean it's you know the
techniques are going to be going with
them
over time
so you know people are saying people
people are talking about people paying
more for six star or whatever else so
there's an aspect where
you know there's obviously different
grades
right
but no matter how pure you make it
you're still limited by your starting
material
yeah are you all getting it from a
single source
right is it all the same cultivar is all
the same cut are you getting it from a
field are you getting it from uh you
know you planted thousands of seeds and
you're harvesting those females
yeah you know
um and uh and all that and so
uh you know there's an aspect there
where
um
you know because you're gonna cut hash
is concentrated right
yeah where you're gonna concentrate what
was in the flower
yeah you're going to concentrate the
qualities of that of that thc or that
blend or that cbd cbn terpene profile
all that you know what do they call it
entourage effect
yes you know so you just you're going to
get a vastly different experience
probably from moroccan from lebanese to
afghanistan to southeast asian to
sherbolato
yeah
right
yes sir sure
sure
and then a lot of times too people
people still like even hash makers right
now it's like oh my god this is
unbelievable
the terpenes off it are amazing but it
yielded two percent so [ __ ] it i'm not
gonna do it
yeah right people want hash dumpers
yeah it's gotta it's gotta be
commercially viable
first
or it won't get beyond some small little
circle there might be some there might
be a few friends that like wash it and
they're all trading grams amongst each
other and all stoked but it won't
trickle down to where the normal person
can get it because it wasn't a viable
amount
exactly and i'm not a hash guy that that
big or whatever but i do know from
working in legal cannabis and stuff like
that that there's minimum numbers of
weight return that you need to get to
make it be viable yeah to pay for your
time to pay for the equipment to pay for
the the shift work and all the stuff
that goes into making hash so if it
doesn't dump enough
regardless of how nice it affects you
yeah it's gonna get it's gonna get
shifted to the side
yeah and if you've got something that
that blows your head off but it yields
three and a half percent
and it's sister plant
tastes a little bit different and
doesn't work as good but yields six
percent yeah the six percent is getting
run and washed all day
yeah because that's making them money
you know
so
um you know so there's that too where
it's like the commercial side of it
people might think oh we have the best
hash in the world but unless it's
commercially viable you'll probably
never see it
unless you're growing it and washing it
and making it yourself
yeah or in your small circle of friends
and trading it amongst each other
just like you know just like before like
if you were growing a 12 or 13 or 14
week plant
you'd probably never be able to buy that
in a store
yeah i wouldn't think so gmo is probably
the first thing that came out that took
12 weeks
that people were willing to jump on
yeah that always shocked me especially
coming from cookies
well part of the reason part of the
reason why i think people were willing
to jump on it was because even though it
took two weeks four weeks longer than
they wanted or three weeks longer than
they wanted it dumped like crazy
yeah and it tested super high
and it smelled like chem d and chem d
was not everywhere yeah so it like so
you know there so the yield made it
worth it yeah right where if the yield
doesn't make the extra time worth it i
mean
matt and i joke that like i mean there's
some pretty famous breeders out there
that are like if it takes any longer
than 63 days it's [ __ ]
yeah
or i'm harvesting it early
yeah i've got this banger colombian and
it takes 11 weeks but i don't take it
longer than 63 days because it doesn't
fit my model
yeah
you know
that's kind of how that rolls
yeah
and uh american way the american well
it's just it's it's there's a difference
between quality and commercial
yeah and that's what i mean too about
about like for instance the uh the wine
industry is now there's enough education
in the wine industry
that
a certain seven or eight year old
cabernet
from a certain winery in a certain
region
you can get that extra ducats
to make that a viable product right now
cannabis doesn't have enough of that
separation
to make the rare and the cool and the
expensive worth it
right there's all there's like this
range that everybody's working in and we
haven't gotten educated enough that you
could be like you should pay more for
this weed because it's neville's haze
and it takes 15 weeks and you know it
does this
eventually you'll have people that are
willing to throw down for that
yeah right right now you don't
right right now it's just it's it's you
don't you know
and so until you get that level of
education until you get that consumer
willing to pay for it i honestly think
like the reason why
people are going to yell at me for this
but i think the reason why freaking uh
hayes did so well in new york
right
was because there was there was
musicians and rich people and wall
street brokers to sell it to
yeah
they could they could sell them a higher
grade
yeah straight up just like that you know
i mean do you think kush would have been
so popular in in la if it wasn't 7 200 a
pound wholesale oh yeah no never it was
an aspect of it where
where it became massive because in l.a
it was like oh this is expensive and
exclusive and it's not in your bag yeah
and then people wanted what the what
what people had it
yeah right and people were willing to
pay a [ __ ] ton for it
but we really haven't gotten there with
weed yet too much there's individual
things that break through here and there
but we really haven't gotten the
criteria as to like why
this weed or why this hash is nicer and
should be more expensive
yeah
you know
um
you know i mean i even saw there was
there was some [ __ ] i can't remember
what it was i you know i see that uh you
know chimeras on here he was talking
earlier this week about he's got rks
that he doesn't want to release
because it's got unique traits in it
that
he wants to utilize later
yeah and he doesn't think the market's
ready for it
whatever those traits might be
you know
and that could be that could be true too
there's lots of times the market isn't
ready for anything
i've always been very good at being
um
at the forefront of stuff and absolutely
making no sells being at the forefront
of stuff and watching others come and
clean up with it it's just about hitting
it at the right time when the market's
ready for something i mean we talked
about that before too like all that
super dog work that me and my and my
homie did you know
um that was like years before american
seed sellers could really get a toehold
yeah we had no place for it to go
yeah
you know we had no place for it to go
you know
so um
uh you know it's it's got to be the
right it's got it there's got to be a
balance between commercially viable
and fire
yeah and it has to match
you know so i don't know right now it's
like we've been in that we we went to
war with afghanistan for 20 years so
it's probably not the uh
um it's probably not the best time to go
over there as a white guy
and
start looking around for hashish and and
rare things like that you know yeah you
can get taliban or whatever
um but
you know but uh
um but they actually have a real culture
over there
yeah they have a real vibrant hashish
culture
and it's just separated from us
you know it's always a trip to me with
how how um
religiously conservative those areas are
but there still is a breeding culture or
a weep culture there you know
it is so counter to the muslim culture
i just you know it's like i think it's
one of those things where it's like uh
it predated you know predated uh that
whole thing yeah it's just it's it's it
was just kind of like how
you know like you know there's any
number of different things where like
christianity just absorbs certain pagan
rituals into itself oh yeah that's true
good because they because they couldn't
get rid of it
yeah they co-opted it
right
yeah so you want to bring you want to
bring allah to
afghanistan you're going to have to
incorporate some hashish
yeah because it's ancient there and they
ain't getting rid
yeah should have done that with
christians
you know better here yeah i mean well
you know they i mean they it just it
just didn't it's probably an anomaly
yeah
honestly yeah you know like it's an
accident
you know um
and you know they probably didn't
realize how much effect they were gonna
have
a thousand years later or two thousand
years later i'm sure
in the in in that regard
you know yeah
so
but yeah i mean hash
you know the the hash in america is
moving along really quickly
uh and i wish i could go back to
um maybe i will sometime and go back and
um and talk in in holland and stuff like
that and see what what they have right
now is their best stuff
yeah that'd be interesting to know
and just how it affects you
yeah because that's what they all talk
about is the the flavor and the effect
is just un un used can't you just can't
get it in other [ __ ]
i'll be the judge of that [ __ ]
you know yeah i don't know yeah
but and they also even back when i was
going back there a bunch it was like
they would grab you know like you know a
certain amount of kilos would hit
amsterdam and it would all get bought up
by collectors
and then they all sit on it and hope
that they didn't run out before they
found something else of that quality
yeah and so they'd have a chunk of this
and a chunk of this and a chunk of that
and you know so on and so forth and
whatnot
and that's what you know they'd smoke
they'd smoke they'd almost keep flour
for the americans
yeah and then they said and then they'd
show you what they really were we're
into
yeah
in that regard
you know
um and
you know and so uh you know we're
we uh
i don't know maybe maybe there's a
there's an aspect with america where we
blend we blended a bunch of the smoking
weed with a bunch of the hashish weed
what do you mean
huh what do you mean
well you know we took stuff that was
bred for smoking like thai
colombia and and mexican and things of
that nature and then we blended it with
all this stuff that was
specifically designed for hashish
yeah
like all the afghans that came over
originally yeah
that was all bred exclusively for they
did they weren't going for like does
this flower taste good
yeah they never tasted the flour
right
yeah they hashed it
but the hash had to taste have a taste
of its own
you know yeah but it's different it's
different when you're burning aged hash
that's versus versus like a bunch of
flower material yeah
you know and so we started figuring all
that out and we started blending it with
sativas and blending it with different
things and trying to see how they all
came out yeah you know it's weird in the
sense that like america and holland sort
of became the two places i should say
canada too north america
sort of became where like all the
various regions of weed started blending
yeah you could probably put australia in
that category
that sounds like it sounds like i don't
have a lot of familiarity with over
there but like it sounds like australia
was another melting pot where they got a
bunch of southeast asian weed and they
got a bunch of uh
um
they got a bunch of indian and
afghanistan and pakistan and blends of
different stuff you know
yeah and whatnot and so
you know it uh
and there was people too maybe we could
switch we could switch bases for a
second there was people that were asking
which is more matt's world than mine uh
i can let him talk for a minute about
what the what the internet what the seed
market is like outside of us like
outside of the us
outside of our like little sts reversals
like what everyone's familiar with oh
this guy's dropping caps dropping
something matt's dropping something csi
has a drop here comes these people you
know because we're used to like very
small scale
um
you know like and i think probably most
people think of the last 10 years as
what's normal
yeah but that's not i would think so
yeah
but that's not really what's out there
but you know obviously like so maybe you
could talk for a minute about like what
what is it like out there
well i mean like
so like someone like chimera that's been
around before me he's gonna have a
different experience than when i entered
when i entered in you had to [ __ ] with
europeans or your seeds weren't going to
sell you know if you weren't [ __ ]
with european seed bank and were trying
to do direct you had a very very small
chance of getting any meaningful sales
because people wanted to buy from seed
banks seed banks were known there wasn't
a lot of places to do exchanges you
could always you know do it get down in
the dms on different forums and stuff
but that was that was really not cool
like it wasn't looked at as a cool thing
to do by the the forum owners because
they were they were kind of taking
some risk for your exchange even though
it was done in the dms it's still on
their server and transactions so it
wasn't looked upon positively by a lot
of the the
the uh forum owners for anybody to be
doing any exchanges of any sorts and
usually you'd get banned from uh places
for doing anything of the sort
um so we were we were
mostly counting on um
when i entered in it had just started
the british and uh
attitude wasn't a thing when i first
started um but yeah most of it was
outside of the us i think heaven
stairway was was that canada or that or
us
i think uh canada
i think it was canada
where it was canada i believe was it
canada where calrissian i believe so
yeah i mean
you had the canadian seed banks a lot of
them wouldn't pick up american folks i
remember um
med user chris
over at wood horse seeds he was really
not friendly to most americans hemp
depot
was around but you still had a hard time
getting them to pick up most americans
so being an american you had the choice
mostly of british or if you were lucky
like a dutch seed bank would pick you up
but yeah it's
it was minimal a lot of it like when
when i got booted off the attitude
subcool had asked and basically gave
that given them a uh ultimatum me or him
and at the time there was just me and
him that were the americans on there
when i left the attitude and uh
on unceremoniously left
i had to to figure out what was i going
to do is i going to take the risk be the
one american trying to
sell direct or was i going to just find
another seed bank and get [ __ ] so
first thing i did was try to operate a
seed bank with a few other americans and
unfortunately chose the brothel brothers
who were notorious scammers and they got
me
and eventually i just learned [ __ ] i
gotta do this myself or it's it's not
gonna work
and from there you know i mean you could
be operating great in the u.s but if you
weren't taking credit cards like the
europeans then you just weren't going to
be any sort of competition and those
were always going to get the the sales
nowadays it's a lot different nowadays
there's all sorts of direct buying uh
instagram kind of changed a lot you know
instagram made everyone a lot more
accessible um seeds were a lot easier to
sell because people weren't as
interested in effect they were more
interested in learning uh by looking you
know oh that's pretty that look that
looks dank became a real catchphrase
during instagram oh that looks dank but
i mean
back in the day we kind of knew that
looks didn't mean anything when it came
to dangerous i mean yeah the weird thing
let me interject for a second because
i'm saying stuff in the comments is that
america was an enormous seed market
yes but everyone that tried to deal with
america
typically got in trouble yeah so
everyone in europe you know when they
saw what happened in neville um yeah the
super sativa seed club just shut down
and a lot of
you know seed banks became very hesitant
to ship stuff to america yeah and then
canadian seed banks sort of took over
that that role for a minute and started
being willing to ship stuff to america
um and a lot of times they sort of like
took the reins from europe because
europe would send it to canada
you know and it would get and it would
get filtered through but as uh you know
camaro was mentioning a few minutes ago
um heaven stairway went down because
there was an intercepted shipment to the
united states and that got cannabis
world and overgrowth shut down at the
same time
and
well and we we're going to do a full
episode on this me and flan but it's
we're going to go into detail on um silk
road
heaven stairway
overgrow
icy mag and how they were all related in
the big bust
this is over a period of several years i
mean it's that people are still being
prosecuted from one major [ __ ] up yeah
and then that's one of those why i used
to go to amsterdam to buy seed in the
90s
was because that was the most reliable
way to get it uh getting it shipped over
was very difficult you know and a lot of
people wouldn't do it uh mark emery who
had you know cannabis culture magazine
uh and all that and he had his whole
seed company um he ended up doing i
don't know five-ish years or something
like that in america
in prison for seed sales
um so there was a big issue with
america's this voracious seed market
but how do you get
seeds there without getting in trouble
yeah
and so
you know there wasn't you know people on
ig now you can see all these things and
that's why i was joking about you know
oh this guy's got a drop coming
you know when 20 years ago or whatever
when i was doing a bunch of breeding
work
there was no outlet to get that to
anyone
yeah there was no way to advertise it
there was no way to set up shipping
there was no way to i mean even like
somebody like dj short who um
ended up working with a bunch of
canadians
part of the reason why he worked with so
many people was that in order for his
sweet his stuff to get out there he had
to work with tony from sag martha first
yeah and then he ended up working with
the dutch passion crew
yeah
i think a dutch passion and he ended up
not liking that and then he ended up
working with various people up in canada
but he had to work with third parties
because there was no way for him
to safely distribute advertise and
communicate with people from america to
get seeds out
yeah so it really wasn't until social
media exploded and ig exploded and
proposition 215 and medical started
spreading enough that it started calming
down yeah for all these seed companies
like you know think about all the
popular you know uh cap or or you know
swamp boys or these people you know
cookie anybody right
all these people came up and their
possibilities started
in the social media ig
yeah so what matt's talking about is how
difficult it was as an american seed
breeder to even find a home
that could that could be a middleman
that could get they could get your seeds
out to people so you know my buddy
that uh that i you know he doesn't like
to be mentioned but my buddy i call
staten island he kept talking about like
the potential for seats
and i was totally dismissive
right
and we were both right
right at the time i was right
what he saw 10 or 15 years down the road
what was coming
yeah
you know he did he he saw it but it just
wasn't there yet
i remember making that that
shift from um
cash cropping i mean it's a very very
clear memory for me when i had to make
that choice of [ __ ]
i can cash crop or i can make seeds i'm
learning i cannot do both you know and
having to make something that i know i
know i can make enough money to survive
growing since mia
that's not what i love to do you know
that way that did that slowly was not my
passion anymore my passion was making
seeds and and learning what i could
create you know what could be created in
these rooms and uh having to make that
decision to only go to siege was a tough
one because at the time they it was very
risky there wasn't a lot of money in
seeds i mean granted greenhouses killing
it dna was killing it but americans just
weren't killing it at that level yet i
mean dna we can talk about dna for a
second those are two americans plumber
and the stunt cop yeah and they you know
they they went to humboldt and mendo and
all these different places and they
gathered up a bunch of seed and a bunch
of clones from various friends
but they had to go to holland to make a
seed company yeah there was no there was
no in the early 2000s there was no way
they were going to do an american-based
seed company
how would they even get a hold of you
yeah how would you get a hold of them
how would you not get busted
yeah you know it was uh it wasn't it
wasn't very easy and so we basically
worked first through holland
and that's kind of why holland became
the epicenter
was it allowed it
yeah right neville got lucky because he
had balls
and a bunch of american breeders were
fleeing prosecution in america
and bringing him stuff right and you
know he got stuff from from greg and he
got stuff from sam skunk man and he and
he got stuff through mel frank and jorge
cervantes and he got stuff from jim
ortega
all these people
you know because that was the place that
it could go
yeah and then when canada became the
place it could go that's where it all
went
and then when california and oregon and
washington started being the place that
it could go that's where it went
yeah and it really sucks
because there's this artificial line
between america and canada
that sort of kept our two cultures it's
made it a lot more difficult
to
huh
i'm not gonna lie between 2007 and 2010
the fact that it was such a small market
it was [ __ ] killer he didn't have all
kinds of competition i mean the the best
competition i had was like swerve and
sub at the time and rascal you know for
americans and rascal was he was at the
top of the the food chain when it came
to reversals but i mean
sub and swerve you know yeah no i i mean
there's there's there's an aspect of it
but it's like that
you know um
people think that like people don't
realize how long it took
to get to get democracy where some guy
in a garage could have a 15 lighter or
two or three four lighters or whatever
yeah and make some breeding and do a
drop
yeah and advertise the drop
and let uh and let everyone know
that it was coming
you know i was just thinking about
something as far as drops go like i
remember when that was looked at very
negatively if you're gonna do a drop
meaning you're gonna hit one male to
more than five or six plants you were a
shitty pawn chucker and that was like a
mark of shame like drops were not a
thing and now that's the common accepted
way this clone or this male crossed x
amount of clones and that's the accepted
way but back in the day that was not you
were not looked at favorably i mean
that's what i did so i'm not looking
down on anyone for doing it i was one of
the people looked down on not favorable
for doing those i mean we talked about
it before but you know 12 or 14 years
ago the four or five guys uh doing
reversals
were looked upon as cheating
yeah it's cheating you're ruining the
[ __ ] you are ruining genetics for
good you're ruining the gene pool you're
eliminating males you're taking
shortcuts
you're doing this [ __ ] up thing that
shouldn't be done
you're trying to do shortcuts to make a
quick buck
yep um and it went from that and it was
you know i don't know
uh
emery is a douchebag i totally agree
that he i think most people agree he's a
gun that he is a he is a non-he is not a
nice person um
by any means um you know i mean but
you know there's a there's a lot of
people that uh you know you get to know
him and weed and you're like oh boy
yeah he's not a good kisser but yeah but
there's an aspect where it's like like
we've talked about it what was it it was
it was matt and rascal and hybe
and
uh a couple other a couple other people
doing rehearsals
yeah and it was a sea of of male female
breeding
and now fast forward 12 years and it's
completely reversed
yeah it's like 98 fems
and two percent of people doing reg
breeding yeah it's rare to see people do
i've got a reg seedline drop
you know what's really weird too for me
like i i don't do that many um
fem seed runs anymore i really don't
even though i saw the spray and i've
been doing it a long time people
associate me with that i i don't do them
often i don't do them very often at all
and i prefer regular seed breeding
because it's so much easier it's like a
[ __ ] free pass to not fail
and uh yeah it's it's it's a totally
different than people's uh ideas of what
fem breeding is and how easy it is it's
uh regular breeding is easy
in the sense of getting actual
successful pollination
with real not not that you're going to
achieve your goals that's still the
breeding is a lot of there's still a lot
of dead ends and failure in my opinion
and sure you know and all that but but
you know feminized breeding even even
getting pollen and getting viable pollen
um
you know uh people
it's a crapshoot people are saying i
don't think the market's telling
breeders what they want
no
i don't necessarily i don't think that's
it i think that
finding males is a bunch of work
and people
started doing things where you can't get
either one of these two elite cuttings
but i'll give you a hybrid of them yeah
you can't get tk by skittles
yeah you know you can't get either cut
but you can buy a hybrid from me
and i think that's what started it and i
think
honestly it's like people buy what's
available
you know um and uh
you know
reversals just you just took an elite
cut and you crossed it to another elite
you took an elite cut and you threw that
on 15 or 20 other cuts and boom you've
got a seed drop
yep and reversals actually really killed
the the line breeding
you know companies used to we were going
to talk about simon today tonight right
yeah we're going to talk about sirius a
little bit or whatever
uh serious seeds they offered the same
six lines for like [ __ ] 15 years
yeah 20 years
you know uh scentsy seed bank you know
uh when neville was there or whatever
probably matt and i were looking at a
bunch of the catalogs
they barely offered a new line for five
or six years yeah it was the same as
[ __ ] and then in the late 90s they added
two or three more lines yeah back in the
day they expected you to work on your
line and refine it hopefully
and you have those flagship strains yeah
make those lines better over time now
it's literally like i did this reversal
i got x amount of seeds they're here
until they're gone i probably won't make
them again i gave it a name
yeah
you know but
that's it there's no lines you can't you
can't hit up you know um you could hit
up serious seeds throughout the 90s and
you could get ak-47 and you could get
white russian and you could get chronic
and you could get bubble gum and you
could get
um you know whatever
right and it was just on on it was just
available
so let me let me use this point actually
to tell a story and you'll like this
story because it it has something to do
with you so
i gave natso some seeds a while back and
i i was pretty sure i remembered what i
gave him right
um i thought i gave him an old pack of
ak-47 and i i was like man when's he
gonna pop those [ __ ] and i
would bust his balls over it like man
where's those aka 47 get him pop he's
like i don't know what you're talking
about i'm like [ __ ] not so right so i
bust his balls for at least a year and a
half two years two years every time i
lost his [ __ ] ancient seeds i'm the
old seed guy i talk up ak like crazy all
this different stuff he sends them to me
not only do i not do anything with them
but i [ __ ] them over by like not
actually cracking them or like you won't
crack them i just [ __ ] ignored them
and then i lost them and i keep telling
them i don't have them over and over and
over again
and i'm like dude i gave you these
[ __ ] seeds what the [ __ ] so anyways i
was busting his balls about him again
probably i don't know a month ago yeah
you know something like that not that
long
and someone i hadn't talked to for a
long time skunk tech hits him up and is
like hey you know i haven't talked to
matt but let him know that i f2 those
ak-47 seeds he gave me so
oh i was so happy too because i called
that up and i was like you're a dick
dude you gave them to someone else
and [ __ ] me and told me that i [ __ ]
lost them and i didn't remember and i'm
a stoner and [ __ ] yeah yeah
you know you said i sent rare [ __ ] from
the 90s and i blew it off
but in fairness he still does have super
skunk and devil's haze over there
but you know there's a there's a yeah i
mean in fairness to me
uh before 2017 there wasn't like
biblical fires every year in my area
yeah yeah yeah i don't mind the fires at
all and so that that ruined a number of
seed crops for me and gave me kind of
some ptsd
and all that
but yeah i mean going back to going back
to simon i mean can you imagine if
you know whoever you know for the last
five years the swamp boys have offered
the same six lines
yeah
matt's offered the same six lines
caleb's csi's offered the same 20.
and they just remake them
and that's what people are doing
yeah and you get you're expected to work
on all those lines and improve them but
you can because you're only offering
half a dozen
now every seed drop is like [ __ ] 20
things
yeah at least usually you know and
they're all given a name and they're all
given packaging and they're all given
this and they're all sold and that's
that that's that
and you'll likely never see them again
because the person's not going to remake
them
and honestly the person the [ __ ] the
person isn't even usually growing them
out anymore
yeah
you know so i i will say just just to
finish the story
i will give skunk tech some major props
he didn't even have to tell me that he
had those he didn't have to tell me that
he did selections and
made more and he certainly didn't have
to tell natso to make sure i get them
you know or make sure i know about them
to get them so props to him for doing
that i was i was that was pretty [ __ ]
cool and uh there are ak-47 f2 somewhere
and they're
based on the cherry stuff so that's cool
too what's sad about it is is that in
um they changed the laws in holland in
amsterdam and um i should say the
netherlands really because only two
provinces
uh are
our holland but in the netherlands they
changed the seed laws where before seed
making was legal
and they changed it to being illegal and
most of the big producers in in the
netherlands got busted within a year or
two of that change yeah um and a lot of
seed strains and a lot of lines that
were available throughout the 90s
then changed because parents were lost
yes being dutch
and i'm not trying to be
racist is the wrong word or whatever but
just culturally
the dutch are businessmen and they won't
admit that they lost anything ever
yeah
so if you ask ben or alan drunkers
they'll tell you they have all the same
breeding parents that they've had since
the 90s
yeah but we know that's not the case and
it apparently simon admitted that he
lost a couple of breeding parents
in in his raid and kali mist and ak-47
were not the same after
yeah
we should also it should also be said
and this is super [ __ ] annoying for
me right
but that
neville
and
s super sativa seed club kind of came
first
right
so they just told you where they were
what they were doing
yeah they didn't have competition right
so neville was like oh i got this nl
from this person and i got this from
this this and i crossed them and i
called it nl by this
yeah right and and he gave you a whole
bunch of information on lineage
yeah we can go through we've done it
before but you can go through and most
of where neville got his stuff we know
the name of the person that gave it to
him we know where he got it we know if
he got it as a seed line or if he got it
as a cutting
right we know all that [ __ ]
i liked simon and simon was really nice
to me right but
i don't [ __ ] know it's an ak-47
yeah i don't know exactly what's in
collie missed i've been hunting for 25
30 years what the lineage on that stuff
is yeah and all the second wave of
breeders uh that came out uh sag martha
syria seeds th seeds dutch passion all
you know uh
um what's his name um luke from paradise
yes what's in scentsy star
god only knows what's in what they all
started hiding it
yeah they they hid where they got it
from who they got it from what the mix
was in
right and so it started this massive
guessing game of i love ak-47
yeah i have no idea what's in it
i would love for simon to one day be
like i'm old and i'm just down to to say
it you know what i one thing i will say
that's also interesting is from that old
pack of seeds and i believe they were
sold and simon said according to the
number on it they were sold in 2000
which meant they could have been made in
98.99
what was interesting was that the cherry
pheno was supposedly popping up what do
you say one in 500 or 1000 something
a lot it took a lot to find it
in the three seeds that popped
out of ten from this old pack
two were cherry
so i wonder if there's some sort of like
viking in it um which was a very cherry
line floating around amsterdam at the
time that a lot of people are using um
but that that's the first thing that
that makes me think that and i think
that's pretty interesting it could
you know
said that that uh something that i
didn't know that it wasn't lost in the
bus that simon's ex-wife killed them
killed a couple plants out of spite
oh wait it was it was it's common
knowledge that he lost him and i mean i
always heard that he lost him
yeah um but you know i assumed it was in
the bust and he admitted that he lost
one parent but he never admitted that he
lost more than that yeah but he would
just never give up the mix
yeah
he just never
that that's another thing that also
really confused me is that
i don't understand why
they would i granted a lot of them were
trying to steal each other's clones and
steal each other's seeds or whatever but
if they were breeders they would know
that how expressions in cannabis work
you know so they probably like i would
think that they wouldn't be focused too
much on well we can't tell them the name
or the the the line that this came from
because they'll get the same thing and i
mean well no one knows you're aware
uh neville's opinion was they stole most
of it from him and didn't want to give
him [ __ ] credit
yeah i know yeah he thought everything
was his though no matter what i know i'm
not saying it is i'm not saying it's
true
yeah but for whatever reason
um you know like yeah what's in chronic
what's what's what's kali missed
what's
what's ak47 what are the parents
yeah where do you get the parents who
gave them the parents
yeah
you know
um all that right you just don't know
yeah you know they've never come out and
saying those things came out in the mid
90s yeah so we're talking 25 years plus
of him being secretive
yeah
you know and yeah neville had an ego and
he thought the whole [ __ ] scene was
based on his [ __ ]
yeah and some of it was but some of it
was his ego you know i still think he
renamed afghani one
i mean i know you do yeah i'm always i'm
always going to push that theory and
it's based on nothing but i'm still
going to push it just because i can i
mean one of the things that i learned
about uh
someone just asked what do i believe in
cali mist
um i was told by some guys in amsterdam
that um
you know that the mother plant was this
thing called the mango
and it was made by this guy that i don't
want to name his name or whatever but it
was he was the guy that came up with it
and that was at least half of it
um and i i see people uh
uh
you know there's people want to talk
about whatever but i mean the thing is
is that when i went over there and when
i started going over there in the mid
90s there was already a bunch of dudes
that were middle-aged that all had beef
with one another yeah and obviously
neville and sam had a bunch of beef with
one another and they sniped at each
other for years
um and so there's an aspect there's an
aspect too where it's like sometimes
people just didn't want to give other
people credit
yeah they didn't want it to come from
them
yeah you know they didn't want it to be
that way they didn't want it they didn't
want to be like oh well i got that from
homie
yeah because homie was a dick to them
in their mind you know and then they had
beef and so then there was politics you
can look at the politics of 90s
amsterdam and you can fast forward 30
years and it goes on today in california
yeah
it's very common
so this is this is one of the
old pictures of afghani one that has a
lot of similar traits to what you will
see in in things like super skunk or
even chem 91 and that's one of the the
things that originally put me to that
and seeing and the la athey cut that we
had that was a afghani number one
selection homie just said uh collie mist
was originally called western winds
western winds was one of my favorite
all-time
uh
cannabis names cambodian cambodian
that's what they said but i don't
[ __ ] know it's supposedly when they
were at cerebral together
it was the same thing
and they broke off tony called his
version western winds
and simon called his collie missed but
they were the same thing
yeah they were the or they i mean maybe
they maybe they made different breeding
selections or choices but they were the
same
the same origin for the most part i will
say tony tony has been ridiculously
transparent and open with me when it
comes to asking any questions he's the
only
dutch dude who who had a seed bank from
back then that never like flinches when
i ask him something he's always been
super open even if it's not like even if
he doesn't know the answer he'll tell
you well i don't really know this came i
bought it in bulk from xyz and that's
what it is and that's all we know he's
been really [ __ ] cool about it so i
got to give props to him for that
you know i mean maybe maybe he would say
what it was but maybe if it came from
simon or he had b for some guy he didn't
like he wouldn't say it
yeah because that goes on today like
people don't want to give other people
credit if they don't like the person you
know or they feel like they got jacked
on a
i mean even like somebody like sam like
if it wasn't for mel frank uh i don't
you know talking about it years later
you wouldn't know that afghani won and
durbin poison came through mel frank
yeah and he gave him to sam
yeah you know sam showed up in amsterdam
with him
you know yeah um
and uh you know and then you know tony
tony has you know and then once a line
splits
maybe different breeders make different
selections
yeah they lean it towards one direction
or another you know they lose with adam
done and and the bubble gum and like the
different ways simon worked bubble gum
supposedly and all that yeah i mean i
know that i know i you know i didn't i
didn't know until tonight that that uh
simon's ex or whatever killed killed the
cut but
simon's kali missed in the 90s was much
more sativa leaning
and then around 99 2000 it got shorter
and thicker and more
more indica more afghan and it lost some
of the ethereal qualities that i liked a
bunch about it you know that's one that
i'd really like to reproduce and we have
the old seeds to do it but i just it's
one of those ones that like i'd spend
money and time reproducing it and they
would just sit there you know and nobody
grew up because kelly missed really
isn't one that people talked about at
you know the average grower still in the
u.s it's phenomenal there's phenos in
western winds and you can look
in western winds and cauli mist
especially in like some mid to late 90s
high times cannabis cups like the glossy
pictures they would have and those and
those things
um and uh
you know and um you know so they uh
they're those are really nice you know
yeah
and um
you know
you know then he comes out and says it's
kind of true i don't mean that like sam
took a bunch of credit for it i just
mean that it was like in the list of
stuff that that mel that you know that
he brought to amsterdam yeah and he
didn't obviously say well i got these
two things from these guys and i got
these from these guys and here's the
three hayes brothers names that i got
these seats like you know it sketchy
back then yes you still can't get that
[ __ ] out of him
you still can't get that out of him all
right he'll tell me is that i'm wrong
about the a story tell me what
one day you know one day
i mean it's uh one thing about weed is
that people are opinionated
yes and it takes a certain kind of
person to take the risks that we all we
all take and the various things that go
on and you know we get beef you know and
all that stuff and so
um but it's it's also true that a lot of
weed is a flash in the pan
so it might be around for two or three
or four years five years and then all of
a sudden it's gone or it's not there in
the same it's not there in the same in
the same category anymore yeah it
doesn't exist
um and there's some there's some really
good versions of ak that still float
around um there was an ak in colorado
that our good buddy working men and i
talk about all the time that was a huge
yielding beast of a sativa
um and it smelled exactly like
sandalwood did
pure sandalwood terps
uh matt worked with an ak version that
had strong cherry liqueur
cherry and then lemon i had a lemon one
too that was awesome and then i had the
rc cola fino that used to go around
skunk magazine and it smelled like flat
cola it was it was pretty uncanny so
that that's a pretty wide terp range in
the ak line and and interesting and
unique terps and a lot of them had some
pretty god some pretty good highs with
them too you know
so that was a really simon didn't have a
lot of strains
but you know the only the only strain
that i think he had there was absolute
bunk and i apologize if you hear this
simon is chronic
yeah i grew out a bunch of chronic and
it was big and midsy and ugly
and i never found anything worthwhile in
it but
his bubble gum and his ak and his white
russian and his cali mist and all that
that was all real nice weed i think
white russian is totally underrated too
from all white russian is super
underrated strain and it was one of his
standards for a long time and it was
killer weed yeah there was some really
nice phenos of it
you know i wish i knew i wish just for
my weed nerdism or whatever i wish i
knew i you know i wish i knew what ak-47
was
yeah like what is it
i think if we're getting these cherry
liqueur phenotypes is from hexabutyrate
not a terp but do you think that i mean
because we know that during that time
there was one real strong cherry kicker
that was being used in amsterdam um
which was the either the holland's hope
which was a version of the viking or
just using viking and they were being
used widely at that time so i i i've
never
now that i know that it's just like and
how how commonly it occurs it almost
seems like it would have to be
chimera and crybaby both telling us that
the cherry is is is uh from uh
it's not a terp you know yeah that's why
you know it's it's the theol's and all
all the various esters and all the
various things that lead to aromas uh
that's not an aldehyde that's not that's
not nice uh forte necessarily there's a
lot of learning that i could do over
there that would expand my knowledge
um but
i would love if he told me what was in
it
yeah
it would be real it would be really neat
just to know because it's one of the
all-time great strains
yeah the super cool strain and it's neat
that there's
um
it's neat that there is uh
maybe here's something that we've talked
about and that most people don't don't
think about too much but um we're
getting close to the end but i'll throw
it out there yeah and maybe this is
something that like a chimera could
chime in on or whatever but
um what would happen let's say you have
two ak-47s
or you know or two nl5 hazes or
something like that from the 90s and
you're pretty damn sure that they are
what they are that they're the exact
same
era they're the exact same parents
they're just two different
two different plants but from the same
seed line
yeah if you reverse one on to the other
do you get a feminized seed line
because it's not an outcross
and it's not an s1
so so give me the situation again
let's say you took
uh
you know um
uh an uh a cherry ak and crossed it to
the colorado sandalwood ak okay
it's not an s1
and it's not an outcross
no
right
that's when we make up words like in
cross that's when we make them up
because cannabis is very unique and we
got to make up our own [ __ ] words
you can do it with anything you could
take any any anything that you know are
sisters
yeah and that came from the same parents
right because most people that are doing
reversals
99.99 percent of reversals are either s
ones or out crosses
yeah we would i mean i know me and caleb
refer to them as f2rs just when we talk
so we know what we're talking about but
i don't think there's any standard term
because there's a way where it's like
you know part of the reason why we do
s1s uh one of the reasons why we do it
in cannabis at least is because often
there's only one pheno there's only one
living cut of a certain line left and in
order for you to look within the
genetics of the line and see what else
might be in there you have to cross it
to itself
yeah we would make normal lines out of a
lot of these strains had we a male
yes or had we but if you have two
females
and you're sure they're the exact same
thing
right then you could breed two sisters
together
yeah and it wouldn't be inbreeding as
much because they would have two
different genetic profiles
yes right it's not you're not in you're
not inbreeding to the extent that an s1
would be no no you're not you're not
isolating traits still so you take you
take a sandalwood smelling
ak-47 and you cross it onto the cherry
ak-47
yeah
and you you know and then you have you
have a you have a a feminized seed line
maybe that's what uh bitter did with the
p91 s ones took two different p91 s ones
and crossed them together to create his
neck but the difference is that those
are two s ones crossed together
yeah i'm talking about like two sisters
from the same exact hybrid
you see on the same thing
that's what it was though two sisters
from the same because if you have an s
one if you have two sisters from an s
one there's one parent
and that's one has one parent right
there's two identical parents so the
genetics is essentially one parent
but if you take two sisters from a
regular line
right
yeah then it's two parents
you know and it's like if you like for
instance i got multiple daughters you
look at my daughters they're not two
peas from the same pod
yeah obviously you know they have some
they got you know they look very
different from each other yeah you know
my wife and i's jeans popped in
different ways in that regard
so you're referring specifically to an
f1 hybrid and then using
two
sisters from that f1 hybrid not from a
reversal necessarily like let's say for
instance you took
um you know we can't get we can't
guarantee this but let's say you took c5
yeah and crossed it to cuban black and
you were sure you know that you're or
you had two phenos of nl5 haze yeah and
you knew that the mom was nl5 and the
dad was haze in both it was just two
phenos from the same thing
right and you cross those you reversed
one on to the other
yeah that's probably one of the most
rare things in breeding
because then you'd have a feminized line
but it wouldn't be an
s1 i mean the only difference between
that in the feminized version would be
that the feminized version would have
less
variation
because there wasn't an additional
uh line
at the
what we're calling the parental level
but that's all but i just mean in the
sense that so let's say you take let's
say you make a cherry ak s1
yeah you're gonna only have the gene
pool that's within that specific
that specific plant
it would be going in that direction for
that specific but if you had if you had
a sister of hers
yes that was something different even
though they're sisters she probably has
a different a slightly different genetic
makeup so it would be a sibling cross
yeah but it's almost never done because
we almost never have to it wouldn't be
nearly as inbred
yeah it wouldn't be nearly as inbred as
a reverse crop and you'd probably you'd
probably get like a a lot wider
expression within the seats
you know what's interesting though what
you're describing is almost exactly what
dj did with blueberry
two
things that were were from the same
parentage two totally opposite different
expressions and constantly re-cross them
from a small population
each generation i mean i'm not saying
that like in a perfect world if you had
hundreds of seeds that's the direction
that you you should go in oh no no but
i'm just saying that is a method sure
there's there's an aspect where it's
like if all you have in the line is one
living living example
then you all you can do is self it
yeah but if you got two
then you could widen the gene pool just
slightly
yeah and have and have a group of seeds
that had a slightly wider gene pool
than you could get with s1
yeah but i think like if you keep like
that
i think if you do that and you keep
doing it in successive generations what
you get is a lot of mutants and
weirdness without necessarily the the
narrow down variation i was just
thinking in terms of like 90s weed or
various things where you might get lucky
and you might have one or you might have
two or even three phenos that might
exist
yeah
you see
yeah like where it wouldn't be that that
would probably be
i don't know
you know it's just something that's not
often done but if there's two females
from the same line you might be able to
figure it out
but it's almost never done
think of somebody that you think of
somebody that has that often
it's like it's almost like back crossing
it's not off you don't see back
you don't see back crosses to males
often done
but it's an interesting thing you know
what i mean it has its place
yeah i just in terms of i mean in terms
of most genetic preservation we're like
super lucky
if one pheno of an old line survives
oh yeah for sure
you know but in the case of in the case
of nl5 by hay c
there's probably three or four or five
that survived
yeah a lot more than that i think if we
really knew for sure i think there'd be
a lot more
you know and so there's potential where
you could you could you know you could i
i don't know i mean it's just
interesting in that in that regard right
yeah projects the monster those are not
siblings
um let's see we don't know for sure
they're not [ __ ] siblings i don't
think so
yeah but we once the
that we hoped that that philos and some
other and some other genetic groups
would be able to prove these things
and it has not happened
yeah no philos got everybody's money
because they promised they would be able
to show what was a grandparent what was
a child what was a hut what was a
daughter what was a mother
and not not the case
and we're still going to do a full
episode on that eventually
on why
why we were able to prove that it was a
broken system
uh effectively prove it
but um yeah
you're gonna give it a little bit of
time so people don't get to butt hurt
and sue and all that [ __ ]
you know but it's it's just one of those
things where uh
uh do we know whether males or females
are responsible specific
there's no there's no you know there's a
lot of there's no way it works
because because cannabis for a long time
has been
well i just i was just gonna say that um
cannabis for a long time has been
deprived of science or the science
aspect
of uh of breeding uh most of it is
observational by people
still to this day there are some people
that um
uh there are some people that are doing
that are doing work uh that are using a
lot more uh scientific methods and
things like that but
um it's rare still
yeah most cannabis breeding is
observational
um and so it's hard to know males and
females
um you know we just don't have we just
we just word did not up until 10 15
years ago or something like that we were
mostly denied labs
yeah we were mostly denied access
um to what you know normal breeders
would be able to use all the time
yeah so i want to do a um giveaway
before we're done since we're almost at
two hours
and i actually thought of something to
do so you didn't have to um
so like we used to do back in the back
in i don't know a year or two ago
i picked out
um
a phrase there's going to be a blank
spot in this phrase and whoever comes up
with
who we all agree
is the funniest answer gets the bomb
threat bubba hawaiian lights hybrid um
it's one of the more expensive ones so i
wanted to get it out there so people can
yeah anyways so
we have a few different ones let me see
okay here we go here it is you guys if
you want to participate you're going to
have to fill in the blank
rub-a-dub-dub blank in the tub who has
the best answer rub-a-dub-dub your
answer in a tub who has the best answer
oh man
i know this one should be nice and
creative
rub a dub dub
blank in a tub
rub a dub dub dank in a tub
12 vc in a tub
these nuts is always a great response
let's yeah
fiddling
tug in a tub
sub in a tub oh that's a good one
because that didn't that did exist
it did exist
until it's gross
yeah i might have to pin this one so we
remember who did sub in the tub to see
if someone could beat him
let's see pin okay let's see what we got
those pictures of sub in the tub were
were not cool oh i remember when i made
the the no i'm not gonna say it since
he's no longer with us yeah they just
weren't they just you know
pre-79 rks seeds in the tub
in the tub
oh my god
yeah
hilarious
sub in his camera in a tub oh my god i
mean the thing about sub in the tub is
that it rhymes too you know yeah i know
it's pretty it's great it's it's it's
creative it has a whole thing you know
yeah i don't want pea butt in the tub
either sub should win rub
i forgot to wear my peabud shirt i just
got another peabud shirt from my buddy
forgot it
yeah so yeah i think i think we're gonna
have to go
with triagrone send me a send me a dm
after this you get the the hawaii the
bomb threat bubba hawaiian lights
so yeah it's it's it's a it's
it can't beat it so we're almost we're
almost to two hours so we'll do our
normal little thing here on friday night
um yeah as always we're down to totally
talk a lot of what we talked about
tonight was suggestions from people on
our discord
asking us to chat about certain things
um that's a great way to get what you
want talked about talked about is yeah
reach out to us either on ig or joining
our discord which matt always explains
at the end
um but we're always down to
chat about things uh some episodes are
kind of formal in the sense that we have
a whole theme that we want to go off of
um and some of them are uh some of them
are are are a little bit more loose and
uh interactive
um but always hit us up you know get me
up hit me up on ig hit me up on our
discord
you know
right now
okay so
you can go to paint or i'm sorry google
type in breederson to get patreon you
can join us on the discord i think
there's some some fights coming up the
second um we just had some cool fights
last week that we we hang out talk [ __ ]
to each other and watch the fights which
has nothing to do with cannabis but hey
whatever it's something else to do um
you also get access to my whole uh
catalog collection in pdf form which i
highly recommend if you are a part of
the the the patreon if you don't know
about that go check them out
it's not just the old seed bank and and
scentsy catalogs there's a lot of really
random uh rare ones
um so yeah beers read using your patreon
go check out rightco.com
hopefully soon we'll start having more
of the podcast show up um we might
split it off to a new one i don't know
how it's going to go but we'll see but
we'll have the audio form of the podcast
going back up very soon
um yeah uh go check out
speakeasy seed bank they've helped us
along the way with with the uh getting
the podcast in audio form up till this
point so go check them out support them
and uh yeah that's it once again friday
night thank you all for your time very
much it's always super appreciated we
like talking [ __ ] about weed
um and so we'll be here again next
friday night pleasure yep
enjoy
oh yeah i highly recommend you guys go
watch what [ __ ] shoe said
yeah it's a good one it's it's a good
one