then uh
a new lesson in
goddamn
see it only lets me search or send
invites so i've got to wait till
let me see i can at least get chimera in
here
so
i'll have [ __ ]
i'll have kip hit um
do a request once he gets in here and
that's how it'll work
yeah i'm gonna have to have him send a
request to join i got chimeras but i
have to wait till kips does so i can hit
them both in at the same time because
when i go to that screen it immediately
after it's done it will make it so i
can't touch anything on the screen to
add anyone in or even have comment or
anything it just freezes the phone so
hopefully one more time is all we need i
don't know if that's all we need
whenever kid gets in here let me know
sorry to keep doing you dirty guys
yeah you can do up to four people but i
have to get um oh good i get someone to
boot already
screenshot
and hide my video
[Music]
that's how we do that one
kip
so we're waiting for kip anybody got any
questions
anything you want to be asking uh the
legend seats crew
get them ready get the good questions
ready
should only be a moment hopefully
who do i beat that fast i don't know who
did i move
guess it was nobody
the highland mexican blueberry yeah
that's a that's a that's a special one
hey come here see if um
kip's gonna rejoin
cake was delicious i had
for my birthday yesterday bring got me a
um
what is that a peach cobbler from
smith's bakery oh my god smith is the
best the best
cobbler
ever made in history for a fat kid to
love
and rejoice with
you got lots of kick
that's a kick
legend's ultimate indica question
let me see if i can do it this way real
quick
yeah it's only showing the requests
let's see
it's not an order so i'm still looking
for kip hopefully to find if he's in
here
it always makes it better when you can
have the whole crew if we can pull it
off
i'm not here yet
yeah dude
boomin boomer i'm a straight boomer when
it comes to electronics apparently
okay
well should we just run with chimera
let's do it
so we can get this jamming
and hopefully um
hopefully if kip does come in we can try
to add him in i might be able to do it
that way
what's up
it's right
here we tried all right so we're already
getting questions about legends ultimate
indica
did you work on that one at all
no that was kip and steve well it was
really it was kit but did it
um was
robot and yes that i saw him
chirping away there he's really
smart good grower you guys should follow
him if you're not already he does some
really interesting [ __ ]
um definitely
the ultimate indica is such a classic
[ __ ] story
you know back in the day yeah
when they were getting switzerland off
the ground
the you know the the the
what was it i guess they call it ended
up calling it sweet two 23 but it was
like a third back cross to the
grapefruit
you know kind of like i say
you know you know breeders that don't
know what they're doing they kind of
rely heavily on back crossing hope that
that just hoping that that solves it
solves it all out
um
anyway
gip you know kipp was
owned legends and he steve actually
owned a part of legends at that point in
time
and so you know
kip was over there working in
switzerland at the warehouse in the
field
and he was supposed to get paid
you know a big chunk of uh
the compensation was in those sweet two
three beans that had been really hyped
up for a year because steven had steve
hadn't been working right he kind of was
like yeah and the game out of stock and
that was the much anticipated release
and so
you know
had suspected that he would be getting
oh what he was promised was he would be
getting a large portion of the sweet two
three seeds
that were to be pre-marketed so he could
just turn around and sell those things
and when they were loading up when they
were loading up the room i guess they
had a few extra lights like maybe you
know like
10 15 of the lights in the room
where they didn't have enough grapefruit
plants to go in
so he took the artic they had all these
ortega plants that were sticking around
that had rose and solid brought over to
switzerland
or sorry he brought over the genetic and
they'd mod them up and you know had
these extra plants
and so kids said well why don't we just
why don't we toss these in the room
we've got the space anyway let's toss
these up these uh ortega plants in and
make an f1 hybrid
and
so
when the crop finally came down
you know steve
i'm gonna pay you in these
untested f1 hybrid seeds rather than the
sweet two three seeds
which was it was kind of a bummer i
think forget because you know yeah of
course
pre-work and those ones were pre-sold
really
yeah
but instead he got those the the ortega
sweet 2 3 f1 hybrid or f1 type hybrid
and so he came back to canada and he had
a couple of shows here and they
threw a bunch of um
they threw a bunch of the what became
the lui in that room to test them out
and grow them before they saw them and
they turned out to be actually quite
banger plants like they really yeah they
are
some real f1 hybrid figure i didn't love
the flavor on them but it was like you
know it was a grower's plant
and if you were
like it made [ __ ] incredible hash
so
here's some of my heady bread is saying
that lui sampled from sativa's sisters
in 2004 it was covered in large
trigramas that would snow all over the
plate when broken up heavy stone that
was the cut that they called we ended up
calling red's pick
which is fine oh was that red
yeah that was the one
and it was it's you know like dude it
was an amazing plant like it really i
don't know actually it was an amazing
plant it was amazing growing plant
and you'd you know you'd lock the tops
off the off the thing at six weeks
because they were so big and beefy that
you'd have mold if you didn't
so yeah that kind of became the cash
croppers method as you come in and lock
the tops off them at six weeks and then
give the the rest like another 10 days
or whatever
yeah
and uh yeah really popular clone i mean
[ __ ] dude that guy ended up they had a
clone house as well and
like
it you know they sold trays and trays
and trays that cloned that thing for
well over a year
and it made all over the place
so yeah
that's crazy
yeah interesting interesting plant
did it end up selling well in seed form
pretty well like i think i would think
so
yeah i think it took like six or eight
months before it really caught on you
know you know what it is
it takes a cycle for someone to go
through it and then
you know you gotta you know say you send
out 20 30 packs of seeds
yeah really it takes one person that has
a really good job that does a good job
with it too yeah that's kind of
advertise it and that kind of makes it
wrong
and by that point in time they really
did roll and they were they started
selling well
and uh
yeah
so there's a here's one for you moon
tide says chimera do you think you could
be bringing back the blueberry of dj's
heyday the more sativa side
probably not in the same way that he
could i mean you know what it's like
it's like yeah
you know you might have them like an
impression of your buddy's girlfriend
but you're never going to know her like
your buddy yeah
right and that's kind of how i feel with
it with with the blueberry stuff it's
something that dj's got his own
vision of what it is
um
and you know i think that to get close
to what he's doing
here you know
he'd be the person to go back and find
something that was close to what it was
we've put out a couple of things i mean
in our blueberry hybrid lines like the
the fighting buddha and then you know
the dolce line
i would probably go down those paths
more than try to go down
like what to work on
yeah that makes sense
yeah so i hunted down the um
i hunted down the
the
the blue bonnet path this last time
which is the more afghani type and i
always had it in my head that
because most of the examples that i'd
seen that were super blueberry muffin
smelling
typically were more narrow leaf type
plants i thought that
i was not going to see it as as
prevalent in the afghani type but i saw
it more prevalent in the afghani type
from that specific line it's really
interesting
yeah i think that those
those generalizations that were put on
the the line like we you know we read
about like the moon time old-time
moonshine essentially being like
you know the frosty indica it's not
necessarily clear-cut like that like
you'll find no again because they're all
siblings or half-siblings
you kind of find little bits of each
other in every line right
yeah
they're more predominantly like like the
old-time moonshine is more predominantly
like that but yeah
yeah did you get to run through any of
them moonshine rocket
i fuel uh
no i didn't that was one of them didn't
i guess yeah i couldn't remember what
era he did that
that was one of the first releases that
he did and it was like right off the bat
right off the bat they were like in
limited supply
i i worked with him but we you know i
was one of the early
clients to be buying pollen from him he
you know he had set up these things and
was going to be selling pollen
and so i sent him like a bunch of money
early on for that
and um it just never showed up like the
stuff that showed up it was so poorly
packaged
um yeah like you just we couldn't have
made it a bit like in my opinion there
was no business there
and he ended up replacing with a bunch
of the blue what was the satellite the
satellite number two
so i i got like 150 of those in exchange
for the pollen that didn't work
and we grew a bunch of them in
california i wasn't actually that
impressed with that line like i was
surprised for being a hybrid
it was still pretty [ __ ] inbred like
it was still weak
and we found a couple of really nice
like
again not nice plants but the plants
that had nice variegation in them yeah
like really
some really interesting kind of
phenotypical patterns
but nothing that was banging and you
know like i said we tested all that
stuff too and ran it through the lab
and it all came back at like
years ago
it all came back at like you know eight
to twelve percent
which is pretty low right
um
yeah
yeah so
[Music]
you know like and i think that that's
actually where the dj gets the
you know you hear people talking about
that kind of cerebral head space
yeah i think that that actually is a
result not of
the terpenes and the chemistry it's
actually a result of the low cannabinoid
content
yeah
my technical abilities at this stage in
a week are really limited guys it was
more my fault than yours
oh trust me i'm sure it was more mental
so for those that don't know this is uh
red kip from legend seeds he was one of
the other head breeders there and ran
the brick and mortar shop and if you
would like to hear more um you can also
check out our podcast that we just
released the other day season two
episode one breeder syndicate happy to
have you dude
nice to be here this is my my first one
of these ever so i i feel i feel so very
you know vulnerable something gentle
please
dude
love it
i feel like i should just lob questions
up all night i mean kip is
you know he disappeared from the scene
for a while but
you know he hasn't really i don't think
you've ever really gotten your dues for
the amount of stuff that you put in i
know it's not about ego or
becoming popular or anything like that
for for you you do it out of love for
the plant but man you've done some
pretty epic stuff back in the day and
like i was telling matt earlier
you know the work that you're doing with
shelter and helping them get that
company off the ground
and buying hundreds of kilos and making
pre-rolls and selling across the market
i mean
they're the consumers are lucky in
canada to have that kind of [ __ ] because
you know as you know the game is pretty
weak right so it's nice to see people
that are out there
um
making making a change and actually
putting stuff out that's a reasonable
price and it gets good reviews
yeah
but guys i mean i have a dream job um i
am one of the most fortunate people
that i know i'm i'm humbled every day i
mean i guys i get to buy weed for a
living and pay taxes
right right it's a trip man it's a trip
um
and that said i get to see the good the
bad the ugly across
this beautiful country of ours and
what's going on and
man the you know the fake news that some
of these small outfits get and when they
come into the scene and are trying to
spread their flower and just like yeah
it's so tough like all the cars are
stacked so far against us here right now
um that you know what i'm loving is
finding small bands of villages that
bind together and help each other out
through processors and vendors and
distributors and um and just you know
everybody kind of pat each other on the
back and trying to lift each other up
but uh the ankle biters will succeed in
the end
yeah yeah it does tend to happen so
great garden says most wreck in canada
is boof though
[Laughter]
it's not you know here's the problem why
somebody would uh say that
the provinces they really they they like
they capture everything in that province
you can't get national distribution it's
next to impossible from you know
newfoundland to victoria to get the same
weed across and to get someone's vision
out there it's so regionalized and it's
ridiculous because
if you think about the taxation the big
that the province uh put on as far as
you know the warehousing and the
distribution that they are obviously
aware of uh or sorry that they are
obviously a part of um you know
it's it's they're like their own little
fighters like their own little countries
each it's like you know having a 12th
country in a massive continent that you
have to deal with uh it's so hard so you
know you get a micro cultivator that
pumps out maybe 30 40 paging a month
and you know where does that go well
that gets eaten up by one province in a
matter of like six weeks if it's fire
you know it's gone and man there's some
good weed out there there's some amazing
growers out there um there's 200 micros
plus in in candle right now
and so are you telling me that all legal
weeds buff well i just by the numbers i
don't believe i think it's [ __ ] i
mean i know better i've i've puffed it
i've seen the grows i've walked in that
and those guys flip ups uh along the way
when shelter first got their first micro
that was gord from north 40 and he was
the first micro cannabis that was
branded under his name in canada
and you know now we've got 242 years
later man it's a trip
you know yeah dude
what now what what qualifies someone as
a micro license in canada what's the
qualifications for that yeah so a micro
license is 21.25 so basically you can
only have 2125 square feet of canopy in
your facility okay gotcha
and that includes your moms your clones
your cuts your production plants all
that kind of stuff
um but i mean the good ones know how to
do it right it's all about my fault in
the plant knowing your genetics
knowing your
system um yeah
and and implementing the [ __ ] you know i
got a micro up here man he's almost
pumping out like
on average probably 60 kg a month out of
that canopy so it's just about the
special sauce and the formula
shocking it's all kush but you know
yeah right right
[Laughter]
yeah it's it's knowing your strains
knowing how they're going to express in
that particular environment and making
them shine for for what you have
that's it and i also have an
understanding for what the market needs
to yeah that's part of it right yeah um
it's not like we're all back in the day
growing bad warehouses and throwing into
some truck into the void
yeah exactly
you know um we actually have to be
responsible for what we put out now hey
that a [ __ ] yeah
right
right yeah you've seen a lot of the
collapse in the market that we've seen
in
the us
well there's a collapse in the [ __ ] part
of the market for sure yeah for sure but
like here in the us it's like i mean
things are hitting really low numbers
all across the board like 350 for for uh
last i saw anyways was 350 for depths
which is insane per pound
so
yeah i mean you know i don't feel so bad
canada's got the cheapest legal weed in
the entire globe man
you're not gonna get some strings for
you guys come on yes
how do you guys make that work up there
it's just
doing it right just you do it and that's
that
great question manny yeah [ __ ] blue
man
you know
efficiencies and scale smaller drops
straighter lines
less government bureaucracy as much as
we can
uh the fact is is that that's going to
be a slow arduous process listen i've
said this before one of the greatest
[ __ ]
injustices that's going on right now is
the excise tax that's a federal excise
tax it's a buck a gram yeah and on top
of that i mean i can go on to the five
layers of tax that come into this bloody
plant that's just the biggest egregious
one because that was based on wholesale
pricing via ten dollars a gram well that
ain't the wholesale pricing these days
no
so we're getting you're getting screwed
i mean the government makes 450 a gram
where where a producer could make a buck
like
it's [ __ ] criminal
absolutely brilliant
um
so anyways the fact is is that in order
to
excuse or to change an excise tax on any
level in canada it takes an actual
parliament
yeah
so that ain't happening anytime soon you
know yeah
until we get lobbyists an association
getting everyone together and backed
like every other goddamn ministry has to
push their agenda to push their goodwill
and their message uh to the rest of the
canadians
but you're not going to get that when
you've got large corporations and then
you've got the small guys all the
midfielders are being
they're being wasted and they're or
they're being bought up yeah they
haven't gonna have nots it's you know
small culture big company uh it's
playing out in canada in an exponential
way like a video game yeah
yeah and so i mean it's coming down
south soon you know the only reason
maddie it's not legal there yet because
they haven't figured out how to take all
the money yet but that's exactly it yeah
you really need lobbyists to make any
kind of headway anywhere when it comes
to government and taxes and any of it
and i think being that we're all a bunch
of
cowboys it's just
not our our specialty to be [ __ ] with
lobbyists it's new
yeah you know what we're
the next generation will say that they
stood on our shoulders as we for the
guys in the 70s before us and you know
back in the day so
we all have a part in this long story
and we're this chapter so we do what we
do hey brothers and sisters we got it
legalized
yeah right man you know like
okay so next step take it further you
know let's get hemp as is the only thing
that should be being grown across the
nation to save us from you know
utter global
dissolve as a yeah so i mean i can go on
and on but uh yeah i'm just i'm excited
to be a part of it uh i love what i do i
get to meet so many cool people all day
i just feel very lucky that's awesome
well we're glad to have you dude
let's let's let's ask kip some stuff
chimera that like talk about some of the
bigger lines he's been a part of that
they can still see today so they
understand who he is
yeah well i mean it was such a period of
time and i think a lot of people missed
it but i mean legends you guys had all
these really interesting little ones
like the johnny blaze and
you had a time warp blueberry line for a
short period of time and what else does
the honeybee
that renee cross the high end what are
you telling some of those ones
and tell us
about the neville's haze
yeah yeah yes
i got so i got the last of the 12 scenes
in neville's hands that aryan from
greenhouse had and his personal stash i
picked him up and
yeah aryan was a true friend and i don't
give a [ __ ] about what everybody's
preconditioned thoughts might have been
about that cat back in the day he was
nothing but kind to us a ryan in our
crew and the people we had around us at
that time he was generous with his time
he was
uh a wealth of knowledge and he was an
ambassador to a land we knew much not
much about back when we were young [ __ ]
running around europe so um yeah he was
just a good person anyways we used to
sell the seeds right so through great
canadian seeds and the amsterdam kind of
thing and legends so we would go over to
amsterdam you know four or five times a
year to go buy seeds right so
a lot of many many dinners and good
times with the boys yeah but he ended up
gifting me the last 12
levels haze he had from when
he got them from the man and uh so i
used those to cross
uh dj's um daddy from the second line
that we did to the true blue and the
f-13 the moonshine the same daddy with
uh with the neville sage we call it
johnny blaze
and it's it's sad that i never
personally and i'll be honest never got
to run any of them i was so upset but we
sure sent the pile out and uh our
brothers uh and og uh
a lot of guys screw them out and man i
mean i just felt like like just so proud
to be a part of it some of the stuff
came out beautiful you know when you can
pick like six brackets off and just roll
them in a paper yeah yeah
i still have some of those seeds and i
actually used it in a project with the
strawberry cream line so still living
maddie how'd that turn out
um it i was trying to recreate the
strawberry cream um because it was a
clone
at the time i only knew it as a clone
from cedarbury farms
and i was trying to recreate it and i
noticed in the room that it was next to
the the old blue dream santa cruz cut
and i noticed like looking at them you
could barely tell any difference and the
nose was only slightly more strawberry
in the strawberry frame but it had a lot
of the similar smells so i was like
if i want to create this i need a male
that's going to be something similar so
i went for the johnny blaze and that
line still sold today it's it's awesome
dude it's one of my favorite lines ever
that makes me want to hear it dude
yeah dude they're killers
that was six the when we made those
seeds they went 16 and a half weeks
um
yeah actually maybe it was a full 17 i
can't yeah i remember that
and they were little pens too a little
pinhead
yeah absolutely those were fun days that
was it um we were living beside a nhl
player in a grow house
on the west side of vancouver when we
made those seats
that's awesome
yeah those were good days those are good
days
but uh yeah i mean again just fortunate
to have been around a pile of different
um
guys that had really tasty cuts and and
mentors like dan dj i mean
you know he was uh he was everything to
me in my career and just in my life i
mean
taught me so much um
danny was uh he was he was uncle danny
to us all for a while there in vancouver
when him and carla were living up there
yeah that's pretty cool
yeah it was pretty cool man i just again
really stupid
my favorite one but again my favorite
one that we ran was the high end that
would be the renee blueberry i never got
to try that one i i've always wanted to
try is renae still around
yeah the original cut i don't have my
hands on that thing hurt me back like 30
years ago i can't imagine
yeah it was actually that that plant as
as hyped as it got
it actually had some really negative
traits like you'd be growing like a week
seven it would shoot a banana and then
just ripen
it was like it would just kind of stop
growing it was a really weird one
yeah um
some funk is asking about some mexican
guerrero let's we'll get into that in a
second but i just want to let um
i wanted to speak on someone was asking
about garrett and the work that he did
with the seed bank originals can you
talk on the seed bank originals
and the origin of all that let that out
of the bag
and maybe just said like you know like a
personal story with garrett i mean
garrett was such a
a nice guy he reminded me of like you
know weird al yankovic
or the fourth member of rush yes
[Music]
magnus seed company
that ended up being bought up and kind
of consumed and worked into the serious
seed company oh magus yeah yeah magnus
that's right that's what it was yeah but
he was motivation
i'm trying to remember what it was it
was like motivation warlock right yeah i
guess
it was yeah it was warlock was his big
one that was like that was the the the
hammer of his entire collection it was
like scentsy seed skunk one
yeah
that means that predominated
for a while in the beginning of the
canadian scene up here
you know
um we're like what was the other one
here they did that kind of equatorial
leading one too what was that ryan i
can't remember his lines i don't
remember yeah it's been a long time
since i've actually destroyed that's
right
that's right i have a great story on the
i'm garrett so
my dad was doing the stage in paris
for a year and i was working in
switzerland and so i decided to go see
my dad he was staying at a an old monk
villa balloon uh like right below say
michelle square
and uh so we were hanging out in paris
and doing that and i said dad i you know
i got a little business in amsterdam
and uh so the year before is when we had
gone and taken all the weed from
switzerland up to uh the high times cup
and entered and gotten third for that
last beer
the mercy third but uh anyways
so we had brought a bunch of wheat up
there and uh there was a bunch of coffee
shops to still hold us money for about
the wee week we literally just dropped a
pile of keys on those coffee shops just
left it and said we gotta get the [ __ ]
out of here and we'll be back you know
yeah so actually pete young calls me
pete young calls me he's like hey if
you're going to amsterdam go to also a
place there was this much and there was
this much and i'm like okay so i got a
little [ __ ] list and okay let's do this
so i said dad you want to come to
amsterdam with me you can be my you can
be my muscle i got to go collect some
money
my dad's my dad's very much like me a
small little white man and he's a social
worker he doesn't have a harmful bonus
body so this was classic
we get there and uh the first so i got
all my meetings set up right the first
morning is at the bluebird with garrett
and uh so garrett's there and uh he
knows that i had this like abs like my
tempo ball my greasy temple ball but i
was smoking tobacco that when with
tobacco and a nice coffee in the morning
just made my day the way it was supposed
to go right
and uh so i take my old man and so
my dad and i are smoking me like so
garrett's there and he's got all the
nice behind the counter temple ball and
he's throwing them all out there and my
dad's just like what the where am i you
know
so
we started puffing up when i'm not gone
joint three i see my old man in the
corner it's 9 30 in the morning half a
croissant in his hand passed out in the
corner i'm like hey crap pop we got
three more meetings like give me a taxi
i'm going back to the hotel
[Laughter]
look at me he's like uh yeah your
daddy's uh not dutch eh
[ __ ]
those [ __ ]
yeah i love garrett garrett was a good
man sold he was one of the first guys to
come on the legendaries from europe uh
from because some from somewhat kind of
outer like with that not dutch passion
that sensei not serious not the big six
basically he was the first guy and man
we sold a lot of his seeds we sold a lot
making suits yeah uh he was a good man i
really miss him he was a good one
is that what i heard
no he just got out of the game he just
got out of the game like
it was kind of when like the first kind
of downsizing was happening
and
in the industry and he he just he wasn't
into it anymore and he apparently made
an offer to simon and simon took it so
yeah it was it was like 2010 2011 when
they merged i think somewhere around
there
right oh that's good that's a good
almost
almost nine years after i last dealt
with them so okay all right well there
you go good for him man he was a nice
guy honest i always said what he was
going to do very kind very little just
really good guy
yeah his stuff had a good reputation too
it really did like the warlock someone
mentioned a bitty early that was another
one that he was famous for that's right
all of them have been right right yeah
dude you know who is around the same
time was felix
from
alex nina did yeah
dude he had he had the um
for so many years in pure form i can't i
mean like i have like f gen of it maybe
somewhere but like yeah it's it's hard
to find and i i as a base purple that
reads true for purple and i i have an
obsession with purples that's always
been on the list and and his stuff's so
hard to get over here you're an antho
head yes um
his stuff what the special part of his
stuff was it was high altitude bread
right so he was eating those yields up
like 14 1500 feet man
i mean that was some special [ __ ] and it
wouldn't mold i mean you could literally
throw mold on it it wouldn't mold and
you know it what it didn't get but if
you but if you threw through labs now it
probably started about 14
yeah yeah
but it got you high it was a good day
smoke it was bountiful
um and you also know what i think it had
ryan i think i had cedarine in it to be
honest with you now that i know i can
identify that terpene now i know that
taste because i've had that taste before
and the first time i had that taste was
in the papriati chinese wow yeah
absolutely
um anyways and then the heaven his
heaven was one of his best bars that
total equatorial that yielded like a
punk was basically like a durban crossed
haze it was spectacular i've never even
heard of that one
yeah he sold that the heaven and prepare
teaching and he had a third one that he
only ran two lots of from like
01 to 03. i'd have to go back into my in
my page if i remember i have proceeds
for three that we bought from them at
one point anyway was it beer
or meat was it the earth beer
it doesn't bring a bell but brother it
might be i just it just stands for
strawberry it's a super strawberry
strain that he would [ __ ] with a lot
you know his nursery was right downtown
almost in uh in lago it was like this
little concrete compound and you had
this
this greenhouse inside of it like there
were banks all around like he was such a
he was the very og original rebel from
switzerland
that's awesome he broke all the rules
didn't give him flying [ __ ] and when the
cops would start pressing i mean just go
run to the hills for a couple months and
then you can get that and come back you
know he was awesome but i really i got
another guy that just another teacher in
this game you know well that's cool like
i i've never heard anybody talk about
him and i've always wondered about al
seeds like who he was how he ran his
[ __ ] so that's pretty [ __ ] cool i
appreciate it this is a total mountain
man uh kitchenaisin you know like he's
just an old italian goat up in the
mountains smoking a chair if it was a
good time that's awesome
yeah
what else we got
the sbos
let's see bank what's that bravery
see back your original feedback
ah jesus i guess 20 years has passed
right we're allowed to talk about this
[ __ ] now yeah yeah please do
so we started legends and um
you know obviously we didn't you know we
were like a sixth speed company on the
internet the worldwide web
uh at the time and um so it was pretty
all new right and so all we could do is
go across the amsterdam buy a bunch of
seed come back and you know and sell it
there you know so resell it and then i
started getting to know the canadian
growers and one of my old partners knew
um ed uh rosenthal and uh he had gotten
uh basically his hands on neville's last
selections in cali before he went back
to the office before he got busted yeah
and so
uh we got our hand those were dubbed the
seed bank originals
and um so we got a chance to uh and
these were and we had our hands on they
were like 25 30 year old seeds you know
and yeah
perfectly let's just put it that way i
mean there was probably 35 40 germ rates
but what we were looking for was
building blocks to what all the cannabis
is we know today let's be frank you know
um this is this has to do with skunk man
it has to do with all those cats and we
all know who we're talking about like
the big fab four as it were yeah um the
guys that
are the only reasons the three of us are
talking to each other right now um yeah
really and
and the people oh it is it's
the founding father the mount rushmore
of cannabis
i agree
you know um
right like dudes
i still i think i know of every
interaction i've ever had with dave i
know that ryan would like to forget a
few
only because he's the most cantankerous
old man who's always right
and god love him for christ's sakes
because he usually is
to rob you know
to neville you know it's howard marks
even if you want to go to that clue that
i mean yeah it's been drunkers for
craig's sakes like anyway
so long story short as we got those
seeds uh through a partnership and we
were allowed to uh we got a chance to
actually sell them up on legends and uh
a lot of folks got a lot of building
blocks like calio was one of my best
hidden secrets on that one and the
ortega three both of those were my
favorite you had three artigas three
yeah we had the one two and three it was
a hash plant cross a cushcross and a
skunk crush awesome awesome um we had
the original ortega in switzerland and
that thing was just buttons of hash i
mean it was the purest hashtag
one of the closer land race hash plants
i'd ever seen to this day to be quite
frank and what i would know because it
wasn't bulked up but the resin was the
the most intense resin i'd ever had it
was so greasy we had those old damn
shakers
you know you put that drive button at
the top and it had this silly screen you
just yeah yeah
yeah
you know right like i don't know they
they were camouflaged they were so funny
yeah so we have one of those uh at the
facility in switzerland and that
everyone would always do it with the
ortega because it would just puke it up
like like there's huge fat heads under
the microscope and dark and greasy as
all hell like
super greasy
and now that i know what mir seen
smells and effects are the thing was
covered in it you know yeah been very
awfully mere scene it was peppery it was
like uh you know uh black uh black
licorice you know it was just woozy
right yeah and uh
those are the ones you always have the
hash backs with your 15 hash bags a day
that's crazy
yeah so so that's my experience with
those seats and they're again just
building blocks that's what i always
radically manage
that's awesome yeah i know a lot of
people have been wanting to hear that
story for a long time so thank you very
much
i know crybaby's in there looking stoked
as [ __ ] he finally got to hear the
ortega story
well the funny here's here's what i'll
go with you one deeper when we got to
switzerland we a friend of ours brought
over two clones from california one was
the grapefruit one was the ortega the
original ortega bomb yeah
and those and so that's what we brought
over to switzerland so that's and a
friend of ours brought those over for us
so that was pretty funny cuts in the
suitcase yeah that's awesome and they
made it
and they made it and
sold a lot of clones over in europe and
uh you know i'm sure we started a lot of
breeding lines
oh yeah
so what what was so special about calio
for you
the flavor uh it was the first time i
experienced any kind of um
what i know now to be limoney limonene
terpenoline um i didn't know it then
obviously i didn't have the knowledge
understanding of the vocabulary or the
coas in front of me yeah um but um that
i know now and so it was that i'm a
terpenoline junkie i mean if i could do
lines of it all day i would i swear i
could do i do that
i think it makes everything taste way
better
birds of a feather
some people hate it it's just one of
those things like if you love it you can
appreciate how much it adds to flavor
and the high yeah yeah
agreed you know it's funny because i
find the selling to this generation
they're all gas heads you know like
total gas heads bring me the gas [ __ ]
the tropicals [ __ ] the exotics give me
gas give me gas i just share it all day
and i just start feeling like an old man
sometimes
[Laughter]
and i know i know people are going to
kick me in my head if i don't ask both
of you what is the most
traditionally smelling like a skunk line
that you have been around
like traditionally smelling like uh like
uh like a skunk that's been run over a
mile away that kind of skunk what's the
most traditionally skunk lines you've
come across
and it was called bc skunk
back in the day that bc
like
yeah like early 90s and you know
i remember hearing about like as a
name-branded thing before i knew that
you knew that there was branded cannabis
or named cannabis varieties right
yeah um
but you know what happened i mean
everybody stopped growing it because it
was
you know during the the kicker during
period of time
yeah
you know you'd lose it
um where people would you know you could
have the cops showing up in your in your
house everybody stopped growing it
but um they've recently identified a
chemical uh like i i can't remember what
it is it's like one mbt i'd have to look
it up because it's got a name like this
but they've actually identified the
compound that's actually responsible for
that smell
so
you know
style ester
um i think it's an aldehyde
i'm i'm actually not an alphabet
again i'd have to look it up
listen that would make sense though just
from the putrid of it with putridness of
it do you know what i mean yeah well
yeah the very the fact you just need a
little bit that has a big effect but
the point is that you
once you once you know what blip
it is on the chromatograph
it's pretty easy to start picking up
plants that have higher amounts
in it right so
yeah um
um
but
anyway whatever i'm not a chemistry nerd
in the type of like yeah
[Laughter]
and then once you find it then you just
start breeding it it'll come up like
that's what we do
right we've done it with thc that's the
last dvd
sorry
that's the lab reading you were talking
about in the podcast
and and the the expense of it is quite
quite right to be doing it right
yeah yeah you have to do you have to
take it listen when once you've done it
you won't go back to the other way like
i guarantee it
or you'll you'll cry to have to go back
to the other way and you'll just you'll
do everything you can including selling
your children to like find a way to pay
for the test right
yeah
because it's it's like it's so
night and day difference between doing
it the old school way just on your nose
you know i've had a lot of people kind
of like be quite resistant to the whole
lab-led breeding thing
or the science-led breeding thing and
the truth is dude
it's it doesn't take anything away from
the way that we've always been doing it
it just gives you another set of data to
look at
and to refine your knowledge like
when i finally got access to the lab we
would grow hundreds of hundreds of
plants from across
and i would save a little nug for each
of them
and then when i had the labs in front of
me i'd go through them individual by
individual look at the lab report not
even looking at the butt just looking at
the lab report and holding the butt
underneath my nose and rolling yeah yeah
right and then and going through them
sequentially
to try to train my nose to like what is
okay so i know that there's a slight
difference in the cell and the smell can
i see that on the graphs yeah right
because we make graphs and everything so
that um
i find when you have lists of of
like terpene names and terpene values is
like a
you know like 1.3
7 whatever whatever expresses a
percentage it's kind of meaningless
right because you're kind of like always
scrolling through the list and trying to
add it up in your head
when you take those numbers and you make
a graphical representation of them
you know we did graphical
like essentially peak line
bar graphs so that you could see the
quantity
but we also made every terp its own
color
and in that way
like it was a pain in the ass at first
because you'd have to remember oh yeah
pinene is green osmine is orange
beta-carotene is blue
but
you know after a hundred lab
like a samples
you knew which was which
and so you didn't even have to like look
down a column and see how much beta
caryophyllene is there you would look at
the graph immediately and be like boom
they have carry beta caryophyllene is
the highest peak
right yeah and then what that did is it
was it kind of reduced the scent
picture
into a graphical representation that
your brain could recognize on a more
productive
notice you were being taught and you
didn't know you were being taught
exactly
exactly i don't know that's right
when when ryan got back from california
he and he showed this
he explained this all to me
i i felt like literally i was the
dumbest person in cannabis
um you know and mariah has such a
beautiful way of being able to describe
things to people and bring it down to
its lowest common denominator so you
have full understanding
uh and it's just it's amazing sorry ron
i had to bust that out because uh the
way you've explained it is really
perfect
yeah well it was you know we listen i
got lucky working with mark lewis and
matt geezy i mean they're both top
top-notch chemists
and so it was really like kind of
spoiling to not have to figure that
whole component out
right it was like these are the
chemicals that we want to be looking at
and they would go and do all the work
right and then come back with these lab
reports that were just [ __ ] like
super informative and like i said you
could glance at two graphs somebody
asked if it was a spider graph there was
a spider craft for flavor
but we essentially had a series of
graphs that did
you know you'd have you'd have a series
of graphs in a all on different rows but
one individual would be on a column
going through all the graphs
and so just by looking at these four
graphs you can get an idea of which
plant was had the most oh look steve had
was here
plant the haba
he's uh actually someone that's been
doing work with these same graphs
that i'm just talking about oh awesome
uh
hobbit for those of you that don't
follow him is he was kind of behind the
lemon crush that won the
emerald cup a few years ago i think
2017. oh wow
um
very very talented and educated plant
breeder in his own right
um
but yeah like when you have the tools to
be able to like essentially visualize
these things that we call smell
you know like here like for example when
we when you smell something you're not
smelling one thing you're smelling an
orchestra of compounds all together at
the same time
right and so it's kind of like listening
to a symphony or like a like a piece of
classical music
you don't necessarily hear
like the
oboe right yeah unless unless you really
train your ear and then you learn how to
like pick out the oboe in that overall
mix
right so
um
yeah
it's
it's something that we haven't done well
even amongst the cannabis breeding
community but i think that we need to
really do that there's a book in
if only a book that david watson showed
that has called lenee duvang and it's
it's it means the nose of wine and it's
a book that you open it up it's got like
i don't know 20 or 30 little vials that
have all the different scents that you
know
like smoke and leather and tobacco like
all the notes that they use to describe
yeah sorry
wine
and so i've always wanted to do one of
those like a really complete one
for cannabis right that would have all
the terpenes yeah you have a bunch of
you know a bunch of
um like all these other volatiles we're
talking about the aldehydes and the
esters and files whatever you can get
your hands on
and
you know put a little booklet with it so
that you can really put this out because
right now we have like i mean there's
some people that are kind of starting to
figure it out
just because like for example kip like
kip's in a job
where he has hundreds of growers
contacting him all the time looking to
sell our weed and he needs a way to be
able to separate segregate like what's
the good from the bad
and so the tool that we have now is a
lab report you know show me the coa and
it brings you the you know the
certificate analysis and of course it
tells you how much cannabinoids are in
it because that's important everybody on
the rec market wants to know that thc is
that
but more importantly
it becomes
about
um
about scent right and like you have to
have some kind of lab measure and so
when you're sorting through like
hundreds of samples of weed that people
are trying to
sell you
you can you're seeing all the lab
reports you get you can actually start
it's like oh look here's one that's
pining dominant all the mercy one
dominant ones go into another pile and
the three penalty and dominant ones go
into another pile
and you can see it's like it's kind of
just like taking a shuffled pack of
cards
like face up
and then sorting them into their suits
right like when you when you start
looking at them only based on the
chemistry you you realize that it's like
oh there's just a bunch of categories
right and then yeah everything falls
into one of those categories
do you have any idea how much mercy
better carry offline limiting i see in a
day what the hell do you think that is
like the guys
i see
but i don't even need to see the sample
i'm just like yeah okay i got it
[Laughter]
you have some form of kosher chicken
i've been digging into the rosin stash a
little bit lately and going through and
you know i'm finding plants that when we
separate out the rosin you can actually
i can tell they have the same terpene
profile but they have like different
profiles about all the hives or esters
and so it's like you really get this
idea where you can actually start to
like we can break cannabis apart
into you know cannabinoids terpenes
aldehydes esters if there's maybe a
thiol class then maybe that comes in
there as well
but it's really like in each of those
scent molecules or not the cannabinoids
because they're not scented but they're
important
is that it's really just us layering
all these different combinations of the
individual suits in every any chemical
class be it like thc or cbd in the
cannabinoid class or like yeah
terpenaline or mercenary whatever you
know
in the terpene class and it's like we're
just literally
we can only put it together so many ways
right but there's some of these
chemicals that like if you put it on or
you take it apart
or you take this one chemical out it
totally changes the scent
right that makes sense so that that like
beta-carotene nursing dominant class
that is ever present on the market it's
like oh gee
yeah cookies and everything in that
flavor class
that's like those aren't even the
chemicals that are responsible for that
gassy scent
right it's just right when they fall in
that background and you get that scent
modifier that's when you get like that
really funk to it right
again orchestra it's about the orchestra
the and then
yeah
i think that that's where it becomes you
know the crybaby was talking about
perfumes earlier
it's like that's what purple like being
a perfume yeah is really about it's like
you're learning how to put together
these different it's like you're being a
chef really right yeah really yeah and
it's a it's a it's a super kind of
deconstructive simplifying approach but
like
anybody that's really into this [ __ ]
like i really suggest trying to do that
like try to find a way where you can
get yourself a bunch of lab profiles and
the standards like having like i said
either having all these different buds
or even better this the like limonene
and terpenoline and teaching yourself
that palette um
is like you
you can't put into words how powerful it
is because again when we're like look
when we're talking about
i'll show you one of our canadian funky
50s but like when we're talking about
like color you know we can both look at
this and immediately understand what it
is
right like we have a reference point
where we can both point to this and say
look that is the [ __ ] color that
we're talking about you can't do that
with sent
yeah because like you
again because it's an orchestra of of
scent
you we can't point to any one part and
without each having a common language
agree that we're talking about the same
thing and that's why you're here using
these words like scenery or earthy or
floral or herbal yeah but really like
that's not [ __ ] helpful
right like no no it isn't you know so
and it's integrating one of those things
it's like you have to you have to teach
yourself that skill right
and for breeding with the labs the fact
that you can i mean the traditional
method i mean we all agree is kind of
like a shotgun mail method where you
pick a male based on something just
something and seeing how it breeds is
completely different but if you know its
actual terpene profile and everything
you can actually see how he's breeding
which is so much more important than
than just the shotgun method
like you said it's a whole other tool to
add to the toolkit
yeah and it's like you know i've also
like i've also learned
you know like
once i have that set of tools i don't
always have to rely on the lab
right because it's like you might walk
across and it's like i can recognize the
profiles just because i recognize what
the sentence i don't need to send that
sample to a lab unless i'm trying to
quantify
right that's the other thing it's like
you know the terping profile is kind of
like the quality like what the type you
know kind of like a really like a
mendelian type way
but really what you're also trying to do
is breed up the level
right and so that's where it's really
important to have the lab it's like
because it's kind of hard to do that
without like
you know if i handed you a three percent
a four percent terpene but
like almost everybody in this chat room
including the people in the lab i think
would have a hard time doing that
yeah
heinrich you can john miss on that
it's just one of those things that's
kind of hard to measure
unless you have it yes you have a gc
you know so
yeah
yeah chem one is one of those ones that
test high like four to five percent
mercy
it's crazy it's so much different than
the other chem dogs the chem one it's
more nl5 haze based i think
but it carries really high terpene
content with the mercy
yeah i've got all the fingerprints from
those i collected all that stuff off of
off of spy rock um
so i'm not oh yeah
that's where you can you tell us some
spy rock stories
can we have some spyro stories want to
protect the enemies you don't have to
you know
you got to see some cool stuff out there
right
yeah well yeah i mean i went there first
time in 2011 and it was like
you know i it's hard to imagine the
context of what it was like back then
but it was a totally different world of
course and i remember being so blown
away
um we were up there and at the time
every property on spy rock there's like
4 000 properties on there and like at
the time every property
and i don't think i'm being like
too hyperbolic and saying every property
had like 99 trees on it
yeah yeah i bet so people were pulling
down like you know 500 pounds on a
property there was a lot of weed coming
out of there
and yeah
i don't know how much time you spent up
there but they've got this incredible
radio station called
kmud
yeah which is like it's oh you gotta
check it out dude it's [ __ ] really
cool it's essentially red i think they
call it redwood radio so it's like
laytonville and
you know all the way up the the corridor
kind of yeah arcata it's the alarm
button
it is it is i know
i was blown away like because you know
like
we're you know i was a foreigner also
keep in mind so it was like i was aware
that this was federally illegal
and this but this is like one this one
mountain
is essentially pumping out like jesus
dude it must have been in the tonnage of
flower
um and and everybody was sitting around
during harvest listening to kmud
radio which is this was essentially
gorilla it was like grower radio it was
community radio it was it was community
radio so it was paid for by the growers
so they were doing their
um
they were doing their fundraiser you
know like npr always does the
fundraisers they were doing their
fundraiser for the year
during harvest because everybody's
sitting around with their eyes in the
chair scissors in his hand
and you know you they they'd be playing
all these weed songs reggae or whatever
kind of themed songs
you know the dj would come on and be
like
there's a grower up on spy rock that is
going to match any donation so if you're
a new guy to the mountain it's your
first year and you're trimming and you
want to donate some money to you know km
radio
you know this grower jay over on
wherever is gonna match the first five
people's 100 bucks or whatever right
and it was so it was really cool because
it was like that's rad it was like the
pirate radio signal being broadcast out
but the really [ __ ] cool thing was
that it was like you know the news
breaking news was like
you know they got someone pulled over
over down on whatever road or the
helicopters are flying in this valley
today
you know like it was they were they were
they were the eyes in the sky that's
legitimate
it was [ __ ] cool man it was it was
like and when i realized that i was like
duke mendo is [ __ ]
on a whole nother level of organization
and culture and that's the thing that
like
can't get lost in the in the transition
is that like
these people cut out a [ __ ] way of
life up there
yeah you know like
the growers all banded together and
built a school on the mountain because
they didn't want their kids going down
to the valley and like saying oh yeah my
daddy grows trees for a living or
whatever exactly i think that's so funky
dude your children well isn't that the
same
exactly right
and they just you know awesome i mean
every year you know they would like all
the growers would save some of their
trunks or their branches and they'd be
given to the school and the school would
learn how to make paper from it
oh wow
you know that's wild well it's just like
just like they do in gilroy with the
with garlic town right like
yeah yeah it's like you know the whole
culture is around garlic but
it you know it makes it's it's totally
normal and that was the thing that that
was so impressive to me that it was like
[ __ ] this is so normalized
and
even an illegal market
or an illegal district or whatever the
federal you know the district of the
state it's going to be
face it all that weeds going back to
back east
right like sure some of it gets sold in
dispensaries but most of it can't now
yeah right so money's not there it's all
interstate or black market [ __ ]
and still it's a [ __ ] huge culture
right like it's it's persistent
right you don't get that kind of that
doesn't develop in a year like those are
like systems that develop over decades
right so i don't know to me mendo and
humboldt the trinity like that whole
zone
is pretty special
yeah you know
um
so yeah i got a lot of i got a lot of
love for those folks on on spy rock
because they're just so [ __ ] balls
out
yeah
i think gene gene gene is a a spy rock
boy if i remember
yeah yeah it's beautiful up there man
it's really beautiful
remember the top there's this like rock
outcropping where there's like there's
these weird patterns that are cut into
the rock and they think it's like
it was like a native map that they had
put up on the top of this mountain so
like you could like
you know you could stand overlooking
this valley and you could essentially
see the different watersheds in which
tribes were living in which watershed
right
that's awesome
isn't that why it was called spy rock
like for the kid to the kids lookout
area spy rock
looking out for the cops
at the top of the mountain there's a big
like it looks kind of like a mohawk
stepping up out of the top of the
mountain
so i think that that was the spy rock
you know
but i don't know where the origin was
but yeah it's like people have been
living there for thousands of years
yeah it's like we think it like in
european terms and pot cars but it's
like there is people that were living up
there for
you know eons
yeah it's cool man
so
yeah is there anything you could speak
on in the tom hill range or that you
want to talk about there or any of the
work you saw
yeah
tom's a funny guy like
he's
he's pretty brazen on the forums but
he's i don't really find him like that
yeah in in real life until he gets like
you know a few beers in him and then
he's like right up in your face
yeah he's a strongly opinionated
opinionated person
um
first time i met him he [ __ ] lit me
up about writing something about single
seed descent in that jorge book like
years and years and years ago and i was
like yeah i don't think that that's what
i wrote but
he's like
he really gets into the minutia on the
breeding stuff but he doesn't have a lot
of space to be doing that
you know he's someone that i would love
to see
get a field
right oh yeah and put a leash on him so
that he couldn't or one of those shot
callers so that he couldn't leave the
property
and get in trouble yeah
as long as he's got his little puppy
totally dead
focused on the [ __ ] grow you know
shiny objects
he could be doing some interesting stuff
i feel like he's like wasting his
talents up there but
yeah i got nothing but love for him he's
a good guy
now how about some of your um
uh watson stories as far as breeding
goes
is there anything you can talk about
with that
there's so many i mean
listen the truth you know how it is with
david he's such a private individual
yeah yeah for sure that
like
i really want him to tell those stories
because that's how i learned them right
to a degree too begging to have him tell
him
oh i know i know and he it's like it's
going to be a thing it's going to be a
challenge to get it done but it's
important because like i don't you know
if if it did come that dave were to pass
then i would start sharing some of these
stories yeah you know
because there's knowledge there
so much
that he that just things that he taught
me about like
collecting pollen or like yeah you know
he did like these epic epic people like
i'll tell you some interesting stories
one day but like
dave found a way
years and years and years ago
to work within the system
with the within the existing
hemp world but get work done like get
work on drug cannabis
whether it was like producing tons of
seed or like you know like he really
figured out
ways to operate in both sides
legally yeah is like he was compliant
right yes he was following the terms of
his license or whatever it was doing and
and
and so you know like everybody you know
everybody kind of knows about dave's
seed collection well there's there's
also a pollen collection
right there's a pollen collection that's
bigger than most people's seed
collection like it's [ __ ] huge
and
you know i just when you start thinking
about
like for example dude every time you
throw a pollen are you collecting pollen
no why not
i i've always had a hard time storing it
and then when i go back to use it it's
just not viable and i waste a whole
round on it
yeah so he's like he's figured that all
out so yeah
he's got like jars of poem like you can
walk into a room crack a jar out of the
freezer and toss it in front of a fan
and then you know we're talking like 15
20 year old pollen and that's getting
full full seat set so
you know that's one of the things i'm
going to be doing as i as i move forward
on the next round of really really
serious breeding is setting up
like
pollen collections so that every time
you're dropping pollen you you have
satchels of that pollen
right little coke bundles or whatever
that you can go back to because it's
just
it's such a little amount of work to do
that
versus
having to go through the process of
initiate a plant and get more pollen
from that genotype again
right it's like you may as well do it
so i was saying that on one of our
little
future cannabis podcasts the other day
but it's like you know i'm all about
like
you know and
um
dude from rebel groan
i'm forgetting his real name right now
yeah okay jay but rebel groan i think
his name is jay but he's like you know
he was talking about like for example
when you're
you know you got you got a parent
or say you're making an s one right so
you've made a cross and then you do a
selection and
you see you you've now you've got your
your f1 c that you're growing through
the cross that you made if you find a
plant that you're you want to sell
in that generation like you may as well
self that plant but also pollinate it to
both of the parental
generation
at the same time because you got the
pollen flying anyway right all you're
doing is sticking a clone in there to
collect even if you get 100 seeds or a
couple hundred seeds i mean that's
enough for like a breeding project it's
not a commercial at least but it's like
you know you've got that in the bank or
in the vault
yeah
um
yeah so just little things like that you
know what i mean i'm going to try to try
to be useful
well that's like listen all that most of
this stuff came from dave
right not necessarily the selfing things
but like
just opening my eyes up to like
different ways of doing it not getting
kind of stuck in the same thought
process that we all get
stuck in through passing in for around
on forums or instagram you know exactly
yeah we get stuck in a rut so that's why
it's so cool when you get all these new
people coming on you know
into the community from outside
you know like the sin change sink cinch
angel guy i don't know you seen him max
yeah yeah
he's posting some really great
information online right yeah and it's
like that's the real beauty of
legalization is that
we now are not like dirty untouchables
yeah we get to associate with all the
rest of the people in society right yes
and and learn and benefit from them
right so i don't know i'm ranting
no no but that's
that pollen text that's something that's
getting yet
so many crops
trying to use stored pollen and i mean i
go through the method of using a pollen
screen you know to make sure all the
male parts are out let it dry
put it inside of a airtight container
that's dark you know in the fridge or
freezer and it just [ __ ] never works
yeah well if
drying it properly is a big big thing
drying it properly is a big thing and
then making sure that it's frozen and
stays frozen like he's got a dedicated
freezer right
that makes sense listen some of these
things like they become like possible
when you have
scale like you can't really do some of
this [ __ ] on on like bedroom scale you
can play around yeah for sure but it's
like it's really hard to really do it
you know
but that's like the reason for sharing
that is that i want you to take it like
i want everybody to take that stuff and
you know those are the those are the
things that dave has taught me
that i would love for him to share with
the rest of the community it's just
you know i think part of the reason is
that
we have all these people that have just
trashed him online for years and years
because you know partly because they
were jealous i mean like you know kim
was talking about aryan before but like
one of the reasons people don't like
harley and it's because he's successful
and he's [ __ ] really good at what he
does and he makes a lot of money yeah
people are jealous
right people are jealous like that's the
truth
um and the same thing happened with dave
he got the licenses to work in holland
when when the dutch dudes that lived
couldn't figure out how to get the
licenses yeah and he figured out which
you know which path to take to get the
trophy
you know and they hated him for it and
and so that's where all the stories
started coming from was it but it was
based in chelsea and i tell you dude
like after noah and david and learning
for from him
for so long
he's the real [ __ ] deal you know
and anybody that says
otherwise they just don't know it's like
when people i see people start barking
[ __ ] about like
watson being a [ __ ] d agent or
whatever it is it's like i'm just like
oh well this guy just doesn't know right
he's like he's self identity he's
identifying himself as someone that
doesn't get it because
like dave's a real deal like and he's
done yeah that should that's been fast
that stuff's been passed around for so
long i was involved in it i mean i
thought he was a dea agent because of
what neville told me directly you know
and i think it and it takes a long time
for stuff like that to die out but with
him not interacting much and not i mean
he shouldn't have to defend himself if
it's not true right but with him not
there's not a lot of input from it so
people just run with it and it's it's it
becomes lower yeah and you know how
these things are it's like
you know you have a negative something
happens in your life and it's like you
got to deal with it like some other
people talking about it all the time and
you deal with it and it goes away but
it's like some of those things it's like
they just never go away like people just
keep bringing it up no matter what yeah
and like
when when truthfully like i will say
this like believing in 100
there is nobody live on the [ __ ]
planet that has done more for cannabis
than david watson like that is the
[ __ ] i would agree
i would agree
without a doubt um
including like you know founding and
funding the international hemp
association right like he created a hub
in that process and brought
all the individual researchers in the
world
gave them all a central hub place to
call home
and that created a sense of community
for the cannabis
like the whole industry like the global
cannabis industry
at a time when
the dea were [ __ ] knocking countries
off left right and center
right
so
you know i i would love to have david
answer all these questions and just ha
just sit there and be like i wouldn't
even want to be i just want to draw the
information out of them right because i
know a lot of the stories now so it's
like i know what questions to ask to get
him to talk but he's done some like just
absolutely incredible things with
cannabis
and if he doesn't share those stories
um
while he's around there has to be a
movie made
to document it for history because it's
like
the level of epicness is like
right
like just what i know for a fact is it
would be a crazy [ __ ] movie all of it
yeah yeah he's managing those shadows
one dinner's worth of conversation could
easily do a movie right like dinner with
andre but dinner with dave easy peasy
you can get lost down so many roads of
his
incredible intellect and adventure
yeah
and balls to do what he did like
just because he didn't like just because
he didn't give a [ __ ] you know i mean he
like he firmly believed that it was the
right like he told me a story about
being in morocco and getting like
sickness and you know and rocker then
off toilets it's just like a hole on the
floor kind of thing right yeah and so
he's like having some virus or some
bacteria just like go through his system
and decimate him and he started smoking
hash on the while he was over the hole
so to speak
and it immediately realized that
cannabis had medicinal value it was like
it can work for him
right and this is back before
anybody
had
really considered like that cannabis was
medicinal like we're talking about 60s
here
yeah um
and just made it his life's work to like
take that as far as he could and you
know you know the horn farm stories and
the gw and all the stuff that people
have said if you can just distill that
down to like the few
truths that exist in there dave had the
[ __ ] first medical marijuana company
in the world
yeah he did right like there was no one
else doing it back then and i think
that's where a lot of the suspicion came
from
you know that he was just he pulled it
off how do you do it yeah
and jealousy right too like
exactly that he figured out whatever
nobody else could
and you know
he you know yeah i don't know i got
nothing but good things to say about
david i mean in many ways he's kind of a
father figure to me
um
you know kipp and and these dudes had
met him well before i had marcus
richardson they knew him before and dave
and i used to just speak online but when
when i met him
he was really rude to me like the first
time i met him
like you said hey i heard that one
that's generally how david meets people
by the way
[Laughter]
i'm sure he has a punch for me but
that's okay
i'd take a punch to meet him
well i i had the key to the secret club
um of dave of david's and it's
essentially like if you have
the five star the six star hash or like
an incredible
you know little jar of rosin or
something like that like something
that's truly fire
and
dave will sit down and chat with you you
know what i mean like he's so passionate
about it
that it's like if you have if you have
the goods then he has to give you
respect because
you don't just end up with a jar like
this you know what i feel like yeah of a
truly top top top top top shelf stuff
right like you have to be an artist or
have at least have an appreciation for
making and finding the best
and if you have that then you're dave's
kindred soulmate right because that's
his only goal in life
i have a little tag on to that when i
first met dave he was walking through
our facility over in europe and uh a
very intimidating figure he's a big guy
big taxes yeah
and
so
you know as you go through the facility
he just kept taking his wooden matches
and laying them and hitting this bubble
that he had on this tiny little pipe and
then they dropped the match
you literally
like a trunk your trail can follow where
dave had been through all the best
methods on the channel throughout the
facility like through doors around
corners come back around
it was like some kind of you know
denny's treasure map for kids
so is he a big hashtag as opposed to a
flower smoker is he more into hash or
i've never seen him smoke flowers never
wild that's pretty cool that's a good
little insight into his brain
yeah he's a pure resin farmer
he is this thing that he says i'll tell
you one story
he tells me that he's i've heard him say
a few times when he was in afghanistan
we're talking like late 60s he and his
wife
were sitting around with a bunch of the
old men the baba's in the village and
they were smoking uh
bubbly bubbly's of the the finest hash
they had and david was over there
collecting seeds right like he was
trying to find stuff to bring back and
so he asked this old afghan stand dude
for
um
some cannabis so that he could get nuts
he didn't say so i can get the seeds but
he's like yeah yeah do you have the
flowers and he said
like like every everybody stopped
talking and it was just like dead
silence and one of the man said he said
the man looked at him like he was a
piece of [ __ ]
and he and he said
hashish is for men
cannabis flower is for women and slaves
oh [ __ ]
we're talking like this is old school
you know yeah yeah old school like
afghan culture
yeah
but dave explained to him you know i
want i want the flower so i can get the
seeds and take it back to california and
grow plants to make my own hash and that
was like that was that was acceptable
that's funny
so dave was
i would love to know if you if you know
when was the first time he was
encountering
afghanis was he one of the first people
importing the seeds of afghanis to the
u.s
in the late 60s
i'm not sure i mean he did
he's always kind of gone through
afghanis i mean even when they were in
um
at horror farm like he was always
screening [ __ ] loads of any seats
because people are always coming back
from there with different lots
but he said generally it was [ __ ] like
it was not what you wanted
you gotta remember they got pretty spot
or spoiled early on with like you know
neighbors with the haze brothers right
so he had like
i think it's hard for people of our age
to understand that there was a time
that was pre
like afghanistan
right exactly yeah most people our age
don't know that it came in the you know
exactly late 70s
it gains popularity and and so when it
did come i mean rob i think it was rob
wrote um an article on it
for high times but it was that you know
they high times had like a ban the bud
issue
it was like we need to ban indica
because it's like [ __ ] up our [ __ ]
right there's like a movement in the
community that was like that's why i
stopped cross indica and everything
because it's ruining our nice highs from
the colombians and the mexicans
yeah like now with cookies i mean people
want to ban cookies from from genetics
because everything's cookies everything
yeah
yeah yeah yeah i'll be the first person
to sign up to that petition
yeah i'm part of the problem though
because i use it too so what the [ __ ] do
i know
you know it's opium for the masses right
yeah
well this this is super gas too so i'm
like you know
i'm also
guilty but i i really do
try to push the the different terpene
profiles because there's just some stuff
i mean yeah we came across this one
thing that was like a piney like it had
almost no other terps but it was like a
lot of pioneer and a lot of limonene and
dude this [ __ ] was
zippy zippy zippy it was like
smear and focused and just high energy
um you're not talking about you're not
talking about last summer
no no no when i first came up the pr i
had a bag of it
um i don't know if you tried anything
where i was calling it the lyman pine
um
yes okay yeah okay but again it's in
that it's just in that very like
equatorial family side of things didn't
yield were [ __ ] you know what i mean
like it was a terrible plant to grow
but it was it had a lovely effect and
the rosin from it was like
you know
took some down to marcus and we pressed
up or a couple ounces of it it was fire
as [ __ ]
but um you know you'd want to be growing
that stuff in large cheap greenhouses
outside oh i'm sure because indoors it
just didn't make sense for the real
estate you know
yeah
those things are big and burly and not a
lot of yield on some of them
yeah and somebody was asking about the
guerrero line on the oh yeah let's talk
about that blueberry that was one of
those plants so i've been playing with
those seeds for a little bit somebody
sent us a bunch of
old stuff um legends used to actually
would people would be like oh i have
these seeds i want you to get in your
hands i just say send them legends
because they're like
and anyway we found these these this old
mexican screen through a bunch of them
and
they were gangly and like just unruly as
hell
and when we were making the seeds for
the blueberry stuff i just thought i was
like let's get one of those in there
yeah and you know i think one plant must
have yielded like it was you know it
grew huge
and it was probably in the like five to
ten thousand seeds
from that one plant um
but the the way that they came together
with the blueberry i mean you know the
blueberry kind of has that phenotype
there's the two phenotypes there's like
the kind of more compact round
classic mud but it also does like those
kind of knuckley buds or yeah like kind
of like little fox tails yeah yeah when
that got into the mexican
that made some crazy expressions
right like the just the flowers that
were like long sets and bracks are like
yellow on fox tape i remember what the
i remember what the cross looked like in
pictures yeah real remind me of
the picture of lamb's bread and jason
king's can of bible
real long
super long knuckles
so that's you know that's still a fun
one i i really want to dig into that
line but it kind of like
i'm kind of hoping that someone on like
in the caribbean says hey come and plant
like you know
five acres down here for selections
because that's where you'd want to do it
it's just it's too it's too hard to do
indoors right and in canada unless you
are tarpon that stuff
you're not going to get that ever to
flat like to finish flowering so yeah
um
yeah these are the fun things that
happen with like legalization happening
all over the world is we can legally
move
germplasm to these new districts and set
up a [ __ ] screening station right
yeah
yeah i have a bunch of stuff that i
would love to run but and that people
have asked me if i'm going to work but
the realistic part of it is i'm never
going to see the ultimate expression of
it unless it's run in a proper place to
even see what you can select
well i'm really hoping that this latest
project that i'm working on is going to
afford you know it's
we're going to get some space to to do
some cool stuff some cool work
and like i was saying to keep earning
tonight like i don't want to make it
about the ryan show
you know if we've got a chance to like
really explore
dude all of my friends that have
interesting seeds you know are going to
be welcome to come and
you know be part of that however that
looks like
is it going to be
canada it's international but there's
gonna be a location in canada yeah
very excellent yeah so the idea is to
kind of have nursery services to to the
new districts that are opening up all
over the world
right that's awesome and so the idea is
to find a like a royalty model that is
that works for breeders
so that they want to be part of it and
they can opt into whatever degree of
participation they want to or not
um and then we'll essentially offer
nursery services so that
it'll help people get into these markets
globally
right because it was one of the things
that was really [ __ ] up about it
it's been it's been a real problem as
the industry grows is that there was no
central place that had a bunch of
different good varieties that you could
work with you know i mean
there's hundreds of excellent cultivars
like across the globe
right but essentially like people are
like trying to start these like
multi-billion dollar companies with like
three seeds they bought off the internet
from cap
you know what i mean it's crazy crazy in
a way yeah one of these massive massive
big like pub clubs where we're talking
like the top three players
when they started their bank their bank
they did the same thing that all the
beginners do is they went and got like
100 different types of
named varieties but they got a three
pack of each yeah right and it's like
dude you'd be better off getting three
packs and a hundred of each
yeah right
right because then you can actually do a
real selection but yeah again it's like
that total lack of understanding of
cannabis
to the point of like you think that you
can grow three things with a name on it
and they're all going to come up looking
the same like that's [ __ ] delusional
yeah that's highly delusional
but at the same time it's like everyone
runs to one side of the boat then
everyone runs the other side of the boat
then they go to the back side and they
go to the front side i mean it's it's
cookies it's wedding cake it's gelato
it's mac one it's i mean it just you
just keep
you know
the problem is keeping it in vogue i
mean you've got to make an iconic
cultivar
to get maybe two year run out of it at
this at the world the market is right
now otherwise you're 10 months you're
out yeah and then that's just the
reality of unfortunately what it is so
how so how does that play with what you
know ryan's talking about and genetics
and and how do because nurse would spend
all this time the breeders spend all
this time perfecting these beautiful
cultivars for specific morphological uh
grows in specific paradigms of growing
and they have all this work on them they
can literally tell they defeated every
bloody day like it's a plug-and-play
like
yeah
then all for it to be out of favor in 10
months
yeah me and um csi were talking about
this the other day and
uh we're both believers in testing like
running your own [ __ ] so you know what
your own [ __ ] is so you can see it in
front of your face so you know how that
mail breeds etc
but at the rate the market's going it's
it's almost getting to the point where
testing will
flush yourself out of the market
as hot as that sounds
like
what i've found effective
in the industry in the short and short
snapshot we've seen is guys who will you
know sorry companies that roll
four of ours
roll them just roll them and so like you
could get like three or four you might
pull a year off a single bar but you're
rolling four so it buys you extra time
and it keeps you relevant and it keeps
you fresh and it keeps people's interest
in you because
like flying like they just like they
forget like they're like nuts consumers
man what's new what's hot what's new
what's hot what's new what's hot brand
loyalty there's no brand loyalty there's
no cultivar loyalty there's no profile
loyalty there's no loyalty yeah yeah
that's not what it's really
the funniest thing is saying that i mean
i i agree what you're saying to a degree
but like
in the states we've seen this thing
where there actually is brand loyalty or
not there is cultivar loyalty
because they can market it they can make
it a culture we can't do that up here
interesting that's the problem
yeah well we're just both insane labeled
[ __ ] dopes all selling the same 12
different versions of cookie and kush
you know like yay
well that's that's kind of what i'm
trying to get to that to like you know
the comment earlier about but i'll be in
booth
to a degree it's true because all these
companies that came out hot and hard at
the beginning with all the money they
were all public companies and they were
all talk and flash and million square
foot greenhouses and blah blah blah blah
blah but we've seen over the last three
years they're all [ __ ] suffering i
mean canopy is just
they're bleeding billions of dollars and
their weed sucks
and you know
like i said like what it should have
been from the start is just
transitioning all the illegal growers
over
and letting them keep running their
business rather than trying to displace
them right but no one would have made
any money brian
they would never be legalized that way
the only money that's in it is because
the money they made is off of stock
place like they haven't actually made
any money selling weed
which is crazy when you think about how
many families
and mortgages were suppo were supported
and paid for
across the united states and north
america and canada as well like i mean
that money went around not only to the
growers but to their communities right
like banks
it's not like people were getting rich
off of cannabis maybe people were paying
the bills
um
yeah but anyway i see that the i you
know i think we're going to be going
through some growing pains here
that you guys definitely are not going
to experience down in the states because
you don't have that federal
like not only do they federalize the the
production laws and everything
but the distribution is all provincial
like it's all run by state like boards
that's right yeah right and and like kip
was saying
the way that you have to sell to those
boards like for example
you know if you go to a wine store in
california
it's like you can get pinots from 100
different producers
try finding like
like a platinum cookies from or what's
give me a popular one camp or a mac 10.
wedding cake
right it's like the ldbs the liquor
distribution boards they're like no we
already have a wedding cake we're not
going to buy that
yeah
right because what happens is people
have to rename it
right yeah i think that that's part of
what's changing what's creating this
like
like kip was saying it's this this
unattainable or you were saying as well
with caleb i mean it's this unattainable
drive for the new new
that it's like we're going so fast it's
like you don't even have time to
appreciate what you made it's like yeah
he's making a new nft and selling it
again
yeah exactly and that's not
the way cannabis is topical very topical
right right
so yeah it's it's backwards it's it it's
very regressive for breeding period yeah
well that's not it's not doable it's
like it's yeah it's literally like yeah
you know
unfortunately the platform right now
it's the instagram immediacy of needing
something new right and that's how the
lead the most recent generation has kind
of learned about cannabis
so i i you know we got a lot of work to
do to redistribute
um the knowledge and get all these old
varieties back in
um not only to the hands of the
consumers but also teach these like
liquor distribution boards so it's like
you know you
you can't come in this
listen they you know what it's like
you're running a just you're doing
distribution you want to deal with five
suppliers and sell to a thousand
customers you don't deal with like 500
customers i mean it's a lot more work
right but we're seeing more and more and
we said it since the beginning
big popco cannabis like public market
company cannabis that ain't the [ __ ]
future
right because it becomes like this like
this dangling carrot where it's like
they're it's more they're more
interested in the stock price than the
wheat
yeah
um and the customer doesn't give a [ __ ]
about the stock price the customer gives
a [ __ ] about the lead
so if you're not giving the customer
what they want what they want
why would anybody buy from you and we're
seeing like that play out year after
year now
where we can track their sales in the
legal market and you see it's just like
it's going down like nobody's buying the
drinks nobody's buying the gummies
but the reason they're doing this and
it's very clear and very simple is that
they're revenue driven they're not
profit driven right it's because and
that's what it needs to be like people
need to understand that's why they sell
for losses that's why they sell and
undercut everybody else that's trying to
make a decent living in a decent wage
you know a family business
because they don't give a [ __ ] they can
run losses for
exactly
so ray look at canopy look at aurora
like they all ran long
their competitors out of money and then
they operate and take over the market
drive everything up and jack the price
is up yeah and you know i would listen
that was that would work that would work
in a whole bunch of other crops where
the consumer wasn't intimate with
quality
the the consumer demands quality in
cannabis i mean you're not going to
smoke [ __ ] schweins
right you're not
um and i'm not going to do this on the
market
because this is what i'm used to yeah
but
but ryan honestly though i mean like 65
of all cannabis buyers buy dry cannabis
here in canada okay
and what what portion are they buying it
in they're buying it in the cheapest
possible way for the highest possible
thc with no differentiation they don't
want to spend over 25 bucks a day
generally and they just they just want
their cheap dope and they want to get in
get out of the store
i mean this is one
these are what the magic they're telling
us like monthly when we get all these
numbers going to come in
and it's just so disheartening but again
it's because
we can't um market our our products
properly we can't talk to the
fundraisers the biggest chasm in the
world in the industry is producers and
bug tenders i mean that's just horrific
you know the lack of education
you know like they're not telling
stories especially making 16 bucks an
hour they're not there to tell stories
no they just want to like punch their
clock and get the [ __ ] out
so
it's on us as an industry to have to be
able to tell these stories and that was
it you know like guerrilla warfare ways
like back in the day like i don't know
what to say at the point of the game
it's
it's it's crazy like
i gotta tell you like you know there's
tons of companies that are pressing and
pushing the boundaries of what's
allowable you know marketing and
labeling and
and
a voice here in canada
they're so understaffed to be quite
frank like they're not they're not
really doing anything i mean you know
look at the lp that was growing illegal
to open illegal rooms and they still
have a license and they got busted cold
so i mean
you can bust me for for putting my font
two sizes too big on a label like give
me a break yeah
anyways uh
know i just think that i think you're
right i think
we have to and i've been saying this for
a while we have to
figure out a way to make people want to
educate themselves yeah and that's so
[ __ ] hard to do when it comes to weed
so hard because and we're like people
just want to smoke that's it and with
pretty as a culture we're preachy we
always want everyone to be as happy as
we are with what we found in life to be
spread
and some people just
don't have that relationship and we
can't push that but yet they're still a
consumer they're just not ahead
right
so and we have to there's also that and
that's a large part of the growing
consumer base they don't have the
attachment we all did with the
legalization
the hidden shame the you know the
meeting in the parking lots all that
crap yeah you know what it is for great
sakes you know
they don't know what a dealer is yeah
and so this is not the generation that
our generation understands and it's a
new consumer and new consumers want
different flavors and they want they
want the cannabis delivered to them
differently they want it in different
skews and they want to be able to go
online
and order it up and they don't want any
personal interaction
yeah so you've got to be able to tell a
story digitally and and and and find a
campaign that touches these kinds of
consumers that aren't us because all we
do is zelda
and you know that yeah that's for sure
you know so again open minds and i mean
i turned 50 this year and man like
my mind is
i know less and less each day in this
industry like if there's just so much
populating this industry all day that
it's so tough to keep a handle on a lot
of it to be quite frank
but if she it keeps you interested
there's no doubt about that
yeah that's for sure yeah i'm learning
the seed industry every
i always think i have it figured out and
then something comes along to make me
realize how much i don't have it figured
out and i watch a lot of these young
bucks figure it out just instantly
around me they they're making it happen
you know
they have an app for it they have a
program for it man
they're more dialed into what's going on
right and and how it operates and i just
turned 40 like yesterday so i you know
i'm starting to feel a little of myself
in all this
nice money
well yeah we got
over an hour and a half in and um god i
i could keep going and going and going
and going and bothering you all night
but uh if you guys ever want to come
back and do this anytime i know
everybody watching enjoyed it i've been
watching the comments and
it's it's been very fruitful and i
really appreciate you guys coming back
to do this for the reunion and um i i'm
really stoked with the podcast so if
you're anybody watching right now hasn't
watched it feel free to go to breed your
syndicate and uh we have chimera and red
right here with us and that was who is
in season two episode one um this this
episode will be available via our
patreon after this so yeah join the
patreon for reader syndicate and uh
hopefully we can have these fine
gentlemen back again and and i i really
appreciate both your time you guys are
both amazing it's awesome
yeah thanks so much man this was a lot
of fun this is uh yeah it's been a lot
of fun thanks again brother yeah yeah we
got a lot to learn from each other and
very very cool to see everybody in the
chat too all these old names haven't
seen it yeah it's cool huh yeah man it's
very cool
all right well thank you fellas for
coming along right on peacefully
cheers man
sorry guys