oh [ __ ] I forgot my intro music [ __ ]
totally forgot it right now [ __ ]
around see what happens when you dick
around you don't get intro music that's
gonna use blowfly today to rap dirty I
just I'll just sing it myself then
what's up everyone how's it going
got a new I don't know if it's gonna be
clearer or better sound or anything but
I got a I knew yeah you like this you
like this [ __ ] I got a new phone in
today so hopefully this will it be even
better than it has been but we'll see
we'll see
umm just been non-stop craziness till
Friday
the landlord [ __ ] always some [ __ ] today
from some forbidden fruit actually
forbidden fruit it's a light light but I
like light stuff so it doesn't bother me
I had a lot to do so I need a light so
what's the what's the topic today guys
what's the topic gonna be damn this is
so this phone is so much bigger and
clearer and everything in between
is it clear today for you guys my chance
is the audio any better any anything any
different anybody notice sunlight supply
sold out of what yeah so the camera
helps boom iPhone 8 plus I could see
every single pore on my [ __ ] head
nice nice I didn't do an announcement
today about coming on at this time but
I'm really gonna try to make it a I'm
gonna try to make it 6 p.m. normally I'm
ps2 you know if I don't show up at 6
then maybe I'll make an announcement if
it's later but usually 6 you want to try
it at 6
all right big pimple on my cheek [ __ ]
you can see all my hairs out of place
see how fat my head really is yeah I hit
the lotto what's up big t8 plus by the
way not just eight eight plus now is
just like my texting sucks on the
smaller iPhones and this is uh this is
way better way better easier to do so I
got some new information I thought was
kind of funny and I you know I I don't I
don't watch a lot of reality TV or
anything like vh1 [ __ ] I haven't for
many like a long long time but I got my
friend Brian Ellis
what's up Mosca my friend Brian Ellis
hit me up he's the guy that I did the
LSD with LSD not LSD LSD the line he was
the guy who that was a part of a collab
he got to pick everything out what he
wanted to cross etc the amazing musician
someone I respect so uh yeah so we did
that together he hit me up yesterday
he's like hey man
my buddy chants from I guess he's the
the stallion airs the the rap group the
stallion airs um and I guess he was on
that show real and chance on vh1 which I
mean that was news to me I'm not I'm not
hip to that stuff but yeah so he wants
his own strain now apparently weed maps
this is this you know what a matter of
fact let's talk about this here's a good
topic me fix my hair first dope sets get
on my nerves so apparently weed Maps has
been hitting up people telling them like
who was it
no I don't I don't show my room at any
feeds I I don't like Dylan and making
myself any more of a target than I
already a.m. but weed Maps has been
hitting up people all over different
different companies and telling them
that they want to go ahead and and make
them a strain and I have a feeling
they're gonna do what Snoop Dogg did you
know try get get some outdoor boof and
pass it off you know just like real able
it as why would I why would I be a
target it's a good question
yeah chance is really nice I talked to
him he was a super nice guy super super
nice guy but yeah I guess weed Maps is
trying to get these dudes to [ __ ]
sign up for for releasing a strain with
them and just gonna slap their [ __ ]
label on some boof and sell it and move
it they're not even making strains
they're just gonna pass strains off man
and and that's a bummer one of them you
know was [ __ ] skateboards and I really
I would love to work with [ __ ]
skateboards man I mean I used to wear
[ __ ] shirts to school when I was a
little kid junior high man I used to
tell my teachers that it meant Fouchet
like I was like no it doesn't say [ __ ]
me that's Fouchet it's a French company
but yeah I thought that I thought that
would be cool but he was like yeah man
weed Maps has been coming after me hard
to do a collab I was like what [ __ ]
weed Maps get the [ __ ] out of here with
that what weed Maps weed maps the
[ __ ] Craigslist of collectives [ __ ]
weed Maps
I'll see ya right now [ __ ] weed Babs
I'll never work with weed maps you guys
are [ __ ] corporate [ __ ] suck a
dick so that's all I gotta say about
that weed Maps they don't need to be
trying to pretend like they can do what
we do and that's an insult that they
would even be able to [ __ ] try to
pull that off it sucks because they also
know a lot of these guys don't know
anything about the weed business they
don't know who makes what they don't
know who's who they don't know any of
that they're they're new to this so when
weed Maps hits them up they think that
is a they think that's breeding man and
they don't know any better
so I talked to
the owner of [ __ ] Erik Brunetti it's
one of Bryn's friends Brina actually set
that up and which is really rad you know
I think that's [ __ ] rad and he's new
to the business so I invited him to come
on watch the live feed if he if he has
time and think about it but I would be
stoked to do something with them that
would be one that would be really stoked
to do you know yeah mids map they can go
suck a dick [ __ ] hearing that just makes
me angry like that's that's a
representation people have up readers is
that is weed maps which is it makes me
cross-eyed you know but it is what it is
man
it is what it is what else did I have to
talk about who else do I have to talk
about there's some [ __ ] there's some
[ __ ] stewing about what oh if there are
any experts in here illegal aliens sign
from San Diego
oh that's rad Dec - I've seen that one
that's a rad dick that is old if there's
anyone that has any knowledge about Tom
Hill or his father's lines DM me I want
to I want to want to talk to you but
just only if you're familiar with Tom
Hills dad's lines specifically the
scientist in any of his notations if
anybody is an expert on his lines or
notations let me know to falsify the
true lineage of strains that they're
releasing every [ __ ] day 90% of
breeders do that falsified lineage and
there's all kinds of reasons for doing
it one some people think that it's
protecting their intellectual properties
yeah Tom's dad was the chemist that's
correct some people do it because they
don't have the lines they really have
and they want to yeah we'll be talking
tissue a culture tissue culture again
hopefully Friday if everything goes
alright
sometimes they do it because they they
want to lie about strange that they
don't have and they wanted to sell
better
that's like ninety ninety percent of
people who do rename are gonna do that
90 percent 90 percent 90 percent but no
really is it's that bad some people do
it on accident because they they don't
know how to chase down provenance and
someone tells them they have a line and
they just pass it on as as bolt you know
it's [ __ ] but they think it's real
and a lot of guys make it up because
they want to pretend to be breeders that
they aren't and I think that's a good
majority of to man a lot of people want
to pretend to be breeders want to
pretend to have the knowledge that they
don't and again I challenge any of them
to do with the [ __ ] I do come on here
let everyone fire questions at you about
breeding about any of this [ __ ] let's
see if you can really answer some
[ __ ] questions let's see if you can
make sense you know I challenge all of
them to do it there's very few who will
karma does I know there's other people
that mike exotic Mike comes on here you
know there's all there's people come on
here usually stand up to it but it's is
not very many man there's not very many
you know Mosca can do it also can do it
real well not many people can how many
land races do I think existed unknown
quantity oh [ __ ] I can't remember now
was it the scientist or the chemist I
can't [ __ ] remember I need to find
out exactly what it is what was it was
it the scientist - Kevin I think the
chemist right I want to say the chemist
this was a guy I want to see it was up
north and yeah you know I've asked Ken
Rado several times to come alive and he
said he would but he hasn't so hopefully
hopefully he will come on
yeah the chemist
I said scientist I met chemistry it's
been a long [ __ ] day long day the
chemist yeah [ __ ] it I'll just tell the
story one of our friends bought property
after Tom's dad passed and I assume okay
this is where there's some assumption so
they brought property from a man who was
known as the chemist his family after he
passed away when they were tearing down
the drywall and stuff they found a nice
big [ __ ] stash of seeds labeled from
1982 up till I can't remember what the
last that most current one was but it
was several years ago and they were just
stuffed in the wall and they're all
labeled but they're named labeled using
whatever notations he had so a lot of
them are like CC X whatever there's some
of them are labeled with China Creek or
China creep or China Creek I have I have
pictures of all of them so we're just
trying to figure it out we're just
trying to figure it out I didn't want to
hit up tom directly because he doesn't
want people like hitting him up I don't
think his name on here is not very well
known and I don't want to bug him and I
also don't want him to say hey man
that's mine that's mine you know so but
I would really love to have him involved
with this I mean they technically it's
it's whoever bought the property because
they paid for everything on it and if
that was in the wall me yeah crybaby's
been working with me on this really hard
and he's done some amazing research
already already done some amazing
research but yeah we want to get these
figured out and I think the only way to
do it
really is gonna be with Tom's help like
to get it exactly right but there's
there's gonna be some cool [ __ ] in there
looks like some cool [ __ ] right cry-baby
he saw the pictures so yeah a lot of
notations earliest one was 1982 yeah
um it's gonna be preserved I don't know
about released it's at least gonna be
purser pre be preserved and that's the
whole point is preservation it's not
like banking off of Tom Hills dad stuff
that's not anyone's goal at all but it
will be preserved absolutely and I want
to make sure that this is even his dad
what if there's another dude Nome is
known as a chemist you know yeah I don't
know man Tom's never been nice to me Tom
has never been nice to me so I can't
quite say that he would be honored to
help anything but yeah yeah exactly the
notations are very confusing and that's
why it's like one of those ones I was
like see see I get DC and I'm can't see
see see em mmm you know it's it's it's
pretty weird what happened to that crook
Crockett cheap I don't know I may have
heard some I'll tell you what I know
and and what I know may not even be
correct I was called by somebody
yesterday and told that there may be
some how the Crockett got fired over
doing something bad or incorrectly and I
don't know who fired him I don't even
know who would hire Crockett in the
first place but they may have been fired
I don't even know if it's true it might
not even Crockett might have been
referring to someone else but that's why
I asked like I did I was like I don't
know what it is but yeah now my buddy
you hear let's see where we got where
command just asked me a question and I
don't want to miss éxito moment why
don't many folks read with EC sd1 the
original clone is still hard to find the
original clone there's a lot of sour D
crosses but most of them aren't done
with the clone my buddy karma does
amazing work with sour D his headbangers
[ __ ] top [ __ ] knotch if you want a
good sour line I'm finishing up a sour
line right now using the clone I think a
lot of people do it's just it's just
trusting someone to have a legit sour
lying you know but yeah I see sour
accounts
we still they just found him with a
jelly bean Club you just gotta see
archive has a good sour - sure archives
of but um yeah he has a sour it's legit
no sour is not cams scum fee a cam 91 is
not the same thing the according to Adam
Dunn's podcast
everything is cam 91 but no that is not
how it works
anything good in that h som her surgery
i have no idea i haven't seen that
didn't know anything about it
oh no I don't even want to watch drugs
in [ __ ] archives shrew me so that's this
remedy which is also known as original
diesel in some circles or Amish diesel
as well kind of coffee I'm drinking area
dandelion coffee from Hawaii um I can't
remember what the I like one of my
friends in Hawaii sends me some kind of
Kona it's a P berry from Kona that lives
out on the island I trade them seats for
this for the Kona
so it works out pretty well I don't mind
bartering for a good coffee I took a lot
of coffee but this is actually starbucks
graham cracker flavor out of a [ __ ]
Keurig so yeah
inbox you my number okay
what is day wrecker is it someone's
original diesel it just depends on who
you ask man I wasn't around
in the East Coast I'm not an East
Coaster so I couldn't tell you what a
legit day wrecker is versus a legit
diesel trusting there's just been so
many people who've claimed XYZ is
original geez let cetera what is sprite
again sprite is the 10k back cross the
10k from Green Day
that was bodis cut so it's very very
lemon-lime in bucks my balls DME your
number I'm not gonna send anyone my
number yeah I don't I don't not big on
passing out my phone number I get enough
[ __ ] [ __ ] up calls just from other
people passing it out you see I'm not
the most popular breeder on earth I know
I know it's hard to imagine that anybody
could possibly dislike my ass of a but
it happens I know must be something
wrong with them because I'm an amazing
special man yeah nine seven six Evo good
3 15cm H fixtures solace tech for sure I
love these ones man I'm rocking them I'm
loving them like it's too vigorous the
growth is way too vigorous now it's
overly vigorous I have too many [ __ ]
too much growth too fast a legit Agent
Orange
well Agent Orange it would be an
intelligent agent orange I would think a
legit Agent Orange Agent Orange cm HS go
up to a thousand watts now
correlations between frost emails and
progeny that's that's one that's up for
debate really I'm gonna have to to say
that quarterly there isn't necessarily a
correlation between every frost email
and progeny every single mail not just
from a single line like not all males
from a single line breed the same the
correlation cannot be it's just there's
too many variables to answer that
question and you would never know until
you out cross it and see and that's
that's the best answer I can give you
out cross it run the lines it's just
there's there's no correlation between
frosty males and frosty progeny that is
100 percent of the time there may even
be a correlation between frosty males
and female dominance but again not a
hundred percent at the time so it's
really it's really hard to answer that
question with so many variables at play
you might have a frosty male and a
female that is not so resinous and
actually you may owe a male coat
dominant I want to say or male dominant
even though it's expressing is female
and it would completely X out any kind
of female dominance in the progeny and
and easy either tilt it back to male
dominance even or just kind of both and
go straight down the middle so there's
so much there's so much to that and I am
a frosty male did you see Scott's
miracle grows dude that was only a
matter of time before they bought
sunlight supply the biggest the biggest
appliers
Oh what do you look for a progeny would
breeding with og that just depends on
the project man depends on the project I
don't just check pollen and see what
happens do you think breeders ever load
their packs with famine claim their eggs
I have three separate packs from drummer
turn out to have 28 females to males
they've all regular seeds I don't think
any breeder would make a reverse line B
and stuff it in regular packs knowingly
unless I mean
would intentionally make a reverse line
and stuff it in packs like that because
it costs a shitload more to make a
reverse line not only in in electricity
but in space-time amount of pollen you
don't get as many seeds etc but if
someone accidentally heard their plants
and sold those seeds it would still have
a female dominance with a high high
probability of hermaphroditism in most
environments easy stress response and
that in that case you would still see a
high female dominance but also a high
herb dominance and yeah that in that
case I would say that would probably be
the the most likely candidate I mean I
don't know if that's what happened with
him at all I wouldn't I wouldn't claim
to know but but that's that's in that
situation that's what you get if you
were to open pollinate the butters I'd
have a whole lot of variants of the
babies and most which you would have
already seen or work throughout the
years the right variant afghani correct
correct correct
I'll makes everything too dark it's
getting hard to read today and up for
too long today
I do like rubber groomers a nice guy
and I've seen a lot of good stuff from
his plants you know a lot of its uh
Mendel breath crosses but I mean if it's
good is good you know where do you think
the peanut nose in p90 one comes from
that's a hard question I'm gonna say I'm
gonna have to say it's it's whatever
skunk or Afghani based skunk that they
used every my guess
who got I mean this
Oh
okay
any info on compound genetics yeah good
guys they have a lot of really good cuts
and they're doing some heavy seed baking
projects as opposed to breeding projects
but there's there's some absolutely
stellar progeny in those as well
nope never had the dumpster never worked
with it the name just turned me off it's
kind of like that like chemo I've had it
never worked with it and it was just a
name man it was a big turn-off it was a
big turn-off and like I felt like if I
smoked chemo all my hair would fall out
and I'd just be all weak and withered
you know that's one of those things
doctor Candyman Lloyd yeah do you dr.
Candyman had some he was and he declared
himself the king pollen sucker but you
know what he had some badass [ __ ] back
in the day
bad ass [ __ ] he was an excellent string
collector and he you know he was doing
better work than a lot of breeders who
were trying to do selections and and I
think that that happens a lot when
people know good weed and they're good
at selecting a male and you can still
get some excellent progeny that way I
could think of a a ton of instances of
people out out how would I put this
making venner progeny than breeders who
called himself readers doing selections
you know what I mean like it happens a
lot and in that case Lloyd was doing
that back in the day he had some [ __ ]
rad [ __ ]
uija I would say he had his much rad
[ __ ] as elite genetics did back in the
day not to be confused liek cannabis
elite genetics yeah he was killing it
and and and not as well-known but
goddamn he did some cool [ __ ] plus he's
a [ __ ] a black guy who's a Satanist I
love that how about punk rock is that
[ __ ] I just got in some compound the
other day what was it um it looks good
as did Jeff whoo jet fuel gelato cross I
said I had the jet fuel gelato s ones
going and it was different it was a
white shirt I think Joey Jeffy of gelato
looking forward to that it sounds
[ __ ] cool
P 91 crossed to the butter now I don't
have the peanut you won't cut anymore I
would have to select from the S ones and
I have so much so many other projects
going out probably not gonna rework in
AP 91 I'll sleep that up to everyone
else yeah Barbara Bush is dead Oh aren't
we sad a [ __ ] Bush is dead
a lot of [ __ ] snakes came out of that
crotch let me tell you what I can't wait
to see him compound did some [ __ ]
cool [ __ ] with that jet fuel gelato dude
and and you guys show off all the
progeny although I mean you don't just
push it out there and not run it and not
test it it's it's solid and we're all
seeing the results it's [ __ ] special
it's special I can dig it
but yeah [ __ ] that [ __ ] the Bush family
[ __ ] the Cheney's [ __ ] all those
[ __ ] gonna died sooner aleister
crowley's my hero
yeah I'm stoked to see what's in that
jet fuel gelato us ones and definitely
it's making its mark they're making
their mark tearing [ __ ] up same with
tiger trees yeah I'm I'm not a fan of
any of that
I know I know what I was gonna talk
about let's talk about sub cools new
secretary let's talk about her did
anybody see the [ __ ] I saw it I don't
even follow the [ __ ] and I still
saw it
that's uh that's how quickly that made
it around she's this raggedy ad you know
hold on I'm not gonna insult her like
that because I don't know her she's
obviously mentally deficient to be
rolling with sub cool I shouldn't make
fun of her I'm not gonna be mean not
gonna be mean she does dress like a
prostitute
and that's not being mean that's just
how she dresses her hair looks like she
stuck her fingers in a light socket hmm
I'm not gonna talk about her face cuz
that's that's too mean but let's just
say let's just say she no I'm gonna say
that either guy I'm having a hard time
with this one guy's [ __ ] is the face
face of meth faces of meth is happening
yes
Thank You brain hmm and I mean if you
look at sub cool you know that anyone
under the age of 25 that's [ __ ] that
thing is is is hard up for meth it's
hard up for meth let's just let's be
real they're hard up for meth and he is
supplying it he's supplying it but man
she was stove to be on his page some
some chicks will do anything for
attention though man
she look like a meth mine she looked
like a math he's very messy any age
which is ugly but whatever you know to
each their own we all see something
beautiful
in something other people don't write
not usually not for real she's a special
special case yeah I just I saw that and
I was [ __ ] dying I was [ __ ] dying
about him won him bragging about her
being his secretary or whatever is a Oh
administrative assistant or assistant
mmm and to her bragging about being his
executive assistant or whatever it's
called whatever they're calling that
personality but would be even more funny
as if she wasn't [ __ ] him and he was
making it look like they are so yeah dad
no I thought that [ __ ] was funny so I
highly recommend going on sub cool 420s
page today here's some free
advertisements up cool and um check out
his chick check out his chick and leave
him a note leave him a note let him know
how what you think oh like he should
never have [ __ ] with me he should
never have [ __ ] with me all those
years ago and picked a fight let me tell
you what cuz the [ __ ] switched up now
buddy the [ __ ] switched up I mean I had
High Times tell me I'd never make it
without them I had the attitude tell me
I never make it without them
sub cult L me he would crush me until I
could never do business in this [ __ ]
business I never make my name in this
business because of him and ain't [ __ ]
time grand right ain't time grin because
eventually your [ __ ] enough people
long enough that shit's gonna come back
on you it's gonna come back on you and I
haven't changed Who I am at all I'm not
even a little bit I'm probably a lot
worse of a [ __ ] pain in the ass than
I ever was Oh 420 promos oh yeah thank
you for reminding me 420 promos starting
tomorrow
up till 4:20 so it's starting on four
eighteen thirty five percent off all
riot seeds that
doesn't include the spray and it doesn't
include smell but you know I can't lower
the price on his seeds if I wanted to
and the spray is already not it's not a
huge margin so but the seeds 35% off
voila I hope that helps you know I mean
is it's a big over a third off I know
some of the shit's expensive there's not
a lot of it but if it's fo twenty you
got do something right and let's see
what can i what can I do to boost that
how about every pack comes with the free
pack of let's say strawberry roadkill
and or what would you guys would prefer
wouldn't you guys prefer I said thirty
five percent off starting for eighteen
as a midnight would you guys rather have
strawberry Switchblade and I'm trying to
think what I should do for the freebies
I'm just thinking of what I have in
stock let me diesel I've already give a
bunch of this out and I don't have a lot
left of lemon teas or I'd be given those
out [ __ ] you on the key lime pie um-hmm
deep chunk banana that's one of my
favorites and nobody's buying it
nobody's growing it so let's do deep
chuck banana
let's do deep chuck banana how about a
free pack of the deep chunk banana with
every purchase every purchase over a
hundred dollars though got to make it
worth it gotta make it worth that I
don't want people buying [ __ ] end up
being $50 worth thirty five percent off
and then wanting some [ __ ] one
hundred and fifty dollar freebie so
let's do deep chuck banana and 35% off
over $100 how does that sound and how
about if you spent $200 or more free
pack of strawberry switchblade and deep
chunk banana huh ah so that way if you
spend $200 there's a bigger incentive
you
you get at least I don't know how much
that adds up to but it's over $200 in
freebies
so I'll set that up tonight on the
coupon code coupon codes gonna be 420
666 so write that down like this for 20
666 that's gonna be the coupon code on
my website right seeds dot-com or riots
et al I'm like the Oprah seeds everybody
gets a deep chunk and that's the coupon
code for 2666
add them to your cart when you're
checking out put that in and I'll throw
in the discount it'll add the seeds in
for you and bam done princ Pacific Coast
oh I wish I could give autograph of
Jannah mass to everyone what's my best
strain not for breeders oh just depends
on what you like man depends on your
personal preference like when people ask
me like what's my best strain when I get
those emails I say the first response I
give is thank you shaggy yes that that's
close enough when people ask me that I
like to say let name some strains that
you do like waves are some strange that
you do like that you like to smoke em
and they tell me that then I can make a
basis off of how certain strains treat
their their brain chemistry you know
thank you redwood thank you Pacific oh
let's see did I do the giveaway from
last night yet no I always leave that up
to brand whenever she finally does the
drawing well know who won meth heads let
I guess that's next after cokehead [ __ ]
because there is a little bit of a
variance right usually cokehead [ __ ]
are
rich rich girls or girls from better off
situations that that go on bad coke runs
and ended up sucking everyone's dick and
[ __ ] dudes for coke right but meth
hit [ __ ] usually are already white
trash and they get into it and they
never had a chance so that's usually how
it goes usually you do coke head [ __ ]
don't dip down to meth they just stay on
coke or crack but meth head [ __ ] that
if they're already on math they're
[ __ ] anyways call it administrative
assistant there you go
but yeah can you flower under cm h3 yeah
yeah of course meth breath lines of
years go with what type of height I miss
something
Hara wanna sucks
heroin is a [ __ ] shitty shitty line
I'm not lying that's a shitty line a lot
of people were conned into thinking Cara
Juana was this [ __ ] crazy potent
plant it's sucks man [ __ ] sucks ass all
of all of the strawberry lines extract
very well all of them all of them
yes 420 666 written like that Friesland
indica sea I say it's boof but my friend
up in Canada loves it track inspector
loves the [ __ ] Friesland but I just
not my thing a lot of it got passed down
here from Canada and it was Canadian be
stirrers
strongest highest yield Lord like just
like all the other questions people are
asking it depends on how you grow
depends on your body chemistry
what is potent to you might not be
potent to me what's putting me night not
be potent to use that's a really hard
one as far as biggest yielding a lot of
the strawberry cream based lines are
good yielders however depends on how you
grow man I don't like telling people you
can get big yields if they suck at
growing you know and at the same time I
don't like telling they're gonna get
quality if they suck at growing and make
everything beastie yields the last thing
you should be worrying about is yields
first thing you should be worried about
is quality I still have some of the old
dog wanna push from motorable the og
cush arowana I the original seeds of
that I wasn't a fan man wasn't a fan
it's not my thing I don't like that
leathery smell of marijuana it was not
appealing to me um yeah not my thing
oh so the next the next a forgetting two
to three pounds of like I mean I it
depends on your growing style again but
I can pull that with blue dream and it's
just still wouldn't be that great
equality just because you're pushing it
so hard you should never push a strain
you should never use bloom boosters if
you want quality because you're you're
redirecting the energy of the plant
I have not smelled the Harry it smells
like peanuts absolutely nice you're
having what strand of mine will break a
carbon filter Afghani heirloom skunk
spray can any of those are [ __ ]
stinky is [ __ ] man
quality over quantity any day any day of
the week and I don't think most people
will ever understand that see and motor
rebel pushed out Hera wanna for a long
time he based it off of Chris wood
horses line however I don't think it was
I think he crossed something in if I
remember correctly if I remember
correctly crossed something different in
and it came out completely different
whereas the original Hera wanna from
Steve tough wood horse that that line
was a more of an Afghani base and motor
rebels is just like very narrow leaf
that's not anything reminiscent of the
original
here wanted Jack 33 it sounds like a
sandy line there any negative side
effects to reversing a plant outside not
really other than I don't outdoor
breeding is not ideal anywhere because
cross-contamination becomes a big
reality when you start [ __ ] with [ __ ]
outdoors always because you never know
who's growing outdoors around you unless
you know are your neighbors and [ __ ] but
I mean even then pollen can travel over
a mile so that's that's the biggest
problem and seeding your neighbors
plants because they'll [ __ ] hate you
forever if they find out you did that do
you think it's possible there's still a
tree cut of UBC Jima oh sure I have a
lot of early UBC chemo crosses still too
but yeah I'm sure the original cuts
gotta be out there it was passed around
a lot it wasn't too rare again groovy
weed in my line
awesome groovy failing it depends on
your body chemistry a lot of people like
herbal because it relaxes them and earth
will freaks me out and makes me question
everything about every decision I've
ever made and hate life so it's again
it's not something that if someone like
if you go in a collective and someone
tells you how this weed is gonna make
you feel they're [ __ ] lying to you
that is not how it works and anybody who
smokes any amount of weed for any period
of time should be able to figure that
out pretty quick I have no idea who
garrison Lane is don't know who Billy
Kimber og is I don't have a wide lexicon
of of new pollen shoppers I apologize I
don't keep up with anything like that
and even but you know what like even
with friends of mine like someone just
asked about professor P was trained
currently going I have no idea what he's
working on and it's not out of
disrespect for him it's not that I don't
care about his lines I'm working on my
own [ __ ] and it's like I just have my
head down working you know that's how it
goes
I've got him longer you've been in the
game nice oh thank you uh as far as like
breeding and selling seats publicly it's
at 13 years now twelve and a half
thirteen years I always eight thirteen
because it sounds cooler but it's more
like two and a half as far as growing in
[ __ ] since I was young man since I was
young I mean I even I used to water my
dad's plants that doesn't really count
for growing cuz I hated doing it but
it's been on and off most of my life you
know potency and breeding potential of
Neville Hayes Neville Hayes is a
beautiful line not every Fino is
beautiful which means that the out
crosses are going to be wide and varied
however if some were to take an L line
that was extremely good work it keep
selecting towards that line awesome
absolutely awesome
I just I'm gonna be poppin some new a
new sour line as we speak so after the
all this [ __ ] goes on just harvested
some of the seeds and they look good
there's a lot of potential in the cross
however you never know till you run them
so those won't be available for quite a
while but yeah there's some some legit
sour D crosses going on and it might
have something to do with something
something sure B maybe I don't know got
to make lines that appeal to everyone
and and you know it makes him good [ __ ]
yeah you better force him on you better
force him on it takes forever to come on
last night he came on when I had like
two seconds left
old man Lopes needs to come through
do these lessons make you look smart I
think they make me look smarter and
sexier and sexier what do I do with
leftovers after I harvest my seeds I
usually throw it in the freezer and
never touch it again but I will be
smashing it soon I have a lot of [ __ ] I
need to go through yeah I mean for a
while when I would be low on weed I'd
smoke it just because it was good [ __ ]
it just had been seated yeah yeah we
brought that up earlier about sunlight
supply and Scots Miracle Grow no real
surprise there no real surprise there
the average time to bring the line
public so like if let's say everything
lines up correctly let's say I did a
good selection the progeny show good
favorable results that like I see [ __ ]
that I like and I know other people with
like and all that [ __ ] is it
lupa had been finicky yeah not too
terribly but I remember the first time I
grew it it was it was a lot I just
wasn't as good at growing oh jeez but
for a line to be finished respect at
least a year year and a half and that's
if everything goes everything goes right
do you think effects with taste do you
think affects the taste with fertilized
buds I'm not sure if that means I'd have
to reword that smart is the new gangsta
very true accept it I'll suck you in
your [ __ ] mouth - I could recite
cannabis genetics and I'll punch you in
your [ __ ] face doesn't mean that I'll
beat your ass but I goddamn will [ __ ]
try damn well try
I have no edit button with my mouth or
my uh or my kicks or punches that's just
the way it is but I grew up in a [ __ ]
blue-collar town and I think that's
normal for everyone around here and it's
not normal for people in a lot of other
cities it's we our town even our punk
rock
we have a horrible reputation for being
violent as a matter of fact there's a
new documentary there's a new
documentary coming out what's it called
I think it's called bonza Brundage and
they did a documentary on Bakersfield
punk rock and the violence and all the
fucked-up [ __ ] in our scene that's
happened over the years so yeah if you
see that coming out check it out the
bones of Brundage I'm in it so of course
I'm gonna push it because that's [ __ ]
ku but yeah it's a it's all about the
history of punk rock and Bakersfield
which was funny flying swordsman came on
and told me that uh what did you say
totally not punk rock or some stupid
shit's like but this this [ __ ]
[ __ ] posted about Grateful
Dead's records on his pages [ __ ]
talking about being not being punk rock
get the [ __ ] out of here I should send
my blood it just is what it is
I hope it'll be on Netflix I'm not sure
but you can see it on Facebook or if you
go I
I know it's on it's on a lot of
different things if you if you want I'll
send you a link so you can see the the
trailer man it's just some of it
but you know it's it's a lot about how
like during a certain era of Bakersfield
the early 2000s late 90s how everyone
that was around during that era
we all knew each other because victory
was not terribly uh it's not terribly
big especially the punk rock scene was
much smaller and we all knew each other
and it was kind of about how from this
small group what happened and how it all
fell apart and how we all ended up you
know most of us are dead most of our
friends are dead or you'll see a lot of
them that are homeless in the
documentary guys that were frontmen one
of the guys that was a frontman of one
of my band he's a [ __ ] disaster
[ __ ] disaster now he just slurs and
mumbles and grumbles and it used to be a
funny dude used to used to be punk as
[ __ ] and now
is a wipeout you know it's a lot about
that yeah not many people made it out
and were successful it was a [ __ ]
wild time it was a good time but you
know I mean everything's awesome when
you're on drugs until drugs take over
and you're [ __ ] you know you don't you
don't get out of doing hard drugs
untouched it'll affect your life in some
way it will absolutely affect your safe
and your life in some way
I grow organic and I grow synthetic it's
a hybrid style of growing and it's just
whatever works best and the most
effective and I find that not being
strictly one thing or another being able
to move fluid you know with what you got
and being able to move fluid based on
the strain is is the best way for me to
grow I can adapt to all of it and that's
that's what works best for me
I see people kick my ass and growing
with organic and I've seen people kick
my ass with growing in synthetic
definitely not the best but but it's all
about being fluid yep lots of heroin at
the pump scene I've been through it
lived it somehow I made it out the other
end though I'm pretty vocal about it
like I don't care I like to be able to
talk about my past when it comes to all
drugs because I know a lot of other
people have been through what I've been
through and in cannabis people are so
[ __ ] judgmental so goddamn judgmental
and people should be able to talk about
their experiences be able to relate with
people too and and you should be able to
inspire people who are going through
that [ __ ] you know what I mean you'll be
able to talk you know say I made it
through this you can too that's it
sounds silly and it sounds obvious but
it's not in our scene and in even though
cannabis whether people ever want to I
don't know why people say it's not a
drug it's a [ __ ] drug alcohol is a
drug anything that alters your mind
state is a drug you know it is what it
is I'm not saying one is worse than the
other obviously some are worse than the
other but I don't think cannabis is the
worst by any means but it is a drug so
for people to be so judge
mental about other people and the lives
they're living or lived when they smoke
pot that's so ironic so ironic
and to this day dude like when people
want to insult me they'll call me a
[ __ ] junkie because they know that's
my past and the the quickest way to
insult someone that's ever had a really
bad drug past is to call them a current
junkie and it's real easy to do that
it's real easy to insult people like
that but I don't get hurt by it um
because I've seen the good that it's
done by me talking about my past with
heroin and methadone and all that [ __ ]
and I've seen how many people pop up and
you know what message me say me too me
too
I think you know so that's all the
reason I bring it up that's all the
reason I talk about it because people
should be able to talk about their [ __ ]
you know without feeling [ __ ] just I
don't know like without having their
reputations tarnished by everyone else
plus drugs are [ __ ] fun right
hashtag me too me too movement yeah I
was a horrible drunk when I was young at
the age of 19 I had my liver fill and
had to be rushed the hospital and
whatever toxins were coming through from
the alcohol infected a lymph node my
lymph system and I had to be cut open
and have my lymph nodes drained and be
stuffed with gauze and pulled the Goss
out of myself six feet of it twice a day
for months until it finally killed
wasn't sealed itself up so you know I've
been there too do you I consider myself
a grower or breeder first um a grower
because you cannot be a breeder if
you're not a an excellent grower you
can't yeah I still got the scar - it's
right on my [ __ ] crotch it looks yeah
it's [ __ ] up
but ya know I you have to be a good
grower before you can advance to
breeding it's just you can't you can't
see lines fully express themselves if
they're not being grown correctly before
all that I'm a collector and a of of
genetics in genetic history
hey brain can I have some water
you want to see the scar no I don't know
it's a little much I don't want you I
don't I don't want to [ __ ] uh tarnish
you shut up Matt god dammit why do you
have to be here when I said I'm a
collector jesus [ __ ] christ
[ __ ] my ass oh you know I'll just start
up one day the live feed and it'll just
be a shot of my crotch scar and that's
all it'll be but I'll make sure and
shave and make it all nice for you so
yeah yeah shrooms I hate shrooms
I [ __ ] hate shrooms it hasn't been an
hour yet five minutes
rooms are too much for me I start
giggling a lot at the beginning but then
it always ends up being a bad drop at
the end always really depressing at the
end so yeah
Jesus same answer I've been given to all
this [ __ ] man it just depends you have
to you would have to try each one see
what worked better for your chronic pain
again you got to realize smoking affects
your into a cannabinoid system along
with all there's many receptors that it
that affects some of these are pain
receptors some different strains even
different phenotypes of each strain
effect different pain receptors
differently in everyone I didn't do
gzhel crossed the afghani heirloom line
I did do Jesus our dub and gzhel s ones
that's crazy the bugs in the plant yeah
that would [ __ ] me up too
again which trains have no narcotic
effect it's not known unless it happens
to you because I mean again purple has a
narcotic effect on most people on me
it's not necessarily narcotic it's a bad
bad situation these glasses is hip I did
not create gzhel that was created by
chem dog the person not the strain the
strain well the person named himself
after the strain because that's a strain
however I'm not sure what came first the
chicken are they egg on that one but he
created gzhel and that is mass Super
Skunk cross tack em dog D thank you dear
egg dinosaur came first trick question
chizel yeah there's been a few cheezles
the cheese diesels Heath Robinson made a
chizel and Heath is a [ __ ] and someone
else made a chizel maybe it was Big
Buddha seeds I am a 50s diner waitress
thank you Midwest yeah and there is a
one minute 41 seconds so remember the
guys tomorrow starts the 420 sell on
4:18 there's the bird
it is 420 666 coupon code for 2666 35
percent off spend $100 get deep trunk
banana spend $200 and get you chunk
banana and for about the other one
already I'll figure it I'll go back over
watch a video and remember exactly what
it is but yeah nope I don't take money
orders good night everyone Cheers
dog and bird at the same time okay
Cheers strawberry switchblade that's
right
spend $200 get deep chunk and flat or
deep chunk cross the Platinum and Anna
and switchblade night