[Music]
foreign
ER Syndicate where we explore the
history of a clan destined scene Through
The Eyes of the folks who lived it I'm
Matthew owner of variety seeds I'll
occasionally be joined by my co-host not
so Josh breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
hello everyone welcome to breeders
Syndicate I'm howdy this is my co-host
not so I know he's been out for a few
weeks everybody's demanded missed my
friend not so and here we are with our
friend direwolf who is in Shadow and
today we're going to talk about some of
the Canadian scene and some of his IPM
techniques I know we've been meaning to
do a show on IPM and needing to and it's
been heavily requested and this man has
a lot of experience with it so welcome
direwolf
thank you I'm kind of happy to be on the
on the black screen with all the
critique not so it gets on his hair
because I'm having kind of a bad hair
day today yeah you've seen how they bust
his balls over his hair it's brutal it
is I mean yeah you know facial
expressions random stuff you don't even
think of they pick up on and all of a
sudden it's a meme or something so yeah
the verbal tics sure yeah the verbal
tics it's hard being a public speaker
yeah it's not easy you know you don't
really realize it until you listen to
yourself and then you're like oh man
wait yeah wait until you're staring at
yourself and a long selfie for an hour
it's really it's really interesting yeah
anyone anyone that knows me in real life
knows that I'm not like a big I kind of
have like a bit I'm known for like my
death stare I'm like I look I look
friendly when I'm smiling but I have a
death stare a lot of the time so it
doesn't translate well over over uh
phones sometimes too
well we're super glad to have you
um I wanted to start out talking a
little bit about your your early
introduction into the import scene in
candidate let's start there um what was
it like what kind of stuff were you
seeing um and what years are we talking
about
um yeah so I guess now that I think of
it I actually my original start was
actually a weird start it was actually
one of my when I first started was
exposed to it it was actually from a
friend when I'm a just a guy from down
the Street's mom who was we found out
later was like a full-on like closet
grower she was kind of like this hippie
lady we used to it was her boyfriend I
actually got us like started smoking
weed and then we'd always just Jack her
weed out of her bedside table and there
was a big story that went with it about
where it was it was this exotic import
and it turned out afterwards it was just
she was literally one of the first
Growers around our area
um growing it all in the backyard right
in front of us we had no idea so but
basically that so my first start was was
homegrown and then but there really
wasn't much weed going around back then
it was really all import and I don't
remember the years ago I started really
I started smoking when I was like 14 so
it's probably like 86 or something like
that
and yeah like for basically in Canada
until like you got a little bit of
domestic stuff but pretty much from
those mid like mid 80s until
uh it was like early 90s there wasn't
much domestic at all because we didn't
get any like that there was not a lot of
outdoor and stuff it was just the
occasional indoor and you couldn't even
really sell it it was you basically had
to like I can totally remember people
growing indoor and pressing it into
bricks and selling it because that was
the only way you could actually
um sell it like you couldn't people
wouldn't buy it or
uh part of me did they not recognize it
as cannabis because it looks so
different not compressed or what was the
reason uh well it was green was one
thing and and the you know back then it
was just people didn't recognize that it
was possible to grow good wheat they
thought it was really it had to be
important and keep in mind this is like
back in like
really you know so this would be right
around the time where Neville was like
launching the seed bank so there
probably wasn't a whole lot of like
genetics and I mean if you even just put
in perspective if you fast forward four
or five years later
I bought my first grow light and that
was the only grow store in our entire
Province so the equivalent of your state
we literally had to drive like three
hours to buy a buy a halide light there
was only there was literally only one
store I mean it really wasn't a thing
so uh go ahead oh what's I just remind
it was wild when uh when Matt and I
interviewed Corel from Super sativa seed
Club
uh he had a similar story of when they
first started growing indoor uh they
tried to Brown it out
because all this lime green and green
color was like a real issue in the
market because everyone was used to like
imported Brown
and they had yesterday it was like an
issue like green was an issue like
people didn't realize it is better they
just saw it as something completely
unusual
if you read that I read a book by the
one of the guys from the cornbread Mafia
and that was pretty much their entire
curing technique was trying to figure
out how to make it brown and crappy
looking so it looks like import that was
literally like everything like Threw It
On The Barn floor and it was it was uh
for sure a thing and the other thing the
area where I came from it was very very
hash Centric so people didn't even
really like buying weed it was all like
it was all like I've mostly that Afghani
border Ash it was around and that was
like the staple and everything else
other than black Afghani hash was
totally suspect so most of it was import
from Afghanistan then as opposed to like
uh Mexican like we were getting in the
U.S it wasn't really making its way up
to Canada
I never actually saw Mexican until dead
tour in like Ohio or something like that
and uh you guys had a wholly different
language because I remember like looking
at going like someone was selling it to
me I was like this looks like really
crappy it's like it's mids dude and I
was like what are mids I don't know all
we knew was hash and and high-end Hydro
in Canada
um but yeah I know it was it was all it
was you'd get some other stuff but it
definitely wasn't the same type of
import you're talking about it was
pretty much 90 of it was all like that
Afghan you know like the gold stamps a
lot of it the stuff you see yeah Afghan
it's like border hash and then you got
occasional batches from Morocco or
Lebanese and then you got some weed but
it was usually pretty high-end like it
was like Thai stick occasionally and we
got a lot of like pressed Jamaican and I
don't think I I think I've maybe seen
Mexican like one time in Canada ever
I'm sure it was around how did you guys
used to use the hash like actually smoke
it was it the the old knife hits or like
a jar so the area I'm from is this like
tells you exactly it's one of those
things anywhere you go in the world and
everyone be like what like but in our
area like if they kind of the equivalent
of like you know New York State this
well like in the kind of it was it was
in Ontario thing so I grew up around
Toronto area and they did what was
called bottle tokes which they are
horrible when I think back but it's like
you get a cigarette and you put a little
piece of hash on it and then you break a
hole in the bottom of like a pop bottle
and you like Brew you brew the hash in
there and there's this whole technique
and then you kind of tip it over when
it's done and it's like a lava lamp and
then you suck the hash out but it was
like a whole like
you were it was like you got social
status and a lot in on my circles
anyways for like being a good BT Brewer
like it was like an art form be able to
break the bottle it was kind of when you
look back it was like pretty cracky but
uh that was and you'll never hear anyone
in Canada no have a clue what you're
talking about unless they grew up around
Toronto area and then everyone knows
what you're talking about bottles you
want to say you want to say cracky look
at some of the equipment now for dabbing
I mean it just looks like straight meth
bites to me you know like it's just yeah
yeah I'm not I'm not I kind of avoid
some of those
um even though I kind of like dabs I
don't dab a whole lot because I just
hate the whole thing and my wife can't
walk by dab rig without accidentally
breaking it so it's like an expensive
hobby yeah I never got into the whole
torch thing like that was just too much
too much too much to screw up too much
to do all that once they started getting
to like emails and [ __ ] or you could
just leave it and set it that was okay
it still felt a little cracky but puff
goes and stuff then it was like okay
this looks like more like a bong I can
deal with this you know yeah I feel like
every two or three years in the hash
movement right now they all kind of like
just move on from whatever they did
before that they were convinced was the
bee's knees yeah and it just slowly gets
dustbined like we're not gonna talk
about that era anymore that we did that
um but it's interesting one of the
things that I'll say about that is that
you know I grew up in uh in Northern in
Chicago right and so even though
direwolf and I aren't like too terribly
terribly far from each other uh vastly
different weed cultures
yeah you know my weed culture was
primarily Mexican green and brown and
there was almost no hash culture
so it's interesting how like you know
Canada and the different uh laws and
rules that applied over there led to
vastly different Imports that we saw
I think it's also what what crime
networks were working there because I
think the big thing if you go and from
Canada east to west was totally
different and so basically what was
going on in our area was Montreal which
is like there's the port that's the big
Port that comes into Canada from the
East Coast that was kind of controlled
by by like Irish mafia and that was
basically like a free you could bring
all kinds of stuff through there so
everything basically for the most part
was coming through that court of
Montreal and what was the interesting
thing about it we found out afterwards
so we kind of had like up until like
about 90 or something it was all this
black Afghani hash and then it kind of
went dry for like a couple of years and
then a guy that I was good for I was
actually living with at the time he had
this connection it was like this this uh
Irish mafia dude from Toronto and we
were like in University and he had for
whatever reason nobody could yeah and we
found it afterwards what the actual
story was which is crazy one nobody else
had hash except for this guy so we were
like the Kings because we're the only
guys that could get black hash which is
what everyone wanted and we could get
like however much you wanted and this
dude used to show up to our little like
you know University student house every
Friday night in like a limo and just
bring like slabs of this hash in and he
was just like one of those guys that
didn't give a crap and he'd like walk
out with a Ziploc full of cash and it
was like every Friday in and out and
what it turned out I found out
afterwards it was the reason why they
had access to this it was it was
actually Howard Mark's old uh stash so
Howard Marx would have been in jail at
the time but apparently he had
um which if you ever read that Howard's
Mark's book you end up with the Irish
dude which kind of all makes sense but
apparently he got when he went to jail
he had all these stash houses sitting
all over Montreal still full so they
just sat on him for a while and then it
started coming out through this and
that's why that's where our connect was
so it was all this kind of few year old
uh Howard marks hash and I might not be
true but I have a feeling it probably
was which probably tells you a whole lot
of that hack and I've heard of similar
overlapping stories about where all that
hash came from in Montreal and so it was
probably that's why everyone was smoking
black Afghani hash it was probably
because they were like one or two major
importers that were controlling that
whole thing I remember the the normal
story
um from Neville talking about nordl and
one of his partners and I think one of
Mark's partners that was that was one of
Mark's partners that had the nordl thing
right yeah
yeah that was their whole deal right it
was a guy that was yeah part of the IRA
and he smuggled they would smuggle hash
through the IRA networks telling them
that it was guns that was kind of their
whole that was how it marks his partner
yeah super gangster for back then what's
interesting about all that too is that
there was a lot of of hash Smugglers
that avoided America because the
penalties were so much worse
um and you know they they viewed America
sort of like the place where you went to
prison for a long time
where Europe and Canada and other places
were viewed as like a lot Chiller if you
actually got in trouble
yeah you know
so I remember they increased some of the
charges here if I remember during 215 I
remember uh like they were there were
bigger charges for hash or extracts than
there were for uh normal cannabis you
know cannabis flower at one point I
remember it was getting really bad where
like at one point I was pulled over on
the way to this I was like some hash
event in LA and it was like I stopped I
was like 4 a.m I pulled over to get gas
on my way out of San Diego and I didn't
have a license at the time that
suspended and of course I got pulled
over like cops sitting in the gas
station waiting for me you know like no
one else is there they were bored and uh
they they messed with me super hard over
the hash they were like you know we can
get you for this though you know like so
they they still took it seriously here
during 2 15. um concentrated cannabis
yeah yeah manufacturing and all
right did you get different grades of
how how would you I mean I know memory
can be tough but like did you think the
Afghani hash you were getting back then
was high quality
um so it was mixed so there was yeah
there was different grades I would say
that we didn't necessarily know they
were different grades
um but basically so a lot of it there
was basically three grades from what I
could tell there was and it was just
there was different batches and probably
the loads were mixed up and a lot of the
times back then unless you're buying the
whole kilo which when we were like you
know 15 you weren't getting
um you weren't seeing what the stamp was
on it
um so basically it all came in if you
ever see the packs it's it's uh they all
came pretty much all came in this red
cellophane paper uh wrap and some of
them would have gold seals like which is
you know probably gold spray paint with
whatever brand of whatever just like you
see with the Moroccan or you see with
the modern day hash and uh
and we all it seems like all the best
stuff we always had no stamp and from
what I understand I think that probably
was the case and it was kind of like the
good loads
um like the stamp stuff was the
commercial stuff and some came through
that was kind of like the dealer hash
and it just got each person's handy went
through you know that guy would take the
good stuff which was not stamped I don't
know I from that 100 but there was
definitely and sorry and then there was
kind of the third grade which kind of if
you talk to some people they're like it
was all crap and that was what was
called repress and I don't know what the
heck they did to it but like that it was
all controlled I think by the bikers on
the kind of street level and somewhere
along the lines uh Bubble Man actually
saw what they did once because he was
telling me I still don't really
understand what it was but it was some
type of thing where they would just it
was cut with something and it was like a
really noticeable like the texture was
different but most of the stuff that we
were getting was kind of really high
grade or a lot of it was kind of just
like medium was pretty good and it it's
interesting now the weird thing about
legalization in Canada now is now we
actually have a really thriving import
hash seen again on the black market so
there's like websites you can go in
Canada that have like the biggest hat
import hash selection you've ever seen
and they're legit like I've tried a
bunch of them and but it's exactly the
same like people say oh it used to be so
much better back then it's literally
exactly the same as what we used to go
yeah
that's crazy so what what kind of years
did the um Afghani plants and the indoor
scene start popping off in your area
like when you notice this started to
become a normal uh happenstance thing to
get to go to someone's house and they
had to grow
uh we were pretty like on the like my
crowd was that was it was going on
before that but so I was in it's
probably like about it was ER really
early 90s like probably like
92 93 maybe 91.
um that we were literally like so I went
to kind of like the Agricultural and
agricultural University and
that was like it had some of my crowd
kind of were the first people I'm sure
other people had grown but we were
really one of the first people that
really started rocking it out and it was
so it was not common at all like I said
when I went to University that was the
year that I bought like my first grow
light which was probably like 91 or
something and
yeah like there wasn't many people doing
it and
um and it was super like we were really
some of the only people in town like
everyone in our crew kind of everyone
was like knew who we were or heard of us
because we were the guys with the
genetics and that was pretty much so it
wasn't a whole lot going around going on
I don't think it was kind of a lot of
scenes like that like I'm sure we
weren't the only people in town but
there wasn't very many
when you say the genetics what kind of
stuff were you first growing for your
indoors your first indoors
uh my first indoor was well we I sorry
our very first one we were actually
growing import because everyone had like
saved all their seeds so the first real
real grow we did was I don't even know
what it was it was literally just like
one of my roommates hit all the seeds he
saved for like 10 years we popped and
they were all
um yeah pretty equatorial and hermy and
nothing great I think we made it all
into brownies and then where our kind of
Big Break came is one of my friends was
he had gone on dead tour to the West
Coast and he ended up living on some
commune I think it was in I can't
remember if it was in Seattle area or
Portland area I believe it was down in
Portland around Oregon and uh and he's
who came he came back and kind of taught
all of our crowd to grow so that's kind
of how I I Learned was from this dude
and he had just learned from living on
this commune
um weirdly growing blueberry indicas
when that was before DJ Short was even
around and he would always talk about
blueberry Indica back then that's not
what we were going so we were so he
taught us to grow and he just had some
old stuff from like
SSC and uh the seed bank so he had it
was mostly skunk one what we were
growing and then I also did
I did a lot of skunk number one and I
also did a lot of haze just because that
happened to be the seeds we had was a
silver Pearl or not a silver Pearl
silver
Haze it was something silver pearls yeah
is that what it was I thought it was
something different but for some reason
but anyway of some kind so I I have this
like thing where I like try to uh
discover uh all the names that Scentsy
changed
right and sometimes you know it's like a
hobby or whatever and so one of the
interesting Parts is when when Scentsy
bought Neville's seed bank they wanted
to obscure how much of it was just a
direct Port over from the seed bank
itself so they ended up changing a bunch
of names right uh but the big clue
um with silver haze was that they in
Scentsy they claimed in the silver haze
advertisement in the in the book that it
won the 89 it won the overall 89
Cannabis Cup
so you go look at what won the 89
Cannabis Cup and it's silver Pearl by
Hayes from Neville
they had to put it in there I mean you
got to get the advertisement yeah yeah
so that that was actually like a really
helpful piece of information because we
actually have like uh we have photos of
the old of the old Magazine spread
and it's right there you know so it
started out as like early Pearl by Skunk
one by nl5 by Haze yeah and then it got
changed the silver I thought it was and
then I thought somebody said it was an
Ortega or something so I I was thinking
maybe that but I I originally had saw
what you're saying so so you're right
too there's this weird thing where
Neville used to call uh a maple leaf by
uh heat crossed Afghan tea to Haze as
well and he called that silver haze but
I don't think he actually ever sold it I
think he kept it private and that's one
of the ones that Shantae uses a lot now
if I'm correct is yeah
from C from seed at least yeah so he
crossed when he the first two things
that he crossed Hayes you know it was
Afghan T and nl5
and nl5 obviously got released and
became the super popular thing
um uh but anyway yeah yeah the uh the 89
Cannabis Cup winner silver Pearl by
Hayes so
that's a good one yeah it was a weird
one to start with like we start when we
had no idea it was just the only
genetics we had so we were running all
this Haze and it wasn't super long
flowering like they were they were I
think we I crossed it that was kind of
the first kind of messing with genetics
that I really did is I crossed just
because that's what we had I crossed
some of that silver haze with like a uh
skunk number one and we kind of had like
the seed line that we kept popping for a
long time just because it was the only
genetics we had and it was it was weird
because it was actually really similar
to like that sweet skunk that that I
grow now and that's partly why I grow it
it totally like reminds me of like 1993
or whatever when we were growing these
uh silver haze crosses I could see that
being really good though like a a skunk
one
silver Pearl hey like that would be
pretty legit I would think like it would
be fast flowering probably have good
butt structure good resin production
relatively fast it was like 70 days and
then we were probably picking it too
early back then it was probably 70 or 75
days I would I would think but it was it
it yielded but it wasn't yeah it
wouldn't have been like a great cash
Cropper and then the other weird one
that you never said I've never most like
I said most of the stuff you see back
then I'm like it's still pretty similar
to what stuff like there's a lot of
stuff now that's pretty similar to it
the one that I've never seen that was
like it is we used to have this Durban
which for sure it was one of my buddies
brought it back from Scentsy and uh and
it was until I've never seen anything
like that it was really like it could
quite well if I had Indica in it but it
didn't look because it kind of it was
like finished really quick and it kind
of had a short stature but it was like
this really weird like full-on sativa
but with really dark leaves and uh and
it totally had that this crazy like
Anna's taste like you hear people say
with dirt it wasn't super potent but it
was definitely like pretty unique it was
one of the better tasting weeds that
I've ever had and I've tried a bunch of
Durban since and I've never seen
anything remotely like that one yeah I
don't really see the the annisturban at
all ever and like you hear these Tales
of this this beautiful Scentsy Durban
and you just it did for some reason the
the terminal one seems to be the one
everybody kept because that just seems
to be what I run into you know yeah this
was a hundred percent just like Anna so
there was like no doubt about it but
that's what it was that's really cool I
mean it's certainly a shame
um because we're talking about things
realistically speaking that aren't that
that long ago but the nature of
prohibition kind of means that like was
you know you could have something that
was common and five or ten years go by
and all of a sudden it's just
disappeared yeah
you know
so talk about some of your early crosses
dude like you talked about the skunk one
by silver haze was there any other ones
that you were doing doing early on that
you found success in or weird stuff in
um I did we did a bunch there was one
that we can go go into a bit but
honestly like I didn't you were so I've
always been like I'm pretty big on like
not messing around unless you can pop
some decent amounts of like numbers yeah
you could never really pop that many
that much for numbers so the only one so
I did kind of so I played around early
and then for a big part of when I was
growing I just kind of got out of it
because I was so worried about plant can
all the time the last thing I wanted to
be doing is like popping males and and
stuff like that but the one so the one I
think I told you guys about where I was
joking that maybe it was the uh the
purple Urkel precursor that was the only
one that I ever did that was kind of got
pretty famous and it was uh
at the time there was no there's really
no purple weed and I had gone to
Amsterdam and brought back uh we went to
positronics and I brought back a bunch
of stuff and one of them was this strain
called Purple star purple was like yeah
yeah yeah well they don't I don't think
it's even I don't know if that's even a
thing in Harlem but they used to be they
have all these different purple strains
that were for outdoors yes
passion had and Paws he had and probably
a couple others and anyways I brought
that back and it was like actually a
pretty good yield or it didn't it wasn't
really very good quality but it looked
decent and it was like a total knob it
was like super purple yeah I had crossed
that to
uh we had like a skunk number one cross
with Hindu Kush and I crossed it to this
purple star and we actually got some
pretty nice ones that were kind of like
way way nicer than the purple star like
they were kind of indoor quality yeah
and uh and we had that and I gave my old
partner at the time he had moved out
west
um to kind of like our little humble
which is like the Kootenays which is
like Nelson BC and he had moved out
there and he before he left he grabbed a
whole crop load of those seeds and I
don't know if it was the Hindu skunk uh
purple star or if it was that I think it
was actually that it was mixed with that
crossed with a an aurora Indica which
was a Northern Lights during the Posse
pad anyways he popped like quite a lot
like he popped like a hundred or two of
those and got this one that they called
they just called it papaya and it was
like this really nice uh purple it was
kind of like checkerboard purple pattern
and these guys were like big they were
like Ballers like so they were doing
they were in like the export crowd and
uh and that clone just totally blew up
um and for a while so in BC there's kind
of like everyone always talked whenever
most people that you hear talk they're
always talking about like Coastal BC
like Vancouver area yeah if you go
Inland with 10 hours there's this is
where the Kootenays are and that's where
our real like
that's where the real players
go so for a while for like a couple of
years there was a that was like one of
the most popular clones being grown
there was this papaya thing and that's
why I was uh
joking because when when Nazo was saying
they used to call Oracle uh the Barney
and that's what the buyers used to call
this stuff was the Barney but it was
probably seven years ago what years was
that
would have been like
I would think it was probably like late
like late 90s like somewhere between
like 98 and 2000 probably
because the interesting part about the
um you know a lot of the purple cuts
that became famous uh in Northern
California and kind of in our scene is
that there's a lot of like people that
claim things to you know about them but
there's very little like uh verifiable
fact yeah right
um which is unusual for a strain strains
that got that famous to stay that
obscure for that long
um and there's a lot of competing things
and there's there's actually a guy in
Mendo I won't mention his name but there
was a there was kind of a kooky guy in
Mendo who claims uh that he went up to
BC uh and ended up uh smuggling clones
back taped to his thigh uh in cigar in
cigar cases like in cigar you know like
cigars like the tubes yeah the tubes
um and he taped him to his thigh this is
pre when pre before Osama ruined flying
yeah
um you know when uh you know when
airport security got a lot rougher after
2001.
um but pre to that uh it was a lot
looser
and he he swears to God that he brought
these clones from uh from BC uh down to
Mendo
um just just to be super clear I'm not
making any claims to purple Urkel and
just joking no I get it no believe me
well that's the thing right is that
there are people that will tell you with
absolute certainty that this is what it
is yeah and then you start poking around
in it and if you and there's holes and
this and that
um it's one of the few things that that
with purple Urkel with Grape Ape with uh
lavender and things like that there
really isn't a settled story
yeah that everyone believes there's some
competing stories and there's ones that
like we're pretty sure aren't true
um but you know for for as famous as it
was and as big of an issue as it was in
California for a while
um most of those most of not all but
most of those purple cuts the origins
are still kind of a mystery it was it's
cool that you mentioned purple star
um purple star is actually one of the
baselines of purples for for purple
number one for Shaman for a lot of the
Dutch purples all came from that purple
is it related to Viking
I think I I think they all probably came
from Viking because I think Viking kind
of predates those and they were all
pretty I think they were definitely
related because we get that cream sodica
you hear about it yeah it was totally
out of that same family
um they just you look at me like that's
one of those old crappy purple Dutch
outdoor screams positronics about a year
and a half ago they they went into their
their uh Library uh mom seeds their
their parent seeds and whatnot and they
were kind enough to take me out the
parentage of purple star or whatever
they used to make it and they sent me
the seats but they disappeared on the
way here I was so bummed because I was
like I finally get to look at the
parents of purple star like most people
wouldn't be that stoked about it because
it's kind of goofy and you know it would
be it's interesting to me it would be
really funny honestly if if there's an
element of that story is true because
um you know coming being in California
uh when this is fast forward a bit so we
can go back after but one of the things
that really made the purple craze in
like
030405 really take off
was that California was getting flooded
by
uh you know beat by Canadian indoor yeah
and once Brokers learned that the
Canadian indoor was so much cheaper than
California homegrown
they started buying it and trying to
pass it off as California homegrown and
making massive margins and a lot of it
was pretty Mitzi you know it was just it
wasn't flushed right it was grown with
too high EC it was in their best down
here yeah well and you know it was it
was also it was sealed in a in a vacuum
sealer you know so it kind of fermented
a little bit like in in transport not
that there wasn't some good stuff coming
down but a lot of it was bad and one of
the things in California especially in
the bay that started the purple craze
was that the purple wasn't Canadian
like it was homegrown
you know and you knew it was from
California because people were getting
bumped by buying weed for 4 400 that was
Canadian that these guys were buying for
two grand yeah and making the difference
you know so it was like that was one of
the things that started the purple craze
uh in NorCal was uh there wasn't any BC
coming down that was purple at the time
and so it was like a it was marketing
yeah it was early marketing
honestly and and 215 it opened up in
California enough that once it got into
the clubs and once you know popularity
spiked then it just was rolling and it
was a it was a marketable thing
I think the beasters guys got a little
bit of a bad rap just for you know that
all the good stuff that went down just
got called and passed humble and nobody
questions and all the crap stuff this
guy oh this beasters so and I think they
did so they definitely did not
disappearing there was a lot of beasters
got shut down I think we actually
probably kept the worst beasters up here
because if you go the kind of backstory
of like the commercial Market here was
always this cut called M39 which is like
yeah I can't imagine anybody ever
exported that but maybe they did and it
was like this it was probably just M39
from SSC which I think was just skunk NL
and it was just it was rock hard
orange like like they probably literally
cut them at 39 days or something and I
mean it was still to this day the worst
weed I've ever smoked everything you
know you know what's so funny about this
fan is that these days
um people most people who smoke weren't
around back then and so there are a
bunch of people that are you know there
are some people out there that are
they're touting that they have M39
red dog's one who's bringing back to M39
yeah and and you know there's an aspect
of it because most people all they
remember is the name
yeah you know
all they remember is the name one thing
I wanted to ask you before I forgot is
that yeah
um when you were on uh you know
before I before you and I had even
chatted you had posted this picture uh
on your IG of this old Northern Lights
clone
uh yeah that was the first one I ever
posted on IG yeah and I was wondering
and that to me
um I would just want you know if you
could expound on that cutting a little
bit because I remember it where you were
like oh you know this is from the late
80s it it descends from the seed bank
era we lost it but it was a staple for
you know 20 plus years yeah that was the
closest thing in my career that was I
would consider like a long like our
cruise like I said it was pretty rough
so people didn't really keep Cuts around
and they were all chasing most of my I
was never like super big into the
commercial scene but a lot of my friends
were like big like they were heavily
into the commercial scene so they were
chasing just no different than today
everyone's chasing whatever the newest
gelato cross is or something they were
chasing whatever was hypey so they never
kept anything and this and that specific
NL clone was around our crew for a long
time and it originally came from that
same guy I was talking about before the
papaya clone came I mean it's kind of
like my original part partner when we
were younger like we got started
together we're still good friends today
and he was always like in the thick of
things so that was he was kind of one of
my kind of main connections because he
hung out with some people I had zero
interest in hanging out with but they
always had good genetics and stuff and
he had brought it back out from uh
Nelson
um and they did they had gotten it there
from one of my friends dads who lives
just outside of Vancouver a place called
Squamish and yeah that one we could
definitely Trace back because it was
literally like I know the guy it came
from and it was like his dad and it was
from whatever like I don't remember 87
or something like that it was right
around like that time period and that
one was totally it looked just like a
lot of the NLS that we've grown but it
totally had a completely different terp
profile and was way way Frost here like
that was the first plan I'd ever seen
that had like if you grew it right that
picture doesn't probably do it justice
if you grew it right it was one of those
ones that had kind of like remember on
the white widows where the resin went
like right to the end of like the Sugar
Leaf like or even hard on the fan it did
that and it was uh just crazy Terps like
I remember the one guy uh one of my
friends that used to move a lot of it
and you like it would just he used to
keep it in his freezer and you'd crack
the freezer and just like his whole
house would smell and I've it was a
really unique terp profile that I
honestly can't even put a finger on I
kind of wonder whether it's maybe when
um Neville talks about those Juniper
flavors it was maybe that but it was
like it was a weird like kind of outer
Spacey type of uh flavor that I've never
really had since and but that one was
definitely like around our crowd for a
long time because I remember like not
keeping it and then being man I really
want that or someone to be asking for it
and I'd go find it and I could always
like a friend of a friend's brother had
that we just called it Dan L clone and
it made ridiculous hash and it made
ridiculous amounts of hash because it
was kind of pretty leafy so you got a
lot of trim but I remember just pulling
like I can't remember what the ratio was
but just giant hunks of hash off that
all the time
I was trying I'm always in picture of it
for so everybody can see it but I'm
always interested in that kind of stuff
because we have so few pictures that
survive of a lot of those original
strains
um and especially like you know ones
that people found in those lines
um and some lines we have a few pictures
and other lines you know it's kind of a
mystery
um and I have it saved just because you
know what it reminds me of and it's not
exact because I know it's a hybrid but
the way that it's super Frosty and the
way that the top crowns it kind of
reminded me of Bubba
yeah I find all the NLS remind me of
Bubba like especially so were the other
ones that we had there it is right there
yeah there you go yeah perfect yeah that
that just reminds me not exactly because
bub is a hybrid or whatever but like it
just reminds me of like that especially
when Neville would talk about like a
single Cola kind of small you know like
almost yellowish at times very resinous
uh short Afghan
um it really it really matches up well
with his description of what his NL was
yeah it might even grow slower than
Bubba it was a really super it was the
squattest plant I've ever grown and I
think because it was so old it had
really lost a lot of vigor but it was
brutal and I remember at the time we had
like this really strong plant count so
this was kind of late when I was growing
it and I used to grow it as trees into
like a vertical scrog setup there were
six feet so six feet tall trees into
like a scrog and it was just took for
freaking ever to to get it up to size
and I actually used to I used to
actually spray it with a really low
doses of gibberellic acid just to make
the internet like during the during the
veg time yeah that's an old trick for
for squatty ones that's cool
so what kind of chirp profile did you
say it had like honestly
I could I it doesn't compare to anything
I've tried now like I would say it was
no stronger like it was similar to a lot
of the modern stuff but I mean it's not
in flavor but in like strength of Terps
so it probably had you know probably at
least three percent Terps which was on
but if you compare it to what was going
around back then like that was it was
totally another level than most stuff
going around
it was a weird it almost had a little
bit of a it was really hashy but it
really had kind of like there was some
fruit like almost like a grapey
tone to it it was just it was one that I
it's kind of like I would it was just
really hard to describe it was kind of
like oh gee there's a lot of stuff weird
stuff
um going in there but that's honestly
when I looked back that's one of the few
that I'm like oh that would that one
would still be cool to have and it would
be novel now that it's something that
nobody else
um nobody else has I don't think it was
necessarily better than anything that's
around now but it would hold its it
would still hold it hold its weight
compared to like modern stuff which I
would say most of the stuff from that
era definitely wouldn't
yeah I mean what what year did it end up
uh kind of fading out and going missing
uh it would have been the exact one if
you look at when Stephen Harper became
prime minister of Canada I was the last
guy holding it and I got rid of it when
he came in because he put all these
crazy mandatory minimums and I couldn't
hold my uh cuttings I'm thinking it was
probably like
2003 or something like that 2004.
yeah they had it literally down to I
think you're gonna go to jail for five
years for five plants or something
mandatory minimum so I that was a time
when I was like okay like breeding and
keeping lots of mothers kind of went out
the uh window under under that dude
and since we're uh since we're on that
that sort of era subject I have another
uh IG post you made that I wanted to
chat about which was um I went out to
the Cannabis cups in the late 90s a few
times
um and one of the things I brought back
which I wish I still had seeds of was
the first year that they released
Neville's Haze
um and I think it's actually one of the
first things you and I chatted about uh
was you posted these pictures of some
old Neville's Hayes Groves
uh and I think you got that you got that
Neville's Haze right around that same
era right the late 90s
uh it was I think it was two thousand so
it wasn't right when they it was the
first round of seeds that I garbage had
been around for a little bit
um
but I I remember exactly when it was
because it was uh I'm pretty sure it was
right around it was like 99 or 2000 and
I think it got released in 98 so that's
basically like the very first era of it
yeah
yeah it was when I first decided I kind
of got out of like the whatever I was
just branched out and was like you know
what I'm just gonna try growing some
different stuff and I don't really care
whatever if it looks nice and stuff so I
just started playing around with a lot
of different plants and and that was one
so I started doing some hazes and that
was uh one of the ones I think actually
how we started talking was actually
Ortega because I threw out a lot of that
too Maple Leaf Indica
um as well but um
yeah that Novelties was that was the
Learning lesson but that was pretty uh I
grew up yeah I think I had like I think
I had three packs of that and I grew
them uh grew them all that I actually
got some most of it was pretty jungly
weed but I mean it was crazy
strong right just like the extracts and
that stuff were just scary and yeah
that's the picture right there
um
but I actually one of the cooler plants
I've ever grown came out of that pack it
was one that looked full-on like City
like really Haze structure and the buds
were little were dead on like nl5
miniature little pine cone buds but they
were literally like half a centimeter
long kind of like little sativa buds but
they were rock hard little Indica things
and they were literally like look like
little candies or something it was still
one of the most bizarre hybrid
Expressions I've ever seen it tasted
like had that kind of incensey taste it
definitely leaned more towards the nl5
but it was a cool uh cool plant yeah one
of the things one of the things I liked
about your description of it was I think
you nicknamed one of those cuts party
Slayer because the high made so many
people uncomfortable it would like kill
the vibe when you brought it yeah so we
had at the time there was one of my
friends was had that he lived just kind
of an hour or so north of Toronto and in
this kind of pretty small town it was
like no it's tiny it's like probably 30
000. and he used to sell most of the
weed to like the 20 something year olds
crowd there and we had a batch of we
just ended up having two we were just
growing it for like hobby stuff and we
ended up having too much every once in a
while so so some of this Neville's Haze
would end up going into like the
commercial Market with no there was no
names back then right so we'd just sell
this crappy looking weed
and my buddy would would uh sell it in
and everyone I think I think we're
having
all right which is I I don't remember
the story but it was it looked like crap
and everyone was like thinking it was
swag and uh
yeah they would all puff that stuff and
that was no we had a bad batch that
didn't burn well so they were all like
really huffing on it trying to get the
thing to burn properly and then they and
there's no idea and you know it's got
like a 20 minute creep on it so they
would all be trying to you know puff him
furiously on this doobie to try and get
it to burn properly and uh
I think the nutrients has gotten mixed
up because the you know we weren't used
to Growing like 16 weeks of Tevas and
stuff and uh and then everyone would get
like super super high and uh and then
the whole party would end and that was
it became like legend for like a year or
so there was all this level so he's
gonna dumped into this so it was like
they were literally that dude you used
to sell like M39 which you could
basically not get high off of a little
bit of that NL and then this the no burn
the no burn uh
yeah you were telling me a story too I
think about like your friends that were
in construction and they got too high to
even come off the roof oh yeah yeah so I
used to have this one friend who's was
one of the heaviest uh smokers you'll
ever meet and he always used to like uh
you know you got like a super killer
weed and most people backward be like
holy cow like that was so good and you
could never phase dawn like Dawn was
just like you could give him like the
you know that bubble hash from that
crazy Northern Lights clone I gave him
one points thinking this is going to
blow him away and you just like did this
massive like dab of it and was just like
so it's okay like nothing would phase
this dude and uh him and one of his
buddies had a roofing company and they I
hadn't seen him for like a year or so I
had moved away from town and uh I needed
a new roof on my house so and I had this
one like a really steep roof that was a
little treacherous to be walking around
and before they went on to redo the roof
he's like you got any weed so I had this
uh Neville's Haze it was Neville's Haze
mixed with Neville's Hayes hash and it
was like really strong this joint I
probably did it purposely really strong
just to try and phase Dawn and uh they
smoked it wasn't even that big of a
joint they smoked this thing and I just
thought nothing because nothing ever
phased this dude and then I was like
where are those dudes like they've been
up there for so long so I yelled up and
they like stuck their head over the roof
and they're like yeah we just got to sit
it out up here for a while man
they were up there for hours just
tripping on this Neville's Hayes hatch
I mean I I literally I have this clear
memory of smoking what I would classify
as a Pinner
of Neville's Haze uh when I first tried
it with two other people so I probably
only got three or four Good Hits off it
before it was gone
and I have this clear memory in
Amsterdam of like walking out of dude's
house and like gripping the railing for
the six steps down to the road like
gripping it with my life because I
didn't want to fall
you know and like it messed with my
equilibrium and like I was soaring high
and it hit me in such an unusual way I
could absolutely see like being like I
am not [ __ ] with that ladder at all
yeah like there is no ladder in my
future for a while I sit here where I'm
at I'm gonna sit where I'm at and I'm
gonna wait until the ladder makes sense
because I have this memory of like like
being like I can't go down these steps
without
this railing without assistance yeah
like I needed and I was like you know I
don't know 23 or something like that and
it was totally nice weather they were
dry steps and I was like I wanted to
make sure that I had a center when I
walked down them yeah so it was
definitely like the extract of so Hayes
is like I always find he's like you can
smoke if you smoke regularly like you
smoke I find most people you just get
hit every once in a while you can smoke
Haze and it's like just because I don't
think it's super strong it just but it's
when you just smoke a little bit too
much which is a lot easier when you're
smoking like a hash joint or something
and it just you know creeps up on you
and all of a sudden you're taking the
you know the night bus downtown
um but I have all the time I have people
that smoke all the time that I'll give
like that sweet skunk to and it doesn't
look that great and they're used to
smoking cookies and a lot of them have
just never even smoked like proper Haze
and uh you always hear kind of similar
stories where somebody Just Smokes every
day was like what the heck was
because they just got caught sideways by
it maybe science will eventually tell
you but if you you can be like uh very
used to smoking a lot of like what we
would consider high-end strains these
days like chems and Bubbas and you know
and and ogs and different things and
there's an aspect to hazes where they
just kind of hit you a bit sometimes
like you're a newbie and you don't have
a tolerance
yeah no for sure it's nothing that I I
generally
I maybe smoke a bit more now but I
remember back then I definitely couldn't
smoke uh hazes every day like I remember
thinking I was like this you know weed
snobbling like oh only like hazes is the
best but if you looked at my jars the
devil's sat there for a long period of
time and the lights like went down real
quick so it was always more it was more
like a mild psychedelic for me like
smoking uh Neville
it could get in the way of your day
yep for sure you know you could you know
uh most weed I can smoke and it enhances
my day but you know there's some wheat
and Haze is one of them that can alter
your day and send you on a completely
different path than you were on before
it's crazy when you get not so or Tom
Hill talking Hayes you could get them
doing this for hours at a time waxing
poetic endlessly about Haze I mean the
real life change I'll say this right so
that at that point I've been going to
Amsterdam for four or five years at that
point uh generally at least once or
twice a year and most of the stuff that
I got was not that great I went through
a lot of stuff and I tossed a lot of
stuff some of the hybrids I made with
some of the American stuff I had ended
up much better and I kind of had this
opinion that you know uh what we had was
clearly Superior
uh and then uh you know those hazes some
of those Haze hybrids that they have
over there that was the first thing
where all of a sudden I was like maybe
these Old-Timers Tales of like soaring
psychedelic Colombian that you get
tracers in your vision and you're giggly
and you have a hard time walking which I
kind of thought was [ __ ] up till
that point
um all of a sudden I was like oh it's
real
it might be rare
you know but it's real I've literally
chased that High ever since I've had it
you know the first time experiencing
that I think that's common with a lot of
people you know and so psychedelic
experience and that well some for some
people too it makes them want to crawl
out of their skin yeah yeah like it's
not it it it's it's almost like a
disassociative very uncomfortable like
not used to it type of type of high so
it's it's interesting in that regarding
experience started out with the roller
coaster paranoia and by the end of the
high is when the visual elements were
started turning into a clear-headed
where you could see tracers that that is
just a whole nother experience uh so
that's just what that's that's why it
sticks with me because like like uh like
direwolf was saying like he's got an
unflappable buddy that like would would
almost never give praise and then the
guy smokes a joint and doesn't want to
use a ladder for hours I could honestly
say he's never given praise ever except
for the Neville's days that's the only
time I've ever seen anything
that's funny
yeah so that I always like that story
you know because he was like oh no
no no no ladder I'm just gonna sit right
here while I'm safe
so one thing that didn't make it over
into the US a lot that I that I
personally am always interested about
whenever I have anyone any of my
Canadian friends I like talking about a
little bit
are the hash plants that made their way
through uh Canada like the Renee the
champagne
there were some other biker ones if I
remember correctly uh that were popular
do you have much experience with those
uh not a ton so I actually I actually
just put coincidence just picked up the
Renee cut off a friend of mine last week
but I've never actually tried it I've
heard pretty mixed reviews on that but
it's it's got to be one of the that's I
was just talking to my friend about that
when I got those like it's been around
since at least like 93 or something like
that so people like not a lot of stuff
that gets held around that long but
there's definitely a lot of people like
my friends like I didn't think it was
that good I heard from Arrow say he
didn't think it was that good I don't
know I never tried it the other ones
were kind of so that was basically from
what I can tell yeah that was like a
group of bikers and those were kind of
their Elite biker cats
um like for sure so the story is and
again all this gets highly this is
reefer man enters the picture so stuff
gets a little uh it's hard to it's hard
to separate facts from fiction because
you're very Adept at mixing the that's
what I always dislike about people like
reefer man is he actually has a ton of
great information oh it's just mixes
mixes it with a ton of [ __ ] so you
never know what's real so he any so
anyways the story that he has which
seems to kind of play out is there's
kind of like a group of bikers
um out on Vancouver Island that we're
doing a lot of of runs back then from
seed and the story is that it was import
it was seed from import which I find
hard to Envision but I guess maybe I've
heard a bunch of different stories but
definitely I think they all for sure
came out of like kind of either
Vancouver Island or north of Vancouver
or somewhere on Coastal BC and I think
almost all of those came from the same
group there was like champagne that's
when the ancestors of like pink Kush
which was like King uh Queen there was
one called Jiffy pot maybe even that God
bud I think they all came out of the
same group
um and yeah like champagne I only saw it
and I've never grown it I've had it in
flower form a couple times and it was
really early like I remember like it was
like 93 or something like that when I
went through and it was there was
nothing else like it like it was super
high-end yeah for the time I don't think
it's anything like super special it's
just like a really nice hash plant
but a lot of the Canadian ones are kind
of based around those that kind of group
like if you look at like the Special K
pink Kush
King's cross it used to be
um there's a bunch of them that all
they're kind of similar and it's kind of
got a little bit obscured because what
reefer man did is he CR he took that
King cut which was one of the little
legit Emoji like original ones yeah and
he crossed it with a whole bunch of
different stuff so he crossed it with
like a lot of like modern U.S stuff
don't hold me to this but I think it was
like MK officer which is like an OG G13
cross he crossed it with I think uh San
Fernando Valley OG seed line and a few
other things and if you look at it now
it's like I don't know is it real so
what goes around is so pink Kush
everyone is like oh that's the old King
cut but yeah I don't think it's actually
necessarily the king cut it's like it's
crosses with the old King cut to Modern
cush varieties and if I had to leave
bets it's probably leans heavier towards
like
modern Kush varieties than the king but
I don't know I've never grown the
original one but uh they were definitely
some of the seeds the king seeds and I
think uh when I was going to do a collab
with why yeast and compound before I
knew much about uh compound he ended up
with them so somewhere there are King
seeds still in existence don't know if
they're a cross though The White Buffalo
guys still definitely hold it like I've
tried to fill out hybrids out of it um
they definitely have a lot of those old
Cuts still like they definitely have the
king but I know they've said they've
told me or said to my buddy that uh
they're like the pink Kush that goes
around now doesn't look anything like
the king that they hold and I mean he
used to be partners with reframes I'm
sure he has the original King oh yeah
I'm sure yeah he did a lot of that early
work for reefer man butterscotch
Hawaiian which I I ended up liking a lot
um I know reefer man always talked it
down but I loved it
did you ever get to try that one over
there
I generally if I did not I generally
avoided anything to do with reefer man
I'm sure he had good stuff he's just one
of those people that just I just I just
his his Aura just passes through
anything he touches for me and I just
don't want anything to do with it I can
appreciate that for sure like you know
there's a lot of lines like that that I
didn't touch because of just the juju
associated with it you know you never
know some people have bad juju that just
flows through everything they touch I
mean you know it's an issue in cannabis
because a lot of the people that end up
doing a lot of work uh you start digging
into them and you're like oh man like we
really attract our community attracts a
lot of quirky
and some of that quirky is just quirky
and some of that quirky is like you're
like oh man yeah that's not that cool uh
depending on your perspective
um but it uh you know one of the things
direwolf that like I don't know if you
talked about this on the the thing you
just did but Matt and I we sort of had
this this gig where we were doing like
sort of like the histories of the seed
banks and stuff
and we were gonna do some stuff on
Canada and we ended up just not doing it
because we both realized that neither
one of us had enough of a base of actual
information in history to like do it any
justice you know
um the characters involved all that I
mean Canada is definitely sort of what I
consider to be like the third wave of
seed banks
um you know uh not not just in terms of
like seed Brokers
um but you know just whole groups of
people all of a sudden coming up with
um you know seed banks themselves and
blends of their own stuff and blends of
European stuff and there was a lot of
that around for a while it almost it was
dominated
for a while it did dominate for a while
for sure you know Federation
uh you know reefer man uh was it Joey
you know the islands
um there was a lot there was a lot of
yeah people up there the one thing I
would say about that that I think gets a
little bit skewed and not it's not
necessarily a bad way but although I
would say
all pretty much entirely the history of
kind of what was coming out of cannabis
comes from a handful of people it comes
from Chimera breeder Steve red from
Legends and reefer man yeah and maybe
I'm maybe mixing a couple but I mean
keep in mind those guys minus the reefer
man like red Chimera breeder Steve they
are all from like the same crew so what
they're talking about when they talk
about all this stuff I'm like that
wasn't what was they you know you listen
to them and you're like everyone was
growing you know sweet tooth and
whatever they were doing Legends
ultimate indica and I'm like in my crowd
and I said some of my friends were
pretty big rollers
they weren't the only people that I was
the only one that knew anything about
that and I learned about it from the
internet not from what was going on in
Canada and I think that gets a little
bit skewed where I think they definitely
were like a representative of what was
going on but it that was definitely it
was definitely far more diverse than it
sounds coming from those guys and I'm
not saying they're being self-serving it
or anything I don't think they are I
just think they're just telling their
story and yeah it was a small segment of
what was going on and the other big
thing there like I said is that divide
where they're all talking about what
kind of was going on in Lower Mainland
BC which is like the Vancouver area or
also Vancouver Island where that other
kind of can which there is definitely a
lot of growing there that's where the
most of the population is but that
Kootenai Nelson area has always been
like the real bread and butter of like
the that's our humble and uh and what
was going on there still to this day
whatever's going like you go like on the
coast it's all like everyone's growing
pink Kush pink cushions been dominating
that scene for like a decade and then
you go to the Kootenays nobody grows
pink Kush they're all growing whatever
something totally different like it's a
tote and that breeder Steve Camara crowd
was really like a coast a Vancouver kind
of based group and then so there's other
groups um that were totally different
they were based out of the cooties but
if you go back to those you're talking
about all those can most of those I
think pretty much all those Canadian
seed companies they were all
from Mark Emery like yeah they were all
getting offered through him yeah
yeah and I think there's definitely like
I think that Federation Next Generation
the Federation turned into next
generation and that next Generation
guy's still around I've never met him
but I think that guy gets
underrepresented and like he's still
like he was one of the most of those
Romulan genetics I would I would argue
all of the Ronald and genetics going
around in the U.S probably came from
Next Generation and Federation seeds
but a lot of those ones that went
through Emery were kind of just like not
I mean that's how those guys got started
it was like it was just knock offs of
knockoffs like yep I think they
basically started as they were working
with breeder Steve and and with a bunch
of reader Steve genetics so they started
I don't know what the story was but uh
that's definitely Federation had a lot
it was a lot of like grapefruit and
sweet skunk and the stuff that Steve was
working with I definitely but I think
they did some real work and they brought
some other stuff like they were doing
UBC chemo which is kind of a unique one
and there's some other ones like Berlin
and some like kind of more BC Centric
ones I'm trying to think who the other
ones Jordan of the island is still
around I've never heard do you remember
BC do you remember a company called BC
grown
uh I do not it was like I remember that
one um it was early early to mid 2000s
it was a dude named Jordan who ran it
and I've always tried to figure out if
that was Jordan from the same person
yeah because it was it was a lot of the
same stuff a lot of the Gaga and stuff
like that because I just you know I I I
come from an era where like uh you know
basically like all those waves
you know um I can't tell you how many
times I read Neville's catalogs or
senses catalogs or the Dutch catalogs or
all the stuff in cannabis culture you
know all the various stuff that Mark
Emery would sell from the various seed
companies and their descriptions
um because there wasn't obviously like
there wasn't there wasn't internet you
know so much and there wasn't like a
vibrant clone trading community and it
was all very tight in your circles and
so if you wanted stuff outside your
circle you would peruse the seed lists
and see what sounded cool
yeah for sure and I the one thing I will
say that in my opinion came out of that
scene I I couldn't prove it but I would
lay bats that it did was
um the auto I honestly think the auto
flowers all came out of Canadian
genetics so if you look at the sequence
of events this is one that uh maybe a
little bit biased too because I was kind
of close to a lot of parts of it but
there was originally there was that much
which you guys probably heard that
Mighty Mite strain was kind of oh yeah
and mighty might was um it came from one
of the gulf Islands which is one of the
little Islands between between just off
the coast of BC it was kind of that area
had a lot of like draft Dodgers and like
kind of Dropout people would kind of go
live on those islands and it is actually
a guy that I know his dad is group that
was growing that and who knows if if
what it actually was it supposedly like
a Himalayan and it's like this really
it's like got a really big really Indica
really strong central Cola and some of
the fenos would go off automatically and
if you traced by in Canada anyways if
you trace back pretty much every time
somebody's like talking about some super
early strain most of them come back to
my email you can just it's one of those
ones you can just look at it you're like
that's not right you might end it I had
a friend of mine sent me a picture a
couple years ago he's like some
acclimated Thai strain he had he's been
passed down to the generations
um but my uh my old partner used to do a
lot of uh so kind of I think where that
got popularized is
um in Mark Emery was sound on some seeds
of it and at the time
my well partner was doing these crazy
grows of it they had up in Northern
Ontario they were like living up in this
Cottage and they had and so that was
back then you could sell outdoor really
easily and uh they were doing these
crazy outdoors in these swamps and uh
and it was all it was kind of like I
almost describe it as a land race so
they were kind of back and forth between
that Nelson area and BC so they'd kind
of have like the best outdoor stuff that
was going around Nelson and they were
crossing it all with their own stuff
which was all pretty Mighty might and it
would go off really early like you'd
start harvesting in like July and uh
not all of it but it was like it was
kind of like a land race so they would
they would pop like you know 1500 or 2
000 seats and grow them out in all these
swamps all over the place and uh and
they basically start harvesting like
July the first ones would come and
they'd go all the way into like the
first week of October it was just like
very that's why I kind of call it it's
like a Canadian land race because it was
just pretty diverse and some of them
were really good and you could never get
away with it then because you sell bags
of it I remember one of my buddies used
to wholesale bags and he's like I can't
take any more of this stuff he's like
one guy tells me how great it is and the
next guy's telling me it like doesn't do
anything and it was because it was all
from seed and some of it was the
Autoflower stuff that wasn't that strong
but that anyway so at the time that was
when I was writing for uh uh cannabis
called so Mark Emery's magazine I was
writing for the Cannabis Culture
magazine and I wrote an article about
Auto flowers because at the time I found
it frustrating because there was
definitely like some not like super good
autoflowers but like decent quality like
flour for the time like you could sell
it sale no problem and so I wrote an
article about uh Auto flowers and it
focused a lot on Mighty might and at the
time there was literally not a single
Autoflower on the market other than a
few of those Mighty Mites coming out of
Markham recedes like other than that I
don't think a single thing had been
released since Neville released those
first ones like back in the 80s well I
guess sorry stencies still would have
had that their crappy whatever it was
called that nobody bought
yeah ruderalis skunk and Rooter Alice
and out and I was kind of frustrated
because I was like no like this is
actually has potential the Autoflower
stuff so I wrote that vertical about it
and it was like within a year that all
of a sudden you started that was kind of
when I think the low rider came off
and then and then Europe all started
doing Auto flowers and then I don't ever
bother with them but they yeah they all
it became a big thing I honestly think I
lay back if you trace that back whether
it came from mighty might or something
else I would lay bats that came out of
Canadian genetics because we are the
only people really doing it much back
then maybe I'm wrong but I I'm pretty
certain that the timing all made sense
what didn't make sense to me was if I
remember correctly lowrider the dude a
joint doctor or whoever was the one that
was originally saying they bred it they
said it was from a Mexican just random
Mexican it's like I don't know you know
like because my I remember growing early
sativa from Canadian bread seeds and
there were a few other ones and they
were definitely they definitely had some
good autoflowering traits back then and
there wasn't a lot being marketed at the
time for autoflowering one thing that's
been pretty consistent in weed is
obscuring the origin of where your stuff
came from for a variety for a certain
you know
um
that's one of the more disappointing
things of wheat is when I've kind of
like I travel a lot through Canada so I
kind of
um like just for work I've always
traveled a lot and I've so I just know a
lot of different people and I've always
kind of chased genetics a little bit and
whatever just when you and when you dig
into pretty much everything you're just
like oh it's just like another seed bank
strain or it's just yeah renamed M39 or
like you there's so I can literally
count on like one hand how many like
Elite things or stuff that have a great
story that when you dig into them aren't
are anything actual unusual
yeah that's that's typically it you know
um and especially once you get past a
certain point in the Years too it gets
much worse you know when you're starting
to realize that you're buying everything
comes from one Spanish Seed Company
During certain years you know that if
you're buying Dutch stuff and it it did
take a big change
um and it's gotten much worse over the
years so you know I guess that's why a
lot of us are still chasing some of
these old ones it's not necessarily
because we think they're more dank but
the the genetic diversity is a lot
better than just gelato times gelato or
cookies times cookies times cookies not
cookies or whatever time to get back
yeah for sure
and there was definitely some stuff when
I think back that this was really unique
compared to what's around whether people
would actually care that much
these days I don't know but it was
definitely
um unique
yeah I think I really don't it's a place
pardon me unique definitely has a place
now I think
um at least among some circles that are
left
when I think of what's actually that
I've tried That's Unique over the years
it's always and I'm not like a big
sativa you know dude but it's usually
sativa stuff it's like more equatorial
stuff that's kind of distinct like when
I think back to like growing up it was
like the Jamaican was kind of the
Jamaican import we'd always get was
definitely like pretty unique
um
okay but this is kind of stuff like that
it's like I think a lot of the cushes
and indicas are pretty similar I I don't
know I'm certainly somewhere in
Afghanistan there's some different stuff
but everything I've really tried in that
realm all seems pretty similar
so uh in that regard I mean and maybe
some of that too is just because sativas
are the rarest thing to get worked uh
because indicas are definitely like
easier to grow and they're shorter and
they're thicker and they yield more and
they're more prone for INS
um so they kind of a lot of sativas sort
of missed like this inbreeding era of
the last 20 plus years I think you know
they weren't they weren't as as big of a
proponent of all that
where yeah it's it's pretty noticeable I
have one of my best friends grows at it
I would argue probably more sativas than
almost anyone like in North America like
he's just a hobby yeah but he's just
always like he pops I bet he probably
pops like a couple of thousand seeds a
year of all like land race or
whatever all the ties so I try a lot of
stuff from him and it's really
noticeable it's just how like unimproved
it is like it's just like it a lot of it
I'm like oh that totally has like
potential but it's just like when you
really think of like it's just really
unworked and it's just like doesn't have
like it's just there's a lot of things
missing and you're like well man if
somebody worked on this for 30 years
which is Big you know it's at least that
what a lot of those cushions have been
worked on who knows what crazy stuff
they can come out of them but I just
find it's pretty unworked because I try
a lot of stuff from him and not very
much of it is very appealing
yeah cannabis doesn't breed itself
naturally towards like getting humans
High the best as we've seen you know it
tends to like try to breed itself
towards happiness uh so it makes a lot
of sense and I think a lot you know
there's a there's a big land race
heirloom collection Community you'll see
it on IG you know like the uh people
offering you know strains directly from
Afghanistan and Pakistan and and that's
great but I I don't know that the the
larger community in general understands
what getting into land races and
heirloom lines truly means and the kind
of space you need to to truly pick
something wonderful out that that many
people would enjoy you know it's it's a
much bigger process
younger people don't get is like I'm
like I've grown up some land races but
even like if you look back to book stuff
um
to be around even if it's been to
decayed like if you go back to a lot of
the seats
horrible Keepers out of packs like yeah
there was some great stuff that came out
of that but the consistency these days
like you can buy most of the modern
stuff like you could buy a pack of
almost anything I'd find like something
great out of 10 seeds and I think that
was not the case back a long time you
know in pretty recent history even when
I go through that that Suites gun clone
that I grow out a lot of and uh that was
basically like I'm pretty sure it's just
a plain old NL AC and if you pop like
hybrids of that and you see like a lot
of like the old nl5 Expressions which
everyone always talks with how great
they are I mean they were horrible they
were super betrayed as susceptible
um it definitely has some nice stuff in
there but I'm like I don't remember like
the last time I popped like a pack of
modern seeds and got something like
rotted out on the you know on the stem
under normal grow room conditions but
that was pretty common back then yeah oh
I definitely think that uh I talk about
it quite a bit like the difference
between like a a low
oh can you hear Francis
no it's all Frozen okay so we'll uh
probably pause it for a second until he
comes back since he's in the middle of
something and then I'll cut it there he
is my connection has been cutting in and
out Strangely I don't know what to do
okay leave a few seconds before you jump
back in so I can edit it one two three
so I I've definitely noticed that like a
lot of the original strains you could
find real gems in it but it did take a
lot of hunting and a lot of work and I'm
not sure that like the modern seed
poppers would be comfortable going
through stuff that had so much junk and
mids
I mean why would they find the right
thing yeah you don't have to spend that
time or space anymore to find something
that that fills that modern market like
that that palette so it's it's it's a
lot to go out of ask someone to go out
of their way to do these massive pops it
costs money time and space
and it's harder to sell now like back
then you remember they could sell
whatever whatever you popped out of that
seed pack someone was lined up to buy it
I mean I wouldn't want to try to be
moving some of that stuff these days
like it's I don't even know what you're
doing to make extracts I guess but
brownies and extracts
so now that we're getting into we talked
a little bit about botrytus on Buds and
and some of the stuff there
one of your Specialties is IPM and we
really haven't covered a good IPM topic
on on the show so I wanted to I wanted
to go over some basic steps
um and some of the practices that you do
to to to keep your room clean to to
really work on your IPM do you want to
talk about some of your basics
yeah so I kind of like I worked in the
commercial Greenhouse industry for like
a long time like I think 30 years or
something and most a lot of what I've
done is in integrated Pest Management so
also I would say don't always take
lessons from me on how to do stuff
because because I work in that sometimes
I go through stages where sometimes I'm
like a super diseaseophobe and I'm like
I don't want to take anything in and uh
and other times I'm like whatever if I
get something I want to I don't really
care that much if I get something in
because I want to like figure out like
make sure I know what I'm talking about
with getting rid of it
um
and the only ones that honestly out of
all the ones that I see the ones that
are just like really like the number one
thing I say is just don't get it like
yeah
it's like that's the easiest thing like
thrips and spider mites to me they're
pretty easy to get rid of the ones that
are just like
they're they're disasters is like is I
mean powder mildews per it's doable but
it's for I mean it's anyone has had it
it's pretty hard to shake especially if
you've got a bigger operation
um but the worst ones is uh cannabis
aphid uh in Maroon aphid just because
they're there's just unless you're gonna
go with us and they're easy to get rid
of with a synthetic like a systemic uh
but if you're like legal and you can't
do that or you don't want to do that
they're essentially impossible to get
rid of so I mean that and that's the one
I always find so frustrating because
people it's like they're you know aphids
are big like you can see them you don't
even need a handling like a magnifying
glass you can see them with your naked
eye and I I've seen I've personally seen
multiple times for people have literally
like brought in like some stupid clone
it definitely wasn't worth the hassle
and ended up with like you know
something that cost them millions and
millions of dollars and they basically
it's never get rid of them
um but I actually just had a recent one
that I've kind of moving so I'm kind of
shutting down all my because I'm not
finishing up my flowering and I was like
okay well I'm just holding mothers for
like the next you know probably a year
or something because I gotta you know
sell my house and move and stuff so I'm
like I'm gonna start catching some
clones that people owe me or whatever
Now's the Time I'll add them and then I
don't really care whatever if somebody
sticks me I got a year to clean it up
and uh
so I got I got and everyone's giving me
a clone recently he's gonna be like oh
that's me but because I'll tell everyone
I've gotten a whole bunch of clothes
from different people in the last month
or so so it might not have any of it
somebody gave me powdery mildew on one
of them that they told me didn't have
any and I had left them
I I had gone traveling for two weeks I
thought it was fine and I left it and
then I went back I kind of left my wife
in charge and I came back and that one
clone had blown up and gone everywhere
so now I got mildew everywhere so that
one's fresh in my mind and that's the
one that I think causes a lot of people
a lot of uh there's a lot of they don't
really understand what's going on there
and I think they think it's systemic
which is a chance it is but I think
mostly what happens where you get it and
they're like I just can't shake it it's
just because once you get spores
everywhere in your room they're
basically impossible to get rid of like
they last for years so I've seen I've
seen that a bunch of times where people
they think they've got it all under
control and then bang like six months
later PM starts up again and I think
that's really it might have been that it
was in some you know one of their plants
just had a bit living on it that they
didn't catch but I think a lot of times
it's just there's spores everywhere and
sooner or later you kick up a Spore and
and it germinates on your plant and and
bang you've got it but in that situation
I believe that's it what had happened is
that plant that I brought in from my
buddy had was covered in spores and the
spores kind of you know they germinate
on the plant and then they kind of have
a little Tap Root that goes down into
the plant that's called a historium that
basically like it's kind of like roots
for powdery mildew and it just like kind
of sits there and it spreads like it's
mycelium kind of across the surface so
it's growing on the leaf surface and
then what triggers powdery mildew like
what people notice is when this when it
spores when it spoilates right and a lot
of times what people think it's like a
humidity thing but usually when it
actually spoilates it's a stress event
so it's either that's why you see it in
like Peak flowering all sudden it'll go
you'll see a whole room go off with
mildew you didn't think you had and in
this case while I was traveling the you
know in Canada usually when it switches
from kind of Summer to fall it'll go
from like 85 relative humidity on
average down to like 35 when the cool
when the Cool Front hits and that's what
I think happens there's a cool front hit
while I was traveling and bang this
thing went off my wife didn't see it the
next thing I know I've got mildew all
over the all over the uh
All Over the Garden but definitely like
those ones so I I guess my biggest thing
is I I'm usually pretty careful like
definitely if I was running a commercial
thing I would be way the heck more
careful than pretty much everybody in
what I bring in that's pretty much all
the time where it comes from it's people
importing clones and
I mean the one that just really gets me
it's it's the Cannabis Seafood
especially like they're just so easy to
see and I think especially if they're
legal stuff people start bringing in
like you know more cuttings at a time
than they can look through yeah properly
and then it only takes one aphid and
then you you know like one cannabis
aphid in three weeks can take down like
a whole garden basically like it really
they reproduce that quickly for the for
the PM what what in Canada I you know
because I know down here like our crew
tends to use like micronized sulfur
spray but I don't even know like in the
legal Market if that's something they
can even use up in Canada is that
something you guys use there or do you
have a different routine uh yeah so no
they can use it so basically what
they're limited to and again because I I
kind of work in both I've worked for a
long time and also like commercial uh
vegetables and Commercial flowers so
I've been yeah I kind of know what's
dealt with
in general and what's different with
cannabis is in any other crop it's
always controlled by a combination of
systemic fungicides and stuff like
sulfur and you know potassium
bicarbonate or like bacillus subtilis or
stuff like some of the common things and
what we've got stuck with in Canada good
or bad and I don't really have a comment
whether it's good or bad but it makes it
challenging is there's there's no like
systemic fungicides registered so
basically once you take the systemic out
you're just dealing with surface level
uh other than sulfur maybe you're just
dealing with surface level controls so
for instance like you know people will
use like uh I think Rhapsody is one like
a bacillus septalus which is like a
bacterial one yeah that people that's a
common one I think they use on both
sides of the border and it works great
but it only controls like the surface
level so it's and it so it's not
controlling that historium that's down
in that little root that's down into the
plant so basically you can can kill
everything on the surface and then that
little Roots is going to keep it's just
you know a week later going to pop up
and slowly spread again and you won't
see it until it spoilates so basically
what they're stuck with in any of the
legal places is just spraying every week
to keep them once you've got mildew in
your facility they just spray every week
with
usually they rotate and they've got I
think there's a hydrogen peroxide type
spray there's a potassium bicarbonate
spray there's a couple of like oil type
sprays which again these are all just
ones that they're just like they control
the surface level the only thing that
really has any systemic effect is sulfur
and that's one that people and I
honestly don't know the real answer to
this bubble I will say for sure all the
cleanest Growers that I've seen in the
legal Market use a lot of sulfur they
use sulfur literally some of the music
right they use sulfur pots right to
harvest I'm not saying that's good or
bad they will argue
um I personally wouldn't use it that far
they argue if you look at the sulfur
tests like the leaf uh like the tissue
analysis sure
there's still not enough sulfur in the
plant that's their argument they're just
like it's just a plant nutrient they're
still not up to Optimal levels even with
the pots burning bubble men and I
honestly just don't know which is true
on this bubble you know a lot of people
will say that the sulfur gets into and
will destroy the flavor which I could
definitely see you know it's soft like
it just gets into everything and Bubble
Man back years ago he used to be the
buyer at the Vancouver Compassion Club
and that was this big thing was he would
make hash with it and he could smell the
salt tell whether somebody had used
defender on their crop and I would say
definitely some of that absent [ __ ]
because I've literally smoked that guy
that the one of the big LPS that I know
for a fact runs it literally until
Harvest day I bought some of their uh
Pink Kush literally I know exactly what
was done to it and I bought it from the
legal store it was covered in Sulfur I
couldn't do some anything yeah I don't
know I personally obsess a little assess
on it but sulfur is definitely like the
most effective thing out of those and
then what I find it kind of gets is a
little bit dumb is like we had I think
you guys did too the whole uh Michael
butanal thing when it first went legal
there's a few people's uh it's called
Nova up here I can't remember what you
guys call it
um Eagle 20 Eagle 20. that's right so so
a bunch of guys got caught using that
and there's this whole thing about how
it makes like some you know when you
smoke Eagle 20 it makes this cyanide I
think it was some some super toxic
sounding thing but then if you look in
and I'm not telling people to go use
Eagle 20 today yeah I'm just saying I
think it's been blown up a little a lot
so if you look at like the the
chemical that they were all talking
about it was so bad well cannabis
already produces it like a thousand
times the level that was in the
microbutanol
um spray so I don't I'm not advocating
when people use Michael but no I'm just
saying that that is how it's controlled
on other crops and sure I would argue
like I personally wouldn't have a
problem doing clones with microbutanol
and like knowing like I personally
wouldn't have a problem cleaning up
Mother's stock with mycobutinol I would
never use it in flowering and stuff like
that sure even though we eat it all the
time like 100 of all your food's covered
in this and stuff yeah so yeah we got
some weird stuff there it's the same
kind of thing with aphids in Canada
where it's really easy to get it I've
seen both with micro butanol and with
aphid uh systemic chemicals where I've
seen people test clean pretty not that
far after they've done that that
application yeah yeah
um and it literally makes like it's
literally with cannabis if it's it seems
like one of those dumb things right
seeing like these LPS that literally
have spent like you know 13 million
dollars on bio control for a year to
control Canada to control cannabis aphid
and they could have literally controlled
them with like one you know Endeavor
treatment
for like a penny or something like that
it gets it seems like it's gotten a
little bit crazy like it's like okay who
who really cares if you test as long as
it's tests clean do you really care
whether somebody used it in their
mother's dog so I'm kind of always a
pretty big IPM I don't really believe in
pure bio control or pure chemical what
kind of believe in both I don't really
see a big problem with a lot of some of
that stuff if it's test if you're
testing it and it's clean at the end of
the day who cares so the issue with that
with that what happens is any of those
powdery mildew that's just a general
issue with a lot of chemicals is stuff
gets resistant to them really quick
there he's back so I was just saying uh
not so like what so what happens with
stuff like that is it's just when
they're spraying it too frequently and
it just gets resistant to it and what so
Canada's got a lot more stringent
pesticide laws than the US so we've kind
of always used a lot more
um you know bio control and like uh
micro
bio pesticides so that where they would
use if you look at a conventional
cucumber crop that gets a huge amount
like way more mildew than the Cannabis
crop gets they would always rotate so
they'll sit there and they'll spray
potassium bicarbonate or like these
off stuff which you can't get rid of so
you can't get results for you can't get
resistant to potassium bicarbonate
um so they'll spray those every week and
then every once in a while they'll throw
in a Nova that kind of just knocks the
crap out of them and that's how they
manage the resistance
um same thing with bio controls like you
were talking about you know your spider
reservites that's how a lot a lot of
crops are just they use the bio controls
to spread out how often they're going to
do the spray treatment just to keep them
much more effective
I mean yeah in in Mendo as well 20 years
ago you could spread people would use
abamectin some people call it Avid or
whatever else and they would spray it
once and they wouldn't see a two spot
for a year
um and then people got to the point
where they would spray they would dip
their cuttings in it every run they
would overuse it to a point where
there's a lot of mites in Northern
California that are immune to quite a
number of the harsher chemicals well I
mean like like direwolf was saying I
mean the main introduction is by
bringing in new clones if they're only
seeing it once a year it's probably
because they're only bringing in new
clones once a year to replace the Old
Stock and bring it in the new spider
mites with it
I think foreign
go ahead
oh I was just gonna say four spider
mites and maybe maybe it's different
because you're definitely in California
is a very Agricultural and intense area
so but where I where I live I live in an
area that's basically the size of like
Ukiah but it's uh it's about like 3 000
Acres of greenhouse so it's just like
solid greenhouses
um and lots of different people own them
so there's it's I would argue at least
as agriculturally intensive as Mendo is
and everyone's spraying different stuff
and what I've seen a bunch of times like
I'll tell you A friend of mine owns a
big cucumber greenhouse and he had the
same story that not so sang basically
like when I first uh was going in there
he was literally like tank mixing like
you know six times the rate of avid with
ten times three to fluoramite something
literally I'm not even making those
numbers up like it was yeah amounts of
stuff and uh and that would basically
Buy in like five days like he was just
in a mad Panic spraying over and over
and over again and
so he switched to using bio control for
that and within three months
um you could and again I'll just
elaborate on this a little bit but
within three months you could go in
there with a regular rate of fluoramite
or a regular rate of avid and it looked
like you dropped a nuclear bomb in there
like you'd spray once it would just like
wipe everything out and but so there's
two things that can kind of go on with
pest populations is the majority of what
I've seen especially with spider mites
is like it's a it's a short-term
selection pressure so as soon as you
take that selection pressure which may
be a spring Avid all the time away for a
while there's nothing selecting for that
in the population so it just goes back
to being susceptible you do get
sometimes if you look at other pests
like white flies a good example there's
a type of uh White fly uh from down from
Southwest it comes from Southwestern U.S
and it comes from those really
agricultural intense areas where they're
getting sprayed a lot and in those cases
the there's a lot of resistance to
insecticides it's actually become fixed
in the population where it doesn't
matter it's just like every single one
just like if you're breeding autoflowers
and you got to the point where
everything is Autoflower well you can't
blend that out but I haven't seen that a
lot it's definitely possible with mites
I have not seen it I've seen it with
white fly and that's about it it
definitely couldn't happen with other
stuff but most of the resistance is
generally local it's generally because
the like the people on that farm have
been overusing okay
makes sense I I what I what I find in
Mendo is when because spider mites breed
more rapidly when the temperatures go up
and the humidity goes down
um people tend to like you know
especially inside and stuff like that
they really tend to get beat up in
summertime and then they tend to get
ahead in Winter and they lose again in
summer
um and you know and then there's a lot
of things too where people used to
overuse all those chemicals especially
when in the 215 era the clubs only
tested for parts per million
uh people had it figured out like how
close you could use certain chemicals
and still test clean when you took your
product in and then they moved it to
parts per billion
uh and that changed things a bunch
um and you know and so now obviously all
those things are banned
and you can't use them at all
um and so you know people have have gone
to bio control or they've gone to pet
they've gone to bugs they've gone to
like simpler methods I think
that's definitely what
that's definitely what's happened in
Canada with the legal market right just
generally everyone uses as much like
there's definitely some people spraying
some nasty stuff in the black market but
most of them are pretty
um they use they they're pretty IBM like
producing a lot of benefit uh bio
control but the one that I just find
there's just there's some things that
biocontrol just doesn't have a great
answer to and cannabis aphid is one that
is just it has great answers like
there's tons of stuff
will control cannabis aphid really well
they're they'll never get rid of them to
understand and they're you know gets
expensive
um there's some that I'm just like I
personally just can't Envision like long
term not like there's just not going to
be a bio control that's going to control
them
cost effectively and so I mean
um there's a couple like that but most
of them are pretty pretty uh controlled
I think probably what you've got going
on in Mendo is a climate thing too where
it's just really yeah 100 bad climate
like where where it'd be hard to make
bio controls work properly because you
got really low humidity all the time
um but sorry the other thing I was going
to mention with the spider mites the one
of the most common things that that I
see is spider mites they go into a
hibernation under short days so they go
into what's called diapause and so
basically what I see happen is really
communist terminal get bad spider mites
and then they think they got rid of them
but just you know a whole bunch of the
population is just like hiding you know
in their electrical outlets and you know
any little crevice in your room
in diapause and they'll do that like
kind of so basically they're going to go
cycle just in and out of diapers so they
might disappear for like two months up
into your room somewhere and then you
think it's all clean and then you're
like where did all these spider mites
come from and that's what it was doing
diapers
cannabis aphids I can say for for Mendo
um it's really the First new pest that
I've seen
in probably the last you know them and
russet mites honestly are only of the
two new things that have come along
really within the last like five to
seven years
uh yeah for sure sure go ahead and you
know and cannabis aphids I've had
experience with lots of other types of
aphids before
um cannabis aphids just breed so
unbelievably fast
um and they're all female and they all
are pregnant and their and their embryos
have embryos
so they just replicated such a rate like
you were saying there's lots of things
that kill them
but you miss a couple and give it a few
weeks and they'll be back to Crazy
levels again
yeah just to like it there I don't think
most people just cry I can't tell people
enough times like don't get them they're
literally the worst thing you could ever
have like so I'll give you an example of
just how bad they are is I had just on a
personal growth so I was doing some uh
we were doing some trials somewhere for
work for cannabis aphid and I must have
had to come from here but I must have
ended up with one on my clothes and
couldn't have been more than one or two
aphid because I don't even like I would
never walk right from a place like that
into my grow room so but somehow a
cannabis aphid can that was the only
place it could have come from so
cannabis if it can only go from cannabis
plants right so if you're like whatever
living it somewhere where there's no
cannabis plants around you got cannabis
anything like you brought them in on
cuttings 100
um or or like someone dumb like me
brought them in on their clothes from a
place that had cannabis aphid and at the
time so I was just playing around with
everything and you could control them to
kind of like blow you could keep them at
a dull Roar pretty
easily with soaps or bio controls or
like we're using lace Wing I did a bunch
of different stuff it wasn't hard to
keep them fairly under control but to
get rid of them was next to Impossible
because you literally have to get rid of
every single one
um and I literally had to take my entire
collection down to
um like four little clones and spray
them almost to death with silt to get
rid of them until they were entirely
clean like they're so on a commercial
thing it's basically possible you could
never
um I don't think it's possible to get
rid of them the one thing I would say
that I have seen and I don't know what
the exact answer to them is is uh heat
treatments so with the crop in
um I've seen it the only people I've
seen actually get rid of them completely
used it did uh via heat treatments but
maybe if we can back up a little bit so
why they're so bad compared to you know
a lot of people you'll get like an
aphids on your cannabis crop and then
they don't do do anything that's like
pretty common so a lot of pests are
they're adapted to the crop species so
for instance on tomatoes don't get a
whole lot of uh aphids and most most
times on a tomato crop in a greenhouse
you'll get
um aphids that'll come in and they just
don't they kind of get going a little
bit and they need to Disappear by
themselves it's because they don't like
the host plant and every once in a while
you'll get one that's adopted and then
it's like look out it's basically the
same as cannabis aphid and it was
Cannabis if it is just highly adapted to
that
um that crop so as soon as they get
going they're they'll go like
they'll go like crazy but yeah if you go
back to the heat stream and that's one
of the things that actually came from
the black market where I don't know but
in general but I was who's kind of
spread that around in Canada
um and I got it from the black market I
knew some black market people that were
getting you can get these heaters that
they use in hotel rooms uh to kill bed
bugs so basically if you heat up a room
to like you know about 45 or 50 Celsius
um
for about five hours it'll kill
everything that's in there
um and some guys were in the black
market were playing around for that for
broad might
um and it doesn't work by the way
um but we also put ended up playing
around with it for cannabis aphid and it
does work pretty well so they and I the
thing is like you can really fast or
crop cranking those temperatures and the
guys that I know that have figured it
out obviously they won't tell anyone
they did but it's something to do with
heat treatments and it's something with
playing around with like those high
temperatures like 45 Celsius or
something for a few hours enough to
um make them all dehydrated so there's
definitely answers that I think will get
figured out because I've definitely seen
a few people do that have done it but uh
yeah for most people I'm like just take
a good look at your cutting before you
bring that in so your your place because
they spread so quick you know they they
can actually in California they transfer
by air
um you know from just different because
there's so many outdoor Gardens and
really what happened to us is it was
Oregon's fault
is Oregon had hundreds and hundreds of
acres of hemp once we made hemp legal
through the farm bill uh federally and
then the hemp Market the CBD Market
collapsed and people had literally
thousands of acres of hemp uh that was
going to be worthless and so they didn't
Implement any IPM and some of these
cannabis aphids took over and just
replicated at a rate that was never
before seen
and then they just started spreading
like wildfire from there oh yeah so
basically that's exactly what's happened
so cannabis safe and needs to go from a
cannabis plant to a cannabis plant and
generally it's I've seen most of the
time it's from cut it's from imported
cuttings but you can definitely get that
so basically when they they don't
usually have wings but when they run out
of food
um a food source or that gets too many
they'll develop wings and fly somewhere
else so yeah if you've got a lot of
growers near you or hemp fields and
stuff you'll get Flyers root aphids
actually worse so at least with those
ones like with cannabis safe and you're
like okay well at least if you know if
you're away from everybody else or if
you screen your Greenhouse or screen
your grow room like do a good job in
your garden you're probably not going to
get them even if you didn't screen them
you're probably not getting them in your
grow room from like a hemp field unless
you're like intaking directly out of the
outside
but uh rude aphids the problem is
they're actually worse because they're
an actual quite a widespread pest that
lives on a lot of different plants so
you can uh get root aphids from I don't
know all the host pieces so you can just
get them from like weeds inside your
place so that's but it's interesting
because I'm the same thing as like when
I grew up most of the time it was just
like it was you know thrips and spider
mites up until p.m the whole PM outbreak
kind of blew up I'm guessing probably on
2000s or something
um
and then all these new ones the you know
have Russ at my uh
cannabis aphid root aphid and then
Obsolete and viroid they're all like
came out of a legal thing it was just
from increased sharing of genetics
material for sure
it was very poor practices and it was
people stopping maintaining their own
mothers and then and then buying and
trading amongst their small group of
friends and going to centralized
locations like dispensaries or stores or
nurseries and just for the ease of
getting their plant stock somewhere
no good
always listen to originally what we saw
was just from people it was just from
you know Black Market channels opened up
more and people were sharing clones a
lot more than they used to because like
for instance in that uh
uh that Nelson BC area that was where
have breasted might first showed up in
Canada that I saw and that was from
clones that came out of Colorado
um that got brought up
um
but I'd say in Canada where the bigger
problem has been it's it's the nursery
thing was kind of stage two of that
where now because it's still legal most
people are buying from nurseries and
it's like whatever they do hype clone is
you got to get it from this one nursery
and then like people are buying it I'm
like dude don't buy it from that place
like you're gonna get all kinds
stuff and they buy it anyways and all of
a sudden they've got you know cannabis
aphid pops late and then everything else
coming from it so that's definitely been
the second wave is those those legal
nurseries which is I think what you guys
are seeing in California a lot too that
was what I was going to comment on was
the the legal Nursery aspect
um like you know different different
nurseries specifically in California
when a hype strain would go off there
would be one major clone Nursery
supplying millions of those clones to
all the different dispensaries out there
and if hlv was just in one it takes no
effort at all to just
ruin every room that it touches so yeah
that's been a massive explosion the the
secondary nurseries the legal nurseries
all that major pathogen vector
the thing with with tops late is it's
again I've never dealt I've seen it I've
had a bunch of buddies that have had it
pretty well and I kind of know I've
dealt with other like
uh you know vegetable crop viruses and
star viroids that are similar to that
and thyroids are usually really easy to
control because the nice thing about
them is like they can't persist outside
of like plant saps so they're not going
to just sit on your like you know floor
for a long period of time and then
reinfect like a lot of us
so when you see those people it's just
like everything they're shipping
got hops Leighton fire like they're
doing something seriously wrong like
it's just really bad
what I think happened is uh people you
know uh people would use similar
scissors or similar razors
um or you know uh with cloning would
spread it really badly I think in a lot
of those nurseries and it would go from
being on just a few plants to being on
hundreds yeah almost all the obsolete
enviroid in my opinion there's
definitely some that's been spread from
seed but I think the vast majority has
just been spread from you know some dude
using the same cutting knife on
everything
yeah it seems to be how it's it's
rapidly spread and the water uh liquid
contact between root systems it sounds
like that's another vector
that that was a new one that I heard
when on your guys when when you had that
lady on it was interesting to me because
I'm like man that makes it but I don't
doubt it either but I'm like man I've
watched a lot worse I've watched it
happen in action it's it's pretty crazy
yeah and then she you know one of the
interesting things she brought up was
just how like Leaf tissue it could be
hit or miss whether or not it showed up
on testing but root tissue it was like a
hundred percent
if if you had it it was going to show up
on if you ripped off some roots and
tested those
um and how it moved through the plant
you know so and we've definitely had
buddies we called it dudding back then I
don't know if it was hop Layton but we
definitely have had buddies that like it
ripped through their whole scene
basically through runoff
that was what that was that was how it
got that one's new to me I I that was a
really good episode that you guys like
that interview she had some really
interesting information that I hadn't uh
uh heard before it totally makes sense
but that's uh it's it's kind of a
different
um thing because most it's not something
you see in a lot of other cases because
for instance like in you know Greenhouse
vegetables everything's getting run
through like all the run like they do
research but I mean everything's getting
it's there's not a lot the way they're
set up
everything just goes right you know
they're all in Rockwell slabs and it
just basically goes directly out of that
one slab into the you know the runoff
cat Gutter and then it gets run through
like ozone treatment and everything so
you're not getting viruses recirculating
like that I think it's kind of like a
it's partly to do with how a lot of
people are set up definitely take the
window to like no-till dudes when you're
when you're like well crap you get
Obsolete and viroid in there once and
you're basically stuck with it
dude there was a um there was a thing
you know the DNA was part of it
um uh and they had they were one of the
first people that had like huge
Greenhouse scenes in Salinas California
when legal first happened
and they did all these like two foot
deep five foot wide 100 foot long beds
everywhere and all these Greenies
and they brought in rude aphids on their
plants very first run
and they basically infected these living
soil beds with root aphids
and then they struggled for a couple of
years and then they went to one gallon
pots
yeah they couldn't get rid of them
I have I I personally wouldn't do it I
have one of my good friends who's a big
living soil guy and I've actually seen
him for sure I've seen rude aphids in
his place and they've never got going
like I don't think he ever gets rid of
them but they don't actually cause him
any problem and and I think it is
because the living soil kind of keeps
them in check
um but yeah I don't I don't know 100 on
that the one thing I would say on hops
late and viral those like one of my
friends he runs a legal place that was
the first one in Canada that I saw that
got it really bad like they had to like
shut down the whole they had like a new
startup got it all rolling they did like
one crop and we're like what the heck is
going on here and they couldn't figure
it out and they finally they were there
was before anyone really knew what
Obsolete and viroid is and he's like
dude it was a disaster for them like but
he's like it was actually super easy to
control he's like literally as soon as
you got rid of it they literally just
got rid of all the plants they didn't
even sanitize they literally threw all
the plants out waited a week put fresh
plants from a tissue culture and they've
never had them again and he's like you
could easily
pardon me Matt that sometimes that's it
you know some of our friends just said
throw it out start over
the quickest way through it
well it depends on your setup probably
now that you've got that whole runoff
thing uh yeah set up on Rockwell cubes
and they probably had like a research
like I said it's pretty standard in a
lot of those sit-ups to have ozone in
line that kills anything like that so
it's going to limit how much it's going
to spread but he said he could easily
he's like if I had to do it again I
wouldn't even have pulled the crop he's
like I just would have like watched you
know maybe did a good job testing his
mother's and then just going oh that
one's got it and he's just he's just
like just from sanitation like don't use
the same knife from plant to plant and
he's like I'm totally confident that I
could uh have done it but he's the one
of the guys I know you were talking
about whether it could come from seed or
not I've seen firsthand lab tests that
he got so that was what was kind of sad
about that whole thing is that dude just
threw out his whole clone collection
when he started that license place
because he was worried about bringing in
some weird Pastor virus but in all fresh
Cali seed I started that whole legal
place from there and that's where his
top late and viroid came from for sure
and he showed me test packs of like
tests from some of the packs that he got
they tested positive first so there's no
doubt some of them are getting brutal
brutal bro you know she also mentioned
or I think someone in the chat at the
time mentioned pollen and it traveling
on pollen and I didn't I'd never even
taken that into consideration like a
dotted nail pollen transfer I don't know
if it's possible but I probably would
for for somebody like me who keeps a lot
of uh a lot of old a lot of old clones
that are not currently popular
um and it's hard to get people to back
them up for you and help because if
there's not a financial incentive
they're not particularly interested
uh it's really scary
um because there's there's some things
that are really nice that aren't very
well spread out
um and can get ruined and I mean we have
good friends of ours that lost some
pretty old and some pretty rare things
um before the Hop Layton thing was even
known we just called it dudding
and people didn't know what precautions
to take uh and so I'm pretty worried
about the combination of root aphids and
russets and hop latents and and even
stuff like you know the the rude aphids
can spread hop latent
yeah I don't know that that's I think
they probably can I don't know that
that's actually been proven 100 have you
seen I don't think so either but I
wouldn't like them
it's pretty likely so there's a lot of
kind of myth about that what I my
understanding is something like thrips
or spider mites is really they're not
thrips are virus carriers but from my
understanding from this actually came
from one of the someone that's like PhD
guys in in virology like you know way
more than me I do they told me that
there's the chance of thrips carrying
hops latent Viro is almost next to
nothing
um I think
aphids is definitely quite likely and
even if it's like to me everyone's right
now so caught up in hops late in viral
they forget there's a million other
viruses out there that are just as bad
that for sure aphids carry and thrips
carry some of them too
um but aphids are probably the number
one like virus Vector in agricultural oh
we've been getting there's this stuff
that's been spreading around beet curly
top virus yep and it gets spread by it
gets spread by Leaf hoppers
um so there's and that's one of actually
one of one thing I'll mention because I
think it matters is you know in the in
the old days when everybody was hiding
in in small and medium-sized indoors and
everybody was up in the hills and tucked
away
um a lot of this stuff didn't spread so
much and now that we've gone legal and
people are going into all these
traditional AG areas to grow cannabis
all those traditional AG areas are ripe
with things that cannabis hasn't really
grown next to yet
yeah and that's one of the things I
don't think people like I said I I live
in a really agricultural intense area so
basically it's all just greenhouses and
corn fields and like it's we've got I
think it's 97 clear-cut for agriculture
where I live so what's interesting is
I've seen it play out a bunch of times
like for instance like on tomatoes
Tomatoes never used to get thrips so
green has Tomatoes they didn't get
thrips and then all of a sudden one year
thrips were like this massive issue on
tomatoes and they never went away it
just kept kind of continued and if you
traced back what it was it was they'd
started growing wheat and so in the
fields around the greenhouses they were
growing wheat and wheat's got lots of
pollen and thrips love it so because
there's like a food source and so you
get these giant levels of thrips right
beside your greenhouse and when you get
a situation like that and I've seen this
with a bunch of different past most 99
of the thrips don't like tomatoes but
sooner or later you get one that does
and then or two that does and then they
breed and all of a sudden you've got
thrips adapted to tomatoes and that's a
whole different story and that's anytime
you get agricultural intense areas
that's what you get is these jumps of a
pest that doesn't necessarily normally
like cannabis or whatever that when you
you know when you grow you know 10
kazillion white fly right beside a
cannabis crop sooner or later you know a
couple like cannabis and they have
babies and then bang you got a whole new
pest complex to deal with
it just sounds like a never-ending cycle
of pests pest pests and probably more
are going to be entering into our
cannabis sphere as it gets bigger more
corporate oh certainly widespread
and goes into all those areas that have
all those different pests and then life
adapts
you know well the one interesting thing
like a year long time ago I used to be a
flower grower so I used to work at a
really like a pretty big uh ornamental
greenhouse and we grew like a lot of
different types of flowers like
different species and one of the more
interesting things that I saw there is
we always had like you know this type of
this variety that always it just was
never happy right and you're growing so
many different things you could never
bait nothing was ever perfect right and
one year we were just like we just took
all the we just did a broad sample for
virus for this specific virus uh which
is pretty I would lay back this as a
canvas one as well it was called uh
uh
insv and patient necrotic spot virus and
there's a thrift spread virus and what
was interesting is when we did a broad
analysis of like all of our plants all
the plants pretty much all the plants
that we were like always having problems
with like I can't figure out why this
one won't grow this one's always got pH
problems it looks like or this they all
had insv so it was all this like
basically like 90 of all of our what we
thought was plant cultural problems was
actually that it had a virus and doesn't
necessarily show the same all the time I
would lay that so that's probably
goes on in cannabis a lot
that could be a lot that could be a lot
of what people call when people think
about like genetic drift or clones get
old and tired and they don't want to
root well anymore and they don't want to
grow well anymore they could have just
picked up some kind of pathogen that
they don't have a way to detect
well I want to keep everything going and
I think we're gonna have to do a whole
nother part two of this because it's
going to cut us off right at two hours
and yeah I mean I think we could do a
whole nother show out of all this so
no I got nothing to plug man that was
good it was uh good talking
well it was an enjoyable chat for sure
yeah we could have kept going forever
except it's gonna cut me off I hate that
so we really appreciate having you there
uh we're definitely gonna have you back
if you'll have us back and you'll be
back on and I'm sure everybody will be
enjoying it and uh we appreciate all of
your your tips and tricks with IPM uh
it's one of the most requested things we
get
um yeah not so you got anything you want
to plug
just always I appreciate everybody's
time everybody listening and tuning in
as we explore different stuff so much
appreciated all right thanks everyone
[Music]
foreign