howdy
what's up everyone
how's everyone doing
i'm barely awake i apologize in advance
i've been on a backwards [ __ ]
schedule so
yeah
gotta move again soon so
fun there everybody loves moving
so i feel about that so now we're just
waiting for natso to show up so we can
get this party started
i came a little early
that's what she said
what's up old song how you doing
how's everyone doing
well before natsu gets here don't forget
to join the patreon guys we have some
cool [ __ ] going on tomorrow there's some
fights
um
i'll be watching
and
it'd be cool
um
i also have the hawaiian lights drop
for the patreon folks all the hybrids
are out
and they've been out for about a week
i'll be adding those to the um
non-patreon
very soon so we got those going on lots
of good [ __ ] popping off
farm stuff too if you checked out those
femme lines those are up right now for
everyone
all right
well not so should be joining us anytime
soon
except that i accepted it
yes we will see
until then
i'll just keep staring at my own [ __ ]
head
there he is what's up
what's up you silly bastard how you
doing i'm all right i got allergies and
my internet connection sucks today so i
apologize ahead of time for
any [ __ ]
ah it's all good i'm still getting over
the sickness that i've been having
mostly just uh in my chest and in my
sinuses still it's [ __ ] bad though
whatever whatever i got was bad
i don't think i'm getting sick i just
think it's
mendo in springtime and things are
blooming yeah
everything's out and about you know yeah
yeah it's about that time isn't it
it is here it's good you know things are
i mean event like what's funny is like a
million years ago when i first came to
california um to see the grateful dead
and jerry garcia band
um i came out here in spring right yeah
and everything was green
and coming from illinois where i'm from
where it's flat as a pancake because of
the glacier it was i thought it was like
ireland
yeah it was all like rolling hills and
and flowers and it was brutally cold
where i lived and it was so nice here
and i had no idea it got to like 110 and
everything died in summer
yeah you know yeah oh i know oh i know
here it gets to be like 120 so well yeah
you you you live and uh you live in the
literal frying pan yeah we live in hell
yeah you live in hell so
uh that's not my favorite part of
california what
i know i know dude i know you know how i
mean i i'd appreciate the desert
but it's not it's not my spot we burst
kevin mccarthy come on
you you did you know if you like flat
and dry and very very hot you know yeah
warm nights and good people good fun
yeah indeed
so what what is our topic for tonight as
far as education goes as far as
education goes i thought we would chat
about a couple of things um we would
talk about maybe sort of like the
very late 90s early 2000s uh period in
the west coast
and because there's a whole bunch of
stuff then
that's pretty pertinent to now
it was all kind of going on and then i
think we might talk about at some point
probably will fit in because it's been
uh a big topic amongst us this week is a
little bit of like authenticity yeah and
uh how to you know how to address that
yeah how do we address authenticity in
these uh times where everybody's making
money off something being authentic
well yeah and people you know people
have their own their own motivations
their own wants needs and desires
yeah you know that type of stuff and so
you know because um
some cherry pie cush talk
cherry pie might be able to fit into
that a little late i've kind of avoided
the whole cookie thing yet
yeah it's probably a couple episodes on
its own and it's pretty complex
so
uh we probably will chat about that at
some point but it needs uh that one
needs some fleshing out a bit
yeah i would say yeah yeah it's gonna be
a deep one
yeah that's a deep one and there's a lot
of people making a lot of money off it
and there's a lot of rep on it so the
more money and rep you have it kind of
ties into the authenticity thing we were
just talking about yep uh you start
talking history and it interferes with
anybody's money or rap and all of a
sudden they're extremely upset yeah you
know
uh
you know i mean i made this i made this
like joking post i don't post much
anymore on ig but i made this joking
post i saw this cartoon and it was like
i remember it differently
in a way that fits my world view and
paints me in a positive light
yeah that's for sure and you know
relating to weed history like you run
into that a lot
yeah
you know you you run into that a lot
you know so um
maybe we should uh i don't know what are
we we're getting up to 150-ish people
here yeah we like to [ __ ] for a
couple minutes and allow people to show
up yeah you know
yep and get to a certain point before we
start chatting so here's one here's one
just
what is the best blueberry not so dog
the best blueberry so this is another
one that when i tell you what i think
people will get upset at me yeah yeah um
because uh you know if you talk to uh
second generation genetics who is jd
who's dj sun or dj they will say the
only legitimate place to get blueberry
is them yes
right yeah um but the you know for some
reason the blue bonnet seems to throw
these days at least
uh some really potent blueberry terps
and it's not mine i didn't make it i
don't get to take credit for it but i
did use it it's just yeah to be
transparent yes he did use it so i had
my i mean
there's actually a tie-in to
well i had my own blueberry line that i
created before um during the time that
blue bonnet was being made and the
lone star was kind of competition to me
at the time and i was very egotistical
about my blueberry of course because
everybody thinks they have the best
blueberry and i used it and it did breed
true for blue traits and very beautiful
blue terps and very pretty but it didn't
have much potency or resin production to
speak of and i think lone star did it
better than i did i really do
so yeah and what we're lucky
is that it still exists
yes and you can still get it from a
number of different sources yes
um
a ton so
uh we're getting there i think we're up
to a decent time so we're going to start
um
and uh these talks have kind of been
we've we've been kind of moving forward
we started in the beginning in the 90s a
bit now we're starting to move forward
we actually still have like a third wave
of seed banks that matt and i want to do
um that we never actually dealt with
that involves canada and everything else
but it starts to get a little bit more
dispersed and difficult to get the the
accurate stuff so it's taken us kind of
a while yeah so there's a lot to it and
there's a lot to cover you don't want to
leave out a lot of stuff and
you don't want to forget a lot of stuff
and some stuff we do leave out and
forget and have to go back and tag
because it isn't that important so yeah
and that's kind of you know that's kind
of one of the things about these talks
is there a bunch of history there's some
there's some speculation there's some
bullshitting
um they're trying to be conversational
and tell people about the memories that
people have
um they you know we'll talk about things
but they get people been under shape
already
um so rather than talking about like the
third wave of seed banks i thought we
could chat more about like what was
happening on the west coast yeah which
is where matt and i both live
uh what was happening on the west coast
in that era
and how specifically california and how
that kind of like started to impact what
came after
yep
right so
just to let everybody know um in 1996 in
november they passed the 215 act uh the
proposition 215 in california and that
made it was the first state where you
had medical
yeah now you know medical was uh
very restrictive at first and it was
only about four or five conditions that
it applied to
and the cops had spent their whole
career just busting anyone with weeds so
they were also slow to change yes
because they saw weed and they were like
[ __ ] you it's weed i'm arresting you
and so people think that it like just
became legal
in 1997 uh it did not
um it started a slow process
right
um and the era we're gonna talk about is
sort of like the very beginning of when
gorilla started to end and that process
started to really take place yeah you
know there was the very beginning of
medical in california so things were
starting to open up
people were starting to be less
secretive
and as we mentioned on shows before i
think it was 1999 that overgrowth
started
and not that long after the cannabis
world started
i i don't know the years on when they
started um so
you know after a few years you had this
network of people
um that were connecting via these
via these you know these forums yeah
and chatting and stuff like that and so
one that ended up happening
is
uh you know this this started a whole
wave of different things it started uh
there was you know really the forums
were the first time you could really
ever trade outside your circle that you
knew in person yeah
you know
right
yeah i mean even even today i still see
people uh you know in other states where
they say you know i can't get that clone
i live in this state and it kind of
blows my mind because back then even
like we didn't all live in like people
were getting bubba clones from ohio you
know that were in california you know
what i mean like if
you didn't necessarily go to the state
to get it
yeah and i mean you know one of the
things that's interesting about that is
that
you know there's there's different
people uh for a lot of people um we have
a good buddy of ours that lives back in
the midwest
and
you know for him the forums and ig and
discord and stuff like that was a way
for him to talk to other weed nerds yeah
right but for somebody like me who lives
in mendo like everyone around me does
what i do
yeah so there's no shortage of hanging
out like i'm surrounded by people like
me so there was some people that like
were
you know really intent upon getting on
there and that was their mode of
communication
yeah and some of us just lived in places
and stayed off all that
yeah you know so like when you popped up
or whatever it doesn't really like
correlate to like what you're up to we
all lived in the shadows yeah right so
tying into that i'm uh i'm probably in
my
i don't know what it is i'm probably in
my mid-20s
or so
and i meet this guy and i don't think
it's weird to say his name his name was
ron uh yeah no right
yeah yeah and uh uh matt knows ron
very well very well yeah and ron was
runs a character and he's still around
and he did this thing where he started
throwing these harvest parties in fall
uh in
in my area and he actually threw him
he'd rent like a big-ass [ __ ] house
in sonoma county uh healsburg outskirts
areas like that like a big mansion
essentially yeah and he had like a
catering company and so this thing would
be you pay a certain amount of money and
this thing would be catered and then all
these heads would come
right
yeah and so it was the first time for me
uh that i really was around like
um that kind of scene because most of
those people that were there
like they knew each other from overgrow
or cannabis world yeah there was like
groups that came with people like me and
stuff like that that like were from that
area as well
but there was a lot of people from all
over
and if people are running who want ron
is he's uh ncga nor cal growers
association a lot of people associate
him with like the blue widow cut that
was one of his uh big jams
yeah and he used to help people get set
up he's always been pretty politically
active
you know he's always been a lot of the
fairs and a lot of various things that
went on you know with he usually have a
booth and he politically organized early
yeah
he got me my first uh emerald cup
cannabis
cup or a cam cannabis booth that was the
first booth i ever shared in emerald uh
cup was with was with wrong
yeah yeah
yeah so i mean i i i
i went to this thing i don't know i was
23 24 25 something like that
and um i went with my friends
i got invited by a buddy of mine
and what was neat about it you go to
this place and you walk in there like
you know huge dining room table or
whatever and everyone that wanted to
share you would write your name which
was usually like the handle yeah yeah
from the forums or whatever you would
write your name and you would put some
weed in the bag or the jar
and so the whole table is full of
different kinds of weed and hash samples
right yeah
and then it's you know and then it's one
of those things where you hang out for
two or three days and smoke a ton of
weed
and trade seeds with people and trade
trains with people and shoot the [ __ ]
yeah
right so
i go there and i'm young
and i'm hoping to meet like i am like so
convinced dude that
that i'm gonna meet these old-timers
yeah uh meaning my age now but that's at
the time uh you know i uh oh dirty old
sog was there look at that
um
anyway so
i'm all convinced i'm gonna meet all
these people and they're gonna they're
i'm like it's gonna like unlock the key
to a bunch of old school strains i want
yeah right
and i get there enough there wasn't some
of that there but there was there was so
much like everything that was super
popular in the very early 2000s
right it was like
apollo 11 apollo 13.
c99
uh you know white widow hybrids freaking
uh ssh hybrids uh yeah he said it's the
best times i ever had they were super
cool parties yeah it was it was really
cool to to see
i mean
there's a bunch of people there who i
won't mention because they don't want to
be popular but i will tell you that's
the first place that i ever met csi in
person
yeah uh that's the first place that i
met uh shaw who some people probably
know is 707 seed bank on ig
who did the you know the chem the chem
dog bx2 and a bunch of work with cat
piss
uh yeah a lot of people got bubba kush
from him
yeah you know um he's a he was a pretty
big guy back then yeah he was pretty
involved shaw
uh you know uh people like jason king
from the can of bible
kyle cushman uh jack herrera
um
you know just you know a bunch of
mountain men from mendo and humble you
know yeah uh you know very and then
various types of people like chip uh who
now has a uh the real dirt podcast i
think yeah yeah um
gold
yeah but he was actually when at those
parties that was before he started royal
gold he was still working on like cocoa
fiber then that was so long ago coco
fiber wasn't even a commercial product
available in stores yet yeah he was
planning on bringing it to uh
uh to america yeah he hadn't started
royal gold but he was planning on it
right that's wild yeah and so and so a
lot of us that was that was a lot of
times where the where we got to put
faces to names
yeah you know like i didn't even know uh
dirty i would have loved to have hung
out and talked to dirty old saw i didn't
even know
you know if i met if i know your real
name i i don't know it so hit me up but
there was a but there was a bunch of
people there yeah and so like chip for
instance who started royal gold um he
uh he had just come back one of those
years he had just come back from
switzerland a tour in switzerland right
because for people that don't know
switzerland was like the first place in
europe to really open up to cannabis
like outdoor and greenhouse style
um and so when amsterdam and holland got
rough
uh shanti and and uh breeder steve and a
number of different people shifted over
to swiss yeah right and so chip had gone
out and visited those guys
right and so he's got all these pictures
on his computer of like these
greenhouses full of neville's haze yeah
like 10 foot tall plants direct planted
in the ground
so
it was just uh yeah vic high it was just
really neat because it was a lot of it
was a lot of connected people it was a
lot of people that were active on the
forums
um it was
five or six or seven years uh before the
reversal era
yeah
so everything was everything was reg
seeds
yeah
everything there wasn't any nes one i
don't even think i'd heard the term s1
outside of a book
yeah
i don't think so i doubt so everything
yeah everything everything was hybrids
you know and people would bring their
hash bring their seeds bring their own
personal breedings
and it was like a way instead of mailing
each other and giving out addresses and
dms and all that it was like a super
swap meet
right
and so it was really neat in that regard
because
for one thing uh ron had a catering
business so part of the money that
everybody pitched in
he hired his whole team
and you and he made two meals a day for
three days
that's wild that's cool so yeah you got
to sit there and roll joints and smoke
and shoot the [ __ ] and pull tubes and
trade seeds and then you're [ __ ]
starving right and like some like tuna
on crisps comes by the thing you know
and you're like i want some of that and
you're just so high and you start eating
some of that and drinking now you feel a
million times better
um and so
the reason i bring that up is because
while now with a lot of these events and
a lot of these lives and a lot of a lot
of times like uh putting a face to a
name has become common yeah but back
then it was uncommon yeah very
so it was like really it was really it
was really like unusual and neat you
felt special yeah
you know and i mean there was uh you
know there was times where i mean i went
i went there i think yeah the foods were
to die for holds they were really good
they were fully catered full on meals
they'd have snacks and hors d'oeuvres
that would be get brought around finger
food and stuff it was pretty decadent
yeah you know and then just like
anything else even if you're an
experienced smoker
you start smoking 8 10 15 kinds of weed
you don't normally smoke
yeah and it's the first time you're
smoking all of them
even weak or moderate weed will get you
pretty baked yeah eventually if you're
just pulling all day non-stop yeah you
get [ __ ] yeah
and so you know there was different
things where it was like you can't hang
out with everyone
yeah so you know you make friends some
friends i made there um you know
i kept up with really well
yeah others like csi i didn't catch up
with again for a number of years after
those yeah because you just you're in
different directions people you know all
that different types of stuff and um
you know uh eddie just it was kind of
just like a who's who
yeah and a lot of a lot of the times
those people fletch people that weren't
very well known then yeah but now
they're all hella well known yeah
you know and they have some of the best
seed banks you know some of the best
breeders around
some of the best collections of weed
around
yeah um you know when i went there i
didn't have most of the stuff that i
have now but i had i had the maui and i
had the the chem 91 and the super skunk
and i had the super dog
um my uh
my buddy who doesn't like to be
mentioned uh you know uh from staten
island he came a couple years with us
you know yeah because we were still like
right in the middle of doing that super
dog project then
so
yeah we had different phenos we had the
super skunk we had different things we
had hash that we had sifted from things
and
all that so it was just a really neat
gathering and time period yeah people
keep asking like what happened but i
think i think we did a good job of
recreating a little bit of that just a
few years ago um a lot of people weren't
invited you know because it was smaller
but i think i think that there's still
an ability for our community to pull
together like that and have these big
events where people just get along chill
and smoke weed um yeah so it was a
privilege because i wasn't around for
for the wrong parties at all but it was
a privilege to be a part of the the
canned illuminati parties those are it
was [ __ ] insane to be a fly on the
wall at those events yeah i mean they
keep they do keep happening
um
but i i will say that like they probably
won't happen like that quite again
no um just for the simple fact that [ __ ]
changes yeah you know uh nobody knew who
csi was then
nobody knew who fletcher was then
nobody who i was that you know i mean
there was people that were known you
know but a lot of them were we were all
in our 20s or whatever just trying to
figure out you know various aspects of
life
yeah you know and we were all learning
and trading from each other and seeing
what was up and it was uh you know it
was just days of and there also wasn't a
bunch of money or rep involved
yeah it was kind of like the last era
before that era started
yeah it was so we were all young
innocent and dumb and you know and all
that kind of stuff and
less of a competitive nature maybe yeah
we were all i mean honestly
i came home with so many seeds from that
event and i gave away
you know thousands of seats yeah for
free yeah we just traded yeah oh you've
got some sweet tooth by blockhead from
steve
you know oh give me a hundred of those
and i'll give you 100 of this into this
into this into this okay cool you know
and it was like try it out
yeah it hadn't been monetized yet no one
really believed that you could make a
bunch of money in america selling seats
yeah i bet especially that area it
wasn't it just didn't exist yet so it
was like all these heads each with their
everybody was happy this to like if you
could get people you respected to grow
your beans oh yeah that was everything
[ __ ] man that was like you know and then
they hit you up and they were like dude
i found fire in your weed
yeah now you're like walking around you
feel good about yourself
yeah
you know
good job
and uh
you know and uh yeah in the forum era uh
caleb was white trash redneck or
inspector
now he's csi
yeah who's turf bugs i've never heard of
her
oh my gosh
so
we're gonna bounce around because all
those different things sort of inter
interact so just to kind of like put a
um
you know ron's parties were where a lot
of us made friendships with each other
um where a lot of us met for the first
time it brought together different
disparate groups of
uh weed heads yeah all from their 20s
through their 40s you know 50s
um it went on for a number of years
uh it you know it happened in the in in
the falls there was a lot of fire
outdoor and i should also mention
because this is pretty important to that
era where this is before the urkel
and the and the purple craze really took
off yeah and so
um that's really important because
all good weeds still got grown and was
sold yeah there really hadn't been waves
where it was like get this one cut
yeah and this cut you can sell all of
that that hadn't really happened yet now
i i attribute a lot of that to [ __ ]
jason king too for hyping cuffs up so
[ __ ] hard that era
i mean you know it's it's it's hard i i
i don't necessarily attribute it to him
i attribute it to the brokers
sure because i can't i can't talk about
other areas but like in mendo let's say
0-405
if you wanted to have a 50 lighter and
you wanted to sell every gram of your
weed you grew
yeah and you had granddaddy purple or
urkel or something along those or mendo
perps it all went yeah if you had sweet
tooth by louis
yeah maybe not
yeah maybe
i mean you probably could i'm not saying
you couldn't yeah but there wasn't
buyers shooting up from the bay like i
got i got room for x amount find it yeah
give me that sweet tooth yeah you know i
mean but you know because all that all
that work i should say that like so
and we'll talk about that um at some of
these things but
um
what were the all the popular things you
can think of
were at that party both as flower and
hybrids yeah and seeds so the white
family was crossed into everything
uh dj shorts the blueberry family was
crossed into tons of stuff
uh brothers grimm was crossed into a
different amount of stuff
yeah um
you know and then you know a bunch of
classics and things like that that would
go around nikai was still doing big
stuff federation was still doing big at
that time
uh people i can answer that question
someone just said where's jason king
he's on maui uh we'll we'll talk about
that in a minute um because that was
actually well that that'll overlap but
it really was
it really was like you know you hear
about the legendary harvest festivals
that happened in humboldt or mendo small
little gatherings and stuff
um that's really what it felt like to me
yeah it felt like being able to go to
one of those type of things and
back then
you really just talk shop and weed with
your close group of hermit friends
yeah
so getting to getting to go to like and
hang out with dozens of different people
for three or four days and chat and chat
it up
uh really set the foundations and a lot
of the a lot of the friendships and
stuff uh for later yeah it really made a
big difference i think
um frank you know friendships were
forged there transfers were made there
bit you know ideas of things
yeah
for a lot for a large part of it and i
think like when you started coming in
heavy
like it was all a bunch of that stuff
yes yeah it was still very much around
like when i first started coming in
heavy i was looking for the blue widow
clone i was looking for the the sweet
thing clone i was looking for all that
[ __ ] yeah you're looking for all that
and that was like that was everywhere i
mean that was like what everybody had in
clones what they had in flower and hash
and seeds and all these different types
of stuff yeah you know
kyle was there documenting it for high
times although i don't think ron let him
actually made an article about it
yeah because he wanted to keep it like
on the down low and not [ __ ] it up you
know yeah for sure um
but uh but you know it was interesting
and the reason why we're gonna kind of
bounce around all these different types
of stuff is it all overlaps
yeah
right so
um somebody asked about jason king it's
probably a good time to to chat about
that a little bit sure so
at that time
uh there was this guy's name's jason
king
and he
had this idea
that i'm gonna take a bunch of pictures
of famous strains
and then i'm gonna write my own super
opinionated blurb about each one of
these things yeah
and he called it the can of bible
and i don't think anybody knew what he
was doing at the time uh would be would
matter but what he did which is super
cool is he came out with about three can
of bibles
yeah and they sort of document this
whole like late 90s through early to
mid-2000s era
right before the clone wars
where all these specific clones of kush
urkel sour all that started just
dominating and a lot of these random
hybrids started to becoming hard to find
yeah
right
um so he came out with this can of bible
and i remember getting it and uh one of
the coolest things about the first can
of bible was that the entire first
introduction
uh is written by one of my weed heroes
uh rob clark
yes
right and rob did rob did this thing
where he wrote this big introduction
into the can of bible which honestly
i'm not sure anyone could have done that
and given as much legitimacy to jason
king
ron clark writing a big long seed
history and clone history introduction
yeah because like i've said before ron
wrote the bible for
seed breeding rob sorry rob rob ron rob
clark wrote the bible for seed breeding
marijuana botany he wrote hashish
uh he's legendary he's an encyclopedic
knowledge he's definitely like one of
the elders of the whole marijuana thing
yeah you know
uh he's made lasting contributions to
cannabis and so him writing that and
what he did is he outlined
which strains which was a huge debate
even back then
yeah which strains went to amsterdam as
clone onlys
and which strains went to amsterdam as
seedlines
yeah and a timeline of who gave what
that was kind of brief but who gave what
over there yeah and then a timeline of
like all these different seed companies
and what years they released different
versions of things yeah that was one of
my favorite his chart on the uh release
of seed companies it was the first time
i'd heard of like lowland seeds and all
that [ __ ] you know really the pearl
stuff is him someone's asking that yeah
pearl is
all the pearl stuff is related to rob
and so
so for a lot of us that you're trying to
piece together all this [ __ ] here's a
guy in the know that knows all these
various seed companies and breeders and
work and all that
and um
you know he he outlines this thing yeah
okay
so
uh you know so he so he comes out with
this thing he writes this big long thing
which is amazing it's my favorite part
of the book no offense to the rest of
the book yeah and then the rest of the
book is a bunch of jason's opinionated
comments on different pictures of wheat
he's taken and what he thinks about them
yeah from all over right so i get this
thing
and uh i'm super nerded out by it and i
love it okay
well uh
flash a little bit and there was this
gentleman who
uh just passed away not that long ago
but uh
um
his name was eddie lepp
yeah okay
and eddie left had a farm in upper lake
which is about 20 minutes from my house
um and he grew a bunch of wheat there
yeah okay
and he really blew it up he's he's one
of the he's one of the best best
he was one of the early biggest
flaunters of 215.
yeah like i'm gonna follow the law come
get me
and so a lot of people
um
that uh a lot of people met there
yeah right and so i met jason king
both there and i should should say at
some of those early ron parties okay
and we became good friends
right yeah uh
through you know through those
connections through hanging out at ron's
parties and then through um you know he
was he was a photographer and trying to
document weed and everybody back then
was fascinated that eddie left was
willing to fill a field full of cannabis
and be like come get me yeah yeah
you know
uh and so you know and and and so i
decided to help jason with his with his
project yeah he wanted to make a second
can of bible
yeah right and
i'd lived in mendo at that point a
number of years and matt as you're well
aware uh weed was weed world was still
insulated then yes very much going to
get a bunch of pictures uh and you're
not going to meet all the right people
without an n
yeah yeah it's still kind of that way
for the old school guys though you know
what i mean like but nothing like guys
are hard to talk to but nothing like it
was yeah before you couldn't even find
how to contact an old guy at least now
they have like maybe an ig page or some
some way you can track them down
that's true when i first got into this i
remember i tried tracking down dj's
short to to speak to him you know
no dice you had to find where he was
going to be speaking and see him in
person if you wanted to get a hold of
him at that time
so we'll crazy we'll bounce we'll bounce
around just so everybody knows i'm going
to talk about eddie and that and that
whole era because that's pretty cool but
um so these things will all overlap
because they're all going on basically
at the exact same time yeah
ron's parties
uh eddie's scene at an upper lake um the
stuff that i haven't talked to can a
bible all this stuff is all like
happening and and as part of the same
flow same few years right
so
um so i become friends with jason and i
decide to
help him with his project
yeah right um get him introductions to
people
let him meet other people that can help
him kind of navigate through humboldt
mendo
and document and all that type of stuff
so
as a result of all that
um
you know and i should say this is that i
i was pretty good friends with jason
back then i haven't
we've drifted apart he's lived on maui
now for a long time and i don't i don't
go to hawaii or haven't had kids so
we've kind of drifted apart we're still
on good terms
um he's a super opinionated guy and he
used to drive some people nuts
very true very true like there are
people that will be like that guy drives
me [ __ ] nuts i always got along well
with him yeah right and on top of that i
was very sympathetic to what he was
trying to do
yeah just another weedner trying to
[ __ ] put the pieces together yeah i
strongly disagreed with him about
certain things you know yeah and all
that you know and we would battle about
you know all kinds of [ __ ] you know um
but that's not that's not any different
than today with people
um but he was documenting and there's a
lot of there's a lot of things in there
you know like you talk about like the
bull ride there's a lot of stuff
yeah that fell off the wayside that's
documented yeah
you know um and uh and so i started
helping him figure out this different
stuff
right
and and and you know and me and eddie
and some other different folks
um started helping them put together the
can of bible yeah right and by helping i
just mean making introductions and and
you know
can this dude with a camera come to your
scene
yeah
because that's kind of crazy right you
got to have some trust yeah can i bring
a dude with a [ __ ] camera yeah to
your scene
yeah you know
uh and just so people get an idea this
is pretty funny um i remember uh jason
got a 12 megapixel camera
yeah with a super nice lens on it to
start taking pictures because the first
kind of bible was all film right
that 12 megapixel camera with a super
nice lens
was over 11 000
oh my god i'm dead serious dude over 11
000 because i was at his house
he actually
rented this house from eddie lep that
was in lake county not at eddie lapp's
property but a separate home healed yes
like i said i lived 20 minutes in there
for we were so we were together all the
time
and uh
you know at like like i said before
about rock about ron's parties at the
time i was growing the super skunk
um
the uh the the chem dog 91
mendo perps
uh the black the black domino the snow
the trinity
a bunch of the super dog crosses and
hybrids
um all that type of stuff and so
you know i start helping them get all
this stuff photographed
and and documented
and you know and it was pretty neat in
that regard um because
uh
you know they um
there's a lot of stuff that was like
that's been lost
yeah but there's a ton that's in those
books but there's video but there's
picture evidence and there's various
aspects right
and uh
you know so
um if people are interested because of
that close relationship
um i had a bunch of stuff that ended up
in that book
um
the the i grew the dog both i was in
this process then of growing a bunch of
my favorite strains completely organic
and then full salt
yeah then in the same room at the same
time right next to each other and then
doing a bunch of blind taste tests with
me and my friends and trying to actually
see
yeah
which is better
right so i so there's there's uh the
chem 91 is in there is both dog and chem
dog
grown both ways
uh my mendo perps is in there the snow
the trinity
my super dog seven cut that i lost is in
there which is a hybrid between the uh
myself and the guy from staten island
made this line it's basically a super
skunk chem dog line
um the purple effects
yeah uh which is uh mendo perps crossed
with fx which is a cool story um
actually somebody said coral reef that's
not mine but uh our buddy fletch has
been hunting for that for a super long
[ __ ] time yeah so if anybody knows
where the coral reef is uh hit us up
but anyway like huh that that that um
that superdog thing is is the odd
connection that me and you have where i
spent years and years and years trying
to figure out who made the [ __ ] super
dog by asking around the whole chem fam
all that [ __ ] and at one point i
couldn't get any [ __ ] answers like
half half the people would say yes it's
jesus it's the same thing it's just
another name you know we made it yeah
you know yeah it didn't turn out to be
that way but i remember before we met i
remember in 2010 i made a superdog 2010
trying to recreate what i had read about
in the canada bible because i could
never [ __ ] find it and many many
years later when we finally interacted
i'd realized you were the source of the
super dog and that was really
interesting because it was such a big
long chase for me because of that book
i i remember i mean i i don't really
want to tell the story of how i lost at
all but
um i i remember like i mean i had it at
all those ron parties i passed it out
freely to a bunch of people um i gave a
bunch of superdog hybrids uh to
mandelbrot
and it ended up being a lot of the basis
of a lot of his males uh that he started
using to get started because even back
then
everyone had to use pollen yeah
not that everybody doesn't use pollen
today but everybody had to use like
males yeah like full regular males
reversals were
six seven eight years away
yeah then um so i i didn't even we
didn't even know it was the only
reversals anyone ever heard of is
accidental herms yeah that was reversals
and sometimes if people wanted to make
accidental herms
they would torture their plant
and rotalization
they would make it dry out they would
make it almost die they would [ __ ] with
its life cycle they would just torture
it and see
can i get it to pop a bunch of pollen
right
yeah
so
technique yeah like i don't have like i
lost the super dog i lost the purple
effects but there's write-ups in that
book of it
right
which is pretty neat because then
there's there's at least pictures of it
yeah that's how it got documented and
why we still know about it
yeah and i should tell i should tell a
funny story just because so
uh jason had this girlfriend named
rebecca back then
and um
he uh she was from north carolina and
they had this strain that is is semi
known right now called the mothership
yeah and it was this old ass weird
sativa um and jason just raved and raved
and raved about it and so he got his
girlfriend's friends to mail it to him
in uh in lake county yeah right so
you're thinking today you know with all
the mailing tech that people have you're
thinking some like small innocuous
package or whatever
yeah so this this [ __ ] thing shows up
and it's a box that's about a foot a
foot wide and a foot you know this and
two feet deep right yes
big [ __ ] box
you know
and we open it up
and inside are two mother ships with a
bunch of with a bunch of stuffing around
them in one gallon pots tied to stakes
and they're like they're like 18 to 24
inches tall
yeah so instead of the person mailing us
cuts
they mailed us like
one gallon pots of dirt and 18 to 24
inch tall plants
in that box that's all there was you
open the box and it's like two plants in
there
yeah that's wild but it was so unusual i
think i don't think the post office was
hip yet to like weed and like especially
plants in the mail sending big ass
plants in the mail no probably yeah and
there's actually in that can of bible
there's some uh there's some pictures of
that mother ship because i was one of
the first people that grew it um because
i actually had running grow rooms and
there's pictures of the mother ship at
eddie lep's property there's pictures of
the mothership from my greenhouses and
stuff it was a really unusual plant but
but yeah it got mailed to us in the most
sketch way imaginable
i remember in cana bible i think it was
the mothership that at one point jason
king was trying to say this has to be
related to hp13 because i've never
tasted anything like this that was one
of those extreme speculations that he
was uh known for i mean i should say i
mean he's my friend and everything like
that but you read the descriptions of
like the dog and the chem dog and
different things yeah and i even wrote
down like lineage in history for him
and then when he went to do his artistic
interpretation of what he wanted to
write you read it and you're like oh
that's [ __ ] yeah oh well
oh well but that happens all the time
people talk about all this journalist
quoted me incorrectly or took me out of
context or whatever else
so but at least that's a documentation
and it was there
yeah
you know
um and well so one thing i'll say and
then we'll move on and we'll talk a
little bit about eddie's situation right
is that
um so we did
uh
i'm gonna lose my train of thought but
um jason decided to do a can of bible
release party
for the second can of bible and he
decided to invite everyone that
contributed to the book
with pictures right and everyone that
helped him put together and who's who
and um
they uh and he rented out this very this
very magical place which i don't know if
most people have heard of there's this
place called ore springs in mendocino
county
and it's a natural hot springs
um and you know so it's got all these
like cabins in the woods and stuff and
all this beautiful redwood and it's
right next to the monk huh
no i'm saying yes okay and it's it's
right next to montgomery woods which has
some of the tallest trees in the world
right i think three out of the five
tallest redwoods are all in mendocino
county right next to this this hot
springs yeah so it's pretty magical
place right
so
he does this thing where he throws this
three-day can of bible release party
right and we all get to come and we all
have our little rented cabins and
whatnot and it's the same thing like one
of ron's parties essentially it's a
bunch of seed swapping and trading and
all this different stuff and eddie left
there and and rob clark's there and and
you know uh caleb and sean like all just
all the people i already mentioned
a lot of the same people are there
and a lot of people that contributed to
the book eddie lepp
his whole entourage and all these folks
right so
i got to meet uh one of my heroes
at the time who's that
i got to meet dj short
[ __ ] a that's one of mine that i got
to meet too what a coincidence yeah so
um and that was that was kind of intense
because you know uh as we've mentioned
on previous podcasts you know if you're
on a weed nerd on the forums
you've got this is way pre-cookie too
right you've got all these like you know
test grows and stuff on the forums of
all these beautiful blue families
hybrids yeah and blue and blue work and
you're like holy [ __ ]
yeah so you know i'm in my mid-20s or
whatever and dj's significantly older
and so you feel like you're meeting an
elder yeah and you're just starting to
[ __ ] around you know my buddy from
staten island and myself we've been
breeding for a number of years at that
point with our super dog and different
things
but we finally felt like we were just
getting started and here's this guy
that's like was released in europe in
the 90s
yeah worked with sag martha worked with
dutch passion had canadian stuff had
this whole movie
and everybody back then
was kind of on his jock yeah
wouldn't you say oh yeah yeah everybody
i mean he was kind of a famous guy then
you know he was internet famous him
hempy vic high
uh you know there was some really like
famous
internet personalities on those early
forums yeah yeah
dj's work was one of them he stood out
yeah yes right
yeah and he was one of the first
american breeders
since the breeders who first brought
their stuff over to amsterdam like sam
and rob and all those guys he was like
the next wave of people that got famous
yeah
and there wasn't that much competition
either yeah people say hempy hempy was a
[ __ ]
heavy had a lot of good points but man
was he a tough character he was a
[ __ ] like he was a little booker he
was uh he was he was if you said
something i mean a lot of those guys
like tom hill and stuff
if you said something ignorant they'd
just tear your [ __ ] head off yeah
hippy can't even be put in that same
category he made
he stuck as an idiot yeah he was he i
mean you know i had to deal with him too
much right
so anyway i um
you know dj is at this at this can of
bible release party right and he shows
up at the time i'm all excited but to
him it was probably like there was a
bunch i was a custody right yeah
so he shows up and he's got manila
little manila envelopes you know
with just you know 50 100
of all his lines yeah
which i think back then was only four or
five
yeah it was only a few lines at a time
that he would ever sell they were super
expensive for for the time too
yeah he had blueberry um and he had
huh flow
and blue velvet
yeah and maybe the moonshine
yeah blue moonshine or old time
moonshine one of them yeah blue it was
blue blue moonshine blueberry flow and
blue velvet yep
those four and so
uh
csi and i get to talking to him you know
and uh
i have to say and he's still around and
stuff and all that so he's gonna be kind
of irritated at me but
um it was my first experience with
realizing that a lot of these old-time
breeders
don't know that much
hmm
yeah i mean i thought here i am this
guy's this guy's been doing it 15 20
years longer than me
yeah you know he's made all these
amazing strains everybody's getting all
these amazing hybrids out of them and
he's releasing all these inbred lines
and
who doesn't like the word juicy fruit
tie or purple tie or this or that so
you're all [ __ ] pumped
and then you start talking to him and
he's vague as [ __ ]
yeah he was yeah
like super vague
yeah he's um i think that is one thing
that i have found with people that whose
opinion i respect
everybody that has met dj short
including me has had the same experience
except that he
with me he just told me i don't own my
own company and that was no you know i'm
not gonna
he wasn't he wasn't he was open and he
talked for a long time and we talked for
hours over multiple days
yeah he's shooting a lot more talking
together he was super jovial and and
conversational and all that so i don't
want he wasn't
he wasn't like we were talking about
empty he wasn't a dick yeah yeah you
know but but you know i kind of feel
like having being a weiner myself and
talking to tons of breeders
um if there's one thing you can do you
can talk in detail about your own [ __ ]
yeah you should be able to because it's
your [ __ ] and it's like you're [ __ ] a
weed nerd and you're [ __ ] into it and
it's your nation yeah it's your passion
and you know and you can just do that
[ __ ] off a memory you don't need and he
just kept saying stuff oh i'd have to go
back and look at my notes
yeah i'd have to check my notes and you
know i'd ask him like
why didn't you know
did you ever did you ever back cross or
did you ever use any of your original
genetics again
yeah and he was like no you know he's
like at the time he was like i still
have thousands of seeds but they're so
old and i haven't stored them well i
don't know if they pop
yeah
right
and so i just remember
like walking away from there and uh
just being like just i just thought i
was going to get a wealth of information
yeah
and in the hours and hours that i talked
to him i don't i don't even know if i
got
too many tidbits
yeah
no
you know and then if you read his book
now it's gonna sound like i'm dissing
him it is a very very rudimentary way of
growing inside
it is yeah definitely
now the one thing i will say that i
think is super cool about his book is he
does describe a bunch of uh
weed that he smoked when he was younger
that's my favorite part of the book
and then he also does this thing where
he has this i mean we didn't no one used
the word terpenes back then but he tried
to make like an olfactory chart yeah
like a smells chart and break down what
smells are related to what yeah it was a
really good chart and it was a fantastic
chart i highly recommend it still
because anything that trains you to
speak about things in language is
helpful yeah
yeah so i mean he was talking about like
squirrel cage fans and you know i mean
but that's kind of like you know he kind
of grew in trailers in oregon and
and use that
used very 80s tech and never really
advanced right um
but be that as it may despite being very
disappointed by talking to him about
things i still bought like 400 450 of
his seats yeah every line he had the
velvet the moonshine the blueberry the
flow i bought you know
i don't know 75 to 150 of them yeah
right
um and i and i i went home and i grew
them all out
um i think is the name of the book is
like cultivating exceptional cannabis or
something like that yeah that's it
right off the top of my head something
like that it's got a really pretty flow
plant or something on the cover yeah
extremely purple
i think it's a flow but some other
people have said it's a blue satellite
too like there's some some
discrepancies on that as well well one
of the things i mean when you
interviewed uh chimera and red
yeah you know um you know one of the
things that chimera is good friends with
dj so he's not going to say anything
rude but what he did say is he kind of
basically admitted that he thought that
everything that he had was like the same
line yeah and it was just different
express like
dj would see an expression within the
line and he would be like oh this is its
own thing it's blue velvet yeah and if i
just breed stuff with expressions like
that it's its own thing
but that's not really what was going on
either because he was crossing opposite
to to
opposite when he was doing line breeding
working directional which is what you
don't do it was very artistic take on
breeding for the time and he and in
fairness like we said before i they were
writing the book as they were going you
know like these were guys just getting
into canterbury there was no books to be
had you know at the time when dj was
doing this so mad props to him for
[ __ ] doing what he did i i was able
to
uh
work at the bunch of his work that i'm
stoked on
i'm not as stoked on his uh human work
um as far as
human breeding but other than that you
know like as far as cannabis breeding i
i owe a big debt of gratitude to him i
mean i'm not but i just you know it's
one of those like he
that's the conundrum right is this
you see all this amazing stuff you see
how it all works you get it yourself and
i grew up imagine people listening i
grew out 450 seeds over the next year
yeah
and uh
know i'd like to say i found a few
keepers that i i miss
yeah i did
yeah i did i it it was unbelievably
beautiful a lot of it
especially pre-cookie there was
lavenders there was blues there was pink
there was purple there was various
shades of in between
it didn't have a lot of terps
uh
and it didn't have a very potent high
most of it yeah yeah for sure um but
when i out crossed it to different
things
i got way better weed
yeah than anything of the pure lines i
got from him so you can imagine how
[ __ ] excited i am right because now
there's no seed bank there's no
middleman it's like i'm getting
hand-written manila envelopes from the
guy
yeah the real deal holyfield mm-hmm
am i going to find the fire
yeah here it comes right
you know [ __ ] labeling backing
everything up i mean you know how it
goes when you're running hundreds of
things and you want to keep track of it
what the [ __ ]
yep you know it's uh it's a huge pain in
the ass
yeah i just recently did that i mean
people were talking about you know
popping 450 seeds in the in the chat not
finding anything i just recently popped
almost the same amount of uh
stuff from from uh blue lines and uh
went through all of it and had a very
similar experience now i i i will say
something because there is some there is
like a an economic aspect that we don't
talk about right where back then
um you know most fire indoor was you
know four to forty five hundred
yeah a pete yeah so
it was really easy to grow flower
and have a side room or two with a
couple of lights in each for
experimentation
yeah
you know the the rate you know a 12
lighter could was was everything you
need in life if you wanted to be so
the economics were really easy to allow
people to experiment and [ __ ] around
yeah now things are super tight and it's
gotten quite hard and mathematics and
economics are much more difficult right
in this particular period of time
yeah um but back then
you know it was like that's what kept
the cropping from being boring
i got a question for you this is a good
question this is from the chat but it's
a good question and relevant where did
that swami guy come from was he around
when you were hanging out
so i no
no no no no no
no
that's weird
i mean he's a pretty recognizable
character
yeah
you know yeah you wouldn't have even if
you didn't become friends with him or
whatever like you wouldn't have mistaken
him no i don't think so no and you know
we'll get we'll get to that i don't want
to i don't want to break it up but we'll
get to that um when we talk about the
authenticity part in a little bit here
yeah sure um as far as that goes because
there's a bunch of people that one of
the things about cannabis i'll talk
about super briefly is that you can just
sort of step out of the shadows
yeah and then people are like i don't
believe where this person came from if
i'm i'm i'm who i am i would have known
him yeah
you know
um so you know it's it's one of those
things where uh
there's a lot of shady characters in
cannabis
and there's a lot of and there's a lot
of people who make good and bad opinions
about people on the internet that you
have never met and you don't hang out
with in real life yeah
you know matt and i are friends in real
life yes
you know like we're real life friends
we've made
made real love to each other so uh
you know platonically from a distance
you know all that
um but you know it it's different and
you have a bunch of people who become
fanboys or girls of different people
and attack whoever they want to and
stuff like that you know and it becomes
difficult because they don't know their
enemy
and they don't know their friend
yes
either yeah they know like a a social
media construct of that person sure
which is not the same thing
no
so but we'll get to that in a bit so
scrolling back you've got you've got
ron's parties
right yeah being sort of a nexus for
this thing you've got uh
you've got the can of bible parties
which were another nexus bringing people
together you know
um yeah but i was i have to say i was
super disappointed because i really feel
like
you know if you take home 450 seeds from
four different lines from a breeder and
uh you don't find anything you really
think or one or want to keep you know
yeah that's super disappointing
yeah that it is disappointing that's a
lot of money so it's a lot of my i mean
he gave me a good deal don't get me
wrong it's not like i paid full custody
because i'm at the no he likes to make
money too
but the the yeah but the the size of the
room the amount of just everything that
goes into the economics of growing it's
a lot of money it's a lot of time
and you know like i talked before it was
like you know there's there's eight or
ten american elites of nl5 hayes
yeah i ran 60 70 in l5 hayes and didn't
find any of those keepers
yeah but other people did
yeah you know
um so dj was a disappointment just in
the sense that he comes from like a a
different generation of weed nerd i
think yeah where they're just not that
deep into detail
yeah
you know i mean one thing you can say
about rob clark or sam skunk man it's
whether or not you want to believe a
bunch of what they say or not they're
heavy on detail
yeah a lot of the old a lot of the old
guys you talk to
um you know they're light on detail
yeah they don't remember or they try to
make it up they did it
yeah but they just don't like it's even
the same thing with like the sour
stories or a lot of stuff that happened
in the 90s that we try to get to the
bottom of
yeah they didn't know it was going to be
important
i'm pretty sure dj thought he was always
going to be important based on having
met him i'm pretty sure he always
believed he was going to be yeah i mean
like i said over that weekend i probably
talked for five six hours seven hours
yeah we were there for three days all we
were doing was like
literally smoking weed and hanging out
and shooting the [ __ ] eating food
dude i would have loved to have had that
opportunity with him i just it just
seemed so
not interested in discussing anything
with me and it was it was it was hard
because i i did look up to him so much
and it's not that i lost respect for him
but it's just like
the more i learned about breeding and
hands-on the more i learned about
why his lines turned out the way they
did and why i was having such a hard
time working those lines you know um it
all made sense in the end yeah i mean
you know i'm not dissing him because
like you're [ __ ] around the 70s or
80s or even in the 90s or whatever it's
like
you learn as you go you know you
bottleneck something when it's early on
and that's what you got
yeah you know i i'm not dissing him by
any means because there's a lot like i
said there's i think his lines are
overly inbred
yeah but definitely over the umbrella
but some of the most fireweed at those
ron parties was out crosses of blue of
blue work
yeah so there's nothing wrong with
having an inbred kind of unique to the
cannabis scene line and it takes some
outcrossing to really bring out its true
character
no that's kind of what what breeders
would want something very stable and
worked you know i don't think that's a
dis necessary now of course do i wish
that dj would have repopulated his juicy
tie and his purple tie and his original
wines every four or five years and kept
fresh seed of the original things
yeah sure of course i do do i wish he
was interested in them and didn't just
let them go to [ __ ] even though he had
them
yeah
well yeah i do
um but you know i mean everybody looks
back on when they were younger and was
like boy do i wish i did this
yeah yeah i mean who doesn't have those
regrets about their 20s
yeah you know i don't even remember what
happened in my 20s so right so the
shit's [ __ ] up you know and
so so that's happening um all these kind
of bible things are happening they're
all getting documented in that regard
and eddie leps was another
place that was kind of like ron's
parties or the cannabis parties where
um people overlapped a bunch
yeah because people wanted to come out
and see this guy is growing a thousand
pounds in his front yard
yeah holy [ __ ] yeah he's a wild one now
now it's like it sucks because you know
uh what happened to him is he ended up
going to jail for 10 him and his wife
ended up going to jail for 10 years yeah
um
and you see gardens way bigger than his
all over the place now yeah and he
didn't people should know this he didn't
just go for it okay
he did this crazy thing this is probably
worth mentioning where
the law said you were allowed to have
six plants and a ten by ten
yeah
so he mapped out his farm in ten by ten
grits
and he collected
right
um
you know he collected medical cards for
each grid
yeah and each medical card was tied to a
specific grid
yeah and you could give him
your strains to grow in that grid
and he would do a certain amount of work
like feed it and water it and this and
that but like you could come out there
and do your own de-leafing and your own
various aspect of different things like
that you could put in more work
yeah if you wanted to and really make
your 10 by 10 nice and then there was i
don't need to get into that part of it
but there was a split between him and
you
yeah you know so honestly it's like he
didn't just like blow it up and go for
it
he literally had 10 by 10 plots with six
plants per plot
tied to a medical card and he would just
stack hundreds of them yeah he was just
challenging the government to challenge
their own
like little uh gray areas of the law
that's what he was doing pretty punk
rock i might say yeah super punk rock
super rebellious and he wanted to have
eddie left gardens all up and down the
[ __ ] the highway
yeah he literally felt like most people
wouldn't be able to grow their own
but why couldn't you come
bring your medical card to eddie left
collective
yeah and grow your own fairly near your
house where you could go 10 to your
plants on the weekend
yeah you know and what happened to him
was he
he had this huge plot in his front yard
i'm not going to dig him out i got some
posters from him and a bunch of pictures
and stuff but it's too hard to show like
on the thing
um but anyway he
and then the the last year he had
he decided to get seven acres across
highway 20 from his house in upper lake
and he was going to grow about 13 acres
of cannabis
yeah dead serious 32 000 plants yeah
that's a lot for the time yeah uh 32 000
plants all
documented
right yeah all with all with and i
begged him not to
yeah because i was like dude i don't
think the dea i don't think i don't
think they'll let you get away with it
like i'm worried like they'll come down
and they'll bring the hammer down you
know
yeah some photos of that are in the can
of bible 100 there's a whole thing on
eddie in the can of bible actually yeah
um you know and and there's definitely
pictures throughout the can of bibles
that are from eddie's spot
uh you probably won't recognize them if
you hadn't been there but anyway um
so i begged him not to do it uh some
other friends begged him not to do it
but there was other people that thought
he'd be fired and they were really
pushing their boundaries
yeah they were pushing it hard
um and uh you know he got raided by the
dea
it cost him a lot with 32 000 plants you
know and he
he him and his wife got 10-year
sentences
yeah uh 10-year federal federal
sentences and the [ __ ] the the shitty
thing about federal sentences is that
you have to serve 85 of the time it's
not like the state where you can get off
halfway for good behavior
yeah and him he was a vietnam vet and
him and his wife were older his wife
passed away in prison sadly
yeah um and then he got out and uh
you know the world had changed
he went from being this like rebel
maverick kind of center of attention
which to be honest he was kind of
egotistical and he had you know he tried
to form a cannabis church and
yeah
you know he was [ __ ] that's you know
there's a lot a lot of characters right
so yeah um but he got out in the world
to change now there's all these
[ __ ] doing gardens his size
yeah and it's all fine
and you know he gave up you know um he
gave up a lot for that
yeah and he got hammered pretty [ __ ]
hard and there's people there there's
people that
i i mean i'll mention a few people i
guess you know um
one of the one of the skittles crew that
like that spun off into dying breed and
now is his own person shiloh probably a
bunch of people know
um
i was like the second person in mendo
that shiloh met
yeah um him in dallas uh who's got
another you know who he works with now
um they both were working at eddie's
yeah there was a bunch of people that
became kind of well-known later
that were kind of eddie's farm hands
back then
yeah you know and we're here because it
was a big deal it was a big mess
it wasn't the most organized character
either so you can imagine
you know
he was definitely king of his hill and
he spent a ton of time entertaining and
being himself
you know yeah and then you're trying to
grow thousands of pounds
yeah
you know
uh and uh you know and but we were all
young then a lot of us hadn't none of us
really made our names anywhere you know
it was all people that you know it was
just it was a smaller world
yeah
you know for sure
um
and so but eddie had a bunch of parties
at his house he had a bunch of
gatherings at his house
a bunch of people from spy rock and bell
springs would come down because they
were shocked that he could they did big
[ __ ] up there but they lived such a
crazy lifestyle um they were shocked you
could do it literally like you dr i can
still dr i drive pius house pretty often
still you can see it from the highway
yeah so he was old house yeah his old
house that he lived at for a long time
um yeah and that's the house that's in
the can of bible
you know um and it was like a who's who
of legalization guys uh i should i
should say something else um you know uh
his last years um
jack herrera moved and got a house right
down the street from eddie
yeah i passed by that house too eddie uh
jack herrera was at a bunch of those
parties
um i have some signed books by him and
stuff like that he was over there a
bunch just hanging out you know yeah um
you know he had he had some health
problem right there on the 20 yep he had
some health problems and some strokes
some stroke issues and stuff like that
so some of his last years he was you
know he kind of had like uh
um you know sometimes some parts of your
face don't work the greatest yeah but
his mind was still there
even though sometimes he struggled to
get out certain things yeah um but you
know jack is another hero
yeah he had a whole cannabis cup made
after him he was you know he wrote the
book on the possibilities
yep um you know it was it was kind of a
it was kind of a smaller world
yeah
but it was all those ron's parties
the can of bible parties eddie lep's
whole situation this was all sort of
like a norcal
you know uh emerald triangle lake county
kind of thing that was going on where a
lot of people were fighting were
starting to come off their hills and and
and meet people
you know and it was pretty it was it was
pretty integral to what came later i
think
yeah
you know it was a lot of us that are our
middle age now and are trying to pass
down history
we were looking up to people like eddie
lapp or rob clark or tom hill
uh who is a cantankerous old man
yeah
yeah yeah i mean he was i love nice i'd
love to get him on here but we'll see
well he was a little he was a little
nicer in person but man uh if he didn't
know you and you said something dumb on
the internet you know
yeah he was going to he was going to uh
eviscerate uh
your ego he would rip it out of your
[ __ ] and make you feel like the
smallest little [ __ ] in the world
yeah and people are saying there's very
weather there's people saying oh i might
have met you back then not so it's very
possible
yeah you know that you met me um or i
met you i mean there was a lot of
comings and goings then even at those
parties at ron's parties like um it's
not like i got to meet and like made
lasting relationships with everyone
there
yeah some of them were 20-minute
conversations some of them were hours
yeah some of them were in the tight
circle of people i was hanging out with
all weekend because that's how it worked
some of them were on the periphery i
mean it's just kind of one of those
things and none of us were none of us
were
anything then yeah we were all just a
bunch of young weed nerds you know yeah
tom was like yeah i agree dirty oh tom
tom was super nice to me
but you read some of this stuff when
people ask them dumb questions online
and holy [ __ ]
yeah
right
yeah i mean he's
he was highly intelligent some people
don't suffer no foods no he was highly
intelligent and he didn't have a lot of
patience
yeah i i yeah i i can i can definitely
relate to that sometimes yeah i mean but
you you see that you see that even now
like you get so burnt out
by dealing with people you know yeah i
think the same thing happened uh to sam
skunk man
to some degree oh yeah yeah you know uh
he was probably nicer and more chill and
then you get you have to answer the same
50 questions a billion times and you get
accused of all this [ __ ]
and all of a sudden you're a
cantankerous old man
yeah it's very easy to fall in that
category
you know but those guys were all legends
all heroes to us vic
tom hill
hempy
you know uh these were all like leaders
of the scene you know um and and
old-timers to us
yeah you know tom's got to be i mean
tom's got to be 20 years older than me
i i don't know maybe maybe i don't maybe
50s
you think he's only in his 50s yeah i
think i think you're pretty old actually
i think you're probably older than him
you're in your 60
yeah you know it's all the oil of olay
yeah you know it keeps keeps me young
or whatever but
the reason why i'm babbling about all
this [ __ ]
is
it's where a lot of people because there
was essentially like there was
essentially like
uh
what's the best way to put it maybe the
best way to put it is that
in the 90s most weed scenes were
very isolated to themselves
to very small circles it was very risky
it was illegal everywhere no one was
really chatting
the grateful dead dead tour fish tour
that kind of thing there was some
overlapping things because people would
meet and not be as scared because nobody
knew where anybody else lived
yeah
no i'm not dude i'm 45. matt's joking
nice 60. he's lying i'm 40 i'm 45 no i'm
definitely not 60. definitely not
um
you know but
but you know i mean and i'll say the
same thing too because i just saw uh my
buddy who i was talking to earlier today
uh skunky uh skunk va's on the thing
right i go to ron's party and i am so
hoping to meet
all these legendary people and strains
and [ __ ] and i'm like just hoping to get
hooked up you know
and not to be a dick but like i felt
like i had the chem dog and i had the
super skunk and i had the mento i felt
like i had the best weed there
yeah i was like i had me that tore
people's head off
yeah you know
and and uh you know it's not to be
bragging or anything like that because
it was literally just the luck of the
draw and the luck of my friends
yeah
you know um
and uh and dead tour you know was one of
those things where
um
it was it was sort of like a huge weed
emporium
yeah and it made a lot of these
connections
and it made a lot of these things that i
tied in and the whole reason i came out
to mendocino county
um was because i had a buddy who lived
in ukaya which is in the heart of mendo
um who after 2 15 past was like dude get
the [ __ ] out here why are you living in
chicago
yeah so it was literally connections
from dead to her that like brought me
out here right
so
getting back to what i was saying is
that
in northern california and in dead shows
there was a weed scene
and on the forums it developed a weed
scene
and in the emerald triangle there was
kind of a weed scene right
and then these parties and these events
and stuff was sort of like the first
mixers
yeah they were the first places where
these scenes started to like overlap
where the forum scene and the mendo and
humboldt scenes and the grateful dead
scenes and all these different groups
that have ties to different circles they
start like a venn diagram the circles
start crossing
yeah and i honestly think that's set up
kind of everything for the american weed
scene for later
i think so i really do like none of us
knew it at the time
no by any means it wasn't like we're
like oh we're here for history you know
it was just it but it did it was it was
the merging of things i mean i should
say even back then this was a few years
after ron's parties but
like um
you know i mentioned the purple effects
that's in the uh that's in the can of
bible
maybe i should talk about that for a
second because people might be
interested in that
um the purple the purple part of purple
effects is just mendo perks right yes
and the effects was this old garlic bud
strain that i got from uh the head
grower who worked for tim blake
yeah now tim blake now is very famous
because he's the founder of emerald cup
but back then he was just a big
uh gorilla outdoor indoor uh farmer
yeah and his his main worker was about
my age they had the purple effects and
they gave me the effects which was a
super golden
gorgeous frosty terpe thing right yeah
and uh
you know there wasn't any reversals but
how the the purple effects got made
um
in the can of bible is that i had a
system that got a little stressed
because i had an air conditioner issue
and it took me a few days to get it
fixed
and you know as as csi will tell you you
stress the mendo perps and the [ __ ]
will harm yeah right
so the mendo perps hermed all over the
effects that was right next to it and me
and a buddy got about a thousand seats
jesus eight hundred to a thousand i mean
at the time we were hella pissed and the
reason we got that many was because we
had like these six or seven you know
quarter pound six ounce you know effects
plants all around it
that we couldn't sell
yeah they were chock full of [ __ ]
seed
but we cracked this thing and it ends up
being super turpy
um
you know and all that and it ended up in
the can of bibles gorgeous weed
um and you know i should say that
there's been some battles amongst the
crew we'll talk about that too but um
some of that weed exists still i don't
have it i lost it in a bust but some of
that weed exists still and it's in
um it's in the rose
it's in the sprite
um it got passed around at some of tim
blake's early and you know people should
know that tim blake had this spot called
area 101 in north of leightonville right
yeah and he threw a bunch of weed events
up there and he threw um a bunch of like
essentially like weird raves and
different kinds of like musical
gatherings and and all that kind of
stuff and it was kind of like a scene
and you know the first half a dozen
emerald cups
were all super local events held there
yeah
um and so i passed out a bunch of seed
there was a gentleman that used to work
up there and used to work at reggae a
bunch called fuzzy um that's not his
real name but that's his nickname
and uh
you know and all that and stuff and so
you know he ended up getting the purple
effects from me and and that's who the
you know tony mendo and those guys got
it from yeah and it got blended into
skittles and it got got all these
different things you know and it it
lives today
yeah you know uh now but that was a
total that was before femmes
that was literally an unintentional
[ __ ] up uh where in summer time the ac
went out for two days
yeah and you know it got hopped and then
i put a new ac in and everything was
good and then the mendo p just threw
through pollen
yeah and i had a and i had a feminized
cross um people are asking what about
california black rose as far as i know
it's the same thing same thing um yeah
so what happened to them
is like a lot of cannabis terms
uh rose is trademarked
yep rose is a very specific kind of wine
and there's also another seed company
that has a totally different line called
rose as well relentless and that's not
related to i don't think it's related to
the same dime greek one but uh don't
quote me now that i think about i don't
know
so they had to change it because they
got because as you get legal and you
start entering these things and stuff
you start getting sued
yeah you know girl scout cookies and
thin mint is cookies because they got
[ __ ] sued by the girl scouts
yeah you know the reason why skittles
has z's
yeah you know is they're trying to skate
around these these trademark laws right
so
rosay is russian og
crossed with skittles that's the z
across the purple effects that's the e
and it took second place i don't know
three four years ago or whatever at the
emerald coast
so what i got out of them and and this
this one's been i think i have a
screenshot of it it was russian kush oz
kush
effects cross back to skittles is the
claim yeah something like yeah yeah so
it's something close about that but they
had the the seeds that they had were
purple effect seeds from from fuzzy that
was from me
yeah because back then it was like there
wasn't any
i mean in this same time frame um i
should say this too but you know uh my
buddy from uh
me and and uh uh skunk va's old friend
who um with the chems and stuff we were
working on these superdog projects
together and crossing them to all kinds
of different hybrids and and clone only
as we had
um and my buddy mandelbrot
uh at the time who wasn't into seeds or
breeding wanted to get started with weed
and i ended up giving him a bunch of
seeds and a bun and some clones to get
him started on this project and he ended
up becoming pretty well known
um some of the stuff he got famous for
was based off that work some of it was a
little different from different things
yeah um but the
the reason i brought that up isn't to
like lay claim it's to say that back
then we were very free with trading
things
yeah because no one ever thought that
they could come out of the woodwork and
lay claim to anything yeah
yeah right
yeah that wasn't worried
now it's all like [ __ ] you you can't
breed with my my cut that's mine that's
my seed line i want matt knows this more
than me because
um i i've avoided so far a lot of the
weed politics by giving away a bunch of
seeds for free
yeah and when you sell seeds like matt
uh you end up getting you know i want
half the seeds because you use my cut in
this one cross
i want rep i want you to mention me i
want you to give me money
uh it's my [ __ ] you don't have
permission jobs i have so many [ __ ]
i've had to give just because of seats
it's not fair
not fair yeah it's not you know i mean
do what you love do what you love so
that's what i'm good at so yeah yeah i
mean so there you know there's an aspect
of politics but this was before that
politics
yeah people just swapped seeds people
just swapped you know people just
swapped cuttings people swapped you know
all this different stuff it wasn't like
you know you didn't want your name
attached to weed
yeah because then they'd [ __ ] find
you what the [ __ ] is that
yeah it's ridiculous you know you be you
you get you getting [ __ ] you get you
get in trouble
yeah right you don't want anything named
after you what the [ __ ] is crazy you
know yeah and then and now it now it's
come full circle it's 180 degrees and
now it's like someone's like i didn't
breathe this cut but i did make it
famous so therefore if you're making any
money off it you must give me money
the rule of the mac
and it's in yeah and it's it's in my
terms
yeah you know i want seeds i want money
i want rep i want all three
and all this different stuff but it's
just like those things
i mean it's even like you know people
were asking way earlier in the thing
that i have to sign a disclosure for dj
yeah dj came up with all that all that
this is my [ __ ] you can't do anything
with it way [ __ ] later yeah yeah at
the time there was no
at the time there was no
i mean people should give credit you
know i mean i just saw uh homie
mentioned that people should give credit
you should say
that i got this from this person you
know you also should um if you got a cut
from somebody um you should give it back
to them if they lose it
yeah that's really good etiquette you
know um i've had multiple things that
i've lost
and i've tried to get back from people i
i mentioned the purple effects that's
one of them it exists i can't get it
back without trading other things for it
yeah which i think is uh super shady and
a breach of the code at least the code
when i came up
um you're definitely supposed to
do that there's some honor i mean half
the reason people trade things is so you
don't lose things
yeah because angry girlfriend angry
boyfriend bust fire landlord moving
accident
whatever
you know
all those different types of things
um
you know you trade things back amongst
people you know yeah i mean one of the
reasons you know i'll say this because
he's because he's listening or whatever
but i mean one of the reasons why the
chem 91 didn't get lost
yeah was because there was a tight group
of uh you know four or five of us myself
uh skunk va i see collective my buddy
from staten island who all had it and
all lived in norcal
and you know we all kept it alive
you know people sometimes people got in
trouble some people had to move
sometimes you had to get back from
somebody or whatever and it was like we
were all heavily invested
in making sure these things lived
you know yeah i mean that's that's why a
lot of these cuts are still in our group
you know like in our tight circle
because
you know we all
move around we all [ __ ] yeah you know
he said he's just saying i'll just say
i'll just say this uh and i got to keep
thinking cause i keep wanting to say his
name but skunk yeah i like i have a hard
time bullshitting at pace and reading
comments at the same time
um yeah i mean he did you know he
you know um you know there were some
people that lost it i mean my whole name
you know he just said that i had to give
ic back the cut like five times
my whole name not so dog is because our
buddy from staten island drove up to cic
collective
and got a bag of dog and brought it back
and it wasn't the dog because
dude was dude dude used to party and he
got mixed up and mixed up his clones and
he grew a whole room of chem dog and it
was like romulan or something like that
you know it really was um we had to give
it to him back because he was like what
do you mean it's not it it has to be
you know and i'm like no dude it's not
the dog that's not it we had to call
them up
and homie was all excited he's like i've
never seen it look like this you know
and i was like the reason why you said
everything i i stuck my head in the bag
because i was in the bag i was in the
car with staten island i told it before
and i looked up and i'm like this is not
so dog it's not dog i don't know what
you're talking about you're tripping
you know and
you know that today
that's crazy
that's good because you know they used
to be
yeah they used to be best friends and
i'm not you know there's and i should
there's aspects to stories i always
leave out because they're personal and i
don't think they're super pertinent
yeah i'm just stoked for us because i
want to get both those [ __ ] on
here at the same time with you
it would be cool to get homie to get to
come talk because a lot of the story
people should know and that people are
like oh not so wasn't there this that
whatever else a lot of the stories i
have
um you know come from staten island or
come from skunk va talking to them 20
plus years ago
yeah before the forums before the fame
before he got on and got his handle
skunk va you know before the cut was
getting traded when it was just our
little crew that had it
yeah you know honestly like they don't
come from me
they come from my memory of like what i
remember about sitting around shooting
the [ __ ] and growing weed and and doing
[ __ ] together
yeah you know
um it would be it would be a really neat
uh thing to do
um both to bridge that gap between the
two of them and get them to talk back
and forth you know yeah um and you know
we've been trying to get dude on here
for a long time actually
i've been trying to get skunkier too
he's just so shy he's kind of he's kind
of he's kind of prickly but i mean i him
and i were him and i were you know me
and um and him and and skunk va we've
all known each other a long time
yeah really long time way back and so
you know at certain point you know you
bury the hatchet about different things
um it's hard you know it's hard it's
it's hard being in weed and having all
these like interpersonal you know you
mix business and friendship
yep
you know and people have different
memories about [ __ ]
yeah you know and all that so
uh
you know it uh but yeah it's good i i
spoke to uh
right before the show actually um uh
skunk va and i were talking ab uh
chatting back and forth a bunch via text
about some stuff and uh we have a ray of
hope
on something that we maybe thought was
long lost so
if it's if it so develops i'll report
back
um but that's what that's what we try to
do it's like old friends trying to look
out for one another yeah you only make
it through this world you know the
people are much more important at the
end at the end of the day than the money
or the fame or the [ __ ]
yeah i'm i'm big into people you know i
need enough money to survive you know
but i'm big into people
yeah you know
so
um it's i like to see my friends doing
good i like to see and we've all you
know all of us are like
semi-autistic weed nerds in some way or
whatever you know and like you it's odd
you know living alone or living by your
you know living amongst uh you know
small groups of people
and living weed and taking a bunch of
risks and staying secret for a long time
like me showing my face is [ __ ] nuts
yeah
you know and now i show up weekly
you know and
you know so i just i just thought it
would be it would be cool because this
era is like right before kind of matt
came into things yeah
which is like i apologize because i keep
trying to get
uh shows done where i make it like more
matt's era than mine
um because there's my arrows were
smaller they had an arrow there's an era
where like you know i was having a bunch
of kids and had some issues or whatever
and
and matt was super engaged
uh when i was a little less engaged but
so far i you know i'm gonna drag him
kicking and screaming into his era
where it's mostly him talking and me
shutting up but he keeps making us do
these things where it's it's a little
older
stuff
yeah i think i think it's a lot too
because i've been you know doing the
live feed for a long time and i think
for
this many years i think people are more
excited to hear from someone else for a
bit and i i'm excited to hear like from
an era i wasn't a part of and i think
nobody gives a [ __ ] to hear what i have
to say about something i wasn't a part
of and i don't either so i think it's
it's it's not just about my ego on this
thing i think it's good to to get all
aspects of history on here and you know
there's a thing too where it's like i
mean we didn't know back in the day that
the chem dog was gonna become super
famous
uh yeah it stayed alive um because our
buddy from staten island used to take it
to
like you could meet him outside of any
jerry show outside the warfield and
probably buy a 400 ounce
yeah you know um you know all that you
could
uh you know
um
when's when jerry garcia died you know
um and he decided to and and you know
skunk va came back to california you
know he got cuts from homie and he
started he started growing because all
of a sudden he was settled down
he wasn't traveling and seeing shows and
stuff and that's where some of his
polaroids come from of that old skunk
cut
you know and you know small group of us
were growing the dog and we were always
we called it you know no one called the
chem 91 and all that that's all like
later we all called it the dog
yeah
and you know uh skunk va and our buddy
from staten island they mostly grew
organic
so they didn't want to call their weed
chem
yeah and we're going to call it the chem
dog
i think that picture i think that
picture the super skunk for me at least
and what i'm interested in is one of the
most important pictures that anybody
could have kept that and some of the
josh dog pictures
um yeah those are specifically the sour
picture and or pictures of sauer
pictures the old super skunk super super
[ __ ] important for solving that weird
mystery of like was this super skunk cut
the same as the original super skunk cut
that was hard to that was hard to figure
out yeah and uh that helped a lot i mean
there's a thing too like part of the you
know we don't need to go over it again
um but we'll talk about it just really
briefly we were talking about like ron's
parties and these and the triangle and
the dead scene and all that i mean the
whole reason that the francine
um got taken out east and you know the
super skunk came west and all that stuff
was all because of jerry shows
yeah that our friend and and skunk va
were at
and friends of his from back east and
smoking weed together at the show and
then people wanting that stuff and so i
don't need to you know i wasn't there i
don't need to tell that part it's you
know that's that's he's told that story
pretty eloquently and stuff like that
but
it is it is showing how those circles
overlapped
yeah you know and one led to the other
and stuff like that you know and so you
know huh
let's lock in skunk the a for next week
next friday's got the aov on and he will
be happy to to be performing thank you
skunk va i don't know if he said i don't
know if he's we locked him in but if we
did
we're gonna
chat again this weekend i have a i have
a line on something i thought was long
lost that's dear to both of our hearts
so i'm trying my damnedest to make sure
i can get it back to all of us uh yeah
but we'll see
you know and i do believe
i'm not particularly uh
superstitious
um yeah but i do believe in in the
energy of the plant and i do believe in
the universe a bit like making things
come to you
and i can say for everyone out there
uh for me at least the number one way
that you get the cuts that you want and
you get the things that you want in
cannabis
is by treating the plant the right way
and having the right intentions
yeah
that's what i say because that that's
going to long term that's going to get
the right people to trust you
yep and that's going to lead to what you
want and i do believe the plant has an
energy
and i do believe the plant wants to uh
wants to
um you know
wants to find people that'll keep it
safe
i agree i really do i don't know there's
not i can't prove it obviously but i
believe that there's collectors out
there and the plant hides
yeah in places where it's hoping that
someone cares about it and isn't just
monetarily attached to it
yeah but loves it
you know and a lot of the things that i
have
um i wouldn't have because i would have
gotten rid of them as soon as they were
unpopular
yeah
but i personally liked them and cared
about them
and then there's friends of mine that
feel the same way and that's why they
have their [ __ ]
you know
yeah and so it's it's a general point
among our friends yeah it's a theme you
know and if you get it's like you get
trusted in circles and you know maybe we
can go into this there's an aspect of
like authenticity that we were going to
talk about before right because we are
kind of getting an hour and a half into
it so maybe we can talk a little bit
about this and there's
there's aspects of things where now that
i'm being public okay and i'm starting
to tell some of these stories
um
i should say that there's a lot of
things that maybe like five or ten
percent of the weed community knows
pretty well
yeah um that becomes difficult where how
do you let the other 90 know
yeah so there's a lot of like accepted
facts among small groups of people that
want to trade this kind of information
right sure and then you want to get it
out there
and you get [ __ ] attacked
yeah and so you know matt can attest
that he tried to get me to do this for a
long ass time and i wouldn't
yeah
right i mean well i mean you were just
watching what happened to me and you're
like [ __ ] that i don't want that in my
life i was also like showing i mean i
did i did caleb's event up in uh upbeat
that's right
you know and it was like i showed my
face i was in front of a huge crowd
yeah you know of people and i was just
like oh my god you know i mean i didn't
give my real name but it's still at the
time it was difficult
yeah but
what it comes down to is that if
what convinced me to do it
is is like if you don't try to get some
version of the truth out there or what
you believe to be the truth
and it's just going to be overwhelmed by
[ __ ]
yeah right and there's an aspect where
it's like and i really get upset about
it sometimes
where there's this ig thing where people
pile on each other
yeah okay and you know matt's a villain
on ig
yes i want to be to a lot of but to a
lot of people that don't know him in
real life
yeah you know and if we want to fast
forward a bit before kovid
um matt and i
there was other friends that helped and
stuff like that so i'm not trying to
just to diss anyone i'm not mentioning
but matt and i and a few other friends
kind of like
uh got this idea to throw what we called
like the can illuminati party yeah and
it was sort of kind of based on ron's
old parties and some of those old
gatherings but more modern yeah and we
decided to do it the same weekend as
emerald cup
you know because um
everybody would be in town
yeah so we rented a huge house
and invited a bunch of people over
on friday and saturday night of emerald
cup
and both years you know we had hundreds
of people come through the house
yeah right and believe it or not nobody
punched matt
no what do you know nobody attacked matt
there's a lot of people that you that
you don't imagine that like respect them
a whole bunch
yeah i don't know about that but they
didn't punch me yeah you know you have a
lot a lot of friends you know there's a
lot of friends you get a bunch of
collectors and breeders and weed nerds
and people in the industry that come
through and want to hang out with each
other and you got to realize that like
we were trying to throw an event where
it's like those guys spend all day at
their [ __ ] booth
talking to customers and trying to give
their customers a little bit of
one-on-one time
yeah right and then at the at nighttime
you know they get to come out and hang
with a bunch of people just like them
yeah and trade weed amongst people just
like them and shoot the [ __ ] and you
know trade cuts and talk about [ __ ]
and do all this various [ __ ] you know
yeah and so we really had a good time
those couple of years before kovid
[ __ ] it all up
yeah that was fun dude yeah we had you
know we had a lot of people we had you
know csi and bodhi and kind of i mean
you could go there was hundreds of
people there yeah uh who's who not
everybody but a lot of people you know
some people were busy or burned out or
whatever you know
yeah and so we were trying to recreate
some of those like more innocent time
parties
yeah
and
you know and you know and i brought tons
of weed
and various friends brought tons of weed
and we just have like a huge table full
of jars that were labeled and anybody
could freely smoke
yeah whatever they wanted
um and even even like just like the
forums there was a bunch of friends i
made on ig
that some of the first time they smoked
the headband some of the first time they
smoked the real chem d some of the first
time they smoked this different stuff um
was at these parties
they might hear you talk about it but
they don't actually see your wheat
yeah
you know and then they get a chance to
do it then you get to share a bunch of
your weed with friends and you get to do
all these different kinds of things you
know and so
that part is really neat because
that kind of i wish you went too dude
we're going to have another one after
covid um
you know
there's uh you know it's it's just like
a who's who of people that have been
around for a long time and you would not
believe
how little beef there is
yeah there was none any person there
wasn't any beef it was just a bunch of
friends it was smoking out eating a
bunch of food having a great time you
know trading beans trading cuts making
connections putting faces to names right
yeah
all that different types of stuff
right and so
you have an aspect where
we've had some issues this week where
you know you start having these talks
week by week and like i said matt's a
bit of a villain online and because now
i'm coming out and we haven't even hit
some of the controversial topics yet but
as i'm coming out and talking about
stuff
um you start getting enemies
you start getting people that are
annoyed that people are listening to you
or don't believe your version of events
or you know on ig or on various discords
they want to like disparage your
character and say you weren't around and
say
that you didn't have anything or your
weed was [ __ ] or your seeds suck or
whatever
and honestly like it becomes really hard
because a lot of people that are
listening
you don't know the person you're siding
with and you don't know the person that
you're against in real life
yeah
like in an honest real life
yeah no you know so it becomes hard how
do you choose
you know how do you make stuff happen i
mean there was people that were accusing
me this week of not even see the chems
until oh eight
yeah
you know and then i came out of nowhere
and that all my stories are lies and not
so it just means the stories are not so
and let's let's be fair though like
the the people that were doing this were
people that were in the outer circle of
our friend group and never made it quite
on the in circle because they were
they were bad people and they [ __ ]
people over or they did certain things
people haven't actually been bad
yeah you know and that's my point right
so matt will come out and say
this person's a scammer he's stealing
cuts he's trying to [ __ ] you over he's
trying to take your money
yeah and then that person and like and
and some bots and like a bunch of fake
accounts and a bunch of people that
bought seeds all attacked matt
yeah you know he's a [ __ ] he's a jew
he's fat he's this he is
all these various things they're getting
attacked and so as i become a public
figure a little bit like they start
attacking oh is that that party is weed
sucks this and that everything else and
that's fine people to throw barbs that's
part of it yeah right and i'm not even
saying you should trust me
but what i am saying is that
you know weed as a a lot of people lived
in the shadows
yeah and it's not documented and the
reason why we're doing a bunch of these
stories is because we want to get oral
history out there and we want to do it
in a conversational fashion that doesn't
bore you to death
yeah
and we try to do that and then that
steps on toes and then people are
furious
and so they they they can't [ __ ] with
the story
right
um but so they'll [ __ ] with matt or
they'll [ __ ] with me or they'll say
you're a liar they say oh i know for a
fact he didn't touch kem until after 08.
or he didn't have this or his this his
headband is watered down or whatever
they want to say about matt it's just
the 707. yeah just just some [ __ ]
and it's like
you know and it's like you don't want to
spend all your life [ __ ] like
refuting a bunch of [ __ ]
you know because it's like everybody
that knows me
knows me
yeah
you know and matt and vice versa you
know and so we're trying to get truth
out there
we're trying to to get truth that like
we're not making any money off of
you know a lot of these a lot of these
podcasts are like weed infomercials
here's three hours of why you should buy
my seats
yeah let's talk extensively about you
and why you're great and why you're
integral to the story and why you're a
cannabis historian and why you're so
amazing
and this is going to help you make money
[ __ ] i should have been inserting myself
into all this old [ __ ] god damn it yeah
you know and it's like you do need you
know we do plug for two or three minutes
some stuff that matt's doing or you know
csi or different people at times because
there is a financial element to like
making all these different types of
stuff work right to some degree um but
really what it is is that now that i'm
old and i'm in my mid-40s or whatever uh
there might be people that are 23 that
want to hear
yeah or might be 40 and want to hear the
real truth and then eventually you just
have to decide because there are some
real scumbags
yeah that just come out and insert
themselves and then rely on if you speak
up i'll blow up your [ __ ] life and is
it really worth it
yeah i'll attack and attack and attack
and attack and i'll [ __ ] you over and
i'll make your life miserable for weeks
yeah so shut the [ __ ] up about what you
all know
yeah and there's so much of that
honestly and coming from so many [ __ ]
angles
like it is a headache it's rife for
sociopaths it's rife for shade balls
beans have always been shady
and they're not getting any less shady
yeah
you know they're just not yeah you know
no and there's no way there's but
there's a bunch of us
you know who have been around long
enough
you know i mean there's this running i'm
not gonna call him out or whatever but
like i didn't even it was like a super
long time ago and like me and skunk va
were talking about
whether or not we were gonna go to these
like dead shows in the
city right and he's telling me he's like
man because he was he's he's a little
older than me and he was on tour for
longer than i was so he has more
connections than i do to be perfectly
frank because he's about six or seven
years older than me um yeah you know he
was like dude we could go but he's like
then i'm gonna see this guy i know he
doesn't pay his child support
and i'm gonna see this guy and he owes
my friend 15 grand and i'm gonna see
this other guy and he and you know these
people's backstories and then it's like
you're gonna see some people you're like
so stoked on
yeah and then you're gonna see some
other people and you're just gonna be
like man why can't you be cooler we were
friends
yeah you're kind of a [ __ ]
yeah pay your kids you know yeah pay
your child support pay my buddy back you
ripped them off when you were down and
out you know yeah and that goes on in
weedworld
yes and then uh what city san francisco
at the time at the time both uh him and
i lived in northern california he lived
in sonoma i lived in mendo so we were
thinking about going down to sf and
catching some shows at mountain view or
something
um you know and that's the thing is like
a lot of times i'll talk about things in
like a general sense
um because you start calling out
individual people and then the next week
of my life is [ __ ]
that [ __ ] trying to defend themselves
yes
and
you know and blowing themselves up
yeah and me and homie matt and i and me
and skunk we know a lot of history
yeah not all of it is not all of it is
is beneficial to the people
no unfortunately but then you can't you
know it doesn't pay to spend your whole
life trying to warn the family
about no jack off because it's
whack-a-mole
yeah i tried that i really did and and
it just it did not pay off if it was
detrimental to my career
i will say i don't recommend people do
that for
any reason whatsoever if you have a an
interest in being successful
yeah i mean i uh
so yeah you know i mean there's there's
that aspect and so i'm not saying trust
me or trust matt
i'm saying like if you're giving us your
time every friday night you get to talk
to us at length and ask questions and
stuff eventually you have to maybe you
can hear enough of things that you get a
general sense of who we are
yeah but i will say that ig is an image
and that sociopaths are very very good
at curating an image yeah
you know what they do best
and um you know and yeah someone just
said nobody's perfect people aren't
perfect you're right
people aren't you know um people aren't
perfect and i'm not even trying to judge
people that's why i'm not calling
anybody out by name
yeah i'm just saying a general i'm just
saying a general state of events
i do have someone i was going to call
out by name but um
it's uh it's getting late and there's
one more big thing i want to i want to
get put aside so it's not just my
opinion i'm actually using their words
um yeah i'm not gonna it's not even a
big enough deal really but it'll just be
funny it'll be fun or someone i must
look up to
do it
do what
whatever you were about to do or you're
not no no i i i still need some of the
um
some of the details yeah yeah so because
i don't want it just to be my opinion i
want it to be dude's own words sure no i
get it yeah so i mean and that's kind of
what we talk about like when people are
like the can illuminati you know yeah
the candle illuminati is not like some
kind of organization or membership
there's no do's
you know there's no one that controls it
what it basically means
is that you're enough of a weed head
that you care enough of the history to
hold on to strains to hold onto seeds to
want to dig for the truth
and you talk to other people like that
and it basically it's a it's a
like-minded group
of people and we know who each other are
and it's like even amongst that group
there's not even really trading
no there's just like dude like once you
know it's like uh you know a skunk va
and i were talking earlier today about
it it's like we're not going to trade
anything no like it's like oh you need a
couple of these and and i can get you
this or whatever it's it's not like a
trade it's more just like
you know
yes this is what i have this is what you
have yeah you know i don't think there's
anything wrong with trading because
trading is perfectly acceptable
especially if you don't know each other
but once you've been personal friends
for a couple of decades
yeah it's just friends helping friends
yeah you know and a lot of the ways that
this stuff exists like you know our
history that's really why i'm chatting
is because i don't want all of our
history to be lost
no
i want it to be out there in some kind
of form and it's almost all oral
yeah and with a lot of the forums going
down over the years whether it be from
the feds you know getting a hold of the
icmag server to
uh you know can a collective pot pimp
any of the the the seed depot any of
those that have gone down they had a lot
of uh information on them like c depot a
lot of people that people look at today
as old school heroes and whatnot or
really trustworthy people all popped up
on seed depot and their whole history is
gone because that's that site was gone
the dude disappeared after [ __ ]
everyone over that owned it so um that's
gone but it's in a lot of people's
memories so this is really the only
chance we have to put that out there
yeah and so we're just we're just trying
to we're just trying to like regurgitate
stuff
and get it out there and get different
versions of things
yeah you know
um and
and you know like like anything you know
some of these stories there's people
that have different memories
yeah there's people that have different
versions even like the three or four
people that were there might not tell
the same tale
yeah they were the ones that were there
i know i got a nickname for being a
power bottom at the last party and i'm
pretty sure i was power top
pretty sure
you know but i mean it's cool because
then you get then you get you know these
parties these gatherings and stuff they
really are bonding
yeah they really are where human
connections are made
you get to smoke a bunch of your good
friends weed you get to see them in
person you get to hear what their voice
sounds like and and hear them laugh
you get to break bread and food with
people
you know yeah um and you get to share
weed and share experiences and so i
think that's you know what maybe we can
get the cantaloupe canned illuminati
parties together again
uh now that covid seems to be dying down
and there's lots of people that are
either been infected or vaccinated and
it's not so much like the plague
yeah it was for a few years where it was
shutting [ __ ] down
yeah
but those kind of gatherings are
important and so tonight you know we're
almost at two hours so i'll probably
shut up here in a second but
i just wanted to give like a general
random overview of some of the
overlapping things that were happening
in that era
yeah it really set the stage for
everything that came after
yeah it was really where a lot of
friendships were made it was where a lot
of trading and a lot of seed exchange
was done it was where a lot of cuttings
and a lot of people smoking other
people's weed and learning happened and
then a lot of those guys um ended up
becoming super well known in the
community
yeah
you know
um so you know it it it uh
you know but you don't know it at the
time
no that's that's the funny thing about
history is you don't know if you're if
you're making it you don't know you know
so
um but really what it boils down to is
we're all just people
some of us
care about the plant
yeah uh some of us care about rapping
money and and and you know scamming
people
and there's a big conflict between those
two right now
yeah in the community there's been one
for a long time
yeah but it's gotten more public and i
mean even like you know matt's been
doxxed before
you know and even some of those comments
i was referencing we're not going to
mention this week people were saying my
real name
yeah um not that i cared to some degree
because
um
it's it you know like i'm showing my
face every week so yeah principle of the
thing though you're not saying your
christian name every week no i'm not
saying my christian name every week or
anything like that you know and so
you know but but what's funny about that
is that i can use that later to prove
something that would like blow them up
in the face
yes
yeah and i've been pushed enough enough
times by this human being to
you know just suck it sucks to have to
do it but because
they're saying such extreme [ __ ] like
there's only a few things in life that i
take real personal is when you talk
about a friend's family or you call me a
[ __ ] nazi like
i spent my whole young life this
literally fist fighting nazis and being
punched by them many many many times so
i i take it very seriously when someone
accuses me of such things so yeah and
you're here
and i'm a jewish mexican yeah
that's kind of funny
there's not there's not too many
nazi jews you know it's kind of unusual
but so anyway matt if you want to do
your plug because we're almost two hours
or whatever
yeah so we have our patreon it's called
the breeder syndicate patreon the way to
find it is to go to google and type in
breeder syndicate patreon if you go to
patreon and type in breeder center kit
it's not going to come up because it is
a pop channel and you cannot search pot
channels so go to google type in reader
syndicate patreon uh tomorrow i'm going
to be watching fights if you want to you
know hang out and do some fight watching
we can do that um
we have uh the the santa cruz goat farm
um fem fem lines the the reversed arcade
of train wreck lines um up for sale
right now on the site go check them out
my boy packs a [ __ ] killer dude and
he made some killer things including the
santa cruz blue dream um train wreck
which i'm really really stoked to see
we also have uh me and csi's uh hawaiian
lights drop i'm about to make the
hawaiian lights hybrids public so
everybody can [ __ ] join in and
and grab that [ __ ] um so go check it out
um yeah so i think i think that's it go
go check out speakeasy uh they do all
the editing of the podcast and stuff so
um go give them support and follow and
and i'll just say one thing after matt
did all that you know we're getting up
to 200 230 250 people a week now doing
this every every friday
um thank you all for listening
thank you all for taking time out of
your night to [ __ ] with us and ask
questions as always
you can reach reach me on ig you can
message me um
he's been approved improving or
approving people so i've literally
approved like 1500 people this week and
it keeps going if you really want to get
approved send me a message
and i'll see it and i'll do it faster
for you i'm trying to get through but
everyone i really appreciate you giving
us your some part of your friday night
and we're going to try to get more
topics and more history out there and
keep it fun so thank you all so much
thank you guys uh see you next week
cheers