there we go
welcome back people coming back in
apologies
uh for those that don't know instagram
makes us stop at the hour on the hour
so um we're gonna have an hour
yo back all right people already joining
back in we're back up to
128 so yeah we can just go ahead and
start rolling
every once in a while like i miss people
writing stuff at the bottom because i'm
just holding my phone so i'm sorry if i
missed questions or anything like that
but uh um somebody said that i was
calling
dude uh skunkva instead of skunk va
i would like to say that i'm having a
real all these people
like i call them by their real names you
know
uh these nicknames and stuff like that
that they get used on forums and stuff
this is not
how i speak of them so i'm trying real
hard
yeah it's hard huh these keep
everybody's personal business
personal business and and call them by
their their ig handle or their nickname
or what
they might know of them as you know
because obviously like uh
you know obviously like i don't um i
don't call them by that ever
you know so i'm trying to overcome my
mental uh
you know just and just not just spout
their name over and over again of who
they are
it's hard it's real hard but yeah you're
doing a great job because i knew
uh skunk va um you know
for you know years
before he jumped online and created that
handle for himself
yeah you know so very easy to call him
is made yeah so far i haven't slipped it
um
but uh but you know i'm trying to be
uh you know like i said uh our uh our
our old uh compatriot that we call the
dude from staten island because he
doesn't have a nickname because he's
never been online
really i'm trying with that i'm trying i
mean every most people on this thing
probably know who chemdawg is but
i'm not gonna say his name out of
respect just because
you know um so
um yeah i mean you know uh
toasted rasta yeah i mean the only thing
that uh
you know there's there's a few things
i'm known for i guess uh i mean i got
lucky and i cracked the
the mendo perps which um probably uh our
our good friend csi
is has bred and brought to the public
more than anybody else yes
i just got uh whether you want to call
it lucky or
vibe or energy or whatever i just got
lucky and
and um got any number of different
cuttings and connections and things
that ended up being quite famous later
yeah
and then there's a whole bunch of hoopla
and mystery and [ __ ] that gets
spewed about them
you know yeah yeah he's he's being
[ __ ] humble as [ __ ] because that's
who he is
but but the the reason i wanted to start
off my
the podcast essentially um with not so
dog
is because he is so integrated
integrally tied
into so many [ __ ] strains that are a
base of our whole cannabis culture and
he's
a and he's he's not uh a pea butt so
he's not throwing his name out there
real big and he's just you know
doing his thing i can't even get him to
[ __ ] sell seeds for the life i mean
this guy's been breeding as long as i've
been alive
so yeah yeah i mean you know i didn't
get so far so far as as far as seed
going is
that uh i had a pretty like punk rock
ethos with seeds
and i brought them for me and for
friends
and we tried to make things that we like
and then i gave them out for free
yeah um and uh
so you know the s1s and the mendo perps
rule dude i highly recommend them
i i went up and visited csi and he did
it he just did a big
s1 test run and i got to
get a big tester's pack of a bunch of
the s-ones
and uh i am currently smoking them on a
regular basis
there's a whole bunch of variety in the
line and have you seen the skunk ones
yes to you
yeah yeah so i went up there
uh the day or two before he harvested
yeah we
a few hours in that particular room he
had half the room was a bunch of urkel s
ones and half the and half the room was
a bunch of mendo ps ones and we poked
around
and smelled a bunch of stuff um and so
yeah there is
um mendo p has a wide
and it uh luckily it has a wide variety
of
uh of genetics inside of it there's
dark ones there's there's burgundy ones
there's light purple ones there's green
beautiful they're all black there's ones
that like the bud is black but all the
leaves are green
um strangely and this i never expected
to see this
uh there was actually even some kush and
some pine soul
in maybe about ten percent of them uh
that was interesting that was pretty
surprising to me
you know and uh some of the nicest ones
hermed
but i mean there you go um
blue skies vienna there's not really a
deal between
any of us and blue skies vienna uh you
know
um i would i would call myself i'm
pretty polite
all in all regards and matt isn't so
polite and so
but we both have we both have a pretty
limited
uh patience for [ __ ] you know and so
you know um nobody nobody would be
happier for me to see a whole bunch of
rank roadkill skunk come back in the
community
um but i it's a bummer when people claim
things and then make a bunch of money
off the public for six months to a year
to a year and a half
before the word gets spread that they
don't really have what they have
and then they viciously attack anyone
that wants to [ __ ] with their money
train
yeah and so uh matt is pretty famous
for calling out [ __ ] as he sees it
uh and that endears him to some of us
and then other people take offense to
that you know
um and he you know and so he gets a
bunch of blowback
and then he's willing to give as good as
he gets
at times like that and so you know he
has a number of enemies out there
um but most of his enemies are just
people that
have something to hide yeah in my
opinion
and um and so they try to insult the
person
without insulting the quantity or
quality of his argument
correct right instead of responding to
the fact that they don't have rks
and they don't have rank skunk they make
fun of how tall he is or is breeding
how bad i am yeah or whatever
punk rock sucks and then you know or
whatever the case may be
to throw proof at the situation and
muddy the water so people won't believe
what he's trying to tell which is
basically telling the general public
be wary of this person and don't give
them a [ __ ] ton of your money
you know because it's probably not true
yeah and like like like i said before
uh the the skunk talk the proof is in
the pudding
everyone is going to be really aware
when somebody finds skunk
yeah it's not going to be hard we can
you can bring it to ec
you can bring it to one of these big
events you can crack the jar you can
smoke it with people
and everyone will know that you're not
full of [ __ ]
yeah that's basic and so until somebody
does that
you know or until it gets into my hands
or skunk boss hands or somebody that has
real provenance with the cut uh i don't
even
i mean i would love for my that original
super cut to exist
um you know if it doesn't exist
hopefully people find that terp
in some other combination of things you
know like
um even if a total [ __ ] that i
dislike
finds it and brings it to the meat
community great
yeah great because at least it's there
one of the things that we you know we
should say about
the seed business has always been shady
and the more you learn about a lot of
seed breeders
you have to segregate what you think of
them as personal people
from their contribution to the community
yeah
because some of them are right scumbags
right but they had an
undeniable uh they have an undeniable
contribution that can't be disparaged
sure
they might be a narc they might be an
[ __ ] they might be a cheat
they might be scummy but you know i mean
at the end of the day you contributed to
the gene pool what you did
yeah and so once you've done that you
can't take that away from someone
and all of the all of the old heroes
as it were everybody has the ones they
like more than others
yeah there are almost no honest folk
no not not in the old hero sense that's
it
i will say uh just if anybody if
anybody's out there listening
uh out of the old school ones i would
say
probably the two most honest ones are
uh mel frank i think mel frank in
general what he's said and what he's
contributed to in his part of the
stories or whatever
like i don't think we caught him in any
[ __ ] that i'm aware of i think he's
been pretty
upfront about what he did and how he
contributed to things and i also think
jorge cervantes
is yeah he's been helpful is in that
same boat
and the most important people in the
cannabis community
in my opinion um you know like and the
sort of godfathers of it all are neville
and sam skunk man david watson and
and jim ortega and you know a few others
and um they all have their supporters
and detractors
sure uh strongly and uh there's valid
points of suspicion and weirdness and
character issues at times you know yeah
so this leads into segways into
what we were kind of talking about last
night now
i i thought it was kind of interesting
that in all the years and in this is
including myself
no one has ever asked skunk va hey
this picture that is in the high times
of
the chem dog putting high times the
first thing is that the same
cut that came from your crew
because it's very distinctive looking
right and um
it doesn't look like it man it doesn't
look like it according to you
so there's a guy there's a guy that'll
remain nameless
that has an old nl cut
yeah right and most people probably
don't know this
but um you know matt and i's little
friend crew or whatever
um we have been in touch with um one of
the originators of the whole nl crew
um and we've interviewed and asked them
a bunch of questions and he's
actually been invaluable in filling in
some blanks and some history of what was
what
right and so this kid had this ancient
nl and he was absolutely sure it was
what it was and i was like man you know
if you want to send me
or one of us you know an eighth or a
quarter or something
we'll get it to dude and he can tell you
exactly
yeah and he got all mad and refused
so you know [ __ ] you you're lying yeah
exactly exactly if you don't if you
don't want to get your old famous
cut to the person that bred it
you know and then there's the flip side
of that and i've seen this
i can't even tell you countless times
when someone
hits someone up and they come from the
point of view that appears to be that
they're actually trying to do real
historical research i had this uh i had
this with uh analog selections the guy
who's passing that the math super skunk
to everyone
um he came to me was asking about mass
super skunk in the history and what not
what we found out
and i was just being open and honest
with him hey this is this is what we
know this is it sharing pictures
illustrating like we do
um
i totally [ __ ] got stoned and forgot
what i was talking about
then i'll throw this out there so yeah
here's the thing so
[ __ ] you know uh matt and i are gonna
do a series of things about history
uh hopefully uh you know and that's
really the only reason why i mean i
wasn't willing to show my face for
forever
um but i'm tired of
so many people you know the loudest
voices
uh spewing the most [ __ ] you know
some of that needs some pushback because
the younger generation
and just history in general is better
served
uh in the long run it's better served
like by the real [ __ ] being out there
you know and you know and so
i mean you know you're
some of these discussions are going to
be wide ranging or [ __ ] or whatever but
what's going to happen is is that people
are going to
listen to [ __ ] and then they're going to
use that information
to make their [ __ ] in the future
more believable that's what i was
talking about yes
that's that's what you were and there's
just no [ __ ] way around that right so
yeah like i'll give you a perfect i'll
give you a perfect example okay
and maybe this should be saved for the
podcast or whatever okay
but someone before i even knew
csi someone who was super close to me
and had heard the story of how the mendo
perps happened in detail
okay honestly told that story
to csi yes there was some special
details in there right
and so he met before we before we
actually met a long ass time ago
uh and then lost track of each other but
when we reconnected
um and i told him my past he was putting
me through the i mean obviously people
call him the inspector right so
he's putting ringer and he's asking you
questions and some are true and some are
lies and he's trying to catch you in
[ __ ] you know yeah
he's amazing at it details that if
you're trying to [ __ ] you just
wouldn't have
yeah it's like you're all into murder
mysteries matt right so
yeah so you know a lot of times when
they put a murderer
when they when they report something
they print a couple things that are not
factual
that way when everybody calls and they
tell stories
that they have a lead yeah they weed out
a bunch of the people
that don't know the truth correct right
and
otherwise they'll get hundreds and
hundreds of bad leads
yeah they have to track down and act
like they're real yeah
so you know and and so the more history
that i
that we spout on some of these subjects
you know
um with the double-edged sword for sure
in the future to like
shape up you know i mean there's another
guy that like we
that we won't say you know his name just
did not give him any fame but we pushed
back against a bunch of his [ __ ]
and he's claiming to have cuts from
two or three years before they were
released to the public ever
yeah like they weren't even created at
the time and he slapped a year up there
out in 95 and they're like i've got a 93
yeah well if you were there from the era
you know they're full of [ __ ]
and that's why pip invented the term the
pre-pre and how it got famous
and so you know and you know and so all
that and so
you know i mean uh you know that's the
you know for a long time nobody gave a
rat's ass
about any of these old cuts they just
wanted to knew they just wanted what was
easy and now that this thing has
happened
and the game has changed a bit old
ancient
my uncle my father my secret chemist
friend
hiding everyone's got these stories of
how these long
lost things carefully passed down to
them
and here's the parts of the story that i
remember but it's absolutely
legit yes so you know we go we run
around poking holes in these balloons
because yeah many of them have [ __ ]
parts of the story that simply can't be
true
yeah and then everybody has an unca
everybody has the famous secret uncle
that has the
just the bomb diggity and gave it only
to them
you know that's right and you know
people do
uh whoever just said this people breed
all the same stuff
so that's a problem is that in my
opinion
and i've said this a bunch is that the
90s was the golden era
and the reason why is that a bunch of
stuff
there was a lot of diversity and if it
was good weed it sold
yeah meant that an enormous amount of
people could grow an enormous amount of
different strains of weed
and they would all sell and thus people
would hold on to them
and there was a bunch of [ __ ] and every
single time there's been a name craze
the the early 2000s purple craze with
granddaddy purp grape ape
urkel from me all that stuff
the sour the kush the cookie
the skittles everybody in the community
that's like
i'm going to be a breeder right take
everything i have and cross into the
same [ __ ] thing
yeah right so now you've got
you know and i joke about this but if
you go back and you look at
like european kings and queens right
they all end up inbred always five years
they only [ __ ] each other
you know the family in spain and the
family in england and the family in
germany they're like they're marrying
first cousins they're marrying their
[ __ ] uncle
they're marrying this and this and this
and so now
the amount of things you have that have
cookie in it or cushion it
or this in it there's probably 30 to 50
cuts
that have been bred into [ __ ]
everything oh yeah absolutely
everything everything is popular you
know
i mean i don't know if i don't know if
uh
if archive is still on here or whatever
yeah
exactly you know but i mean you know
docido becomes famous
and boom docidos and everything yeah
boom skittles
and everything boom all these ot cuts
are and everything you know
and all that and so basically over the
last 15 or 20 years
we've been on a massive short-term
bottlenecking project
sure all this diversity and so now we're
all looking around and we're like oh
where's all that diversity
you know because you know i mean we
we've done this whole thing on uh
you know you can hate docido that's fine
you know i mean
to be honest uh you know i find the chem
dog
to be one of my top three or four
favorite things and my buddy
and i have some really good buddies that
don't think highly of it
doesn't work for them very well so you
know when i
if i basically feel like if there's an
elite cutting
it's because there's enough heads that
like it
that yeah enough people that all
commonly agree on it there's always
going to be some heads that don't like
it
for instance my staten island friend
yeah he was a prickly mother he's a
prickly [ __ ] right so creepy
player
yeah he's prickly pear and he is not
easy to calm down
so he only likes things that calm him
down
yeah right he's not going to be a sativa
lover he probably doesn't think any
sativas are elites
yeah he doesn't want to get hyped up or
psychedelic or energized or excited
you know he wants to be mellowed out and
so people look for different highs
amongst things
and uh you know and there's different
strokes and
you know to me an elite is just enough
people
right yeah and and the you know
now there's this whole thing i always
call them midzie elites right where
everybody with
modern marketing we wasn't prepared for
modern marketing
no all these companies all these head
stash all these cali companies all these
different companies everybody has to
have the bomb
everybody has to have elite everybody
has to pump their [ __ ] up everybody has
to use flowery [ __ ] language
you know and really to me is like what
an elite
is is like people were willing to hold
on to that [ __ ] during prohibition
people trade it people were willing to
hold on to it people cared about it
people wanted to like you know uh to
you know and even that a bunch of them
got lost yeah
oh so you might not like something but
if enough people like
i mean for instance you know i don't
like most cookie
yeah you know but there's enough people
out there that love cookie and breed
with it like
you know i might be in the minority in
that regard exactly yeah you can
burn the greatest then it has kind of a
semi-blandish high
you know um and my thing is like i like
highs
yeah people speed that gets me high and
it can be anything from dog [ __ ]
to chem d to dog to
you know i can deal with racy i can deal
with couch lock i can deal with all that
like
i just want it to be potent and
different and if it's a roller coaster
rides
and if it's got terps and and burns
right then that's
me too you know yeah you know um
you know i mean that's the most common
thing is something comes out that's
popular
and then everybody's like oh that guy
sucks or that weed sucks or his weed
sucks
you know because i don't like him
specifically or whatever you know
but that's irrelevant it's like it is if
people use your stuff to breed
you're winning yeah you know whatever
you want to say about neville
you know uh there are a bunch of
cuts that people still hold on to
tightly that come directly from dude
and they're 25 and 30 years old and 20
years old
and and they're still some of the
hardest to get most tightly held
cuts still it speaks to itself
you know um you know i basically feel
like
god i don't want to diss people but i
basically feel like
if you're breeding there's like three
ways to like know whether or not you're
a good breeder
is like can your stuff pop elites
yeah are there any keepers i would
rather
i would rather have a high ceiling where
there's a percentage of absolute [ __ ] in
the line
than a high floor and a low seal
right so i don't care if there's a bunch
of junk in the line as long as the line
can
produce amazing cannabis yeah
if it just produces a bunch of mids and
none of it's too bad and none of it's
too great
i don't think that's particularly
impressive no it's not personally you
know
like and if someone takes your stuff and
they start breeding with it
that's impressive because that means
other breeders want to use your [ __ ]
exactly it's worth carrying on in their
lines they find value in it
sure even better than that if someone
wants to take your [ __ ]
steal it rename it try to claim it as
theirs
well then they really like your [ __ ]
yeah that's true
and maybe they steal it and maybe you
don't get any money for it or maybe you
don't get any rep
for it or whatever yeah what did do is
you
undeniably improve the gene pool
and at the end of the day that's only
what [ __ ] matters yeah because at the
end of the day a lot of this no one's
gonna remember a lot of this
like like the amount of people that
actually know who seattle greg is is
[ __ ] tiny
correct yeah but he's a giant given
the amount of people that remember
neville will be a lot smaller
yeah certain on these things people even
super famous people will be forgotten
you know but their weed lives on they
made a contribution to the gene pool
they improved it they made it a little
cooler you know
and so you know i mean that's just one
guy's opinion i'm just one guy
but i mean you know that's kind of how i
view it
it's like i like good pot and
essentially what you're looking for
is you're looking for look you know if
you're looking for elites you're looking
for lebron james
yeah you're looking for the one you know
pick a hot supermodel that you're
personally attracted to you're looking
for that
yeah you're looking for rarity in the
line
yeah it's not very many people that come
out built like lebron james
that have the combination of athleticism
and strength and height and everything
else
you know and it's the same thing with
wheat but it's true it's the same thing
with weed
yeah you know freaking neville says he
grew up thousands of nl5 hazels
yeah over time and the ones that that
are getting traded now are the ones he
selected out of all those
yeah so many so many good nlp haters
it's probably a bunch of junk
oh i'm sure there's a lot in there tons
you know
and all that um you know so
i mean you know it's it's not easy to
find elites
you know i mean i did i you know i went
to amsterdam in the 90s and i bought
hundreds of seeds
and i found a bunch of junk yeah you
know
the mendo perps i got one female yeah
just happened yeah dog you know he
popped
two seeds in the beginning yeah one of
them became kim sis
one of them became dog yeah boom
two seeds there's only one smaller pop
that's possible right
they're right yeah you know two seeds
he got dog boom there you go
you know so sometimes you can hunt and
hunt and hunt and hunt
yeah of course i think that breeding
with air heirloom or land ray strange is
a promising path to finding
elites it just requires a bunch of work
because there's a bunch of junk in there
and you gotta do that junk
like that's the thing is like all the
stuff we're doing today
it's like you know we're building on
what they did 30 or 40 years ago
so you know um in the beginning there's
all these different groups breeding
things and then they they made it over
to europe and neville and a couple
others got to combine them
that stuff got sent out to america and
now we're
grandchildren and great-grandchildren
and great-great-grandchildren
but it's all off the work of others you
know and it took
um yeah i mean uh scab you know uh
scabies on here uh yeah you know
he goes you go that i i watch his feed
he goes through a bunch of sativas a
bunch of
you know he gets a bunch of junk yeah
he'll say i'm sure he'll hop on and say
yeah there's a good amount of junk but
then every once in a while
boom that is not junk yeah
fire you know and that fire makes it
worth it
to get all the junk you know i mean
i bought i bought dozens of nl5 haze
seeds
from the era yeah i never found [ __ ] i
wanted
yeah but yeah the colorado cough
the piff the heights haze 88 the cuban
black haze
dog [ __ ] hunk the dog [ __ ]
you know those are just the ones in
america yeah correct
nl5 haze like there is not another
hybrid out there that i know
anyone that i know anyone where there's
a there's that many
name deletes that still exist yeah i
don't either i really don't
literally has double digit named elites
that have survived
both in america and europe and yeah
right there is the only and chem dogs
like cuts like that
that spawned a lot of s one and backseat
or the only other things i could think
that
that's that's like that's that's
different lines and different pops and
different things
yeah you know nl5 haze was just like
literally one line
yeah that's true it's a very good point
just one
and it was only it was only there for
what six years or something before they
walked
before they lost the nl5 cup okay before
we start
before we start cutting into our podcast
um territory
let's hit it back let's head it back to
diesel
so we don't uh cut into our podcast
material
all right so so let me just state this
you know like for for so everybody hears
it so
like i mean i don't know you know chem
fam is a weird word or whatever
um i guess you could call me chem pham
on some level
uh that i got a hold of the cuts um
in the 90s and pretty early but i was
part of the california
side of things which was basically um
me staten island skunk va
and i see collective yeah so a bunch of
the stuff that happened east
that wasn't my crew that wasn't who i
was friends with i didn't meet or know
of those people
other than like stories until way later
um
you know and so uh some of these things
you know i don't have as old of
experience with sure
um you know uh you know the diesel
um you know more than most of them
um as you know uh i have almost no
personal experience with
sure you know in terms of me actually
growing it some of these things i've had
for forever
yeah and uh you know some made their way
to me relatively late
so um
uh yes uh bodhi and i are friends
we don't see each other that frequently
but uh we we are buddies yes
so the reason i wanted to bring up the
jesuit was because
it's amazing for me it's where i come in
i have no i
i had an mss cut i am positive it was
fake early on
um i have no experience with mss
itself however what i have a lot of
experience with is the diesel
and the s-ones and i've i've been able
to go through a shitload of the s-ones
uh over the years and out crosses of the
diesel
and see what it is and um through
finally what i talked about earlier
asking skunk va
is this mass skunk cut in this
high times the same cut that you
and not so were growing and he said no
and at that moment i realized
[ __ ] jesus might not be directly related
to that super skunk cut like i had been
assuming all these years this is a plan
i've carried with me for a long time you
know and before me body was carrying it
for a long time
um and yeah and so
it really changed everything i think i
knew about that plant
uh and i i'm not sure and
at this point we don't know if if diesel
is an
s1 of the mass skunk but we and the mass
skunk may
or may not be uh s1 hybrid of the
original super skunk that was popped by
skunkier's mentor
so yeah that's where we're at yeah i
mean you know it's
um
it's tough because um you know
uh how do i put this in the most
diplomatic way possible
let's just say that you know a lot of
a lot of this history that was being
made was being made by a bunch of young
partiers
yeah yeah young you know ragers
uh oh man look at that
so uh let me just respond to that one
plant-based ma
um i have like a i have like so many
friend requests uh when when 2 15 ended
i i kind of stopped posting a bit
because i was angry
and i haven't really posted very much
since
um you know maybe if you hit me up in
the dms or something like that after
that
and and request uh i'll poke you through
and you can look at some of my
old posts i mean i wasn't super prolific
or anything like that but
there is some cool [ __ ] on there um but
it's it's a couple years old at this
point
uh but getting getting back to what i
was chatting about is that
like let's take chem dog for a minute
right sure everybody everybody wants
chem dog to have all this amazing
information and all this specifics and
all this other [ __ ] right
you know i mean he was he was 17 years
old or whatever in 91
18 when when he popped the 91 the chem
dog and the sis
yeah right most of the stuff that was
happening he was in his late teens early
20s he was a deadhead he was partying he
was having a good time
and he was growing weed in a police
state where he could get in a lot of
trouble for getting in trouble for
doing it get in trouble at one point
you know yeah and so you've got you've
got a bunch of people and people don't
realize
that like you know the amount of
information
that everyone has there has access to at
their fingertips now is [ __ ]
incredible
yeah when i started growing weed in 1993
i [ __ ] you not i bought mel frank and ed
rosenthal's
deluxe growers guide and i bought
jorge cervantes growers guide and i
bought robert connell
clark's marijuana botany and i knew no
one that grew weed and there was no
internet and there was no forums and
there was no [ __ ] and you were scared to
tell anyone
and so information traveled slowly
it spread around the way that it does
now super fast
you know people learn things over time
and and slow you know
and so you know um a lot of people
you know people's memories differ too
you know and like
things get famous and then certain
people get asked hey
give me the play-by-play of what you
were doing when you were taking a bunch
of acid at 21 years old and chasing
girls
running around doing all this stuff i
really want to know specifically what
happened
yeah and you're like oh okay uh
so yeah so then this happened and then
and then we all know like
just like getting back to your true
crime thing right they've determined
that one of the worst forms of evidence
ever
is eyewitnesses yeah absolutely
that they've just proven that people's
memories are [ __ ] up
yeah they're not the greatest and people
can have
if you've ever had a business partner
you've ever had a your you ever had a
grow partner or whatever and you end up
not liking each other at the end
both of you have like very different
opinions of how that [ __ ] started
sure yeah you know [ __ ] happened and
whatever happened happened but people
can have very different mindsets about
what happened
yeah absolutely you know and so
you know i mean um you know maybe that
gets saved for the podcast or whatever
whenever i whenever i poke holes in
somebody's gig
you know it's not like to i'm not trying
to chop anybody down
it's mostly historical accuracy
yeah you know rather than like i think
this person's a liar did you hear not so
dog he just said that guy's [ __ ]
scumbag you know but
you know i don't really yeah you know
and so
we don't know when diesel was made no
we don't know when the seeds were made
we don't know
how many years between when the seeds
were made and when they were popped
right correct um you know so
um you know nothing about it actually we
know uh virtually nothing
we know that it was called greg's diesel
yeah that's it
the diesel and it had some pretty orange
hairs you know
yeah you know i mean at some point like
i mean
you know matt and i have tried to figure
out an enormous amount of information
about haze specifically and it comes
down to
the end of the day you know neville has
a story
sam skunk man aka david watson has a
story
they agree on a large variety of the
parts there's some parts they don't
agree
and there's not very good like external
evidence
to like lean one way or the other yeah
so diesel's that way yes we don't
know when i mean people say day wrecker
dude
so i mean the heck we can talk about
that on the podcast or whatever but
the headband the headbands the sours
that whole family and how all that [ __ ]
works that story is nuts
that's a [ __ ] even us
multiple people intimately involved in
the creation of it
and being able to pick their brains at
length
right yeah like to figure it out you get
a bunch of info
but there's still parts where you're
like oh [ __ ] you know yeah
but that's not uh that's not easy to
determine
and so day wrecker headband
sour this this this this there's these
names that are interchangeable
right same thing with you know um
the 88 haze the heights haze the pip
cuban black haze all that like
those names get used interchangeably but
they're
the same cut no and knowing the people
that know enough of the differences to
actually say
this cut is this and this cut is that is
tiny
yeah and so so you know uh
geez you know diesel is i mean it's
obviously super skunk
yes that's one thing we know about it
for sure is that it has
heavy super scum traits you can look at
it and
you know and you can tell that it's
super skunk yes
super skunk for people that don't know
is
is basically it's a plant called afghan
tea
which is um
uh this guy named jim ortega and sam
crossed it or neville crossed it to a
very skunky male he had that he got from
sam's man and robert connell clark and
that adding that afghan back to the
skunk
created the rankness right
yeah and that rankness um is unmatched
you know it really is it really is
unmatched
and so you know um
you know having grown a bunch of super
skunk myself both the famous cut and the
seeds
um matt you know matt's cut of diesel
is undeniably a super skunk female
correct you know now does it lean away
from
the rank skunk yes yes you know it's
buttery pip pip described it best
buttery skunk buttery skunk whatever you
know
very pleasant so it's in the family you
know yeah
um and obviously it doesn't breed very
easily for
scoops for super skunk oh man don't call
it the murder cut please
oh god please the murder cut no
um he hates that name he hates
it i don't even use the word hate in my
life generally speaking but it's true
it's a it's not a good name for a
variety of reasons
um but uh you know
the um and obviously like you know the
the the super skunk rankedness might be
a recessive thing
you know um you know because obviously
it hasn't been very easy to find and
you've done a bunch of hybridized you
know you've done a bunch of hybrids with
jesus
so it hasn't popped correct you know
um and uh you know oh it's not foot and
mouth dude
that's one of the things where like you
know like the name of it
is uh uh
it's not even like that the the nickname
of that headband is untrue
it just got added so much after the fact
it's very late it's almost a joke now
within the last few years that that
nickname got added to that headband cut
and i would just greatly prefer that we
pick some other
nickname besides that one
uh like 56th day
sorry about the sinking so no we call
that 56 day
really right in all in all honesty it's
not even it's probably a bit longer than
that yeah it is
i've never taken a 56. and and it's not
headband either
really so so there's a whole bunch of
and that that's a whole bunch of
different things you know so
there's a few headbands that are renamed
cushions yes and there's a variety of
reasons behind
why that is um the headband we were just
talking about
there's a really good reason uh related
to
that name that i don't like why they
renamed it you know there's another
headband
that uh you know [ __ ] got renamed
because
you know dudes shyster in a way
um but so
you know if if people really i mean
probably
the closest thing to the original super
skunk in my opinion
my headband cut that we call the la
which doesn't always throw super skunk
terps but at times
can yeah you can crack a jar
and um you know and then uh
uh you know and then the original sour
yeah you know the original sour at times
can
be skunky depending on how you grow it
and what you
how hot it is uh when you pull it 707
headband is
is not the cut i'm discussing um 707
headband
is a strain created by mandelbrot
and he used the the mother of that cut
is the cut i was talking um
and uh you know so people can't see this
because i can't
post it but i posted some pictures of
original
original sour diesel um right next to
uh skunk va's super skunk cuts
um and you can you can just i mean you
can just absolutely see the family
resemblance
yeah yeah you know the spears the way
they form
you know all that kind of stuff uh you
know it's it's just clearly there
so she's not lost
she just got mixed with some different
things and she does exist
yeah you know um right now the breeding
world mostly sucks
um the people that have the real heart
are generally speaking doing it in a
garage or other small areas still
rooms and things like that and the
people that have a bunch of money and a
bunch of time
and a bunch of [ __ ] in the legal world
and all the space in the world
they're not really using that to do a
bunch of real breeding and isolate
things and find it
you might be able to isolate super skunk
from original sour
yeah absolutely absolutely it should
take some
it should take some time but it would
take time and a bunch of space
you know and uh you know
hold on real quick since we're down to
the last 15 minutes
so what i'm going to do uh just while me
and natsu are continuing to talk
you guys can bid in the chat but what
i'm going to put up is a hundred pack
of um diesel and a hundred pack of sour
diesel
are up for bid so place your bids
whatever
whoever has it near the end we'll call
it whatever
so place your vids now in here and me
and nuts are going to continue talking
i mean the other thing i can say is you
know you know i'll
i'll puff him up a little bit since he's
in here or whatever but
i've known skunk va for 20 years right
um and he is uh he is not full of [ __ ]
uh what he knows about uh he knows about
you know yeah
and he has been very honest and you know
and when he made his
and when when he made his podcast you
know uh one of our mutual buddies and
him don't you know
uh you know we don't see eye to eye very
much anymore
um and so he listened to it and
even he had to say you know he was
upfront and honest about it
you know and so um you know the dog the
super skunk the various
you know cuts and strains that that you
know he's had access to
um he is a reliable source on
information for that
you know yes very he's a he's he's a
good dude and he's got love for the plan
and really what i mean i just told him
this the other day is like really what
it boils down to over a long time
is are you good to people and do you
have a love for the plan
yeah people that have a love for the
plant and a curiosity and a reason for
knowledge and trying to find that out
um you know it just it proves itself
over time
you know yeah and he's definitely not
the most
outspoken of the chem fam in terms of
history and stuff like that
uh especially before his podcast um yeah
but he's them he's he's he's reliable
and he's honest about it you know
and so um that's because he's a punk
rocker and he knows what the [ __ ] up
i mean at the end of the day dude
there's just you know like lying catches
up to you
it does it does and i think a lot of
times when people
um especially early on were renaming
relabeling [ __ ]
it was people that were doing it that
didn't understand breeding themselves in
the first place so they didn't know
that later down the line people were
going to be able to pop these things and
be able to see these traits and
expressions be like oh [ __ ]
yeah you know so the naming thing is
tough and maybe
i mean you know it's always hard to
figure out like you know
matt and i are we're going to do a
series of podcasts together or whatever
and we're going to talk about a bunch of
history maybe some of you will find it
interesting or not
um and yeah someone talked about
headband we can do a variety of subjects
i mean as long as
interest um you know we can keep doing
them because we want to get
um we want to get this out there so
there's some pushback
against the people that are just um you
know i don't have any skin in the game
in the sense
that like i'm not making any money off
any of this i don't have
seeds to sell i'm not coming out with
you know i have various friends that
have tried to push me matt's one of them
into like releasing things to the public
or whatever
and it's like you know i mean maybe
that'll happen in the future or
something but really what it boils down
to it's like i uh is you know
um i just i i want the truth to be out
there for the most part
you know and so maybe i'll use a couple
examples real quick with the time we
have left so the nickname thing
it's definitely part of american culture
and it's cool as hell
a group of friends they get a cool cut
they give it a [ __ ] nickname
the nickname sticks it gets passed as
that nickname
right you know i mean for instance
um you know uh um
you know the puck you know the rumor is
is the puck got the nickname the puck
because their buddy used to carry it
around in a hockey puck
canister yeah like a little bubble tape
thing
yeah like you'll know the hockey putt
canisters are these like hard black
round you know there's like they
literally just hold the hockey puck
yeah and he would keep his weed in there
and so it got named the puck
you know um when it really is a hash
plant
yeah no um you know the the snow
for instance you're in csi's crew in
humboldt
you call it humboldt snow yes you're
part of my friend
my friend crew that comes out of like
the eugene glassblowing crew
you called it eugene snow yeah or oregon
snow yeah
oregon snow right yeah the guy and
his girlfriend who i both know who drove
it out from florida
in florida it was called skunk five
oh wow i didn't know that yeah skunk
five
like i literally like i my my kids are
friends with
the the girl who her and her boyfriend
drove it out
she lived just down the way from me um
for forever it was called skunk five in
florida in the early 90s before they
drove it to eugene
wow that's okay so skunk five right
is it shortened is it nl5 skunk one
from neville could be that right
five nlp junk one is it
basic five from sssc oh yeah that was
around a lot
is it something they bought some hybrid
they bought
and then it's the five
yeah you know that could be yeah the
fifth pop yeah
i mean the five makes me think that
it's likely an nl it's it's likely an
nl5 skunk one
if i had to guess either yeah but but
that's just an ex
that's just an example of like in
florida it's one name
and and eugene and oregon it's one name
[ __ ] in humboldt it's another name yep
right another another thing that we
could do is you know
um let's talk about the dog [ __ ] right
yes
yeah dog [ __ ] had one of the coolest
names in [ __ ] cannabis
by far by far one of the coolest names
an inspired name
supposedly came out of minnesota
minneapolis era early 90s it's supposed
to be an nl5 haze
and in in minnesota they called it
electric boogaloo
that's correct which is a killer name
right
uh it gets taken to oregon somebody
renames it dog [ __ ]
the worst name it doesn't even smell
like feces
the people that passed it out it's from
oregon so it gets called dog [ __ ] so
everybody calls it dog [ __ ]
yeah almost nobody knows it's called the
electric boogaloo but it wasn't electric
boogaloo either
and so what this does okay is for every
but for everybody that's out there is it
just makes figuring out the [ __ ]
lineage
of what these things actually are and
what seed companies they came from
really hard yeah it does but he gave
nicknames to [ __ ] right yeah
and so once you give nicknames to stuff
then it's like a very small group of
people
are gonna know what the previous name
was
you know and the only reason why i know
that snow was skunk five
is because i literally know the people
that drove it out in their car from
florida to oregon
yeah well that's creighton too
those people are that's just luck of the
draw
right and so you know
you know those are just two examples you
know i think i think electric boogaloo
is an nl5 haze
starts out as nl5 haze the first crew
names it electric boogaloo the second
crew names it dog [ __ ]
90 of the people that have it call it
dog [ __ ]
yeah yeah that's such though i'm really
i'm gonna push
back on that i'm calling that [ __ ]
electric boogaloo from now on electric
boogaloo is a great name
you know yeah good snow bee called skunk
five
you know it got called snow because in
in oregon
it was white yeah frosty
makes sense yeah you know and uh
you know yeah i mean you know so that
kind of stuff happens over and over
again and so
what that does is that you know because
in america and canada
so many people give names give nicknames
to stuff
um it obscures the fact that
the vast majority of it came from like
four or five seed banks dude
yeah yeah it does you know
and this is why like i really really and
i know you do too like
i push people so hard to to learn the
history of the the baselines
that's why i'm uploading pictures of all
the catalogs so people understand
no it's not snow cap is a large yielding
semi-midsy afghan that became very
popular in mendo and other places
because it
yielded like crazy it is not the eugene
oregon humboldt snow bud it certainly is
not
uh you want to see real snow bud yeah
the electric boogaloo exists
i have it um archive has it
uh i have it uh yeah matt various people
have it
um dog [ __ ] uh it is uh
it's a it is a killer strain uh
it really isn't it's really nice pot so
yes it still exists
um yeah this guy loves snow cap you can
love snow cap it's totally fine i mean i
don't like it that
that much um but you know
these names get interchanged you know
um you know i mean sour used to be one
cut
you know last year you know we throw an
emerald cup party every year
i brought four or five different sours
to the party
uh that i get yeah that was bomb but
none of them were the same
no they weren't you know none of them
were the same and so
these name games get changed and changed
and changed
uh i prefer mendo p to urkel
um but thank you but
i meet you but um as far as smoking
because urkel [ __ ] makes me go in bad
places
you know urkel is uh you know um
urkels you know urkel's interesting and
maybe we can talk about that in the
in the pot in the podcast but i'll say
when i talked about earlier in the
podcast like
um i am not fair family although i have
attended any number of oregon country
fair
events um i have a bunch of friends who
would certainly be considered fair
family and some of my oldest friends why
did i pick the handle not so dog we only
have five minutes left
so we're gonna have to save that for the
podcast that for the podcast but
it's just it's a play on the dog and
it's got kind of a silly funny story
behind it
um i love that story yeah you know so
i don't know i mean uh i kind of got
distracted by that question and now
um oh so urkel you know we'll talk about
that real quick and you know earlier in
the podcast i was talking about on the
live i was talking about how every time
a name strain came along
that became super popular it crushed
what came before
okay so in mendo mendocino county where
i live in northern california
there was so much demand for purple for
a number of years that everyone grew it
and no matter how much of it you grew it
moved
right so i'm literally talking there are
thousands of growers up here
that grew urkel then sour becomes
popular kush
cookies skittles this that everything
else now there's like six [ __ ]
that have oracle
yeah yeah it's crazy it just all of a
sudden died everywhere
it you know i mean you know if there's a
few people that hadn't saved it it would
be freaking gone like the super skunk
yep and we're lucky that csi saved it
and loves it
and decided to breed it into all kinds
of stuff so it can't be lost
exactly we went in 15 years from
literally thousands of people in
humboldt and mendocino county having it
to almost no one in either of those
counties having it it was being sold as
a clone in almost every collective
as a and the legit cut was being sold in
almost every clone
or collected the clone fast forward 10
or 15 years and nobody cares about it
because
you know uh it's not marketable
currently and yeah
nine percent of people that had it drop
it and they grab something
that's more marketable uh breeders
syndicates the podcast
it's available on itunes spotify
sound i don't know and it's coming soon
i had i had some life issues i was
supposed to record it with matt a few
weeks ago
i had some stuff come up it became uh
you know problematic for me to do it but
um
we're gonna keep doing it um uh you know
a lot of you guys probably know fletcher
from archive
and csi um you know matt
and myself all we're all good friends
we're all planning on doing
various historical podcasts and in
various ways shapes and forms
as much of that history out there as we
can uh that we know about
you know and um and have people
be able to hear it you know yeah from
someone that's not trying to sell you
[ __ ]
so yeah and and it's hard for people to
research you know even
even the forums a lot of the forms are
gone uh you can't find a lot of that
info that was up there once
and um it'll be a cool place to have a
resource for people on stream
if you know mostly what you're looking
for and you already know how to weed
through [ __ ]
yeah if you don't know how to weed
through [ __ ] it boy
you know you can get a lot of bad info
okay i'm gonna
give a call uh last minute
on the option so if you're gonna bid bid
now it's a hundred seeds of the sour
bonnet and a hundred seeds of the diesel
bonnet
um yeah sam seeds i still have to record
it
with matt like i said we got delayed it
already should have been done i slacked
i had life issues uh we're going to try
to do it
we're going to do a series of them if
there's interest uh in it continuing
um you know there's a lot of history out
there and we'd love to get it out there
and have people talk about it so thank
everybody for
listening paying attention and uh all
that jazz
all right it looks like no till you're
the man you're there oh wait wait
wait breathe easy came in breathe easy
came in
the minute isn't up breathe easy came in
well i gotta
put that [ __ ] i gotta well breathe easy
is it 1650 so people know i always try
to pin it but
my ig's [ __ ] up anyway we're literally
down to the last 50 seconds so if you're
gonna bid bid now
or forever hold your piece uh breathe
easy there it is
and not so thanks so much man um i'm on
my phone on this so anybody that that i
might have missed some comments if i
didn't respond to you
i wasn't ignoring you i probably just
missed it or i was thinking and talking
and looking at matt's
uh ugly mug so uh all my friends thanks
for listening
and uh you know we'll try to do it again
very soon and make it a little bit more
regular of occurrence
all right lots of love bud have a great
evening
you too thank you
thanks everyone lots of love um i'll
message
i'll message you uh breathe easy