[Music]
there we go
i just had to play this again i'm gonna
force everyone to watch it because it's
real funny before i started
when i was in high school
i tried to activate straight you know
play football
[Applause]
i didn't want to act too gay
i remember the time at the football
party in high school we all watch porno
and we jerk off in the same room through
[ __ ] story i was there were you there
i was there i was there i was there i
was there i thought this is kind of gay
porno at the same time jerking off at
the same time i guess that's pretty
straight
[Applause]
anyway that [ __ ] was funny
had to play it
uh yeah that's a fe black beauty with um
custom pickups in it sounds better
so oh yeah i need to bring a natto let's
see
did you get to hear the i just want to
fit in song again i did i did yeah i was
one of the people you forced to watch it
yeah yeah i know it's really good yeah i
mean you've always been fascinated by
male bonding rituals
you know
i wish i had more hands that's all i
mean it you know
make friends that way make better
friends oh damn it let's see
we're going to get my trying to get my
little
skunky guy on
oh look at that
yeah there he goes
all right
here we are here we are
okay
um let's see what are we going to start
off with
what do we usually start off with
i mean we usually start off maybe with
like a general overview of like what
we're actually going to chat about i
suppose okay
you know so
we thought today we would we would talk
about like different parts of
uh growing and flower and like what it
means for you so we'll try to there'll
be times where maybe we'll get a little
technical but we'll try to make it
topical and bring it back to stuff that
uh because there's a lot of different
ways of growing there's a lot of
different ways of uh you know there's a
lot of methods right yeah and if there's
anything in in weed that leads people to
religion
it's the way that i grow is the best way
yeah and i have the best pot
because of this method
right and so it gets really hard to
debate any part about it because there's
so much
there's so much pride i guess
yeah i mean it's it's like art you know
everybody's got ego with their art and
if someone tells you that you know it
could be done a little bit better it
hurts something you know so yeah
definitely and you know there's there's
aspects of
two of like
you know one size fits all
yeah sense of depending on what your
goals are and we'll talk about we'll
break it down into chunks whether you're
breeding or whether you're growing for
pure heads or whether you're trying to
grow commercially on a bit larger of a
scale like there's different pros and
cons to your approach
they're not all the same so it's really
hard to be like oh i just need to learn
this one thing
and this method if i perfect it will
consistently do the best for me no
matter what i'm trying to do yeah
and that's just not the case no no no no
just really not the case you know and
then maybe we could talk a little bit
about like what those methods do to the
flower
sure and some misnomers maybe about how
and everybody thinks that like nutrition
is like the only thing
really that messes with it but there's
temperature and there's spectrum and
there's how you treat it afterwards and
all that that kind of goes into it
yeah you know
um you know and so as a result of that
there's like there's a lot of there's a
lot of people trying a lot of good good
ways to grow cannabis that they're not
putting all the pieces together
yeah you know i one of the most common
questions i get the in in relation to
nutrients and in feed is
um
when people email me about a specific
strain they'll ask like hey
how do i feed it what's it like and and
i try to explain to them the difference
between like you know it depends it all
depends i don't even know what
expression you know you're going for i
don't know what expression the plant's
gonna get in the first place in your
environment so it's really hard to tell
people how you're going to feed because
it's not just strain dependent it's it's
individual plant and individual rooms
dependent and i think it'd be a good way
to illustrate it talking about it
matters it's like trying to be like well
this if you just do this like you can
pick up any woman you want yeah you know
this this this dating method is just 100
effective yeah and doesn't take the
other human being into account you know
and i also thought like this is this is
a little esoteric but there's like uh
there's this really cool book
um by this he writes the new york times
or whatever and his name is michael
pollan
uh and it's called the botany of desire
yeah yeah it's a great book and
documentary and it's a it's a um you
know it's like a plant's eye view from
the world
so i thought maybe too like we rarely
talk about like what cannabis or hemp or
whatever wants
yeah like what it's trying to do and
what it's going for because in order for
us to get what we want
right we have to play with what it's
doing
yeah to convince it to give us what
we're after yeah because what it wants
isn't necessarily what our end product
of smoking it is
no and i mean in some cases you know
like i mean basically at its most basic
level
uh the plant wants to mate create seed
continue the progeny of itself
uh it has zero interest in creating good
smoke for us yeah that's not seedless
seedless is failure genetically to it
yeah um and so there's a bunch of stuff
that that plays into that
you know and we just thought that you
know like we i i you know we we listen
to a lot of these things we hear a lot
of discussions and mostly what i see is
a bunch of people
no offense i'm not trying to piss
anybody off but like patting themselves
on the back for what method they've
chose
yeah and that's the superior method and
people aren't really interested in
hearing different opinions about things
too much
yeah you know there's yeah it's so it's
it's very like it's very cliquish
it is very cliquish whether you're a
salt farmer
or you use bottles yeah right there like
bottle people or you know that's that's
kind of faux pas right now organic wait
you know like not only organics but no
bottles organic yes no bottles or no
bottles knf
living soil you know full salts synganic
uh you know there's all the i even you
know all these different things play
into it and like
and i you know i mean i think that
there's i think that there's a lot of
misunderstanding that goes into all of
it yeah right and so you hear all these
there's all these talks i'm not gonna
sit here and say that i'm some you know
there's other more intelligent people
that can talk about like the pure
nutrition aspect of it
i can give a general overview that'll
probably work but mostly what we're
talking about is like end results
and how to manipulate your plants to get
what you want yeah right and there's
different goals and it's not all the
same
yeah i mean like like
i've talked about this a lot in the past
uh choosing for selection
a lot of when i choose a plant for
selection
or for keepers i'm choosing a plant for
keepers for breeding you know whereas
someone someone else's keeper may not
be that because they're looking for an
immediate production plant that has all
the traits they want right there i want
something that's going to have the
traits that it passes down as opposed to
what it's showing in itself you know
yeah neville and so the old-timers used
to talk about that that sometimes the
breast the best breeders
were not the plant that they would put
into production from that same line oh
yeah yeah very different things there
could be there could be they could be
the same
and they could also just end up being
different
we end up breeding with production
plants
yeah because those are what survived
yeah
for the most part you know uh you know
trying to you know it's not like there's
a bunch of even amongst traders and
collectors like ourselves
we're not you're not trading old males
yeah right no no but you're not getting
like oh that's the 98 male of this and
this you know
no that doesn't you're lucky if you're
lucky if like you know you get a female
from that long ago yeah
yeah i don't i don't think i've ever
heard of anybody keeping old mails like
that from uh the dutch days
no i mean some people some of them do
but they're certainly never going to
trade them for you they they view them
as like the bedrock of their company oh
so much g13 haze mill that's one that's
one that did make it out now that i
think about it i don't know if it's a
step around yeah but yeah rare
yeah very rare rare you know
now with sts and stuff like that it's
even become more rare because they've
eliminated the mail in a lot of cases
yeah
so i don't know maybe we could give it
we could start because it is a little
rambly or whatever but
uh we could we could start maybe with
like what's your goal so like i was
gonna break it down basically into like
three
like big chunks
right there's like growing for you which
is basically trying to make it as heady
as possible and usually relatively small
scale
then there's growing for seed
and then there's growing at a larger
scale for
uh production yeah and there's various
obvious there's various grades and
levels of that
uh and that's a lot of what people are
faced with today in terms of like how
um how do you scale up headies
yeah
yeah yeah that's been a major major
problem for people yeah and people are
realizing that like oh like you know
this method that i've done for 20 years
it's worked great my two greenhouses
yeah well now i've got six 10 000 square
foot licenses and my weeds not as nice
yeah and i think a lot of people
convinced themselves at the beginning of
rec that they were totally going to be
able to scale up you know like it
shouldn't be hard you know right
anyway it just didn't work out that way
and not only not only from a difficulty
standpoint but also certain things that
might be perfectly economically feasible
at a certain scale
you know inputs that you might be using
or whatever um might not scale up
yeah
yeah right and the amount of liquid
you're going to go through and the
amount of this and the amount of that
and the amount of labor it might entail
yeah
uh you know and so and and so all those
things all those things play into it
right so
maybe we'll just start real general and
we'll talk about like the difference
between like growing good weed and
growing for seed
okay
right okay so
you know if you're growing if you're
growing if you're trying to grow for
good weed these days that means seedless
so that means you're going to trick the
plant into constantly
going waiting for pollen that never
comes yes right and so what you're
trying to do is you're trying to give it
you know enough nitrogen enough veg or
boost or whatever and to get it to a
certain size
get it to flower set and then grow good
flour harvest it smoke it that's your
gig yeah right and so that requires a
certain kind of nutrition
right where if you're growing from seed
um you're planning on pollinating it
right and then since it's going to be
making babies like seeds inside itself
you'll probably give it a lot more
nitrogen and you'll give it a lot more
of a mix
um that is is very different than if
you'd smoke it
yeah i i tend to uh feed heavy nitrogen
during uh flour for seeds uh i feed it
like tomatoes a very tomato regimen is
great for seeds keeping them healthy and
viable
but um i i flip out like if people feed
cincimilla like that because it just to
me it just
ruins it you know when you just flood it
with nitrogen for the most part i mean
and so maybe there's an aspect that
people should realize here so
one of the interesting things is there's
this i'll give a plug there's this
company called canna okay which is a
dutch company
that designed nutrition for cannabis
right and the reason why they're special
is that for a super long time when
people were developing nutrition um they
couldn't test it on cannabis because it
was illegal
yeah but canna could so
canna um
you know they they were able actually to
grow different plants you know cannabis
different ways and then test how the
plant actually up took nutrient right
so they had this method of like give it
just enough and nothing more
yeah
right where like i would say american
companies are more super size me like
we'll sell the customer way more than
they need like advanced the 32 product
[ __ ] sweet yeah or you know general
hydroponic you know i just i just mean
like the usage rates it's like go heavy
put a bunch in there right
and so what happens with you know from a
plant's perspective right um you know
plants will sit there and what they want
to do
is they have no idea that there's like
humans taking care of them really right
so they want to soak up as much food as
they possibly can within themselves
so that when the food starts to run low
they have enough left inside themselves
to like carry on the process of making
seed
yes
right so like back in the day you see a
lot of people they're like oh i want to
pack on weight on my flower right and
they would like give boosters or
something heavy at the end
yeah and then you just you end up with
unused nutrient in your stuff and what
can i figured out is that if you gave it
at the at the like early mid part of
flower say like week three on a 10 week
strain
right then the plant would have the next
month to use up that excess yeah and
grow all that flour and boost itself and
then it would still be running out
running low towards the end yeah because
what you want is since you're going to
trick the plant and you're never going
to seed it you don't want a bunch of
that excess stored inside the plant
itself
no
in general
no right and so that's what happens
sometimes when people like quote unquote
pump it or they ride a high ec or they
have a lot of organic nutrition that's
like their soil is hot
yeah the plant just soaks up a bunch
and it and it's got a bunch in there
because it's trying to make sure when it
runs out it has enough to make seed yeah
it doesn't know you're gonna make
seedless
yeah
so you have to like plan your nutrition
around what you're trying to do
yeah
if the plant knew that it was going to
be seedless it just it would probably
not put so much energy into making the
little hairs you know oh yeah and i mean
you know like our buddy uh you know csi
who grows in beds
in his rooms that he makes seed i mean
he puts enough nutrition in there for
six or seven months
yeah he mostly feeds water
because he's not concerned it's really
high nitrogen it's not something he
would ever do if he was growing for a
flower for market yeah it's like a
completely different mix and that's why
it's so bunk
uh you know when he talks about like
when it fails people act like oh well
then you just got a bunch of good heady
weed
yeah no and he's like no i got a bunch
of overly nitrogen
you know
you're not gonna burn the right way like
it's not gonna come out heads because
it was it was a mix for seeds for seed
creation yeah you know and for to grow
heads you kind of want to give the plant
everything that it needs
and then ideally let it use up its
excess before you're done
yeah and it's like
it's also why it doesn't show a lot of
pictures of the actual seed process
making because it's not pretty like it
to feed it correctly to uh
to to have it making healthy seeds it's
not a visually appealing plant you know
some people and the majority people
wouldn't understand that part they don't
even know
it's doing a great job of making thick
healthy tiger striped seeds that are
that are going to be good for customers
but it's not going to look pretty where
if he has different rooms for instance
that he's grown he's using to do like
seed pops and experiments yeah he's
going to like pheno hunt and see what
they are
those soil beds will be mixed at a
different ratio yeah
you know it'll be a lot less nitrogen
you know it'll be a lot more scaled for
flower
yeah you know and then you know there's
and then there's an ac there's there's
other aspects too where it's like plants
really are like people
in the sense that you know you've got
your friends that can eat whatever they
want and like you know and they're and
they stay thin as a rail and you got
your plants that like look at a potato
chip and again gain 10 pounds
plants do that same thing they eat at
different rates yeah they have different
feeding requirements they have different
root systems they drink different
and so what becomes what becomes hard is
like
you know i've always thought when i was
doing bigger [ __ ]
that you're trying to put plants that
drink the same
and eat the same
in the same area
yeah right because i've had situations
where i'm burning one plant
or one line and the other line wants
more food
yeah
right yeah anytime i have purple in the
room that's going on
yeah or or you know you're trying to
grow something that drinks a lot and
really fast versus something that like
drinks slower like kush
and you don't need to water that thing
as much so you end up over watering it
to compensate you know and that's what
makes like that's that's honestly like
people diss monocropping
but that's why a lot of people like to
mono crop yeah because you can dial in
your nutrient regimen or how you're
feeding your plant or your style
right to fit that crop like we have a
good buddy pip uh souvenir seed co or
whatever
and he talks about um you know he was at
our party one year
remember he was he was blown away by how
good that diesel was yeah
and he said you know it was it was you
know the cut was from him at the time
and you know he was used to putting one
or two in the corner
and he couldn't feed it the way he'd
feed a whole room of sour
yeah so it would come out nice but not
perfect yeah
you know because it's one of those
things where it it had different
requirements than the rest of the stuff
he was doing
yeah so it wouldn't come out as nice
yeah sour is also one of those where
it's like [ __ ] you miss it you miss
it yeah it's very easy to miss
you know it's finicky and so
you know there's an aspect to that where
people think that there's a
one-size-fits-all there's a one method
they can they can take the method they
know and apply it to anything
i mean you start to see there's these
like a5 and c5 and the cough and pith
and cuban black haze are starting to
gain in popularity
or even gmo right
yeah if you're gonna have a plant that
takes 12 to 15 weeks
you're going to have to feed it
differently than a plant that takes
eight to ten
yep
you're going you're gonna have to you're
gonna have to veg it for longer you're
gonna have to give it a different mix
and just so people know it's not like
the mix
dictates what happens to the plant
the plants trying to feed on what it
wants
yeah and it's either there or it's not
and i think that's a misconception like
maybe we could talk about that for a
second where like the plant absorbs
salts
yes that's what it absorbs right so if
you're feeding gh or
you know i don't know uh
you know
eagle or 20 20 20 or you know or any
kind of salt or liquid chem nutrition
you're giving it like the 17 major and
macro elements like
in like an iv basically yeah
right but if you if you're fully organic
you're still feeding it those same salts
it's just they're in longer chains so
you have to get various bacteria and and
fungi and stuff to break it down yeah
make it available
right and so
like people don't get that they're like
oh you you know the plant and if you
break it if you took a perfectly derived
organic salt and a salt the gh or
cutting edge or somebody throws in their
mix
you couldn't tell the difference under a
microscope
yeah i i don't even know anything like
even if you were a soil scientist you
couldn't
right no that doesn't mean they're the
same thing
that that's not that's not true so it's
like
because like basically like
you know chem is like you know our
understanding of what the plant needs
organic is more like if you get it
perfect it gives the plant everything
that it needs and then there's a bunch
of like relationships with the with the
soil itself that like it likes and we
don't really understand
you know i have a question i have a
question for you so i i am not
worldly or knowledgeable about organic
feeding i've always been like a housing
garden canada type dude bottles sure and
that's just what i rocked with you know
um
so
when you want to force the plant
to drink what you want it when you're
doing organics do you just do something
to lower the ph or raise the ph to no
you have to you basically when you're
doing organics us i mean there's
different approaches like there's
bottles like for instance like to use
the same thing canna bio canna if you
buy organic bottles you're essentially
buying things where like the company has
taken the time to sort of like cook it
or ferment it or brew it or whatever
method
yeah and those salts are more available
than just adding raw amendments to the
earth
okay yeah so like for instance we you
know if if you were if you're going to
be that kind of guy where you're going
to get soil and you want to amend it a
lot of times
you would get it and all you want to do
is raw amendments you'd probably get it
add your raw amendments and let it cook
for a month or two before you even ever
use it
yeah
you know um and then because what you're
trying to do is you're trying to like
get all those all that bacteria and
fungi and everything time to break down
the organic
food in there
and make it available
right because that's the issue right so
the big difference is like when you feed
salt
you can guarantee that the plant the
availability is there
yeah if the temperature is right and the
ph is right and the mix is right and
your salt it's going to get all that
food
in organics you're hoping that food is
there
but it has to be at a certain ph like it
at certain ph is nitrogen can't be
carried right certain p at certain ph
chem or organic the the plant has to
have that ph to absorb it through its
roots
yeah and certain ones like nitrogen is
more available at certain ph and yeah
there's a range there's like a chart and
that's kind of why people um they give
you that range for cannabis
yeah is because you know you get five
and a half or five point eight or
something yeah there's going to be
certain things that are more available
than in the mid sixes and vice versa
right and it's usually uh you start out
lower and up higher right
yeah i mean if you want to do it that
way so you know it's it's it's one of
those things where like if you have a
well-buffered organic soil
it's probably something you don't have
to think about
okay if you know uh but it also depends
like if you've got a great soil but your
water is ph9 coming out because it's
well water
yeah you might need to treat your water
to not make the life of the microbial
life in your soil harder
okay
right but yeah
so
there's an aspect to it where it's like
you know and i don't think most people
most people look at it it's where it's
like salts are sort of like a cheat code
you know where organics is like the pure
way to go right
and
i don't well i mean there's an aspect to
that i i do think it's true but i also
think that there's some organics that's
dirtier
than salt
you know people think that like salt is
made in some kind of crazy lab when
really it's like mined minerals that are
refined to a certain purity
and when you're talking hydroponic
purity that's like one step below like
pharmaceutical grade
so it's really really clean and it's
designed to run through aerial jets
sprayers drippers all kinds of [ __ ] not
clog
yeah for the most part yeah you know
um and all and all that and so you know
it's low and heavy metals uh the good
ones um you know and that's another
thing too is like when people
people started uh
you know and then you go organic right
and so organic is a label but i don't
think most people get that a lot of the
organic stuff that you get is byproducts
from other industries
i didn't know that you didn't know that
i don't
know if you get i'll give you a perfect
example right if you get bone meal or
blood meal
yeah okay that's organic by law but it
comes from major slaughterhouses
well that makes sense the cows aren't
organic yeah they weren't fed organic
food
you could be getting mcdonald's
hamburger cows
yeah your bone and blood meal burger
king wendy's right think about like the
biggest meat buyers and producers and
that's all mixed together and it's all
it's all the same and there's not
actually a way to differentiate unless
you're really lucky and you know an
organic farm
but it's all certified organic
right is one better than the other
though like realistically so bone meal
is ground up bones from cows right okay
blood meal is the juice and the sluice
that comes off the slaughterhouse floor
and they collect it and like powderize
it delicious right feather meal is the
same [ __ ] it's a byproduct from
the the poultry industry
oh i didn't know that yeah that's better
sense okay you know turkey uh chickens
you know
uh all the parts that they can't sell
you
yeah ground up and turned into
fertilizer
okay right so you have an aspect where
it's like oh i'm fully organic
and then you end up like in the i use
bone meal and blood meal and feather
meal and this and that and you're like
holy [ __ ] you know yeah because it's
it's it's legally organic it's got the
legal label
yeah by law but it doesn't come from
organic animals
blood mill smells like girls periods
it's gross well yeah it is and you know
the issue the issue used to become too
where it's like you know when we used to
be guerrilla and stuff like that or
whatever uh when i first got to
california you use blood meal or
something like that and all of a sudden
you get it wet
and the the the vultures smell it
yeah my dog slips out and they start
circling or the dogs want to get into it
or a bear comes and wants to rip your
[ __ ] up because it's not you'd go put a
bunch of awesome fish emotion
in your [ __ ] and then you get a black
bear
yeah and who wants that who thinks that
there's fish and starts digging for it
yeah you know and then you're and then
you're [ __ ] you know and so
there's an aspect where it's like people
think there's a free lunch and it's like
it takes
even if you're using that stuff it takes
it a while for it to break down some of
it's available quick
some of it not so much and like fish
emulsion and all that that's all from
the you know the seafood industry yeah
it's all the it's all the brewed bits of
the nasty parts that they can't sell you
some of some people like build the soil
or whatever you know like some people
have stopped using uh bone meal because
of the issues with cows and mad cow and
just all the chem
yeah and they're selling you fish bone
meal
okay because you know because it's it's
still bones and still calcium and all
that but it comes from the seafood
industry because it's not quite as toxic
yeah
even though it's organic
so
you could have an organic style where
you could pick all these inputs
where i would rather use can or cutting
edge yeah i would think it would it
would be cleaner to me
yeah you know
even stuff that's clean like baquano or
seabird guano right
where they don't they're not there's
obviously not like factory bakuano or
factory seabird but you know you are
destroying habitat to get it
yeah right there for bats they're going
into caves and for seabirds they're
going to a lot of habitat and they're
scraping the [ __ ] off it
literally to send it to you
yeah and you know do you know why that
[ __ ] comes from like indonesia and peru
and all that not america
i i don't know
because america has osha and you can't
send a 10 year old boy with a bucket and
a shovel into a cave
that's a good point i have watched him
collect the quantity i'm dead serious
[ __ ] up they do it where it's super
cheap and there's not a bunch of labor
law
and they'll do it industrial style and
they'll have a bunch of people with
buckets and they'll have like a bunch of
bulldozers and they'll be [ __ ] up
some huge we have plenty of bats in
america yeah yeah it's just cheaper to
get it out of peru or indonesia and ship
it
because they don't have to obey labor
laws
yeah and kids are great workers they're
great yeah you know and there's not
child labor in there so a kid with a
bucket you know and so it's good i'm not
i believe me i've used tons of
background on seabird guano and stuff so
i'm not dizzy again i'm just saying that
that's the reality of getting it
yeah yeah it's a great nutrient i love
plants from i love brewing teas with it
and stuff like that it's like it's good
stuff but
uh it's not exactly harvested
environmentally soundly and what happens
with the people isn't the greatest thing
i remember the first time i got sent
home
with tea from the hydroponics store my
very first trip
got sent home with compost tea
and i really sat there wondering if i
was supposed to drink this like if it
was some hippie brew like that i was
supposed to drink i didn't understand it
was for the plants
yeah so you know i mean back you know
now we are really in a golden age
of
teas and compost and inputs and
availability i'll i'll say that like i
mean i used to work in the hydro
industry and so i i got to know
how they sourced a bunch of amendments
what the differences in quality were and
why certain why why certain companies
were cleaner and better
yeah versus other ones that were using
cheap inputs and covering it up
yeah right and now you have a situation
that goes on it's really a bummer but
it's like
there's a lot of stuff that's from the
ocean that we used to consider super
heady
right
but now that they test for heavy metals
it's dangerous
yeah because it's got too much lead or
too much arsenic or too much cadmium or
whatever in it yeah you know so you
could you could be like oh i'm using
fish emulsion and this and that and i've
got all this amazing stuff and i even
have a hook
and you're putting all this stuff in
there and then your weed
test high for heavy metals yeah i mean
that's why they tell like women you're
only supposed to eat so much tuna and so
much big fish when you're pregnant oh
yeah because the mercury because the
mercury well that stuff is in you know
you want to get some amazing crab or
shrimp or whatever
yeah it's got it in it because they live
in a bath of it right yeah and so in
some cases it's like people are like oh
you know salts are the evil bad choice
yeah and organics is the smooth reliable
choice
and i think that that there's you know
there's like it's more complex than that
yeah and you can grow good weed with
both
you know there's a lot of organic weed
that's grown that i don't consider
that's that nice
yeah
you know oh yeah yeah i've seen some k f
[ __ ] be [ __ ] wild
yeah and so maybe maybe we'll maybe we
should like get out of the esoteric for
a bit and i'll tell a story that like
like is pertinent to people smoking
right
so
i used to go i used to go to the oregon
country fair okay which is right outside
eureka it's like a famous hippie
festival still goes on uh got delayed a
little bit with covet or whatever but so
i i went up there
and i was i was from chicago and i lived
out in cali for a few years and all that
but so i was all salt back then
because where i grew up and where i came
up like growing weed you used salt
i lived in apartments like there wasn't
you weren't like grabbing soiled you
weren't you didn't have a backyard you
know like you it was like
so anyway but you move out to mendo and
it's like a lot more it's a lot more
like back to the earth back to the land
or whatever so there's a lot of people
out here that grow dirt
and i went up there and i had all this
salt weed okay and it was like the super
skunk and the chem 91 and the mendo
perps and you know sour uh super dog and
stuff like that
and they all loved it
and they were all super prejudiced
against
chemweed
yeah but they loved my chemweed right
yeah and then they all grew organic
and i never knew a bunch of cats that
grew organic like that
yeah and so we were like comparing each
other's weed all the time
yeah you know and so we
uh you know we we ended up
you know we ended up teaching each other
a bunch of [ __ ]
yeah right and i ended up i ended up
going and working a little bit for john
jevens who's written a couple famous
books he lives up in willets by me and
learning as much as i could about
organics right yeah at a time when
like organics was very very like do it
yourself
yeah not very many online didn't exist
really like you know it was basically
you were buying raw amendments and
everything you had to do you had to do
the work yourself yeah maybe there was
earth there was earth juice
yeah earthquake earthquakes yeah yeah
still around there was very few products
there was very few inoculants there was
very few bacteria there was very few
anything it was very
like buy raw ingredients and go for it
yourself right yeah so
i did this project for
i don't know probably four years
where i grew my favorite strains
in my in one of my rooms and most of the
room was dedicated for flour for medical
right but yeah i had a section that side
by side and the same two lights i would
grow the best organic wheat i could and
i would grow the best salt weed i could
yeah of the same strains over and over
and over again right
and then
it was just for head and so i would pass
out a bunch of joints to friends of mine
and stuff like that and it would all be
blind testing and they would just smoke
and tell me what's up
yeah
and that started to shock me
right because sometimes
with certain strains they consistently
preferred the salt
yeah
right and the salt was so much easier i
didn't have to put all that i mean
people should know back then it's like
we made the people that taught me like
we made our own soil in like concrete in
like those concrete tumblers
you know you'd buy one of those no you
know you know you buy your own concrete
tumbler and you put all your elements
and you put everything in it and you'd
stir it up and then you pour it out
you're wearing a mask and i mean i had
multiple friends go to the hospital for
um fungus infections in their lungs
from breathing guano
yeah so it was actually kind of
dangerous you kind of had to like eye
and mask and glove up to be cause you're
working with a bunch of [ __ ] and a bunch
of animal by-products and all this
different stuff right
yeah and so
i would try to make the headiest mix i
could
yeah and i learned that like some
strains
consistently people like the organic one
better
mm-hmm
and some strains people some
consistently like the salt without which
was remember
yeah 100
the the chems and the sours
typically like we're easier with salt
yeah
uh the mendo perps the super skunk a few
different ones would come out really
nice organic
yeah right
um and it's not like you couldn't it's
not like they weren't good it was just
like what you preferred back to back and
i think that's really important for
people i people have been asking me a
bunch because i've been making some
posts about various historical strains
yeah really the only way to have like an
effective comparison is for you to grow
it yourself
in your environment in your room same
time
okay i'm gonna get these four sour
plants yeah and i'm gonna grow them at
the same time under the same environment
right i'm not gonna get it from my buddy
who grows a totally different style and
his room's different temperature
yeah i'm going to like it doesn't you
just have to be able to see it in the
same event right
so when you consider all these plants
all these plants for three four years
were all treated the same way every time
yeah you know
and
and uh you know it was
and it and and so
you know and i have a bunch of obviously
you have a bunch of friends with smoke
weed
so you're giving out a b joints
yeah
right and um
and and trying to get feedback and i
don't think most people ever compare
styles they're doing one style at a time
yeah
right so how do you know what's
different
right and so we were trying to figure
out like me and a few friends we were
trying to figure out well what is better
yeah
what is what is and it was surprising in
the sense that you know and there's
another aspect too where it's like you
start to realize once you start to get a
little bit more educated about it but um
indoor organic is almost never like
outdoor organic
yeah i wouldn't know so well i mean i'll
give you a perfect example it makes
total sense right so
indoor organic is almost 100 organic
right it's like a mixture of peat moss
and perlite and you know or or cocoa or
different things where outside maybe
like 10 of the medium is organic yeah
and the rest of it is clay or
or crushed rocks
minerals are like almost 45 of most
soils
so like that's why they talk about like
there's a six inch layer of topsoil
in a lot of places and that's like your
organic matter and then underneath that
it's a bunch of rock basically it might
be porous rock but crushed rock but
that's what most earth is so like most
people's organic inside is like soilless
with added amendments
yeah like you'd never find like if you
took say like sunshine number four or
something
and rice holes and other [ __ ] you add
all your amendments and you make the
super heady mix
yeah it wouldn't exist in nature
anywhere
your mix yeah it's like a cannabis
specific mix basically for an indoor
garden
yeah so you never actually really
like
any kind of organic inside is like a
series of compromises
to begin with
because you're not like scraping up a
bunch of native earth
yeah and then using that
yeah i mean it's not really organic is
it
well i mean you can't call it organic
anyway organic is like a federal term
yeah that's right it's like i don't even
think legal weed
i don't even think legal weed you're
allowed to use the term organic yet
interesting
i don't think so because because organic
is actually you have to you have to meet
federal criteria
yeah in order to to get the organic
label and not be lying
right yeah but you can't get federal
approval for cannabis because they still
think it's it's it's funky
yeah you know people are saying organ
artificial light is an organic right so
you know and then there's a thing too
where people talk about this is like a
big key word and by no means am i trying
to diss anybody but
what does living soil mean
right you know i always assumed it meant
there were [ __ ] worms and microbial
life a bunch of that [ __ ] right but
almost all organic if it's active has a
bunch of microbial life
sure you know if you if you take home a
well-made tea from your hydro store
that they brewed fresh or you make tea
yourself
you're putting in trillions of living
organisms
into your soil it's alive
you know it typically means when people
talk about living soil they're basically
talking about usually like a some kind
of no-till method or some [ __ ] like that
right yeah but
you know but even that is like do you
know why most people use no-till
i have no clue
to prevent erosion dude
there's a lot of because if you don't
till the earth then when the rain comes
it's not going to wash away into the
riverbank
okay does that make sense
no
no okay so imagine imagine like you're
on a factory farm in [ __ ] you know
somewhere like iowa
okay and you're tilling the earth
like a foot deep you're fluffing it up
and you're making it all light and loose
and then there's torrential rain that
comes in
okay and in that runoff a bunch of earth
washes away into the mississippi
yeah that makes sense right okay so
that's how that's where most of our top
soil went when they talk about the dust
bowl
in uh in in oklahoma
yeah they tilled up all the earth and
the wind came up and it blew all the
[ __ ] earth away
it did there was like yeah because of
the buffalo and [ __ ] there was like 10
feet of topsoil in oklahoma yeah and
they didn't know what they were doing
with with farming and they got a drought
and they tilled it all up and then all
these huge winds came in and they and it
washed it all [ __ ] away
so i had no idea that's what the dust
bowl meant that's what the dust bowl was
it was literally it was literally
people tilling farmland and then the
farmland blowing away in the [ __ ]
storms
so weird
so
no-till is basically like this thing
where in conventional agriculture they
don't want to till the earth and have it
blow away or rinse away in rain
so they don't they don't till the earth
they leave it right and they just dig a
hole for for the plant
but a lot of them use conventional
herbicides and kill all the weeds
okay so no-till inside is like this guy
just commented i thought no-till was
like not disturbing the microbial
content
well that's what weed people say
for no t for no-till outside it's that
but it's also a huge amount of erosion
control
but you don't have erosion problems
indoors
yeah you could till all you want it's
not like you're going to get a wind
storm that's going to blow away your
[ __ ] you know yeah that's why i was
confused when you're talking about a
windstorm i'm wondering how that applies
to indoor for no-till but that's what i
mean but like no-till was designed so
the soil doesn't fly away
yeah and then it gets applied to an
indoor environment where there's no wind
yeah
that's yeah
right yeah and then you know there's
people and when i'm talking about
nutrition i'm sure how many people are
gonna get all upset because i'm gonna
you're gonna start stepping on toes and
they're gonna say oh well no it's about
the layers of
microbial and fungal and this and that
not disturbing them or whatever you know
um but to be honest like cannabis is a
shallow root growth plant it likes to
grow wider than it does deep
yeah and so basically what you're trying
to do with cannabis is give it a not
some kind of aerated good amount of air
and water and the ability for the roots
to freely go where they want
yeah
you know so a hard compact soil that's
not that's not a good job
i i've also been i've also been accused
of being wider than deep this this is uh
wider than exactly
yeah shallow even
shallow some say shallow some would say
shallow
blight is all in perspective someone say
so getting back so you know getting back
to like what all this means is that
you know i i was reading some comments
from some people the other day where
they were talking about like their
friends that do no-till it works amazing
for certain strains
yeah and then other strains they do
don't respond very well to it or you
know you have a situation like we have a
buddy up in trinity and it's like if
you're going to do depths organically
yeah that's a lot harder than a single
season where you can give it you know
food designed for vegetative growth for
three years and months
yeah and then food designed for bloom
for a series of months
it's not as easy organically to like
get two or three rips out of the same
thing a year
no yeah that makes sense
you know and time it perfectly for what
you're trying to do so it's like and i
don't don't get me wrong i think organic
quality weed is like
can be better than any salt
to be honest but i think a lot of people
don't get there
like salt has a way higher floor there's
a lot of poorly grown organic wheat
yeah you know and it's not like they're
messing up it's it's more just like the
availability of the food isn't there
when the plant needs it
yeah
so that you know
it took me years
years and years and years to finally
smoke organic weed that was really grown
well organic and and to me was as
uh
well grown as anything grown
bad acid salts and that was from um mad
elite that dude kills it organic and
changed a lot of my own ego with like
thinking the [ __ ] salts are so much
better so much easier why waste the time
because it was it was really special i
mean it also depends you know like so
you know you've got to fit and this is
kind of like what i said in the
beginning where it's it's like you know
you got to fit your growing style for
what you're trying to do
yeah of course right and that's
important because they don't all fit
you know yeah and
you know if
let's face it like in today's economy
with wheat prices so cheap and you know
no matter whether you're whether you're
in the traditional market or you're in
the fully legal market um you know times
are tough
right and so people are trying to get x
amount of weight per greenhouse or per
outdoor patch or per grow room right and
so you're trying to get as much pretty
weed because people are visual as
possible
yeah right and that's not necessarily
heads i mean even back in the old
traditional days
a lot of the guys i knew that were
running 50 or 100 lighters would get
their heads from people that were
growing six or eight lighters yeah yeah
that's a pretty common thing even now
yeah well the other part of it too is
like back in the 215 days when anybody
with a 215 card could go to a like a
dispensary and excuse me legally sell
their earp to that dispensary right yeah
think about that dispensary there was no
regulations there was no cost of entry
they bought so much garage weed oh yeah
talents dude and they could just pick
based on quality yeah and guys are
bringing in weed that's like you know it
was cut two weeks ago it's fresh it's
still in the perfect form it's in turkey
bags it's like not very regulated and
they can just pick the best and ditch
the rest
yeah
now with all this legality
you know a lot of times some of that
weed doesn't hit the shelf for two or
three months
yeah and it's being grown in these big
salt factories or it's being grown at a
scale where like all the little things
that the egg the eight lighter guy could
do they can't
so sucks huh you you've actually
experienced scaling up major right oh
yeah why don't you talk about that i
i've never done the
except for the big big uh reversal and
having to save those dummies [ __ ]
already flowering crop for a reversal i
had never done major major scale as far
as feeding and all that stuff it was it
was
significantly different especially
re-vegging at that scale it was insane
any you know and there's a there's an
aspect to where you can talk about this
is pretty funny because you know there
was these people that just opened up
like whatever it is like 126 acres in in
[ __ ] socal and they're calling it
craft right yeah yeah uh
everybody agrees that there's a
difference between craft and commercial
yeah the difference is is that people
get
hyphy about like when does that where is
that line
yeah
you know and like i said before i used
to never see the people that would who
are great growers and doing a great job
they still would not get the same
quality weed of their 50 or 100 lighter
that we would get out of a garage sized
scene
yeah
for the most part they just wouldn't
they had way less time per plant they
weren't doing quite as many little
things that made the plants happy
you know like it was a little bit more
commercial and yeah
you know and then there's an aspect too
where it's like
they um so scaling becomes hard and a
lot of times when people scale they lose
quality
so we can talk about that for a minute
too and i'm not trying to diss them but
you look at like the the jungle boys
right
or some of these big you know rockwool
factory farms
yeah they're doing that because they
have all these different rooms
and relying on a bunch of hippies and
weirdos to like hand water everything
right every day is problematic
yeah so you know they're trying to
automate all this different [ __ ] and
then just like work on looking at the
data and then messing with the the
settings and the data and not looking
each individual plant right yeah and so
what they're doing is is that there's a
lot of technology from northern europe
um that basically is the basis of all
hydroponics
yeah grow dan all that they all learned
how to do all this growing tomatoes and
peppers and cucumbers and all these
vegetables
for places that are shitty like northern
europe but have money yeah yeah and you
can go there and you can see hot houses
greenhouses that have tens of thousands
of plants tens of thousands of lights
huge
right so you see these trick systems
that they're installing
they're all based on that
yeah
right yeah so
they get all these things and they're
looking at graphs right and they've got
they've got like the moisture meter and
they're perfectly planning the wet and
dry cycles and they're and they're you
know dialing in their their salts and
everything and it's like even the setup
itself is like a plumbing nightmare
it's so intense
and then people call their weed
cardboard
yeah right because what happens is
they're you're trying to do a
one-size-fits-all
and cannabis actually it turns out it
doesn't like being fed perfectly its
whole life
no
like they've done studies where they've
shown that certain amounts of drought
stress or certain amounts of stress to
the plant
um actually creates more terpenes and
more crystal
yeah i'm saying beat the hell out of
your plant no i've seen it firsthand
though straight stress
like uh
where did i first learn that about it
was it had to do with uh bugs attacking
the plant and and that's why the
trichomes are there yeah bugs like bugs
signal uh you know they they signal a
thing to the plant where i need to make
more thc i need to make it harder for
them to crawl on me i need to make it
harder for them to bite me you know and
yeah so you get these perfect rooms and
everything's perfect and everything's
everything's dialed in and they're like
fine-tuning stuff and they have control
over all their parameters right
and
then their weed comes out
not that good you know and the guy that
like you know like they got a little dry
and a little wilty a few times and they
stressed here and there a little bit
like that weed was happier
yeah there was it was better but
they're trying to grow like a reasonably
good looking product at scale
yeah and they can't have [ __ ] you
know three dozen rooms
and treat it like you have a garage
or treat it like you have one greenhouse
and no job
yeah you know well you know you have a
situation there's people that you that
rig that are quite popular and they they
don't have that many plants and they
have a greenhouse
yeah and that's their job and you can go
out there and you can baby them
and you can give them every little thing
but then you join a legal scene and like
you're working i don't talk very much
about what i was doing but like you try
to develop some things at scale
and you've got to water some acreage
and it's a whole different thing
yeah
and it's not that easy to do
no i can't imagine
you know until there's so much to go
wrong
a lot of people messed up even just
going from how big they were doing just
to like two or three or four ten
thousand square foots
yeah
like and they started really and they
started you know really messing you know
they started really messing up
yeah you know and and so
like a lot of and that's why because
because like dispensaries can't just buy
the best weed from whoever walks in with
a duffel bag anymore yeah they were able
to buy from like a lot of small time
local gardeners
you know and the bay would get tons of
people from
even la la and san diego were flooded
with weed from humble and lake oh yeah
yeah
there was people that would drive up to
my area every week to get to bring it
down to the dispensaries that was their
entire gig
was to flow it right into dispensaries
and so they could they could say yes or
no to any wheat that walk through their
door
right
and
now there's all this regulation and
there's all this thing there's all this
packaging and there's all this testing
and there's all this time and people are
trying to learn how to grow on a lot
bigger scale
and their weed is like
[Music]
yep way down
way down in quality in my opinion
you know and people are going to learn
they're going to get better over time
but right now customers are [ __ ]
because they're paying more than they
used to
and the availability uh is shittier
but at least it looks good on ig
and that and that's another thing ig
[ __ ] it all up
yeah because you couldn't sniff it or
smell it or anything like that like you
you know you could just see it
and so cookies cookies was perfectly
timed for the social media wave
yeah because it was unusually
visually attractive
and very unique looking it definitely
did stand out from what was out there
yeah and now there's a whole thing where
you see so many of these different
strains and a lot of them i think have
been chosen based on looks and testing
and they can be like not to judge it oh
look here's apple fritter and it tested
33 look how fire it looks
and then it [ __ ] is the worst term
bomb on the face of the earth for
breeding oh you smoke it and everyone's
all excited because the the people that
they respect are hyping it and then six
months later you know you're like i
don't think i'm gonna buy that seventy
dollar eighth
yeah it just didn't it just didn't hit
it for me
you know what before before we scoot too
far along i do remember there's one
thing that i wanted to talk about and
when it's uh feeding for breeding as far
as vegetative stuff one thing that i
find a lot of bridges do when i talk to
them and it's totally counterproductive
is when you are running cycles of
different rooms and different different
strains you're trying to do multiple
projects and they're one after the other
after the other
you start learning to
feed differently to slow down the growth
to try to make room and that's not
something that's that's totally
counterproductive and counter-intuitive
but some of us have learned how to stunt
our plants and bring them out of being
stunted because it's just there's no way
to to constantly have that room to feed
in new cycles so you know there's things
you'll do when breeding that you would
never do for production because it would
absolutely just butt [ __ ] you for for
great flour well yeah i mean if you've
got if you've got a big collection of
models and stock then
very likely what you're doing is you're
keeping a bunch at moderate to small
size
under enough light to like keep them
going and happy but nothing too vigorous
and then you've got always moderate
health and then you're planting you're
planning on putting some plants in like
a vigorous very well-lit spot to get
them going
because you have projects in mind for
them and you want to get very vigorous
cuttings and small plants going off them
and so there's a rotation there that
goes in where it's like a fine balance
yeah
hurting to
to not you know if you're someone like
kale you know like like csi or whatever
and you've got 150 different plants
in mom's and then you've got a bunch of
stuff you're keeping for feno hunting
and all of a sudden you've got hundreds
of different strains and and you might
want to slow things down on a bunch of
it
yeah a pheno hunt you might want to keep
it going really slow
yeah you know and even starve it
somewhat
until you see what you have because if
you start pumping it like you're trying
to pump it to get ready to bloom a room
all of a sudden you've got jungle growth
and where do you put it all
yeah
yep especially keeping some of the older
lines the the all five hazes and stuff
like that you get it gets junky so
[ __ ] fast
yeah i guess yeah you know and then you
know and and so you have an aspect where
it's like i just thought we could talk
about it from a flower perspective too
because
you try to talk to people and like the
thing that i get the most when you try
to talk nutrition is like smugness
like they want people
people are smug
oh yeah yeah like they want they want to
know that i'm growing the better way
this way works
you know what the [ __ ] are you talking
about i get two and a half pounds of
light everybody thinks my weed is fire
you know
and i'm not i'm not dissing anybody i'm
i'm not like that's not what i'm trying
to say i'm just trying to say that like
very few people are doing side by sides
to try to see
what methods are giving them better weed
they're growing the same style at one
time and if they change styles they
change it over entirely
yeah you know and so you're not really
comparing you're just and you know most
people's goals are just to sell it
right so yeah there's things with
organic like when i first moved here
there was people that had been using
their beds or using their holes in the
in the hills or whatever for 10 or 15 20
years
and every year those things got better
and better
right because they were able to add
amendments they were able to add you
know bacteria and various things it was
alive it was like old and aged and fully
functional and work and going good to go
if you're going to grow
the first rip or two probably isn't
going to be as nice as the fifth or
sixth one
okay that makes sense because it take
like you know you've heard about green
sand
you ever heard about green sand green
sand doesn't even become bio available
for two years after you put it in
yeah same with uh normal silica you know
it's like one year i think there's
things that are on that are fairly
immediate there's things that take two
or three months there's things that take
a year
you know and so if you have aged if you
have aged stuff you know like a lot of
that breaking down availability has
happened
and yeah and the natural cycle is doing
it for you but if you're starting a
fresh facility
you're going to get a bunch of raw
ingredients or whatever like you know
tossed together and you're going to have
to amend
yeah
you know and so if you're like if if you
probably another thing is that like if
you're a small tent farmer or you're a
small garage farmer and you're just
trying to grow the best you can
don't try to copy some giant scene
yeah they are not the way for you they
are not growing as good of weed as you
could on a smaller scale
you're like you're like a hobbyist slash
farmer
right yeah if you're gonna grow at scale
you're gonna try to have to figure out
how can i take the methods that i like
and scale them up
yeah probably going to sacrifice some
quality at scale
you know
and you know and if you're if you're
trying to grow for seed then
you know then definitely you're not
growing for flour
you're probably going to want to add
more nitrogen you're probably going to
want to top dress with some different
things
you know i also like to use a and i'm
i'm a sucker for power si just because i
used you know regular silica for so long
and didn't understand that it wasn't
really very bioavailable for the plant
and when i started using the power si
stuff because someone was asking about
feeding for veg moms and stuff like that
that's probably one of the the biggest
game changers for me was that specific
additive monosalicic acid or ortholicic
acid because it makes it makes
everything so readily and bioavailable
it's just so fast how quick it uptakes
nitrogen and everything that goes along
with it and i should also say something
too right like so whether you're organic
or salt
uh one of the big reasons why things
don't grow in winter is that the roots
get too cold
yeah and then the pores shrink
and when the pores shrink and the and
the and the relationship between the
pressure both in the roots and within
the the soil itself changes they can't
uptake salt
so if you're feeding with 50 degree
water
and you've got and you're growing with
like canna or you know or athena or any
of these things people are mentioning
and it's too cold your plants are all
going to suffer because the plant's not
going to suck up the nutrition your ph
can be perfect
right it's not that the temperature is
too much for it it needs it needs a
certain temperature range
yeah and there's also a thing too where
it's like water in the 80s holds like
half the oxygen that water in the 60s
holds
so there's actually like a window there
yeah where like the mid 60s to low 70s
is probably the best ratio of like
absorbability versus like
oxygen ratio because the only place your
plant really absorbs oxygen is through
its roots
yeah it takes co2 in through the leaves
and it takes o2 in through the roots
you know and when people over water
that's what [ __ ] the plant up is
there's no oxygen in there they can't
that's the roots
yeah the roots can't breathe so they
drown
right
and so
you know there's an aspect where it's
like if you're growing indoor and you
want to be organic
there's trade-offs like you see these
people that are like oh they're i'm on
the 26th cycle
you know i just add various amendments
over time i just water it the bio you
know the
the organic does what it needs to do the
plant absorbs what it wants when it
wants
but then i have people that grow organic
that grow in pots and their whole goal
is to give it enough food to veg and
bloom to where they want
and then run out of food
towards the end
so that the plant starts to starve
itself for nutrition and you start
getting all those beautiful autumn
colors on the plant
yeah and then when you harvest it it's
used up all of its excess because if
you're growing k f style or you're
growing like stuff that's amended that
you just you know you're no-till and
you're never changing it well then
you're never flushing for instance yeah
and so some people are a big believer in
flush
you know whether you're even salt or
organic some people want to give it just
the amount of food it needs and then
starve it
yeah and some people give it chock-full
food right up until the end of flower
yeah
and a lot of times when you're growing
for a production
you know like people the other thing is
is like when you're growing through
flower and this always used to make me
laugh right is that people want the best
weed
but
one yellow leaf and you [ __ ] up
you know they're looking at a bag and
they're like oh there's a little bit of
there's a tiny bit of brown in there
yeah there's a tiny little bit of yellow
you should give me a deal
yeah this is some [ __ ] up wheat and
you're like no i flushed it for two
weeks it's perfect
right that's supposed to look and yeah
and they're like no no it's got some
funk in it so a lot of people will just
pump it
right up until the day of harvest
because it looks better because it looks
better to the broker it's not going to
smoke as good
yeah but it looks better to the broker
yeah and that's what they care about
they don't want the broker to [ __ ] and
start kicking the tires and try to knock
points off
yeah
right and so then people don't grow as
nice a weed
i mean there's even a thing where
like
you know uh i'll say this about the
chems where it's like if you grow
the dog or what people call the chem 91
now and you take it what we all use to
take it which is about 70ish days
it usually tests between 18 and 22
yeah and it knocks your head off
right
but if you take it 53 or 54 days
it'll still have white hairs all over it
but it'll test 28 to 32 percent
yeah
and so a lot of people that like put it
on the market they take it early
right to get that high percentage
because the the shop and the and the
distro or whatever like it's one they
don't want to give you for a 19 or 21
percent weed they don't want to give you
the price point that's so [ __ ] but if
it's 31 so you'll you'll see weed and
you're like i'll look at this weed and
i'll be like that dog is like two weeks
premium
yeah but it tests at 30
and the shop is happy
yeah the distro is happy and they'll
give you your price
yeah and it's not as good for the smoker
right but yeah a lot in a lot of cases
like these regulations and these new
rules
are not taking the smoker into account
i mean it in some sense though like i
think smokers may have priced themselves
out just by
just by
absorbing
things like cookies things things that
are you know cardboardy with high thc
stuff and they were happy with it
despite most people like when you really
ask them like do you really like like
that you know the form cut do you really
like getting high off that like they'll
be like oh it's okay you know for 20
minutes or 10 minutes and then it's you
know whatever
but
yeah they kind of let themselves be told
what to buy
you know they do and this is where we
ended up
they so there's an aspect one of the
things that's interesting
and it's something i mentioned before
but it bears repeating i guess is like
the first four or five years that they
published like the emerald cup and like
some high times entries for thc
and you were able to see
like you know before people were
breeding by numbers
before a lot of breeders were getting
data on like what you know what what the
thc content was almost everything that
was winning was between 22 and 26
yeah there was like four or five things
in the first five years
like that ever tested in the upper 20s
or hit 30. yeah yeah right i can like
and two of them were chem 91 there was a
strawberry cough there was another weird
one remember how rare the 30 club used
to be yeah yeah it was unheard of until
like
2009 10 people started claiming the 30s
30 right and so now you have this so
basically
all the favorite weed that people were
paying good digits for
was coming in in the low to mid 20s at
best
yeah so it basically means as soon as
you hit high teens to mid 20s that's
where almost all the elites were falling
yeah everything that everybody [ __ ]
drools over from back then kush's sours
[ __ ] all this [ __ ] was all hitting
that range
yeah and then people started growing
because shops were like i'll pay you
more for higher thc
yeah so they start selecting
cuts that test better
yeah
not necessarily ones that smoke better
and start
selecting labs that test higher so now
that's why i say breeding by numbers
yeah so instead of breeding by smoke
testing and what your friends think and
how long lasting the high is like you
were mentioning
or how intense it might be they start
being like oh well this one tests at 32
and four percent terpenes
there is no such thing as a [ __ ] high
30 yet is there
i mean
so i mean there's there's a lot of
things that people do like like uh you
know csi have talked about this a bunch
where there's a lot of labs that over
test
sure because it's good for the distro
it's good for the store it makes an easy
sale everybody likes it
and so he's done experiments where he
sent things off to commercial labs and
sent the same bud to a friend who he
knows is going to do an accurate test
and it might be as much as five or eight
percent different
oh yeah i've seen it much different
vastly different it's insane but the
thing is now you've got five or six or
seven or eight years ten years or
whatever breeding by numbers
and there's a huge 30 plus percent club
oh good good skunk master flex posted
something that's 40 well there we go so
you start getting higher and higher
right and but then the effect sucks
yeah
so then what does it matter
yeah you know i mean i had a blueberry
purple punch tested 34 so you know
anything's possible you can't even pull
those numbers out of individually you
know and what's crazy about that is when
you think about 30 or 35 or 40 like matt
was just laughing about that's the
percentage of thc by weight on the
flower
yes
so yes it's crazy because you start
getting these numbers and it's like is
it just going to be
like
you know how much thc can you pack on a
plant yeah and how much is left for
cannabinoids and other cannabinoids and
yeah and it's not obviously like alcohol
where everclear is stronger than vodka
which is stronger than wine which is
stronger than beer it doesn't work like
that
like there is
there is a certain situation where like
you know csi and i see fletch on there
there's some old school strains that
only test like eight ten twelve percent
yeah and they don't hit that hard but
once you get up to 18 to 20 to 22 to 24
that's where like all the elites and the
old best weed faults
you know where most of the skunky stuff
is falling right now that we've been
looking at low teens
no
four to
eight four to eight for the most skunky
stuff i mean you know the the mendo
perps is supposedly you know seed from
the late 70s or whatever yeah um and it
tests you know eight or ten percent at
best
yeah some of the s1s can get up into the
high teens yeah but the mom cut itself
is pretty low
you know
and i think that used to be super common
like i think even like old school skunk
one right yeah it was 13 to 15 back then
yeah when they could get testing done
you know um and so we've gone from like
the start of everything where things
were
you know low to you know single high
single digits to low teens to mid teens
to upper teens low 20s
yeah and now it's all
maybe it's all fake or whatever but um
it doesn't seem like after a certain
point there's a big correlation between
high numbers and best effect
no not at all
because my friend would get all pissed
off because they'd be like dude i don't
know if
i don't know if i can get your weed for
the right price this dog is only this
chem 91 only testing an 18
but it took your head off
yeah
you know but they would rather take
two-week preemie
chem 91
because it tested 29.
yeah
right and so
i just i just think that like people
started rob the only thing that matters
is like how
how it affects you
and yes the more people get away with
effects and like not testing stuff like
by smoking it with a variety of humans
yeah because even one person two people
like some of my favorite weed is stuff
that matt doesn't like at all
yes just not that he doesn't appreciate
it it just doesn't make him feel good
yeah yeah some of it just [ __ ] me up
like paranoid or anxiety or yeah yeah
some people get some people get weirded
out some people love a buzz some people
like sativa i mean there's a range of of
effect
yeah and so i think if you get away from
like i don't think a bunch of people are
doing smoke testing anymore
yeah they're trying to find something
that looks impressive and tests
impressive
yeah
right and then all of a sudden now we
have a bunch of like midzie elites
yeah
right
we have a bunch of elites where it's
like people are saying oh i hate fritter
you know like well there was a minute
there where like and people are growing
stuff because they're like oh this weed
gets this amount of pound
yeah it's an elite
so i'm gonna grow lemon cherry gelato
and i'm gonna grow this runts by this or
i'm gonna grow this jealousy cut because
my buddies can get top dollar for it
and i'm not trying to call it mids
but it's probably not going to stand the
test of time
no you know like like right now sour is
coming back around diesels
yeah why because it's fireweed
and it works and it smokes and it tastes
great
yeah you know and that we weed that
works
is always going to have a popularity
basis
yeah where we that doesn't work you know
like you can only the hype boys can only
hype it for so long
i mean burner can obviously sell the
[ __ ] out of anything
yeah yeah you know
he's great at promotion he's great at
getting hip hop and rat and various
stars smoking his weed and exclusive
spots and building up but he's a
horrible horrible kisser
i have no idea you know don't let him
lie to you he's a liar about that but
there's an aspect where it's like you
can only promote something for you can
only force people to like something for
so long
yeah
before they make their own decision
right and so that's why
that's why you have all this [ __ ] that
like gets like flash in the pan that
gets popular for eight or ten months
or a year or a year and a half
yeah and then it's gone it's replaced by
some new hype
yep where things that used to get
popular before like the purples or the
cushes or the sours or whatever the
skittles when they become organically
popular
right where it's like grassroots
popularity drives it
they're a lot more lasting
than when it's hyped
you know
because hype has become marketing
cannabis weed wasn't we wasn't ready for
modern marketing dude
no
we weren't ready for it at all we were
so ripe to be abused by modern
advertising techniques yeah then like
you know it just got overwhelmed and
people realized oh i don't even need to
have good weed to make money
ten years ago that [ __ ] wouldn't have
worked everybody would have laughed at a
[ __ ] for trying to front that
hard you know but nowadays it's just
flies ten years ago the only way
something became elite was when enough
people that were respected decided it
was good yeah and like or you know the
market demand or the market demanded it
yeah and the market really when it boils
down to it when you have stuff like the
purple wave with the urkel and the mendo
p and the grape ape and all those and
granddaddy and all that or you have the
cush wave in southern california or the
sour thing that happened for 10 years
that was market dictated a bunch of a
bunch of people wanted to get as much of
it as they could
yeah because they knew that the
customers would endlessly buy it and
they didn't get burned out
yeah that's why you can have 40
different [ __ ] named kush's in socal
yeah i was trying to name them all the
other day and it like made me want to
pound my head against that because
there's literally like you could walk
into you know 2010 you could walk into a
dispensary in la and they would
literally have like two dozen kinds of
kush oh easily some of them had like 50
60 different types of ogs yeah yeah all
these different names and some of them
were repeated and just somebody of
course
they just had different names yeah but
yeah like the entire dispensary was one
family of wheat and slight variations
yeah you know and you know from the east
coast and different things coming to
california sauer was like endless
yeah there was endless demand for gas
you know and now
instead of seeing endless demand for one
or two things that people can focus on a
lot of growers are like what the [ __ ] do
i even grow
yeah because if you're in the legal
market
you don't have a direct connection with
your consumer
you have to get a distro and uh unless
you own them you have to get a distro
and then a dispensary to buy it
i remember red um up in canada talking
about that with the the canadian legal
stuff about
now they have the buyers or are people
that aren't even from cannabis now and
they are who determine what value you're
getting for your weed non-smoking oh
yeah
corporate people honestly that was a
depressing part of that i really liked
that interview he was super personable
yeah that was hard to listen to
uh just the just the reality of what
matters and what doesn't
yeah and him
looking at at testing and paperwork
and deciding what to do without even
seeing the wheat because if it didn't
have the testing and the paperwork right
it was irrelevant yeah it just didn't
matter and so a lot of times okay
there's a lot of stuff out there that's
really fireweed and the reason why you
can't get it
is because it doesn't make financial
sense for the grower to grow it because
the people that are in between him and
you
don't want to do it
yeah so you get [ __ ]
you personally out there you get [ __ ]
because the growers friends get to have
it
sometimes you know it gets traded
amongst each other it gets survived and
all that you know
but the consumer doesn't get to see it
yeah you know and we were joking i'll
mention it one more time because there's
there's this you know huge grow that's
getting set up in socal it's like over
100 acres and everybody was ragging on
them or whatever because it's like
another big corporate takeover type
thing right yeah and you look at their
clone list and they're getting a bunch
of gelato hybrids and skittles hybrids
right like the market is under
underserved right now with gelato and
skittles
yeah they really got to fill that niche
yeah of course not you know
and so and you know if if customers
could
buy straight from the farm or straight
from cooperatives or whatever
you know then cooperatives would be able
to grow more niche weed
you know and be like oh i'll do some
trying to get some real bubba kush
yeah try to find some real sour diesel
try to find some urkel try to find you
know they should be with legality all
the classics you should be able to buy
led zeppelin
in the in the in the record store oh i
was like what did what
led zeppelin i just mean imagine like
you're like oh no it's not popular
anymore you weren't around the 70s you
can't buy it oh yeah yeah like legal
weave there should be a thing where it's
like all the hits if we're gonna compare
it to music right
you can go get all kinds of punk that's
like way out of date
yeah but you can't get acapulco gold
yeah you can't get urkel
you can't get you know g13 and l2 you
can't get you can't get the classics of
wheat
right and so right now california itself
is a wash and all this candy name
[ __ ]
right which is fine if people want to
buy that stuff it's fine i'm not not
trying to throw it out there but you
can't
you know like you know it's it it can't
all be sherbolato
this is why it is though it is why can't
i get real sour diesel why can't i get
real
kush why can't i get trinity why can't i
get bubba kush
yeah why can't i get granddaddy purple
yeah you know because because there's
there's like you know consumers don't
have power
to demand they have to go to the store
and they have to buy what the store
wants to put in their store
yeah
you know and that that might be getting
chosen based on their margin
there's this company up by me [ __ ]
floccana right they blew through a [ __ ]
ton of money do you know i don't know if
people know this but like there's a lot
of big companies that pay dispensaries
for shelf space
yeah
straight self space
shelf space
like
you know and that and that's a profit
they make just to put the [ __ ] the
weed on the shelf so the consumer can
see it
you know in the 50s or in the 60s or
whatever there was that huge record
scandal because everybody all the dj's
disc jockeys it was pay to play
oh yeah the payola yeah so how did how
does your how does your hit get be
popular if you can't get a radio station
to play it so people hear it and they
want to go buy your album
yeah and there's people that were
getting bribed to play certain things
and not play others
yep i'm connecting it to music again but
it's the same [ __ ] thing these
dispensaries because there's not enough
of them they're deciding what gets on
their shelf and not and they're deciding
it what's based on what's good for them
yeah not what's good for the consumer
out there what's good for them
yeah you know so
choice has actually gone down
quite a bit quite a bit expenses up
quality is down choice is down and how
do you how do you like let's say that
that you know csi or somebody like or me
or whoever fletch comes up with an
amazing new hybrid
yeah
right unless you're vertically
integrated and you can control the
supply chain you can't even guarantee
you're gonna get it in a shop
oh yeah you can't guarantee at all that
a bud tender will give a [ __ ]
yeah
you know so
it's like a whole deluge of like
everything that's already already
popular
and variations on that theme
you know and it gets controlled and so
the reason why i think that all these
elites from i always talk about like the
90s and the early 2000s are still my
favorite era of weed is it's because the
best weed from then was consumer choice
sorry i just read that question popped
up after everything we said
anyway yeah anyway but you know but yeah
that you know it it all the you know
sour became popular kush became popular
because people wanted it they were
willing to spend a bunch of money on it
there was demand
and yeah you know and and and people
wanted to fill that demand
yeah
and now it's like oh it's you know it's
here's a bunch of here's a bunch of weed
and with nurseries people might not know
this but most most like cultivators
they don't even get to keep their own
mom house they have to get it from a
nursery
that's so wild and then the nursery
might offer 10 or 15 different things
for this season
they might have 100 things but they're
only they only mommed up enough to do
like a lot of certain stuff
yeah so then you're you're forced to
operate off their menu
so it's like the nursery limits you
right like when i was working in a big
scene a couple of years ago i was trying
to find some some some real sour diesel
like on the legal market metric
yeah
and i couldn't find it pure
of course the best thing i could find
was spy rock sour which was some sour
across to some kush
i couldn't find it pure to grow on the
farm i was consulting at
yeah
you know but back in the day in 215 you
could be like oh we're gonna fill these
four greenhouses with this
yeah and then we're gonna take duffel
bags to the dispensary
and then you're gonna buy it
and people are gonna be stoked
64 ruin the [ __ ] world most of most
of most of uh
most of the good cushion a lot of the
good kush that was in la came from my
neck of the woods
yeah there was constantly brokers coming
up that their entire job was just to
grab excess capacity from up here and
bring it down to the the socal
you know dispensaries
yeah
you know and and so people could go hunt
the best weed
and then go and then the and then the
you know the
the uh dispensaries could pick the best
wheat if they wanted to
yeah now it's like they have to buy it
from a dispenser they have to buy it
from a distro and the distro has to buy
it from a farmer and it just turned
everything into like a commodity
yeah
you know and so as a result of that
everybody i never thought i was worried
about a bunch of [ __ ] with legalization
i never thought that like we would
accept way higher prices than the black
market or the gray market and shittier
quality
yeah but so far that's what we've gotten
yep
sure is
you know that's what we've got
and so you know we started off talking
about
and the reason why we've gotten that is
because you have all these
commercial farms that have intense
pressure with taxes and overhead and
regulations and paying out all this
[ __ ] money right
and quality and consumer happiness is
like they do the best they can in some
instances but it's not that great
but they're doing the best they can with
the constraints they're put under
yeah
and a lot of little things that used to
get done to make weed nice is getting
eliminated
yeah and so your weed isn't as nice
you know when people talk about all the
time your weed is fire your weeds not
fire
yeah
you know and a lot of times
it's like some of these things like the
emerald cup and all this different [ __ ]
you know
like
and i'm not saying this i've known tim
for a long time so this isn't a
disadvantage on any level but
when you're forced to basically like for
the most part only accept from like
licensed buyers
people aren't entering the best weed in
california anymore
no no
because you have to cut off this large
segment of the population that used to
win [ __ ] cups
yeah that used to be able to come there
with their perfectly grown greenhouse
weed
from their little greenhouse that they
treated perfect and they got to give two
four two to four ounces to the testing
and then they placed third
yeah oh but you know but but the thing
is the difference fletcher's like stop
[ __ ] on my weed the difference
between fletcher from one like from
archive from what i understand is that
they have a dispensary
yes they have control archives can make
a choice to i'm like i'm going to take
the moonbow i'm going to take this that
i love
and i'm going to make sure consumers get
it
yeah
right
so but most farmers most farmers in
california aren't vertically integrated
yeah they have to sell their we they
have to sell their wheat
you know and so if you're vertically
integrated then you can have some
uniqueness and you can choose like he
could choose to take things that he
doesn't want to share
and you can only come to his stores to
get them
it's no fair [ __ ]
you know and a lot of people are cut off
and a lot of people's top shelf yeah
dispensaries top shelf
used to be
six to 20 lighters
yeah
you know done by small scale people
and that was constantly filling the top
shelf because that was the top shelf
yep now all those people are [ __ ] cut
off
and what used to be the midzie shelf is
now top shelf
for more money a lot of those people are
looking for new [ __ ] jobs
you know and so a lot of the best weed
got cut off from consumers
yeah
you know before they could even smoke it
you know i you can't like i don't know
you can't
you can't get real haze in california
yeah
no
you can't get real sour diesel it's
starting to make a comeback maybe it'll
start forcing itself on some shelves
yeah yeah
but there's only but then there's all
this stuff too where it's like
these vertically integrated companies
like if you're going to get from jungle
boys or whoever you're probably going to
get mostly their weed that they're
growing because they want to sell their
weed through their outlet
yeah
too so then you know you get the
selection from them
you know and a lot of these dispensaries
have captured markets
so what you're getting
is you're getting a lot of commercially
grown weed
that they're trying to grow for cheap
and get a minimum level of quality
and then you're trapped because you can
only there's only you know 700 stores in
california
you got to buy it in one of them and you
can't really get great deals so you end
up like getting a bunch of expensive
commercial
yeah and that access to that actual top
self top shelf that actual fire that was
treated deliciously and grown perfectly
with organic or salt or whatever and all
the little things done the right way
yeah you don't even get to see that
anymore
yeah like you know what's funny is uh
all these american beer companies were
never winning any any beer awards
did you know that
right no so these all these like
international competitions
obviously like michelob and milwaukee's
best and budweiser and all that we're
never winning any gold medals at any of
these at any of these competitions the
beast wasn't winning medals no so they
made their own
they made their own category american
lager
oh now so now a bunch of these companies
have gold medals
because they were only [ __ ] competing
against themselves
yeah right when they were competing
against other microbreweries and places
from belgium and germany and all that
[ __ ] they had no chance
yeah their beer wasn't as good
yeah right so now you're getting the
same thing here where you're getting all
these big factory farms and they're like
do you want
old style do you want old milwaukee do
you want michelob do you want budweiser
do you want coors
yeah you know like oh you want some hedy
how about some heineken
yeah oh well it's maybe some amstel
light get an import
right and that's what they're you're
competing against you'd actually can't
get these little
you can't get these little things where
the quality really matters
and until they open that stuff up so if
you're growing for yourself
i said it before
don't emulate some big farm
yeah they're cutting corners
they're doing things that only work at
scale
you know uh and and all that right like
do things there's there's a there's a i
mean it's i don't want to get too
technical because i'm trying to keep it
general
enough
that like uh you know it it stays fairly
popular because i don't know how many
people are actual growers on this thing
versus just smokers or whatever but yeah
um
but yeah it's it's it's there's an
aspect where it's like plants don't
drink the same
it's really hard to like just automate
everything
and there is microclimates even like
this and reversing a shitload how how
one clone to the next clone won't
reverse the same way even if they're two
feet apart from each other or a foot
apart from each other getting the same
exact feed
microclimates a real thing too so
climate and some of those big rooms the
microclimates are really different
yeah you know and i mean we haven't even
talked about spectrum
but yeah that has a big roof you're not
growing with with the sun
um one of the best lights to this day is
still the single-ended old-school
hortilux thousand
a lot of these grown under double ended
and stuff like that like a lot of them
people are choosing spectrums that give
the most weight
yeah and not blends that give a better
quality
yeah
you know uh and because because we're
not in a position yet it's like such a
regulated and taxed industry
that
the best isn't allowed to bubble to the
top
yeah it's controlled
by dispensaries by dyspo's by burner by
people popularizing things by
celebrities stepping in and people
throwing their money around
and so that's why that's why if you're
if you're bummed at how your the weed
sucks in clubs that's why
yeah
because consumer choice has gone way
down since 215.
we are at an hour and a half right now
dang people we want to start winding it
down we could start doing the [ __ ] you
want to take some questions or i could
take some questions i mean i could talk
to maybe i'll talk for five or ten
minutes even though we're winding it
down because i haven't uh i haven't
talked about it but
aside from nutrition and environment
which we kind of talked about a little
bit before
um the spectrum that the plants grow
under makes a big difference
yeah and that could probably be its own
whole show but just in general plants
developed underneath the sun which has
all the spectrum all the time everything
from uv to
you know ev every color
huge
where most indoor lights are
approximations of that and they have
relatively narrow spectrums yeah right
and you put plants underneath them
and they grow vastly differently
depending on what kind of light they're
exposed to
yeah we used to 20 years ago when there
wasn't all these other lights we would
grow one light of metal halide
and the buds would come out half the
size
but they would burn better and they'd be
way frostier than the hps stuff
yeah
now you see all this stuff with ceramics
and leds and this and that and
everything else and it's like
different plants some plants respond to
like a different different types of
light and do well regardless some plants
do phenomenal under one type of light
and then like you move them and you
think oh i'm gonna put them under this
and it's gonna do great and then they
hate it
yeah because they're not getting
sometimes you'd see people where
they were growing all these straight
hps's
and then they'd have straight up
old-school metal halides like hanging
from the ceiling
yeah you mean the vertical ones yeah
vertical just just to give but i just
mean i still got scars from those
[ __ ] but just just to give a
different spectrum like not to be the
majority of it but just to shine some
blue
yeah so the plants had that to use and
you remember like the crusty buckets
yeah that guy's that guy swore if you
didn't have 25 metal halide light
you couldn't get those kind of huge
plants
yeah he swore if you if you had all hps
you get you get shittier wheat
yeah in order to get the size and the
frost you needed some blue
yeah and that's partially why the old
hps single ended a lot of people
considered them to be the best
all-around light and they were the
standard because they had 25 more blue
yeah you look at their spectrum versus
like a double-ended right now that's hps
and the hps is almost all orange and red
yeah very little uv very little and so i
have a bunch of plants like my headband
and my sours and dog and stuff
you know and you grow them under
different lights i grew that i grew the
dog once under pure ceramic
yeah i cut it at 85 days and it still
had white hairs
yeah and you know what's weird is that i
grew the dog [ __ ] under that same light
and it finished two weeks earlier than
it normally would
with a different spectrum
yeah with the with the cma normally the
dog [ __ ] would go 12 or 13 weeks yeah i
grew it under pure 3 100 ceramic metal
halides
it was done in 70 days every hair turned
fully ripened i've got beautiful picks
of it it shaved two weeks off but the
same spectrum
made the dog go two weeks longer than
i've ever taken her yeah that's funny
i've never taken the dog 85 days in my
life dude yeah
you know she's she's 65 she's 63 to 70
and she's pretty done
yeah and when i finally cut her and i
gave up
tons of white hair is all over
yeah so you know maybe like as a as a
final thing if you're trying to grow
heads
spectrum plays a big deal food plays a
big deal your style definitely helps and
like less is more
yeah in a lot of ways like just enough
and nothing more is a better style than
like let's give it way too much and pump
it
let's super size it let's get hot you
know let's run hot
um you know i don't
that's not gonna that might give you
better weight but i doubt it'll give you
better better weed
yeah you know and so
and that's a lot of times like what what
it happens is like
like whether it's drying or curing or
growing or your nutrition or your
environment
like growing the same strains over and
over they're your favorites and learning
why some rips they come out amazing
yeah and some rips you're like eh
you know
yeah cause even good growers get they
get the ant runs
oh yeah yeah
yeah i mean honestly people people are
still using [ __ ] other than leds i think
leds have come a long way
i'm still not convinced they're better
than a blend of other light
i still have never even tried led lights
so if any led light sponsors want to
sponsor i'll give it a [ __ ] try but i
i tend to like cmh quite a bit do i
think that leds are great for for
various aspects of heat and do i
have i started seeing a lot of nice weed
under them and do they have good
applications i do
but i still think some of the best heads
you can ever grow are off an old school
hortilux single-ended bulb
yeah
you know
a lot of award-winning weed and a lot of
fire came out of that
yeah the whole indoor sauer era the
whole indoor kush era the whole indoor
men uh purple era all grown under those
bulbs
you know i always hated [ __ ] horde
deluxe there's they had a chick that was
running it and they were so anti-fucking
cannabis it was [ __ ] how
anti-cannabis that company was and how
much money they made off cannabis
growers yeah i mean it's well you know
there's prohibition it's it's it's
dangerous
there's a
like we could wind it down but i'll tell
a story so i live in mendo
and one time
uh i'm i was friends with the uh i was
friends with the produce guy
at our safeway
and there was one point in willets where
that safeway sold more organic produce
than any safeway in the country
yeah because there was so many [ __ ]
of us
right it was just unbelievable so this
guy he tells me this funny story of this
guy
from
reynolds comes in
right
because
this safeway was the number one selling
turkey bag store for reynolds turkey
bags in the entire country we were
number one he couldn't believe it they
came out there to figure out
what the hell is going on
why are people cooking so many [ __ ]
turkeys why are people cooking they had
no idea they were like this zone
we have more like can we spread what
we're doing here
to other parts because our sails are
through the [ __ ] roof you know yeah
and when they found out it was all for
weed
like the dude's face just
you know he was just so bummed right
yeah
but it was it was like because back then
you couldn't get like turkey bags in 50
or 100 packs like you can today yeah you
would have to go to the store
and like the turkey turkey they came in
like two or three packs yeah yeah so if
you had you know an indoor and 20 pound
you'd buy 10 bat 10 boxes
yeah and you're at the store you know
it's like buying like lube or something
like that you're like you want to get
other [ __ ]
why i never got the turkey bag [ __ ]
thing because it's not like it really
kept smells
it was the standard it was it was a bag
that fit a pound you could tie it and
like the thing is with fluffy weed if
you didn't get the bigger turkey bag you
could not have enough of a tail to make
a knot
and i'll seal it down yeah off of off a
full pound so like where do you get a
bag that can fit a pound
yeah that's a good point that's a very
good point you know and it's like you
grow kush or something or you know urkel
you're gonna get a a tight pound
yeah right you grow diesel and it's
gonna be like a a tall pound yeah
you know
so there's an aspect to it where it's
like it it just became the standard
and what days of fighting over [ __ ]
sizes of bags and weight
yeah and and so the amount what's crazy
is that like wil the will it's safeway
learned and they just had i mean they
would just they would they would just
buy immense amounts of the [ __ ]
all the time it was like such a huge
seller for so long because there wasn't
eventually companies started making
where you could go to the hydro store
and you could buy like 25 or 50 or 100
and it was like something you could
purchase there and not be so embarrassed
but
you had to back in the day you had to
just go into the grocery store yeah
that's where you [ __ ] got it you know
yep and that's how it fit so
um so yeah i guess we've been on i mean
we've been
the reason why we wanted to chat about
this is because we thought that
uh and we could get deeper into it so
you can always reach out to us on our
discord which mattel plug or you can
reach out to us on ig or whatever but
there's a lot of different strategies i
didn't want to nerd out too hard
but there's a lot of depth to what kind
of weed you're trying to grow and what
your goals are for it right and how you
want to feed it and how you want to
treat it and it matters
you know and so don't just look online
at someone you think is killing it
and just feel like oh i figured it all
out i don't have to ask any more
questions i'm good i'll just
replicate this one method
yeah i know all i need to know
yeah uh because a lot of times there's a
lot of issues with them
you know so
you know um
so yeah i mean matt i'm i'm not very
good at doing the plugs matt do the plug
on the discord and whatnot
you've got it
so
um
our discord you have to go to google
type in breeders syndicate patreon and
that's how you find us uh we have our
discord we have all kinds of uh
additional features
at the discord that we can enjoy
together um we're always there shooting
the [ __ ] talking
[ __ ] around posting pics just being
obnoxious i'm me i'm being obnoxious on
there i try to be as obnoxious as i can
be and um we have riots eco.com i
promise i'm going to get the hawaiian
lights hybrids up there's only three up
right now
um we're having problems figuring out
why they weren't displaying and
hopefully they'll that's fixed i think
so hopefully those will be up there and
you can grab them this weekend my
apologies for being late a week um or
two weeks maybe i think um what else is
there uh speakeasy seed bank all of our
friends are on there go check it out go
show support and i'll put on a plug too
after years of not dealing with it
i my follower list
and i accepted thousands of new people
i also rejected a [ __ ] ton of people so
if you got rejected uh maybe
who knows maybe i was in a bad mood
maybe you didn't have enough posts maybe
whatever you can always message me and
say hey dude i listen
add me
you know i'll try to keep up on it from
now on we're gonna try to create more
content
um basically we're just trying to shoot
the [ __ ] about culture history and
growing better wheat
yeah and so you can always ask us
questions you can always hit us up uh on
ig if you have ideas for shows that you
might want to talk about maybe it takes
us a while to get them but
um you know we want to talk about what
you want to hear
you know and and so
you know some of it will be can be user
generated you can always ask us longer
questions and get better responses
um on the discords
you know and we talk about various
subjects and things like that it's
easier it's easy to get there so
you know uh we're trying to do our best
we're trying to do a little different
podcast than most or you know live or
whatever and
just basically like
you know just have it be like a little
bit about culture and life and growing
in a mix
so yep you know thank everyone for
listening on their friday night we'll be
back again same time same place all that
yep and uh you have anything to add
no i think that's it well everyone have
a great friday night thank you so much
enjoy your evening
you