hello
i don't know i need to see if there's a
sound coming so if any of you can hear
me let me know
trying a new microphone with all this to
see if we can get better audio quality
i guess we are going to see but let me
know if you can hear me
a quick yes thumbs up we'll do yeah cool
thank you dan
trying to keep the audio better so when
we switch it to audio podcast it's not
as
[ __ ] up but i have to wear purple blue
headphones these things are sexy though
science sad about it does it sound
better than usual or does it sound the
same am i too loud
anything else
that you can think
all right
all right let's bring in the homie
extra science tool
wasabi how you doing dude all right
oh weird i can't hear my headphones hold
on a second
i can hear you
yeah it maybe the mic isn't actually
working like it should let me see can
you still hear me i can hear you fine
do you hear me better now
no but i can hear you fine okay now i
can hear you through the headphones and
everything but hopefully the mic is good
oh i got louder okay let me turn it down
a bit
sorry i'm trying to work out this new
mic
for the audio stuff so when we do the
audio quality oh jesus yeah i'm going
off trying to get it nice
i it i don't know if it sounds better
than normal to me
uh what do you guys think is it better
worse let's get it started and ask them
before we
because i can turn it up and i can turn
it down sometimes
i did not get a haircut nor did i shave
full rough neck this week
yeah
it is a big vibrator it's a big vibrator
it does look very very very phallic i
would say but i mean it's a microphone
so that's just kind of how they're
shaped it just gotta fit in my mouth
buddy all right so it looks like
everybody's saying it's good so we'll go
with it and see how that is good
all right um
today's topic you wanna you wanna say
what it is
yeah i mean we're gonna we're gonna
bounce around a little bit like uh
always but
uh
one of the things that we might start
with is just sort of like we keep
getting questions on
you know we talk a lot about
on various shows and it's certainly a
big thing on instagram and other places
of media of like
how many different directions uh the
scene is going that we don't like yeah
right and you know we've so we've spent
a bunch of time talking about like
various effects and all that and then
people keep suggesting well what if we
talked about things that we could do or
you know on that level or something
destructive something constructive
perhaps or something that like even
someone who's not very connected or
whatever on any level could accomplish
right and so that like that resonated
with me pretty good because
it is uh it is better to talk about
constructive things
you know than it is to i mean it's
important to like discuss the problems
so people know what's going on
right but then it's like it can it can
definitely seem insurmountable
it does and right now is a really easy
time for it to filter insurmountable and
there's so many different
problems coming at cannabis in general
from so many different directions as we
see it
yeah and so you know i kind of do this
thing fairly often on the discord where
i'll throw i'll throw out some questions
for everybody to see what they want to
hear talked about
um and you know sometimes people come up
with some pretty good some pretty good
angles on things on top of that so we
might delve into that too but
um
i don't know you know yeah how to change
things where we're at
right
so
i think maybe
what what's really happening is that
anytime
you know uh people really aren't adapted
to fast change
yeah right so there's been a lot of
changes happening really fast
and i think it makes people's heads to
some degree
um and it's happening fast enough that
like
you know i don't know if you think this
way matt but it's almost like every year
or two is like a different scene
yeah especially now where that like that
maybe took like five or ten years
for like things to like seem
dramatically different on any level and
so great big strain changes and stuff
like that yeah like strain you know
strains that got popular had a longer
had a longer like run time of popularity
you know um the laws changed slower um
you know pricing and just you know
there's a lot of things that just seemed
a little bit more stable and now
everything's kind of rapid fire yeah
right there's rapid fire change and that
makes people uncomfortable right yeah
people are people are talking about
there's a bunch of stuff going on like
right now on the internet of like
you know the community's trying to
figure out like well who can you partner
with all these changes going on what is
ethical
yeah what's happening for the for
something that's been black market and
illicit and clandestine for so long it's
a different time
kind of so what is okay and things that
weren't okay before that would get you
blacklisted may not be the same today
yeah so i mean and some of that is just
some of that is just changing culture i
mean you know i don't want to be like
old man yells at cloud you know or
whatever
because changes change but sometimes
uh
you know there's different forces now
than there used to be right um you know
and maybe the best way to put it in a
nutshell is that like before
all the forces against us were pretty
much in prohibition
yeah to a large degree right yeah and i
i've even been giving this some some
thought because there's people that are
getting roasted now for some of the
people they're partnering with and stuff
like that and they're fighting back and
i even think to some degree like maybe
the way
that people fight back against those
people like matt even for somebody like
you who like it used to be very
effective to call somebody out in the
community yeah
you know i don't know if that's even the
most effective path anymore right yeah i
i don't think it is
and it's hard sometimes for people who
have a
past of doing that constantly you know
you know one way to handle certain
situations but i think now it really is
a lot of beating your head against a
wall yeah i mean people are throwing out
the names and stuff like that that's
going on and you know what it's really
exposing is that you know there's uh
there's never been like this uber
ethical time in wheat yeah weeds always
been full of shady characters you know
for a long time it was criminal in
various regards us you know and so some
people
you know um some people were in it just
because they felt like that was silly
and they loved weed
yeah and you know some people aren't
cause they're criminals yeah too you
know and that was just another criminal
[ __ ] to do or whatever and some people
are in it for rep and money and some
people are in it for the plan everyone
wants to say they're in it for the plan
yeah i mean that's a good thing to say
it's a good talking point but it isn't
necessarily true for everyone but what
people are noticing is by people's
associations now
right now you're starting to realize
well like where do those ethics lie
right and so there's and you know and
it's it's gone back i mean matt matt
remembers even like when colorado first
went legal there was people in colorado
that should remain nameless that got
into battles with buddies of ours
um about like well you know
go legal that's the option and if you
don't then you're unfair competition and
it's not even snitching or ratting to
like get you gone
yeah because you're just untaxed you're
not paying the same dues i am like
you're refusing to take the path
and so that was like a massive split in
the community
that was a that was a very big turning
point in the community when when it
became possible to
snitch people out to med boards and not
necessarily the police and at what point
is
yeah or whatever
you know or doxing or their doctors yeah
it's just just a variety of pressure
tactics to get people off their back
because a lot of times
you know really what it boils down to is
there's people that are making all kinds
of choices about their own personal
future and their friends right
um and in some cases like when they get
exposed they don't want to be exposed
because
um they feel like that might hurt their
customer base sure
yeah i heard seed cells potentially
which could hurt their ability to
partner with some of these people
because they have to be useful to these
bigger powers yeah and stuff like that
right and so
um so there's an aspect now where it's
like there's a lot of
there's a lot of secret snitching
there's a lot of doxing there's a lot of
like through proxies or whatever and and
how so
kind of what's happened is now is like
the community has sort of lost the
ability to police itself right
i can't even believe that word but it's
like now people are like you know it's
acceptable to work with police
yeah
it is
you know like and be like oh this you
know and uh
yeah
so
i mean that that's about as 180 degrees
c change as you can possibly imagine
yeah right and so we're again we're
discussing issues now but really what it
boils down to
is
so
i look at it and i i talk about it uh in
my head like i think about this a lot
right where yeah my whole life they've
been telling me for in regards to
cannabis that it's it's bad for you to
have it you can't have it you can't have
it you can't have it you can't have it
right yeah and we've all been fighting
in this in this community like you know
the overgrown overgrow was named
right yeah for people that don't know
the first real weed forum overgrow was
named because the concept was overgrow
the government yes like if too many
people start growing and so many people
start disobeying and people refuse to
respect the law then eventually they'll
have to
change the law so that people keep
respect for other laws
yeah so that was like the whole that was
like the whole theory right was like was
uh
um
you know was overgrown yeah okay and so
now we have that comes
it's old school yeah it was that concept
it was him and bernard mello yellow the
whole thing his big thing was to to get
a bunch of hemp plants give them out for
free hemp clones and say overgrow the
government here's how we're going to do
it i'm giving away all the hemp plants
before uh before 1996 when california
actually passed proposition 215 which
was the first medical in the country and
it was the first place to take it from
totally illegal to like a path towards
like like you can call it a gray area do
you remember when they used to push for
like to get like hundreds of thousands
of hippies to move to wyoming yeah
because it was so lightly populated we
could probably affect the vote and
people were trying to figure out well
what state can we actually get some
movement yeah right what state can we
actually get something and now we've
overgrown to the point where people are
looking around at prices uh and how to
survive and all the various things that
are happening and then like maybe man
maybe we overgrew a bit too much yeah
and so that aspect that price dive that
worry that we talk about that's
caused a lot of people to look around
and and
and choices are being made yeah
right
yeah people are mentioning certain
choices right now i mean when we're
talking about choices um you can go back
to even
the the roll-up of of how it worked
and how the community reacted when we
saw things like icy mag and heaven
stairway get taken down he was
mentioning shebang you know that was one
of the people that got taken down for
um i believe running icy mag and heaven
stairway somewhere after that when that
happened and was that o5
somewhere
icy mac was later they have the stairway
is right about oh five i haven't i i
mean heaven stairway that got like
cannabis world and overgrowth taken down
yeah but it's all part of the same bus
it's all part of the same thing when
that happened i got scared enough of the
internet i honestly didn't really start
poking around again until
social media really came back on in the
mid teens yeah
i was scared off it for a while you know
make sense i got scared off i see mag
once the cops seized the servers i and
usually um yeah shabang is actually
there there's paperwork right now and
he's
he's in trial so yeah he he did get
busted unfortunately um that he got
busted with the server
and and top cops don't tend to give
servers back when they take them either
so a lot of people need to keep that in
mind
but you know so there's an aspect of uh
you know people are asking well what can
we do to change things positively
yeah right
um and you know there's an aspect where
they're i'm i'm not big on mentioning
names on the show or whatever there's a
bunch of comments going on but obviously
like there's a lot of stuff going on
recently on ig and and you know people
are talking about like associations that
people are doing
yeah right well you know you can you can
vote with your wallet
yeah
they're gonna try to hide their work and
off in different brands and different
this and different that you can figure
out who they are and you cannot spend
your money on them yeah right they
essentially need an enormous amount of
consumer money to stay afloat
always they're all doing this because
they think this is the best money play
for themselves
so the way to hurt them is to is to deny
that money play
yeah right is to you know you can so you
know maybe maybe i'll continue my
thought or whatever so my whole life
they can't have it you can't have it you
can't have it right and now we're at
this point where they're like man this
thing's kind of cool
i mean we'll take it from here yeah
so to me the fight hasn't changed really
the fight has just shifted we used to
fight for
access and acceptance
yeah right that was the big fight access
acceptance and the ability to do that
without getting in trouble just because
it's a plan it's [ __ ] stupid yeah so
now we're kind of getting there
yeah we've made we've made way faster
expansion on access and and safety and
the ability to use it and i think with
within a number of years a lot of these
like piss testing for jobs will go away
i think there was something announced
today about that right in the news
i'm not sure actually but
it's gonna go away soon because so many
states are led making it legal
um it's just gonna you know and then
wide varieties of people are gonna be
able to start using it without penalty
yeah it has something to do with jobs
not being able to discriminate in legal
states where there's medical cannabis
and yeah they're not allowed to
discriminate against legal cannabis if i
remember correctly so so here's the gig
when it as it shifts from like safety
and freedom and access
right and the right to do so now it's
going to shift to like who controls it
who sells it to you like who
um you know like
that really that who controls it
that's the fight and it probably will be
a fight that we're battling but what
people have to remember it's dark days
right now and
it's like a lot of people that are like
deeply in the cannabis industry are
hurting pretty bad
yeah which is why i think it's causing
some of these desperate moves
yes right is that when it comes down to
it there's people that like they want to
survive they want to make money and if
they have to deal with the devil they
will
right
but i would like to throw out there that
um
you know when it comes down to it that
we are winning
right it's just that the fight has
shifted
you know like we were fighting huh who's
we that's winning well i mean in the
sense that like you know imagine 15
years ago if you thought that like 38 or
40 states in in in america would allow
recreational or
medical campuses
right like there's more access for more
people now than ever before
right so we're not happy with the
direction the scene is going but that's
because our previous goal we were all
pretty united on
we want this thing to be available and
accessible and not get people in trouble
and we want to be able to smoke and
share weed
yeah and now it's gone into like this
economic thing where
people are like when you think about i
don't want to say corporations because
that's just like a group of people or
whatever but when you think about big
business say
yeah they're going to want to control it
they're going to want to patent it
they're going to want to make it look at
all the recreational stuff going on it's
not exactly legal
it's more like highly regulated tightly
taxed and controlled
yes you know
nothing
decriminalized about it yeah i mean if
if i want to grow a bunch of vegetables
or tomatoes or fruit or anything like
that in my backyard i can do that i can
grow as many tomatoes as i want i can
cross tomatoes every person on this on
this thing tonight i could send them
tomato seeds yeah you can
yeah we could all we could all trade and
share and post pictures of our hybrids
and our this and our that and everything
else and it would be free no one would
give a [ __ ]
um that's legal
what we have is like so what we have
going on right now is that um you know
if you have a six plant limit for in
your state
you basically can't breed
yeah you can't keep mom stock you can't
have a normal amount of plants that a
per even a hobbyist
and this experiment to me this is where
the the term legal legalization was
bastardized and a lot of uneducated even
when i was 15 even when i was 15 i knew
that once corporations got their hands
dug in deep enough to be able to take
over immediately that's when they're
gonna flip the bill even as a 15 year
old kid i realize that's how the world
works that's how corporations work
that's what happened but i did not
expect them to push it under the guise
of legalization because even today any
any average citizen who doesn't grow but
smokes and if you ask them if wheat is
legal they're going to tell you yes 99
of the time
yes and they don't even know what's
happening to the real growers side of
the aspect that there's nothing legal
about
being
they're making it legal in the sense to
possess or whatever but you still have
to go to approve stores
and buy it from approved vendors
and
and as we both know that invites
corruption and all these different
levels sure you know and so strangely
and this might be
like from a capitalist perspective this
might be one of the first cases that i
know of of this where it's like uh
the
legalization of something led to a
massive drop in quality and a massive
increase in price
hmm
yeah
i don't know about the massive increase
in price with the drop in quality that's
a hard one
you know well i mean there's think about
how many people are buying like 70 and
80 eighths
yeah
right yeah and think about how expensive
all that stuff is now yeah yeah and i
mean there's there's plenty of cheap too
but it's like the taxes i mean i saw
that thing where
you know they broke down like how much
an eighth is and like the farmer gets
three bucks and the tax man gets 21
bucks
and the dis and the and the dyspo gets
20 bucks and then the
[ __ ]
you know dispensary gets 40 bucks and
you end up paying 80 bucks yeah
you know it's it's that that is
preposterous there's like three layers
there there's the government there's the
distribution and there's the store
and they're all
you know pillaging because they can
i paid attention when i was a kid i
watched that movie robin hood
and i remember there was a sheriff of
nottingham
and i remember they would
bug people for money and i kept that
with me growing up and i was like wow
this tax thing is a scam isn't it like
to at some level
at some level the way it works now this
is
we've all been conditioned to think that
this is what we need to do and i agree
to have society people need to pitch in
but i mean
what i think has happened is like
you know it's it's one of those things
where any time like any kind of vice
becomes more acceptable
they want to give money to cops in
schools
yes obviously like they're just like
well you know here's funding for various
groups
right and so we're going to tax the [ __ ]
out of this vice or whatever it might be
right so he's the other voting half and
you know they they made taxes based
probably on like a much higher pound
price than people are getting
yeah
in that regard so
you know so it's not really so that's
really what's happened is like in the
215 era
anybody could grow whatever they wanted
and if they had a medical card and they
grew good enough weed they could walk
into a medical dispensary and they could
make a deal yeah and that allowed a wide
variety of things to proliferate
i mean one of the one of the aspects of
the person that's getting [ __ ] talked
about this week um is that not only are
people upset at like the the
associations that he's making right
um but he but it you know a lot of the
genetics that people you know he sold
his genetics for a high dollar and they
were and there was a nurse reaction and
there was a lot of disease and viroid
involved a lot of vibrate which we will
be doing a show september 8th about the
hop laden viroid and everything you'd
ever want to know inside out we're going
to try to cover yeah and because it's
it's uh it's the new
you know with a all it takes is poor
practices
at a facility
especially at a nursery uh and not and a
lack of care and spending on testing and
you can nuke uh you can spend so many
gardens and get infected
yeah we've had friends who have lost
whole collections time and time again
because of this virus because it's not
really your vibrate because it's not
easy to clean
and that's you know that's a that's a
that's a that's a product to be honest
of legalization but without proper
regulation yes
you know
um you know i mean on on a certain level
it's like uh you know using using razor
blades on multiple plants is sort of
like using tattoo needles on multiple
customers or junkies share needles it's
the same whatever whatever it's the same
gig it's like unless it's sterilized in
between or you use a fresh one for the
next like it's it's got to be kind of
that kind of of
of environment now yeah because it's
written it you know and so
there's important another reason
to not forget to buy seeds we should not
let the seed industry die
so yeah i mean that's that's another
thing is that
maybe one i don't know my comments have
totally frozen i haven't yeah mine i
haven't seen any new comments in a bit
so if people are typing stuff in
it's like for the last five minutes it's
just not done jack so i apologize if i'm
not seeing anything
um
but
you know there's it used to be that
uh the 215 era and sort of the grain
market era um allowed a lot of
capitalistic activity a lot a lot of
small businesses a lot a lot of garage
sized growers independent breeders
uh you know various types uh you know
pretty low bar to entry
yeah
you know and now that that's all getting
now that's all getting like you know
legalized or whatever else it's barring
entry to a lot of people yeah oh wow it
just totally disappeared i know i tried
to turn it off and on but it didn't
really work it didn't really work now
it's just you and me just talking to
each other that's even weirder we could
we could stop it and uh i can edit this
back in
to the uh audio one i mean it's a bummer
not to see people's comments yeah i'd
like to see people's comments too so i'm
gonna restart this and we'll resume
okay restart i guess i'll see in a
second