thank you
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not soja breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
alright so tonight I was thinking about
maybe we could talk about
a breeding A to Z but in the form of
like maybe I'll give you
um
a set of traits and that I want out of
an end goal so just teaching people to
start using goals and reading right if
you traits for an end goal hypothetical
end goal and you build it with
in your in your hypothetical toolbox
what what have you and you talk about
the ways you would go about this project
and then Vice the verse you can give me
some surprise traits and then I'll do
that with a feminized version of
whatever you give me
um
you sound like you're underwater today I
don't know what the deal is is it is it
coming clear for everyone or just you I
don't know maybe I guess we could ask
who's [ __ ] on right now can you guys
hear him super clear as he muffled
how we sounding testing testing one two
three
I didn't use the cool microphone and
[ __ ] this round because I thought it was
just not doing anything different but
maybe that's why okay
well maybe it's just me so I'll suffer
you suffer through it I'll suffer
through it
okay so yeah so I'm gonna so basically
it's like one of the maybe I'll I'll
throw like uh my Spiel on it or whatever
but
um for a minute there uh probably the
last five to seven years especially
there was like this explosion of seed
making
right and you know we've talked amongst
about it's probably like maybe even to
the point where like ninety percent of
the current people selling seeds started
in that era yeah right and so in that
time like there was this big explosion
of monetary value and all that and so
the that that economics changed how
people bred yeah a lot not everyone but
certainly a lot of people right and like
what used to be like side projects
um you know that were that could take
some time or have goals ended up being
like mashing a lot of famous things
together
yeah not if there's anything wrong with
that right but it just changed the
dynamic of like you know a lot of
multi-stage breeding kind of went like
to the Wayside yeah I sure did it sure
did right and so what what we're talking
about this evening is sort of like you
know I mean I guess you could get lucky
and just knock it out of the Park One
Step but for the most part like it would
be a multi-stage process to get to where
you want yeah I mean over several years
over several several years it's really
hard to knock it out of the park
consistently all the time unless you're
doing certain kinds of Femme breeding of
known clone to known clone you know but
um yeah yeah you know and so you know I
one of the benefits of like what's
happening right now in the community
might be that like the people that do
decide to keep reading
um people are into like longer projects
yeah
you know and so it used to be there was
a minute there where people would be
like well you can't get Skittles and you
can't get chem 91 but if I make a hybrid
maybe you'll buy that yeah right and so
rather than like Skittles has these
things that I want and so does chem 91
and is there a way I can blend these two
things and eventually end up with this
plant that has the best of both worlds
yeah right I mean that that's still like
if I can blend these two things I guess
that's still an end goal if you have an
end goal of what you think they might
end up at in the end but that's still
kind of like the process the beginning
process of making crosses is just like
hey plant a plant B I want the best of
both let's see what happens you know but
having an end goal where you're like I
want this plant to end up like this for
this environment for this this XYZ is is
super
uh detailed you know yeah well I mean it
depends on how similar you want them to
be like you might only care about like
for instance a couple of the traits yeah
that you're trying to combine and not
need it to be like this I obviously like
the more things you're trying to achieve
the more the more difficult it becomes
yeah but if you know a simple way to
think about it would be like what if I
want to combine the Terps from this
plant with the potency of this other one
yeah then you're only searching for two
things yeah right so it can be defined
by your goals too
yeah right in that in that regard I just
think about it so differently I don't
even think that like to me that I don't
consider that
it's goals but it's not what I'm
necessarily referring to when I say
Goals sure
because one one is I'm predict I want an
outcome desired outcome and I'm picking
many I'm picking from my library to make
that outcome happen and the other is
still I'm gonna hit these together and
try to get the best out of what results
based on what I know I'm not saying one
is more legitimate I'm just saying that
like they're you know it's like a little
bit different to try to create like a
line that has certain traits yeah and
what I'm going to ask you to do is going
to be the hard one that's going to be
the hard one the hard one you know and
then and then on top of that too like
you know it it's kind of interesting but
like if you have breeders
um Matt's one you know like that have
been at it for a long time and that keep
certain plants around quite a long time
right like our buddy Caleb or flight or
whoever right what they get to do is the
more you breed you actually get to start
to see which traits of the plant that
you breed with
follow up in the kids yeah because
there's some really amazing cuts out
there
um that suck as breeders yes very nice
so like the the individual cut itself is
amazing it's great smoke and all that
but it's not a stable or a solid thing
yeah and then there's other things that
just seem to breed true for certain
characteristics almost no matter what
yeah there's a lot that are just [ __ ]
Growers that people normally wouldn't
keep but are are amazing breeders and
don't breed for the traits they visually
Express somebody just said yes
terpenolene is very hard to breed out
yeah uh once once it's in there uh boy
it's really difficult finding what you
want without it in there it really
dominates yeah it does if she throws her
weight around
you know and that's interesting too
because there's aspects where it's like
uh since I'm gonna do the hard one
um you know what used to be [ __ ] up
about breeding especially if it took
multi-stage is that you have to make
sure that you save seeds from every
stage yeah because you can totally [ __ ]
up a line and do something that you
didn't want to do and it's a real bummer
and if you don't have a way to go back
one generation and go in a different
direction then you're just stuck with
that mistake yeah definitely and and I
don't think most people when they think
about breeding realize that they would
ever have to go back a generation I
don't think that even comes into the
equation in there and there might I know
it didn't when I was young oh yeah I
mean you fix it
most of our friends wish they had
there's at least one project they did
that they really like that they feel
like they [ __ ] up a bit along the way
and they wish they could go back and
redo you know yeah so uh he feels like
DJ did that DJ's stuff is DJ stuff is
his own story in itself it's Unique
um but you know I mean there's an aspect
of like different people have worked his
stuff in different directions at
different times he's given it over to
seed companies and then gotten back seed
stock
um so it definitely is like what era you
got it from it could vary quite a bit
yeah I would say so yeah you know so you
know but yeah I mean there's there's an
aspect of like I think for like most
hobby breeders really having some kind
of goal is is probably good you know
because I tell people all the time like
the most important thing of what you're
doing is that like you're happy with it
yeah right in the end that's that's it
well yeah I mean we for a long for a
long time we bred we just tried to breed
weed that we like to smoke yeah um
because it was it was long enough ago
that like we just never really felt like
any kind of seed company was was even
realistic yeah I never thought ever
about getting a famous Seed Company ever
in the history of my company yeah I mean
when we were when we were breeding in
the in the 90s and early 2000s and stuff
like that like the people that started
seed companies back then literally still
went to Europe oh yeah yeah you had to
go there to to make it big pretty much
so it was like a massive life [ __ ] like
it was you know so a lot of us we just
bred we just bred for ourselves yeah you
know now it's cool with Instagram you
know and all these different various
platforms you can do some a lot of
people can do small breeding and then
offer it up and Reach people yeah and so
there's this commercialism aspect that
was like hard before so like before a
lot of times people were trying to just
please themselves and their buddies
and now it's more like please the public
which is fine and there there was a
certain era too where it wasn't even
just please the public it was a much
smaller crowd and it was pleased The
Forum crowd you know what I mean oh yeah
sure tiny era of well it may not be what
I like but it's what sells on the forums
and even that is is a vast difference
from what sells on Instagram now you
know so I think I remember those I
remember those arrows and what was hot
and like the pressure to breed with all
that work because it's just people want
it and I mean I you know we there's even
posts from Neville when he was when he
was posting in like 2009 or 10. that
even in the 80s and early 90s he would
get [ __ ] for everybody would be like oh
I want the purest Indica imaginable yeah
he'd release something that was like
that and then they would suffer and
yield and he would get endless bitching
yeah so there's always been a commercial
aspect of it you know and then you end
up having to like you end up having to
please people so so in some ways all my
friends anybody that breeds for
non-commercial purposes you just get to
do whatever the [ __ ] you want
well
in this case you're going to do what the
customer wants oh my God okay here we go
so this is a rather picky customer right
um it's something that obviously has to
work in the modern Market since this is
2022. they want something with eight
weeks flowering they don't want none of
that long flowering [ __ ] that you love
they want eight weeks flowering
um they want a little bit of purple
right a little bit of purple the most
important thing that they're missing in
their Arsenal is black licorice mixed
with gas they want they want some gassy
back end on it and black licorice and
like I said uh modern market and
they don't want any OG or cookies they
want unique
oh man
so where do we start
to please this customer we don't want
any OG or cookies so so right there
right that makes it every everybody just
heard like they want like six different
things yes in the same line so that
everything you add make potentially
makes it harder or longer of a search to
try to figure it out yeah or you have to
get luckier to find it quick or you have
to have a large library that you're very
familiar with you know that helps too
because obviously like if you know how
your plants breed that could narrow it
down a bunch that would be helpful like
for me but if you were just trying to
smash plants together to find that
aspect it would probably be pretty rough
yeah and so basically what they want is
something that's pretty funny they want
quick purple
they want good Terps
Frosty Frosty is [ __ ] because
[ __ ] oh my God it's a modern Market they
need something that washes they need
something that washes
um no OG either not just cookies no OG
no oh gee that's right you're in that
corner like burner is doing and they
want it to be feminized or regular no
right you're doing regular oh my God
you're gonna do the same for me in
Reverse with feminized and you can pick
the traits that is horrible yeah
he just said here you go he just [ __ ]
me
um so the hard part obviously is that
okay so just break it down right you
need something you need something Frosty
terpy fairly attractive
um uh you needed to come in relatively
quickly and
um uh the the hardest one out of all
that is probably like the black licorice
Terps uh because that's pretty specific
and [ __ ] rare
um and then the other part of it that
sucks you know is that it has to be a
regular seed line
so in that in that regard what you would
have to do is you would either it can be
several it can be a multi-step
process well yeah I mean so that's what
I'm saying is like you would end up you
know one of your first steps probably
would be like you would have to figure
out what what kind of mail you wanted to
use and then you would cross it to you
know the uh one of the females that you
want to use and start there and then you
have a male female blend then because
now at first you need a pollen source
yes right that was one of the
attractiveness of [ __ ] uh everybody
like doing feminized is because they
could create their own pollen source and
they knew pretty much what traits were
going to probably pass because they
could smell their pollen source and look
at the bud yeah yeah so there's so
there's basically there's a way too
where it's like you know once you once
you and that's where all like the BX or
BC is people talking about like that's
where it started yeah is people needed a
pollen donor to start working on their
line idea yeah and then they could start
playing with it once they had pollen
they could make pollen every generation
yeah is really what it boils down to so
um realistically speaking uh probably
what I would end up doing
um is that uh
uh my buddy is throwing me off by
answering but what I would probably do
is I would cheat and I would uh my buddy
that just made me laugh uh him and I
made some a bunch of hybrids
um with some old Maple Leaf Indica seeds
from the early 2000s right and one of
the things that they did is we crossed
it to the Mendo P okay right so the
Mendo P has some color it's got crazy
Terps uh it doesn't wash that well or
anything like that but at the very least
um it's something old and basic that you
could start with yes yeah right so you
know one of the things you need to start
with is like an idea of how you're going
to start and how you're going to finish
yes right because whatever you finish
with the cross is 50 that yes you know
and so you're starting you're starting
and you're ending is 50 50 and in the
middle you get to play right so
um and it's not potent yeah no I mean
that's the thing is you're starting with
limitations
we don't need it I don't believe potency
was a part of it because in today's
market you can watch it and everything's
potent so potent's not a part of the
equation
so probably what I would do is I would
take that Maple Leaf Indica by Mendo
perps right and I would grow it out and
I would pick a male probably one that
leaned like in leaf structure and all
that and especially one that turned
colors um male flowers and stuff and I
would probably pick the most Mendo perp
leaning
uh male I possibly could yeah which
should be relatively easy because the
maple doesn't turn colors
and the leaf structure is way different
right and and Mendo P kicked certain
kinds of Terps doesn't it and Mendo P
kicks certain kinds of Terps right so
and well the other two is that it's like
a basic Indica that I started with and
then you cross it to something extremely
unique so hopefully you can pick out a
bunch of that unique
right in your mail which makes it a lot
easier than if it was like two similar
things yeah
um so take some pollen to that and I
would probably throw it on something
like the snow
interesting I wouldn't have thought of
that choice that's an experience yeah
well the reason is is that when I was
doing that project down south you know I
got to run a lot of Caleb's gear yeah um
and I probably ran half a dozen snow
hybrids yeah and the [ __ ] just
consistently kicks nice pretty colas
covered in Frost it shortens up the the
flower time and all that right so yeah
um you know the Mendo perps would bring
some color and some Terps the snow would
bring structure and and Crystal and like
a nice look yeah that's a good that's a
good choice I like it and I've seen it
and I've seen it work consistently on a
bunch of hybrids already yeah throw the
kind of traits through a bunch of
different crosses that I like so the
chance that it could do that and this
one is probably reasonably High
I think so so boom now I have a snow by
by Maple by purple yeah right so
you grow up that now it's more
complicated because you're looking for
traits
um so now probably what you're doing is
because you're it's not going to be as
easy to visually pick it out it would
probably get shitty and you'd probably
end up picking like three of the nicest
males you could find yeah and separately
pollinating
like the female of your choice yeah then
you grow them all out and you see which
which of those three hopefully passed
the most traits that you were looking
for
because there's an aspect with males
where you're like really not going to
know yeah you know so the wider mail
pool you use the uh the vet yeah but as
long as you can isolate it and see which
one goes to which yeah for the sake of
this argument not to get like crazy
esoteric and stupid I would just say
three triplets yeah you know and so now
I have a a snow Mendo P Maple okay right
and
um so I take a male of that or three
males of that right
and I hit it to I hit it each separately
to my modeling
because the Maui is bringing the Maui
well the Maui turns purple in the cold
it's super Frosty it's got chunks all
over it it's done in eight weeks so now
you've got a quick Maple a quick Mendo
pea a quick Maui you know the snow is
reasonably quick so all of a sudden you
start upping your chances that like a
Fino that you want is going to be in
that
that 50 to 60 day range of what you're
going for I guess right yeah you know
um and since the Maui turns a little
purple and the Mendo peas purple you
don't have a lot of purple in there but
you have some definitely and you can
start looking for it and the the snow
and the Maui end up having like you know
the structure and the frost yeah so then
I would hunt through that
but that's let's see so Maple onto the
maple onto the under the Mendo P that's
one stage yeah right and then that onto
the snow that's two stages and then a a
a male out of that onto the Maui
you're already at three stages yeah
you know and where's your gas coming in
where's my gas coming in
boy you know the gas is going to be hard
I think because I think right there you
probably have your your
um wait you said gas and
yes gas and licorice gas and licorice
[ __ ] dude that's [ __ ] hard you're
gonna have to do this what if I just
pick one I'm just gonna pick one and
you're gonna have to deal with it yeah
yeah we could do one
now we have a like what is it like it's
like a four-way hybrid now it's like
Maple Maple started the pollen Maple
Mendo
and snow and Maui yeah
so if we wanted if we wanted now it's
gonna be 50 of the Cross right so we
have a bunch of early [ __ ] A bunch of
Frosty [ __ ] a couple purple things if I
really wanted to jack up the purple and
the licorice I only have one thing I
could do I could put it on the anise yes
but then that would be but then that
would be that would be [ __ ] because
then there were the the chance that you
would also get gas would be kind of hard
the anus the anus the Stars you know uh
because black licorice is really hard so
I don't think to be perfectly honest
anymore we're not going for gas anymore
we're just dropping that going for all
black licorice and modern people are
talking about Jaeger the the Anise is
actually extremely close to the Jaeger
the fish oh somebody who said the
fisherman who the [ __ ] just said the
fisherman
that's why what's that one what's that
one so my buddy uh my buddy and I we
used to grow a bunch of Anna's together
and he used to take it down to the bay
and give it to certain Crews right and
he was a professional tuner fisherman
yeah so they used to call they used to
call when we sold them that way they
used to call it the the fisherman
nice because my buddy's nickname was
actually tuna
tuna oh yeah is he in the movie Blow no
he was not in the movie below damn but
he but yeah I mean he's he's actually
like uh
um you know he's actually a big part of
that story really
um but yeah the uh the fisherman he uh
um that was probably back in 06 or
something like that so just so people
know right like I didn't even talk about
like you could get really lucky in what
I described and you could do it all in
in that many steps or you could grow
[ __ ] out and realize it's not at all
what you want and want to go back a step
yeah that's like a best case scenario
right there yeah that that definitely is
the best case scenario you know because
that that's assuming that like each
stage and then you could talk for a
little bit about like well how many
yeah
you know because every cross you have a
female is the certainty
yeah but does the male pass what you
want of the hybrid that's why I always
call it the shotgun method yeah you
called it the shotgun method and it's
right but like what they people used to
do in the old days is they would
they would cross like their three every
stage they would cross their three
favorite males yeah to the same female
and mark them different and then when
you grow them out
you look
yeah whatever one gave you the best
females
you picked males from that
that donation
you know what I'm saying yeah you know
because you were because that that was
the way that we tested back then if you
just did one nail you're just hoping
three isn't even all that great but it's
like let's be reasonable about people's
ability to actually do [ __ ] you know
yeah yeah
so you know and then you know it doesn't
I mean it doesn't have to be huge it
just depends on everybody's size it
depends on what you're trying to do you
know 50 or 100 seeds held back is
probably plenty for most people's
purposes yeah yeah you know to stick
with and then you'd probably and then
you put right there you'd probably have
a situation that would be there would be
plenty of purple plants there would be a
lot of Frosty and Visually attractive
plants the licorice would be in there
but it might be a little harder to find
you know and the gas we'd have to do one
more stage to something yeah to get
lucky and you know they asked what
you're naming it I think um he's gonna
probably call it the obvious the purple
anus
yeah
but that's how I mean in a sense like
you know when when we were planning the
super dog project it was like we we were
trying to get the the the looks and the
greenery oh and the smell of the skunk
combined with like the density and the
and the hour of the chem dog yeah you
know and so what Matt just gave me was
he just gave me like what was it five or
six requirements it was it was several
yeah yeah that makes it a real paint
purple black licorice gas eight weeks
flowering works in the modern market so
that's that's like five five that's five
yeah yeah it's half a dozen it's half a
dozen different things so that makes it
more difficult yes if you're only
looking to combine a couple of traits
from from one cross then you can do what
I'm gonna do with Matt and you can do
easy and you can cheat and you not don't
even need a male yeah you know but
that's how everybody used to start
things and then the traditional way
which is like what got done to maybe
like the c99 and other [ __ ] was that
people would now it's BC but back then
it was BX people would just repeatedly
cross males of a hybrid to the same
clone
yeah one two three four times basically
trying to get an inbred plant that was
as close to the mother clone as they
could yeah and because of that
that explanation of c99 and there and
and that long explanation of how it was
achieved and blah blah blah people have
consistently even myself I I was trying
to do bx3s for years and finding that
like I'm ending up with way more
[ __ ] than I started with why does
this look like an F2 as opposed to an uh
a bx3 this should be locking in stuff
not going way further away from it and
it it just doesn't it sometimes things
work great in theory in other plants
that don't necessarily apply as well in
cannabis because it's so variant and a
lot of people don't understand that
because of c99 the the misinfo given
with c99 yeah and I mean people just
think that like you know when you're
bxing it's like you'd probably need a
pretty big population and then there's a
reason why they call it inbreeding
depression yeah you know it really takes
big populations to avoid that and so
most people are doing hobby ship you
know and so what you just you know is is
like there's an aspect active like
trying to
um you know it's like I always think of
like what Neville's criteria was for his
nl5 hazes yeah right is he didn't want
anything that went over 16 weeks because
he thought that was way too [ __ ] long
and he wanted the potency
and he wanted nice enough Buds and
enough yield that it was worth going the
four months it took
and it had to grow and grow down a grow
Dan Rockwell on the ground well yeah I
mean they I mean that's all they used or
whatever so that was that was the aspect
but that's not he didn't really actually
breed for Terps he didn't breed no he
didn't add in a bunch of extra [ __ ] he
was going for weight potency and it
couldn't take 22 weeks you know like a
lot of the hazes were so you know he
only picked really three things yeah
you know
um and you know we just picked five or
six so it just goes to show that like
don't don't get discouraged you know try
to try to pick a reasonable a reasonable
blend and it's always easier if like if
Matt hadn't given me like the the
licorice thing was a super [ __ ] but
like if because it really limits there's
only a few things that have it I was
gonna go cinnamon but I decided to be
nice cinnamon I would have just thrown
my hands up and been like what the [ __ ]
you know [ __ ] yeah I mean because you
can get too specific but I mean
obviously there's there's scents like
gas or like terpenolene or like citrus
or whatever that occur commonly enough
in cannabis yeah that you'd have a bunch
of paths to pick where you wanted to get
that terp from yeah the terp that Matt
picked was hella limiting so you really
are like grasping at straws there's
there's some good ones I thought of that
you could have come up with that would
have covered all the bases too it was I
might have missed it you know it's hard
to think off the top of your head oh my
God a four or five stage project that
requires a real male because you know 20
years ago go all your buddy seeds it was
like everything you had in your
collection had regular mails in it yeah
and now most of my not all of it but
there's a good chunk of my [ __ ] that's
feminized yes so that's all I don't want
to say it's useless but it's like it for
this particular [ __ ] thing it's like
not very helpful yeah how many people
make red seeds right now yeah but you
could have done a femme female with a
male Thin Line female side I could have
yeah I mean there's probably and that's
the cool part right is that it's like
sometimes past your goal it's like what
you have access to yeah like the chem
dla Kush was the one I was thinking of
specifically for like maybe some some
Terps like uh uh gas and black licorice
but it's not necessarily purple you know
I actually missed that I didn't realize
that until a whole bunch of people
started popping that hybrid the La by D
yeah and and there's a bunch of people
that got gas and headband Aromas and all
that like I was expecting but I would
say there's been a few dozen people at
least that have talked about Anna's
Terps yeah they got the anus
us which was really interesting that you
know to to have that pop up
um you know even occasionally or
whatever
you know uh and you know I I you know I
went on a mission a while a little while
ago and I brought back all those seeds
right yeah and my buddy just never never
did the Femme so remember I was reading
them to you the other day yes and it's
like a hug because it's like what males
did he have when and what was he using
to blend with what you know but that's
something I've noticed with like um a
lot of Mendo breeding and a lot of like
the old school breeding
as opposed to like like with my mindset
it's like I want to use something very
very very basic like almost as close to
land race as I can or something very as
stable as possible um phenotypically
uh on the mail end so I'm not seeing a
lot of variation so I know where I'm
going whereas back in the day it looks
like they would do that single stage
crossed poly hybrid to poly hybrid to
polyhyper to polyhiber to polyhybrid
even back then like it was just how it
was done
it was yeah I mean there was a lot of
like what I call hillweed
um where people would when they sex
their plants their males would stay in
five or ten gallon pots off downwind in
the woods somewhere yeah right and then
when they wanted to make fresh seed
every couple of years or whatever they
would wait and they would go collect
pollen from all their saved males and
blend it together
right and then they'd walk up to their
patch and their two or three favorite
females that year they would take a
paintbrush or whatever and they would
brush the bottoms yeah of those plants
and mark them
so then they're taking a blend of like
you know whatever it is 6 or 12 or 15
boys yeah blending it together and then
adding it to like the three or four
sweetest females they saw from the line
yeah and you do that for 10 or 15 years
and then you have you have a bunch of
kind of unique Hillshire yeah you know
it was like it was relatively diverse
and they wouldn't do it every year most
people would just try to make fresh seed
stock every two or three Sometimes some
people were nerding out and doing it all
the time and some people like seeds was
like the only thing they knew about so
they just tried to freshen them up every
other season or so
you know it sounds like I'm talking down
on it but I actually like that's the
kind of stuff I hunt like if I hear
about someone having old Hill weed seeds
on something I'm like oh let me get out
of you know like I don't know why but
it's always the most appealing to me for
some reason it's also from an era where
there was a whole bunch of diversity
yeah and it was before like the same 45
clones get Blended together in
innumerable ways yeah so even just going
back that far opens up the gene pool in
a way
um I mean that's kind of why when I said
like you know what my buddy that I made
those seeds with or whatever
um he breeds seeds every year yeah you
know he's got stuff going back he's got
all kinds of odd stuff nobody I'm sure
people would love to hear it but he but
you know he breeds for him or whatever
and so he had these you know roughly 20
year old like you know probably from
like right around when Scentsy was
starting to go south yeah
um he has these maple seeds and they
were you know we crossed them to we
actually we actually uh grew a bunch of
them out um in uh five six years ago the
Mendo perps Maple uh there's some really
pretty pictures of them but they burned
damn they burned you know so they got
all the way to like October 9th and then
and then they went to [ __ ] you know yeah
um but that's kind of how you have to do
it it's like you have to like figure out
where you're gonna get it from and for
me it was a little easier because most
of the plants I've mentioned I've had
for a long time yeah so I know how they
work for someone that's just getting
started or whatever like that kind of
complicated thing not knowing how the
plants they have in their stable might
even breed yeah it could be there could
be more missteps
right uh I [ __ ] up a lot yeah you know
so don't don't uh there and there's and
I don't mean [ __ ] up I just mean like
you breed things you hope that these two
things come out of them and they don't
yeah so it's like you just have to try
it a different way you have to try a
different pairing you have to see if
they blend
you know and the more stages you have to
do that you know the you have to get you
have to get bigger you know yeah
um so anyway they uh
um but yeah that's that's roughly how
you would do something like that yeah
you know and then you want me to pick
something out for you yeah you go ahead
and fire off some traits I'll write it
down fire off some traits and I'll do it
from the Femme angle
no no you know you should use them
because because that's that's more
direct and it's easier for people to to
get right so I I wanted to like the main
reason I wanted to do it was I wanted to
illustrate to people how hard it truly
is to be able to say my seeds are going
to deliver XYZ and to be consistent with
what they say they're delivering there's
a lot more that goes into it than just
I'm gonna make a cross and these things
smell like this and that's the way the
seeds are going to come out it's just
not one way one way for people one way
for people to look at it is like how
genetics work is uh when you're Crossing
two things that are pretty simple or
especially things that are widely
Divergent from one another
um like say for instance Neville
Crossing nl5 and Haze uh or me Crossing
maple and Mendo P like you can see the
differences because there's certain
things to look for like if Neville's
growing some [ __ ] and it's super tall
and thin leafed and grows like a tree
it's hazy yeah it stays short and
wide-leaved and Afghan and stout and you
know all that it's probably nl5 Hicks
yeah you know and for Mike the hybrid I
was talking about you can look at purple
you know and and some of the traits that
are unique to Mendo Pete but
um if you cross things that are similar
to each other it can be a real pain in
the ass yeah to try to figure out which
one leans what way which one's breeding
which way
you know exactly you know and so there's
there's an aspect there where
um
I guess what I'm saying is that we have
entered the era where most things are
like a mass hodgepodge unless you go
older strains yeah it's a big mix of
genetics these days
right and so people start putting these
things together and you try to put like
a whatever you know like a freaking
um cush mitts you know by sour sour dub
two things with like huge histories what
could you get
you get a mass amount of [ __ ] right yeah
oh yes yes yes with those two especially
cush mitts
and sour dubs not too uncomplicated or
whatever right so
um so let's say let's let's say you were
gonna hunt something
right
um you know what are you gonna hunt so
what kind of traits do you want say
you're a customer and you're buying for
some big Corporation and they have these
certain wants you may you don't even
have to want them but someone wants
these and you're giving the direction on
what these traits are that they want
okay so they want something that's going
to be high yielding yield okay high THC
potency high THC potency yeah got it can
can go up to 10 weeks
up to 10 weeks up to 10 weeks yeah and
um
and let's see here give me three more
give you three more all right and then
so uh I don't want to say purple because
I just did that or whatever but
um let's just say that it has to have
um
it has to have citrus turps
laughs
brutal okay what and wash well
because they're because they want those
those High yielding Citrus extracts as
well as that okay and so what do we got
now we got it's got a yield well one
more
high THC up to 10 weeks Citrus wash as
well
hi GNC washes well that should pretty
much cover it I'll give you those okay
okay
um
I THC let's see
I'm gonna give myself a little more
complex I'm going to have I'm going to
give it density because otherwise I
would just say linen I just threw that
in I mean as long as it yielded well
yeah and and wash as well I don't think
the [ __ ] I don't think the client is
going to give a [ __ ] yeah I would like
this this like
it would be probably lemon G or like
lemon G something like lemon tree
um but if I were gonna make a femme line
from scratch without the obvious [ __ ]
and also leaving out like cookies and OG
and stuff like that and I'm not I'm
gonna remove lemon G because it's just
too obvious
and with Citrus let's see here
I'm gonna go
one second c99 grapefruit
as the start and as the base oh man
there you go on the male side because I
know that this is the dominant
um oh wait no I'm not doing me I'm doing
female but so it's even easier yeah but
it's also the dominant
uh scent expression from c99 the seed
lines going around so it's going to be
more commonly occurring so when I'm
choosing this female and it's showing
that has a citrus grapefruit Terps it'll
likely also breed for those knowing c99
well like I do so we know we've got that
covered but we also know c99 is like a
seven to eight weeker so we've we can
allow ourselves to bring up the THC with
something a little more
um
a little more typically sativa end
I would do
I would do a a clone from Appalachia
hi oh it's Appalachia Green Crack tray
dog
we've got the potency you got the wash
well you got somebody actually just said
Appalachia by senior second time yeah in
the comments hilarious
nailed it that's that's what I would do
a good cut like a a green crack dominant
cut with a little bit of gas of
Appalachia and to a c99 grapefruit
reversal and I would probably you know
uh do it under middle halides on tables
small plants
um more plants uh in numbers for the
reversal as opposed to bigger plants I'd
want smaller and more
and yeah that's how I do it
that's how you do it no c99 doesn't wash
super well but Green Crack washed pretty
good and uh I believe Appalachia will
too especially because the tray dog and
I mean the other thing that you could do
too is that if it ended up not washing
well then you could have a c99
Appalachia hybrid that gave you some
Citrus and some Bag appeal and some
weight you know and and was going to
come in within the time and he could go
another step let's say he failed yes
right let's say that failed let's say
that got you high yielding plants
right that had some citrus
um but it didn't wash very well yes but
you got high potency high yield and you
had Citrus yes
but you're short
they're trying to they're trying to run
it they're trying to they're trying to
make ice water they're doing all this
different stuff BHO and it's just coming
out at a percentage it's not making
their extraction happy yeah so now you
need another step
I need one more step for resin
production I'm going to cheat and go for
the white
the white you're gonna go for the white
the classic boost resin production uh
the Terps aren't that great but I've
seen it combine well with stuff that is
really dominant like c99
so I'd probably add the white in there
because it was also it also has that
that huge bag appeal and and it does
have good THC do you think the c99
Citrus is strong enough that it would
carry through in a lot of those hybrids
still and still be dominant I do I think
you can't wash it out I think it's kind
of like deep chunk one of those so you
think it would be it would be one of
those things where like the the sheer
blandness of the white yep wouldn't
dominate yep
so then we'd have a a
c99 by uh by Appalachia by the White
Appalachia uh c99 White yeah that's the
way I do it so reverse the white because
I also know the white reverse as well
that was the other thing I was thinking
right so that's the other part is you
can get a failed reversal
and I know the white reverse as well
Rascal did it consistently I've done it
a few times so it's a good one
interesting I mean I uh
and that ladies and gentlemen is when
you start talking to corporate guys
about what they want why things like
Jack Ferrer and Jack Herer hybrids are
blended into everything because they're
like I want three pounds of light gotta
look pretty
It's gotta be quick you know I want to
sativa high and it's got to be eight
weeks yeah and so then they're like oh
c99 Jack Herrera like I remember when
Colorado I was gonna make fun of you but
I held off when Colorado went legal
think like I remember that everybody was
getting three pounds of light but it was
all hybrids of Jack Herrera Durbin
poison green crack and there was one
more because there was anything that
threw like big long forearms golden
goats yeah and then they would just
hybridize things looking for Finos that
they would get three pounds of light
yeah you know and so everything was
crossed like one of those four things
because they all looked at it from like
mathematics
you know I think um I think uh
realistically why c99 still is popular
today even easy even more so than um
even more so than Jack Herrera even I
think c99 still dominates is because of
the outdoor scene in California and
because of that demand for a sativa type
that's super fast flowering that
finishes in time in NorCal and I tend to
think Appalachia is going to be what
totally wipes c99 out when enough people
run it it had a good it had a good run
for a while uh by a high-end Lonesome
when he originally made it and then
Bodhi did a bunch of crosses with it but
um I still think it's got It's it's a
big run coming Jack does carry the
terpenolene Terps for Generations yep
you know uh Green Crack is actually a
really nice strain grown well yeah most
people have got a bad name because there
was a bunch of people that would grow
six to ten pound outdoor plants kind of
be great of it and got blown out but
if you grow a nice little four to eight
ounce plant
and and you know and you treat it right
it's got some nice Terps it's got a
sweet high it's not like knock you out
like but it's it's pretty you know it
might be my like if it is mostly skunk
one it might be my favorite example of
Scotland yeah yeah I would say like just
the way sometimes like when it comes out
really nice the bud is really green and
the the crystal is really silvery
you know and it's it's got a nice sweet
terp to it yeah there's a good chance it
might be a Mendo perp skunk one of sorts
I I do think that
Green Crack yeah holy [ __ ] that would
trip me out yeah I mean it's mango
Turkey
um it's very purple with even the
slightest bit of cold but I mean it's
like black people say where can I find
it that's the thing is that real Green
Crack was so common that and all of a
sudden it's like really hard to find the
real one yes and you know it got renamed
honestly in like the people doesn't read
its name people because real because
Green Crack got a bad name like Brokers
put off on it but then when the extract
era happened I'm convinced that there's
a bunch of papaya that's just [ __ ]
green crack
it could be yeah you know I'm not saying
100 all of it but like when you abstract
green crack and you wash it it has nice
tropical fruit Terps some people get
papaya some people get mango some people
get whiffs of other things depending on
their nose or whatever
um but you know it it has that similar
profile yeah in that regard you know but
I I think because of certain traits
there's a good chance that mental
purpose tend to be in that lineage I'm
surprised you'd never noticed that one I
would I would honestly trip out if that
was the I mean I've been wrong before
yeah I'll I'll say that and we've had
good friends of ours that that told me
things that I was just like oh no and
then later on I was like whoa whoa you
know so it's it's possible but
um you know I the story of that one is
pretty mysterious it is very mysterious
because there's
um the tale of of Cecil and when I when
I first encountered it was through
through uh James Hall he had green crack
but we had it labeled as green Kush with
a c in our room and it actually said
green like written out cushed with the
sea so because of that when I first went
online people were talking about how
well Cecil C has a Kush with a c so for
a long time me and Cecil tried to meet
up so we could talk about this stuff and
figure it out and when we finally talked
it sounds like his Kush with the sea was
very skunky like he says the one that he
said to San Diego was very skunky which
is not like the green crack or the green
Kush that was in San Diego
um I don't know if it originates in San
Diego I don't know if it originates in
Mendo or up up in Humboldt it could be
from freaking Oregon for all we know
with a different name I know it made it
to SoCal with the name uh bring Kush
with the season oh yeah and then became
Green Crack after that people are
throwing around different things people
are asking like well how do you Source
what you're breeding with and to be
honest
um you know like I never really did a
bunch of breeding projects where I had
to go out and like have a treasure your
map and find the things I wanted
mostly you end up reading with stuff you
have access to yeah let's be real we
were creating a hypothetical situation
and I tend to have a so I tended to pick
things in my library not hypothetical
things I'd have to get but like actual
things that I possess yeah because
that's just where my mind goes right it
would be infinitely harder to like be
like oh well I need to do a project
that's going to take three or four steps
and I need to gather
a bunch of different things that are
going to be new to me you know and
there's an aspect people are talking
about I don't think philosophilos can't
actually determine family relationships
the way that we did one day one day we
will sit down and a few of us will tell
the story about how we put philos's
science to the test by using known
clones known parentage of these clones
and submitted them to philos to see if
they could truly determine parentage
yeah there's an aspect too where people
are saying green crack and blue dream
got played out right at the same time
yeah there's there's an aspect you know
because I live in Mendocino County or
whatever like and for a long time it was
sort of like the heart of of uh you know
outdoor and stuff in California before
it spread
um a lot of times you would have plants
that were really nice on their own like
the blue dream or the green crack or the
berry white or the this whatever it
might be and they get there's an era
where like they're really popular and
they're and they're moving really well
and their people are growing really nice
examples of them and then there's a
point where people realize how much
money they can make and they can throw
out 99 plants and get eight pounds of
plant and you do the math and so all of
a sudden there's all this B and C grade
of the same strain and it kind of
harshes the strain out so a lot of times
people will be like oh that strain sucks
and really what happened is the market
got exploded by a bunch of low quality
enormous waves of it because it was
super profitable
um and then the you know the you know it
moves on and so people move on you grow
a little four ounce plant of green crack
or blue dream you'd probably be prepared
happy yeah yeah you grow it nice you
know you grow a little three four ounce
plan of it like you'd probably be stoked
and so are your buddies
Blue Dream because I was still very
heavily involved in the seed seed
business when Blue Dream got real big
and all that got blown up and what I saw
happen right before my eyes was there
was a few of us that made s1s of that
original cut and released it in some
good hybrids and then we saw
major Spanish companies making seedlines
called blue dream that had nothing to do
with blue dream to cut they would
combine like a blueberry and their hazes
whatever they had and put that on the
market and uh I don't want to name any
names or anything but certain companies
would buy these import them to the US
and all of a sudden these Blue Dream
seeds were everywhere the attitude was
doing giveaways with everything you
bought you would get these Blue Dream
seeds so blue dream hit the country in
Mass but it wasn't blue dream it was
blueberry haze from some Spanish company
with the with the California Market
getting the majority of the actual Blue
Dream bus right and I mean there's an
aspect too where I think that for most
plants there's a window of uh of quality
yeah you know it it varies plant to
plant but I actually think a lot of the
indoor look
is just because people are growing
relatively small plants compared to
outside and yeah you know
so you're only asking a plant to give
you say like one to eight ounces it'll
have a vastly different look than if
you're asking that plant to give you a
pound or two pounds or three pounds or
eight pounds right yeah um and I've had
I've had times where it was like when we
were transplanting and stuff like some
plants got broken off at the stem yeah
you know and so not used and so I would
grow these like depths and these plants
would get like a pound and then like
helpers wouldn't want to throw away the
ones we broke so there'd be like a
branch this Bay a stem this big with a
few branches coming off it and when we
pulled that stuff down that lift stuff
looks so amazing compared to compared to
like the the rest of it because it was
like three ounces
yeah and it was just super Frosty and
choked out so there's an aspect
certainly with different plants of like
there's a size sweet spot
yeah where you get it I like blue dream
at four to six ounces that's where it
was like just [ __ ] perfect every
[ __ ] time most weed is if it's gonna
be good weed you know that's a decent
that it can it can get that big you know
uh some plants can get to a half pound
some plants can get to a pound but
there's a there's a point of diminishing
quality yeah absolutely you know where
it's like the resin doesn't stretch or
the Terps don't stretch or the plant
just has to put so much energy into its
stem and its structure and it's how it's
going to survive it doesn't have enough
to put into you know it's the quality of
its wheat yeah I mean there's people
that swear that small little plants in
one gallon pots
you know or or is the headiest wheat
yeah that's I know that um when CSI was
talking about shabad's uh sour that he
talks about is like some of the best
Smokies ever had out of it millions of
plants he's probably smoked
um he always says that you know it was
in a one gallon pot in the flower or
power flower and that's it
yeah I mean so there's an aspect there's
an aspect there where it's like you I
mean I used to actually do uh a bunch of
breeding that way right once I got smart
uh smarter I said I I suppose I should
say because I used to just grow up all
these [ __ ] seeds and granted the era
was different but still you get all this
random weed that you didn't like very
much yeah because let's face it when
you're breeding it's like you're only
gonna like so much of it yeah you know
and then I got smart instead of like
blooming the seeds I would grow them up
and I would take cuts and I would put
them into like a one gallon pot and I
would grow like on a you know I might
grow like 50 or 100 plants on a 4x8
and I'm just going for like a single
stock try to get a half ounce
yeah but that half ounce will tell me
does it have the Terps does it have the
high that's enough smoke and then maybe
I can grow out a hundred things at once
and it's small enough to still know
you're getting the quality the ultimate
quality that you can get from that plant
without having to push it hard yeah and
you're starting from a clone because
that's the other thing that I realized
is like a lot of times I wanted to see
like what a clone would do yeah because
you only get one shot at the seat yeah
you only ever see that seat one yeah
it's got a Tap Root it's gonna act
differently yeah so I got more
consistent when I just like when I would
just take I would breed and I would I
wouldn't flower the seed plants I would
flower the Clones
yeah I would want to see what they did
as clones and then I could flower almost
like a sea of green Style
and then you could have 100 or 150
things and if they're like you know 10
to 20 ounce 10 to 20 grams each maybe a
zip
yeah and that's one thing that's one
thing I've been trying to teach
everybody that's watched like breeder
Syndicate or my my live streams uh since
I started doing them is when you buy
seeds when you buy seeds and you're
popping seeds you know a lot of people
run into
um
sexual instability issues all kinds of
other issues or they like it the one
time and they don't like it the rest and
they don't understand why you know I
always tell them I always say don't
worry about blooming the mom don't worry
about blooming the seed mom Bloom the
Clone mom because that's what you're
going to see every time and that's what
matters that's what that's what matters
that's where you need to make your
choices from and it'll at 99 of the time
any sexual instability issues are gone
with the Clone 99 time for whatever
reason that's how it works it's just
different hormones so yeah but yeah I
mean I used to get two ounces four
ounces five ounces eight ounces all
these different plants all these
different sizes all all that and like
it's hard to do that but you can
actually go through a bunch of plants
and you really don't need to me you
really don't need more than you know 10
or 20 grams should give you like a
really good idea yeah whether or not
which ones you like enough to like work
with again yeah and that's good that
could be done on one or two four by
eights yeah it doesn't even take that
much you know and then you and then you
know I would just toss the seat bomb and
I would just keep clunk you know
clones's back up
yeah and as soon as they grew a little
bit just flip them and I wanted to see
like what the main the main stem would
do wouldn't top them just try to get
Spears yeah relatively speaking Yeah
I mean it's not the only way to do it
but it is a way for people a lot of
people these days are going to have
smaller size areas to work with and then
if you did that into a greenhouse you
could look what you could look through
three or four hundred plants if you
wanted yeah but the hard part is going
to be testing it
is always labeling drying it keeping it
separate I mean you know Caleb he's got
[ __ ] hangers with all kinds of
color-coded labels on them and notes and
[ __ ] and then you're trying to keep them
all separate and different plastic bag
or different jars or whatever
and then you're trying to like smoke and
take notes so let's talk about like the
the downside of doing too big of a pop
that's what I was just saying you know I
was like how do you you know like
there's an aspect of like
um doing too big of a pump
is cool in the sense that when you're
looking for certain physical
characteristics you're going through
more faster
yeah right and so you can you can you
can sift through but then you know
um you know smoke testing let's say you
have 50 things
smoke testing all that takes a while
and you usually got to engage friends
yeah let's say you have 13
000 things though
that was yeah I mean that was uh at that
point you're not really Fino I mean
you're you're not really Fino hunting
you're doing some Fino hunting but you
realize that like the vast majority of
it it's gonna get lost to time yeah you
know there's no time I mean you know we
have a pretty big thing going right now
with some of Caleb's work and it's it's
like we really get to see what's in the
line yeah and how it expresses right but
the vast majority of them are going to
be kept for any reason yeah vast
majority can't be smoked I mean it's
just to get to that like if you're let's
say you're popping
2 000. like how are you gonna smoke that
within a certain amount of period unless
you just have people chiefing for free
all day and those [ __ ] don't go
away you know yeah I mean there's an
aspect where really like for a hobby
Gardener I mean a lot of depending on
how people smoke even if you did 60 or
70 things
it would take you you know if you smoked
two or three of them a day
you know it would take you you know
almost a month yeah to sort through it
yeah and so you know
um you know and then you could also have
certain kinds of criteria maybe some
things you smoke one bowl of and it
doesn't have the flavor it you don't
like it you just immediately you know
but then it's like how fine of a comb
yeah you know
um people say cut a clone latent flower
you know there's a lot of uh there's a
lot of Euros that don't like to keep
backup clones and they'll literally do
this thing where they'll leave all the
bottoms on their plants and they'll
Bloom them
and their favorites they'll just like
move before the plant's fully finished
and re-vege the bottoms yeah you know
the problem with that that there's
nothing wrong with that method
um because a lot of times the easiest
things to re-vadge are like the poorly
floured out uh you know wispy [ __ ] on
the bottom so you can cut a plant down
and smoke it and be re-veging it
um but it does take months
it does it takes a few months for it to
start kicking back yeah it's like I did
it a ton for a long time
um when I would do uh uh final hunts
because I would try to do as big of a
Fino hunt as I could do in with as many
different lines and what usually ended
up happening was that I couldn't keep
you know four clones of every single
thing that I was hunting through so I
had to get really good at reveging I had
to get it right every [ __ ] time and
figure out how to do that and eventually
I figured out how to do that and be
consistent with it but it's hard and it
takes a long [ __ ] time my buddy I was
mentioning that I did the maple project
he was he that he was just saying he
does 50 60 things at a time and it's a
[ __ ] yeah you know it's like you have
lives it's not that easy to like it's
one thing to get baked every day it's
another thing to like take notes and see
how you feel and you know be looking for
certain aspects of things so you either
have to be a super harsh dick or It
Takes a Minute yeah you know
um and and so and a lot of times what
sucks
you know is that uh you know the runty
shitty [ __ ] up plant that you almost
killed
ends up being the most interesting one
to smoke in flavor yeah and all the ones
that had all the structure and growth
and vigor that you wanted were were oh
just you know okay compared to some of
those other ones yeah it's always the
scrawny shitty one that doesn't want to
revege the most stubborn one that's
usually the one I want to keep yeah I
mean obviously I mean imagine imagine if
you know the OG craze happened but like
OG grew like blue dream
yeah
there really would be blue dream
billionaires
[Laughter]
you know and all that because it's like
that but that's the that's the kind of
Interest maybe we could talk about that
for a minute
um because well it's interesting is that
I was talking about like when things
went legal in Colorado and all of a
sudden all these high-yielding plants
started getting bred into all the indoor
because that's what met the model yeah
there is a risk uh as Things become
legal that the weird runty [ __ ] up
offshoots that we all know and love that
end up becoming like our Elites get cold
yeah because they don't meet the
production model
well I remember
um even even when sub cool was at the
height of of breeding Fame I would call
it even what he would what he had what I
would call is genuine Fame at one point
that dude was pretty famous and um he
was putting it out there
um
my [ __ ] I'm gonna interrupt then for a
second uh go ahead our homie from Hawaii
was saying taking Cuts two or three
weeks into flower is nice they stay
small and about the time they re-veg
you're finishing up the round
That's What CSI does a whole bunch uh
his primary method is to take clones
clean up the bottoms about two weeks
into into bloom
um and then that and then that slows
down and they freak out for a while but
they kind of are on the same timing as
your room so around the time you figure
out which ones are good
um or hope you know they're because they
get because you can get them too big and
then you're chopping them back
yeah I was gonna say sub cool he would
call a lot of seeds in the seedling
stage like in the seedling stains he
would do major culling and I was always
a big opponent of that because I found
that like a lot of the slower growing
stuff can be just as amazing a Keepers
for different reasons you know but for a
while that that was in cannabis and
still kind of is a common thought that
if it's weak as a Seedling call it well
I mean there's nothing wrong with that
in in a certain aspect but then it's
just making it harder to find what you
want because you're trying to guarantee
that it's going to be in a strong and
vigorous plan exactly and if there's one
thing we know about cannabis is that
like the week the weak shitty ones
sometimes have a tendency of being like
the Market's favorite yeah OG Kush I
can't even believe that wasn't called at
the beginning just to how floppy limbed
and it has so many traits that that are
hard hard I mean let's talk about you
know do you know the thing that I will
put this number one all time I can't
believe it was cold
the quays
oh yeah yeah the wild one how how can
you grow something that takes that long
and every bud is like a tiny fingernail
sized [ __ ] calyx Ripper yeah and it
becomes one of the more famous strains
in in Holland uh that was a labor of
love because there's a bunch of people
that would look at that halfway through
and be like what a mess deaths so I I
got Finos like that or expressions like
that from
um Alaskan ice seeds that I purchased
from uh seed Madness I want to say in
the UK
um
yeah it spit out females like that and
they were immediately called like I
didn't think anything of it it was
before I had ever seen or run the
question yeah you would just kill it
you'd be like this is super [ __ ] this
is the worst thing ever this is horrible
yeah this is [ __ ] ridiculous so you
just kill it you know and that's
actually what Neville did to about half
his Haze seeds that popped yeah because
they were so sparse and [ __ ] up that
he didn't realize what he had and he
called him and then he smoked it uh and
then yeah somebody was saying oh gkb OG
KB is an excellent example of something
that would never make a production model
yeah super slow takes forever to badge
doesn't yield that much you know all
that and so I always think of tomatoes
right
because there's been this heirloom
tomato sort of Renaissance in America
yeah um but when people are like you go
to the grocery store you see lots of
delicious vegetables or whatever but
tomatoes are bred for size and weight
and color and to not rot and to not
split and flavor is way down there so
the tomatoes that get stuffed into most
people's grocery stores are like big
money making watery
it's like all the production values are
Paramount yeah and the part where it's
delicious and it tastes good and it has
the flavors that we want like we can't
force them to do that which is why a lot
of people think store-bought Tomatoes
suck yeah
so but what I mean by that well yeah but
what I mean by that is that like as
cannabis goes into a production model
and they start looking at square footage
and cost and yield and this and that and
everything else there could be very
different uh pressures put on what
strains make it to the public yeah the
OG would never have made it the ogkb
would never have made it the qua the you
know the quays would never have made it
like there's a lot of varieties out
there for one reason or another that
wouldn't fit somebody's production model
yeah I was always surprised when cookies
showed up like the form cut because it
was so low yielding like so so low
yielding uh compared to what was
typically going around even even most OG
cushes had been they've figured him out
to make them yield their cookies was
just so low yielding I was shocked that
it ever got commercial viability I don't
think it would have without I mean there
was an aspect where prices were starting
to fall yeah and and Instagram was young
and it was like a perfect moment where
it gained a bunch of popularity and then
it sold for high dollars so it was
almost kind of like the same thing with
Kush right like and our buddy resin it's
like sure you might not get as much
weight as you were getting off other
things until you figured it out but if
you were selling it for Seven Grand a
pound you really didn't care yeah
exactly you know that there was some
there was some like oh I can get lower
yields off this baked into it yeah
you know but still and it's still uh
yeah makes way more money than otherwise
right and so there's an aspect now where
it's like yeah biomass people are
looking for like you know like weight on
you know wet weight how much I can
extract what's my yield what's my this
where the previous selection process in
cannabis was entirely consumer based
yeah right almost all these fads needed
a bunch of people at the other end
willing to buy it for top dollar yeah
that's what drove the purple craze
that's what drove sour that's why sour
was the best selling weed in America was
because there was this massive Corridor
on the East Coast that this couldn't get
enough of it yeah right yeah it became
part of the culture it became part of
the culture you know and then cush had
its whole moment in Southern California
and elsewhere yeah you know and then
cookies was the bay and then you know
and you have Skittles winning all these
Awards and stuff so a lot of that stuff
is I mean we used to joke when we first
got the real Skittles where it was like
you'd start edging next year's death now
yeah I did you know because it was like
oh just give it a good six month veg and
it'll be three feet tall yeah I remember
the first time my buddy I had a I had a
good friend of mine that got Skittles
kind of before it was it was named that
as much and he grew these plants he had
light County beautiful sun 400 gallon
pots you know all organic really nice
and he called me up all panicked and
wanted me to come out and I was like
walking this was like back in the trees
era so I'm walking through he has shot
diesels and green cracks and you know
different things and they're all you
know nine ten feet tall trellised out
you know scat all that and then you walk
to this section and there's like five
Skittles and they like come up to like
my waist yeah I bet and they're all wide
and like little chunks and his buddy was
like oh I'll give you like four times as
much but you're looking at these like
tiny little runts they were all started
at the same time yeah and he thought he
was [ __ ] up
yeah he just didn't realize that it grew
eight times as slow as anything else
yeah
um you know and so there's that aspect
too where it was like Skittles would
never pass any kind of production model
Skittles looks like they've got a
goddamn disease Skittles is ugly as
flower for the most part you know which
is fine I don't mind I I am totally a
pre-cookie person so I'm fine with ugly
flour that works good yeah
um but you know it it's very slow
growing it's a bit mold prone
um you know uh but none of that mattered
when it was winning a bunch of awards
for extraction exactly because you're
just testing the extract and the hash
was fire and that's that was my point
about the potency aspect too it's like
yeah I mean like it used to be a major
deal that if the flower wasn't potent
but that's not such a deal breaker
anymore with the extract Market thriving
no I mean in fact I'll you know I was
joking with you about Citrus and it was
it was a little I get me saying Citrus
gave you a bunch of pads because there's
a bunch of kinds of citrus and citrus
for people that don't know also tends to
breed fairly dominant yes you know
orange things a lot of time past Orange
grapefruit grapefruit lemon lemon that
kind of thing right it's a pretty
dominant term work
um you know but a lot of times those
um those Citrus cuts are pretty moderate
to mild potency yeah there's not really
a lot of ones that test very high or by
themselves are particularly potent and
so I almost think that like Tangy came
along at a perfect time because it was
like a big skunk plant here I am
shouting out DNA or whatever but it was
a big Citrus skunk plant at a time when
a lot of people had forgotten about
Citrus because it was so unpopular yeah
coincided right with the extraction
movement
and that Citrus Turf passed or at the
time a lot of other Terps kind of ended
up tasting like axle grease and it also
was not named Cali o no most importantly
so people were like oh that's his no
it's not named Calio and so and so I
really I don't know if it would have
caught on without that BHO era being
timed right then when people were
getting nails and dab kit and all the
different little tools and accoutrements
that went along with it you know yeah
um and then it's like you take something
that's like 15 THC and not that potent
but if you extract it and it's 80 well
now okay now we're somewhere yeah it
might not be a long lasting high but
it'll get you high
I know there's something and we can keep
talking about this but I know there's
something that people wanted you to
cover and it's something that we missed
last time a few times ago and it was
your drawing Tech
oh man
well let me uh I'll talk about that let
me just say because people are throwing
in Calio so in that big hunt that we
were doing
um down south or whatever uh I ran a
number of csis Calio hybrids
and I was actually amazed at how sativa
it read
yeah it really it really did like even
things that were pretty Indica that I
thought would be would lean they were
big tall branchy
orange smelling
you know yeah the grandpa weed looking
uh phinos and stuff like that so it was
it was a lot more in different hybrids
it was a lot more sativa than I was
expecting yeah right
oh I'll say that and Cali o went through
periods where it became so unpopular it
was almost unsellable yes yes I it's the
only weed well a type of Kaleo is the
only weed someone ever brought back to
me and said not not this didn't get me
high yeah and there's an aspect with
almost with a lot of very citrusy weed
that's like that where people find the
high to be some some people find the
height of these fleeting or super
short-lived or they just develop a
tolerance to it after two or three days
um you know and uh and other people are
fine with it but there is a percentage
of people that develop a tolerance and
find it boring yeah and there's
definitely a difference someone said
cleaner there's definitely a difference
in Citrus there are some plants that are
like sweet Citrus that have almost a
creaminess to them yeah and then there's
ones that smell like you just sprayed
orange cleaner in your mouth yes very
stringent and orange just pissed orange
or a lemon you know something like that
just Berry like astringent and weird and
and like you've sucked on a chemical you
know yeah I I hate that that long
lingering mouth-coating lemon like lemon
G and lemon tree I can't stand that oh
you just burn out I mean I'm one of
those people I burn out it's fine to
have it in rotation
but if I was stuck with it as my only
weed for a month I would be so bummed I
I get yeah I don't even put it in
rotation I don't like the tip flavor at
all and but there was a moment where
with BHO and certain things when that
was super popular before rosin was
really hitting that those Citrus Terps
came through really clean and clear a
lot of people made a lot of money off
[ __ ] lemon G in Ohio yeah lemon G and
and the Tangy I mean Tangy sort of
rocketed DNA to being super busy for
four or five years after that
cracked it yeah I mean you know whatever
whatever combination yeah Crockett you
know so
um as far as drying Tech man that's a uh
that's a big subject but I could chat
about it or whatever yeah this is your
specialty man I will say that um
I will say that like you know there's a
lot of people that throw a lot of stuff
out there as far as like what's drying
Tech and I think there's a lot of like
copycat stuff out there yeah um so for
me
um because I've always been a smoker uh
I was always interested in making sure
my weed came out nice yes right and
curing it you know a lot of times people
put an enormous amount of of uh uh
weight on what they feed their plant
and all that and like all these
different environmental factors and
those those things can all throw in but
if you don't cure it the right way
um a lot of that gets overwhelmed yes
you know and so there's an aspect where
there's no point in my career rally
really where I was competing on scale
there was always way bigger people than
me so I always tried to make sure even
if there was a flood up in my neck of
the woods that my weed was just good
enough to go yeah
right like some of it's gonna move yeah
should be mine yeah you know what I mean
and so damn right and and so as a result
of that you had to and then on top of
that too
it's like coming from like a my own
perspective is like I never grew my head
stash super separate too much so like I
needed it all to be good yeah in that
regard people are saying let's hear the
dry Tech well there's like but it's it's
just like the breeding Tech or whatever
right there's like there's goals like
what are you trying to do right and so
one of the things I had to figure out
was that and this is kind of what like
separately led to caring is that there's
this thing up here that we use now it's
permanent but there's this thing we used
to call that uh called the flood
and the flood used to be November
December January and it was it was way
too hard to sell herb okay it's because
you know people would go on vacation
people would go to see their families
it's around the holidays some people
like Hawaii some people are back home
with Grandma and if enough links in
those chains disappear
people end up sitting on stuff yeah and
then people figured out that there was a
dry spell in Spring
and so if you were if you were smart you
would hold on to most of your stuff
until spring when it would be both much
easier and
um much more higher price yeah higher
price right so that was good so uh is
the flood happening this year this year
the flood is the last few years the
flood has seemingly never stopped we are
yeah we are living in Water World
there's been no receding there's been no
price spiking going on it has been
Atlantis man this is this is yes this is
the ice caps melting as far as pricing
goes on the west coast so
um but what happened is is that you
ended up needing to figure out like
people realize that if they trimmed all
their weed in in Fall it both cost a
bunch of money because you had to pay
the Tremors and then for the most part
unless you were really careful about how
you stored it your weed was worse in
spring when you had to when you had to
sell yeah and then sometimes you were
growing enough that like you weren't
even with the size trim crew you're
gonna have it was going to take you a
while to even get to that weed yeah so
you had to be able to dry and cure it
right in a way that it stayed nice yeah
for a period of time for a variety of
reasons yeah right and then there's an
aspect where you can always like if you
it's it's basically like you get one
shot to do it the right way and you can
like adapt along the way but if you [ __ ]
up too bad you've just ruined it for
that round yeah
so I know that's like a I haven't really
said anything about the tech but there's
like a
a reasoning behind it of how you get
there right so uh and for people that
aren't Growers that are listening I'm
sorry if you're bored or whatever but
because it's about to get a little
specific but
um basically what I what the way I look
at it is that when you're drawing weed
I like to either cut the plant down
whole
um or chop it into chunks yeah okay
relatively relatively big chunks okay
um someone just said oh teach me your
ways in an eight by four so
um if you're worried about temps or
you're worried about water loss or
you're a little extra dry you can leave
it in bigger pieces
yeah because those pieces will hold more
moisture because there's a lot of
moisture in the stem if you have really
good control over your environment you
can chop them into smaller mid-sized
pieces and hang them that way
um and I just hang them up
um people can you can use hangers you
can use netting uh you can use you know
just a variety of things that allows you
to click create lines or walls
is basically how it boils down to and
um I leave all the water leaf on yeah
100 I don't take off any water leaf and
the reason for that is that the things
that [ __ ] up your buds are
um are uh basically air
heat and light yeah right those are the
things that start to oxidize your weed
and start to mess it up okay so what all
that families do is that they fold down
over the flower and they essentially
like if you have fans for air movement
and stuff like that they're generally
blowing on the fan leaves not on
directly on your flower yeah and it's
making your flower darker yeah right so
it's protecting it from wind it's
protecting it from from light it's
protecting it from the various things
that might degrade it and
as your plant starts to dry it'll suck
that moisture from all those from all
those leaves into itself yes and that's
kind of what you're trying to do is
you're trying to get you're trying to
get
um how do you put it you're trying to
slowly sweat out enough moisture gotten
enough chlorophyll right so you want
this to be a slow process do you want it
to be a slow process so I see all kinds
of things where people talk about 60 60
you know 60 degrees and 60 humidity for
two weeks uh I do disagree on that a
little bit
um I think the 60 humidity is fine
um but I think that that's actually like
a little too cold yeah you know and it
really slows down uh transpiration at
times I like it I think the 60s is fine
I like I like uh you know mid 60s and
anywhere really realistically speaking
from mid 60s to low 70s you're pretty
safe yeah you know in my opinion like
there's ideal and then there's like what
you're going to deal with and then
there's an aspect of like
um there's a there's an aspect of uh
when you're hanging it the first three
or four days a whole bunch of water is
going to flow out of those plants yeah
so depending on how much weed you have
and how much space it is like it doesn't
really matter if you have a stuffed four
by eight or you have a stuffed big
garage or you have a stuffed Warehouse
or whatever whatever size it is if it's
stuffed
um you know it can be really hard to
have enough dehumidification yeah in
order to pull that much water out of it
so a lot of people lose control or
whatever like the and you know a lot of
D homes don't even like to work at 60
degrees either yeah so having them a bit
warmer really helps it but that's one
thing people should all look at is that
there's a bunch of dehumidifiers if you
don't have a low-grain refrigerant d-hum
you probably don't have a d-hum that's
suitable for drying yeah and most d-hums
are rated for a certain temperature
which is quite warm and a certain
humidity which is quite high and you
should look at like where their
operating temperature is right so if the
D hum says it's stub operating at 58
degrees yeah don't run your room at 60.
yeah it's too close to it just not
working you should probably run it at 70
and give your D home a chance to work
right yeah so but if you have a low
grain refrigerant d-hum
um it'll work at those temps so there's
basically a mode where it's like you're
just trying to make sure your weed
doesn't mold and you get that humidity
you're trying to keep it cool and you're
trying to get that humidity out of there
yeah some people vent you know some
people literally exhaust air and bring
in fresh air because that's like if the
temperatures and outside are fine or
whatever that's great yeah um some
people try to do a combination of air
conditioners and d-hums but you're
basically trying to keep it somewhere
between the mid 60s to low 70s and temp
and you know somewhere between ideally
60 humidity but don't panic if it's 65
or 70 or even 75 four or five for the
first day or two it should come down but
if it doesn't that first day there's so
much moisture yeah and depending on how
much vegetative material in a small
space it could be insane like you were
saying yeah I mean it's it's people are
talking about dipping it hydrogen
peroxide yeah uh don't do that
um people are doing that because they're
trying to pass testing with various PM
or Biologicals or different stuff like
that hydrogen peroxide is um uh is a uh
it oxidizes
various Terps it's going to oxidize
various compounds it's going to it's
going to lower the quality of your weed
you know yeah
um so so there's an aspect of and look I
mean these are just like people can hit
me up later these are just like basic
things it's actually kind of hard to
just walk through like all the little
details of how you would do it yeah but
essentially I'm just trying to give you
like a range whatever your equipment
might be some people might be able to
use outside air some people might be
able to use dehumidifiers and air
conditioners maybe even dehumidifiers
and heaters depending on where they live
and what time of year it is but you're
just trying to keep the plant in that
range and after three or four days
your plan is going to shrink a bunch
yeah right and once it shrinks a bunch
then you're in a mode where you're going
to start to see
um most of that water is gone and it
should be a lot easier for you to
moderate your drying room yeah right
like as long as as long as you have the
equipment in place that's going to make
it work right you're not really battling
in that middle section yeah right so
you're just trying to keep it at those
same temps and now another three or four
days passes right
and
now you're in the third stage stage of
drawing which is actually kind of weird
because you risk your plants getting too
dry
but if you take them down often after
six or seven days they're still got too
much moisture in the stem and you try to
bin them up or bag them up and that
sweats right out yeah it's a lot more
work yeah right so I like to go 10 or 14
days on the line yeah if I'm doing it
commercially it's usually 10 or 12 of
them doing it for myself it's usually
more like 14. you know but you might
actually have I have humidifiers
uh where sometimes I add moisture bad
back into my room yeah sometimes it
might be fall and it might have not
rained in months and it might be bone
dry and 20 humidity outside and your AC
is removing some moisture and so is your
whatever sometimes you turn off all your
D humps yeah right sometimes you turn
off your fans
um and because you're just trying to
conserve that moisture sometimes and
you're just trying to get through that
next three or four days to let the
chlorophyll on the moisture slowly sweat
out yeah and if it's too dry your stuff
will start to get crisp
yeah right so you're going low and slow
some people just want to say just leave
it at 60 and 60 like the jungle boys or
some [ __ ] and you just like Let It Be I
don't actually I think that there's like
three distinct stages and if you treat
them different it's a little easier to
deal with well 60 60 can't work for all
types of Bud densities either like I
mean you've got to be some range there's
a lot of CopyCat stuff in there so I'm
just kind of trying to give generals and
maybe I'm talking fast because it's kind
of a big subject or whatever but and if
you have if you have the right
environment
um if you have the right environment
like you can actually you could you can
keep it three weeks four weeks you know
it's not like yeah you know you can
actually I mean with the right outside
and the right inside you can leave it up
there for a while if you wanted to I
don't tend to like to because I often
have to refill it or I just find that
the next stage I can actually get a lot
more control doing it what I do next so
this is where a lot of people [ __ ] it up
in my opinion right here right I don't
think I've like talked about anything
too revolutionary yet or any [ __ ] like
no no
um but here's where it's a mess is that
there's an aspect where
after 10 or 11 days like people tend to
think that they need to store their weed
at a consistency that's perfect for
smoke
yeah and you actually probably don't
want to store it at that you probably
want to store it like a little bit too
moist yeah for smoke right and so what
you what I end up doing is at that point
like I think that's where the Cure
begins right and a lot of people think
you cure in jars you actually cure on
the stem okay if you take it off the
stem you're not curing
okay why is that because most curing and
like if you talk to Tobacco farmer
people or whatever like they'll talk
about this all day or you know yeah they
grow tobacco for cigars or different
things there's an interplay between the
stem and the leaf yeah the stem and the
flower
right and the plant can if as long as
it's all connected the plant can move
that moisture around itself yeah right
so what I tend to do is that when it
comes time I will take like a bunch of
like uh literally like a store like
grocery style paper bags yeah and you
open it up and at that point
you got to feel when you're about to
seal something up you gotta think like
you know how like osmosis and like like
Aromas and moisture and all that will
try to equalize yeah so at that point
I've got a bunch of fan leaves and this
somebody was mentioning earlier when you
do it that way bucking is a [ __ ] it is
when you Buck
um before I put my stuff in there I take
most of the No No Sweet Leaf but I take
most of the big leaf off yeah and then I
chop it into chunks that fit into like
the I'm not holding my hands open the
right way but I chop it into chunks that
fit into the paper bag yeah you know so
think about how long a paper bag is and
they're about that size yeah and then
you start stacking it with things that
have Mo not all but most of the family's
removed yeah and left on the stem but
chopped into chunks that fit yeah and
then that that bin can you that that
paper bag can usually hold between I
don't know 400 and 600 700 grams okay
okay so then you fold it over
right and you put it into a contractor
bag
now this might not sound too crazy but
what it does is that you then fill that
contractor bag with say depending on how
tall the contractor is like six or nine
backs
okay okay and so here's here's where a
bunch of people [ __ ] it up in my opinion
right is that it is most people when
they take it down off the line they just
throw it as is into a into a plastic bin
yeah build the band shut the bin that's
a super common way right well the reason
why I don't like that is because what
happens is you have all that extra stem
and you have all that extra fan Leaf
right
yeah and that [ __ ] smells like hay
yeah it really does that's the stuff
that smells like chlorophyll that's the
stuff that smells green that's the stuff
that has all the Aromas that you don't
want and when you put
a bunch of weed or anything into a
sealed container a lot of times all that
Aroma tries to equalize itself yeah so
you're gonna send that Aroma all the way
through your week
yeah right so by picking off most of the
big families and then by chopping the
excess stem off and just leaving it on
stem chunks that are big enough to fit
in the bag you remove most of that and
so the vast majority of what's in that
paper bag is either Sweet Leaf or flour
yeah with some Associated stem right
yeah and then you fill that thing up and
you turn it over and you put it in there
okay so here's where it's also different
than bintech
yeah right in a bin most people use like
the black and yellow totes right yeah
they're like 25 or 30 gallons okay yeah
so you fill one of those up and you put
a lid on and there's nowhere for it to
breathe
and it's two feet of cannabis weighing
down on the bottom yeah so what is that
bot what is that bottom third like
it's got weight pushing down it's gonna
be moisture pushing down on it there's
nowhere for it to breathe right so if
you put like six or nine paper bags into
a contractor
go ahead
um they uh they stop they hold their
shape
yep right
they hold their shape
so you never have
a few thousand grams weighing down on
the bottom yeah there is there you know
what I'm saying yeah you know because
they stack and that paper holds its
shape and the paper Okay
um
the paper actually is porous
yes it's not like a bin so instead of a
bin where you have two or three or four
pounds you know of of weed stuffed into
a bin and then sealed and there's no
breathability yeah all those bags get to
breathe yeah and that breathing is what
brings the moisture slowly from the
center to the outside
okay
right so then you can you can put it in
there right and and you can tie it off
and if you did it just the right way
it'll stay stable like that for straight
up weeks to months
oh yeah 100 okay and I've done I've done
like experiments with friends or
whatever where like you know you trim
some up within a few weeks
yeah and two months later you go back
and all the stuff that was still in the
paper bags has a bunch of Terps
yeah where where the stuff that got
trimmed and started to oxidize
right and so there's an aspect there
where the reason why we came to this is
that for one you don't end up with a
million bins that reek that you have to
sterilize and clean all the time you end
up with like super light contractor bags
and paper bags yeah and let's say you
seal up the contractor bag and it like
you open it up and you [ __ ] up and you
were a little too fast and it's a little
too moist right you can then just open
and leave the contractor bag open yeah
right then if it's if you really [ __ ]
up you might have to take those bags out
of the contractor
yeah but then they all breathe yeah so
you can open them up
right and then if you really messed up
and you were too aggressive about it and
you feel down there and it feels wet and
damp and uncomfortable right yeah you
can actually take an empty paper bag and
your full one and you can dump it in
there and now the bottom is the top yeah
right
you just fluffed it essentially and you
can do that one by one to all of them
that's only if you screw up and you
realize that after you've sealed it up
for a day it's not as stable as you want
it to be there was too much moisture in
there and it actually got re-wet yeah
when you get it to the moisture level
you want you can seal it back up and you
can put it in there and
you know I've had a situation where like
a lot of times in outdoor season in the
fall it took us quite a while to get
through all the work
yeah so you had to store it in such a
way that you could
um you know you you would you would keep
the quality
yeah and that definitely uh made it all
the way to our parties and [ __ ] because
I remember smoking that you know after
fact and it was still just amazing oh
that first year especially yeah pip and
myself and and home you know the friends
like we went and all that weed in those
in those bags and jars we pulled out of
that's why most of it was on trimmed you
know or partially trimmed we just pulled
it out of the bags just like that Tech
and it had been sitting in there for two
months yeah and most of our close
friends to be perfectly honest uh in
Even in our Circle and our Discord and
stuff like that that have tried this
method keep using it there's ways you
can refine it I kind of skimmed over
certain parts but because there's depth
and there's things that can come up but
as far as like a modular small the
large-scale way right
um a lot of times people they talk about
curing in Turkey bags or curing in the
jar you're actually not really curing
your fermenting yes yeah you're
exchanging gas when people talk about
burping that's not actually caring
you know what makes it fermenting as
opposed to curing
there's this one I mean it's like I
don't wanna I don't want to misspeak and
have somebody jump in that knows more
than me about it but but in general what
it boils down to is there's some acts
there's some interplay
between each of the flowers being
connected to the stem
yeah that doesn't mean you can't put it
in a jar and it improves over the first
few weeks in the jar too I'm just saying
that like a lot of times people think
they remove it from all they removed it
from the stem way too fast yeah and like
if you let that that few weeks I I would
even tell people like once you put it in
that contractor just leave it alone for
a week yeah leave it alone for 10 days
and then go back to it and then trim it
and we've had we've had a bunch of
friends that have tried it right and
they all keep using it yeah and they all
feel like it improved their personal
smoke yeah yeah
right we'll dig it that's why I wanted
you to tell it it's important so so yeah
there's an aspect and there's there's
there's parts of it where you know like
like I said I glossed over certain
things because it's kind of long and
involved and you could ask a bunch of
detailed questions and stuff that went
on and I wasn't trying to like drown
people and uh but anybody can reach out
about it because I want people to have
better weed and there it is true low and
slow but I definitely think there's
drying and there's curing and then
there's jarring and a lot of people just
dry and jar
yeah and they miss that middle part
yep that doesn't mean your weed's not
good I'm not dissing your weed I'm just
saying that like I've found you know for
a lot of the things that I grow that I
get better flavor profiles when you give
that plant a week or 10 days or two
weeks to interplay between the stem and
the flower and back and forth and all
that and cure in a big pile into itself
yeah you know because back in the day
when things moved really fast
um a lot of times people would I just
smoke some in New York people would uh
they would just dry weed as fast as they
could get it to Market yep and it would
have a little bit of that chlorophyll
Tang I had somebody try to tell me it
was like they they only smoke it like
that because after two weeks the live
terpenes fade
oh okay yeah and I was like yeah I've
smoked plenty of weed that was dried
fast for commercial purposes I get it
you know like yeah yeah
you know and so yeah people can be you
know they're yeah most people skip
curing they go from right from drying
you know right from drying to jarring
right from jarring right from drying to
packaging you know yeah and uh and this
Tech it's like it's really easy it's all
that stuff is really available it's
nothing special it doesn't take up a ton
of space in your house you can condense
you can reuse the the paper bags
multiple times if you treat them right
you know you can shove a ton of them
into one or two contractors it's light
as a feather
you know it's modular it's easy it can
fit in a closet it can fit in a garage
it can they can stack on top of each
other because and and there's one thing
like and you pointed out sometimes you
might need to fluff it but it's okay
because not so it's a professional
fluffer
yeah indeed I've been trying to get that
joke in for like five minutes sometimes
you need to go sometimes you need to
make you know from bottom to top you
need to really just change up what's
going on
um and you know that's the thing is it's
like when you do it perfect you don't
have to do any of that I just wanted to
go through like because it is weird and
we have close friends of ours that when
we first when I first showed them how to
do it they thought they were putting it
away too wet yeah and a lot of times
they don't realize that it stores really
well like that
um but then sometimes it does get too
wet like it gets a little mushy or it's
scary wet or whatever and you need to
let it breathe and so there's a variety
of ways you can let it breathe and
um you know this is like I just don't I
don't like plastic bins for a lot they
don't breathe at all and so what happens
what happens in anaerobic environments
yeah yeah it just creates stale air and
and moisture hanging and different kinds
of different kinds of processes happen
in low oxygen versus higher oxygen
environments yeah yeah
you know and so there's an act there's
an aspect of that where it's like so
even if you screw up a few times there's
like various ways you can get out of
panic mode yeah sometimes all I had to
do was just open the top of my
contractor and leave it in the living
room for you know a night or half a day
and all of a sudden the excess moisture
had breathed and escaped you know those
paper bags are dry so like they will
absorb a little bit of excess moisture
without becoming damp you know so that
helps too uh and uh you know there's
there's just it just keeps the weight
because that's what you don't want is
you don't want
pressure and low oxygen and you know you
want things to be able to breathe you
want things to be able to like slowly
take that last bit of moisture out from
the center of the buds and from the
center of the stems and bring it out
into the flower yeah and I think you
know your your weed Burns better
you know yeah your weed Burns better it
tastes better I've grown a lot of
strains over a long period of time and I
have a lot of repeats and so you know
you you grow it one way for a while and
you're like oh I killed it and you grow
this other way and you you don't get the
trim you don't get the dry right and
then you're like oh I [ __ ] it up yeah
now it's not as good now my weed that's
like three months old still Burns a
little nicer than this weed that I just
got fresh yeah and so you you know and
then your friends do that too and then
you have feedback loops and then you
know and then you you go through and so
there's a lot of things people can get
all Tech and you can go to like moisture
in the buds and higher meters I'm giving
you like Hill Tech I'm giving you like
observational Tech that's basically by
experience and by feel and then you have
some Basic Ground rules on when not to
panic about it yeah right
um and you know we have a buddy too that
like is people were talking about
elevation earlier as well I mean we have
a we have a good friend of ours that
um we worked through it
um and he lives in very high elevation
um and his weed dried way too fast yeah
yeah way way too fast and we were able
to really slow it down and get cures and
he's ecstatic good
yeah I remember so I'm not saying it's
like this is like the be-all end-all I'm
just saying that it's worked for me and
my friends for a long period of time
it's an excellent way to cure we we I
did bring a bunch of weed to the can
Illuminati parties dried because the
canned Illuminati parties were in
December yeah most of that weed came
down in October or November so it was
one to two months old yeah by the time
that you guys got a hold of it yeah and
all the weed that I brought whether it
was trimmed or untrimmed all went
through that whole process
yeah and I really do think it brings out
quality it's definitely a way to like
not screw it up at the end
wait yeah like as far as far as our
group goes like it seems like everybody
kind of contributes one more some more
than one but everybody kind of brings
one major thing to the table and when I
think of not so his drying Tech is the
one thing I think he's brought to the
table that's changed it for our group as
a whole so that's why I wanted uh to
bring it up because this is a lot of
skilled uh people in our group and and
if if it's if it's changing their minds
it might be something that other people
are into too yeah and there's and you
know there's there's there's patterns to
it or whatever and there's ways you can
adapt it here and there and so there's I
don't know I just I've just found it to
be really flexible and I haven't found
anything that gives me better quality
weed it's not done at all on the
commercial market and I think the
commercial Market suffers for it
you know uh the the whole curing aspect
and the whole treating it nice for a bit
um that seems to be you know shoved away
to efficiency
yeah and then if you the problem is if
you mess it up you can always rehydrate
weed but it's never the same as if you
dried it low and slow and got it sticky
if you can get it a certain stickiness
and a certain ratio
um it can stay good like that for a
really long time and if you get it
overly dry which a lot of people used to
do and then they'd re-moisten for sale
it'll be all right for a week or two but
not that long no and then it'll go back
to being a a lot a lot blander yeah you
know so if you do it the right way you
can get like a a weird sponginess
that has enough give to have some
moisture in it and but enough you know
but it but it's it's really well cured
yeah and and not so much that it just
goes poof in your hand yeah if you hear
crunching that's not that great you
don't want to hear a crunch you want to
go you know I mean the the you know
it'll probably still get you high
but a lot of delicate a lot of delicate
terpenes orange peels in the sack all
that [ __ ] that's all failure
yeah I mean I'm not saying it doesn't
work don't get me wrong but I'm saying
like your weed is never as good if you
have to rehydrate it yeah if you have to
rehydrate it you didn't store it the
right way
yeah you know
um you know yeah people saying this
didn't it didn't work at scale on his 30
lighter that's ridiculous I mean like
you know uh I mean I did it with like
when we when Mendo first went legal and
we were allowed 10 000 square feet yeah
which is far larger than a 30 lighter
you know
um yeah small by today's standards right
now but still
um you know it's it's a chunk of pounds
yeah so it works you know
um and then on top of this too it's
really easy to do this at a small scale
for everybody that's just trying to
smoke better wheat
yeah totally you know if you might only
have you might only have one or two or
three contractors or something
you know if you're just growing for your
personal smoke and it's for you or
whatever like then it's really easy to
like baby it and then you'll really see
yeah for sure you know and there might
be a time too when people want to
experiment with it or whatever where
like they get to a point where
um you know you might end up like if
especially if it's just for you you
might end up like trimming some and then
leave half the bag cured and super nice
in a cool spot that's dry
yeah and go check on your weed a month
later and see if you like the wheat in
your jar better or see if you like the
the flour you just broke off the branch
and hold the joint with you might be
surprised
yeah I know I know Bodhi has this
perfect room
um or did at his house that was like a
humidor and because where he lived is
just that perfect oh yeah I know he said
he's there's some weed in there from
like
a long time years yeah and and it's all
hanging and it's on the branch and you
know like I've noticed even with seeds
like if they're stored in their Bud they
last longer it's like a natural
protection for it so you know I think
there's a lot of good aspects even if
you're just making seeds and drying
seeds there's a lot of good aspects to
keeping it under pressure
bury our seed
in um in uh 55 gallon drums and it would
all be on the cola yeah you wouldn't
deseed it you would store it you know on
a dry Cola yeah it makes it great it
makes great storage makes great storage
they're not they're not rubbing up
against each other I mean a lot of
people don't know this right but uh you
know Caleb and I were just talking about
it we're like that tiger stripe rubs off
oh yeah it's it's a thin layer it's not
an it's it's more like a super thin
tight fitting skin shell than it is like
an embossed feature of a hard shell so
if you people that start people that
like hand Harvest their seeds and all
that and they treat them really lightly
they could end up getting all these dark
tiger stripes you start putting them
through like a blower and sifting them
really nice and doing all this extra
work to make sure people get perfect
seeds and all of a sudden you could end
up with some pale seeds that were dark
before yeah because they lost their
tiger stripe because it just frictioned
off it's a thin almost transparent skin
with dark stripes so yeah I watched it
come off seeds constantly yeah and a lot
of us use blowers that make a lot of
seed so yeah it was interesting is I was
actually just talking the last few weeks
to uh to a Jamaican who was telling me
about how they store seeds and they
can't bury them they store them in in
big 55 gallon drums in Jamaica and they
store them basically either on bud or in
the shake
because it acts like a natural
insulation and protects it from the Heat
and it works wait they'd rather have a
big drum full of shake and Seed than a
big or you know Buds and Seed then a big
thing just full of seed
because it'll die someone asked is it a
more Indica trait tiger stripes I've
noticed it a lot in afghanis and and
things the bigger seeds that I see
typically from afghanis but it's not a a
general trait you can apply like that
one of the but never mind go on no as
you can say a lot of the land race like
Africans and and Malawi's they tend to
be smaller black seeds yeah it also
depends on what the mother was
right so um you know you uh if you're
you know if your seeds are forming in
some kind of Equatorial sativa they're
going to tend to be smaller because the
flower clusters and the calyxes they're
forming in are also small
yeah and it depends on when it's
pollinated and where on the plant it's
pollinated how big the seed there's so
many things that go into factors but
like the tiger striping you don't see it
a ton in traditional land race uh narrow
leaf plants and there was an aspect
where there was for a long time there
was a misnomer among the community where
you know if it wasn't tiger striped
enough that means you didn't let it go
to full maturity and you were trying to
sell young or immature seeds or you were
trying to cheat a bit or whatever
um and so there's a thing with seeds
where people are very visual
yeah and you know we have you know we
have friends or whatever that like won't
sell the pale ones even though they get
crazy germ rates on them yeah I I've
kept a lot of lines off the market that
were just light or lost their stripes in
the blower they just kept them off the
market because I knew it'd be more of a
pain in the ass to explain all that and
teach every single person than to do
that
oh my God color-coded seeds uh if you go
to if you go to greenhouse's site on
their accomplishments the color-coded
seeds is one of the top
I don't go to greenhouse's site although
I will say I did before I before I
dissed them too hard that when I was
traveling in the 90s to Holland a bunch
um they had a great coffee shop in the
90s yeah
I mean I I started talking [ __ ] about
greenhouse and all of a sudden I was
banned from the internet yeah that was
crazy so let's finish it up we're right
there at the two hours I saw you I kept
trying to join but it kept telling me to
[ __ ] off so yeah it didn't I don't know
what the deal is but yeah I mean uh
before I uh maybe it'll cut me off again
I uh I did enjoy my time going to
Greenhouse uh I did like it when Shanti
and Neville sold seeds and weed there
um I you know I don't really appreciate
what happened after or whatever but
um we covered a bunch of stuff we just
tried to give an idea of like what your
thoughts could be on like a multi-stage
breeding project we tried to go over
what it would look like
um breeding Tech random [ __ ] so I
appreciate everybody that's staying with
us yeah sorry I got kicked
it's all good yeah um we're just gonna
get patreon go Google that come join us
uh write teacher.com for all your
feminized reversal spray if you want to
make Femme seeds like we talked about
tonight all the instructions are up
there and it's 40 off right now using
Code invisible 40. uh we have some cool
stuff coming up soon so be sure to check
it out we'll have these up on all of the
podcast platforms very shortly probably
in the next two hours uh it'll be up on
YouTube as well as SoundCloud iTunes all
that [ __ ] so yeah we hope you enjoyed it
and you can always reach out to me on
either Discord or on IG for follow-up
questions or anything like that and uh
always send us your ideas and your
thoughts about what you want to hear and
what you want to talk about
so you know thank you once again for
your Friday night as always yep thank
you everyone peace good night want more
breeder Syndicate be sure to check out
our patreon by going to Google and
searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray from making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]