[Music]
[Applause]
you
Brin did not like my song choice today I
just want to make that clear
that was all me there we go me invite
you to Kevin it should since then just
hit yes lay down we all right this will
work on my phone I guess it's probably
gonna be easier than my cell phone you
hear me yeah I can hear you it's a
little quiet alright let me try some
music you try some earbuds
you
how's that better yeah yeah it's good
it's good just talk loud as loud as you
can I think it's just yeah okay yeah
alright how's that perfect thank you for
coming on no worries it's about time
right now you know with everything going
on with philos the fallout from all that
I know people have a lot of questions
for four other companies in the industry
they're looking they're looking for
someone that they can trust
obviously that's that's Benny right okay
so I would say that in general don't
trust me
because Trust trust is what has gotten
us where we are and I think you should
look at people's actions yeah we we saw
this coming many years ago and it
happens in every like genomics industry
I've been in people startup company they
offer a very low-cost test to entice
people to submit they harvest that data
it turns into surveillance capitalism
and then they run off and make a
database all of that is is fine I think
if you're forward with that and if yes
that stated intent and I don't think
anyone on this thread is arguing that no
one has a right to breed everyone has a
right to grow this plant absolutely they
have a right to go and breed I think it
is the concern on the table is did you
have you know in notorious intent did
you deceive people in the process of
doing this and I think that's probably
where most the upper is so how you know
how would we not deceive people well
don't trust us look at our actions but
I'd say since 2016 when we saw this
coming we realized all right we got to
build an antidote and the best antidotes
to this are to enable point of grow
testing so people don't have to hand
over their DNA so we've been building
those tools for the last few years if
folks aren't familiar with them they're
there on our website there's a variety
of people that actually run them as a
service we don't run serve that service
here and because we just don't we're not
comfortable shipping stuff across state
lines sure the farm bill has made
changes a little bit we're still trying
to get our head around that but we do
accept
samples that can go in the mail if
they're if they're non-viable that's the
ruling from hemp industry associations
versus the DEA you can't have viable
stuff so you have to isopropanol treat
them
I think finalist is doing the same thing
and I don't know whether their stuff is
viable or not the I don't think that's
the real issue at hand it's that they
have your genomic DNA and they can do a
lot with that the leaf smears our
lawyers wouldn't let us put those in the
mail because they claim people could
tissue culture them and I've never I've
done cell culture I've not done cannabis
tissue culture so I don't know if that's
true or not we just weren't allowed to
do it so I don't I think that's a very
thin chance unless people have given
them tissue and seeds that they're
actually doing that I think they're real
I think it's a bit of a red herring when
they say we can resurrect or Jurassic
Park your your your strains in DNA
that's partially true what they can do
is they can take her genomic DNA amplify
certain regions of it and transform it
into other plants and that's not part
yeah in fact we saw that happen with Jay
Keasling he actually amplified out all
the cannabinoid pathway and put it into
yeast and he did this pretty quickly
when you consider how long a lot of the
other companies have been trying to get
THC expressing and he's accusing lab
came up I took everyone by storm and did
this very quickly John page did this -
he got cannabic Romijn into yeast and
and show them the most recent laughy
paper so the cannabinoid genes are very
small they're very easy to clone and
they're very portable so it's possible
they can taking scan through all the
genomic DNA that they've got and say
alright these strains make THC V these
ones make that we should call in a
couple of these James into other plants
and see what happens so the genomic DNA
I think is the real crocks they have
that and to the extent that they're
turning and using that against the
manner in which they sold people will
dismiss it in you know that goes against
that doesn't help that they had that
really broad data release policy because
that probably gives them an out to do
that oh yeah but it's certainly it's
certainly challenge Abul I think because
it was done under false pretense there's
even some post we've seen where they've
claimed that they they use that when
people press them on what are your
methods they say oh we use the same
methods in the human genome project
well that's lately
false and I can attest to that in a
court of law that those aren't the
methods they used and you can tell that
by what they submitted into NCBI the
sequencers they use didn't even exist
back in 1999 so um that that's a clear
stretch and so there's false advertising
going on and I think that's where where
a lot of the attention should I think
she'd be placed the other thing we did
outside of trying to decentralize the
testing so people could do it at the
grow the sequencers aren't quite point
of grow yet they they maybe in like two
or three years with these nanopores but
they're still a little noisy and hard to
use so if people are still submitting
samples in we think you shouldn't trust
us you should assume one day we're gonna
get either pushed out of business you
know step on to the wrong law federal
law and get in trouble or that we're or
months not let's say the worst case
scenario but it's not so it comes and
buys us yeah what are we gonna do then
so what we've tried to do is make sure
the record of the time stamps of your
material are not in our control and not
in anyone's control whoever owns our
business and the way we do that is we
take your sequence and create a hash of
it it's not the whole sequence it's just
a hash this is a so it's known as a
uni-directional hash function so your
sequence file turns into gibberish but
it turns it always turns into that
gibberish that fingerprint when you run
a program called sha-256 it makes a
cryptographic hash out of your data
whenever you present that algorithm with
your DNA file it will make that same
hash you can't go from the hash back to
the sequence though that's impossible so
we put that hash in a blockchain
transaction so that it's globally
distributed on a public ledger with a
timestamp on it that no one in the world
can change so if we disappear and you
still have your DNA file you can prove
that my sample existed at this
particular time and we put that in place
from day one on canopy dia back in
probably 2014 or so long long before we
saw this risk happening we just knew
that was that was the right thing to do
so those are two things that we're
trying to do is we're we're actively
building business components that enable
point of grow testing as opposed to
trying to horde those assays for ourself
to run them for breeding and and those
actions I think speak for themselves you
can see I mean Seth Crawford has
Viji line out there now because he used
some portable tools he used orange
photonics so look for CVG and are in our
UPC RSA so to the extent that we were
ever going to harvest information out of
the database our intent is to turn that
into a test the growers can buy and use
themselves not that we would keep that
private and use it as some advantage to
breed
we've never read before we're not it's
not our comfort zone we've always built
if you look at our history we've always
built genetic assay tools that's our
sweet spot that's where we want to stay
and we actually think that's a very
attractive market that if we can build
tools that all the breeders can use
there's plenty of upside to go around oh
sure yeah yeah so I I mean I hope that's
compelling I can tell you in the test
the fact that every assay we've built to
date we have all privately funded but
that doesn't mean we wouldn't find
something I can't predict the future
maybe we find some marker in the data
that's in canopy dia and that turns into
a test people can buy but it won't turn
into a proprietary advantage for us to
go and compete with customers that's not
our model in fact yeah I think that's a
very dangerous model when you when you
look at businesses whenever you polarize
your investors against your customers
your end
net result is a lawsuit yeah and so it's
not a healthy practice to do you've got
to find synergy between your investors
and your customers to make this work and
if you can't do that you're I think
you're in for a world of hurt yeah yeah
I think I think the main issue with
philo States you know some people don't
quite understand what's going on and
they just here they they assume that
they're stealing genetics and I don't
know if they think they're going into
people's grows like you know pocketing
[ __ ] that's not what's right yeah I've
I've not heard any of that and and I
can't support any speculation I'm
certain our lawyers have told us like
you can only stick to facts or you'll
get libelous claims and yeah I can only
talk about the the facts that a few
people have provided we didn't even
chime into this until it was three days
late because we felt it wasn't our place
to and then once we saw there's enough
evidence that others presented we can
confirm it but it wasn't our place to
snowball this yeah
by first you know going to breeders like
me and saying we're never ever gonna
breed we're never we do not have a
tissue culture lab we will never
participate in this and then they went
and did that and then came back and
called me a liar which which at that
point I was like wait a minute now
now you're yeah yeah yeah that's that's
you know yeah replications everything so
does anyone have that in writing that's
that's the thing they delivered it all
all verbally over the phone stuff like
that I don't know anybody that has it in
writing and that was what was dangerous
yeah well it's hard to know what's real
now we've seen a lot of double-talk so
it's very hard to look through what
they've said and what they've presented
to know what is true and what's not true
I do know some things that they're
putting on paper aren't real and that's
a different concern but the information
they're putting forward to investors is
is not a hundred percent true I mean
they've gone out the videos at least
suggested that they have some exclusive
right to Illumina tools and I know
Illumina really well I mean they tried
to purchase one of our companies in 2008
and I know the CEO Jay Flatley really
well he's since retired but those people
are all in the same circle that I've
been in since 1996 and I rang them up
and said hey what is this is the first
exclusive license I've ever seen you do
and that it's so it's a running joke in
the genomics field that I got an
exclusive from Illumina because you
can't these guys have been here monopoly
in the space they never give out
exclusives so I rang them up like to the
did you guys give one out in cannabis
I'm curious no send us all the
informations going straight to legal
we're gonna put an end to that so if
he's out there presenting stuff to
investors if he has an exclusive he
needs to clarify that because he it's
probably true he has his own chip like a
fifty thousand case separate that they
designed it's their snips but there's
like 40 million to choose from in the
genome and you can easily make a
different one change one snip and it's a
new chip and Illumina doesn't police
that and they can't their position is
will make anybody a chip and they've
offered to make us one as well we're
looking at it but it's the economy's of
it don't look as good as sequencing to
us right now so we're sticking with
sequencing approach but you know that's
something that I think is a little bit
maybe even have the time to fully
explore that or explain
with you know on the stage and investors
were running people being a little too
probe him about the details not
exclusive but that's that's not
completely true and then there's others
on there that are listed as
collaborators of theirs and various of
their scientific presentations that
we've that we know very well and we've
run them up saying is this your are you
really in bed with these guys and the
answer has been no please send it to us
and we're gonna send it's illegal and
straighten this out we don't want to be
misrepresented in the cannabis industry
so there's there's things on paper that
aren't real and what they're saying I
can't discern because they seem to be
giving a completely different story to
customers and they are to investors and
that leaves us somewhat ok what's true
what isn't true it becomes a respective
some questions I know so first question
from strain Lee says Kevin what prevents
mg medicinal genomics from selling the
data you would have acquired through Tet
through the tests from your customers it
would be very complicated to demonstrate
if you did that's probably true we
haven't sold any database licenses today
we have had various synthetic biology
companies come and ask us if there's
anything valuable in the data and
unfortunately our answer has been we put
it most public so it's the Jamaican
lines you know we put public in 60 days
and then a lot of the canopy dia stuff
you'll see we put public immediately in
blotching hashes so it's hard to sell
something when a lot of its online yeah
what you're seeing with FiOS is very
different though they they claimed they
were going to be putting this stuff
public to give you guys prior art
protections but they were actually
hoarding it for two years at a time so
they did have the capacity to go and
sell it to other people because it
hadn't been necessarily revealed so we
we've not entered into those
arrangements I can't say that that would
never happen in the future
but what we do have are two different
layers of data release policies right
now and we're probably going to add a
third after this whole mess just to add
a category where people can put data
into our database and it can never be
used for other analyses right now
there's a public option or your data
goes public and the whole world can
is it I'd point you actually to there's
been seven papers published off of
canopy dia data that we're not authors
on that people just scrape the data and
reanalyzed it and published a paper on
it so the premise that a few these I
think there's a few out them off the
list and afterwards I can't recall them
off name offhand but people are grabbing
that data and publishing work on it
there's probably people grabbing into
not publishing work on it and keeping it
to yourselves there's a class of
customers that want to keep it all
private the only challenge we have in in
the privacy events is that we do need to
compare it to everybody else's data in
order to deliver the product so if they
want to know if the sample is excuse me
if the sample is related to anything
else in the database well it's hard to
have that data not compare it to
everything else
yeah and still and still deliver the
relationships right we're now realizing
we need one more tier we're fine you can
do that you can compare it to everything
else in tell us the relationships but we
don't want you to then go and sell it to
somebody else we want that to remain
private so we need another another tier
after what we've seen here I can't say
that probably this is a rough guess but
probably 70% of the data is already
public and only probably 30% of the
people opt to keep it private and they
usually convert it to public once they
once they talk to more people and get
more legal opinions on what they should
do so it's it's a rare case where people
are keeping everything entirely private
I think one of the biggest flaws I saw
from the beginning of Philo's was that
they they were crowdsourcing data for
their legacy strains what they called
their legacy strains meaning like let's
say for example chem 91 the original
chem 91 strain maybe the more people
that submit it the more likely it is to
be the original strain when in fact in
cannabis that's not how it works
yeah right have the original well we've
been reluctant to police the oral
history so what we have all we do is
present your relationships and you do
see clusters of like blue dreams they're
all next to each other and other ones
that aren't and and yeah I'll just make
their their assumptions is what they are
we have been reluctant to enable people
to edit the names that they send in and
that's a big debate in the company
whether we should and if we do do that
we record that history because what what
can happen in a scenario like this is if
you allow people to edit the name after
they see where it lines up to everything
in the galaxy you tend to get a bias
toward the samples that seeded the
galaxy or the CVS canopy dia if people
start to see that oh look I'm I thought
it was og but I'm not in the og cluster
I must have mixed something up it splits
blue dream let me rename that one in the
galaxy so I don't look like an oddball
in the galaxy that creates I think a
real mess particularly if if the data
that is that is deriving these
relationships is questionable yeah this
becomes a chaos generator in the
nomenclature system of cannabis yeah and
I do think it's questionable we've
downloaded their data and when we try to
run their data through tools it throws a
lot of it out in fact throws all of it
out now you can force it through because
we know why it's ROS it out so it's gets
in the weeds a little bit but in the
best tools for doing sequencing QC come
out of the Broad Institute in Cambridge
Brown Institute MIT runs this program
it's open source it's called gatk genome
analysis toolkit and you take sequencing
data and you run it through here and it
screens it from the crap that creates
bad calls and one thing it does not like
to see our single PCR implements because
a single PCR amplification event could
get the maternal allele or the paternal
allele and miss one of the other and so
it wants to see at least two different
molecules calling a variance that way it
knows you surveyed both alleles turtle
in the paternal line you only have one
you don't know whether you surveyed both
so it has a program in there called the
card that rips anything out that has
only a single amplicon and the entire
Philo's assay design is they've got a
single amplicon covering allele now the
broad wrote this because they sequence
human genomes lots of human genomes
other things but humans have been there
mainly their focus and human genomes
this problem is tenfold less problematic
we have a variant human human of one
every thousand letters and cannabis is
one hundred ninety four letters so when
there's that many variants in the genome
and you're trying to design PCR primers
to amplify one of the variants what
often happened
as you put these primers on top of other
variants you don't know about and
therefore you artificially amplify what
your reference was what you thought you
were going to sequence from let's say
they probably designed it off a
catatonic cuz they have a nice catatonic
reference yeah so in their design they
may have designed these primers so that
they fall in these variants they amplify
only the modern line and up the father
line and they get it they get a skewed
tree now you present the community with
these skewed trees without any
peer-review on the methods you start
calling it certifications and you enable
people to edit the actual names of the
strains and you have a [ __ ] show in your
hands
oh yeah and so I don't believe anything
that comes out of that system because
the methods behind it have never made it
through peer review and I don't think
they will because there's many papers
that have been published warning against
doing this exact thing that you really
cannot do single amplicon variance and
you really shouldn't do it in
polymorphic genomes because you're gonna
get all types of reference bias when you
do this I so I think that's the reason
why their methods aren't peer reviewed
all the other parties who have arguably
been working off of less funding than
they have have gotten papers out you see
Nolan Cain published lon we submitted
some data to that paper steep hill put
data in there mary jean put data in
there you've seen Phillipe Henry put
some things out you've seen and andia
publishes all the time on their methods
I mean almost every other genetic
provider out there has their methods
published Soilers another one and so you
can review whether or not there's any
artifacts going on in the data so this
leads me to what I'm most concerned
about is that why did they hold the data
back and for so long were they that
understaffed that they couldn't put the
data public I don't think so
it takes about it it is hard to put data
in ncbi can take a whole day to have a
bioinformatics person get burnt up
putting that data into ncbi but it
doesn't take two years and what else
what are the data they have I mean they
are talking about a 50k zip array from
Illumina quite publicly well they're
asked they only sequence a couple
thousand sniffs one to two thousand so
how did they design the 50k snip array
if they were only surveying two thousand
snips and everyone's samples they sent
in where did they design the other 48
thousand from well they probably had the
sequence more territory
every one sample to intelligently design
that ship or the chip is unintelligently
designed and it's perhaps not a very
good breeding tool one of those two
things is true so it it does lead you to
question how much have they been putting
public and how much have they been
keeping private and what type of Vantage
doesn't necessarily give them a breeding
program those are you know open
questions I don't think one has the
answer to actually really good questions
to ask okay this is a great a great
Kevin will this data hurt or help
cannabis in the long term in your
opinion the whole not necessarily by
Llosa's what they're doing but overall
the breeding using these tools using
these tools in general I think the tools
will help I do think we need a chapter
out of the crypto space here of
decentralizing putting all of the data
in one honeypot database where let's be
frank the security policy there was not
very good I mean I don't know people
have seen the threads but it Bert it was
burping out admin password throughout
the years so we know we got it and we're
their competitor were the last people
that should get their admin password but
it ended up on our green one day oh that
means you have a collection of
everybody's data where the customers
have don't get to see the data for two
years but the people who got that admin
password probably did so that's the
worst possible scenario for getting a
prior art as you held it from the people
who paid you for it
and yet you were sloppy with the keys
and let other people get in that is not
a prior art system yes yes yeah yeah
that I didn't quite recognize that
password until I went back and looked at
that after all this went down I'm like
wait a minute let me look at that email
oh my god so yeah if those who know the
password that bit burped out I don't
know if it's a real password or not and
this was many years ago and I never put
this stuff public because it's it's it's
bad policy to put someone else passwords
public but it was been 2 years and I
gave it to Mowgli privately and I'm
assuming he went and changed all those
things the next day when he realized his
competitor had it he didn't I'm sorry
that's a bad policy to be not too
yes right I tell you what it is but in
that list was the password was Otto
flower allele and I think someone else
that's right maybe some grown maids
pointed out that it the username was
forged like forgery it's like those are
bad names so when they say we weren't
looking for anything in your data I mean
yeah you made the Helen Keller would
have been a better name you know not
Otto flower yeah but again that's
speculative I don't want to get involved
in too much speculation but I don't
think I need to speculate because the
videos that were put out pretty much
show the Jekyll and Hyde of this right
there's the investor side of the story
which this date is extraordinarily
valuable we're gonna rule the world and
then there's the customer side saying
the data is all garbage don't worry
about it those two you can't square that
circle very easily and I think that
video does you know it's basically the
nail in the coffin this whole time you
know people come to me for dirt on FiOS
or whatever because I've been I've been
researching them for a long time and it
padded out with them several times but
the fact of the matter is I don't even
have to say anything from my opinion I
just show what they say and that's it
and that's where I've left it and I
think that's been damaging enough you
know yeah unfortunately I mean it would
have been nice to have everything on the
up-and-up from the beginning that would
have been ideal but it's not it's not
necessarily the case I like what you're
saying about decentralization obviously
that's that's the goal for for having a
company that's successful yeah I mean so
there's maybe two things to consider is
you know I've seen a lot of growers like
that are early on and they don't want to
buy all their own sequencers yet and
that you know they either outsource to
us or other people and some will even go
to their local universities because it's
unlikely University is gonna turn around
and breed on you right and so they'll
get the university so we're trying to
build tools that some universities could
run that way you know we're not
necessarily the data hoarding risk that
people may consider because we were
understand after this went down no one's
gonna trust anybody the sequence their
stuff I mean but we hope we can convince
you these blockchains work but have
time when we tell people about
blockchains our eyes glaze over and say
I don't get it go away so we understand
that's not gonna satisfy everybody and
so we're gonna start building tools that
may assist universities to be able to
sequence for you because frankly they're
gonna have a big learning curve if you
went to one today and said here's my DNA
they're there they're gonna stumble on
whether they can take it in or not or
whether it violates neither federal
grants once they get past that hurdle
they're gonna they're gonna be some
bling on the fact they've never sequence
genome before and it's very hard to
sequence and we have a lot of that
worked out into kits where they could
run these kits under their sequencers
and get data that's very similar to
other data that's gonna be that's been
made before and then they could compare
it excuse me the canopy dia data the
biggest challenge we've had in PT
testing in cannabis genomics is that for
the first few years of this every
service provider was running with
sequencing a different part of the
genome so it's really difficult to cross
comparing ones data because you're not
covered sequencing the same basis yeah
about two years ago we changed that and
we downloaded the file of data we
downloaded the Kane data and the soiler
data and then we built a panel that
covers at least 50 snips and all of
those things so that we could try to
triangulate you know if you sequence on
our panel you can figure out what it's
closest to and all the other data sets
but we need more of that and so we're
we're looking into ways to enable a lot
of the other universities to pick this
up that way it's it's somewhat
decentralized if you don't like the
university in your state maybe you send
it to another one and and then it
doesn't become this surveillance
capitalism approach in most other
markets sequencing is very commoditized
there isn't this this window for someone
to do this because you can't shop around
for sequencing providers and and
therefore they don't get to collect
large hordes of your data you can send
one strain to one place and one to
another and one to another and and and
this means the the aggregation of that
data doesn't fall into one person's
hands who can be co-opted to sell it to
a party you're not you're not thrilled
with that that does lead me to a couple
points people should be aware of this is
the sequencing test that the people are
running at Philo's is the most expensive
sequencing per base I think of any test
in the world you're only getting 300,000
letters out of this for about $285 to
put that in perspective and you might
get 2,000 snaps one to two thousand
snaps the 23
test you get for like 99 bucks or
surveying 1 - like 5 million snips right
so there is this is a complete ride when
it comes to sequencing costs even though
the tests that we run are sequencing 10
times more than ten times the territory
of the Philo's test for nearly the same
price so there's a very heavy price
that's being paid to give them your data
yeah and you're giving them data to
potentially be sold was what it looks
like it's yeah in the data they're
putting public I don't think it's very
valuable it's really the fact that they
have the genomic DNA they've got
presentations out that are public now
that demonstrate them cherry picking 99
samples out of the galaxy they have this
structure thing that tells you whether
it's like Barry or I can't remember all
the names so they they they categorize
things into six buckets and those
buckets are somewhat fictitious based on
what you tell the program to look for
you give it a values - how many
populations you think are there and it
spits out it's like a consultant that
tells you what time it is you you know I
think there's six populations it gives
you a pretty picture with six
populations but anyway they use that
data to cherry-pick 99 samples are gonna
do whole genome sequencing on so when
they say they're not using the galaxy to
do the breeding program I think that
project right there begins to blur that
line you're you're using the fact that
the galaxy to figure out what the
sequence - really extreme depth to start
your breeding program yeah and that to
me looks as if it is utilizing the data
for the breeding program and that's
that's that's that's been publicly
presented they also have publicly
presented that they're looking for the
BTB D allele the the CBD allele which is
already out there I mean South
Crawford's already bought it and used
our kit we have a we have a marker that
tracks that and we didn't turn that into
a breeding operation we turned that into
a kit that anyone could buy and and and
any breeder could use and he's done it
successfully I wouldn't know how to do
it successfully because I know how to
breed but he's managed to know if I can
track that which samples do not have any
CBD alleles and I'd start with type 3
plants and they're all CBD negative that
means they're probably type 4 or type 5
then one of those two and he was able to
figure that out with orange photonics
that it was in fact a type a type 4
and and move on with it so but
nevertheless they're picking samples I
don't know where they got the samples
that's the question I can't answer they
have them listed in some of these
presentations they may have got they may
have sourced them from Spencer's you
know I don't know but yeah they're
they're clearly hunting for markers for
the breeding program and it looks as if
it's being guided by their historical
data here's here's here's a good one and
I know you briefly touched on it you can
choose to answer it or not it is kind of
a personal opinion question it's
referring to what Bodie asked the other
night about chimera okay some data on
chimera cuz I know a lot of us like I
grew up I grew up like that was chimera
walks in and Clark we're the end-all
be-all when it came to breeding and
slowly over the years you learn things
and you realize they may not be who I
who I hoped they would be so I I have to
say the first three people that
contacted me after we put chem dog
public in 2011 were those three people
in that exact order and I met and I met
Robert Clark and Dave Watson you know
the nice enough to host me over there in
Amsterdam and show me around we never
came to any agreement on I think they
wanted to do something like Philo's back
then but we weren't funded and that was
early it was the laws in the United
States weren't really favorable at that
time so we got to put mgc on ice for a
little bit while we waited for the Cole
memo to get you know more clarity on it
but so I spent a lot of time with Brian
Lee and a lot of the ICRS
meetings and I've had a great time with
him in person I I think I'm an [ __ ]
on mine I think it's becomes constant
and I just pissed him off online in his
qualities but he's he is one of the
people that convinced me to back off on
FiOS in fact he got me to apologize to
them at an emerald couple couple years
ago for calling them out on this so in
2016 there's a lot of news on our
Facebook site and arguably back then it
was not as we didn't have the videos you
have now we had information from people
well I I had the history of big scenes
you know Matt companies get billed this
is what always happens so I was
naturally suspicious and then I saw that
they weren't putting any data public but
telling you
but if they were saving them from
Monsanto by putting a star on the galaxy
star on the galaxy doesn't give you any
prior art the USPTO can't do [ __ ] with
that they if you look at the patents
they issue they talk about the be TPD
allele which is a genotype and they talk
about chemo types those are the two
languages the USPTO uses to evaluate
strains right now might change it might
get broader in the future but the the
precedents that's been set with a
biotech LLC patent is that you need a
genotype in any chemo type free for us
to understand what it is you have
there's some lawyers that may have
better information on this than me
Reggie might be a good person or Dale
Han might be a good person to talk to on
this because they're more versed in that
and some of what's allowable there but
so we made a noise and we probably
weren't polite about it and a bunch of
people kind of yelled at us about it and
convinced us to kind of shut up you're
you're being a bad community member here
you don't have enough hard data on this
and you're being paranoid and then over
time we've after we apologize I should
say I apologize about this
I saw the behavior didn't change they
put out 845 samples a couple years ago
and another two years went by nothing
else showed up and I was like well I
thought we came to agreement that if
you're gonna be open about this you had
to be open and not use the cover of the
OCP to act like are open when you're not
and that that's what kind of triggered
us to get back involved when we saw all
this go down like Oh God we're kind of
complicit in this because we were
barking about it a few years ago and
then we backed off and now look what's
happened so so yeah I don't know I don't
to say I really spaced long enough to to
really weigh in on those three
individuals and and where they live
you know weigh them in cannabis face but
you know and I know Ryan's had some
fingerprints on on the biotech LLC stuff
and so he's generally been thoroughly
supportive of patents and I'm not anti
patent either I generally I generally
think they're evil but I think they
exist and because they exist if you put
your head in the sand over the rules of
that game you're gonna get screwed so
you got to learn it and you got to play
the game at least defensively and if you
have enough money you might be able to
afford the offensive tracks but a lot of
companies
many years ago we're so new in the space
they couldn't afford the offensive
tracks offensive tracks can also be 20
to 30 grand a pack you can probably get
the Provisionals like chucked in for a
couple grand but a year later or 18
months later you're gonna be held to
make a decision on whether you're gonna
go full boat on this thing and those are
gonna cost you more like 20 grand so
defensive IP seemed to be the cheap way
to start and that's what we tried to
enable with canopy do is get things on
broad chains got things public so you at
least don't get Submarine by somebody
else you can at least say my [ __ ]
existed here and it's not some [ __ ]
site that might disappear there's
actually it's we've got something on an
immutable ledger that seems to have a
financial reason to exist for a long
period of time and the site's not gonna
go down and my prior art it's not gonna
disappear I think that's the biggest
issue the USPTO has in the cannabis
space is the site's go down because
there's all the censorship on the
internet over cannabis sites and so you
can put your stuff online and find it
get wiped off my Facebook or something
else and then you no longer have your
prior art so we need these tools that
that are immutable
to you know survive all the censorship
that's going on yeah and that's a great
answer about academia I think it was
very informative yeah you know and it's
just based on your opinion and your
brief interaction this smart guy he
knows the stuff I've learned a lot from
doubt I've learned a ton from him so I
know it's not discouraging there but
everyone gets different interests and
sometimes these you know these conflicts
make us go different ways here we go if
plants aren't patentable then who has
the prior art so plants are patentable
unfortunately I'm not saying this as a
supporter of what's going on in fact if
anyone wants to watch a very good review
on IP I'd encourage people to look at
Steven Gonzales work on this he's a
patent attorney who hates IP and so he's
got a very refreshing perspective but he
also is very legit about it and that
look they exist and if you don't play by
these rules you get your you know you're
exposed so you can be as anti patent as
you want but if you put your head in the
sand you're probably gonna lose so you
have to respect the fact that the law is
there so there's a lot of fun ways you
can patent in fact the the best way I
think that may have just emerged
is the USDA just opened up its doors to
take in cannabis ease and that is that
might be the best protection I think
growers can get right now because I
don't think violence has stabilized
seeds and I just got to say they're
there they just turn into breeding in to
breed if they get cultivars in from
other people that agree to license them
to them they then need to probably cross
them and change them a little bit so
that they're unique that'll take a
couple cycles and then you got a back
cross those so that they're stable and
what the USDA does is I think they want
like three thousand see it's a lot of
seeds they did check them for whether
they are in fact stable you pop a few
and see if they're really extreme and
phenotype and if they are they don't
consider it a viable PvP so there is
plant variety Protection Act that's one
there is there are plant patents which
are their own class of patents but those
patents are for a sexually reproduced
material clones and then there are
utility patents which are the broadest
patents which are the patents that we
saw biotech LLC get and those can be
very expensive to unravel once the
patent has issued you need to do an ex
parte re-exam which can be a couple
hundred grand to try and invalidate a
patent so that's that creates a
different financial dynamic and feel now
now we've we've put some data public
that may challenge it and may not you
know I'm not a lawyer on that but the
Jamaican lion project we did we did that
one we needed the type to plant the
sequence and two we tried to find
something that predated the patent and
and build the best forensics back to
that date this particular strain one a
cannabis cup in San Francisco in 2011
and has been known to be a type two
plant
that sometimes is is is beta-carotene
dominant sometimes mercy and dominant
and then that's one area I think at the
USPTO I know Reggie's trying to help
educate them and others need to educate
them is that this concept of using
terpenes as a fingerprint for strain is
really dangerous because it's not really
a fingerprint it's an environmental
signature yeah and and that that means
you could have the same plan and put it
somewhere else and you deter people or
you can have a completely different
plant that's genetically distinct has a
different cannabinoid profile but still
gives you you can tweak it to pop mercy
in or pop beta care depending on how you
you grow it so
I don't like those as I think those are
very broad and very dangerous because
when you get something it says I have I
own all type 2 plants that don't have
mercy as dominant terpene you suddenly
own wait we wait too much property Wow
yeah and it's it's not clear to me I
know mark those great reading and great
work and I don't doubt that that guy can
breed good stuff it's it's it's more
that the the the scope of claims there's
there's a ratchet effect they always get
bigger they never get smaller so a good
lawyer is gonna take that patent and try
and broaden it even more and brought
anything more we've seen it get pushback
in Canada there's a there's a there's a
collection up there of probably LPS I
don't really know who's behind it but
there's a group of people up there
funding in opposition to the patent up
there and they managed to narrow the
claims going into Canada
so the claim on that patent is enforced
in Canada right now and it's smallish
it's it's more narrow than it is here in
the United States all right here's a
here's another question and and also
just just so people know as far as as
far as being stable you know typically
in San abyss that is a rare thing IBL
it's very hard to apply to in cannabis
its bare there are very few strains that
have less than three phenotypes if any
yeah yeah it's hard
I'm not surprised when I look at the
variation in the genome I mean this is a
it's a quite diverse plant it's it's
hard to find other species that can be
it's almost it's not quite there but
it's pretty close one snip every ninety
four basis is almost like having
chimpanzees and humans being able to
cross and still have collective
offspring it's it means that you get a
spectrum of phenotypes in anyone's plant
you have it's it's rare that the most
homozygous plants we've seen came from
Franco and those are those were land
races yeah yeah yeah and there may be
some controversy about that we didn't
source them but I think he got him out
of the Congo and there's some biopiracy
concerns there that I'm not really
attuned to but he's shipped us a few
from there and there's those things are
the most how homozygous things we've
seen maybe those will be stable would
give you you know seeds that are all
near clonal but I think until we get
April mixes worked out
gonna be we're gonna be dealing with
that but I think that's coming at some
point someone's gonna figure out how to
make double haploids in cannabis and the
whole thing's gonna go seed okay here's
one regarding defense of IP do you
believe open-source breeding is
practical affordable and common standard
for small breeders so it depends on
what's affordable I think you'll you
might hear you know tail hunt they have
a different opinion on this because you
can't file Provisionals very cheaply and
maybe that's the right thing to do and
you can decide after the term of the
Provisionals up to say screw it I'm
gonna go open with this I can't afford
to go any further but it really comes
down to whether the USPTO is gonna be
effective at their job looking through
the prior art that's and that's my
concern having been involved in the
patent system a long time and people can
call me Hippocrates up and I have a lot
of patents in my name from all the stuff
that I've done and my experience using
the patent office is one that makes me
very disgruntled about it because the
USPTO doesn't have a financial incentive
to do the preliminary search report
correctly they make just as much money
on the reexamine so they don't really
care if the issue a broad patent the
market is gonna sue over it later and
then they'll get more revenue when the
reexamine happens so the incentives
there aren't right for them to do very
thorough preliminary search reports so
you really have to kind of put it if
you're gonna go and put it open you got
to make sure it's open and obvious and
in their face and they can't miss it put
it you know publish the data in multiple
places so that it's found and that you
have a mechanism for whatever's indexing
the the internet to find it you know
that Google has to be Elysee if you're
putting this stuff up I like on the on
ipfs the you know Google doesn't crawl
that and will never find it great place
to store some data but if not it's not
gonna be found by the USPTO gotcha see
what else do we got uh can I ask you
what what's your experience with
cannabis as far as personal is this
something you've been interested in
prior to the genetic aspect yeah so I
got introduced to cannabis
seventh-grade long long time ago and
then I took a big hiatus from it when I
got my first job just it was a human
genome project is was afraid I was gonna
get tested and get chucked off their
that so so III was probably wait for it
until 2010 or so a bunch of friends of
ours were getting cancer in their mid
30s and 40s and it was everyone was like
what the hell is this and we were we
were building DNA sequences at the time
that could sequence the tumor and
sequence the patient figure out what
druggable mutation they actually had in
the tumor a problem is they they then
would turn to a set of tool boxes like
cisplatin and all this poison you'd have
this wonderful targeted approach of
nailing the tumor and achilles heel but
the selection of drugs you had all
sucked and that's when people started
forward me cannabinoid papers saying
what about these these are safe these
are non-toxic and that's when I really
don't think we started getting cold feet
about that business model someone in her
family would get sick that would benefit
from it and would rearrange us into
doing more my father's one my father has
had type he's had stage four cancer for
four years now he's been fighting and
it's a prostate cancer that went to the
bones that went everywhere the only
thing that's dealt with his pain has
been type 2 plants it very similar it's
actually what was patented and that's
one thing that kind of got me into the
Jamaican lion project is like look this
case is helping cancer patients really
close to me I'm not tolerating this
someone owns this this is something that
needs to be public and so fortunately -
funded that and they funded it in a way
where it it went public more or less two
or three days after the assembly was
done we didn't even have a chance to
really look at it we queue seed it put
it public and we've since been combing
through the data to figure out what we
can learn and I think that's the right
model is get get we need to you know
float all boats right now having this
cart alized everyone having their own
private cannabis genome that's fine but
if we really want to accelerate the
field we need good references out there
that everyone can utilize even our
competitors and I'm certain finalist has
probably used the Jamaican lion thing
further making their 50k chips I mean
the timing of that would have been
perfect for them and
fine the we've seen others published off
it already there's a someone some groups
done a cannabis proteome off of the
Jamaican line reference we put forward
so that's in bio archive right now it's
really interesting read
but yeah so my history has been on and
off but we've seen CBD helped
tremendously and and arrhythmias as well
we have a lot of afib family and this
actually affected my brother and there's
a there's actually a nice your s
presentation I gave on this his actual
case was really fascinating because we
sequence the genomes ever in the family
and figured out he has two different
calcium channel mutations one for my
mother once for my father he's got
debilitating afib and the only thing
that nails it is CBD and so an aphids
big there's like six million people in
countries afib and now I don't think it
works on a leaf he's got a very private
those variants aren't known to any any
other database but him so they're very
rare variants ones in our way or to gene
and and my sister is an electric
cardiologist and she was afraid to
basically oblate it she's like I don't I
can't map this arrhythmia I don't I
don't want to burn it you're gonna have
to do something else and so CBD came to
the rescue for him so there's been this
consistent theme in our family where
this plant keeps pulling us back you
know the craziest thing about my
father's story is uh his uh I didn't
recognize this or put the put two and
two together on this and so we were we
were flying him back into like a hospice
care scenario and uh all the nurses are
constantly asking what's his birthday
what's his birthday and I kept telling
I'm won't October first nineteen thirty
seven I Tober first nineteen thirty
seven and I'm like I know that day what
the hell's that date from you know that
that's that's the date they made
cannabis legal Wow
he was born on that day it's like I
don't know it's weird cosmic [ __ ] like
that that makes you know alright I think
I have to keep doing this absolutely I
think that I think that's awesome that
you actually have a personal connection
with it that's that's lacking that's
that's seriously lacking in any kind of
corporate world or testing or oh yeah
well this is what motivated us to do can
med you know we run that
conference every year and it's we have
CME credits there because our interest
was like we need more doctors when we
initially got in this field it was hard
to find a doctor that would certify him
and we you know we're in Massachusetts
and we're way behind and dried and lived
in New Hampshire it's even you know live
free anti is what I call it now it's one
of these states where they're there
their cannabis regs are way behind
everybody else and so he had to have two
doctors sign off and had to know them
for like three to six months or
something like that in New Hampshire for
EM you get cannabis in New Hampshire and
we're like that's crazy
you know we figured out something where
a Maine certificate would work in New
Hampshire and and his big runaround for
someone who's got stage four cancer to
be like oh you got to wait yeah exactly
you know no I'm gonna wait so yeah so
can med hopes get more doctors certified
and also we try to get everyone to
present down there and and it's all
science-based I mean we invite mark
their mark to mark lewiston's great work
even though we don't agree with his
patent we believe it does great science
and so we welcome into present what he's
doing
I'd welcome Ryan Lee too if he has work
to present it's all about if you present
good work we try to keep the politics
and the business conflicts out of it
we're running out of time
but that went really fast and honestly I
think you came like and a really odd
time in the business where you know all
this just happened and snow evolved and
it took some big nuts to come and just
you know take questions firing the math
union well I get it I want to thank
everyone online that's chipped in on
this because it is hard these folks do a
lot of money and they could get
litigious over over you know calling
this stuff out but you know it's it's
stronger wouldn't everyone can share
data and see what's what the truth
really is it's it's really hard if
you're just one voice and and you know
you don't you don't want to bank your
entire reputation on it unless you see
other people saying you know they can
corroborate the data and it looks like
other people did that they really really
did their homework on this and integrate
what was going on to a much higher
degree that we did so that's very
helpful
well I appreciate you okay yeah that's
fine so it's got a permanent home so
people can see this but yeah thank you
so much and and if you have time in the
future I'd love to have you
I know like this is a lot of data to
throw at people so I know people gonna
be watching this room watching this and
have more questions later
so yeah yeah we get the discussion going
I'm still really intrigued on where this
goes whether it goes open or closed and
and what what's this is all gonna turn
into because I don't think we have clear
answers but we're a tool provider I
don't think we necessarily need them we
just need to be transparent and make
sure people understand what we do with
people's data yeah I think that's the
most important thing is transparency
that's all people ask really yeah be
straightforward and honest and it's not
that hard
yeah no it's amazing actually it's much
harder to actually be a liar because you
it's too hard you trip up on yourself
yeah and yeah and truth truth makes it
really easy you don't have to remember
anything cheers thank you thank you all
right guys I'm sorry if I didn't get to
everyone's questions I'm gonna have them
back on if you'll come back on there was
a lot of data there there's a lot of
heavy science a lot of stuff I I'm even
trained to process right now you know I
mean it was hard science so I'm gonna
have to go research a bunch of this
stuff but it does take a lot of nuts to
come on here and be face-to-face with
someone like me that's gonna not pulling
punches per se so I appreciate him doing
that you know you go go research go
research everything that he said go look
it up if you find something incorrect
let me know well we'll bring it to him
and I think the fact that he's made
himself so available that's a big step
it's hard to trust people then are
cannabis outsiders and I think it looks
like at least it appears that his heart
was in the right place so that's that's
important anyway I think I think someone
recorded this I hope someone recorded
this if you did I think flap nil is
gonna record this send me the link
when you get it up and I'll put it up on
the YouTube as well on the youtubes and
yep that's it Cheers
you