what's up everyone
sorry i'm still getting uh set up here
waiting for everyone to show up to
we will be
joined shortly by not so and to me
genomics
and we will be doing
our
um talk on hplv
so i'm pretty stoked
we made it here
to this moment
i've been sick all week so apologize i'm
a little [ __ ] slow today i've tried
my best i really am and i didn't want to
miss out on this because it's important
to me that everybody gets this
info
so yeah
my fans allowed
i think friends in here maybe bryn can
help with that
let's see
i'll grab it
you can okay
okay
got natso coming in
maybe if this works like it should there
we go
i'm here what's up now i just have to
wait for uh casa from toomey
there she goes to me you know goes let
me look her up now
you'd like to join
to me
there we go now i can invite
and she can jump in
i have a whole bunch of notes
do you i do
really i'm
i am semi prepared
hi casa nice to see you yeah good to see
you can you can you guys hear me all
right absolutely
i'm matthew this is not so dog and we
are the reader syndicate
nice to meet you guys nice to meet you
thanks for inviting me on tonight this
is awesome
no i think i think the whole community
needs to know more about what's going on
which the with the hplv how it's being
transmitted through clones how rampant
it is or isn't and how scared they
should or shouldn't be all of the above
so
i don't know in a in a conversation like
this do you want to start with
where would you want to start a patient
zero or do you start with what we're
dealing
with um well maybe the best place to
start is to just kind of explain what a
vibroid is what that's a great place
thyroid is that was one of my questions
i thought would be a good place to begin
yes perfectly yeah so um so what is a
viroid um viroids are
one of the simplest forms of life that
exists on the planet if we can even call
it life
um as opposed to other organisms like
bacteria
or fungus or even viruses they don't
have anything on the outside to protect
their genetic material so most organisms
have like a fat layer or a protein layer
viroids are simply a free-floating tiny
piece of genetic information and that's
all that they are
so when i say tiny
the human genome has about 3 billion
letters or
base pairs um
viroids have 250.
so we're talking about a really really
small
life form and a lot of people actually
refer to them as
fossils that are left over from
basically the beginning of life when the
theory is that it was just rna
and so
they're kind of a remnant of that
primordial earth time when all life was
replicating rna um and these tiny little
things are really infectious in plants
yeah
yeah are they are they then considered
are they parasites
because they
can't i mean they can't exist without
contacting some other more complex form
of life right and infecting it
exactly there are they are 100 dependent
on the plant metabolism to
replicate it to help it you know
transport all around the plant to do
everything that it does
um so they're the tiniest molecular
parasite uh that we know of yep
and what we're working with with this
current uh hops latent
virus or viroid i should say because
there is a difference right there a
major difference
yes yeah so so just to clarify and
because there is actually a hot platen
virus also
just to make things confusing
but viruses have an some type of outside
protection for their dna um and it's
often like a protein coat that goes
outside viroids are just the naked
genetic information so they are two
distinct things
and viruses are more complex
than
right they have more of those they're
they're viroids are even smaller than
viruses correct yes exactly so um
viruses not only do they have that
outside coat but they actually encode
information that forces the cell to make
special little molecular machines called
enzymes that will that will help the
virus to replicate viroids do not encode
even for a special machine so they are
completely dependent on hijacking the
machines in the plant and forcing them
to replicate the viroid instead of doing
what they're supposed to be doing
so very simple
i mean maybe another part of the
beginning and like you you could talk
about the beginning for you but i
thought maybe it would be interesting to
talk about the beginning for us
okay
so
there was there was an aspect like you
know because i'm old or whatever like in
the 90s
um
none of the stuff that we're probably
going to talk about later
as far as like you know preventing
transmission was used people used the
same razor blades there wasn't very much
disease there wasn't very much worry
going on
a lot of these things were kind of
unheard of and because it was a
clandestine thing and very small circles
even if a circle got infected with
something it didn't spread that much
so
during like the ig period
we had some good friends of ours that's
that you know they would you know clone
trading happens and all that right and
all of a sudden people started
experiencing something that we call
dudding
yes
right duds all of a sudden the plant
went from being healthy and happy to
unhappy
and for a long time we didn't know if it
was one thing
we didn't know if it was a multitude of
things
we just observationally could see that
some plants resin production would go
way down their health would go way down
we had some friends before they even
knew it almost reminded me a little bit
of like
um like when the early part of the aids
epidemic but in plants where people
didn't know how it was transmitted
people didn't know it existed
people didn't know how to take
precautions for it and then by the time
that we figured out like what it was
and we can start talking to people like
you it's everywhere
yeah yeah exactly i so um hoplin vibrate
itself was characterized in hops in the
80s
and
because hops plants are so genetically
similar to cannabis at some point the
viroid sort of came into cannabis but
nobody knows exactly when this happened
and just like you said i suspect it's
been circulating for a really long time
and the negative about that of course is
that by the time we realized it like you
said it's everywhere um and you know
it's just been going unchecked for so
long that it's really become
like a cannabis pandemic and you know
that's going to lead to a lot of
questions for me actually because i
think there's like there's like two
things here one there's like the the
aspect of figuring out what it does
right and then there's like best
practices for how we can slow it down
you know and one of the interesting
aspects is like is that there's a
there's a thing that matt and i called
bro science
yes
bro science where you know there's a lot
of rumors because cannabis has been in
the shadows for a long time um it hasn't
had the ability for like uc davis or the
university of iowa or various scientists
to study these things so we have to make
we have to like observe and guess
right and so then there's um so then at
times then there's there's a i think
there's a lot of
uh
you know i watched a previous interview
that you were in and i think enormous
amounts of people were shocked when you
said that like 99 alcohol does nothing
to it yeah that was a big shocker yeah
right and then i've been i've been in
greenhouses where they had like the
torches attached to the end of like
propane canisters and they were cleaning
their tools in between and then you were
like oh that doesn't do anything very
much either right yeah yeah yeah and so
not that we need to go into all that
right this second but i just mean that i
think there's a lot of misinformation
right and just like any other kind of
virus or anything going around the best
way to figure it out is so people know
what works and what doesn't
how
how do you even get infected you know
can bugs infect you
you know can touching plants infect you
is it just
run off in razor blades is it there's a
whole host of stuff that i think most
people are still pretty ignorant of
yeah um
and uh it might be it might change over
time but you know you seem to be
someone that like has some real
experience and like what is actually in
testing
turning out to be effective how did how
did to me come into testing um for hplp
how did you come into testing for
cannabis anything
yeah so um so basically i can just give
you a really like quick two-minute
background on the company um
so we uh started tumi genomics about two
and a half years ago and it was actually
um started originally by myself and my
husband who is also one of the
scientists in the company and one of our
entrepreneurial friends
um and basically we were both at the end
of our post docs we kind of decided
academia wasn't for us and um we wanted
to take what we knew how to do like all
of this inventive you know cutting edge
science that was going on in academia
and bring it into an industry or a
geography that really needed that the
tools we could make or the information
that we could share
um
yeah and so we started the company and
then about a month after we started
covet hit and everything stopped and we
all the plans that we had made for our
brand new startup were completely
squished
so um we said well okay we'll just
jump into cobit and see if we can help
out
and we started doing that we made a
covid diagnostic kind of a point of care
or an on-site test and we ran a cobia
lab for the university and kind of at a
similar time we had somebody contact us
who had to grow and she was having
issues with hotplate and viroid and she
couldn't find
uh you know a place where she could
reliably test or whatever and she asked
if we could help out
so we designed a test for her kind of at
the same time that we're also doing like
a ton of qpcr testing for kovid um and
it just kind of grew from there by word
of mouth but um once we got into the
industry and i started you know meeting
the people and understanding what was
going on i was like cannabis is
absolutely the industry for us because
yeah um we wanted to make a difference
we wanted to take what we knew how to do
and help people and i think in this
industry you know we can add a lot of
good insight and tools to really help
people out
and that so that was kind of how we
ended up here um my husband's overjoyed
because we've had a tent in our basement
for like a decade and that's always yeah
this has always been his favorite hobby
and now he's like ah now it's my career
so um well that's gotta be awesome for
him for sure
he's he's always down there taking notes
and stuff so and and now he doesn't
i mean
you know there's i mean this hop blatant
is just one aspect of it but i do think
it's interesting that
you know um you look at other crops and
you get to stand on decades of research
um there's a lot of information that's
out there there's a lot of breeding
there's a lot of resources for people um
and then all of a sudden you have this
thing that's trying to make legal and
it's a multi-billion dollar crop and
nobody knows anything about it other
than
like in terms i don't mean anything i
just mean in the sense that like the
type of money and energy that gets
brought to bear
on other agricultural crops
in the infancy of hemp and cannabis
being looked at at all in that fashion
yeah yeah all the other crops have had
decades of research federal funding you
know lots of grants and money and
academic institutions supporting them
and you know cannabis doesn't really get
to benefit from much of that so
we have a lot of work to do a lot of
research to do and i think sadly too i
think the onset of legalization is
really what cr and even like maybe
medical in the 215 era is really what
created the problem
um and what i mean by that is that in
the original era that i was in like i
said you either made your own clones or
started your own seeds or got them from
a close associate and it was very small
circles
once you started being able in the 215
era in the medical era with a medical
card to go into dispensaries or go to
nurseries and buy your clones
right and now especially in the legal
market like in
california but in other places too where
they've mandated that you sort of have
to get you have to have a nursery
license to even provide plant matter to
most farms
they sort of centralized that aspect
which meant that when some of these
diseases got into some of those
centralized nurseries
it went everywhere like really quickly
right and so
um and then you know one of the things
we don't know
is for instance like how long can it
persist on surfaces how long can it
persist in soil you know all these
different types of things because what's
happening to people is that they're
getting they're getting clones from a
nursery and they're to me to my
knowledge there is no regulation or
penalties
for a nursery selling you
diseased or infected products yeah right
yeah i mean that's another thing the
canada's industry you know i suffers
from is that a lot of these other
industries these these pathogens are
highly regulated and they're you know
there's government mandates of what to
be tested and how to be tested and how
to decide if the testing lab is is good
enough or has done enough validation but
um yeah there's no requirements right
now in cannabis which which means that
you know lots of stuff is going on that
lots of stuff's going on and that i
think i don't think
with regulation they intended for that
to happen
but it was simply like an outgrowth of
forcing everyone to go to a few
nurseries
and then this gets into a few nurseries
and they're cloning for everyone and
they're not changing their equipment
they're not taking precautions and so it
spreads from maybe one or two varietals
through their whole thing
and then everyone is getting infected
plants
yeah and um you know and so
um there's definitely been already legal
farms that have failed
uh because being infected and reduced
yield reduced quality
uh you know that type of thing so
um i guess maybe we should go on to like
maybe the first thing
that we should we should we could
discuss is like
um because there's a lot i was i was
thinking of but like
what's the best way like let's say that
you have a plant in your garden that has
it like a mom plant what's the best way
to keep it from spreading
because you might not know that you have
it so you might as well act like you do
right
exactly yeah i mean that one thing i was
going to say is that you know
kind of above or throughout all of the
recommendations to keep it from
spreading the most important people
thing that people can do is to
acknowledge
that this is everywhere and nobody is
immune from it and
it's not
you know a them problem
you know it's it's it's a ubiquitous
issue and in order for it to be
addressed the first thing you have to do
um i guess
i don't want to sound like an addiction
counselor or whatever or but is to admit
that there's a problem yeah for real
yeah for real all of us need to be
taking precautions you know from home
grower all the way up to multi-state
operator mso
um to make sure that we're not spreading
it through the industry you know passing
it on to other people that kind of thing
um so um the most important precautions
to keep it from spreading would be um
sterilization so that's one of them
that's very critical
um so you need to be sterilizing your
tools and
um there's a lot of information out
there flying around about what works and
what doesn't and um i've even heard a
scientist contradicting each other which
i'm sure is super frustrating for
everybody out there i'll hear one thing
in one podcast and then another thing in
another
um so i actually went through all of the
literature and
consolidated into one document which you
guys can find on our website if you want
to
um and they basically tried 53 different
things
um in the literature uh with scientific
experiments and there were only five of
the chemicals or treatments that worked
and there was only one where they were
able to show worked on multiple viruses
or viroids in multiple crop species and
that was bleach uh 10 to 20 bleach 60
seconds um i know i sail it all the time
so here i'm saying it again use bleach
um so you want to sterilize your tools
as you move from plant to plant
you can have a couple pairs of you know
scissors or razor blades or whatever all
sitting in the bleach and just pull a
clean one out do your cuts put it back
in the bleach and grab a different one
for the next plant
if you get sap or whatever on your hands
you are going to be want to be wearing
gloves and you can get put some bleach
into spray bottles play your hands and
rub it around just like you put on hand
sanitizer or something like that and you
said 60 seconds 60 seconds for the tools
yes
and does that include your hands like if
you had gloves on and you're rubbing it
does that mean like
similar to covet if you if you wash your
hands that long
it's going to kill it
so so basically if you spray it on your
gloves and rub it around and just leave
it there it's going to end up sitting
there for 60 seconds anyway so you don't
have to rinse it off your hands you can
just let it dry on there and that's
exactly how we do it in the lab to be
honest too because you know
contamination there is also an issue so
um you know if you get plant matter on a
table or whatever just sterilize it
clean it up really quick quick you can
use some bleach there too
don't let debris and whatnot sit around
on the floor or on the tables um
so make sure to be sterilizing all those
surfaces let me let me throw in let me
throw in another question that might be
slightly technical or whatever but does
it matter what kind of bleach
because i have i have heard that for
instance say that like sodium like
normal household bleach for your
clothing or whatever sodium you know is
um is a little bit more unstable and if
it gets a little bit dirty it can get
inert fairly fast i've heard that like
pool bleach is stronger and more
effective and it's more stable right so
um there's different types of bleach i
guess you could go to the store and you
could get you know splashless bleach
versus cheap bleach versus pool bleach
you know some of them are calcium
chloride some of them are so i just
wondered if if there was a difference
there or you had a preference like in
your lab what would you use
yeah so in our lab we use good old
sodium hypochlorite which is your
regular household bleach
the critical point here is not the kind
of bleach or the splashless or whatever
it's um the the concentration of the
active ingredient so um you want to make
sure that the the final concentration of
the bleach the active ingredient is
above point zero or point five percent
so that means if you're making a one to
ten or a ten percent solution the
household bleach needs to have at least
five percent of the active ingredient
um and most of them do in fact i think
the lowest one
that i know of is
two 5.25 percent so if you're in a one
to ten solution or a one to nine which
would make a ten percent solution should
be the right concentration
because i see a lot of people out there
going and using pool bleach or different
forms of bleach because they thought
that the household bleach was inferior
and wasn't as strong or didn't work as
well and it was risky to only use that
and so i just thought like some clear
direction on um it seems like it seems
like you know cheap available household
bleach will be fine
yes and almost all of the studies um in
fact i think all of the studies have
used sodium hypochlorite so
um you do want to make it up fresh every
day because you are correct it does lose
um effectiveness especially if it sits
at a dilute solution if it gets really
saturated with plant material it'll also
start to lose effectiveness so you're
just going to want to you know dump it
out of whatever your little jar is and
fill it up with some more 10 percent
bleach
you can also make it up at that 20
concentration which would be four parts
water one part bleach
um and then it'll last a little bit
longer
just to make people feel more
comfortable they actually did do a study
where they asked how long it was
effective for and they made a dilute
solution of 20 bleach and it was still
inhibiting transmission up to 30 days
this was not saturated with plant
material it was just kind of hanging
around now so you could make a spray
bottle for instance of 20
and and it would be and it would be
staying you know contained it wouldn't
be getting contaminated by plant
material and you could use that to spray
your gloves or whatever for quite some
time is what you're saying
yeah now i i would definitely recommend
making it up fresh but if you know there
was a miscommunication or you weren't
sure when it was made there is some
flexibility there leech is cheap
leech is cheap and it's very effective
because i remember i first saw that
interview with you where i was at i was
we were i was at a good friend's nursery
and like i said they were all heat
sterilizing their tools yeah and then i
just watched you and you were like oh
that doesn't work and i was like oh no
because they're out there trying to do
best practices and do what they can to
make sure it doesn't work and then all
of a sudden they're doing something
that's ineffective
yeah yeah so that that was actually
tried in the literature six seconds in a
propane blow torch um and it reached an
average temperature of 430 degrees
fahrenheit um and it did not stop the
transmission
um so
i mean now this i should i should
qualify all of this
almost in fact none of these experiments
were done with hot latent thyroid all
the viroids have a very similar
structure and
metabolism in the cell
so um we're extrapolating information
from other viroids because a lot of
research has been done
in other plants that makes sense i was
there was one of my other questions is
how because there's not there's not a
lot of money yet coming into this type
of stuff like how much specific research
is even going into it
yes yeah and that's uh not much right
now um we're we are trying to bridge
that gap we actually started a
collaboration with texas a m um and we
are we're starting research
into some of the really basic questions
um seed transmission
you know levels around the plant that
kind of thing um so we're trying to
encourage more academic uh cooperation
and and more research so
maybe we could ask a series of of
questions and you could say i know i
don't know or explain
so
obviously it seems like sterilizing
tools is very important so like if
you're taking cuttings that would be a
primary method of transmission right is
um what about
uh what about runoff from watering
plants
yes so um what i'm going to tell you is
what's been
demonstrated in the literature
so
um
for a viroid called potato spindle tuber
viroid which is in the same family as
hotplate and thyroid with a very similar
structure
they showed that the viroid isn't high
level in the roots and that's the same
in hops plants for hoplite and viroid
the viroid leaks from the roots into the
water and if they water tomato plants
with thyroid-containing water
those plants
became infected with the viroid they
also showed in that paper that the virus
remained infectious for up to seven
weeks
so in the water
so
that research wasn't done in cannabis it
wasn't done with hot plate and viroid
but i think there is enough demonstrated
evidence in the literature for it to be
a concern yeah okay but think about it
so
that i was going to ask how long can it
persist you're saying that it could
persist up to i mean like seven weeks is
a long time seven weeks is a long time
yes um on surfaces they've done these
experiments and they've tested it out to
24 hours and shown that it does survive
for 24 hours on most common surfaces um
unfortunately they didn't go beyond 24
hours so it could be longer but um it
can persist for that long
um what about
uh
for instance um insect vectors
things like thrips
mites root aphids you know i mean i know
obviously we can catch malaria from a
mosquito we can get lyme disease and
other stuff from ticks
how worried are you about um
bugs spreading it from one plant to
another
yes so i would not be at all surprised
if that was a method of transmission um
as far as i'm aware there was only one
study in the literature done with
hoplate and viroid on bug transmission
and it was done with aphids
and hops plants and they were unable to
show vector insect vector transmission
with aphids
now that does not mean that aphids
wouldn't spread it in cannabis it
doesn't mean that other types of insects
wouldn't spread it and a lot of viroids
are
spread by insects
the research just isn't there yet to
one way or the other as to whether or
not it can be spread by insects for
hotly thyroid and cannabis because to me
especially like as a um
you know as somebody who uses the sun
quite often
um i was i was talking about it with
some other farmers and you know we can
you can do all these best practices and
you can do all these things yourself and
be very self-contained and have your
mother room be perfect and then you know
some thrips blow over from the
neighbor's garden
and you're and you're in trouble
exactly yes and i mean i should say when
we're talking about hapleton thyroid
right now but there are viruses in
cannabis
um out that affect outdoor more and
those are spread by insects so
um like pearly top coming from leaf
hoppers and stuff like that
yeah so you definitely want to be
concerned about insects um because they
are a big vector for a lot of different
pathogens
um
the seed the seed one's probably going
to be the one that we're going to hear
the most and leading up to this
interview for
like since i announced it i have heard
so many answers on so many people so
confident
on the exact percentage of
transmissibility in cannabis seeds for
sure
and wildly different percentages that
they think are proven as well yes some
very low some quite much higher
um so it's you know we
what are your what is studies that
you're seeing uh show as far as seed
transmission
yes so there is one study in hops
showing that c transmission of hot plate
and thyroid in hot plants is eight
percent
um
we have started preliminary studies so
this is very preliminary and um we still
are working with texas a m because
they're they're growing out the plants
but um
what we are finding is that it's
variable
based on the cultivar based on how
infected the mom was and so
um my gut is that these people are
claiming wildly different numbers
because it's going to be wildly
different for each batch of seeds each
cultivar and you know obviously if your
plant is on fire with hop latent thyroid
that that percent transmission might be
higher than a low-level infection maybe
you see nothing or or zero percent
transmission so
pretty par for the course with cannabis
like anybody who tries any serious
scientific studies into cannabis sexual
expression
via ethylene
production or inhibit inhibition they
find that it's just so variable in every
single it's not down to strain it's down
to
not just the plant it's down to the
plant in that specific environment and
it's just there's so much variability to
even be taking steps at numbers like
that until there's like this
wide-ranging study that just hasn't been
allowed to be done yet
so seed transmission you would probably
it's fair to say is just
um it's
variable or requires a lot more study
before we know it's sort of an educated
guess at best at this point
yes i would say um there's probably
enough evidence to say seed transmission
happens
or can happen but there is not enough
studies out there and and high enough
numbers to come up with a percentage
um and that's going to take a lot of
research and certainly not in cannabis
specifically right like the studies work
done in hops so canvas is a completely
different beast even though they're very
similar in structure i was almost you
know uh i'm by no means a scientist but
when i was reading about the the viroids
trying to like prepare for talking about
tonight it almost made me think of like
some of these viroids have some
similarities with enzymes
and then like they're not actually alive
they're sort of like waiting for a
reaction to happen like to encounter
something that then triggers what they
can do
yeah
that's exactly so
they um
you know one of one of the aspects that
you know uh
so like it you know can if it persists
then it can just be sitting there in a
seed or it can be it can be you know do
you think people can transmit it by
touching
so
potentially um the way that the virus so
the vibroid needs to gain access via a
break point so if for example you're
trimming your plants and you have goo on
your hands and then you touch another
plant and you even if there's a little
micro tear or you know just a little
breakage of a stem as you're touching
you can spread it like that
um but it there needs to be
like some sap exchange between a sick
plant and an a healthy plant that has a
little opening for this for the sick for
the infected sap to get in so for lack
of a better way to look at it like
healthy skin would prevent you would
have to have a cut or abrasion or
something like that in order to give
them a vector for it to go in
correct yeah there has to be some type
of even miniature mechanical damage for
it to access the plant
okay
um
one of so i guess
do you know anything about because this
is the other part of it that is really
harmful is obviously like cannabis is
under a lot of financial pressure right
now
legalization has not been smooth
there's a lot of odd regulations going
on and people are really feeling it um
and you know one of the biggest aspects
of hop latent um is the expense of
trying to figure out how to deal with it
once you have it right yes um
and you know there's there's also you
know one one of the one of the groups
that spread it a bunch one of the
nurseries then later came out with a
cure
right um of you know oh i've seen a lot
of stuff about tissue culture meristem
heat treatments
various um to be honest very expensive
and time-consuming treatments
um that you know p some people have been
jumping on because they have a favorite
cultivar they have a favorite strain
they don't know where they can get it
again and it's infected
and so there's a big push to like i want
to save this thing
rather than just throw it away and and
give up
right
but i see a lot of conflicting
information on whether or not this stuff
actually works
yes yeah so um
tissue culture can work it is not
a hundred percent effective it's not
going to work
the same on every cultivar so here we go
again
and it's gonna depend on how infected
the plant is
um when people are doing this heat
treatment thing so it was shown in hops
that if you subject the plant to high
heat
like 35 degrees celsius i think is the
temperature they use
the level of the viroid will decrease it
doesn't go away completely but it goes
down enough that when they dissect the
apical meristem
they have a higher chance of not getting
any infected material along with the
apical meristem
um
it so
you can clean it with tissue culture it
is a lengthy process and it takes a long
time and and not everyone works so if
you if they i mean what they do is they
clean it then they you know they they
grow a bunch up and they have to test
each of them get rid of the ones where
it didn't work and just keep on testing
and that they usually are testing for a
really long time before they can be sure
that they've cleaned it completely
and that's because the the apical
meristems not in the vascular system is
that why the virus isn't just there and
that's what they try to keep it like
that little bit from any kind of
contamination on the sides and
okay yes yeah so it is excluded from
that region that the the
like the stem cells in there but you do
it you have to be super careful and know
exactly what you're doing to get rid of
all that vascular tissue because that
tissue does have uh hopefully
environment in it so
i'll uh maybe that leads to another
question then
um because i've seen people who
have had inconclusive testing
um
you know when it comes to testing for
hot blatant which is obviously extremely
frustrating because
you want to get a negative test then you
want to be like okay i'm in the clear
right my plan is clean um but what what
it seems like is that almost like with
covet or something else if you're
heavily infected it's almost always a
yes that it'll pick it up
but maybe if you're only lightly
infected it could come back negative
right and you might so how many
what maybe walk us through like if
somebody was worried that their plant
wasn't performing the right way or
looked a little sickly um how many tests
how far apart what protocol should they
have to like ascertain whether or not
they're infected or not
yes okay so um so first to understand
why
you
there's such a frustration with you know
getting a negative test in the positive
test or part of the plant's positive and
part of its negative
um is understanding how viroids actually
move through the plant
so when a plant gets infected the viroid
moves through the tissue until it
reaches the vascular system once it's in
the vascular system it basically has to
hitch a ride on the movement of the sap
of the plant so where it's going to go
is dependent on where the sap from that
branch is currently traveling
so viroids are going to move for what
they call a source to sink type movement
so they're going to move towards areas
of the plant that are experiencing
active growth at the time the plant was
infected so you can imagine if it's a
middle branch
and it travels to the vascular system
it's going to move up towards the new
growth but those lower branches are less
likely to receive fibroid so
not every part of the plant is going to
get the same load at the same time
um so the reason that they say oh submit
multiple samples is we don't you don't
since you don't know when the plant was
inoculated and what the source to sink
you know flow was at the time
you have to grab a bunch of different
spots of the plant um
to feel confident that you've cased
enough areas that the statistical
probability of catching it is high
enough
i will say we did run a little study
it's not quite ready for uh publication
yet or putting on our website um but
capricorn nursery was gracious enough to
take in a couple positive four positive
plants actually and they took samples
for us all over the plant you know new
growth old growth stems roots everything
and the part of the plant that was the
most predictive of infection was the
roots
we got a hundred percent success rate
when we tested the roots
um
and if you think about it this makes a
lot of sense because the roots are
always growing and you're always going
to have nutrients from the foliage
moving into the roots
um so it i would say if you were going
to pick a part of the plant to pick
some root tissue as well as um some
petiole tissue around the plant just
because this was a preliminary study it
was for plants and i don't want to base
someone's diagnostic on
you know a small study like that but i
think it's suggestive enough to also be
submitting root tissue
one of the one of the ways um we had a
good friend of ours who experienced at
the time what we call dudding uh which
you know uh i'm a collector of of old
and rare and unpopular things and so for
people like us uh it's really scary
you know because in cannabis there's not
very many people that are willing to
hold on to a wide diversity of genetics
especially if they're not currently
profitable right
and so to have something like this
ripped through your collection of
possibly old unpopular not backed up by
very many people sometimes not backed up
by anyone
is pretty scary and one of the things
that he learned or he guessed was that
it was his runoff
on sharing on trays and things like that
was that it was infecting things and so
he instituted a program where like every
single mom was elevated
and drained away
so that no runoff would ever touch
another plant
yeah right
and i i think that's that's a good idea
and it's not just for hotplate and
viroid there's a lot of root fungal
pathogens that spread through the water
and um
shared water if you're trying to prevent
pathogens um
is not recommended because it's it's an
excellent way for a bunch of pathogens
to move around i i can tell you that um
before we ever heard the term hop latent
uh a lot of us were considering dutting
to be an aggressive form of fusarium
yeah you know uh and and we were you
know there was a lot of there was a lot
of like you know
uh our research going into like well how
do you cure that how do you get rid of
that because
we couldn't do the testing we didn't
know what it was we were just
observationally seeing what was going on
um and
uh
so
basically i guess what you're saying is
you think is it fair to say that you
think that the vast majority of
transmission is happening via runoff and
via cloning with contaminated tools
so i would say
the vast majority is happening via
mechanical transmission with tools um i
suspect that there is a percentage of
transmission going along with water
transmission although
i don't have published evidence to show
that right um sure we did we did take
some
tubing from a water admitter from a
facility that had an outbreak and we
just used the tube itself in the pcr and
we were able to amplify hotplate viroid
from the tube
so
it was in there and it was stuck to the
rubber on the inside of the tube whether
or not it was sufficient to infect a
plant
you know i don't know but it lived there
it was it was there yeah and i i want to
make sure that i answer the question how
many times to test your plant um yes
certain that it's negative you need to
test it at least at least twice
um three to four weeks apart so that if
it was missed because it was a very
early infection you give that plant long
enough to have enough of a systemic
infection and a high enough load that
you can you can catch it the second time
around
um and
honestly i would i think people if you
know they're you're really trying to be
careful
um i would test your mother plants
periodically you know on a continual
basis on a routine basis not everyone
has the ability to do this yeah um and
it's difficult but we
in in recent years uh with the influx of
just a bunch of horrific things um
that started getting spread around not
just hop latent but rude aphids
um you know we call them super mites
which are basically two spotted mites
that have been trained for decades to
grow resistant to many pesticides
every every pesticide yeah well you know
over over just like any other thing
overuse of certain kind like you know
like overuse of antibiotics or whatever
and all of a sudden you have so you know
there's
um
basically i guess what i'm saying with
that is that
you know you would recommend let's say
that you bring in something new or old
that you're excited about and you
quarantine it you would recommend at
least two tests
four weeks apart and get both of those
negative before you would feel confident
to even want to move that plant into
your larger safer mother room of
hopefully clean genetics
yes absolutely i think strict quarantine
for anything new two tests
for economically critical pathogens and
i would probably add fusarium oxy sporum
to that list
because you don't want that floating
around your grow either
separate tools you don't want to be
using the same tools and
if you're thinking about the workflow in
your facility obviously don't start in
the quarantine room
and then move to your mom room
sure
so this is um yeah and this is exactly
what the us government does right when
when plants come in they go in strict
quarantine and they're tested and
observed before they're allowed into the
country
so um
this is about protecting your borders
another another aspect of that that i i
find interesting and i'd love some
clarification on is that
um
you know when people are doing clones
right and obviously especially like in
commercial instances where you're taking
hundreds or even thousands of clones on
a work shift
right
you can do stuff like you can do what we
talked about earlier where you could
have bleach and you could have rotating
tools and you can clean all that and you
can have you know fresh starting
material whether it's rockwool or plugs
or whatever
but
one of the things that i know about
cannabis that everyone does is
most of the time
every single stem goes in that rooting
gel or goes in that dip and grow or goes
in that hormone right
and trying to figure out how to isolate
hormone or rooting gel or whatever for
each specific plant themselves and not
mixing that
that is a bottleneck and so um you know
it's expensive
yeah how how risky is it to d let's say
you dip a clone into dip and grow for
three or four seconds
how much and but it's a fresh wound
right yeah you just cut
how much risk is that and how and what
what practices could people even
institute
um in order to not make that a vector
for transmission
yeah so
unfortunately if you cut a clone you
know and and you have this huge open
wound it's and it's it's infected it's
going to be seeping
hot plate and thyroid into that solution
and um if you get a clone that's
infected and you dip another one in that
solution you're you've basically created
an inoculum and you're using it to
inoculate every clone after that that's
dipped into that solution
um that's definitely
yeah
i mean just to be honest you know i get
it's the reality of it but it just
it just leads to a whole series of it's
basically like you want to have a
different vessel
for um for cloning material uh for every
single plant
yeah yeah and i mean i don't know if you
know maybe you can put it in an egg
carton you know so you just have a
little bit in each each spot or
something something i mean
i i hate to break in but like it even
goes down to like even different parts
of the goddamn plant if it's a big
enough plant because some of that might
have more viral load than the bottom
half and you may actually
increase your chance of
inoculating it when you might otherwise
not have and got grabbed a clean branch
somewhere left i mean i was almost
thinking of like uh i mean you could
have permanent you could have like you
know 20 different glass shot glasses
that you have a little bit of different
grow or a little bit of your hormone or
whatever in each one and then as soon as
you're done with it you dump the excess
out into something and you drop it into
bleach
and you move on to the next one and then
by the time but something like that
would have to be because
you could sterilize it and just wait a
minute or two
right and it would be clean
yes so if you had say 10 shot glasses
you could go from plant to plant and not
spread it
because i will tell you
that 99 of people out there
um that are taking precautions are still
using
a centralized dipping solution of some
kind
that's just the industry standard that's
just how it how it works
yeah that would that's definitely if you
are concerned at all that any of your
plants have hot thyroid then you you're
not going to want to be sharing anything
that has touched sap and then dip
another plant in it with a gaping wound
um because
you're just going to spread it
that makes that makes excellent sense so
i have a question um
so
you see a lot of plants probably that
come in that are negative
for obsolete and vibrate but people
suspect them of being dutted now
when you see this negative thing pop up
for the hops layton what
i mean do you test it for what else it
could be and at that point what is the
next most common form of things that
people are calling duded
that you're seeing
yeah so
beyond hoplaton viroid
the
percentage of plants that have other
viruses you know at least that we know
of is pretty low it's usually hot plate
and vibrate if they're seeing viral like
symptoms
um other things can cause stunted growth
like fusarium pythium right because
these things are chewing on the roots
and so you're going to see slow growth
or it'll look like a nutrient deficiency
kind of yeah
so we're definitely seeing those
pathogens also and
just a little sidebar
we're also seeing that
those pathogens can come in through
people's water sources
especially if you're not chained like
you know following all the
recommendations for how your water is
filtered yeah um so i would highly
recommend that people test their water
systems periodically um just to make
sure that they don't have anything
growing in there and they're you know
watering their plants with like pythium
water
so yeah that is i mean that's something
i haven't done this in a long time but
20 years ago i was a mostly hydroponic
person
and when you're growing with water
culture and like nutrient film technique
and stuff you learn about pythium
you learn about water temperature how it
can grow how it can replicate
um so if let's say you had a 50 gallon
drum for the sake of argument right and
you were worried about your water what
would be what would be the way that you
would think would be the best way to
sterilize it and then how long would you
have to wait before you could use it
could you add a certain amount of bleach
stir it for 10 minutes an hour two hours
and then go or do you have data on that
so
i'm not gonna say for sure because i'm
not exactly sure at what concentration
i'm comfortable with that what time i
don't i don't wanna
no i get it there's i figured there was
gonna be you have you have certainty you
have uncertainty and you have i don't
know which is
that's where we're at
yeah i i'm not sure how
how effective it could be to actually
sterilize the water that's in that tank
um i can say if you want to test it you
should take the stuff from the bottom
the the stuff where all the material
might settle and grab whatever that
sludge is
um and we can usually find it if it's
there because we for the water testing
we grow it out on plates um so it's not
like a 24-hour thing like testing for
the viroid but um then we can grow it up
and look at all the fuzzy stuff that
grows and do a pcr test on each colony
to see if you got something going in
there um
so another thing
that uh
maybe would be really important for
people is that obviously there's some
growers
that start with fresh
material every time they grow whether
that's rock wool or coconut fiber or you
know peat moss perlite whatever but then
there's also a growing movement of
people uh certainly outdoor
but also moving more indoor you know all
kinds of living soil or multi-cycle
grows that type of thing
and so um you know we did a uh i had a
commercial thing we were working on and
we got some plants that did absolutely
horrible from a nursery
uh and we tested the soil
um about three months after harvest
and it came up positive
yeah so
perhaps
yeah so i'm curious if you could tell
because there's a lot of people right
now
that want to move to more like
regenerative practices that want to be
reusing their medium um either from an
expense per you know perspective or
maybe like uh you know what just
whatever it might be right and there's a
lot that are trying to reuse their soil
reuse their mix do multiple cycles in it
um so
you know basically what it what's really
scary for people like them is that if
they get infected
it's a lot more expensive for them to
just throw it out and start over than it
is for someone that just buys six inch
rockwell every crime every time right
yeah yeah so what do you recommend i
mean obviously sterilizing soil is its
whole thing do you have any data or
anything like that on how long it can
persist
in soil if you plant inflict infected
plants after you've killed them
yeah so
um
once again these experiments have not
been done in cannabis um in hops they
can show that the viroid overwinters
um but that's a perennial plant so it's
not it's not a very good you know
comparison because it has living roots
and stuff that it can stain
yeah um i will say uh it's
even in in cannabis from you know the
limited studies that we've done it's in
very high concentration in the roots
so if you have an infected plant and
there's still root material left in that
soil if you plant another plant in that
root material
i i think you're playing with fire as
far as getting infected plants
um
that's everyone that reuses their soil
because they typically cut the plant
down and they're relying on biology and
various things to break down the root
mass in the system and return that
energy or whatever to
the soil food web so no one i mean it
would be impossible even unless you like
micro screen to remove roots
right right so i think you know you you
if you
i mean i don't know what's cheaper
testing every plant or the you know the
some root decay left in the pot or just
starting with new soil but um i would
definitely not be reusing soil from a
plant that had hot plate and thyroid so
basically what you're saying is anyone
that uses the same soil year after year
in an outdoor situation or in a
greenhouse or anyone that is in some
sort of living soil organic regenerative
thing where they're doing multiple
cycles
they would need to be even more militant
than normal
yeah i mean i i think kind of what this
comes down to is that you know all of
these practices can be worked into a
regular standard operating procedure as
long as you're testing as long as you're
constantly measuring you know the
the biotic stress of your plants and so
you know what's going on you your you
know you can adopt your sops depending
on what outbreaks or which types of
pathogens
are there but if you're not collecting
information then you can't make
intelligent choices downstream about
what's safe and what isn't
so
if we're gonna get it under control
people need to be
monitoring their plants all of the time
to make sure that they don't have
something you know spreading in there
and and
because if you don't
then you end up with catastrophic losses
or possibly you do
so on that level
um that leads me to another question and
it's related to something matt said you
know you said earlier too that like in
addition to hop layton you would also
test for a certain kind of fusarium you
know matt was talking earlier about um
you know other forms of dutting to use
the common term
um you know i uh so for you since you
offer these services or something like
that how how affordable is it
like if if if we were to create a panel
of hop layton with two or three other
common things
right
how much does it how much is it gonna
honestly cost somebody just like even
just like a hobbyist who's concerned and
wants to test their little collection um
to do like a one once a month
uh on a plant for instance
yes so um i mean obviously every testing
lab is going to have a different price
and whatever um our cost is 25 dollars
for a test um
specifically or for multiple things
so that's for hot blatant specifically
we're working on channels putting
multiple things together um and then you
know
kind of figuring out where where the
cost of that will fall
but um
even if you know if you're a really
large or a larger facility and you want
to get on some sort of regular testing
schedule then there are you know bulk
deals and and kind of subscription type
things where we can help with sops sure
and then and then it gets more
affordable there
um
because so matt uh not matt always he
never um
you know uh people ask sometimes what
the size of my collection is and he's
always like you know don't but yeah you
know in that regard for a variety of
reasons but you can imagine let's say
that someone does have a fairly
extensive collection right yeah and you
want to regularly get them tested
um that could that could be a major
expense for a normal person
right trying to stay on top of things
that could run into the thousands of
dollars a month perhaps
yeah right i mean
depending on your collection you know if
it's if it's big enough it can be an
expense for sure
um so then maybe maybe i could get like
perhaps a little like political slash
regulatory
um
so you know one of the one of the the
the equitable things or people talk
about like social equity a lot uh in
cannabis because
um a lot of the people that are
traditional or legacy cannabis breeders
um are you know sort of small outlaws
type folks and now you have a lot of big
money you have a lot of investment you
have a lot of like people that never
would have dealt with it before so the
culture is changing dramatically right
yes sadly
um the little guy has a lot harder time
affording this
than the big guy
uh when in my opinion as far as i've
been able to determine it's unscrupulous
or simply poor practice big people and
that are spreading it everywhere
right and then they have no
responsibility once it's gotten out
there to do anything about it they don't
owe anyone anything right
so
do you think then that there should be
some kind of regulatory or political
change where you know clones sold
should come with a clean bill of health
that that should be like an absolute
standard because to me if you're paying
all this money for instance i'll just
use
as an example but if you're paying a
bunch of money up front for the right to
grow for your square footage and you're
paying all these taxes and fees up front
and you have all this cost
and then you buy a thousand clones that
ruin your season
and now your soil is infected and you've
got this massive issue
uh the only person that has no liability
is the person that happily took your
money
to sell the clones they're free and
clear they you don't have i don't think
there is any cases of being able like in
the regular agricultural system
if you spread some kind of terrible
disease
from your nursery to a big agricultural
people they'll come after you right
yeah yeah so i mean i think so this
problem
needs to be i mean this is my opinion
attacked on multiple levels um i think
it should be standard in the industry
that you know if you're if you're
selling clones that you're getting your
stuff tested and that you can provide
some type of
documentation certification
um that you that it was tested and and
these are the results like this mom was
tested within 30 days of me taking this
clone
yes um and i think on the other end when
people are buying clones they should
have the right to say hey is this tested
and if the person says yeah i say
awesome can you give me the can you give
me the results and tell me what lab it
was tested through so you can do your
own research and decide whether or not
you believe the results you trust the
science um
you know you can you can get clones and
um just do a quick screening yourself
you know if you bought a thousand clones
you can you can bulk test
you know maybe five or six clones per
tube and just try to get like even even
like five percent of them and send them
in to
your own i'll throw something out there
because this is
this is maybe a little technical so i'm
not going to try to borrow anyone but
with the rate with but you know honestly
with the rate regulations exist or
whatever in legal situations like a lot
of a lot of you know licenses that have
flowering rights you know you're
supposed to move your plants into those
areas within 24 hours
you know you don't have like it's not
that easy to like just sit there take a
bunch of clones spend a few weeks
testing them waiting for results making
sure they're clean keeping them healthy
without transplanting them and then
figuring out whether or not you need to
buy more clothes because a lot of these
nurseries
you put your orders in in spring you
know you have a week that you get your
plants it's not like if if somebody
screws you
on you can go to another nursery and be
like hey i need 9 000 cuts and i'm
behind
they might not even so i i guess what
i'm saying is i don't know that putting
the the responsibility on the farmer is
very effective for the farmer in terms
of cost and just the way the regulations
are i almost it almost seems to me like
in uh i mean this is a crazy analogy or
whatever but like you know um like you
know uh people that work in the sex
industry like in in movies and stuff
they have to get tested every two or
three weeks
right and they have to like before they
go to work they have to provide a clean
bill of health so it almost seems to me
like the same thing should be done with
nurseries like if you want to sell
thousands of clones to someone you
should have a recent test
you know that shows that the mother that
came off this stuff was not infected
because otherwise it's going to keep
happening
yes i absolutely agree i mean and i
think
um we work with nurseries that test all
of the time i mean that test every you
know they they cut they and they send in
hundreds of samples to make sure that
they're not selling
positive plants to anybody and i think
those are there's ethical people very
much so um shout out to our our friends
uh at radio ridge who i know spend a lot
of money monthly um testing their stuff
but there's other unscrupulous nurseries
that don't waste any money on that
and they end up spreading a lot of
disease without realizing it
yeah yeah and honestly you know i think
that the biggest responsibility that
would fall to the clone the person
buying the clones is to simply ask did
you test
and you know you have the right to move
to a different person if you if that you
know if they haven't been testing and
you don't feel confident you know you
can try to source them from elsewhere
but i i think
that moving forward that's gonna have to
start to become the industry standard if
we're gonna you know get this thing
under control everybody's gonna have to
be testing i can tell you um having
consulted and worked at multiple legal
scenes especially ones that like are
brand new and getting off the ground
um most of the bugs for talking of those
will stop talking about viroids for a
second but most of the insects that come
under those onto those first grows come
from the nurseries
they come with free root aphids or free
cannabis aphids or free thrips or you
know free
free you know two spotted spider mites
and there's no discount
uh for that gift that comes along with
that so um nurseries haven't done a very
good job yet of providing problem-free
plants
um yeah
i kind of want to rewind it a bit
because i did notice some people were
mentioning we didn't go over like
initial
reasons why someone would even suspect
they have hops late like me and not to
have seen a lot of plants with this so
we know like we see one we're like oh
[ __ ] that's that's it it's like it's
obvious but a lot of people watching are
going to be very confused on how they
would even begin to identify it so are
there some some markers maybe you would
tell us to look out for
yeah so common symptoms are going to be
slow growth um you'll have branches that
instead of them coming up like the
normal angle they'll they'll go out more
horizontal like this um yeah more of a
90 degree branch yes correct and they'll
be brittle so you know if you if you
like touch the plant like this you know
they'll break yeah um another common
thing it's a little subtle but the
leaves instead of kind of being
separated will overlap a little bit and
that's another symptom you can also see
things like leaf chlorosis
sometimes it'll like puff out and look
more like a christmas tree
um like a christmas tree type growth
um you know in in little clones you're
gonna see a much slower slower growth
and sometimes it looks kind of sparse
and sickly but um
you know and then obviously sometimes
the symptoms can be really subtle and
depending on when it was infected it's
not super easy to see it um until it
flowers and then
it's just super duper disappointing
those are those are all i would i
wouldn't say all but i would say about
90 of what you mentioned especially the
angle of the stem the brittleness of the
stem and the on the small leaves
are all stuff that we had noticed
um among plants that were worrisome um
before we even knew what the word hop
layton was
yeah yeah i remember one of the others
was the stem color
uh there wasn't a lot of stem color i
don't know oh yeah that's a really good
one so i don't know if you know about
that but what we saw with infected
plants is that
most infected plants would be like a
uniform pale green
they wouldn't have any red or purple or
any kind of coloration they would almost
be like a pure
i don't want to say sickly green because
that's not right but well their texture
was different too it wasn't like the
normal texture that i would see it was
almost rubbery and when you would move
your hands down the stem it would
definitely break because of its
different type of texture it was it
would basically be the the plant would
look almost a unif the stem would be a
uniform pale green it wouldn't have some
of the variation we've come to expect
with you know as it gets woody or this
or that and so yeah um you know one of
uh
um
but the other the other risk of that is
that
uh maybe we can jump into this for a
minute is that the problem is is that
you can be infected and be asymptomatic
correct
yes you can have you can have an
infection that's young enough that it
hasn't started showing these deformities
if you will right yeah yep
so
maybe you could explain
you know and maybe you maybe you know
maybe you don't know
but we you've mentioned a number of
times where there's differences between
the viroid just like exploding around
through the plant versus a plant that
has less viroid
um what are some things that can you
know outside of just the plants health
what are some things that slow or speed
the plant being infected
in the sense of do you have any idea on
those aspects or ways to slow it down
even if it might be infected
uh that type of thing
yeah so um so it is mentioned in the
literature that um
higher temperatures and um more intense
light
tends to speed up the
replication of the viroid so it it so
the plant's gonna have a higher load
you're going to see the symptoms more
robustly if the plant gets stressed out
so that doesn't mean that it isn't it
isn't in there replicating but
if the plant gets stressed out dried up
or whatever
um the stress response of the plant
isn't going to be functioning as well as
a healthy plant and so you're going to
see those symptoms come out really
pronounced
if the plant gets stressed out um you
know it's
it's tough but what you what you really
want to do is try to find it before the
symptoms are super obvious because once
they're super obvious the plant is you
know really infected and the chances of
it spreading are quite a bit higher
um you know which is why i'm back to the
you know screening thing because if you
can catch it early on with a sensitive
enough test
um you can it's much easier to contain
and and keep it from spreading like that
matt do you intentionally have comments
off
yes okay
just just just to be clear so
um
there is a
so basically what we're talking about is
that we we've established there's a
couple different things you can do that
really that really prevent spread
but the best thing is just to prevent it
from coming in
yeah all
right the ideal yes that's the ideal
um and then you know so and you say that
uh because you know one of the things
that i see a lot of these places when
they offer tc or meristem
this is uh four to six thousand dollars
often
yeah and here's the price and it's it's
very pricey and you're saying and it
takes months right and you're saying
that it can be effective but the people
doing it have to be really talented at
actually removing all of the vascular
only getting it down to the meristem
itself and starting from that point and
there's some luck to it as well right
like
yes
yeah yeah some of it some of it's really
know knowing what you're doing really
understanding the plant getting the
plant you know really healthy before you
you know even attempt the process you
want to pick the right the right part of
the plant or the you know the healthiest
bit
um and then it's not going to work on
every single one so you could do numbers
your tests so
maybe i could i i think i already know
the answers to this but
um i have i'll just take you through uh
some bro science for a second on
what people are doing to cure it right
so one of the one of the ways that
people have heard you learn it
you know is you clone out of it
right you have a plant that you think
has an issue you try to get it as
healthy as humanly possible
right you take some clones that was my
my
my method
that was your method you you take the
healthiest clones you root it you get
you you root it you take a clone off it
very soon you throw that away you cycle
through
repeatedly trying to like sort of outrun
the viroid
is this
could be effective or is this sort of
chasing your own tail and it's it's
so
um okay i'm not gonna say that it can't
work because i have not done the
experiment and i don't know and so
you know this it could potentially work
um
one of the problems with
the viroid is you don't need a lot to
get that infection again i mean one or
two copies um you're not going to see
much for a long time it's going to take
a while for it to build enough to even
be detectable on a test
but just a little bit and you're you're
right back to an infected plant
um
and the vibrate chases the new growth
right like correct yeah so it's it
you're done it's definitely uh you're
you're playing a a chasing game right
again
um if you think about it if if the plant
was just infected and it's moving down
that first branch into the vascular
system and up
if you can cut a clone off before it
gets there like intellectually it should
be possible to grab a clone that doesn't
have it
um
i don't you'd have to start the race
before you knew that you should be
racing exactly in order
in order to outrun it but then the next
step
of that
so it's it's it's it sounds unlikely
um
i tried that with the trend so hard on
the trinity and and
we i think we had it outdoors trying to
chase it
up and out that way it was growing
vigorous taking the healthiest cuts
every time and over a period of year and
a half it just was not
it looked great and then slowly but
surely the traits would start showing
back up again yeah so then there's
there's some big companies out there
um that have claimed that they had
dutting issues and they cured them by
you know dunking dunking plants and and
something like say xeritol or you know
uh putting stairs in a date sanitate uh
putting you know um soaking the roots so
the roots uptake uh whatever sterolant
it might be
type of thing and that they have cured
it and never seen it since
kind of gig
and uh you know there's a
there's a big push with any kind of
nursery or any kind of big big grow
if anyone in the community finds out
that you have it
uh they want to let everyone know as
soon as possible that they've solved it
and then it's gone right and so
uh
you know i have a certain amount of
skepticism that that would work from
your experience that would not also not
be probably very effective
no no so
i guess to help people understand
viroids are intercellular pathogens so
what that means is they're not just in
the plant tissue they're they're inside
the cell and then once they get inside
the cell there's actually another little
tiny
organelle in there called the nucleus
and so they traffic all the way into
where the dna of the plant is and they
they hijack the machine that's supposed
to be interpreting the dna for the plant
and they use it to replicate themselves
and so
any type of non-specific disinfectant
that would actually make its way all the
way into the nucleus of the plant and
and non-specifically destroy rna would
kill the entire plant
because rna is used by the plant to do
its own biology like it's essential so
if basically you you could get it to
work by dropping your entire plant in
bleach or something but it'll just be
dead after like an hour or so right so
there's no way for a topical or you know
something that's being taken up that
that's a non-specific disinfectant to
get all the way into the nucleus and
only destroy the viroid and not the rest
of the plant maybe i'll ask a related
question but just more general
so in your experience the only thing
that has a chance of curing it
um but even that is variable would be a
high quality meristem
uh tissue culture with
testing afterwards to select the healthy
ones
um and to get rid of the ones that it it
remained you haven't seen anything else
uh in you know so far that
will lead to success
yeah so right now that is the only
option for a reasonable cure that has
evidence that it works um that doesn't
mean that there you know there are ways
of
um obviously genetic modification uh
selecting for plants that are resistant
there are there are things um that you
can
basically mutate or deactivate in the
plant so that the thyroid can't traffic
through the plant anymore it can't
replicate
um and then there are
they're more theoretical right now or
you know still in the literature kind of
research zone
some types of molecules that can
actually
encourage the secondary immune system of
the plant to respond specifically
to the viroid
and that would be by activating
something called rnai
which is uh the plant's version of the
secondary immune system now none of
these things as far as i'm aware are
actual products um they they've just
shown some success in
academia in theory
yes yeah so they've shown they've shown
some success you know in a in a
scientific lab that's looking for for
things that could work but as far as i'm
aware nothing's been turned into a
product that people could
i mean it almost seems to me like an
analogy that i've kind of started
settling on as far as like
what it's gonna take to stop this thing
is
um you almost need to start uh treating
your plants like they're in a tattoo
parlor
right
where
you know where where you know you have
every every plant you know is gets clean
gear
yep you know people are you know uh
every time you know that that level of
because obviously all those practices
um in tattoo parlors happen because we
wanted to stop transmission of hiv and
hepatitis and all these other things
that you know because back in the day
that wasn't so so much a worry um and
then it became a big worry and then
basically i believe not that i'm uh
you know familiar with tattoo regulation
but i pretty much believe that you have
to have like autoclaves you have to have
a certain level of sterilization you
can't even operate
um without these this gear
yeah make sure that you're not going to
be a vector
for spreading issues
yes yeah absolutely i think that the
entire industry is going to have to
adopt
standard operating procedures very
similar to that um and we actually to
help people kind of
remember what they need to do we've
actually kind of created this dorky
little acronym called stop
um like stop pathogens up that stands
for um you know sterile environment so
that's the sterilization of your tools
sterilizing between plants sterilizing
your pots you know the surfaces and
everything
testing regularly um so that you know
what's going on and you can catch stuff
early
organizing your facility that's the oh
like
flow of the people organizing where your
clones are sitting so if a mom plant
pops positive you don't have to throw
out every tray because you don't know
where those plants are sitting that came
from that positive mom so thinking about
that um and then the p is to protect
your borders right you don't let
anything in that hasn't been tested
and make sure that you're keeping
infected stuff out
um so if you can if you can go through
that whole stop uh
process then um you stand you know
you're making the right corrections to
sort of keep the thing at bay and limit
your economic exposure to it
so it's really it's basically
you know one of the aspects that people
uh um people get mad about right where
they want to talk about like being a
libertarian or something like that you
know we should have no rules is that
in positive aspect of regulation is it's
there to force people that would never
do it
to someone do it
yes you know um and so one of the one of
the hard parts about regulation for me
right now is that because you don't have
federal legality on any level
every state is its own island
yep so you know if we you know obviously
winning in california would be big
because you know it's it's going to take
much like hiv or something like that at
this point it's it's so
prevalent
that it's going to take years and a
bunch of outreach and a bunch of
knowledge
to sort of slowly beat back the tide for
how much it spread when it was invisible
and nobody could talk to people like you
and figure out how it even moved around
yes yeah it's gonna it's gonna take a
long time and the entire industry
working together and you know i include
people like us in that as well because
you know if you think about other
industries like human diagnostics or the
rest of agriculture you know or even
veterinary medicine there's a bunch of
regulations and rules and standards for
testing labs too
um you know you've got to validate your
tests you need to show
like level of detection
you know all these things like
inclusivity and specificity and positive
predictive value and all these things
that you're supposed to do
um and when we came into this we were
used to working in human diagnostics
where you know i mean there was like
this huge list of things you had to
prove
um and realize that here you know a lot
of labs aren't doing any of those
experiments you know because there's no
standards right now
we need to hold ourselves to a higher
standard too i just i just saw something
proposed and i don't know if it's going
to i don't know exactly remember when
it's going to take effect but they're
starting to push for standardization of
labs for thc and terpenes and stuff
um because there's a lot of shady
business going on uh with that because
there's no standards that people have to
adhere to
yes
yeah and it's unfortunately i mean even
for for tissue culture and testing labs
because there's no standards
some of the you know it's not fair but
some of the responsibility or way to
protect yourself is to
know the right questions to ask you know
and if you if you find a testing lab and
and they you know they wanna you know
you're gonna send your plants there you
can say hey can you send me your
validation can you tell me the
experiments that you did to prove that
your test is accurate or sensitive
enough to detect it
um and a good lab a lab that's that's
you know done its research should be
able to send you a document where it
spells out the experiments they did so
their stuff works i mean in all honesty
having sourced clones for some pretty
big scenes uh in the legal system most
nurseries are only really prepping say
10 to 18
different strains for their season it's
not like they might have a big library
but they're only really they're only
picking so many things to mom up and
offer numbers of
so it wouldn't be that prohibitively
expensive
like in winter for them to test these
things make sure the moms they're
propagating are clean
you know and it's not like they have to
put their entire collection through they
just have to put what's in current
production through correct yeah yeah i
mean if you you know if you if you test
your moms
you know rigorously before you cut those
clones um and then you know even if you
do like a really small random sampling
of five percent of the clones
um
all like the entire sop that we
recommend is a couple bucks per plant or
something like that and um
like if you if you if you take all the
costs together and calculate it per
plant and it's just totally worth it
to not you know to feel confident that
you're selling somebody a good product
because i think nurseries too want to
feel good that they're giving people
high quality clones sure and be trusted
and stuff like that
as a breeder too like i think it's
becoming more incumbent upon especially
learning that there is even a remote
possibility of the transmission from
mother plant to seed stock because right
now i mean
it would be a great solution for the
current problem right now with clones
and the mass you know i mean like people
are all pretty much growing the same
[ __ ] like whether
i mean it's all gelato cookies some form
thereof right but this could really
be a good advocate for more seeds more
seed stock not relying on the same exact
clone more diversity
but that only is great if also the
breeders are also
aspiring to the same level of
testing that everyone else is yeah and i
mean with eight with potentially up to
eight percent transmission to seed
you know of course like just by the la
murphy's law or whatever you know the
one that you pick is your winner
yeah it would be like eight percent or
something
you know you'd be like oh this is the
one i want this has the terps this has
the high this oh it has the latent
but
yeah yeah i mean it's really gonna have
to be this the awareness of this the
testing the you know the preventative
nature is gonna have to percolate into
every faucet
of this entire industry in order for
everybody as a collective to get the
thing under control breeders clone
producers you know you know growers home
growers um
i mean we grew a plant that had hot
plate environment in our basement you
know with no idea just yeah it flowered
and we're like what
it's gonna last a week right so um
so i mean it's it's it's the whole
industry as and we all take
responsibility together and then i think
you know we can start making a dent in
it
yeah it's going to take a lot of
education for the actual um end user and
that's that's always been the hardest
part when it comes to uh like we do a
lot of talk on on cannabis uh genetics
history seed history what have you and
it's not always as important to everyone
like a lot of people have that genuine
idea that it's dank who gives a [ __ ]
what it's called or what what it is but
when it comes to stuff like this there's
a reason that people care there's a
reason that everybody takes is sets
these standards or aspires to these
standards it's because
we we give a [ __ ] we'd like to see these
these genetics carry on in the form that
they are we don't want to lose
everything
and and not paying attention not giving
a [ __ ] not caring not testing is a good
way to end up with
gelato for the rest of your life
you know there's an issue with that and
maybe maybe this is a this is a a good
time to bring it up or whatever but you
know in in regards to other to other
agriculture one of the things that matt
and myself and a number of our friends
are concerned about is that with the
uneven rolling out of legalization right
um not that many people like i said
before care that much about holding on
to old things right um and it's
expensive and time consuming but it used
to be that it was a little bit more
lucrative to do this and that allowed
you to fund you know your passion if it
were right and so what i'm worried about
is that as we grow into this big
industry
um
you know we could lose like the
legalization movement right now is
probably a bigger threat to diversity
than even prohibition was yeah
definitely in my opinion and then we
could be looking for like you were
talking about uh like maybe five or ten
minutes ago and one of your answers
where you were saying you know we might
we can breed for resistance to certain
things we can bring you know you can
look at like the banana or other aspects
of agriculture where some disease came
in and crushed it and they went and
found varieties that resisted that and
then those became the standard and so
cannabis is going to in the next 10 20
30 40 years it's going to encounter
things that need to be dealt with like
that
yeah and we're not going to know where
the answer lies
but it probably lies in some plant that
if it gets lost in the next five years
due to all these things happening
we could end up i mean i was joking
about cookies and gelato you know even
if those are your favorite strains they
might lack genetic
aspects that later on would be critical
for the survival of the plant as some
kind of bug or disease or viroid or
whatever comes along i promise those
those definitely will not be the ones
because they are so susceptible to
everything because this is this this
might sound a little nerdy or something
but forgive me but i read this huge
article on why
um you know 30 40 years ago like when i
was a kid every lots of people hated
brussels sprouts
because they had this really offensive
odor when cooked and so what they did is
they went back they figured out that
there was this one
substance within the brussels sprout
right that led to that aroma so they
went back and they started breeding all
these hundreds of varieties that were no
longer in production but were still
saved in these various banks yes they
grew them all out they looked for which
ones had the least of this substance in
it they started breeding them together
and lo and behold this new improved
brussels sprout that doesn't have that
funny cooked smell
is now on your shelves in the store
where does that [ __ ] exist i've never
seen it i guarantee you no you can you
could type in it anyone could type it
into google and it'll pop up that they
literally rebuilt brussels sprouts from
the ground up because they realize this
aroma was really affecting its sales
and so they were able to go they were
able to go back to the 50s 60s 70s 80s
and grow out hundreds of different
varietals of brussels
looking for just low amounts of this one
compound
and that's the type of stuff that's
going to happen in cannabis in the
future and so we don't have a bunch of
variety
we don't even know what we might need to
go hunt for later
yeah yeah i think that you know the fact
that there isn't a bank like a
centralized bank for all these strains
and cannabis is you know that's one of
the serious issues
right now because you know there's all
sorts of cool stuff out there being made
and unfortunately maybe strains being
lost you know and that all the time
yeah yeah which is and you know hot
plate and vibrates obviously making it
worse right because if you know if you
if it's infected and you you can't
afford tissue culture you don't want to
go that route you know then
it's just kind of you know i have this
thought while we have you on and i know
this isn't um tissue this isn't uh hop
late and related but it is somewhat
related to genetics and so i thought
maybe we could get your your opinion on
it and you can say i i know or i don't
know but there's been some there's been
some literature coming out where it used
to be
um for best practices for a long time
was when you were cloning and you were
taking new mother stock that you always
went for the fast growing tops
the tips of the plants all that and now
there's been some research it seems like
that's been coming out that's been
talking about how the top of the plant
might actually have more like
more mutations
and it would be safer to keep that plant
there would be less mutations lower down
on the plant on the lesser growth that
as newer growth happens there's a
greater chance of something odd
right and for us for a long time you
always went for the healthiest newest
growing tips
we called it the cult of our cut yeah
yeah and then and now it seems like
there's been some evidence coming out
that maybe that's mistaken
and that it might be safer to take new
moms and new new genetic material from
the lower parts of the plant that have
less of a likelihood of some kind of
mutation happening
um is that something you're familiar
with and seen and you could speak on or
no
so i mean i so i've read you know some
of the literature i'm not going to speak
with extreme confidence sure um i don't
know that that body of literature as
well um
i do know that you know so when you're
cutting plants clonal wise you're taking
somatic tissue so somatic tissue is
everything that isn't the germline um
and it the
the the genome of somatic tissue is not
protected in the same way
as um if you were to go through seed
right because yeah germline is is really
protected
um and so those tissues are going to
accumulate more mutations and
when you're cloning a mom you're not
getting a new plant you're you're
actually have the same old plant you
know with the same somatic tissue and
you're just continuing to propagate this
extremely old muscle right yeah um and
so that those somatic mutations over
time will accumulate
um i you know the the people if you're
trying to take the apical meristem area
that area contains new stem cells and so
uh beyond somatic mutation beyond actual
changes in the base pairs you also have
these things called epigenetic changes
which um they're like edits if you think
of of the dna sequence as as letters and
words um epigenetics is like
highlighting in a capital letter maybe
you scratch out a word
so it's stuff overlaid on top
so a lot of those epigenetic changes are
are reset in stem cells especially the
freshly made ones and so you can get if
you grab that top
part or you use those stem cells you can
reinvigorate the plant
um whether or not there's a big
difference in somatic mutations like
point mutations in the dna like the
changes of the letters
dramatic enough to make a difference in
the vigor from the top to the bottom i
don't know
if there's
and what kind of research there is
around that
the ideal of course would be to take a
really healthy vigorous
mom plant and preserve that plant
um you know in tissue culture and stasis
yeah and then you you bring out you take
the cuts and you bring it out and grow
it up and then what you know take your
clones or whatever and then toss that
and always go back to that plant in
stasis because you're gonna have less
somatic mutations um if it's just kind
of hanging out at four degrees yeah
growing that makes sense super ideal
maybe i could get one more non-viroid
question in and see if if what you think
so
in in relation to that i mean keeping
moms healthy and stuff like that there's
a lot of talk in our community about oh
the plant got tired or it got cloned too
much and it suffered genetic drift
or things of that nature
matt and i both have i mean i i have a
number of things that at this point are
you know 20 15 20 25 even 30 years old
right so pretty ancient in cannabis
terms right
um do you feel that that kind of like
when you're taking clones
do you think that if a plant starts to
not perform the way you want to it's
because there's some mutations that
happened or there was some of what you
just spoke about do you believe in it
and do in the genetics itself you know
some some um undesirable changes may
have happened do you think plants get
old
do you think they get tired
if you will i realize that's that's a
bro term but it's thrown around
enormously like the plants just tired
the plant got genetic drift you didn't
clone off it when it was healthy enough
and you ruined it forever it's not the
same as it was it's not like it was five
years ago
um and so if you could talk a little bit
if that's within your knowledge base on
what you think about that kind of thing
that would be very helpful for people as
well
because it's thrown around enormously
yes yes so um
there will be somatic mutations that
happen now this is not
going to be happening on a massive scale
all right so it's
i mean there there can be mutations here
and there but it's not like it's going
to take a completely healthy plant and
turn it into a total diet you know
really fast
um
i've heard a lot of people say things
like that too like it stopped taking up
nutrients or you know like somehow the
plant randomly decided i'm just not
gonna eat anymore whatever
um
i think a lot of times the decline has
to do with pathogens
that you don't know we're in there if
you're if you're experiencing a serious
decline i think it's much more likely to
be some type of pathogen than it is to
be
you know completely suicidal plant yeah
exactly
it's hard to come across that i'm sure
well i mean for us it's like you know
for humans right
we have a you know we have a lifespan
you know so if you if i obviously you
can't clone a person but you know you
clone a teenager and they're they're
very healthy you clone an 80 year old
and they're not that healthy and i
realize it's not the same thing at all
but
i just wonder like you know these plants
are theoretically in nature they survive
a season
yeah and i have clones i have clones
that were are from the early 90s
and so they've survived you know 32
seasons
right yes yeah i mean mutations will
accumulate in you know older somatic
tissue and
you know just like a person over time
those mutations
it's possible that could lead to you
know decreased vigor um i think it kind
of depends on what you're seeing usually
when i when i hear people talk about it
it's like it was fine
last year and now this year it looks
like hell
and i'm like well that's not that time
frame doesn't fit you know slow
mutations accumulating the plant that
sounds like a pathogen
um but do i mean will a plant eventually
get old you know and go you know into
having issues it sounds reasonable to me
but again
i don't know any literature on that so
right now
you know
my thoughts not not data no that's i
mean that's you know we're with this
this podcast is about thoughts you know
and we always try you know when we're
talking about history um because most of
cannabis history is oral
we always try to be like this is what we
know
these are our educated guesses
this is what we're pretty sure of but
there's disagreement amongst people and
it's hard to say what's specific so this
is like right in our wheelhouse of what
we deal with
it really is
you know it it it is because
huh the the general
consensus when it comes to cannabis
whether we're talking about like i said
reversals and and and sexual identity
with cannabis or what have you the
answer is just it varies so heavily it
varies so heavily and there just isn't
enough research yet and i think that's
one thing that
anybody who who delves into the data
just runs into constantly time and time
again
yes there's definitely a lot of unknowns
and very few knowns out there right um
so you know
we've been talking for a long time i
think mostly we got our questions
answered do you feel that way too matt
yeah yeah yeah i do
it's amazing maybe maybe you could plug
you know i noticed a number of times you
mentioned you have some sops or you have
some best practices available on your
website that people could go reference
um maybe you could talk a little bit
just for a second about what you guys do
uh what you have available for people uh
resource wise testing wise that type of
thing so
feel free for a minute to just sort of
lay into all that if you will
yes absolutely um yeah so you know we we
definitely do testing um hop weight and
viroid obviously that's the thing that's
tested the most often we also offer
a panel of
testing for pythium as well as fusarium
we have a panel of viruses and even a
viroid hop stunt viroid which
hasn't been shown to be in cannabis yet
but it has a really high uh large host
range and it has some pretty damaging
effects and hops and so
um you know we're kind of screening
things all the time to make sure that
we're kind of staying on top of stuff
um
among the stuff that i am the most
excited about that was it's hoping
hoping to come out the beginning of next
year is
our on-site testing platform
um so this is one of the ways that we're
trying to help the industry bring the
cost of doing a lot of routine testing
down into a range where people can
afford it
um and so you know we've been working
really hard at
evolving a platform that we created to
test for covid in human saliva
and evolving that into the cannabis
industry starting with testing for
hotplate and thyroid
and the thing that i'm most excited
about it is that we we sat down with the
chemistry that currently existed
isothermal amplification or lamp i think
a lot of people have heard of that
when we started addressing some of the
um
weaknesses of that technology the false
positive rate the low sensitivity the
you know the lack of internal control
and um we were able to improve that
technology quite a lot so we were able
to bring the sensitivity
to the point where you should be able to
detect about 95 of the reactions that
are found by a qpcr in the lab um and
the test can be judged you know it's a
color change test but there is an
internal control so you can tell if
you've done the test incorrectly or if
your plant is negative
and it also comes with
an analysis software so
if you want to do it high throughput if
you'd like to do you know 96 plants at a
time that's totally possible and it'll
give you a digital readout
um and so you know we're really excited
about bringing this out because
we've worked really hard at making this
a really good test and a really good
tool and i think
this is going to help people do the type
of testing that they're going to need to
do to really
start yeah knock it thing down
okay
and then your is your website just uh is
it toomeygenetics.com is it genomics
genomics yes yes
to me genomics.com yeah and hooked on
phonics never came to my house
i mangled at times
you know
i have a little twang but but so that
that's where people could go to read
about the sops that you mentioned and
some of the some of the data and stuff
some of what we know
there's an easy to reference area on
that where you can learn yes and we are
constantly putting up new content and we
try to let people know in instagram when
we're putting new stuff up um
and there's a lot of i'm so
i've just been busy making content and
doing research to help people out so um
you know what we're going to have
some stuff about all the different
viruses and viroids that are known in
cannabis the ones that aren't known what
you know what's the evidence they exist
which should you worry about which not
a lot of a lot of content like that so
um
it's and it's all going up on the
website uh um just to help people figure
out like to navigate all of this because
there's so much contradictory
information that it's it's really
difficult for someone to figure out what
they're supposed to do and what they
should be worried about and what's
actually proven and what what is
somebody just saying something really
confidently even though they don't
actually know
we hear that a lot
yeah like i said for this episode the
amount of people that told me exactly
precisely how transmissible
this
hplv is in cannabis seeds was astounding
how many people were sure you know what
i mean like yeah and so this this whole
thing is very helpful and we hope
anything else that you guys work on
whether it's it's it's these new um
different videos that you put out or
whatnot you'll bring it back to us and
we can have you on again to talk about
more and any new findings with hplv or
anything anything you think the campus
community should know about or be aware
of like this because this is so
important
yes absolutely yeah and we are like i
said instigating research studies in
collaboration with texas a m and i'm
hoping that that's really going to
accelerate you know good science and
real data and and as soon as we find it
i'd love to share with the community
because i think that's what's really
needed here is quality research and a
lot of education so people understand
maybe i could throw this out there just
real quick and this and then we could
end it on that but you just mentioned
texas a m right uh
texas is not cannabis friendly yet um so
you know what do you like you know what
do you think about like obviously like
bringing to bear some of these colleges
and some of these these departments and
stuff like that that have been working
in agriculture and other areas for a
long time is going to be part of the
fabric of our new world
um
how do they work on that in texas
uh do they have to get special like
federal permission or something like
that like texas law doesn't allow any i
mean it's not california it's not
anywhere where they have any kind of
medical or recreational program either
um it's one of the states that's
anti-still
so um in texas a m they work on hemp
varieties um
the you know the the
the difference between a hemp variety
and you know a thc containing variety is
the amount of thc the plant has right
so because it's in the farm bill they
can work on it
they can work they can test all that
stuff via the hemp
and just get around the drug cultiva
drug cultivar aspect or whatever
yes yeah and you know um there are
universities like colorado state
university here in colorado is doing
research um and they actually uh put out
a paper where they did next generation
sequencing on cannabis looking
specifically for what pathogens are
actually there yeah and so there are
universities that are starting to jump
in the ring too
and do research and i i really think
that that's where the answer is is
you know collaborations between you know
academia and industry and open sharing
of information
so that everybody can benefit from
what's being learned um both industry
research and academia research the one
biggest bar between academia that i
found and
and maybe maybe it's a bar between
academia the people who have the money
and the actual cannabis people who've
been doing it you know for decades
is that not often to the people with the
money or the people with the
academia ever encounter the people
behind the scenes that are doing that
are the people that have these
collections that have been doing the
real research and taking real data
trying to keep it as straight as they
can not often do any of these people
ever meet in the same realm so i'm
really hoping that somehow that's that a
bridge is is reached between academia
and the what they would probably term
black market botanists the observational
community
right yes
the observational community yeah that's
a better word for it yes and that you
know what that's one of the major
missions of our company is um i was an
academic scientist my husband was an
academic scientist
half the scientists on our team are
academic scientists and what we really
want to do is bridge that gap and bring
academia and what's going on
you know all the knowledge in the canvas
industry and bring that all together and
really get some some solid data from i
like the testing that you guys are doing
yeah i have issues i have issues with
like the terpene and thc testing because
i think it's so inaccurate and i think
it's led people to assume a bunch of
stuff that's not true
um you know and i don't think we know
yet like why plants why those why
cannabis plants make us high
right like and or why the different
highs happen like you can't look at a
test and be like oh this is going to
give me a racy crawl out of my skin i'm
nervous feeling versus like i want
potato chips and i'm giggly and i'm warm
and happy and comfortable feeling
right right and then you know i do we do
testing all the time and it's like i uh
you know they say that there's like 150
different terpenes and cannabinoids that
they've discovered and they test for
like 30.
yes
there's i think there's a really big
fixation right now on the level of thc
and everybody wants the highest level
possible
but i don't you know
based on personal experience now we're
not talking about data at all yeah yeah
um just because it has a really high
level of thc does not mean that it's
going to give you you know give the
consumer the feeling that they were
going for you know and they're
much more complicated
than that and i think we just don't know
right now how all that stuff interacts
with the human body and with it with
each chemical with each other you know
maybe you know this from academia but i
bet a lot of people don't know this
where because cannabis was is a schedule
one substance right
you needed the dea's permission um to
test for it right and so during the war
on drugs for a long time
um if i if i was a scientist then i went
to the dea and i was like i want to see
if cannabis lowers my blood pressure and
makes me a happier person
they would deny me
and if you went and said hey i want to
test and see if cannabis makes me more
violent more prone to illegal acts and
and raises my blood pressure they would
allow it so what's happened is we have
like 40 or 50 years of cannabis testing
looking for negative correlations and
effects
and barely any looking at the actual
effects or if there could be positives
yeah yeah there's there's very limited
research and um you know i think one of
the most frustrating things and i was
actually discussing this
with a lawyer at a cannabis conference
is that to get something off the
schedule one list you have to do
research to prove that it's not
dangerous but you're not allowed to do
research on things on the schedule one
list so you're you're caught in the
catch-22 yeah exactly the dea was able
to prevent anything from messing with
their narrative
by
them having a bottleneck and you had to
get their permission to actually have
cannabis to test with
yeah
yeah no i i mean and i am really hoping
that
this is going to change because there
there needs to be so much research and
you know from a virology pathogen
biology perspective
having a reservoir of pathogens in a
plant where we're not doing any research
we're not monitoring it that's dangerous
for all of agriculture sure
perspective of of what you think about
the legality
if we're not doing research on it then
everything is is threatened by it
especially with legality they want to
take all the cannabis out of the hills
and mountains where it thrived
and they want to bring it down to the
valleys and the ag land
and next to a lot of other kinds of
crops
correct yeah so i mean we need research
we need to understand what pathogens are
there which ones are coming you know and
how to keep you know all of agriculture
safe like how they do with all the other
crops yeah
yeah well we're about two hours here
which is normally when we cut it i don't
know we i want to thank you so much for
coming on and chatting it was really
engaging uh and it cleared up a lot of
stuff i wrote down a lot of questions
and uh it's good to hear the state of
where we are
you know uh where where we know we are
and where we were worried about and all
that and so maybe matt if you want to do
your end of the end of the evening plug
and then we can all have a good night
that would be great
yeah well thanks a lot for coming on
tessa we really appreciate you and to me
genomics and everything you are doing to
help us uh to help bring us into the new
in this new weird feature that is
cannabis for a lot of us that would that
have been very resistant to it like i i
didn't do a lot of testing myself um
over the years like early on because it
was so expensive and just didn't make a
lot of sense but i think we're at that
point where testing has to be a mainstay
so we appreciate you bringing your
knowledge and and everything you've
learned uh for free here to share with
everyone
absolutely yeah thank you so much for
this opportunity and this was actually a
lot of fun so
but again i i love talking about science
so and teach teaching science so this
was great uh thank you guys so much for
inviting me here well we're happy to
have you um for mel all of us here at
breeder syndicate uh go check out our
patreon breeders patreon uh go to google
type in breeders and patreon you'll end
up there go check out riotsteads.com for
seeds and reversal spray and that will
be uh this will be put up on youtube
shortly and as always thank you very
much for your friday night
much appreciated
bye everyone bye everyone