thank you
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not soja breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
hello everyone and welcome to breeders
Syndicate reviews
today we will be looking at a strain
from Santa Cruz goat farm and it is his
Afghani train wreck the first strain
we're going to check out is Afghan rails
from Santa Cruz goat farm
so as I first look at the buds it's very
very dense especially for a train wreck
hybrid but it's not as dense as say a
cookies or a kush or an OG uh
looking at it it's very very resinous
lots of trichomes amazing resin
production as as you usually find in
train wreck hybrids train wrecks a a
very nice resin producer though it does
have short resin glands and stalks
um now the first smell I smell
when breaking it up
there is a soapiness that is like OG but
it's not OG like I wouldn't smell this
and immediately go that's got OG in it
it's it's it's an old Afghani type smell
that I usually associate with old
Afghans
um
there's also a lot of funk there's some
skunkiness to it
and again typical of old Afghans I
believe this Afghan is supposed to be
from 1988 an old Santa Cruz uh special
um so yeah that's that's I mean it's got
the earthy tones it's even got some
chocolate
um lots of Funk it's got clean tones
almost like laundry along with the
soapiness which is really unique it's
it's got a really unique terpene profile
and at first glance
um you know it looks like an old Afghan
type but the complexity of the terpene
profile really really stands out so I'm
pretty impressed so far let's give this
a smoke
so when doing reviews I always like to
make sure whatever piece I'm smoking out
of is completely clean just as if the
day it was bought you know totally clean
no resin I want to be able to taste
everything I want to I want to taste all
the complexities I want to be able to
smell the complexities as I bring the
pipe up to my mouth there's a lot to it
but the main important thing is keep
your water clean keep your piece clean
if you're going to be doing reviews and
really trying to figure out what's going
on with the high and and how a strain
interacts with your body best
so let's check it out
so I can taste the soapiness
there was almost a tobacco note that
came with it which is really weird I've
never really tasted that in cannabis
um
the little bit of terpenoline from the
the train wreck really does give you a
mouthful of flavor it's very special
very unique
um the highs very quick very quick I
think I can already feel it sitting in
the back of my eyes so like most Afghans
do it does have a very narcotic body
high type it immediately sits right
behind my eyes and now remember
everybody is going to feel the different
reaction due to their brain chemistry
and how certain cannabinoids affect a
person everybody's brain chemistry is
different so when you go into a
dispensary and someone tells you that a
plant will always affect you a certain
way indica's always do this sativas
always do that please don't take it at
face value there's no one who can tell
you exactly how any any strain will
affect you at any certain time of the
day I mean certain strains I can smoke
in the morning the first smoke of the
day and it'll affect me much different
than it would right before bed so that's
that's something to keep in mind too
um so yeah I give this a 5 out of five I
love old afghanis I love train wreck and
uh I'll be growing this this will be in
my garden very soon and I'll be doing a
selection so uh shout out to pop from
Santa Cruz goat farm killer Bud killer
grow killer breeding and I'm looking
forward to doing other reviews on the uh
other herbs dropped including the Santa
Cruz Blue Dream crossed a train wreck
so keep your ears peeled for that one
if you're interested in picking up Santa
Cruz goat farm genetics please check out
riotsseeds.com in our feminized section
we have all of his train wreck crosses
uh one of which was the Afghan rails
that I spoke about and the Santa Cruz
Blue Dream crossed a train wreck so uh
definitely check it out right seeds.com
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeder syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds
foreign
[Music]