foreign
much better hey Rings what's up what's
going down let's see if we can't get
Frank on here now
um
God what a pain in the ass that was I
guess my my right seats account's been
reported
a bunch and isn't working anymore
correctly now we need to get nothing all
right
or maybe he's trying to go live on his
trying to figure this out
so let me see
one second I might have to pause it just
a text no no problem
can you hear me
I can hear you
yeah okay good
all right not so there you are
invite
join in
it should work
can you not get the invite not so
this is ridiculous to smooth this silk
always
I don't know can no one else hear can
anybody hear only one person's like
responding about that so hopefully
no you also cannot join
not so good do a live and we'll try to
join that one then because there's some
[ __ ] up [ __ ] going on
laughs
all right
not so anybody
let me get what's going on with it
request to request to join NASA I'm here
ah there he is I have no idea what
happened we got a [ __ ] show well I
don't know my other account wasn't
letting everybody join for whatever
reason so well that was uh yeah smooth
to Silk right there you go there you go
so everybody can hear it seems like
people can hear so that's positive yeah
hopefully people pop on
without kids can you how many different
pastel colors of headphones do you own
a few I got a few pretty pairs of
headphones because every week you're
busting out new these are old these are
those are all these another week
and then I also have these for these for
indeed
so people are joining yeah it seems like
Well normally that was that was eight
minutes of [ __ ] up
yeah but I don't I don't know that most
people are gonna know to come on this
account
to uh watch so it may be a lower uh
account watching but you could get this
[ __ ] let's get this [ __ ] done covering
your microphone no nothing's covering
the microphone or maybe this is maybe
the mic's going through this is that
better that is better pick it up it is
better it is better so it's running a
mic through this stupid thing okay makes
sense
for doing that all right so today this
week's uh topic we're going to talk to
our buddy rings around his own anus
we're going to talk about farming and
Mendo you guys are old buddies
um he's been in Mendo uh uh a few years
longer comes from the Midwest he's a
stray nerd like us and we want to hear
about his adventures in old mendoville
so you want to kick it off Frank you can
introduce yeah so you know when um when
Matt and I were discussing like this
whole podcast
um like kind of the whole theme or
purpose of it really was to sort of like
share in a way uh how we Talk Amongst
each other all the time right like
because we you know and and bring bring
a little bit of that to like the
discourse or whatever right so
um so we're gonna talk about world
problems yeah
my buddy my buddy
is one of the people that I've talked
about uh all kinds of stuff for a long
time we live in the same small little
town uh we both come from the Midwest
like homie said
um he's actually been out here probably
four years longer than me or something
like that so over a quarter century and
so we've kind of both seen uh you know
like a lot of the different eras that I
think people would consider I don't know
if you want to consider him legendary or
just old
you know but also when we were talking
last show about like a lot of hobbyist
reading and a lot of multi-stage
breeding and learning about your plants
uh Rings is someone that has been you
know basically when we when you first
got here in the 90s
um that was the way it wasn't a clone
world it was a seed world
right yeah well not yeah I don't even
remember any popular clones for quite a
while
you know when I got here it was all seed
you'd hear about some indoors
here and there you'd see little batches
of indoor
here and there but there's a couple
lights
you know little bits yeah
and you know so there's an aspect there
where
um nowadays people view the kind of
breeding like that used to be done
around Mendo a lot just to have beans uh
something sort of mysterious
right well you know Rings basically
never left that era
in the sense of uh he always he has been
breeding kind of for what he likes
plants he likes things that interest him
you know regular breeding no feminized
reversals or anything like that maybe
some accidents now and again
um and just looking at what plants show
you
right so it really does tie into what
we've been talking about but it also
ties into like a whole era
um like pre-215
you know
um and even like after 215 passed it
probably took what Rings like
five or eight years
for I remember like
2002 people feeling like they actually
could lean on
215 even though it passed in whatever
year nobody thinks yeah nobody thought
they were going to be able to grow in
their yard not get [ __ ] with yeah so
they were still you know keeping it
mellow keeping it on the download but
then some friends of mine let her rip
they just went for it
and cops came people tried to rip it off
cops got called and the cops left the
plants and then we were oh it's a
[ __ ] green light
and yeah that was a major green light
so that was great though I mean for the
first time we were
putting them out in the sun and not
worried
and realizing the potential
that a plant could get real big so
chronologically speaking when you were
in Wisconsin what you were seeing out
there was what type of strains like
mostly were you seeing the afghanis
proliferated out there still pretty
heavy by the time you started
yeah I didn't really know I knew a few
few some of my older brothers buddies
were growing little gardens in their
apartments and whatever but
I didn't really know any outdoor Growers
there but you'd see the weed once in a
while come through
yeah uh but it was it seemed like it was
pretty standard kind of Afghani I mean
that climate back there you are limited
you know yeah that's true you could do
so
man what's that what were you seeing in
Wisconsin strain wise
you know people would say things like
Danny
I mean it was simple so basic not named
like this they were just stoked if you
got something that wasn't compressed
yeah right you know yeah and there was
there was two kinds of weed basically
there was green Mexican and brown
Mexican yeah and the level of
compression could vary widely
the best stuff was green and lightly
compressed the some of the worst stuff
was incredibly compressed and very Brown
yeah and strain names I mean you know
they just uh yeah I think I think uh
maybe maybe I'm speaking but
barely anyone knew what I was doing when
I lived in Chicago and was growing weed
absolutely
you were in a major populated area I was
in a rural area there was
it was all bad you could yeah they I
mean I remember just
people hearing about my friends and I
smoking weed and then like one of my
buddies got busted drinking and driving
and when he was in the cops they're like
we know you and that guy are selling
weed and oh you know I mean it was like
we were we were buying like a quarter
ounce once a month and smoking it in
one-hitters
we were so far away but I mean we were
like
dealers in our hometown because of that
of course people are asking about
various Imports I can't speak for rings
but we both come from the Midwest he's a
little farther north than I was and he
was Rural and I was City but I literally
saw Mexican and when the Grateful Dead
came into town there would be some kind
bud
there was no Jamaican Imports there was
no Colombian there was no tie there was
no anything named there was brown and
green Mexican I remember I got Thai
stick once and it was literally tied
with a string on a stick but I was very
fortunate where
I met the I I like to say the right dirt
bag
hippie biker types
that were older
and they weren't gonna smoke the worst
Brown weeds so they they had networks
set up somehow or whatever I was at
least getting like pretty
decent green weed pretty much from the
start
but that was I mean there was no weed
seen in my high school it was all just
drinking and there was a couple of
Stoners but there was no scene there at
that time
it just it just wasn't you know
go ahead you moved from northern
Wisconsin to our neck of the woods
Mendocino County you said was it was it
94 94 1994. right at Harvest time I had
no idea what I was even getting into I
just knew one person
came out here
within 20 minutes I was standing next to
a pot plant watching naked girls swim in
a pond it was it was like walking right
into a wet dream
I was already very into the hobby
I already had all the seed catalogs
memorized because I was buying High
Times and stuff and I had grown a little
um we've wired up a 175 metal halide my
friend rigged one together we had a few
plants and uh that I had saved some
seeds from uh some decent weed and we
grew them
some failed attempts at growing some
some Mexican seeds or whatever outside
that just went to [ __ ]
but yeah I mean it was very minimal
before I moved out here what was your
what was your impetus for coming out
here
I actually thought I was going to end up
in like New Mexico I kind of had dreams
of desert living when I left there and I
knew one guy here
and he was one of my hookups for good
weed
and
um mushrooms acid whatever
he
he he left I saw him and he was like I'm
moving out to California if you're ever
there here's my aunt's number she'll
know where I am and I got a hair up my
ass I was like I I had been all over the
country traveling with my family growing
up but I had never been in California
state line so
I I just thought I'd swing through but
like I said within 20 minutes all kinds
of just on to me unimaginable things
were unfolding in front of my eyes I was
just like
weird hippies you know I grew up in a
pretty conservative in a box type of
place there wasn't a lot of various
lifestyle choices and
diversity or anything like that so it's
like where I'm raised I get it this [ __ ]
is entertaining right away I mean
stories of weird hippies in the
mountains and Pagan groups and old
communes I was just like [ __ ] this is
entertaining right here
right and for me naked girls were a big
bonus
Francis it would have been the other but
oh yeah I see why you guys are drawing
that
so yeah but I mean a lot of times people
people think people think when they hear
a Mendocino County because now it's
super famous for growing weed
it's not that it wasn't famous for
growing weed already it's just that most
people's like earliest memory of like
Mendo now is like two is the two is the
medical era yeah when you had like a leg
to stand on and you could kind of there
was sort of a cat and mouse between
things but when we both first moved out
there it was a totally different world
in the sense of
like uh everybody that did it kept it
pretty quiet
there was a there was a number of people
in town that had successful businesses
and stuff that did it but they kept real
quiet about it it was done in the Hills
it was done tucked away people didn't
want people to know their money came
from wheat yeah showing the [ __ ] yeah
not so and I were talking about
the successful guys were driving beat up
old trucks you would have never known
they weren't there was no flash that's
for sure yeah we were we were talking
just the other day about it and there
would be guys that like were worth a lot
of money
and their truck would be old and a
little rusted and have a few dents or
whatever
and then like they pop the hood and the
whole thing is Chrome and super Cherry
souped up they've got a souped up like
they've got great suspension they've got
all this nice [ __ ] but it's like they
could drive through our crap little town
and look normal
yeah right because nobody wanted to
stand out nobody wanted to get targeted
and then even when 215
um it took like he said it took a number
of years for people to get a sense of
what you could do
yeah you know most of the people I
learned from and were was exposed to
they were older already then and had
been doing it for a long time
so they they they were they didn't even
they didn't even have
they didn't even have a fancy engine in
their truck you know they were just
chill they were just glad to to be
living up in the mountains and having a
home and
and be hanging out and being more
comfortable than a person working at one
of the local businesses or whatever they
were they were living good eat and go
Gotta realize too that Mendo was pretty
famous for being a huge logging
community
but that had sort of Fallen apart in the
80s and so I would classify it as pretty
poor when I first arrived very poor very
poor very run down so like even having
money was unusual like everybody that
had money was from some established
well-known family that owned businesses
in town yeah
you know yeah there was no there was
hardly even any weed around here
honestly I mean even though it was Mendo
and whatever
it would run out and if you were holding
something decent you were the man I mean
there really wasn't a lot
then no you know if you if you had two
or three patches in the woods and you
got away with one of them and you got 30
pounds
you were like loaded down with cash you
had a lot of loot you had whatever you
needed that year you were doing good you
were stoked a hundred and twenty
thousand bucks in 94 would have been you
know that's like that'd be like having
500 000 bucks now practically they'll
pay the prices were at that time for
land and homes and
stuff like that
yeah yeah those people
but yet they couldn't show it off so it
was kind of you didn't really know who
was holding I mean natso and I were
talking the other day and he met some
guy that had copious amounts
and he was living in a Shack in walking
around in his underwear all the time I
mean it's actually like I was telling
him it's probably like the wealthiest
person in wheat I've ever met
like I'm not even exaggerated I knew
exactly who he was talking about he was
the wealthiest person I I think I've
ever met in weed and he had a bunch of
huge scenes that I don't want to
describe but he had this like this queen
like black and white poly Shack
that like stretched like in between the
trees with rope right and he had a
really nice like teak wooden table in
this thing and he slept in it and he
walked around like he had a huge like
multi-pack of tighty whities and it was
hot up there and he would walk around in
his tighty whities and his boots and he
lived in a visqueen shack up on the Rock
and he literally like I mean he and he
sold like unbelievable I mean he made so
much money
yeah you know but it was just that was
his life he ran various things he didn't
leave the hill he and it was just hot
and he didn't like it so he walked
around and
you know it almost think you'd almost
think that like he escaped from like a
mental institution I can't I can't blame
the man I walk around like that in my
house and I'm not me too I'm still I'm
carrying the torch too but yeah I mean
in a way it's like if you busted that
guy like farts but you know he had
nothing
you know I mean he might own 15
properties yeah and have like
underground grows and generators and
this and that and everything else but
it's like you know it's like if they
came and got tried to get him it's like
he didn't have sports cars he didn't
have a nice big house he didn't have
boats he didn't have anything that they
could find
like and that's that's kind of like what
I was thinking about when when you were
talking about that Rings was like the
real Old-Timers around here
they just like to live up here and they
liked having enough money so they
weren't poor
and they didn't occur yeah they'd go on
vacations
yeah you'd meet a lot of like popular
kids and they traveled the world and
stuff but they weren't flashing anything
else like that was like their luxury
like their parents would help them
travel
so that was like that was more like
flashing wealth and Mendo kind of became
more of a 215 era thing definitely
because you had to like to stand on with
the with your you're legitimate yeah it
was the medical card to flash in the 90s
I think I would put it it was
Unthinkable I only know um a few people
that were probably dumb enough to flash
in the 90s and they ran a um
some kind of Hollywood Mansion they're
bringing actors in and out to show them
their little tiny [ __ ] grow I think
one of them went to jail and had Woody
Harrelson bail him out that's the only
people I could think of that were dumb
enough to flash like that like bring
people into a mansion with grows and
yeah they're not very common one guy
before I even moved here I mean they've
had documentaries about that guy and I
can't remember his name
he was one of the biggest importers in
the country he was bringing everything
in through the bay and he built on
Robinson Creek Road he built this big
mansion with like watchtowers on it and
hidden rooms and stuff and that happened
before I got here it was rural like his
house was pretty hidden
but it was pretty extravagant and he
went down he went down big and he's out
now
he actually just bought that Mansion
back from this guy I knew who owned it
but there was there was a um
maybe people should know that that like
so when I first moved out here I had my
my I literally had like just like rings
I had one friend that lived a little
north of Ukiah and that was like sort of
my landing spot where he got me situated
in the community
um and I thought it was going to be a
bunch of like Grateful Dead hippies you
know and back to the Landers and like it
was like I was from the city and it was
all these country people that lived
clean and beautiful and I got here and
there was some hippies but there was a
lot of weirdos there was a lot of
rednecks there was a lot of poverty
meeting a person that like like you
that just seemed mellow and like nice
and stuff was kind of rare it was a
rough crowd a lot of it I mean the
hippie side of it was pretty mellow
but I mean most of it was pretty Outlaws
I mean as far as quantities went those
those were people way out in the boonies
and they had guns and they were
you know I mean Tales of shooting at
helicopters and yeah
people out in the boonies growing a lot
they're gonna always been a way where
we'd allowed a certain amount of people
that have like a lot of [ __ ] mental
illness anger management and various
other ticks to like survive well but not
have to like like Smooth those issues
out
and so people were suspicious you know
there's aspects of uh of that you know
in the sense of it was just very
eye-opening like like once once logging
left this place was poor and so not only
we people think it was a weed Mecca
before the Mexicans took it over like
Northern California was also like where
lots of little batches and meth got
cooked so there was a whole underbelly
of meth people and there was a little
bit of a blending of the two communities
but not always but but you know there
was there there was various motorcycle
groups there was all kinds of weirdos
that owned land in the Hills I mean
because girls not populated growing a
lot of weed was always a lot of work and
I remember people way back then talking
about like hiring meth heads because
they would work you just keep keep them
High they'll dig 200 holes in the woods
yeah people steal all your [ __ ] when
you're not alone yeah and like you know
I mean maybe not if you had uh I mean
people did things like
tight Mountain lines in the middle of
their patch and chained them up to trees
I mean there was that checks out I mean
the stories
the Deep Well of bizarre
stories in this part of the world is
it's troubling funny you know very a lot
of disturbing stories you know it's I
mean actually it hasn't been very
violent around here the last few years
the murders
the partners shooting each other
seems like it's really tamed down
finally it has you know I mean you know
there was an aspect where there's
someone even older than us that I hope
to be able to bring on soon uh that can
speak of like the 80s but by the time
rings and I got here
you know Camp had been sort of hammering
the county for a good 12 15 years right
um you know there was a lot of back and
forth between that there was a lot of
sort of secret society like people
really kept to it to themselves it was
really hard to get accepted into certain
groups
um it was very it was a little paranoid
at a time and then on top of that
um you know let's face it right like so
you're getting four or five thousand
dollars a pound for your weed and you
have a whole bunch of money and it's
dark and it's cold and it's Mendo and
you're bored and it's winter
and so there was all kinds of scandalous
you know substance use
which was fun and some of which had
negative connotations for whole little
groups of people you know yeah YouTubers
on on some of the old Growers I met when
I moved out here they were like
in the 70s or whatever late early 80s
they'd be like things started getting
[ __ ] up they'd be like that's when
people started trading their weed for
Coke and then it became trading it for
meth you know and it just started
getting funky you know one of the first
guys I worked with told me basically
that exact story that when you get 4 500
or 5 000 a pound for anything that you
grow that's decent right he said you get
bored in the winter and then the one guy
gets a kilo of cocaine or something
right and he goes and he goes then the
problem is is five years later
everyone's cheating on everyone else
yeah you know people are messed up
people are this people are that and when
you got in trouble back then you either
went to jail for two or three or four
years usually or you had to knock on
your friends there really wasn't a
defense
you know so there's an aspect there of
like you know I mean there's yeah there
was you know there was there was opiates
there was every problem you could
imagine existed on some scale there
wasn't that many people yeah right so it
wasn't like it but there was there was
Partiers of all kinds and there was
people that were definitely into a bunch
of bad things sure
um and uh you know weed was a way to
survive and so like maybe on a positive
note
uh before we get too dark on that level
it does set the stage because I mean I
I'll tell a very quick story I remember
like I was hiking with friends and we
were up on this Majestic trail and I was
still pretty like new from from the
Midwest so even just Hills excited me
you know like big expansive trees and
stuff and I'm like oh I'm tripping and
I'm like looking out over this thing and
it's all beautiful and I look down and
there's like dozens of cars
that people it was like a spot that
people drove up to and just to get rid
of their trash they would push their car
off the ledge yeah and it would just
roll down the hill and and like the
hills were littered with this [ __ ] yeah
I was amazed when I moved out here like
every time you found a beautiful turn
off to stop and look at the scenery
there'd be like just trash below you
every time
because a lot of the country people
would just take their trash and drive
and be going down the road at night and
just bags of trash they would just throw
out their vehicle off off the hill bears
and so people so I was shocked because I
thought it was going to come out coming
from the city I was like I'm gonna come
to this clean pristine Place weed
growing hippies redwoods Oregon food
organic food all that and that was all
there in bits and pieces yeah but there
was all this other stuff that I had
never seen and you know it makes sense
because you know that that stuff really
started stopping when the weed money
really started changing the game to the
point where there wasn't so much poverty
yeah most of the houses that we bought
or got into or the land was very cheap
um most of it was very run down people
would do little indoors or do outdoors
and they would end up fixing the
bathroom fixing the roof putting on a
deck just taking like a falling down 50s
Farmhouse yeah that they bought on a
handshake deal and every weed crop
improving it yeah so many funky houses
out in the country around here
yeah tons I mean now there are a lot of
them are all fixed up and nice because
it had 20 years of of money coming in
even if they're shitty still they're
worth a ton of money at this point you
know it's true you know so but they
maybe we could talk about for a second
just to get go from like the Ambiance of
the area to like what were the what were
the the strains that you were seeing
when you first came out here and then
obviously like you know
um just so people know there was there
wasn't a lot of there wasn't a lot of
names back then a lot of individual
families and friends had different seed
lines maybe you could get a cockamami
story out of a few of them about what
had happened in the past yeah but
everyone Grew From seeds so people got
seeds from their friends and then every
two or three years or something they'd
be like oh I need some more seeds I
better like take some of these males in
the bushes and pollinate some of my
females yeah
it seemed like a lot of like the ranches
around here there'd be like
a couple of people that were into making
seeds and everybody else just got seeds
from them that was pretty common too
there was some people that were just
into it into that side of it
you know and everybody else would just
go to them buy starts from them or get
seeds from them that was pretty common
too there was there was still nerds back
then before we came out
yeah there was they were just harder to
find yeah you know and Matt and I have
had a lot of experience too with like
even people that we would consider to be
nerds today
you ask them about specifics of when
they were young
and they just don't have it yeah
they don't they just don't they just
don't remember it turned out good or it
didn't and even if it turned out bad it
was still worth the same um obnoxious
amount of money
you know it's still all sold yeah one of
the good things is it led to a lot of
diversity yeah right so I just want
people to know before we start chatting
about this that like lineage was often
hard to come by there was some like
poorly sourced legends about a lot of it
but everyone that was growing weed had
seeds
yeah and there was a lot of different
Hill seeds there was a lot of different
neighborhoods that had different seeds
because like Rings said there'd be one
or two guys that was like the
neighborhood nerd
and they would do breeding and then the
friends would get seeds from them and
stuff and so there was just a lot of
diversity yeah yeah you know a lot of
people just didn't even realize they
could keep a male and make seeds and it
wasn't wasn't that hard
you know they just they just thought it
was taboo to even have a male
anywhere around even though they could
have sold their seated [ __ ] for big
bucks even back then too as long as it
was green and trim decent
you know everything it's just that's
just the way it was then I mean you
can't say like
I mean that's why like with being into
the genetic side it was like when you
saw something good it wasn't all the it
wasn't even that often you know so if I
got something good I would be like
where'd you get this can I get this
I don't care where these are I'll drive
anywhere to get these seeds you know
just to try you might go you might drive
up to Oregon to get some seeds and come
back and pop them they're all Herms
you didn't you didn't know you know
so yeah and most people didn't keep we
lost most people didn't keep clones over
the winter
so it was like people would pop a
certain amount of seeds in Spring and go
through a process of sexing them and try
to figure out how many they thought they
could get away with yeah and then plant
females where they had to put them I
mean even I have a buddy who's uh who
was telling me like even some of the
first like hundred lighters he worked at
in southern humble right uh indoors they
were like literally like they made beds
on the floor and they planted seeds and
they went in and they cut the males off
at the base
yeah because it wasn't it wasn't a clone
world yet yeah so that's what they knew
yeah I mean you hear a few stories like
like that orange thing you had yeah
Nintendo yeah being like an old clone
that was super rare I'm gone yeah that
was that was that's kind of unusual tell
us about some of your first breeding
projects that's what I want to know
about I want to hear about some of these
breeding projects this arrange what's
some of the first stuff you worked with
when you were actually like like I have
a [ __ ] goal I want to I want to end
up with XYZ like what's some of the
first stuff you worked with yeah it was
just looking at things like in the way
they appeared you know at that time I
was young and
and uh you know dense and shiny was
pretty pretty desirable you know and
it's funny to think back of how
sometimes you'd see something great and
you'd be like oh that stinks I would
never grow that but man does it smell
good because you didn't want you didn't
want your [ __ ] found
yeah and uh so it was more about just
like finding something
that would come in before the weather
that was chunky and decent to work with
you know we didn't want Sour Diesel buds
at that time even yeah you know we
didn't want to do that kind of trimming
so it was really about just making
something that was decent to work with
not super needy to it like you're
sticking [ __ ] way up in the mountains
and visiting it here and there yeah
you're keeping a close lengthy eye on
everything so you you didn't want
something that like I remember the first
time I grew like a skunk one type of
thing we put it up in the hills every
time we went up there it was [ __ ]
yellow
it just wanted [ __ ] you know and some of
this stuff we we had going would be dark
green and happy with virtually nothing
it would do all right I mean the plants
weren't big they didn't need a lot
because we weren't growing these
monsters they were yeah Quarter Pounders
under the
in the bushes you know yeah so they
didn't need a lot we would just bring a
bag of baguano up in the hills and some
water holding crystals and and the hope
that things went all right you know
water rules could be a dream dude water
water crystals used to be huge yeah
because you weren't able to get to yours
because most people hiked into their
site and it was far enough away from
your house or it was on uh because if
you only went once a week in the your
little water line some an animal [ __ ]
it up or something and they went six
days without water and 105 degrees
wasn't cool I mean we I I've said this
before but there's a there's a a big
like uh AG store I guess you'd call it a
garden store in Willits in Mendo called
spare time and they used to have you
used to walk into their front door and
they would have them you know they would
have a six foot tall stack of cases of
camo spray paint yeah because what he
was just saying is if you use soft poly
the rats the wood rats various other
Critters they'd smell the water and it's
so dry they'd come and they'd chew
through your poly to get [ __ ] hate
rats together you know to get water and
then all of a sudden your plants aren't
getting wet you know so people would use
some people would use PVC but then it
was white so you needed to spray paint
it to make it look like the ground cover
yeah right before you put it together
because otherwise like you know and then
they couldn't they could smell it but
they couldn't chew through it yeah it
was amazing how
how Camp was back then too like they
would find like they took their time and
scanned the hill so closely they would
find
like a few little plants in the bushes
they'd take their time and just work
areas I remember diving in the bushes
when I first moved I I thought it was
cool as [ __ ] like all the government is
trying to find people like us we're
diving in the bushes and I thought that
was cool as [ __ ] yeah
I mean there's an aspect too people
don't get that's why like everybody take
a shot every time not so says aspect
you people would hide them in the trees
like on little on on I never did that
but I had friends who would put them on
on you know raised Platforms in the
trees because the the uh helicopters
they'd be looking at a certain line and
they a lot of times their eyes would
miss it or they'd put them along the
line of a tree line or manzanitas you'd
hollow out branches and you'd still
leave the top cover and hopefully they
would make it but they were after it so
hard
um you know you really had to be careful
and then you would take different ways
to get to your spot often like it's not
like you drove your vehicle there or you
drove your ATV or whatever you didn't
even want to walk no the same pathway
because they'd see the path from the air
so you would take different routes to
get there and get in and get out you
know yeah you walk on the animal Trails
real carefully to not make them look
weird from the air
yeah it was fun to try to camouflage
things and and it was fun to be a little
ninja I mean we weren't even doing much
it was just worth something and and
really
we were just into it you know we were
into the plants we wanted to have some
we were willing to hike up mountains to
get a very little a bit you know it was
y'all are [ __ ] nuts dude I couldn't
take that kind of heart trauma like
going up and watching like you know
eight of your big [ __ ] rips like you
plant one for thieves plant one for pigs
and plant one for you like that's the
theory [ __ ] that I mean that was so
dramatic
even in spring when you're like setting
it all up
that's when you're digging your holes or
you're bringing in your if you're not if
you're not using the right the Earth
there that's when you had to hike in
your you know your your your soil you
had to bring in your amendments so you
could feed even if you were using native
Earth it was hard to feed on nothing run
your water lines maybe drill a spring
and then you're crawling in the bushes
carving out little spaces for your
patches that whole drill is spring like
people my age like from California we
don't even get what the [ __ ] that means
drill a [ __ ] spring yeah put in a
spring box so so the spring collects
water in the spring box and then run
piping from that box sometimes hundreds
of yards especially if you're downhill
you would try to find water witching
[ __ ] to find the spring that's how you
do this I mean there was little springs
on properties you would you would like
build a box and then just rig up a pipe
going out the end it would collect a
little bit and just slowly trickle I
mean a lot sometimes we had them feeding
little tanks or something but because
you needed Springs because you it's not
like you could put in a well
because even if you had solar or
something like that they'd see it yeah
so I don't even like I just don't get
how people found Springs out in the
[ __ ] mountains like how did you find
these things under the ground for wet
spots I met people that knew Rings were
you know or or found properties where
there was like little hidden parts of
the property that had a little water
source yeah yeah and basically a spring
box is just digging a hole big enough to
put a certain size like man-made box in
there that's going to collect the water
and let it build up to a usable amount
and then you can drain it out one end
and then the gravity feed yeah gravity
feed it yeah for the most part yeah it's
up started
low low grade to somewhere it was tricky
to get the bubbles out of those lines I
remember working on that very hard
yeah lots of hiking back and forth to
see if it worked now or not you know
that's a great question was there ever
turf wars over Springs
[ __ ] man hell yes there was I was
thinking about that I was thinking about
that when
when 215 happened I mean a lot of I you
don't hear this talked about very much
so all these water sources in the
mountains people kind of had them that
was kind of their Turf you know they had
those spots and when 215 happened
the cartels came with guns and pretty
much kicked everybody off their spot and
what it but 215 was allowing all the
people that had those spots to do it
right in their [ __ ] yard then so it
was like a little transfer
of territories or whatever Out of the
Woods yeah
but I mean people used to there used to
be a thing where you know I mean people
would have arguments over how far away
the patch should be from your home so
that if they did Camp it they would just
take the patch and not mess with you
yeah and there would be arguments about
how much you should hike and how far
away
um and so it's not like it was just like
off in the bushes you know 100 yards
from your house a lot of these things
you'd hike into or hike up to and it
would be a good distance away and that's
why the little how like the little
Trails were so like we really had to
think about that stuff you did if they
saw a trail they'd just walked right to
it and there would be you know you had
to really ninja that stuff
and be careful you know so yeah it's
like I remember like a lot of times
especially when I was hiking up like uh
dry amendments or something like that in
the spring I would just want to puke
because you're like going uphill and
you've got like a 50 pounds of food on
your back and you're hiking and then you
know you get to mid-summer and it
doesn't even feel like anything because
you're in shape and you've done it for
months super in the beginning and that
was as a young buck I'd be like oh my
God this is [ __ ] rough so another
thing that's kind of funny that people
should know is that for me it's like you
use something like uh like fish meal or
bone meal or blood meal or something and
then all of a sudden you realize like oh
that attracts Bears yeah
you know yeah and bears are some kind of
big animal comes in looking for what
smells
because you've got composting fish meal
or composting crab meal or whatever and
then a big ass bear starts to dig in
your soil and ruins your patch yeah
because you use the wrong kind of
fertilizer yeah I think the people I
learned from right away was it was like
bakuano right away because they were
kind of hippies
but then a lot of people who didn't care
about that kind of stuff they use those
little osma coat pellets oh yeah balls
and they would just put those in there
and that would be done all they had to
do was just Add Water
time release I mean there were some
people that once you I mean and I'll say
this too there was people that had
established spots that they were able to
do small patches in year after year and
so some of those people had some really
nice soils some really nice holes they
amended them well every year so it was
like an active organic situation and so
there was some better pot that came out
of those well in the line it up sucked
the water was really good
really affected the weed back then too
people aren't using city water
treated water it was just like Mountain
Water you know and just like any other
living thing
the quality of water is it makes a
difference you know it had minerals in
it it had little bits of stuff in it
that's where I learned too that the old
timers always taught me that pot was
like a lateral root growth plant and so
they would always say like in the bushes
it's better to dig like an 18 inch or a
two foot deep hole that was wide
rather than one that was deep you know
they're like the plant's going to want
to go wide and you'll get more weight so
like make a shallow a depression and
fill it in rather than just digging like
a I mean there was people that would dig
like four five six foot deep holes but
that would have been me
dude it's such a [ __ ] you're like
crawling in the manzanitas with like a
shovel that can strap to your back and
then you're underneath there and you're
just like chomping at them six feet with
the tiny little and then you gotta like
that and then glad I was young at that
stage I mean because nothing [ __ ]
mattered you know yeah you just got it
done or whatever but it wasn't easy and
then you had to remove this the you know
like because a lot of it a lot in Mendo
is red clay it's not like we have like a
ton of black loamy deep rich Earth that
you can just like plant into it's like
mountainous and Rocky and clay-like and
so you definitely had to add some stuff
to it and amend it if you wanted to get
anywhere it's not like you could just
like dig a hole and plant yeah
yeah let's get into strains guys people
want to hear about the strains oh God
okay so it's always so funny because
without clones to reference people it's
like you're just telling them about a
ghost
you know
like a little bit a little bit you know
but I had a moment today where I was
harvesting some volunteer accidental
thing that popped up in my yard
and uh the rain got it it was the only
early thing I had and it it had some big
soft colas on it and the rain kind of
started getting to them a little
botritus yeah
and I'm smelling the piece I picked a
few days ago and I'm smelling it I'm
like this smells just like afghan's 30
years ago what was it do you remember
what the volunteer was from yeah it was
uh
some cookie cush crap across with my
blue Dynamite Super Lemon OG crap that
guy had one male last year so it had to
be from that male I can dig some blue
Dynamite crap over cookie cush [ __ ] you
know people hate cookies and I don't
like what it stands for either but
ultimately if it's gassy and it has a
good I mean if it's gassy it it's still
decent smoke I mean sure I can't stay
high off it I can't I can't stay high
off it has no legs for me some of it
strong and some of it's not and
sometimes I when I first found cookies
like forum and animal and tried those
things I actually appreciated
not being so [ __ ] I don't need to get
Sledgehammer [ __ ] freaked out stoned
all the time sometimes I want to yeah
you know but I mean I was high I just
wasn't just because I'm not tripping the
[ __ ] out I'm not high you know not
everything has to have me [ __ ] just
feet for me like I get I Get High like
it's a good height for 10 minutes and
then it's just like yeah so that's fine
if you gotta go pick your kid up from
school and that happened a good point
that is a good point
there are times and I talk about this
with rings quite a bit actually where
like I'll smoke something like that my
headband like the LA and I'll go into
town stupidly like I've done this
hundreds of times to myself over the
years I'll get all baked on the wrong
thing and I'll go into town and I'll be
standing in line at this weird little
store and it'll be like the Twilight
Zone in line and I'm like why right am I
here history storm great oh no but one
thing I will say about cookies
is that I don't like cookies that much
either
um but but two things about it one is
that since we were just talking about
the gorilla era I would have flipped out
to have something cookies what came out
in the wrong era if we would have had
that [ __ ] in the gorilla era because
cookies requires low light
it's super dense right it doesn't have
to get that big to weigh a lot of food
it doesn't need a lot it doesn't like
food it doesn't like sunlight so I could
have put it in a deep shade
not fed it very much and just loaded
Manzanita patches with cookies and it
would have came out to come in early
enough to not mold oh it would have been
great it would have been great yeah a
lot of a lot of the things people are
growing when I moved out here did not
come in early not everybody grew
specifically for early that was kind of
my own like mission was to create
something like early that was strong and
looked good and decent to work with and
and stuff like that but a lot when I
moved out here I was hanging out on a
mountain and people were
were uh bringing in [ __ ] baseball
colas from the for out of the rain in at
the end of October
you know and the people I learned from
were really good and that was
they knew how to let things get there
they weren't gonna freak out and pull
[ __ ] yeah you know they really they they
taught me a lot of stuff for like I I
just got lucky and met people that
really were into it and
and cared about it and were also down to
take their time to show me some stuff
and tell me why
they did this or why they didn't do that
there was a lot of of just Hill weed
that had a good amount of sativa in it
of all kinds back then yeah and it took
a while like there's a lot of weed that
didn't finish until say like late
October to early November
um but it resisted the rain pretty well
and Mendo most Falls there's a lot of
warm dry fall in Mendo
you know it might rain for two or three
days and then be sunny for weeks yeah it
just depends you know so there was a lot
of Sativa weed and because all the weeds
sold there wasn't like I think what
started with the purple craze and then
you know the various things is is
everyone started getting the same
cuttings and blending them this era is
the total opposite of that like all
kinds of random unique weed some of it
pretty Mitzy but all kinds of different
stuff just floated around because all
weeds sold yeah and every every smell
you can imagine today was already there
back then
you know who you if you took the time to
see as much as possible which I was into
if people were like
I was just into it you know I was just
like oh somebody's got some different
[ __ ] I'll go and look through it and ask
him questions if I like some but I
remember smelling
super intense cherry
back back then Super intense lime all
the earthy skunky Afghani smells
and just just kind of a little bit of
everything and all different Leafs
all different kinds of [ __ ] you know
talk about some of the the most unique
[ __ ] that you remember seeing um during
your early days there what some of the
most not necessarily by name but
describe it if you can yeah
I mean I keep on thinking about this
this some stuff that uh
my friends grew it actually down in the
Watsonville and uh I had a girlfriend
down there that was going to college so
I was down there a lot when they were
doing it but
one of the guys was ex-military he had
friends up in Humboldt
and they had some little gorilla thing
in a canyon in Watsonville
and when it was done he brought us all
this stuff and it was just like sativa
you know and there was
there was there maybe it was kind of
purple but it wasn't it was like great
and these guys knew how to cure things
beautifully they were really into it
they took their time they cared
and we had called it gray bud and one of
the one of those two sativa strains was
called Golden Lion so somebody up in
Humboldt would recognize that name
yeah Golden Lion and
and uh you know I just figured it was
from some Rasta crew up in Humboldt
and uh
but
I remember that gray Bud
my friends and I smoking it and like not
even talking
like we just left our [ __ ] bodies and
it was [ __ ] amazing but
the most memorable things to Thai
Afghans from spyrock one of the first
things I saw that just had everything
Beauty smell really wild highs and stuff
I remember my buddy would take his
scissors hash and it looked like what we
called monkey's blood opium it was like
translucent red
and I remember smoking that and being
sitting on the ground and just holding
the ground waiting to come just to get
my bearings it was so potent but the
those Thai Afghans blew me away
um you know all these characters were so
funny low bird the guy who called
himself lobert a weird
jungle monkey from Hawaii growing
Hawaiian sativas in their in the like
94. he had great stories of swazi's and
he said all him in the old heads they
liked swazi's that was like the the gold
in Hawaii in like the early 90s or
something interesting yeah I never got
to see that he grew some Hawaiian sativa
seeds here
and would bring the plants in every
night because they weren't going to get
done until I think he harvested them at
Christmas they were [ __ ] great they
take they had really floral sweet smells
really nice some of them had really nice
little shade of purple in them some of
them stayed green no matter how cold it
was yeah you know
and some of that too is like because
weed was was that so valuable then it
was a lot easier to dry and handle
things if you wanted to in a really nice
way because there wasn't so much of it
like it wasn't some overwhelming amount
of [ __ ] you could treat it nicer you
know
um and uh and that made a difference too
one of the things maybe we should note
is that
um when you get pounds or you'd see
pounds most of them were all mixed
phenos
yeah because they weren't from clone so
you would get there would be pounds and
they would be all the same line
you know but they would trim it up and
they would blend it up and you'd be
looking at this and this would smell
like that and this would smell like that
and then you'd be like oh wait what is
that one and then you start digging in
the bag looking for weed that looks like
that and picking out I try to gather
yourself a little pile and you're like
that one right there we always joked we
always joked how people would uh there'd
be like an over ripe purple bud in a
mixed bag
that had no resin on it just smelled
like garbage because it was way over
ripe and somebody would see a pound
they'd focus in on that one they'd be
like look at that purple
oh [ __ ] yeah maybe we just laughed
because it was garbage you know that
would probably be me not all for me
would be doing that but yeah but I mean
there's an aspect too and then some
people would be like oh some of these
pounds are kind of midsy but these
plants are really flavorful so we're
gonna take a few ounces and put them
into into the top of each of these
pounds so that when people open the bag
there's like a nice selection and it
makes them think that the whole bag is
like that but really it's like these are
nice and the rest of them are just okay
and but it all went because people
wanted good weed there was it wasn't
hard they didn't have any options to get
better weed there was you know there was
no like you weren't getting rejected
yeah if you just dried yourself stuff
nice got kept it green got it dry enough
to where it wouldn't turn yellow right
away
your [ __ ] was was golden you know I mean
it was really appreciated by people
whatever it was sometimes I remember
that one time I grew that skunk one it
was funny because people are like this
[ __ ] is weak
and they were just bummed on it
I can imagine I I've heard similar
experiences recently with another option
they didn't have money and they're
spending 50 bucks on an eighth even here
in Mendo you know if they took a smoked
a you know they would Brash and [ __ ] out
if they were taking a couple hits of
something and not getting tore back they
were kind of bummed well and also one
thing that that I don't know if a lot of
people realize seeds prices probably
have instead of inflation risen have
maybe dropped now compared to what they
were they've always been pretty
especially Scentsy they've always been
pretty expensive for the time they've
dropped massively because if you think
about the purchasing power
of what that the seed cost hasn't
changed all that that much you know but
I mean obviously there's some people
that have some hype that try to like
counter inflation or whatever but
um you know for me imagine buying seeds
from Europe back then you know like some
of my older brother's friends went to
Europe and brought back seeds in the 80s
and stuff and they had their little they
lived in Metro areas you know
Minneapolis things like that and they
would have their little closet grows
about 400 or a couple 400s or whatever
and so they had that Dutch stuff but
you know when I moved out here I was
just like man it didn't seem like that
Dutch stuff even mattered out here but
it did everywhere else you know I mean
most of the Dutch stuff was imported
from either California Washington or the
Pacific Northwest so they didn't really
have a need to go to the Dutch to get a
[ __ ] up version of what was already
there yeah you'd never I never heard
people say like oh we went to we put
Northern Lights in this or we put skunk
one in this it was like it was mostly
older stuff
and it really didn't have much which I
appreciated I already was a total nerd a
High Times nerd
I knew all those strains I lusted at
wanting to try them and stuff but here I
was able to try some Northern Lights and
skunk Northern Lights mixes at my
brother's friends had made and my other
one of their friends grew G13 clones in
their early 90s
and I I got to smoke that but most that
was yeah they were actually the first
crew I knew that didn't clones they kept
stuff if they had a great plant they
they kept it they were into their
gardening there was actually this crew
from before I even moved out to Mendo uh
from Wisconsin
um that had this they called it
blueberry skunk
and I used to get it in 93 94 95 96. I
never was able to get a clone of it out
in California
but they had little you know in Madison
and some of these rural areas outside of
Madison they'd have these little four
and six lighters and they would all grow
this blueberry skunk that's what they
called it yeah and it was really
attractive I have no idea what it was
related to
um and I never grew it myself but I got
buds of it
um and uh you know but that what's
interesting about that too is that when
when you when you found somebody that
was intelligent in the sense that like
they cared about the intelligent as the
wrong word I'm sorry when they were when
they cared about lineage
yeah when they were [ __ ] autistic
nerds like us right when they cared
about lineage not intelligence but just
like a weed nerdism to like they'd tell
you something like that like oh it's a
Mexican with a swazi or it's a Colombian
mixed with some afghan that we and they
get you know but most of it was the name
of the closest Little Mountain or town
that it came from when I first moved
here there was so much weed that was
like oh this is from whitethorne
this is from the hills above kovalo this
is some Sherwood Road this is some Long
Valley this is some you know some Alder
Point weed and it was just named kind of
by the little town or the little area or
the little Hills that it came from yeah
yeah more than anything nobody wanted
their names associated with anything
you know and so when I brought out the
Maui because I you know I brought out
the Maui and the Crystal chunk to
California because from Chicago that was
all we knew was like the only reason why
you started seeds was to find a killer
clone and then you use the Clone yeah
you know we were all indoor and stuff
like that so
um you know and so I came here and
clones like you said clones were rare
people were shocked that I was like
running rooms of the same thing yeah
Keepers were just planes that were kept
because nobody kept [ __ ] you could have
kept anything and and if you had those I
mean there just wasn't many clones I I
you know I always think of your Maui
afghoo
um what else yeah we had the afgh up
here Matt oh yeah big time it was early
incredible it looked like indoor because
it was so resonance and stuff so it's
very popular because it came in at a
decent time Outdoors too it had it has
amazing terms too unless you get sick of
it because pretty much everything with
Africa smells like after and you can get
sick of it if that's all you're smelling
like that cantaloupe weird mangoey I
loved it there was a Northern Lights
blueberry I think that went around here
that smelled it either was the same or
it smelled very similar
early on back then and that was that was
sort of like when you when you did a
bunch of outdoor seeds and stuff like
that that was my first experience with
like oh wow there really are dominant
traits you know and I remember some of
my first meetings thinking that I could
breed away from certain things I wasn't
fond of and breed towards other things I
liked more
and then sometimes that worked really
well and I Pat myself on the back and
sometimes that trait was just ingrained
and I was like oh I can't get rid of it
you know it's just part of it you know
like you were saying things like half
goo smell like AFCO or terpenolene or
something like that you know like
there's things where you're like oh I
can't get it out of there yeah yeah I
remember getting really sick of after
pounds because I was born I just thought
all clones were like great to see and
maybe they were great to smoke here and
there but as far as the mission I was on
it was all clones were boring unless he
just made seeds with them and then the
seeds you grew out of them were fun you
know like I just wasn't a clone guy ever
pretty much like I loved sour so much
that I kept that for a long time and a
lot of times having
other friends hold it at times or this
or that I kept it around because it was
just like a daily driver to me like just
a something I like smoking and we could
talk about the top three favorite
strains but I'm not sure I can get any
strain names out if we could actually
talk to them about that yeah I mean I
know all the Clones you know I always
hung out with people that grew the
clones and enjoyed them and stuff I mean
as far as like things that are
identifiable there certainly is some
something not even identifiable I just
mean like top three favorite smokes not
even necessarily strains but smokes
events would smell like taste and like I
mean that's really like they're stray
names there's identifiable stuff and we
use that so other people know exactly
what you're talking about yeah you can
transcend that just by talking about
what it smelled like tastes like the
highs maybe top three interjects just
really quick though is that before we
get away from it which is uh
there was two sour diesels I saw early
on one is the one that I still have
um which I've talked about before but
then it was this other one that that
Rings was much more familiar with that
existed that was took longer was more
feathery uh harmed more was more
delicate so you could talk about that
for a minute because the sour that I
ended up keeping was one of two that I
saw and the one that he had was much
different but we but it was it was
spread around back then but it was
significantly different in growth
pattern and it had a similar nose it was
definitely similar but it was very
different in growth yeah we considered
it to be like Piney
um
I mean it it was that I mean the whole
sour thing was just crazy how it just
took off I mean the first time I got it
actually was from a guy um Mean Gene
uh knows two he grew up near him
um
the guy gave it to me and I was like
this [ __ ] is ugly because still at that
time everybody basically wanted
something dense round with a lot of
resin on it
and my buddy handed me the sour and I
was just like [ __ ] this shit's all
feathery as peach colored hairs on it
and just looked weird to me but
as soon as we smoked it it was just like
I remember looking at it and just being
wow this is going past what the norm is
like this it was the first like
commercial thing that didn't look like
everything people wanted for a long time
dance round Chris Lee blah blah blah you
know it was just such good smoke it
would make people forget about those
other things they thought they desired
so I thought it played a really good
role
in that like kind of breaking down some
walls that were just always there
like it it didn't always look great in a
bag you know sticky little
fluffy
I mean it really you had to hit it right
to get a lot of resin on it but even if
it didn't have a lot of resin on it had
big flavor and it had that Zippy high
that was real clear
would cry
because they wanted that big the stuff
that he was just talking about all that
big chunky resonance that stuff's easy
to trim and people can get through it
sour gets popular and a bunch of people
are growing that cut and it's feathery
and shitty and loose and sticky and you
have to be all gentle with it to not
[ __ ] it up it would give trimmers why
they were [ __ ] doing it what yes you
would have to go a little sour
introduced Psychotherapy to trim bossing
because you had to like convince your
trimmers like this is going to be worth
it please do this I know it sucks
because it was a struggle it was like
sometimes it looked ugly outdoor I mean
it still had all the Terps and the Good
Buds and stuff like that but it
it did not form up into a piece you know
but then I saw some people growing in
greenhouses and feeding it intense food
you know we are kind of more on the
hippie organic side so we weren't
dropping big you know we weren't
throwing grow more on it or anything
like that you know
so but I remember people pulling a lot
of different looking stuff out of that
same clone just by the way they were
feeding it for sure they could get some
pretty big dense bugs out of it if they
nuked it with food
you know but I mean top three strains
I'd almost say sour sour sour I mean
there wasn't and I'm not I'm not really
that attached I'm into keeping on moving
and seeing
what comes out of these seeds that I've
collected or bought or whatever over the
years
I don't I don't really get that attached
they all get me high there's certain
highs I like better yeah
but I'm willing to have a bad Buzz just
to try something new you know there's
something I don't like I just like to
keep moving because I want to see planes
that's it's kind of I was a hobbyist
when I got into it it was just like more
plants all from seed preferably just so
I could it was like information to me to
go to those kind of Gardens and just see
Expressions see different
Tendencies you know you could after a
while you're just like oh that's heavy
Afghani at this guy's Garden you know or
I think that's that's something like me
and Caleb and a bunch of other people
that that are are big into
identification through Visual and
bringing for traits and and all that the
one advantage that we had was seeing a
lot of different strains and like I told
you the other day my mentor
um uh hog he would always tell me like
you you want to learn you learn by by
growing the bass lines baselines
baselines Northern Lights skunk one Haze
you want to grow as many different types
of afghanis as you can you want to grow
as many ties as you can in Mexicans and
Colombians you don't if you don't grow
those you don't know [ __ ] about pot and
that's what he told me yeah that's cool
that's good yeah it's a good place to
start and you see you know one one of
the things that always interests me when
I when rings and I are in one of our
many combos is that there's certain
lines that he's been playing with for a
very long time and then you really get
to see because you've crossed it to a
lot of different things what are the
traits that are dominant that keep
popping up what does it give to crosses
you know there's things that he'll be
like to me he'll be like you know a lot
of people don't like this line but
here's four things that I just love that
it just throws in its progeny all the
time and so I kind of lean towards it
you know because of these things you
know and there's stuff he's done like
you know we did um it's gotten Pat we
you know we did a little a little collab
if you personal collab where he had some
you could talk about this he had some
old Maple Leaf uh Indica from Scentsy
seeds and that era where they were still
selling it
um that we blended with a bunch of stuff
um blue Dynamite uh you know there's
been you know sours and cushes and
various different lines
um and I base you know he makes seed
basically every year yeah so some of
this stuff someone was asking in the
comments when did you first get blue
Dynamite
2002. I said early 2000s but yeah that's
when I got sick of just kind of
freeing my stuff to itself over and over
and kind of just being like okay this
stuff has this kind of range and and I
want to see other people's [ __ ] I want
to see what these people in Canada are
[ __ ] with or
or whatever and I'd read about Maple so
I ordered some maple seeds and it's
funny because I've bought in so many
things over the years to check them out
all these things that I hear old
schoolers talking about the only things
I really have that are still fresh and
poppable in my collection to this day
have blue dynamite in them or Maple Leaf
in them everything else is just come and
gone and it's not that I think those
things are are the greatest or this or I
mean none of it's the greatest to me
it's just all
more more more I just want to see more
plants but they were reliable they were
reliable to do what they did yeah
you know the maple was great it wasn't
very good looking generally it had a
nice smell and it had a great smoke
ability that's why I liked it you said a
lot of terpineline Expressions but there
were some cushy and they're or more
dense Afghani type yeah I remember when
when Nazo and I did that little collab I
remember Caleb hit him up and said do
you see any actual maple
leaves yeah yeah had one I had one I
sent it I sent it to him you know yeah
that's cool yeah yeah and I mean we we
kind of we kind of did like a little
open pollination with that not that it
was very big I think we got
four boys and three girls to pop out of
some of the old seed but we let them
pollinate each other like crazy and then
we threw in a bunch of like uh clones
that I like uh yeah if I you know chems
chem 91 chem D Mendo p uh the tanjo the
super silver haze the headband uh you
know just a a collection of stuff
because
G from seed in there I threw a few
things from seed in there too and I've
grown I mean
not so as in part many of those but I've
popped I've seen hundreds and hundreds
of plants out of there
um
the Loompa headband Maples and I had a
Karma G I had let go and a buddy of mine
wanted to would you say that Karma OG
never heard of her go ahead
what was interesting it was really cool
I had a buddy a few years ago call and
he was off the grid and he was like I
want to just dap a whole bunch of
seed stuff can I get some seeds so I
gave them tons
and I gave them the Lumpa headband with
the Maple and the caramel G I had made
with the Maple and it was it's like the
classic OG story where they're all kind
of the same even though they got all
these names those two rows those two
rows they might as well Bend from the
batch same batch of seed there was
basically like two main expressions and
they looked like each other you know so
that's why I like running seeds you get
to just see that kind of [ __ ] you know
yeah I crossed um I the other day I was
trying to add it I was some like nine
different OG's to the Blue Bonnets just
to see how each different one combined
to the same exact mail then that was
pretty true breeding throwing the same
expressions and there there was very
little variance I mean like mostly like
the sfv and the Louie and all that you
can't it's hard to tell them apart yeah
yeah they're so similar and I mean sure
there was a little different smells and
stuff you know in the different cuts but
the genetic there whatever was in them
wasn't that far apart exactly yeah
and you know I mean I don't know it it's
interesting in that regard because uh
you know just so people know too it's
not like I don't think that those maple
seeds that we used were like from the
original pack they had probably been no
they were used a couple of times they
were they they were just spread to
themselves several times to just keep
them going I mean
that was 15 years after I bought them
what was the medwoman
medwoman who brought oh yeah bad dude I
couldn't believe he posted a picture of
this medwoman medwoman was a Northern
Lights something if you look it up
it won a contest up in Oregon
[Music]
or Washington years ago and it won for
being like a good medical strain I had a
buddy up in Eugene
that sourced some really good great
clones that was in 0.607 I was living up
in Mount Shasta area
and my buddy from Eugene came down he
brought from Roseburg to Oregon he
brought medwoman he brought shishka
Berry he brought a grapefruit cut that
is unlike any grapefruit I've ever seen
again it was [ __ ] amazing it's one of
the it's one of the few ones I wish I
had because usually I just don't care
I'm just one popular but that grapefruit
was [ __ ] insane
um cheese
he got he brought down some really great
stuff I threw
I threw my this this whole this thing
and my friend and I made the Bilo I
threw that on everything because that's
what we had I had moved back down here
and we brought these beat up moms down
here
and nobody really had the capacity to
like take cuts and keep stuff or or we
weren't interested at that time it was
kind of a transitional time in my life
and so we just threw what pollen we had
on it
I still have a whole shitload of those
somewhere in the freezer seats yeah of
the grapefruit
the grapefruit's The One That Got Away
the the last batch of those seeds I gave
to a buddy to grow out the year we had
our fire they burnt there's no more
grapefruit hybrids no
I know and I and we've tried to find
that that cutting and organ several
times
very hard with such a generic name yeah
I tried to grow out Relic grapefruit
um to see it because he was in the
similar area and he had a lot he had a
lot of the same things he worked with
berry cheese
grapefruitment man he probably had the
same ones I did I grew those out there
was no crazy grapefruit there was old
school smells in it it was cool but it
was a different kind of grapefruit
probably yeah yeah yeah definitely yeah
I mean people call different c99s
grapefruit we have a sweet pink
grapefruit we have grapefruit Romulan I
mean there's so many different
grapefruits yeah that's a bad grapefruit
I mean the good thing about it is is
that it's like I was talking about it uh
the other it's kind of funny when people
find some kind of terp or combination
and then start to claim that like
anything that does that comes from them
right like you like if there's
grapefruit there's going to be
grapefruit again just because we lost
the terp combination of certain ones
it's common enough that it popped up in
enough different things that I'm
confident it'll exist again in some
format well you know it's kind of like
the blueberry story right like I mean
one person claims all smells of
blueberry and cannabis is all his
descendants you know but we know that
like I've seen blueberry pop out of
Irene Sour Diesel you know like super
blueberry chirps it's possible to find
in all kinds of different combinations
and we'll always run into it again yeah
you never no I mean especially if your
seeds have a good deep pool in them you
know you could get all kinds of [ __ ] I
mean when I grew out the maple
uh Mendo perps I probably popped I don't
know two three hundred of them or at
least 200 of them or you know to be
conservative yeah range is [ __ ]
amazing you get such and that's fun to
me at this point instead of trying to
make something consistent I almost would
rather make something wild at this time
that you can actually get something
unique out of you know yeah I mean Caleb
makes a really good point dude where he
talks about like he used the Mendo perps
as an example because it has a really
wide genetic he was like if I gave a
hundred s1s to like seven or eight
different friends and ask them to select
what they like and breed with it yeah it
would probably end up with wildly
different selections yeah and people
would take it in their own way and it
wouldn't be similar at all yeah and I
think the maples kind of like that the
maple the maple from Scentsy is probably
it's probably like two or three
different of Neville's Maple cuts and a
little skunk one and it's probably
pretty wide you know yeah and then the
mendo's wide so you cross that and you
just get like a whole host of it isn't
really is what it is it can be a lot of
different things the maple was
dominantly I like I told Matt the other
night it it had long inner nodes it had
fluffy kind of terpenolene based stuff
somewhere resinous some looked pretty
ropey Dopey
but everybody liked it as far as just
smoking a joint you know it was good
but every once in a while I'd say the
rare thing in that line was to get
something that actually had a little
density to it and a resinous appearance
to it in more of a like a fat leaf that
wasn't the common thing but it was in
there yeah you know I had that same
experience with black domino the exact
same experience it was one that I
expected to find some faster finishing
almost blackish purple like uh really
resinous cushy looking things and what I
got was exactly what you described which
were like 13 14 week Airy fluffy
terpineline not a lot of stuff that one
actually didn't have a lot of variants
that from what I saw it was just all
tended to be that yeah but I'm sure
there was other stuff in it just in the
pack that I popped that yeah like 30 or
exactly I bought 10 you know it's like
what are you gonna fight I remember
people ordering Scentsy Afghani Ones
based on the picture oh yeah at least
fun stuff they are all just super tall
super leggy they weren't they were they
did not get fat leaves
buff structured [ __ ] out of that you
know yeah there's a lot of really poofy
ugly Afghani number one I've only seen
like a few really Prime Cuts ever
selected from that line I will say that
you know uh a lot of the Afghan that
first came over to Mendo and Humboldt
and stuff a lot of the Old Timers I
think that's a consistent thing with
Afghani in the sense that like there's a
lot of kind of boofy Afghan I mean
everything ran that G13 nl2 from Neville
some of the last original seeds he had
and it is exactly as as well
as he's describing it it was terminoline
loose
yeah he wasn't stoked yeah no but
there's I mean there's an aspect where
then you you find afino that you want
and breed with that and there are you
know it's like that's kind of like
everybody wants land race but nobody
wants diversity because that means it's
like they don't want to like pop a few
packs and it all sucks yeah I get
excited about ugly plants at this point
like to me that's fun and some of those
really ugly things smoked really nice
and some of this really dense crazy
stuff to me that's not like the most I
mean I need to get you some of that Rose
flow I grew I know I gave the rest to
cry baby of it pure but it is some of
the
ugliest [ __ ] [ __ ] I've ever seen in
my life it burns up with any nutrients
but it's bright red pretty leaves like
there's so much pretty about it and it
and for flows there's like no density to
it but it breeds great yeah but
ugly as [ __ ] not much resin yeah it's
it's one of those that you it's very
unique High
yeah yeah I know I mean
you know we didn't need to really be
visually that appealing until Instagram
I view the Instagram era as like a
massive change in what lead had to look
like there was lots of weed that was
somewhat ugly
but if it worked and smoked and tasted
really nice and got you Zippy high like
you were stoked like he was talking
about that sour you know that's sour it
was it was it was stemi it was loose it
was funky looking in some ways but it
got you ripped high yeah it tasted great
tasted amazing yeah
you know so yeah I think of it a little
different I think the market and people
just always especially when spending 50
bucks was a lot to them because they
didn't have much money they wanted it to
be
like they wanted the appearances that we
used to call it fake
fake tits and bleach blonde hair weed
you know they wanted dense crystally
buds
just to look at because blackberry kush
I have blackberry kush I mean honestly
dude you know I remember I never [ __ ]
with that clone I saw tons of it but I
remember getting an ounce of weed in San
Francisco in the 90s once and it was we
you know we just called it Hydro you
know it was some kind of indoor and
there was only like nine butts
and we were like so pumped you know
because each Bud was like two to four
grams yeah you know what I mean it was
like looking at like these chunky you
were like oh God somebody gave me like
the breeder stash yeah you know because
you know it was one of those things
where it was like it wasn't that common
to see so you wanted visually appealing
I don't remember anything about that
weed except for how impressed we were
that it was nice butts yeah it looked
nice and big yeah it was just blue it
was just bright green and bright orange
hairs and Frosty and all these big
chunks
a lot of times people and they got an
eight that just had one Chunk in it they
were kind of butt hurt you know like
they they or they questioned if you were
giving them 2.8 instead of 3.5 of course
yeah
but it but if it was good if it if it
was strong they've just didn't forget
you know
they they'd want more
and yeah
let's see someone asked what were the
earliest purple strained Ring song Cali
I'd say the earliest well the the real
the earliest ones were just overripe
depleted plants that maybe turned purple
and they weren't we we thought oh
somebody said they had purple he'd be
like oh it's garbage you know because it
was always like something left on the
vine depleted
whatever it wasn't really good but
Laytonville Laytonville had uh in fact
that ties back to the underwear guy
um lived in the shack
um
they there was a a real common type in
Laytonville and this I kind of sometimes
I think of this with the Mendo perp
story it's kind of my own take or
whatever but
there there was a green and a purple and
they were both really pretty you could
tell the purple was supposed to be there
instead of something that was you know a
reflection of some something not good
you know was that the strain that people
called the purple from Laytonville
maybe okay maybe that's the second time
I've heard uh the Laytonville purple
like a specific Laytonville purple
mentioned in relation to like one of the
early purple yeah I've seen a bunch of
families that I'd met back then had the
similar stuff and it'd be like they'd
have either this bright green it was
never real dense it was just nice yeah
and then there was like a purple side
that was really pretty
that would be in there too yeah and so
and it all it often had a real sweet
like Fruity
type of smell to it also interesting and
there's an aspect too that people should
know that what what Rings is talking
about when like overdone [ __ ] is
freaking uh uh uh
um people would do first and second and
third Cuts oh and so a lot of times
there would be purple weed that would be
like all the smalls that everybody left
to ripen and they'd stick out in the
cold and they'd turn dark and it was
like all the under light under fed stuff
that would happen and then they would
cut that and put it into pounds so it
was the same price as the tops back then
you know it just sucked but but it was
still yeah people would really milk
their [ __ ] and I didn't see not too many
people cleaned up their plants to try to
make their tops the best
you know they would just pick those tops
let those other things go until they did
something and some streams really
actually did okay with it and some of
them would just [ __ ] out as soon as you
picked on them they would everything
else would be shitty but they would
still pick it and sell it there was this
aspect where people thought oh we can
leave this stuff on and let it ripen
because it's underdone it never got
enough light we'll just leave it out and
it's not gonna rot because it's too
small yeah and then that stuff would
ripen and turn colors because it would
get pretty cold at night you know and
then they would go out and harvest it so
it was often like late batch under
underground you know like remnants yeah
for the most part
um
yeah
yeah no it's fun I mean that that I mean
being a hobbyist and moving out here and
just seeing all that [ __ ] it was just my
mind I was just the happiest boy in my
20s running around these Hills looking
at as much [ __ ] as I could I thought it
was great
I can only imagine yeah
and being being that age and and like I
obviously I lift my era because that
would have been something I would have
loved to have lived through so it's
pretty cool to be able to pick your
brain yeah and to be able to sit here
and ask you questions about it and kind
of uh live via proxy through an error
that I missed yeah I mean we're all born
when we're born we all get our turn I
know you still got to see cool or punk
rock [ __ ] than I did too
[ __ ] yeah and you know what I
mean growing up in the town that I did
there was it was almost Unthinkable that
it could have happened it was just my
older brother and their friends I don't
know how they stumbled on
that's how I got sucked in too is was
who became my older brother-in-law yeah
me and punk rocks even a little kid so
yeah makes sense yeah
yeah that was fun too and still was for
all those years too moving out here and
being able to run down to the city down
to San Francisco and
sometimes I'd see bands I knew from the
Midwest played in San Francisco that was
always fun too just little reunions in
the street
yeah is there anything else you wanted
to cover not so one of the things that
we could cover that kind of ties into
what we were talking about is that both
rings and I arrived in Mendo when it was
I mentioned it before but when it was
kind of poor and weird right and uh it
was very odd place and you know and then
you know people think too like people
used to come to Mendo all the time and
be like oh my God wheat is legal
and we did this thing where we passed
this thing measure G which kind of
basically forbade the cops from messing
with you too hard if you only had 25
plants and you had your paperwork and so
people would come to Mendo every week
and be like wheat is legal I can do
whatever I want
and you would be like oh my God no like
there's very much a cat and mouse game
that goes on between you and your
neighbors and where you're at what part
of the county there was neighborhoods
that you could get away with it fine and
there was neighborhoods where like
retired doctors or lawyers or whoever
would just report anything that they saw
absolutely and if you didn't know like
which streets and which areas were
kosher and not you could come up here
and like way get like like in the wrong
spot and get the most amazing things was
that you could go to the sheriff's
department and buy 25 zip ties for
625 boxers you could yellow big yellow
zip ties I mean my my ex had cancer well
you're in the sheriff's department
getting these zip ties from some old
lady
and you'd go and wrap them around your
stock and you just felt like [ __ ] the
neighbors whatever they can [ __ ] all
they want if you got these things the
cops and you have only 25 like you were
you felt pretty empowered so that
created probably I would say in
I don't know I've been here four or five
years or longer then so it was probably
0203 maybe it was when it really started
what we call like the Green Wave so
probably like 0203 to maybe like 09
there was just an immense wave of
Outsiders that came into the county all
at once buying up property they drove up
the cost of properties by enormous
amounts
people really started blowing it up huge
um it changed the culture of the place
because anytime you get a bunch of
Outsiders coming in too fast they can't
learn from the people that were already
there and so there was like friction
between the people that had been here
for a while and the people that were
just sort of like there was people that
were like
I moved here I bought this land it's in
the country which means I'm American and
I can like fire guns and get drunk and
drive 70 miles an hour up the thing and
I can drain the community spring and I
don't give a [ __ ] I'm growing weed and
[ __ ] my neighbors and suck a dick and
you'd be like oh no no no no that
doesn't actually work well you know
people yeah you'll end up in a whole
[ __ ] this is Mendo
clones too that was the beginning of
like the seeds
the seed the past was just disappeared
into clones at that time too and I I
remember being really bummed because I
knew I could see it happening I was like
all this diversity is just going away to
Barry White half goo
and blue dream clones like all these
people all these people would have grown
25 plants from seed
any time before this but now they're
just mono cropping one one thing
and they you know they would come here
and they would want to make a bunch of
money a lot of them wouldn't even stay
here over the winter you know they would
come seasonally to make money in bail
um and it changed the culture of the
place it brought a lot of money and it
definitely improved thousands upon
thousands of of rural properties that
got built up and made nice and Ukiah the
hot main Hub I mean it it put a switch
it polished the turd if you will oh I
mean when I first moved Willets uh which
is the town north of us and you in uh uh
in Mendo was half of it was boarded up
it had some really hideous buildings it
was it was way on the downturn and now
what's funny the reason why I brought it
up is because we we've been talking a
bunch about how we watched all these
people flow in
and now with the collapse of the wheat
economy and the prices dropping to so
crazy and everybody getting used to
Growing volume which Rings hates and
growing a bunch of B and C Grade weed
and just hoping it was good enough now
all these people are flowing back out of
the community because everyone that came
in for easy money is like oh it's not
easy
Oklahoma bye-bye
yeah they were there was a lot of rich
kids a lot of you know because I mean
you had to have some it was either like
big Hustlers from from cities all over
the country are rich kids because you
had it still cost a lot of money to get
a property and actually set it up
and pay people and stuff like that you
had to
you know they had to you you couldn't be
broke and come to Mendo and start a
scene no you know they there's a lot of
people up here that didn't want to admit
that they got their parents to buy them
properties
and then they started blowing and then
they started blowing it up and like
going on vacations and I used to think a
lot of those people I was like man
they're just so much better at what
they're doing than I am and then I
realized that like their parents bought
them like it was just play money to them
well I was trying to like live and
survive and breed and do these different
things and like there was no backstop
like they had the parent that like put
them put the property in their name they
put the day payment down safety nets
would be [ __ ] awesome and you didn't
realize that none of them none of them
really wanted to tell you
right now we're going back to work for
their mom and dad's corporations after
15 years yeah they are bendo yeah of
blowing it up in Mendo and a lot of them
too to be honest they would come up here
for two or three years and actually grow
and then they would Farm it out to a
good friend or friends that weren't
doing as well and still take a huge
percentage but it was their property
yeah and they would live in Santa Rosa
or the bay or Southern California or
whatever and they would come up at
important times to their property and
make sure it worked yeah but they
weren't really from here yeah they just
kind of came up and blew it up and made
some money and then left and then used
the funnel to like funnel money to
themselves so they could live where they
wanted yeah we know lots of those yeah
and so it's kind of getting back to like
broken weird again in a way yeah which
is painful to see but
you know it's not like it's not like
Ukiah will turn back into uh poor town
with a big factories on the edge of town
you know exhaust over the whole town
it's it won't be back there because now
it's just
it's like the new affordable place for
City people to put their money because
all the towns between here and San
Francisco are ludicrously expensive you
know like every time a person sells a
house in town There's a person from the
Bay Area willing to just buy it because
it's only six hundred thousand whereas
anywhere south of here it's 800 or a
million for the same and so there's an
aspect where if you live in like The
Valleys where where uh yeah where we
live right now he's making fun of me
because I got this verbal tick I got rid
of one and then others came in my place
but
um there's part where around Ukiah
around Redwood Valley around certain
valleys the I think the properties are
maintaining value but there's a lot of
like mountainous properties that when
people tried to get them permitted
they're just not permittable that
without hundreds of thousands of dollars
of improvements most of them don't even
have enough water on them to grow a
garden I mean if people came up here and
spent 350 000 buying a raw 20 acres that
had no water on it and they set it up
and buy water
and have it delivered
and now that the weed isn't bringing
money what is that property worth really
you know exactly sure and so there's a
lot of things too and this is another
kind of conflict in our area where the
regulations want people to come out of
the traditional pot growing areas in the
hills and they want them to come down to
the valleys and like get legal on like
AG land
and then there's a bunch of retired
doctors and lawyers and wine people that
are like what do you mean there's a grow
down the street
I don't want to see that that's supposed
to hide up in the hills I bought this
retirement property it's all supposed to
be rolling grapes and Orchards and not
these degenerates with me I don't care
do they have a permit well
um Sonoma County had a big problem you
know at first when they were starting to
go legal and I mean who owns Sonoma
County Rich conservative wine Growers
they were not into it and then some of
those people were actually investing in
weed once it really got legal oh yeah
you know but they hated it before and
and they probably still ate it but
they're going to invest in it now to
make some money money is money yeah
but there's a there's an aspect where
you see a lot my my point to that I
guess was that I'm curious in two or
three years what a lot of these Mountain
properties look like because the price
of wheat has collapsed so much and it
might cost hundreds of thousands of
dollars just to fix your road so that
like you know the fire department and
whoever else will sign off on you having
a a one license growth and if it's if
the angle of your road is more than 14
degrees you have to get it paved or this
or this or this and so a lot of these
places where it used to be traditional
and good to hide and grow Mountain weed
and it's clean and it's pure up there
it's not suitable for the current form
of legal yeah unless you get lucky very
few of them had enough water they barely
had enough water to just
Supply a normal household
you know let alone a big Garden out in
the out on the left you know so they
were all trucking it in foot people in
the last few years were spending trying
to grow these 10 000 Square foots off of
bottom water
they were spending like 1200 bucks a day
or more I've heard about that people
Trucking in water and people Trucking in
water water trucks running around
everywhere they're tanking I talked to a
water truck driver that I knew the other
day he's like ma'am
there ain't [ __ ] going on he's like I
didn't make [ __ ] last year from it you
know it's just over there tons of people
bought water trucks it was all the rage
yeah I mean there was enough profit in
it that it made sense to do a lot of
things like that you know and so I used
to I used to have this running joke that
like it'd be you'd find something and
it'd be like a a composting toilet you
know cute little Shack you know solar
power 20 acres and it'd be like 700
Grand because people would be like oh
you could put 50 plants on that thing
and make tons of money pay it off in a
couple of years and so now what is that
property going to be worth in a couple
years
like the you know what what really is
that is that weird it doesn't have a
septic it doesn't have a this it doesn't
have a that it's just a spot how many of
these people have moved here just had no
idea how to like maintain a property you
know like these properties are just [ __ ]
they're leaving them with just broken
down carports and
shitty Shacks they threw up real quick
just to dry some plants and I mean just
garbage tons of garbage you know on them
they're they're crap yeah there's a lot
people leave a lot of garbage everyone
thinks that like Mendo and Humboldt is
this beautiful pristine place there's a
lot of human garbage
my friends from Santa Cruz would come up
here and go man
why does everybody like having garbage
out in their front yards up here
a natural repository for garbage yards
too yeah Endo fashion is having some
sort of blue tarp ripped up and you know
yeah it's normal around here
I mean there was places that we bought
that we went in and like they would take
like an old barn or an abandoned cabin
and they would just fill it with their
household trash because they didn't want
to have trash service
yeah yeah and you'd have to put on like
essentially a hazmat suit and you'd rent
most places we got a hold of in the late
90s through the mid-2000s
one of the first things you would do was
get however many 40 yard dumpsters you
needed yeah yeah and you could just load
40 yard dumpsters with trash and some
people would just make a huge pile and
cover it with gas and set it on fire
that'd be a big black [ __ ] black
terrific
oh God yeah people would you know it was
uh it's an interesting spot but one
thing that one million Whip It
containers and all that kind of [ __ ]
later I mean in the Whip-It containers
in the in the open blast era of butane
it got really bad up here and people
would do stuff where they got scared of
throwing away thousands of empty cans of
Tain so they would like use a backhoe
and dig a hole in the woods and just
pour all the thing in there and drive
over it and then fill it back in
that was I mean
I've seen a lot of them just left on the
side of the road huge piles thousands
and thousands of butane canisters just
left out in the beautiful Wilderness
with just a big massive pile of butane
cans you know I mean so there's an
aspect to that where like that whole
open blast era uh which was probably
eight or eight or ten years or something
like that yeah um it was a lot of damage
you know there's a lot of dumping
there's a lot of those legs again on
humans too you know some really bizarre
stories of humans melting as the
clandestine butane you're laughing but
it's true dude it's true
I have friends that their their skin
looks pebbled you know yeah it's not it
wasn't good no anyway we're at the end
of the two hours oh you just ran all the
way through it nice well you know
obviously we're just the kind of dorks
that could babbles in there so this is
what we do anyways yeah
but that's the vibe we wanted to give
you what is it like to shoot [ __ ] for
the first time I I was on uh on
something like this I just I didn't even
realize it was I was just bullshitting
with YouTube yeah well what the good
part is nobody can see below your waist
because he's absolutely [ __ ] naked
we want to thank you for coming on
brother
oh I'm a ghost we we definitely want to
thank he is one of my good homies uh we
chat a lot he
um you know all that and it's a little
bit of a Vibe into our world we didn't
even get to talk about how he lost his
sisters in a sense or what what brought
him to the butt stuff worlds there's a
lot of un unturned stones that we can
get I'm glad I didn't have to cry this
whole episode you know indeed he only
cries after sex so
yeah but anyway
yeah
um so next week starting next week
I'm [ __ ] done with Instagram I'm
[ __ ] especially after tonight [ __ ]
Instagram like I couldn't add anyone to
the shows none of that [ __ ] so it's
YouTube from now on out
um next week not so will not be with me
I may have someone else in his place
um we'll see who to get
um
we also have our patreon go to breeders
and get patreon or go Google read
yourself get patreon and you can find
all of our patreon stuff there we go
there hang out shoot the [ __ ] all the
time
um there's lots of extras for everyone
there we have a 50 uh slot we just added
and there's a gift monthly gift for each
person a part of that uh what else is
there check out righteach.com for my
spray seeds we're getting closer to
getting NASA getting to release some
stuff uh I hear there might be a collab
with CSI coming up soon which I'm super
excited about to see uh but yes please
remember go follow
um right seeds just go to Google type in
right seeds YouTube you can find it that
way subscribe make sure you click the
Bell icon move it to all so you get all
the notifications because next week no
more [ __ ] Instagram and and because
of that I'll be able to add in pictures
I could put together videos with
slideshows all kinds of cool [ __ ] to
illustrate while we're talking it'll be
a much better better presentation and
all that [ __ ] so yeah anyways thanks
again rings for you brother yeah and we
really appreciate you talking to
everybody enjoy your Friday night thank
you for listening to us pleasure as
always
cheers nighty night