[Music]
haha second time
nailed it ah welcome everyone they're
trying to nail that that's a good one I
like that one that was a my friend's
band the locust god that was 2001
probably 2001 a good era for uh I don't
know
electronic punk-rock how's everyone
doing
what's up bicycle everybody check out
get see it's right here calm he now has
the website up and you can find the
finest in cannabis strains from bicycle
and he's a hell of a guide that's my boy
so what's good everyone tonight I wanted
to talk about you know I get I get asked
a lot of the same questions from episode
to episode now that we could finally
have these backed up on YouTube I can
actually reference people to which
episode it'll be so I wanted to talk
about people starting seed companies
do's don'ts what you should do what you
shouldn't do what you should do but
might get your [ __ ] balls busted all
of the above so yeah we'll get into all
that first off anybody hear anything
weird about Crockett today
anybody catch that yeah I'm stoked on
the YouTube back up to it'll be nice to
have that you know it'll show everyone's
questions etc etc so Cubans since you
guys here thank you Cuban I love you
brother
Cubans gonna be going on after me as
well this is just gonna be a one-hour
thing give them to me after me so
everybody go check out his after this
please he's smart kid man smart kid
so what happened with Crockett I mean
you don't know it might just be rumors I
don't know I just heard some I heard
some rum
and stuff Thank You Johnny thank you
thank you I you know I haven't I haven't
heard the the sub sub tool podcast but
yeah yes
Friday we'll be doing another video with
moon we're gonna have another episode
going and that one will absolutely be
backed up on YouTube
so if you missed out on any of those we
might cover some stuff that we covered
before and I'm sure most of you won't
mind that because it was I mean it's
it's a thick topic man that's thick
science it's hard to uh it's hard to to
handle you know all in one run a lot of
people had to watch that like three or
four times and after 24 hours it gets
taken down by Instagram oh yeah I shaved
a little bit you like that [ __ ] [ __ ] it
was looking a little mountain-man II
swear I don't really have much of the
rumor I was just I just heard some
something I just heard something
something about bad with crock it
happened
someone got fired for something and
rather I don't know I I don't know but I
was just wondering if you guys heard
that which is why I was asking if I knew
more I'd say it you know me I don't give
[ __ ] I don't like those [ __ ]
anyways spread what you have meaning a
vagina right
the JJ's for all so yeah there's over a
hundred people in here right now let's
get let's get this party started
I don't know what happened that's why I
was asking you guys so you guys are more
knowledgeable than me about this [ __ ]
especially with the jeez man I don't I
don't have the gossip man I don't have
it no need to be coy get off the bus
good all right
so what is it the word for the day is
legs please spread the word Oh killing
it freak will be here all week let me
ask you I don't know what you're talking
about the mask you're talking about my
special guest that I
sometimes I don't know we'll see if the
special guest pops up so let's talk
let's talk about let's talk about new
seed companies
I'm sure there's got to be one person in
here who's thinking about starting a
seed company where would you guys like
me to start
like what questions do you have when it
comes to that or you just want me to do
you want me to start firing off
different things I actually wrote an
article earlier and I was gonna put it
up on the I was gonna put it up on the
right seats forum however I think strain
lis might put it up but we'll see we'll
see
IIIi want I want to see strain ly do
well because they are very very nice
guys very nice guys it's not like a big
corporation doing [ __ ] you know these
are guys doing this in their spare time
just because that's what they want to do
you know they want to have something
good going no well I mean let's see what
should I do when is one and rename your
seeds change your name to dirty water
you should be good mm-hmm where should
someone start with their genetics well
that's that's a kind of a weird question
I mean I I don't know how to answer that
one as far as start with genetics get
good genetics in the first place do your
research know who's making what know who
actually has what clone cuz a lot of
things are just claims man a lot of
things are just claims actually you know
you could technically just buy one of
them all of one of my line and just
rename the whole [ __ ] you know
but yeah let me find this article I
wrote that I just want to be able to
reference this okay rule number one I
have here pull up a chair and shut your
[ __ ] mouth man I you know I might
have taken some of that advice early on
because I was a [ __ ] loudmouth [ __ ]
know-it-all and I I definitely did not
know everything early on you know what I
mean so but but like when someone when
someone comes to talk and I'm not even
talking about me
just talking to general if you're on a
life eating someone pops up and it's an
old breeder shut your [ __ ] mouth man
unless you have a good question
shut your [ __ ] mouth don't look dumb
don't don't look dumb if you're starting
your career a lot of people remember
everything they see you know and don't
remember hey that was that dude that was
asking how to [ __ ] clone out of his
[ __ ] you know like don't don't don't
be dumb don't say dumb [ __ ] any genetic
profiling to protect your intellectual
property I'm actually I'm working with
the open cannabis project on IP
protection IP protection and they're
doing some [ __ ] awesome things they
have good lawyers on this yeah but let
me get back to this real quick yeah yeah
just shut your mouth you know when an
old school breeder comes up that that's
your chance man that's your chance to
like get that get that power up like on
Super Mario Brothers you know yeah it's
your chance to absorb it like a sponge
take that take that chance man listen to
what they have to say there's a lot of
guys who have a lot of amazing [ __ ] to
say let's see what you got
breeding number two number two I did
tell you Nick not to use protection
I'm sorry breeding is a [ __ ] science
there is an actual science to this there
are [ __ ] terms that have actual
definitions don't be one of those people
who uses the term IBL and not know what
the [ __ ] IBL is right no F ones no F
two years no backcrosses know that in
crosses are a thing but no the
appropriate time to use them this is
there's a science to this and believe it
or not there are other things besides
weed that people grow that they've been
growing for a long time that also have
breeding terms associated with it as
well and that's where we have somewhat
borrowed and we have changed some of the
breeding terms because some of those
don't apply to cannabis but but
definitely understand all those inside
out if you need if you want a good place
to start don't start with the [ __ ]
forum don't
start with reading what some
[ __ ] breeder like Melvin says
or or whoever you know I mean mostly if
people are using IBL in their lines and
it's not CSI humboldt it's not me it's
not professor p chances are they don't
know what a [ __ ] IPL is guaranteed
don't slap that on the end of your
[ __ ] [ __ ] if you're a new breeder you
don't know what it means learn how to
write and I actually did this earlier oh
the book list
Robert Colonel Clark marijuana botany
that's all you ever need to know as far
as books you really don't need more than
that DJ shorts book I can't read the
title it's good for learning about
specific Mexican lines but I mean other
than that when it comes to straight
breeding you don't need more than Rob
Robert colonel Clark's marijuana botany
learn how to write cannabis genetic
nomenclature female X male female X
female parentheses reversed that use
your brackets brackets are your friends
parentheses are your friends there's a
reason that those are there people don't
just throw those in there to make it
look pretty and more established use
them correctly it makes you look more
intelligent and it genuinely get you
respect from your peers better alright
breeding has a purpose part three
breeding has a [ __ ] purpose if you
are crossing two things just to see what
happens and you don't really know what's
gonna happen because you've never grown
those lines before
that's not breeding that seed making now
with that said it's possible to be a
seed maker in a breeder and in fact it's
advisable to do both because people need
that new shiny [ __ ] thing and it's
hard to stay relevant in the cannabis
community if you are not doing both and
that's just a fact I mean it really is
if you're not constantly pushing out new
lines it's hard to stay relevant so push
out new lines do your thing but work
some lines in the background get to know
get to know what it's like to watch
plants evolve let's see what else we got
here but yeah yeah a breed with the
purpose
say this is my Engel I want something
that is say I want it short with [ __ ]
dense structure but I don't want to deal
with PM and maybe some purple would be
nice then look in your toolbox see what
you have to create that make that [ __ ]
happen sometimes it'll take several
generations but when you do that you'll
have some true braiding lines in the end
and that's that's the most valuable then
you can have in your tool kit as far as
a breeder goes let's see what else we
got now we're at permissions it's
probably the question I get asked about
the most permissions the number one
determiner and all this stuff is did you
pay for the seeds okay that's something
you need to take into account when
thinking about all this stuff short
stout and sticky mucky [ __ ] it's
true it's true it is true I have like
pig pen I have a little cloud when I
walk around if you paid for the seeds
different rules apply I mean if you are
a tester you definitely need me to ask
me to ask permission from that breeder
and it needs to be clear before you use
those seeds if you didn't pay for those
they're a gift or whatever ask
permission if you paid for them
realistically you should be able to do
what you want except for direct copying
that's not okay in any industry why
should it be okay in this industry
breeding is an art and if someone is
taking your art changing the name on it
like wiping off your name writing their
name on it and signing it with a new
name hey that's that's [ __ ] right
that's [ __ ] that doesn't fly anywhere
so but if you're making it f1 hybrid
let's say and you're using two different
readers work if you paid for those seeds
you really don't necessarily have to ask
them for their work but you should you
should its proper it's polite you'll get
more respect from those people whose
work you're using you'll definitely get
more respect
name-check those [ __ ] later you
know shout out some props to them that's
the way it's done man that's that's the
way you get respect from everyone your
elders and everyone that came before you
you got to pay your dues you have to pay
your dues however if you ask and they
say no and you bought those and
[ __ ] and you're not doing a
direct copy it's up to you it depends on
how much you want some some breeders get
more upset about that than others right
as far as the make your own mail thing
that's that's nice and dandy but again
not it's not an obligation to do that
you're still trying to get bodis
permission buddy I don't think Bodie
cares so much man he's one of the most
open breeders there are as far as people
working with this stuff when I say
direct copy I mean s 1 or F Gen let's
see when is it okay to F gen and if you
if you don't understand what GN is refer
back to rule 2 and get the book Robert
clown hood Clark
Robert Connell Clark marijuana botany
that'll help you learn those terms when
is it okay to f gen if a company is no
longer around if a company is no longer
around and they and there's no
foreseeable future for them coming back
around it usually is okay
especially when a line is really hard to
find and there's a lot of people that
want it in their collection and there's
a chance to like to be lost then it's
not just okay it's really advisable to
do that we don't want to start losing
lines because that's all so many been
lost already
because of stuff like that in the case
of let's let's let's choose the brothers
grin Graham situation they left there
was no foreseeable future of them coming
back a lot of people made c99 F gens you
know Apollo 11 F gens Apollo 13 that
made sense a lot of those lines were
hard to get even back then they were
expensive and and a lot of people did
what they could
save those lines if it's from key plane
you want to use it shoot yourself
because you should be using [ __ ]
[ __ ] from that idiot but that's when
it's okay to F Jim without permission
some of those guys aren't even around to
ask permission for or in the case of a
clone only where the breeder is not
determined you can in you need to do
your due diligence to make sure that the
breeders not determined but there's some
pretty obvious candidates out there that
nobody knows who bred it bagsied etc
rule five respect man respect and and
don't give respect where they haven't
earned it because there's a lot of
[ __ ] they have an earned
respect that have been around a while
doesn't mean they have have respect a
lot of these guys have respect respect
from customers and not even to their own
customers respect from people buying
seeds because they're on the attitude or
whatever seed bank and they're getting
hype but they don't have the respect of
their peers what you want your ultimate
goal if you really want to be a breeder
is the respect of your [ __ ] peers do
you have the respect of your peers do
you do the people that you interact with
do the people that you respect respect
to you that's major man that's major the
six this is probably one of the most
important and I should have probably
listed as number one come with thick
[ __ ] skin you're not gonna make it if
you get your feelings hurt I'm telling
you what it's really really hard to make
it in this industry it's even more
cutthroat than it used to be people say
[ __ ] about you and if they have enough
[ __ ] people listening to them those
people will say [ __ ] about you they'll
post it everywhere a lot of these guys
have all the time on their hand to do
this [ __ ] man and you know lots of
retirees or disabled people or or not
necessary disabled people but people on
workman's comp or whatever they have
time to do this [ __ ] and they will
[ __ ] try to crush you people don't
like competition people do not like
competition and they will try to bring
you so get some thick [ __ ] skin you
know I when I came to this I thought I
had thick [ __ ] skin but there was
there
years where I was [ __ ] completely
doubting everything that I did and I
shouldn't have ever let anybody had that
effect on me but it's hard man it's hard
so when you get trolled once you start
getting the following and you get
trolled take it as a compliment for
reals
take it as a compliment hey that means
you're doing something that's that's
stirring people's emotions I mean if
you're being a [ __ ] and you're
getting trolled that's a different thing
but for the most part if you're if
you're doing some good [ __ ] for people
and people are liking it and you're
still getting trolled take it as a
compliment a lot of these guys that do
troll people just want you to recognize
them they just want your attention be it
negative or positive kind of like little
[ __ ] kids like how they just they'll
like slap you to get your attention go
you know kind of like that yeah that's
what I got for the the rules in general
is there anything anybody has any
questions about my paper one put my bit
Bop um I mean jaws did a great job of
making himself you know popular off
trolling me and that was only because I
responded to his [ __ ] so there's a time
and place to respond and sometimes I
suck it at just not I sometimes I do
respond too much and I've been trying to
way that reaction better
what's wrong with cookie mean I haven't
figured that out man and figured that
out what are the unwritten rules now
give Matt everything for free be it
lights be it nutrients just give me [ __ ]
you know just give me free [ __ ] I like
free [ __ ] what's up Jax what's the best
way to collect money for seeds I can't
go into detail on that since that's an
illegality you know and I don't want to
set myself up but there's ways to do it
I don't recommend paper
PayPal is [ __ ] terrible and they like
to steal your money on a morale clause
so I don't recommend that do reversals
cause more harm snow only if an idiots
doing a traversal and they haven't
properly assessed their lines what was
your question Jax I saw something pop up
but every time I pop from here to
somewhere else like it turns off my
screen so I couldn't answer I saw
something about God's gift and something
else what do you consider strange built
off height not good breeding and no I
mean they're there strains that
absolutely deserve the hype you know and
that are good breeding but there's
plenty of it aren't ya
send out tons of free gear that's a gif
you would like you all right guys let's
help
let's help my friend Jacqueline decide
fire OG or lemon meringue or God's gift
I'm gonna say no on the gods gift
I don't know much about lemon meringue
other people well I take that back
that's right you never smoke but you
want to try go for something light go
for God's gift go for something light
and when I say take a little tiny hit at
a time wait ten minutes taking out a
little tiny hit and being serious it's
not like when we were young and smoking
pot it's nothing like it it's called
micro dosing and and it works great with
cannabis when you don't have a tolerance
so go for something light yeah fire OG
will [ __ ] her up oh [ __ ] her day up if
it's grown well so yeah definitely go
for something light okay I'll be around
I got ya let me know how it goes
do you think if someone finds a cut in
someone else's seeds or bad seed that
passes it around do you think the person
that found it should say what is done
with it let's see I think that's one fun
to cut someone else's seeds or bag so he
passes around do you think the person
that found it should say what is done
with it that's a good question man um I
mean I think
I think both people should have a say
but that doesn't always happen exactly
man I remember when I quit smoking for
two years I was dating a [ __ ] [ __ ]
and she didn't want me smoking despite
what I do for a living
so I've played in and I'm not referring
about to Britain in any way by the way
brings great but yeah I mean the first
time smoking again it's just like that
first high and some shit's too much man
have you curled up in the corner and a
little ball crying that's no fun and
that's no fun at all have you ever made
something so dank you didn't want to
release it no um I want people to have
good we don't when I have the best weed
out there of course I'll release it
there were times where I wouldn't
release cuts of stuff but I would
release weed of it and clockwork being
the main one with that and it was just
because I didn't want us to get ripped
off but eventually that's gonna happen
anyways if it's good enough if your weed
is good enough it will get ripped off
and that's part of the process but you
the thing I just tell myself is these
guys are still gonna be working with my
tailings they're always a few years
behind me
so whatever mmm God's gift storing God's
gift was it GDP and oh gee I think GDP
oh gee isn't that God's gift
most God's gift cuts like the Sonoma
God's gift cut out there that's the
original was the Sonoma God's gift and
it was kind of leafy and very non long
narrow leaves it wasn't very frosty not
very great but for its time it was okay
best strain for consistent piney chirps
don't know I'm not big on the pines how
do I get some seeds to you if you would
ever like something I need to get a peel
box I really do but just DM me man DM me
what if you make a known strain with
different source to parents what do you
mean if you recreate a strain with
different parents like let's say it's
fire og cross two abusive og let's say
and you use those same two cuts to make
the line that's yours man you do
whatever the [ __ ] you want with it
there there's different ways to paint
the same picture you know what I mean
and not and once the strains are
acclimated to your room what you make is
going to be different than what is
presented especially when it comes to
selection you know what I mean if you do
a selection from that specific cross
it'll be different than the selection
that's available as a clone only there
you go snow cap four pint herbs I don't
know much about snow cat did you like
that I rock you just mad because your
face is longer than the [ __ ] donkeys
bodis one of my good friends I recommend
everything that he does the guy's a
[ __ ] magician he is the Wizard of
weed so you're in good hands with
anything from the guy man just look at
the description see if it appeals to you
and try it and and in if it works for
you that's great if not move to the next
that's what groans do we adapt is p90 1
classed as a skunk p90 1 it would be
class more as an Afghani Thai hybrid
Williams wonder frost - I think no hold
on what was that it was it was it was
silver-backed I crossed you I always
forget the other part well I'll have to
look
have you found any skunky ones in the
green suicide absolutely and all of that
and anything I use the the roadkill
Afghani mail with you're gonna find some
skunky phenotypes in it it's very very
heavy with skunky phenotypes Bodie is an
amazing dude I I can't say that about a
lot of people but I can absolutely say
that about him he is he's when my
company almost crashed when I got a
really [ __ ] up disease from the
Philippines a plant disease but he made
sure that my business did not crash and
I could never say anything bad about the
guy because of that and not only because
that he is at his base a good person
what's my favorite strain I have a lot
of favorite strains it just depends on
the time the day my mood etc
bodis one of my favorite human beings
not just breeder but one of my favorite
human beings on this earth what to
expect from platinum alien orange
cookies did you are you familiar with
the the the orange cookies from obsolete
I'm a I'm a grower not a shower
definitely not a short grower alien
orange cookies are you familiar with it
the orange cookies there's an astringent
phenotype in the line that is crazy
frosty really dense and it's it's the
the one phenotype I found that didn't
[ __ ] her tell Loompa to come on right
now while we still have some time - oh
man to get on I'd love to have him on
anytime
I love the looms bring them on but it
has like an astringent like almost it's
not even really that orange the
phenotype that I picked it's very
astringent very [ __ ] frosty very
dense and it breeds very well that mixed
with my platen of an animal that passes
over banana Terps like artificial banana
Terps you'll find everything in there
and in between if I could recommend one
of my strange to pop a pack what would
it be it depends on the person's grower
level orange cookies was full of [ __ ]
Herms it took a long time to find a
single cut that didn't pass on her
traits
it was [ __ ] really hard to find it
made it worth it to spend money on all
this packs
however yeah pretty much anything with
Caleo has some issues a skunk number one
crossed with the female p90 one with
time L is is it skunky all maybe just a
little
let's see 19 years ago that crossed with
the FEM of P 91 with time male I've kind
of confused on what you're asking
um you know psychedelic effect really
depends on your own brain chemistry what
might be psychedelic for me and trippy
for me may
not have that effect for you so it's
really hard to say there are certain
lines that are known to have that effect
for a majority of people be it Malawi
different Malawi is different Africans
but yeah
alien technology is in the alien Orange
cookies I believe I'm pretty sure aliens
orange cookies I don't remember but yeah
it's good [ __ ] man
that orange cookies cut is amazing but I
don't recommend running the seeds
because you will have a long hunt in
front of you what made me keep popping
packs when you get Herms I understand
cannabis science and and and how plants
work everything needs some acclamation
to an extent there are some lines that
hurt more than others and that just
means the lines are not as happy in
their current environment as other lines
would be some lines adapt better knowing
that full well if you find like one in
30 that aren't a herm it still usually
passes on her traits when you breed with
it that's why you have to run the
progeny to yourself to make sure that
that that trait didn't pass on yes did
an original Indian cookie strain correct
I didn't release it I let some out to a
few different people the strongest are
KS Terps would be the heirloom Afghani s
ones that to me had the strongest
descanse ray cam was really loved for
it's a scotch berry chirps as well uh it
was never really into peyote purple for
crossing I already had Bubba's that I
was working with
yeah
exactly I mean the her Michoud Rives me
nuts I see people complaining about
Herms
and what that tells to me first when you
see someone say man you look 10 packs
you know everything's [ __ ] herb that
says more about the person growing then
it does the whoever seeds here an an
experienced grower gets that should be
able to hear that and go oh you got a
[ __ ] problem dude that's not that
common to have that many [ __ ] homes
but even then man like if you're a
grower you're supposed to be able to
adapt this [ __ ] that's what good growers
do you see a herm you catch that [ __ ]
early cuz you pay attention to your
plants pay attention your [ __ ] plants
don't [ __ ] [ __ ] it's a part of
growing cannabis is an intersex plant by
Nature you know what I mean so just
handle your [ __ ] handle your business it
makes you look like a [ __ ] when you cry
so yeah but I mean if you if you spent
thousands on a line and you have not
found anything that won't herm and
you're not the only person having this
problem then there's a problem and it
needs to be addressed exactly you know I
mean that's how it goes but nine out of
ten times it's gonna be because it's not
happy in your room let it acclimate take
a clone from a clone from a clone if
that line is good enough to put that
much time into and you really see some
potential in it but it still has her
arms clone from a clone from a clone
acclimate it'll probably not happen
again nine times out of ten it won't
happen again
limelight is not is not a massive
yielder it's one of the Jack hairs that
has a smaller yield compared to typical
Jack hairs but the resin production
makes up for its yield tenfold
especially if you're an extract artist
and the lime the lime skunk is is insane
the lime skunk combo is insane I loved
it
same questions different feed you what's
your thought on breeders or even new
scope readers making profits off s ones
from kick-ass clones like lemon tree TK
to bring a Kim dog other than getting
beat up um there's a there's a time and
place for s ones you know I can't I
can't really call people out for that
because I mean early on in my career
that's what I did I would I would
reverse plants and cross them to popular
fun on the hybrids back then the clones
didn't get sent around the country as
often things were a lot more rare so at
that time there was a high demand for it
apparently now there's still a high
demand for it
I just wish like when people s one lemon
tree they'd call it what it is
it's [ __ ] lemon diesel you know well
you know get the names right at least
Topanga Canyon I don't even know who's
responsible for that so I don't see a
problem with us wanting that chem 91
that's a different story that's a
different story we know who was
responsible for that one the fact that
he isn't kicked down anything yet seeds
or anything that's a shame you know so
when I see chem 91 s ones I kind of that
that does kind of earth me yeah would
you say poly hybridization is a reason
for more firms occurring no I would say
it's from bad growers feeding the plants
like tomatoes
but yeah I mean when it comes to when it
comes to people of in reversed hybrids I
especially if it's a hybrid I I think
it's awesome especially if they know
what they're doing and they're good at
it you know what I mean if they're doing
it right why not then again I I don't do
a lot of reverse lines anymore I sell to
spray but I tend to stick with regulars
just because it's just what I like doing
it costs a lot more money to make
reverse to do to do reversals it costs a
lot more money less pollen people don't
realize how much more of a process it is
love you stray I still got to send you
your [ __ ] dad tools still have them
here for you yeah I have my press but I
haven't put it up because the landlord
walkthrough [ __ ] so yeah I don't I
haven't put anything up or used it
because of that it's gonna be a [ __ ]
hectic week I'll tell you that much it's
already been crazy trying to get all
this [ __ ] done why do people get so much
[ __ ] for making s ones that's a good
question and I think it's um I think
it's just misinformation for a long time
everybody was saying oh it's one sperm
feminize you turn the her a lot of the
time what people were seeing and they
were calling harm reversals were males
true males in a line
what's up Mean Gene I want to bring Mean
Gene on the show to what I want to I
want to have you on the show so many
people I want to have on what's the
difference between your heirloom Afghani
to roadkill's gun
well I had a roadkill Afghani and that
was my heirloom Afghani cross to
sourdough and I also did a version where
it was the male Afghani that passed on
the skunk tray cross to soured of is the
female but the main difference is one
has the sour dub in it and the other
doesn't sour dub did great at passing on
skunked herbs
it already has kind of a skunky Terp to
it when I grow it anyways it's very
skunky but not supersuit
skunky but because of that little bit of
skunk it really really absorbs a skunk
when crossed and that and that's cool to
see very underrated line very underrated
cut man I wanted to be at the San
Bernadino cup it this weekend my friend
bikes gonna be there but I don't know if
I'm gonna be able to make it because of
all the landlord [ __ ] going on it's
[ __ ] me in the ass not too stoked
about it
Mean Gene Mean Gene deck ice lays it
with the memes have you ever used an S
one male in a breeding project once in
the clockwork piff and it was it was
phenomenal he had a higher female to
male ratio which is you know kind of
cool but that was the only time I did it
it was an experiment and it turned out
to be good but I don't like using s 1
males too much do you ever hit the a fee
with the reverse cut I never got around
to it man I had a lot of trouble with
the a fee still having some trouble with
it I just lost the mom I have one single
cut of it left trying to root right now
and I'm gonna do my best to get it to
mewni to do some tissue culture with or
who else DSG labs one of those guys I'm
giving them to tissue culture it just so
it doesn't get lost it's an important
line but it's not very vigorous the
seeds were super [ __ ] old it's slow
but god damn it has amazing terms okay
however my max looking they're still
young man I've kept them in small pots
just because I was trying to finish this
last run and right now I don't know what
the future is for the immediate future
is anyway for that what is dumpster it's
usually a big box outside of a like a
convenience store you know a moon is the
boss mony is the boss that guy is a
tissue culture [ __ ] genius do the
strawberry switch made like to be pushed
out or left alone it depends on where
you're growing it and how you're growing
it
it grows completely different outdoors
than it does indoors the Terps also
change do you ever cut off mail shoots
with pollen sacks about to open and
isolate them to collect the pollen
better yeah that that can definitely be
a method for collecting pollen like you
know cut off a big branch to get in some
water so it's like a water cup so it's
easier to collect the pollen as opposed
to trying to move a tree around you know
yeah that's that's a definite good
option for it I remember the story about
dumpsters something about someone saw a
cannabis plant that like had been tossed
or a seedling or something they'd been
tossed right by a dumpster so they
picked it up kept it and whatever that's
the story I remember hearing I don't
know how accurate that is but that was
the can of Bible story if I remember
correctly anyone got the real purple
cush or grape ape from comp Chi I have
the sr-71 purple kush which is pretty so
close to herbal it's ridiculous and was
the other one Grape Ape I don't have
great paper anymore Bodie ran that a lot
and I used to run it I made Grape Ape a
swans I made a grape Apes our bubble
cross back in the day but I don't keep
the grape ape anymore it's very similar
again to Urkel with slightly more narrow
leaves
endure with LED on the switchblade I
really couldn't tell you I've never
grown under LEDs at all so I don't know
how she'll react
she's a very the switchblade is very
lanky very lanky so keep that in mind
very lanky it stretches a lot in Flour
those underdog purples are some of the
most ancient on earth I gotta tell you
got to tell ya what was the deal with
rehearsing the Uptown piff to make us
ones wasn't the restrictions on that the
only restriction that I had was that I
couldn't release it pure I didn't
reverse any pits I had the h1 the h2 h1
being the Frankie type H to being the
mango piff but I was never allowed to
release appear that was the only thing
that was never allowed to [ __ ] do and
I kind of wish I would have just done it
just to have to do a CD increase so I
didn't ever lose it so yeah I I don't
know man
but I just didn't want to piss off a
bunch of Dominicans that's not it's not
the way to go is have a bunch of
Dominican gangsters pista here loud
watermelon chirps Africa is the first
thing I think of when I think of like
melon like a blue melon type I growing
I've seen some watermelon skittles that
didn't have the watermelon Terps it was
more sweet F gooey definitely had melon
what about the watermelon hash plant
from Bodhi I believe that had some
watermelon phenotypes as well very hard
to grow indoor but definitely had the
watermelon chirps you know what like I
figure if I keep doing these eventually
more sales will come so yeah I guess
that's a way of getting picked it's fun
though man I like I like interacting
with everyone and it makes me happy when
my friends come in you know like we can
just shoot the [ __ ] and talk [ __ ] I mean
this is what I love I love talking
genetics I could do it all day
sour bubble as in gorilla I have never
heard of gorilla bubble I'm try
about sour bubble as in sour bubble it's
a bubble gum bubble gum line from bog
twitch gets you paid I need to look into
that [ __ ] I think I'm the last the
furthest thing for a cannabis therapist
I'm too chaotic people don't need that
[ __ ] yeah you can ask about springtails
does anybody here know anything about
springtails I I know absolutely nothing
about springtails
but does anybody here have any
experience with springtails my friend
here beard ed is having a little issue
with springtails and he wants to know
what's the deal with them like are they
beneficial are they all beneficial is
there a chance it could cause root
problems
I don't know who's gonna be at San
Bernadino and I know that selling seeds
is gonna be an issue in San Bernardino
it's not like it was even a few months
ago yes go to go to CSI Humboldt for the
underdog Oracle definitely was you just
giving multiple micro supplements like
mammoths and so yeah yeah definitely
feed feed your autos just like you would
a normal plant when it starts to flower
adjust and cut nitrogen oh there you go
there you go beard edie message cry-baby
organics about the spring tales he's
[ __ ] a an amazing brain for this
business an amazing brain what's the
[ __ ] deal with sell and seeds what's
HAP yes there's a problem selling seeds
it shows now especially in California
because they're saying that the
California met Burt is going to be going
around checking everyone's licenses to
sell set seeds if you're selling without
a license they're gonna have a [ __ ]
problem you're gonna be on a big radar
you don't want to be on best place to
pick up si si Humboldt seeds ooh I don't
have an answer for that I don't know
I'll ask him and get back to you on a
mmm feature feed what nutrients do I use
I use uh nod right now what am i using
NPK raw I mean it just really it tends
to be whatever I have around as long as
it has the correct NPK values that I
need I can use a plethora of different
nutrients I don't need a line spelled
out for me it's very very simple
um feeding cannabis plants is extremely
simple so so simple nitrogen with low PK
in veg high nitrogen low PK like a 5:1
one in blue you would be closer to a 155
or zero five five
it add cal-mag add some beneficials I
had some what's that stuff called and I
like a lot silly
so mono silicic acid you can you can add
in some B vitamins you know what I mean
like it's it's not too complex and then
carbs carbs of carbs and flour as well
it's not complex that the whole
hydroponic industry was based on people
it's like a bunch of used-car salesmen
man yeah C guy gotta have a nursery
permit Geno's yeah so yeah I think I
think the Emerald cup was the last big
rodeo I don't recommend Seed Vault
because I've watched them rip people off
before and then changed their name to
Seed Vault have you heard the term
unlocking your plant potential I've
heard it but I mean that could mean any
number of things you know I like the
term grow with your plant don't just
grow your plant grow with your plant I
like that a lot
because it's it's very true grow with
your plan how did I get the virus out of
my room when I lost everything
I didn't lose everything but most of
everything got hit I had to start from
scratch lots of bleach throw a lot of
way really really use some hardcore cans
back then to try to eradicate whatever
it was happening I just hit it with my
my black death potion and that's only to
be used in the most extreme
circumstances when you have like the
last of a last of a cut in existence in
the world and people are relying on you
to keep it alive that's when you use the
Black Death but you don't flower ever
from that plant you need a clone of a
clone of a clone of a clone to do that
but yeah what virus would you two look
like okay um the best way I can describe
this and I'm gonna tell you right now it
wasn't [ __ ] powdery mildew it wasn't
any kind of normal mold spore it didn't
really react
mold to mold treatments it looked like a
mail hit my whole room and a layer of
pollen was sitting on all the leaves you
could wash it off it would go away you
come back two hours later and there it
was again
it was [ __ ] weird it was weird
so I trusted to do trim the Philippines
to send me a clone and what exists in
the Philippines doesn't necessarily
exist in the American cannabis world and
what the clone was that I got it from I
didn't see a little anything too shaky
on it you know but it may have already
built up a resistance being a Filipino
landrace so yeah that's that's wild I
tried everything with it and eventually
the last two cuts were saved but I had
to go get clockwork back from someone
else
I had to get a lot of stuff back from
other people I'd passed it to and if
you've been in that situation you know
how hard that can be
all right I need to get ready for the
giveaway so here's how the giveaway
works go like the post that I posted
earlier that announced this exact yeah
Danny Danny oh wait that mother [ __ ] go
like this post that announced this live
feed if you like it you're in it for the
shi'ite the free sheet I'll be sending
out some unreleased stuff that I did and
that I'm really stoked about stuff that
I've never released before so you'll be
eligible as long as you like that thing
and brynn will throw your names into a
random generator and it'll pick one and
that's who gets it so I wanted to
announce that before I closed anything
down I don't know when the alerts gonna
pop up but I imagine kind of soon so
yeah I want I want someone to get that
so though your throw your your [ __ ] in a
hat man and no one's not eligible I mean
unless you want it in the past two times
please don't join it because you're
already getting [ __ ] but I want everyone
to be eligible for this yeah so
again go like the post that announced
tonight's live feed and that's the best
way to do it for those who don't know
yet my live feeds are now going to be on
YouTube I put the one from what's up
fire Fino how you doing brother I put
the one from last night up on YouTube so
that's there and this one will be up on
YouTube as well I love that term cut of
their jib did you know that a jib is a
sail and it was an old sailors term when
you like the cut of someone's jib it
means you like the cut of their sail
little did little did you know now you
may have known but I feel smarter saying
it YouTube does blow but it's the only
way you can re-watch this video or watch
it for the first time if you miss it so
I want to make sure that people can have
access to this stuff the youtube link go
look up right seed cove on youtube i
believe that's my name on youtube you
corny [ __ ] yeah right Seco look up I
think it's there right right it seeds
podcast or something like that right
sees live feed and it should show up
there's only one up there right now
Mooney will be doing a another live feed
this Friday so if you missed any of the
tissue culture stuff we're gonna review
a lot of that so we can save it and put
it up on YouTube so definitely come
check those out especially if you're I
mean I can't tell you how rare it is to
have someone with Muniz experience that
teaches all of the guys who owned and
run the big labs come and give you this
information for free that guy makes
thousands and thousands and thousands
per hour for consults so definitely
definitely definitely come check it out
man like and like I said when it comes
to him it's the only time I ask you
bring your [ __ ] a game bring your A
game it's just important man like it
shows
a nice level of respect when you've done
your research and you come in here and
you don't ask crazy [ __ ] you know that
you could ask the [ __ ] some nerd at a
[ __ ] hydroponic store save the
questions for the Nerds at the
hydroponic store that you couldn't ask
me or Mooney otherwise you know what I
mean yeah so any more questions time
isn't out yet so let's let's get the
questions going oh oh also when this is
over go to my buddy other Cuban breeders
live feed watch him
learn some [ __ ] how many of these folks
would get together if 10 or 15 of us for
you I think a lot of people would do it
man it's just a matter of getting us
together to do it in one area where it
can all make it
do you believe Adam Dunn's bubblegum
story no I definitely think tissue
culture as a future in a method that
will either stop or prolonged Rick yep
um tissue culture is the way of the
future
absolutely is cloning is going to be a
thing of the past and there will always
be a place for cloning for quick-quick
clones but tissue culture is the way of
the future
gibberellic acid versus STS for
feminizing I would think GA 3 would work
better and you are incorrect GA 3 is
much less effective GA 3 is great for
stretching plants however GA 3 doesn't
necessarily block ethylene on its own
you need something that's not only gonna
increase gibberellic acid in the plant
but will also block ethylene and that's
where STS comes into play you have a DNA
holy grail yeah I wouldn't even admit
that [ __ ] out loud freak I wouldn't
admit that [ __ ] out loud on it some DNA
[ __ ]
yeah man it's it's a matter of of trying
to get us all together in the same spot
that's all it is man a lot of there are
plenty of us that get along that that
are very educated they can do a show
together but it's it's a matter of
getting us to a place where we'll travel
to because frankly we're a bunch of
[ __ ] Hermits we're a bunch of [ __ ]
Hermits for real total [ __ ] Hermits
and we don't get out very often most of
us can't leave our plants long enough to
get away that long yeah his cult
classics are KS for me I don't think so
I don't know where there's this room
yeah come to me let's throw one in
Bakersfield and I'll get arrested it
would be awesome I you know I'm I'm
waiting for sub cool - come on I've been
waiting since April first and for some
reason he hasn't gotten back to me oh
wait I think is that sub cool do your
sub cool coming hold on sub cool where
are you
hey man I'm dying I'm [ __ ] dying the
doctor told me I didn't get a [ __ ]
transplant cuz I'm not dying but I'm
telling you what I'm still [ __ ] dying
and it's ramen [ __ ] thanks for coming
sub thanks for coming by
thanks for coming by sub cool stay chill
brother and that was a true statement
from him so yeah I wasn't just saying
that to be mean that is actually what
happened went to the doctor to get a
lung transplant and they said dude
you're not that bad come back later to
even get on the list so anybody who
talks about him dying or using excuse
for him dying we are all [ __ ] dying
we've all been dying since the day we
were born and I don't think he's any
much [ __ ] closer than I am with my
fat ass what do I think the og bags he
came from I would say so
Super Skunk of some sort crossed with
probably tie Super Skunk I could
probably recreate that or uh Super Skunk
Mexican tie anyone else noticed that sub
wears the same yeah well meth does that
math does that Oh G came from Bob I'll
never forget that one what else we got
what else we got
but yeah Blackbeard have have have Lou
Pokemon made with me man me and loompa
do good playing off each other it's
funny I was one of the best Adam done
shows ever when it was me and Loompa
just being [ __ ] crazy
well I was being crazy cuz I was high on
a lot of xanax and that that's for real
a little [ __ ] up used a few choice
words kind of being stupid wasn't making
much sense but yeah lemon tree oh gee
I'm not sure what lemon tree oh gee is
is that the same things lemon tree but
the original lemon diesel is lemon tree
and it was it super super Airy it might
be too much cal-mag or nitrogen and in
defeating I know it doesn't like that
like most most most narrow leaf dominant
plants long what happened cry-baby I did
I miss it your question oh we got a
minute remaining I wasn't paying
attention one minute remaining pom pom
pom ball what's up loops next time come
on earlier and we could do a show
because because our shits funny anyway
yep everyone if you want to get in for
the [ __ ] giveaway go like the [ __ ]
go like the the post I did about this
show throw your name in the Hat get some
unreleased [ __ ] looms tomorrow let's do
a show together
oh wait where's my outro
[Music]