hates it when i do that
hates it he's like trying to sleep next
to me like this [ __ ]
this loud ass music
no that was harry j all-stars old
skinhead reggae stuff
putting bob marley to [ __ ] shame
anyways here we go
so
i'll let the i'll let people join before
i get started um
the clowns yeah it can sound a little
bit like baby elephant walk a little bit
sometimes um
so where this all started
last night
was i was
looking up original diesel
and uh
you know i have this i have this old
clone had it for a long time i lost it
during the mooney thing matt from elite
cannabis set it back
um
and it was it's called original diesel
it's been it's been the original diesel
that i used for the original diesel bx1
lots of projects and the other day
someone asked me yo yo
what's the source on it
you know
i'm not sure what the source is on this
um i remember shrumi's diesel being
listed as original diesel but shrumi's
diesel is different
oh
thank you dear
there we go
um
so i started i started digging around
and what
i found was [ __ ] crazy
and i realized you know what like people
that don't
really have a
a long experience in this when they
actually go try to look up something
they need to know who is who
how to really
sift through the [ __ ] so i decided i
would go uh
i would go do that
yes the image is good let's see do you
think mr nice super silver haze uh is
still the original appearance you used
in the scentsy silver haze
um
now shanti says yes
i don't know i don't know
by the way um for the people joining and
everything i said that uh
i would give out a coupon
i think this is it
oh yeah no it's this here's the coupon
code for 35 off everything except the
spray uh it's pre pre 420
is there anywhere to get authentic
supersore haze uh old people's uh
collections is about it i would say man
because the super sur hayes coming out
of shanty [ __ ] is nothing like um
what you would expect his old super
silver haze granted you could go find
old jack carol lines you'd get similar
phenotypes i would say mango haze from
mr nice would be a good one
there's the coupen
um i i might try to archive it on
youtube i'm not sure if i'm gonna do it
but we'll see
but as i go through this i'm not gonna
be taking more questions on other stuff
so
uh just so i can stay focused i'm going
to be putting this up so try to keep
your uh questions focused on what i'm
i'm presenting in this because i get i'm
i'm [ __ ] uh
adhd you know it's really
it's really hard to keep focused on
anything anyways let's see
god damn this [ __ ] phone
let's see
wake up druggy
krish people making no sense let's see
where do i start with the stupidity
now that would be the diesel stuff
yeah yeah
um anyways so this is uh where we start
boom
and unfortunately i can't shrink this so
i'm going to have to
let's see i'll bring some stuff up on um
my computer because this is obviously
not going to work great if i can't
[ __ ] shrink it
but so you guys can get an idea of what
i'm looking for
so
the the first thing i type in
would be about original diesel okay
let's see uh go to google and type in
original
diesel
strain right that that would be
what most people would uh
would do it
so
some of the first stuff i'm seeing
is that dr underground is the breeder
and original breeder of
diesel
well that's [ __ ] weird right like dr
underground from what i know about dr
underground he's a he's a british dude
he's a [ __ ] british dude
yeah i don't think he was the one who
bred original diesel so now this is seed
finder
um that'll that'll give you your answer
on whether this is a good source or not
um no it's not
second thing i see
original sour diesel comes up
and that's not original sour diesel
that's not what sour diesel looks like
either and that's from swerve
so thank you swerve for
sticking [ __ ] up in here
let's see what else we got
okay
let me get in let me find this one
um so we get into thc farmer now
um thc farmer a lot of times like when
it comes to diesels chems ogs you're
gonna find a lot of um topics uh
conversations on
diesels chems ogs stuff like that
specific cuts and a lot of people that
pretty much think that they know every
[ __ ] thing about
cannabis there let's see thc farmer
especially during a certain era original
day record diesel
this is the uh
this is the
uh
hold on i can't read [ __ ] let me put it
back here
this is the original diesel day wrecker
thread
um you can see it up in the corner
on the farm someone says
i'm a bit confused here
when i try to find info on the strain it
comes up saying it's the same cut as
diesel number one
headband
underdog
day wrecker but i was told they're
different if anyone can clear this up
that would be cool and that's a valid
question that's a valid question man
a lot of people say that that it's day
wrecker diesel number one headband that
they're all the same cut
so
then they give someone comes back
someone named indica
tilda whatever that whoop sign is tor
don't know who this person is
um
i found this in my archives i hope it
helps up
so this is where where someone first
brings up in this thread the grateful
dead show quotes uh about dear creek
amphitheater about wang kenobi
the aka joe brand [ __ ] um and talk
about peabud chemdog that whole thing
how many seeds were popped how many
seeds were labeled what
and uh
but yeah it still doesn't get down to
the
um
answer so it lists you know all the chem
dog crosses original diesel here we go
also known as diesel number one headband
day record diesel underdog came from a
cross of 91 chem dog crossto
mass super skunk cross to northern
lights done by a guy known as weasel
okay so that's that's probably been the
most common and
answer when referring to this
up until a little bit later up until a
little bit later
now
down a little bit further
jj new york has been working on a chem
dog d based seed line for several years
now
he started crossing a chem dog d to
scentsy afghani number one
after thoroughly testing both senses
afghani and sensei's hindu kush to
determine which was more stable and
would be better for the initial cross jj
then did a back cross known as double
dog several phenos of this blah blah
down under trade trade nothing to do
with diesel
this is all to do with uh chem dog d
reservoir seeds res dog of reservoir
seeds recent release to chem dog cross
or several chem dog crosses as far as
part of his trinity
trinity
uh charity options the crosses included
chem dog d
cross descent uh scentsy's hindu kush
and snow dog crossed a sensei's hindu
kush chem dog d sour d ibl snow dog
and um
this all goes back to
the chem 101 thread by my friend heian
lonesome so he did what i think is
probably the best
compendium of answers uh that could be
given at that time and then someone
quoted him in this and and mad props to
high and lonesome for trying to dig
through all that [ __ ] and put
the most common consensus answers out
there during those years now he he gives
him uh
he gives himself a real hard time
because he knows that you know a lot of
things have changed over the years and
stuff but for the time it still is still
pretty magical that someone could put
all that into a
a nice area i mean he goes through
the chem dog crosses being og sour
diesel all this is correct uh super snow
dog diesel bubble cab dog days chem dp
bud stuff like that
all right
so
is that the answer though is the answer
that is just uh what is it um
chem 91 mass super
um northern lights well
read on
quote from green green thumb danny on
thc farmer
yeah d9 brother
diesel day wrecker headband all the same
[ __ ] slap whatever handle you like on
her
boo i see my old buddy estates on here
um estortes was actually one of the
first people to pass me the white really
cool dude
um he passed me the white dj's flow and
dj's blueberry not a lot of people
remember his name but he's a really good
dude
there's a fake headband going around the
club scene aka
707 headband and this is this is correct
it's a sour diesel og cross by all
accounts not the same lindy lineage as
the indie posted above
bryn is obsessing over this
all right
look for aj's cut on oh god don't i i
looked for aj's got a thc farmer that is
not worth
that is not worth navigating through um
let's see as far as i know the real
headband underdog is closely held and
not in the club scene currently and that
is correct to start days
inject some uh
inject some nice info
okay and then we have my buddy true grit
on here it's funny because he messaged
earlier
damn funny this thread popped up today
i've been looking for day record info
for a couple days that or maybe i get
stoned to see it on here forget it was
on here and then search more anyone make
any s-ones along the way that still
float around or is it locked up clone
only so he was on the same
on the same search in 2009 trying to
find info about um that and he goes into
the name uh los tesoros real really good
guy really smart guy
he's been on the boards a long time so
he he asked like after i posted that i
was going to do this he was like oh
great is it going to be a lot of people
saying what they think and a lot of
[ __ ] and
yep
all right
so let me scroll down
now a person named da farmer
no lumpa did not have the real headband
every site i get on there is always some
stupid uneducated debate on the chem dog
genetics this is the first time i truly
feel as if someone has done their
research i commend you brother indicator
we appreciate it
okay
so i'm gonna keep scrolling down
and then there are some quotes about um
this is the guaranteed original s chem
dog
uh
with skunk va cut which skunked va cut
is the original chem 91 it's got the
best provenance out of everyone
see that was a guy named reaper then
someone's showing no off their booth
and then someone's showing hid band
headband
um
but basically it all takes this weird
curve into the headband realm right
okay let's see
let's see one second here
and then we go to chem dog's original
diesel
so we're gonna go to a different thread
because this one is is already done
that's that's all the info you're gonna
get there let's see chem dogs
original
diesel
headband
that should take me straight to the
thread and see yeah here it is so this
is the one that i i went through the
most and i thought it was worth showing
the most let me see what we got the
blind leading the deaf is exactly right
if ja hoover's profile is still in there
i think he did a thread of aj jaw hoover
is and and ojd i'll go through this i
actually kept pictures because neither
of those guys deserve to be mentioned on
anything about anything they're [ __ ]
retards all right here we go
i i gave ojd a lot more credit than i
should have because he's just been
around a long time i figured he wouldn't
be a [ __ ] [ __ ] by now right but
i i digress
and then someone says original diesel
gives the same quote also known as
diesel 1 headband daywrecker underdog
came from a cross of 91 chem dog mass
super scentsy northern lights done by a
guy known as weasel
now what they
didn't know back then is that weasel
would eventually come out and talk
um
he speaks
um and he's around he's on instagram
it's uh
not looking so good for all weasel
weasel can't keep his story straight
twice
um and a lot of this
uh
i don't know it's
there's been there's been quite a few
different quotes from him since then
anyways and i don't know if it's it's a
matter of um
i'm gonna block y'all jeffy because he's
[ __ ] getting on my nerves let's see
there we go
no
weasel has made several different quotes
i don't know if it's attributed to age
whether um
whether it's
it's being stoned i don't know but you
can't get the same story right twice so
that's a problem right
all right so let's go ahead and go
through the farm and we're gonna see
more about this original diesel
here we go venom eight one eight
i've seen many dispensaries but i'm not
sure it's a chem dog cut did progressive
options say where they sourced it
the original d and this is here's here's
our buddy swerve here's our buddy swerve
the original diesel cut going around to
socal is shroomie's original diesel it's
good but not the real cut
so we have swerve chiming in with some
info there
thank you swerve
and then uh venom 818 responds thanks
for the input swerve do you know where i
can get some seeds or a cut in pure form
so
swerve has now put himself as a uh an
expert in this area and people are
asking him for cuts and
info on seeds why not
and then we have winter who says top dog
siege just had a couple packs of
underdog number one on the bay a week
ago i quickly got a pack because i was
searching like you might do now this is
in 2010.
um
i'm not sure when the original diesel
day wrecker cut
aka
if it is the same cut as underdog
was that around in 2010
i don't know
then someone named eco comes in and
probably one of the smartest things
that the original diesel story seems
super complicated with info
as to which ones are out or by who found
this on a chem thread it's interesting
here we go
now this was
this post that's up there in the right
corner right now
this one right here
the weird thing that shroomy's original
d clone is not the same as chem dog's
headband well that would be weird right
if shroomies d if swerve was right that
shroomy's original diesel
is the one going around and it's the
same thing as headband but it's not the
same thing as chem dog's headband
well
kem dog himself
has said to me multiple times that he
never had a headband never grew a
headband so that throws a little wrench
in the uh
in the in the problem
it says chem doug smoked out swerve and
a friend of mine located in santa
barbara california with a batch of
headband and bo said it was basically
straight up og kush completely different
than the original diesel cut i am very
confused by the whole headband day
record stuff because i've been seeing
more and more of the og cush-esque
headband flooding santa barbara norcal
growers in fact kim dog even told my
buddy in santa barbara something along
the lines that this is og bro yet this
is head yet this headband is another
headband than the cut that's been going
around the boards for a while now
jj new york wrote a description of the
original headband day wrecker underdog
and it sounded a bit like or a lot like
the original d-clone he said it smelled
spicy skunky diesely taste jj also said
i don't think chem dog ever had an
underdog headband cut
so what the hell is this og-ish
headband cut that cam has that's
flooding the socal medical scene right
now so overall like um
what what you can illustrate here is
when anybody asks about the original
diesel so far what keeps happening is
that it gets moved on to day record yep
uh
bye-bye it gets moved on to day wrecker
uh unless and unless you know guys like
my buddy el jefe there have something to
add instead of just being a [ __ ] then
they get booted because i'm trying to
stay focused here anyway
it always gets uh shoved off man like
you try to go for original diesel you'll
get info on headband headband headband
um and there's no there's nothing but
the can of bible stating that they're
all the same
it gets convoluted real quick and i can
see why it's hard for a lot of people to
go research a lot of this stuff that
weren't around during all this
um
someone asked joe brand your outdoor cut
or your original diesel cut is the same
as the shroomie got passed around this
is actually true juan's original diesel
is the same exact cut streaming source
from pennsylvania which i've heard is
different than diesel 1d record and
underdog cuts so just more confusion
with uh
with that
um now venom1818 says good read bro now
i'm more confused
right like who wouldn't be
um
and then some and then sway says i've
noticed that pretty much every cut from
progressive options has been fake now
progressive options was an old uh clone
only collective in
l.a
um not even that old wasn't even that
long ago that they were still in
operation but a lot of people uh went
and got cuts from there and bred with
them snow hi
and uh several other people went down
there and got cuts because that was
easier obviously than sourcing them
correctly and a lot of them were fake
um
and then we have dusty bowls aka danimal
aka backyard farmer aka
however many mean however many names he
needs to try to stay in
in this business because he's [ __ ] so
many people over i hooked up juan kenobi
with the with the s420 original diesel
the shroomie 420. now shroomy i wish i
would i should have kept this i have a
picture of him um
he's a sex predator
pop for [ __ ] little kids so
shroomies not the most reliable source
but i mean just because you [ __ ] little
kids doesn't mean that you [ __ ]
backdoor farmer it doesn't mean that you
know you can't be trusted on clones but
i don't like kid [ __ ] so [ __ ] ruby
right all right last year this is a
shapeshifter january 19 2010.
yeah that part [ __ ] sucks but what
are you gonna do last year cush corner
used to ven dayrecker the double dog
snow dog cat piss unfortunately they
were shut down otherwise everyone else
has that 707 good but different don't
know what that means
um then we get down to let's see where's
the where's uh the lumpa part let's
let's go answer some lumpa questions
there it is
in kkk hills let's see what let's see
where we're at here so this is some of
the other stuff let's see swerve there
there's swerve
there there's the quote so you guys know
i'm not just
putting it out i mean he these are his
words not mine
[ __ ] turd
uh let's see where we at here
shapeshifter there's the cush corner
quote
uh
huh that guy was a fraud it's worth
calling someone else a fraud
don't be lost come back
you'll be okay moda militia
spelled terribly lumpa's headband is the
is it the same there's a question
so now we go back to the moda militia
lumpus headband now if if
we conclude and there's no reason to
conclude this other than jason king that
diesel number one is the same as
original diesel as the same as day
wrecker is the same as headband
etc
where does lumpa's headband fit in
um i'll go back to the jj response so
basically he just repeats what someone
else said
um
no lumpa's headband
was not sourced and it it was not
sourced in a way that can be
proven
um loompas said a few different things
he said that it was stolen from a place
in new york smuggled in someone's pocket
to him
right um
he puts it back
i forgot what yuri said but it was
something he said it was the very first
og kush to show up on the boards which
is very incorrect
um
it is an og kush it's it's got some sour
traits to it but it's definitely an og
kush it is nothing related to the old
original diesel
yes uh yeah inspector used the lumpa's
headband which is the correct term for
it
only because it's not headband it's not
the original headband um but
yeah that's actually one of the best
lines that i've run um of the lumpa's
headband crosses is the oracle underdog
that shit's bomb
and then they move this over
it jumps over to um what is this it's a
a double underdog
why anybody's talking about double
underdog other than the fact that it has
underdog in the name i'm not sure
it's obviously not original diesel
it is a seed line and then there's a
person named dub wobble let me let me
find this one
dub wobble let's get to the dub wobble
part
there's the double underdog swerve
double underdog where's dub wobble
should be right about here
yeah
i don't think there's any seeds of pure
headband at least i've never seen them
i've had a cut of headband for five
years now
it is it is not og
it is not chem dog d
it is not sour diesel it is way closer
to sour diesel than og and
characteristics
i have been i have seen the so-called og
phenotype i believe that someone got
their cuts mislabeled and are actually
growing og the structure just isn't the
same as the diesel type headband
so that's again
a little bit more clarity from someone
that kind of knows what they're talking
about that has had the original diesel
cut but
it's really hard to figure out
and real headband is not og again not og
um different different area of the
country wasn't called headband at the
time it's not og
and then dub wobble says the 707 is not
headband at least not what harborside or
blue sky passes out by the way for every
everyone that pm's about trading i'm not
able to pbm back blah blah blah
and then we have venom coming back in
yes the 70k 707 cuts definitely bomb but
i don't consider it real headband
and then we go back to joe schmoe's
double underdog cut for a while
gotta keep scrolling down because people
are still talking about that
and then someone bringing up underdog
number one and then green thumb danny
now green dumb green dumb fanny
is a better name for him
he does consider himself quite an
authority and a lot of people consider
him quite an authority on this site for
some reason i'm not sure why
um
and then it's it's him talking about
again double underdog and joe's cut
throwing balls and then he calls someone
porch monkey but i think that was their
name um
yeah
they every every single subject no one
takes it back to the hey wait a minute
are we talking about [ __ ] original
diesel here how the [ __ ] did we get to
all these other topics
let's see
i'm trying to find
uh the next part
um we have cowabunga ron
to confuse it up even more
see
empress fire starters and candy kush
big l don't you have some of those beans
already i've seen you write that in
another thread just wondering man i
would have popped those immediately so
what he's referring to empress fire
starters candy kush candy kush is
another name for or the candy cut really
is another name for lumpus headband
empress was a candy lumpus headband
um
yeah so it's nothing here nor there
trying to find if there's anything else
to reference in here real quick and then
we'll move on to the next uh the next
quote
we have power og showing up who's a
[ __ ] [ __ ]
um
he says go look at lumpa's forum to see
about the real and only underdog cut i
know of from lumpa himself i know thcs
is selling another real or another not
real underdog right now i'm running cali
connect 818 headband which i think is
swerve's creation guy's a [ __ ] [ __ ]
yeah and and it's hard for people to do
this research that go on that have these
questions that need these answers and
they don't know who these character our
characters are and how well they can be
trusted and um
this is a shining example of uh being
able to go through this thread navigate
it
as best you can
and see if you can find the answers and
by the end of it we have power og
talking about
more lumpas headband and uh
yeti and how we got it from the man and
it's the real deal and that's where it
ends
so
let's go to the next one
let's see
where's the neck where's my next one
this is my favorite my personal fave
all right back it up back it up where's
out here they are
and then i gotta find the original pose
though
let's see
that's not it that's icy mag what about
this one
there we go
so this is what uh
this is what
[Music]
on th from original sour diesel cutting
so
looking up original diesel this is where
i [ __ ] keep ending up right sour
diesel [ __ ] like that this is started by
th gobbs my old buddy
t.h gobs right
yeah i did uh a skunk va that's exactly
kind of what i was
i was i was getting to is like
man
people have all these questions and i'm
like dude go do some research go do some
[ __ ] research and then i realized
this is what i send them to
anyway th gobs original sour diesel now
this guy is also known as nyc kid this
is michael tech's best friend um this is
the guy passing the asian fantasy cut
and the blue asian fantasy cut
this is his original sour diesel clone
what do you guys think
pretty [ __ ]
pretty sick huh
pretty sick for a sour
there's some more shots whoa look at
that sour
sour
anyway
oddly enough everybody blasts him on the
thread and he never says another thing
again it's one of the few times where
i'm like wow everybody didn't just buy
into it and go [ __ ] that's dank that's
[ __ ] awesome so let's move on to uh
let's move uh
this is this is actually a really good
guess if that plant is a clone only my
guess would be f gooey i wouldn't say
blue dream that doesn't look like blue
dream to me um afgooey is even a stretch
but it's it's a better guess than sour
all right and here's here's pictures of
ecsd
there you go
they're sour
anyway so let's move it over to ic mag
because at that point
that's what you got you know so here we
go original diesel
hello connoisseur this is ojd he's
referring to in ja hoover
i was just wondering if there are any
pictures of original diesel that you use
is it the same as underdog day wrecker
etc now these guys are over in in
england and and what a lot of people
don't know and they take for granted i
think is the fact that these guys it's
really hard to get clones over the pond
even still
um it's still really hard to get clones
over the pond so a lot of times they're
only using seed lines
and and so nowhere know where things are
being made know who is making them
and uh you'll have a better idea of
whether it's legit or not just uh
it's it's
it helps you break down the process of
whether these guys are going to have
legit [ __ ] or not so
going and sourcing american clones over
from british breeders probably isn't
going to be your best bet
anyway so this guy's asking him hey is
this is this the same as the american
original diesel i mean it should be
you're calling it original diesel right
you're calling it underdog and day
wrecker right
all right so
next let's see where was i
boom oh jd hi bro
i don't think it's exact same cut as you
posted i don't have any pictures handy
but i'll try to dig one up later and
post it
yeah well
here's the pictures jah hoover chimes in
here are some shots of the original
diesel ojd uses this was sourced by dna
genetics and was passed out to our
friends this kind of verified to be the
real deal original diesel
by the big dogs in the game
dna being the big dogs here you go
here's some uh
shots
not sure what it is
but they put up plenty shots of
something i'm guessing it's uh some res
work it looks like a super sour silver
diesel haze
to me
that's what i would assume it is
not sure i mean granted they grow
shittily so it's hard to tell but it's
definitely not
it
and here's just the the typical picture
results when you look up original diesel
right none of none of which are it
closest one is that middle one that
looks a little similar to it but it's a
little more bulky in structure looks a
lot more like uh
it looks a lot more like jesus let me
show you a picture of jesus
let's see
just for illustration purposes
uh what's a good dee geezel picture like
that there you go
that's like a uh diesel i think it's a
glass one but here's a diesel picture
that's that's much more uh what you
would expect and it's more mimics the
original diesel look um
so yeah overall
this is what happens when you you search
this [ __ ] out
and as you see there were many people
that chimed in that have respect in our
community that are raiders that um are
his cannabis historians uh and and and
putting their input on it and you see
and granted you know what a lot of info
has come out in the past
10 years about these these lines uh what
they are what they aren't and uh so so
you can't hold it against them they're
trying to use what info they had at that
point but you can hold it against swerve
because he's a [ __ ] [ __ ] um you can
hold it against green thumb danny
because he's a [ __ ] [ __ ] and
they're speaking in in facts and and
like this is definitely this this is
definitely that
uh
um
doesn't gage green work with the day
wrecker cut who [ __ ] knows what he's
working with he probably sourced it from
dusty bowles would be my guess backyard
backdoor farmer danimal that dude
i'll try to leave it up for viewing i
don't i have a hard time saving these
after i do them so they need to be
uploaded to youtube and stuff so if one
of you wants to do that and
and pass me the file i'll be happy to
put it up
weasel story i know weasel crossed
scentsy northern lights to a diesel chem
91 this became the underdog aj then
renamed underdog to headband well we
have some issues with that too we have
some issues with that too because jj new
york has also said that he named a
headband
we don't know who named it headband
aj and jj are very good friends
i'm not calling either one of them a
liar one of them probably did maybe
maybe
but uh we're not sure which because they
both take the claim to it
all right let me see what i miss now
the exodus cheese cut camera skunk one
seed pack in eighties that is correct
germinator two did i miss something
earlier
it didn't come from a collective in
luton and milo
didn't put it out in the racing not
facts at all
yeah it came from skunk one
um
selected director i talked to jj years
back said he lost it way back never gave
a clone out neither said it was extinct
that's what i've heard too you know but
um
pretty much everybody says everything's
extinct that they no longer have access
to in that little circle so it's hard to
say you know
i've seen cam dog refer to headband and
his own stuff and then i've heard i've
seen kem dog also say that he's never
run headband but it's usually other
people referring to chem dog having
headband as opposed to kim saying he ran
headband so that's a hard one
um
what else was there
the extinct mass super skunk i found a
picture of it last night
um
supposedly it's supposed to be the best
the diesel is supposed to be the best
representation of mass skunk but i saw
some pictures last night and i was like
wow that doesn't really look like
anything that i remember seeing
anything close
yeah i i'm not sure why headband and day
record got stuck together other than the
can of bible and people [ __ ]
read that book and they stick to it
religiously
religiously anything said in the can of
bibles got to be true um and it's just
so many things have been proven to be
incorrect in that in that book and again
it was a long time before there was a
lot of info out there and a lot of these
guys were talking so they're pro
probably trying to make best
do with what they could but jason king
had some good access to people
so he you
know yeah gran supposedly ran the diesel
now the one thing when researching um
when researching
diesel
the one thing after talking to all the
dudes involved is that no one on the
diesel side from the new york side says
that they for sure had the chem 91
what it turned out to look like was that
they have chem 91 bag seed
and that was what was used to then
call diesel so it would have been a
little bit different than chem 91
beard ed i don't yeah i don't know
that's what the that's what the source
says up there about old dr underground
let's see
i don't know that he claimed it but he's
uh the first person that comes up for
having created it so
someone say diesel
hold on i'm trying to find some
this masked skunk picture now this the
picture i'm looking for was taken from
chem dog's
room and was shown in high times of it
god damn
too many [ __ ] pictures of [ __ ] on
here
but yeah that's the best we could tell
it's either it's either a backseat of
chem 91 or chem 91 that was called
diesel
uh i i would believe the bag seed story
that's more likely to have happened as
opposed to the cut just being passed
but yeah
it's hard to say um so
overall what the answer ends up being is
who [ __ ] knows
i got
nothing i got no answers going through
all that [ __ ] not a single answer
worth going over there's the mask skunk
that's supposed to be the mass super aka
the virginia super skunk
um
it's gunfield does that look like the
the virginia super skunk
i know it's kind of a shitty picture let
me try to swap it
there we go you can kind of see it up in
the corner hopefully it's not too small
there it is up in that corner it's
really airy i don't know if it's just
that yeah it's not the best grow of it
so it's really hard to say
it has similar leaves to the diesel but
god damn it's it's pretty airy so yeah
it's hard to say this is uh
this is from uh
greg's room i believe
mystery seed from the kmd
i wonder what that was
it does look like it was hating life
doesn't it
these are all the other pictures
i don't know who's ringing my doorbell
right now kim's sister lay down murray
lay down lay down
murray get over here
get over here
anyway yeah that was uh that's what i
wanted to run through um
it was it was a fun trip down memory
lane going through [ __ ] old uh
the big dogs are coming for me the big
dogs are like what the [ __ ] this [ __ ]
guy just gave away all our secrets
i think it is gunky i think it's around
2005.
when you when you can't explain the
difference between all 14 real chem d
plants being passed around
yeah that's a rough one let's go see
who's at the door because i'm sure brynn
didn't hear that
let's go see
stay
or if it's the uh
dancing habibi
[Music]
oh it's the the cartel lady lovely
something to do with the box
i'm sure brynn loves talking to her
anyway anyway anyway back to what we
were doing
oh swears going to threaten to quit the
business you guys don't have enough
respect for me
i've done so much
swerve
oh man didn't i put that naked picture
of him somewhere up here
i might be able to even post it again
i don't want to dig all the way back to
the beginning of my [ __ ] but i thought i
took a screenshot of it and made a
smiley face on his nipples for him
i did there we go guys there you go
that swerve who is swerve that swerve
i'm just gonna keep sitting here
clapping
notice the kid's toy in the background
that's my favorite
that's my favorite almost as good as
that [ __ ]
oh lord i don't have so much of that
what was that about
yeah i know what did they want they
wanted their kids and yet flowers
they got our books oh and they're like
do you have our kids
i said no ma'am
no we don't have your quinceanera
flowers ma'am
here give them to me i want to see what
they are it's my book oh it's your books
oh [ __ ]
anyway i've been trying to write to two
currents for about 10 minutes i can't
[ __ ] write on this thing
two currents thank you for the pictures
of my brendie so it's beautiful
and thank you for what you said it's
very kind there you go i appreciate your
sweetheart
there you go you're killing it
there you go
anyway um yeah so that was that was our
buddy swerve
i had to bring it back up because he's a
[ __ ] [ __ ] and he you know whatever
anyway so the whole point of this was to
show like
i've kind of been a dick like when i
tell people go research it man why
aren't you [ __ ] researching it why
are you asking me why don't you go
[ __ ] research it like when i started
snapping on people um i'm sorry some
[ __ ] you just can't research it's not
there the answers aren't there you have
to go to the root
the the root of the sources you know you
have to go back you to talk to the clops
the the weasels uh
you know i wouldn't recommend talking to
aj you're not going to get the same
answer twice you have to go back and
talk to these guys um
don't bug skunk va though because uh you
don't like being bugged just kidding um
no don't go don't go be impolite in
asking this don't
expect stuff but you know be respectful
when you're asking and that and that's
the whole thing
um
there's no answer to the original diesel
what what this cut is where it came from
is it the day wrecker is it the original
diesel number one i don't think it is
because i remember everybody saying that
the original diesel number one including
vondo said this that it died very early
on
um
is it headband probably not headband
seems to be a different cut than the
original diesel
um
i just i'm guessing that it's not the
same thing and it's not the same cut
that
i see collective and the elite crew have
his headband so
uh i wanted to break that down if
there's any other uh
any other strains you guys want me to
research and do this on i'll do that in
the future
um but we could do this once i don't
know this is
a pain in the ass but you know every few
weeks
i love you duker i love you skunk
um yeah it's
it's confusing and it and it is
absolutely confusing being in the middle
of it back then and just shaking your
head like god these guys don't know
[ __ ] [ __ ] why people keep asking them
[ __ ] and in the end yeah it goes to show
they don't know [ __ ] what's that cartel
what
[Laughter]
oh my god i would have [ __ ] killed
you let me see it i'll show it
so i just got this we just got this i
think there's two of them in here
they're acid blotter papers
you can see it's actually real acid
blotter paper too uh from luke chu i
believe is how you pronounce it the
artist
no it's actually pronounced chew
uh but yeah these are these are pretty
[ __ ] cool and the cartel just got
delivered them instead of our [ __ ]
house again
are you ever going to make panama red
shirts they are up and they are already
for sale
uh cannabis carnivore they're over on
skunktech.com
see see it's even got a certificate of
authenticity a little luke signature but
yeah i think it's [ __ ] rad when an
artist
goes out of the way to make acid blotter
[ __ ] art that's [ __ ] cool
i'm really stoked about those as you can
see on the back it is really meant to be
used for that but i don't know if i can
these are a little expensive to be using
for that
anyway
yeah
i would have been pissed if they
delivered this somewhere else [ __ ]
pissed
god idiots
all right
so any any of uh
and when i say these guys are cartel i'm
not [ __ ] kidding i'm not that's not
an example of of being racist or
anything they are [ __ ] cartel we have
mexican cartel here pretty [ __ ] heavy
um
family motors stuff like that is all
cartel owned so
yeah they live right next to us and they
are not nice
i went up to the dude because he was
dogging me after we first moved in he
was just like sitting there [ __ ]
dogging me and bran and his wife was
dogging bryn and i was like okay you
know i'm not gonna put up with that [ __ ]
so i walked over there and i didn't
really see anything i just kind of
walked like i was [ __ ] pissed and i
went over there and they kind of looked
you know kind of like this [ __ ] white
guy doing and then he says uh
i was like hey what's up my name's matt
and he's like they called me pancho and
i was like yep
i bet they do
yeah i know i saw i heard
[ __ ]
living weirdos
one two-story house yeah 20 people
living in a two-story
um yeah so if you guys got any questions
go ahead and start shooting them i can
answer questions now we can
break this down
oh harry harry j all-stars did that
regular track it's called liquidator
okay you said the black
seen your tattoo
oh i don't know if duke's seen my tattoo
i don't think so
i have a black hand tattoo
yeah there we go
[Laughter]
the vagabond inn in bakersfield ooh we
also have the villa in and it just like
it looks like villain
duke it says
duke gets around apparently dude that's
shady yeah duke you shady what's up
stray
dude keep in places i don't wanna know
yeah jesus is one of my favorites by far
artist and link to his work the artist
here i'll type it up
luke yeah
but it's pronounced too
and you can find him at
there you go
um i think they still have one of these
left on one
dot com the other one's sold out there's
only a hundred made of each so
dude
you kind of give me a funny feeling in
my tummy that you know that [ __ ] i don't
like that
he knows about the vagabonding
oh nope i lonesome i'm i'm gonna bring
you on so uh you can tell us all about
the uh camdees
is jeffy totally sad that i bumped him
from here for being an [ __ ]
how or why
happy why was he being a dick halfway is
always a dick that's what he gets
i know right
chem valley need the chem valley
ken valley d
the worst shop in bako oh god
we got like a thousand way tied
all of them they're all bad weasel story
and sour d apparently multiple sour d
cuts weasel across the male underdog to
mask okay so
there there's a debate on what happened
with the sour diesel whether it's the
hour diesel hef it would have been nice
to have had jeffy [ __ ] in here to
answer the the our diesel the the from
vondo's [ __ ] point of view because he
knows the the story from vondo better
than most um
uh
they had the the bag seeds of
whatever
um
the diesel
in a bag that said our diesel and that
became the sour diesel that's the story
from um
from vondo and that's when i have faced
friends but he had to act like a jackass
so he's not in here to [ __ ] answer
that
dummy
how did you describe the differences in
smell and cola growth between chem duve
that's a long question to answer on here
buddy
uh so weasel and aj don't know what
albany crew did with mass skunk diesel
and l to make sourdy
i don't know
i was trying to focus jeffy was acting
like a jackass
jeffy didn't want me doing this and i'm
i'm not sure why jeffy didn't want me
doing this
maybe he just wanted attention i'm not
sure
but yeah um
there was a
a really
after the adam done show weasel did
another podcast and it was a bunch of
info contrary to the original podcast
and i've really been trying to find it
but i can't because there might be some
answers between both of them and what
was
consistent right but i can't find that
one i've had a really hard time finding
that
ever hear of a strain by gooey aaa death
i have not but i'm not proficient in
gooey's uh work
where's the pink death star it's up in
canada
can canadians run the [ __ ] out of that
miss jill purple afghani any eta miss
jill
any eta on the purple afghani that is a
beautiful cut you got
707 seed bank cat piss i believe it's
the the pittsburgh piss
nor calcat piss that's about the most i
know about it
any truth to cat piss there's so many
different cat pisses it's almost like
chem d 90 of them
um
yeah
there there are so many different ones
so it's it's hard to say maybe timewarp
was one of them but you can get it from
an afghan haze that typically spits out
those uh
ammonia piss terps
my buddy in canada
uh um um lame game on flame he knows
where to get lots of pink death star
he's been showing me lots of pink desk
death star [ __ ] uh extracts and bud
and all kinds of [ __ ]
are they all related i'm not sure if i i
don't think all the chem d's are related
for sure cat piss i doubt all the cat
pisses are related yeah super silver
haze you can find it in that another
afghan haze combo
yeah ziggy is awesome i love that dude
he's a hell guy plus he's he's a little
punk rocker gotta love it
jill gonna do a reverse so she's
handling it handling her [ __ ] look at
that
can you see my comment because it
doesn't show up i don't know what but
i don't know it's cause it doesn't like
faded and all you missed your bud yeah
i don't know
you'll figure it out and then i said
missed you too see there you go you got
your answer
all right what are the questions you
guys got
how those blue bonnets from texas kid
turning out from uh lone star
i believe lone star didn't lone star
make that [ __ ]
see i had a picture somewhere i was
illustrating
because i have all my males in a in a
tray together they're all kind of in
small pots but he was standing out so
much
the the selected blue bonnet male hold
on let's see if i can find him
he kept standing out in a crowd of
everything and it was it was pretty
amazing let's see
is that it no that's not it
i've got [ __ ] liquidator in my head
yeah i had a picture of it but like he
uh
in the midst of all the
let's see let me do this
the code is pre-pre 420 thank you
the 35 off right now of everything but
the spray it's pre-pre-420 that's it um
he was standing with his his family is
like this almost at 90 degrees straight
up like it was pretty crazy in the
middle of everything so uh and his
stock's like this thick
yay thick in a in a tiny little bigger
than a solo cup but it's a square pot oh
whoa
and uh
he's super tall
so he he made himself stand out so i'm
doing some um
a four-way
a four-way the the fairfax four-way
cross to uh the blue bonnet
some mac blue bonnet just to see what
that or that takes it because i don't
like mac terps
jesus
did he live did two cars live here
i don't know jerry's all the time i
don't know
what's up i'm all day
can i find any roadkill skunk in your
other lines aside from the ireland candy
there's still heirloom afghani hybrids
that i have that you can find
you can find skunk spray
some people call roadkill skunk
different things i just
when i think of a roadkill skunk i think
of a skunk being run over you know what
i mean like that's that's a smell you
can smell that [ __ ] half a mile away
so yeah
that kind of stuff's in there
uh what is the trip [ __ ] trip with
copy cat genetics what a sweet webpage
never seen so many frosted s-ones even
an rks debut copycat's a fraud dude
that's dude's a fraud he released s-ones
and they were all redlines
so stay away from it
um we're gonna be having an even bigger
sale on 420 but that's always away but
we'll have a really big sale i'm going
to put out a bunch of
stuff that's never been released um and
it's only going to be one or two packs
of some stuff but put it out there um
the sale the pre-pre 420 sale is just
for tonight uh it will not be available
tomorrow so if you want in on that 35
off everything except the spray and
tonight duke's going to be doing a live
feed so everybody go check out duke's
live feed i'll be there too um he has
some of the best live feeds out there so
i'm excited to see it
um yep that's it
go go watch dukes i'm not sure what time
he's going on he said tonight maybe
after this maybe a little bit later but
pay attention
cheers y'all
[Music]
you