how you doing
what's up clack
how y'all doing
how y'all doing yeah people are getting
notifications today i'm happy about that
so
here we go here we go so
um some of you may have heard oh first
off i just gotta show this before i even
start in on this let's go ahead and show
this
let's go and show this um oh god my ugly
head cut it off this is joint breath um
relishing in the fact that
duke got popped so
um
you know despite whatever your views on
anything are
that's uh
he's stoked he can
go sell cuts that he doesn't even have
of the puck which is mid
um
trash but um yeah
it's always interesting when people
people have that um point of view so
when people come in and ask what my
problem is with joint breath this is it
all summed up in one
yep
that is uh it's just about as offensive
as you can get
uh anyway so i was looking up some [ __ ]
and i noticed there's a story about this
dude in kauai
a dude in kauai nate what's his name
justin britt apparently he got sued for
um
he got sued for uh embezzling and you
know that happens all the time pieces of
[ __ ] and bezel and steal from each other
and all that [ __ ] you know a bunch of
noobs trying to get in the [ __ ]
medical cannabis business there's a
better shot of the guy right there
is that keanu reeves no you know who it
is this dude's brother this dude's
brother and the only reason i don't feel
bad about this is because this dumb ass
decided to put his real name
up on high times
this is super kawaii by the way
um
yeah he's a this is supa here so people
also want to know what the deal is on
super kawaii so he showed up i don't
know five years ago maybe claiming that
his uh
his dad made crippy or someone made
krippy
um
i you know i don't i don't know
you know but uh you know saying his dad
went to jail did all time that his dad's
a [ __ ] thing
oh no
no your dad did not go to jail did he
buddy did he
eddie anyway
it's just
he needs to know that i mean
just because we don't unload onto dude
we don't really unload on nobodies you
know um but at least now he knows now he
knows
that we know
i need to shut his [ __ ] mouth or shut
him down
so yeah anyway
i thought that was cute his [ __ ] ugly
ass head
[ __ ] meth is a [ __ ] up drug
can't forget his dancing roots
so this is purely for science
but i want you to see something here
do you see those little things moving
[Laughter]
so that [ __ ] roots are moving
to bob marley holy [ __ ] anyway
any [ __ ] way what are you guys up to
no no no one got busted in that um
soup has never done time because dad's
never done time i mean i don't care i
don't doing time doesn't make someone
special to me it doesn't you know i mean
people get popped every now and then
that happens it's a shame but he uses it
as like a flex right
um
but it's always weird when people that's
not what happened and you're flexing
with it like
it you know yeah street cred stories and
it's just not gonna happen bro not gonna
happen
there's no street cred for you super
no street cred for you
anyway yeah i just thought that [ __ ] was
funny i thought it was funny
um
you know
i unloaded on mass medical the other day
so i figured i'd unload on his stupid
ass too
so what you guys got what kind of what
kind of stuff we got today what kind of
questions you got
hey what seeds can i pop with some old
stella blue flavor um
the we had a blue baby [ __ ] version two
that is essentially that stellar blue
the same same [ __ ] tart profiles and
stella blue
yeah that's the guy behind 808 yeah yeah
he told me he was he saying he's never
heard of me before and then he called me
a fat method on something rather
yeah i collect you know i mean
a lot of people tell on themselves and
that's how they get caught they want to
brag those who don't don't get caught
sometimes what's up
tonight wanna give me a bj tonight
[Laughter]
yeah babe
the rest of course i'll take a bj oh you
mean the restaurant yeah that too
yeah
that too i'll take both thank you
what a woman wonder woman not feeling
good and still gonna go down
breeder steve is on future cannabis
project now live that's cool
can you get them or do you have the blue
baby [ __ ] version too i do i do and i
know you're a stellable fan so yeah hit
me up
a
bazooky have pizookies there
i won't [ __ ] pazuki
bj's is good
happy wife yeah that's for sure
the opposite definitely true too
oh let's see what else i got i know i
have some other
prized things some i cannot show some i
cannot show i wish i could show all you
show you all this [ __ ] that i got on
this dude
[ __ ] hilarious hilarious
i'm not big on doxing folks but when
someone puts their their first and last
name in a high times ad they kind of
just are
what are you doing no not very smart
right
pj tastes like bj's yummy
extra yummy
diet or that
anyway what else we got in here
yeah please do stella drop it to me here
on right cedco i never checked the other
ones um
there was a blue baby [ __ ] version one
which was the uh it was a stella blue bx
um and then we have the uh
uh blue baby [ __ ] version two and that
one it's not it has no stella blue in it
but it is based on that type of thing
genetic drift is a myth yeah i uh um
i think acclimation is real
um as far as something drifting
genetically there's such thing as
epigenetics that affects stuff but
nothing is ever gonna drift genetically
ever
ever you can't it just doesn't happen
genetics don't drift like that
um
acclimation's a real thing which is why
you can see the chem 91 cut [ __ ]
blown out [ __ ]
uh or really beautiful looking you know
there's a few different ways to grow
that same with the puck and and other
cuts
see what else funny [ __ ] we got what
questions you guys got
we have clack in here so we can actually
ask soil question you know i don't i
don't ever answer soil questions because
i'm not a soil guy but it'd be nice
what else do we got
been seeing some pretty pictures from my
buddy
of the p
can you explain the uncle fester cut
okay there is no uncle fester cut for
real
um that is a myth by uh uh nature fraud
nature farmer um
that that started back with uh what's
his name i got a headache right now so
i'm trying to think it's uh what's his
[ __ ] name
the dude who said he made tahoe that
[ __ ] idiot master tai he was the one
that started
all that [ __ ] about like oh it's skunk
18.6 or 18.8 blah blah blah i have this
it's [ __ ] rare um
yeah it's not
and he was a liar too and he never made
tahoe like it's just one liar after
another trying to build up on [ __ ] they
don't have
um and really people bragging about
skunk one
skunk 18 as you got what i'm talking
about there is an original skunk uh 18
but it is it's gone like that's not ever
been something um
in circulation
jaime chiba skunk you know i don't know
on that one i haven't talked to him
about it and i you know i don't like to
say someone doesn't have something
absolute if
if i don't know for sure
you could add one amendment to your soil
what would it be there's a good one clap
if you're still in here if you could add
one amendment to your soil what would it
be
i have not heard of ginseng og that's
new to me what's up sun grown
is there a particular strain that
changed my life financially i would have
to give all credit to um oregon kid in
the banana ocean as far as financially
um the clockwork orange of course
um there you go kelp mill
kilt mill that's your answer from clack
um he's very experienced with that so i
i'd uh
say that's pretty good advice
all right
but yeah um clockwork um
and in banana og like a banana og it
helped me
it's something that i used a lot and it
did really well for me
i can't take any credit for the banana
og stuff that really was someone else is
doing um it was already good when it got
to me
oh i've been having trouble though um
can we
i can't tell if this is male or not
maybe you guys can help me figure it out
i've been trying to sex this plant
or kelp meal not seaweed extract black
powder there we go
i've been trying to sex this for a few
days and i just
can't figure it out
what else do we got here
thanks thanks to all heart for that one
[Laughter]
oh too good too
good see
fully erect
about ready to blow
where's that [ __ ] pee picture that i
had
there it is look at that
look at that [ __ ]
um
that's the p91s one for bitter
his selection of it lay down lay down
marie
definitely not cookies
are me and coma still good i mean yeah i
mean i have no reason to be
a [ __ ] talking coma at all
we just disagree on some things but
nothing bad
another person asking about create
[ __ ] have you ever seen the dude in his
tooth his one tooth
that's about how many you're about to
have up your little cute little bj that
was you that was all you
you know what i was talking about what's
up mr vitus
oh no snake's in here
create yeah i mean if if you like a
little side of meth with your seeds
great would be awesome
do i know of any crosses made with a
hawk and i think black pack is doing
something with a wahawkin of some sort i
know bodhi's done some uh wahawking
crosses
um
uh
uh blueberry has wahawkin in it
somewhere
yeah see keep it on and on knows what's
up
what's up roots
thoughts on boneyard i like boneyard i
like him a lot i like tony quite a bit
um
he's he's one of the the few people uh a
lot like all heart that always inspires
me to to be a better person you know
he's been through a lot um i lost one of
his legs
yeah art is a beast but but tony he's uh
he's a special dude
and he keeps fighting
does honest genetics live up to his name
dude if you have to put honest in front
of the your name you're trying to sell
something that you aren't that's all i
got to say with that
well how can spear circa 76
i see i'd love to see some nice oaxacan
nowadays i wouldn't know i'm too young
to have known wahawkin
never knew hindu kush was actually an
area until last night yeah the hindu
kush mountain region
mountain range
mexia i had a um
meximillia i forgot who did that one but
it was really good too
what form of silicon can be added to
soil without jacking up ph and does it
need it
i don't know about amending with silica
but i like the ortho solicit um doesn't
jack the ph too much what about the rks
from blue sky guy oh lord look dude
and you know i mean some people are new
to this and whatnot but you have got to
be just a little bit
suspicious of that dude when
nobody's grown it nobody's seen it
uh the only one pumping it is him on 90
different names um
yeah it's
that dude is something else man
something else another guy that's lying
about [ __ ] like i actually put up uh
screenshots of what um old timer one
said about his skunk line the skunk one
line and that's what this [ __ ] keeps
saying is his rks and
you know i mean ultima one himself said
that it was not skunky so yeah ever
since then he's been
riding my dick pretty hard
yeah roots let's see it
clackamas break down add still 16 versus
some
height like aptus or power si
yeah axil versus xl16 versus like power
si
um
man i want to say i use the axil i
didn't have any results like i did with
power si to be honest
tropic trees why would you tell you
can't when you tagging super ky for we
already we already done been over that
little [ __ ]
this guy
oh and i don't know if he ever says he
was pop but just in case
no you ain't never [ __ ] been been
popped so just in case he tries to ever
pull that one we already know the answer
to that did you hear the ggg interview
[ __ ] no i don't give a [ __ ] what ggg
says [ __ ] flat earther anti-vaxxer
[ __ ]
idiots
your neighbor's children oh no i've hope
you don't have like an idiot like we do
it was a pre-sam kel there's no such
thing as a pre-sound california skunk
i mean when you're depends on what let
me rephrase that there's no such thing
as a pre-sam california skunk one that
doesn't exist before sam
um skunky weed did exist before sam that
was just afghani
they had nothing to do with skunk one
uh yeah
hey yeah clap you want to come on
[ __ ] i'll bring him on
yeah dude
there we go see if it works
let me get this
picture off here
or it'll probably mess up
bring super i would never bring super in
here i don't get super quiet exposure
how you doing
yeah how you doing answer that question
and
it comes up all the time
almost
every
so-called liquid silica product is made
from potassium silicate and that's where
your ph issues come into play
uh problems with raising the ph so uh we
we can get it from other sources a
couple of the posters here mentioned uh
rice halls and that's true there's even
a powdered rice whole product that build
a soil carries i can't remember the name
but
i've used it and it did well
one person asked a very legitimate
question
is it even necessary
and
um
it depends like in my worm bins i run a
lot of uh rice holes as an aeration
material
so on that deconstruct it's releasing
the uh
silica oxide
i believe that's the form it's in
so
would i add it to my soil no
but
you know so that question isn't
you need some silicon in your soil
and if you use it judiciously
and get like the uh egg sale product
because that's what all the other ones
like the silly one from
oh the guy advanced nutrients wet betty
or something yeah um
even a sillier label but uh
it's made from axil i mean all those
products that you see in the grocery
store
or what i call the house of perdition
um they're all made with eggs so get
exile
yeah you know and then cut the chase and
it's in a powder form so you mix on as
need basis
uh
and it's good for emulsifying
horticultural oils i don't want to get
into that mess uh neem or karate oils or
whatever but uh
yeah and i still use them and they're
full of crap the people you know
yeah
you gotta learn the difference between
an extract
and oppressing but
you know that's like trying to explain
why is it called unsulfured and not
desulfared
molasses and if you can't wrap your
brain around that one
then i don't want to talk to you about
the differences between an extraction
and using solvents
in a pressing that goes back at least
3000 years you know whatever
i'll get off myself how do you feel
about
uh how do you feel about um like like
power side the the orthosilicic acids
and and monosolicic acids
i'm sorry hold on a second let me turn
my sound up excuse me
that's all right
good question
um how do you feel about orthosilicic
acid and monosalicylic acid stuff that's
not from potassium silicate you know to
be honest with you i'm a real minimalist
um if you looked at my recipe
uh
the biggest criticism is well there's no
there there well it's all in the worm
castings you know i don't
look i think everybody should
recycle their kitchen waste if you don't
do that you should have to be forced to
listen to some tv show that's really
horrible or something
but it's not going to give you a worm
casting it's too much water and as much
as those worms are they can't turn water
into castings yeah so you need bulk and
that comes from either
aged manure and by that we mean five to
six weeks
to allow the
um
verbicides that are given livestock for
like we do dogs you worm them right yeah
well those herbicides kill
the good guys in our worm bin so you
need to let that sit for about five to
six weeks and they'll degrade
into a form
into its basic uh
ionic structure if that makes sense
yeah so it's no longer a vermicelli it's
carbon and hydrogen and oxygen and all
those good things um
so
so we want to use that that gives us
bulk
and that's how you make good castings is
through bulking yeah without the stuff
that there's some uh
i'll leave it at that yes a good good
cat good uh bedding that's been
uh
elevated with uh nutrient dense
materials like small amounts of alfalfa
meal
uh kelp meal i like to run neem and
karanja
this might you might find interesting
karanja is actually
a legume it's closer to a
alfalfa plant and it is the neem tree
which is a mahogany
and the properties in those two
materials couldn't be more different
there's no shared
constituent as a direction comes from uh
neem and uh pongamia oil
comes from karanja
i'm not familiar with karanja what what
what is that used for well in india as
the preferred one for medicines for uh
skin products
and india has some of its own race
issues the beliefs that lighter colored
citizens are more intelligent than
darkerness said to be used to lighten
the skin tone i know that it can
uh
but if you look if you went into an
indian market
and went to the haba section everything
would have either neem or quarantine you
know shampoo toothpaste
but over here if you get touched with
team you're gonna fall over dead or
something or
you know you can't go to the rose parade
or something i don't know
but um
yeah i mean
if you looked at the ayurvedic medical
system you know you have the tcm
traditional chinese india has the
ayurvedic and 72
of the uh
bottled
compounds you know
elixirs and stuff 72
have some part of the neem tree root
bark
leaf
oil
um
and it's behind the tulsi
basil which is a forerunner of all
basils like the
wolf is to the or canine friends
well this one okay it's the most holy
plant in india is the tulsi
and then neem is the second one
so
anyway there you go at all
look up there sometimes research.ca
uh
is nothing to do with gardening nothing
okay it's all about human health
diabetes uh
viruses uh all kinds of things you can
rub the oil on your feet
as a
cure or a prevention of athlete's foot
if you
do a lot of uh running or you know
whatever
so yeah it's been around for 5 000 years
but suddenly 18 months ago became a
you know point of discussion at uh
canacon and uh yeah indo expo you know
it's just
you know whatever
ah all this is appreciated there's
people asking all kinds of questions uh
go ahead i mean to dominate there but oh
no worries no worries i'm enjoying it um
let's see
why my why is my worm casting running
hot in sodium and then uh and you think
i can push out sodium with calcium
gypsum
no because uh gypsum is simply uh
um
wait a minute
oh calcium sulfate and it's calcium in
its elemental form whereas the calcium
we get is say limestone
or
oyster shell that's calcium
calcium carbonate
so there's one
calcium ion
there's one carbon ion and then three
oxygen ions
in calcium carbonate but in this
in gypsum you're getting calcium by
itself
and then you get sulfur oxide which is
water soluble
and so what and like let's say
you're using core
uh
one thing that has to be
you know acknowledged is that it's an
inert
medium that's why it's
preferred if you're going to use salts
but
in a uh
organic soil it's a nightmare
so what you want to do the big one
that's missing is sulfur and without
sulfur
sulfur is at the base of almost every
metabolical function on this planet
including the production of terpenes
terpenoids and ketones so it'd be a
really good uh red i'm using corn i
can't get any flavor
and i don't get any aroma
okay put a half a cup of uh gypsum
you know and say a cubic foot and there
you go you're dancing
yeah yeah that's something i had to
learn on my own too to add add sulfur
yeah some kind of sulfur too too because
i use core that's all i use right so i
like a mix i like to add in a calcium
carbonate like limestone or oyster shell
it doesn't matter the same thing
and then a little bit of gypsum so i'm
getting my elemental calcium along with
my calcium carbonate and then i'm also
picking up
uh some gypsum
so i think that's that's a good balance
if you i don't like using this term but
a liming agent if you will yeah for lack
of a better one
okay we have a request here on um the
history of the strain the one which is
one i've been fascinated with for a long
time myself okay uh pretty simple um
in laguna beach in the late 60s and
early 70s before
the whole lsd the orange sunshine thing
took them apart
you know
it's one thing to taunt a dog behind the
fence with a stick but you don't want to
do that with the federal government yeah
that's especially when you're
understanding containers
contains like a patch
okay those are like 48 000 you know i
mean
these guys weren't just a dude
we're gonna see the dude and get some
stash tonight you know this is like
you know you gotta bite even then 10
kilos to even
communicate but anyway
so the seeds came a lot of the guys
because they're in the bl there was like
it had to be 13 right 13 original
founding members that's yeah that was a
good one okay yeah and so seven were
part of this ragtag motorcycle club
that used to hang out this really weird
bar not far from disneyland uh
they were just you know
drinkers and you know like rowdy bikers
it was the 60s man so
there was also this group of surfers
in the mid 60s that were traveling
around the world as
it was easy to do
maybe easier than today
and when surfing in the surfing spots
all had
somebody there with good weeds so they
started bringing some good weed back
because they knew how to pass their
boards
so they could make a hole in the board
and stash in a pound or two
and so that's then the two got together
and then the whole thing so the seed
that i had were from kandahar
1970 and i know exactly who brought him
in
the whole
story
okay so then i went off to the army got
drafted kicking and screaming to send
the women and children first
um but off to save the world make it
safer democracy
so it came back and uh
in the december of 1976 the first thai
sticks came in
okay and they came in uh 10 kilo
uh bales
and they were wrapped in uh
i'm sorry
yeah 10 kilo you know 22 pounds right
yeah okay yeah so uh 20 of those pounds
were
sticks
and
since to me it was still two or three
years away
so they were seedy is all get out
and uh there was then two pounds of
loose buds that of course had to be
renamed the buddha buds
yeah yeah i've heard of that yeah okay
so those seeds became the first crop i
ever did that summer in 77
and there was no growth stores there was
no new program
i don't not even sure
even would know what to do if i had a
bottle of maxi or miracle grow or
whatever you know
yeah but i understood that you had to
water plants
so
and that was before the banking laws you
could walk into a car dealer and buy
four
celicas if you want and
pay cash and it was no big deal yeah
that came later in the reagan
administration you know
yeah
just saying no that crowd
so uh
so that was a female and
there were 10 plants that were selected
out of this mass
i'm not a breeder so if i told you you
guys be laughing so this was like
flying by the seat of my pants just be
reliant about it you know well that's
early on though no one was really
well there were no companies and the
guys in california were still dinking
around with goofy names you know
yeah um i had a couple but
i would have named that's another story
um
so
that one uh the way it got the name was
that
they were all against the wall and they
went from sativa over to
afghani dominant
which i had no interest in at all
so i just said okay the one over here is
mine and so oh so it's like the one huh
no it's like the one over here is mine
okay and then it became a running joke
you know he still got the one yes still
got the one
and uh
so that's just like you know it has
nothing to do with i thought it was like
oh yeah it's like the one no i've had
the one that came from sri lanka and i
didn't want to
ever smoke weed again
it was like that far out you know it was
like yeah
some hindus i mean real hindu not
you know he picked it up in new delhi i
mean like in the cush valley or
something you know from the saudis yeah
so that's all the you know no big deal
and um but ironic is
that i've given that way i've never sold
a clone in my life
the last time i sold a seed was 77.
uh that's early that is early yeah i
take thai seeds you know because i had
them
because
i learned early on that if i was going
to take the risk of
being a
serious consumer of cannabis that you
might as well do the good stuff
so i would sell like
i know you think i'm not but say i would
get fronted like a ton or two of uh
colombian
from guys in uh
detroit with way too many vowels in
their last name
they'd give you like two months to turn
it
yes so our motto was i don't want to own
it i just want to finger print it
meaning
you know bump it 25 30 bucks
yep and just keep it you know so then i
would turn around and go buy like
premium mishma khan
or yohaka o'hakan spears were personal
and went to sears and got a deep freezer
so i could freeze it
you know so i could buy three or four
pounds you know that kind of stuff
that's [ __ ] awesome yeah so that was
yeah you know
can i just say one thing about skunk
number one
sure i mean going back to the like
original in the mid 80s yeah i don't get
it
what do you mean
as far as like why it's called skunk in
the first place i
you know it's like
i just don't get the whole
thing about it
i mean why like it's that desirable
oh okay now i understand that one okay
all right i can i can understand that
one okay it's like yeah
yeah one of my favorites
somebody will give me a
bud to try what do you think
now let's say
so did you clone this more than twice
why
yeah
it's made it through three rounds but
yeah i mean yeah come on
uh
one nice thing about growing an old
strain
is that you really can test the soil
because you can't test this off though
this time i'm going to do
i don't know skittles or piddles or
whatever it's called right
um yeah yeah okay and then over here
well i'm going to try this oil but i'm
going to
i know use or whatever the thing is you
know whatever the hot button is
but with me
i mean i can tell you by day 24
uh
i'm not gonna finish this i appreciate
you let me try it but you know
best wishes uh go back to the drawing
board
so
that and so in my opinion which means
nothing
is that at least if i test something for
you i can give you a an accurate
comparison analysis of one
uh that i've you know grown like forever
yeah
the main reason people don't like mine
is that if you really want to get the
full you know
twilight zone theme comes on right here
um
you got to do at least 12 if not 14
weeks
and here's the best part this is the
part i love the best
i've taken it 18 weeks just to see what
it would take to get the trikes to turn
even cloudy
it doesn't ever happen never
so you're never going to get the amber
forget that one
all right yeah
let alone cloudy
no it never goes cloudy even outdoors
like seven months where you like
southern california where you can take
it through november into december
yeah it never no it never goes cloudy
it has to be the highland tie that has
to be
i would think so maybe if you tried like
way less light hours like six hours like
oh yeah oh yeah i still didn't do it
over the years i've done every
i haven't when i was uh ignorant got
into that well you know you need this
bulb okay
uh yeah right
this bulb will make it finish yeah
this bulb will make it faster yeah right
yeah magic stuff what's in i can't say
it's proprietary
excuse me
you know
so
but anyway that's
that's my you know just a guy that
decided to get into soil real serious
and figure out
i have post on my uh ig feed
of a soil test that i mixed five years
ago
and it has all the npk it has all the
macro and micro nutrients
and you know we're a little weak in the
microsoft throw some kelp in there
that's why kelp is the perfect one
because it's a plant right
and it accumulates all 83 elements more
importantly in the right value if we
don't go nuts
that's adding some kelp will take care
of all our micronutrient issues
wow i see i didn't even know that
it's the only brown killer makes sense
not not blue marine algae not red
but a green i mean green red but brown
only brown is the only
organism on this planet that creates
allergenic acid
and i'll gent i'll leave you for
research on that but you can see why
brown kelp has algenic acid seaweed
extract is created by by law under
federal
usda regulations has to be created with
either sodium
uh hydroxide or potassium hydroxide the
stuff they use in drano to clean out
your uh
drain so they use that and they burn
everything off so what are you left with
you're left with powder
you got your elements you might as well
just do salts see what i mean yeah all
the life force is gone
yeah but it's convenient
but at a convenience that
is detrimental to your soil in my
opinion
i don't want to put a fungicide
in my soil after i've spent
several months building up the nutrient
yeah and fungal profile in my compost
before i ever hit a warm bin
um can i ask you
are you self researched and you just you
just delved into it hardcore and learned
it all on your own are you are you
oh no no no i'm academically yeah i was
going to say this is pretty pretty heavy
academic stuff yeah but the real stuff
is that you have to do it
you have to get your hands dirty there's
no bottled solution there's hey it's
it's hard work and if you want to have
scratches in the game
you got to do it
and be consistent don't
don't be you know my phone because we
released my product today
oh good hey there it's patty the one
with uh how you doing malted barley
malted or heirloom corn and uh hemp
seeds and where can people get this oh
build a soil it's called don't laugh i
named it so
i want to sound cool uh gnarly barley
gnarly barley yes 50
barley and it's uh 30
corn that's for the cytokinins
yeah
and then the hemp
which i could spend a couple days
explaining all the enzymes and compounds
well you know from
it kind of goes like this if it works
good on a plant it's probably good for
you and vice versa
that's interesting
means nothing more than this it means
that you took a seed
and you germinated it
and then you arrested at about 116
fahrenheit what that does
it leaves the uh
enzymes intact so we call that diastatic
malt
now if we take that
mold after it's dried and ready to store
used
or aroma for ales and what have you
that's great
but it kills all the enzymes so now we
call that non-diastatic malt and if you
use non-diastatic malt in your beer
formula
then you need to add
the diastatic mold because you can't
make beer without amylase is the main
player
uh enzyme
in the barley but that's not what we
benefit from
can i explain this one because this is
really important
so all plants produce chitinase
and
chitin itself is an acetyl form of
glucosamine
okay all seashells contain
are made up from limestone
or calcium carbonate okay okay but the
crustaceans the the crab the lobster the
shrimp
and i guess that would also include the
one in the south uh crawdads yeah have
chitin
and kaiden for example you had surgery
either oral or external they probably
showed you up with kite and string
okay um that goes back to like the 1880s
this has really got an interesting
connection so in 1922 this young man by
the name of albert hoffman graduates
from cologne university and his paper is
on the molecular structure
of chitin
and then
21 years later he would introduce
or find lsd 25 and then 15 years after
that he was commissioned to do the
research on these
mushrooms out of uh
oaxaca
and he's the one that gave the name to
the two compounds psilocybin and silicon
so in a 15-year period here he does lsd
read his book lsd my problem child
there you go write it down
and then anyway so
the only thing that can deconstruct
microbially that can deconstruct
a polysaccharide uh
is fungi
bacteria in their weak attempt to try to
deconstruct it create an enzyme called
chitinase
and chitinase deconstructs egg shells in
the soil
so that's kind of cool you don't have a
poison yeah yeah and then equally
important
animal kingdom and plant kingdom have
immune systems
and in plants you have like har hormonal
acquired resistance and sars
systemic acquired resistance and some of
them are called pathways the most
important pathway in a plant's defense
system
uh is um
the chitinase salicylic acid pathway
okay and
every plant
produces uh
salicylic gas
some plants produce copious amounts like
the aloe vera plant
you probably heard in your career oh you
can use willow shoots
oh yeah okay well that's salicylic acid
okay and so that's why people would use
aloe vera for that's why i know i
started that
look man i'm not climbing a tree
i can go to a mexican market and get a
fresh aloe vera leaf
and you just cut off the spiny stuff on
the sides
and you stick your stems in there
inside the gel that sit overnight and
the next day
put them in how are we i don't want to
get into that one but how you do your
cuts yeah in that salicylic acid
creates a barrier against pathogenic
fungi your molds and all that
i average seriously over 98
success using just that and i don't
oh that's actually the best one is you
can find true
like the sign on the side of the road
that says honey so it's never been
touched yeah it's just used straight
honey
it's straight
yeah
wow
i had no clue about that yeah it's
really cool but you got to get organic
because
what they do to honey from the time they
pull it from the beehive so it gets in
that jar with a little bear you know
i'll let you know yeah um
it's a sad story you know it's not like
the real deal you know yeah
but anyway so that's why if we use
malted grains in our soil
the chitinase you don't have to go
through the expense of using crabmeal
because what you're really after is the
chitinays not the chitin
yeah so here you get it right in the uh
malted grains along with uranus urea
protease protein
phosphatase what cannabis grower doesn't
obsess about phosphorus right yep uh
much to their barrel usually
um yeah right yeah but you get the idea
i mean so there's like 360
enzymes in a malted grain
so what i can do and have done is i can
document okay here are the
you could take something out from under
your fingernail and put it in water and
say it's got enzymes
oh yeah okay
but i can explain each one and how they
work and i'm only taking like 10 out of
the 360
that are in barley so
and then you add corn of the cytokinins
and what that does to
between the tip of the root system and
then
mary stem
at the end of the branches is quite a
phenomenal uh study
and the first
cytokinin was discovered in corn in 1937
in the latin name for corn is zia
so they named this enzyme zeatine
um makes sense yeah so that's and
there's other uh there's other pgrs and
other things in the corn besides
that one enzyme excuse me hormone
yeah so anyway
i was just thinking botany 101 i
probably bored your audience there but
uh no no i think everybody's [ __ ]
loving it to be honest with you um i
love it
i'd love to have you on anytime you are
bored want to come on i know it's a real
treat for me and everyone else so i
really appreciate it because i like
talking to uh gardeners
instead of a salesman you know yeah man
it's a pleasure
to have you look at my feed
your what my feet yeah okay you've seen
some of the plants
yes okay i wanted a ten and a half
pounder
yes yes don't you think it's a little
disingenuous to come on my feet and tell
me what i should be doing
oh my good lord yeah yeah that's
everybody's uh everybody knowing that
i'm gonna scholarly
right
yeah sometimes i wanna say is maybe like
do more reading and
not so much
editorial stuff you know until you kind
of
uh
i figured i've been involved in at least
yeah at least 300
serious gardens in my career
yeah i can imagine so dude
hey the first slice i ever bought was
some jor oh yeah it was called george
cervantes then before he became jorge
so uh yeah he had a place here in
portland it was one of three gross
stores in portland at the time that was
it
and uh
we went and bought these uh dutch lights
from pl light systems
okay i mean the professional stuff i was
gonna burn down my house in orange
county california
you know trying to grow some weed so we
decided
there was you
know funding was available i'll leave it
at that so uh yeah we decided to set it
up first cabin and uh i was using uh
what do you call them oh dosatrons
30 years ago
that's funny yeah and buying like full
jugs i think they were five gallons
yeah dyna girl and dinah bloom uh we'd
ride down to uh
there was some in the bay area like san
jose something like that
yeah and uh so we just put the dosatron
inside the jugs
and then i had i did the strip system i
mean
by today's standard you guys got it made
i mean it's all off the shelf and plug
and play for the most part you know
we had to kind of like huh
so how are we going to do this oh yeah
one time pulling stuff out of the field
and staging it next to the pickup trucks
and uh
the guy that was like our leader i
called him oph our personal hero
in this case i just said hey some dick
have you given a thought where you're
gonna dry this
and everybody just looks down at the
ground like oh man
and we were using bull tacos to go back
into the forest to get the
the plants where i can bring them back
and stage them you know
so uh jorge servants
i know he's friends with some of the
northern lights crew did you interact
with those guys at all
no not at all because that came out of
uh what they called the uh
bcga the british columbia growers
association
and uh
the nl came out of uh canada
on a guy that broke you see the bcga
wasn't going to do business with any of
the two groups that came out of holland
the what is now called scentsy seeds
then it was called the sssc
and then uh neville and
his partner uh david yeah
so yeah
they wandered around and everybody had
cash you know
yeah a briefcase is full of cash and
they were buying seeds and cuts
so
northern light came out from a
grower in canada
that
said hey man you know yeah you cut hay
when the sun shines you got money i'm
selling so uh
that's how the nl thing
went over to uh
uh
neville's deal the seed bank that was
the only thing i've ever bought in my
life i bought them one time
uh hayes northern lights
and did you find any keepers in it did
you find good stuff in it
i never bought another seat again in my
life that i you know
every story i hear about old older
growers that we're growing the northern
lights haze and it's heyday they all
have very very fond memories and they
talk about how many keepers were found
that became like one of them clone only
that are still around nowadays well
there is a caveat to my comment i want
to make this is really important
here's where you're getting conflicting
things
in a case that i was indirectly
i wasn't involved but
i was on the possible list of uh come
talk to us
back in boston
and
in discovery it came out that the dea
and the u.s postal service was
intercepting letters
from the seed banks to customers here
and they were switching it out with uh
ditch weed seeds
this was in discovery this is what they
came to the you know
here's our evidence evidence whatever
they call it i'm not an attorney but
yeah they all sit around before they do
lunch or something and decide how
they're going to screw you
yeah exactly
yeah so i mean that just like
it clicked but have you ever noticed how
many times in your life
you've been back in the forum day before
the social media okay like i see mag or
grass you know that
people go home a shirt my plants sure
don't look like the pictures from the
seed bank
and i just used to think i don't even
want to open this can of worms man i
just
no i'll be i'll be hated on forever for
spilling that one oh yeah people are
going to realize their collection's
worthless and then they're gonna really
dislike the messenger yeah yeah yeah
yeah exactly so but no that's uh honest
to god i was like
i just went well that party's over you
know so let's go back to square one
because we know who brought them into
the united states
and the whole history
and who who had possession of them and
everything else so
i don't have a lot of confidence
one breeder here
that a farm or whatever they call them
gave me 13 samples
in those little jars with you know
yeah probably hold i don't know half a
gram or half an
ounce
they had them all
gorilla glue
girl scout cookies this did that this
this i've had put them in a bag i
brought them home
they were going to hire me as a
consultant and uh
so my wife's in the kitchen cooking
dinner and i sat down in the living room
and i opened one up and i smelled it i
went god that's really terrible
but
you know you never know so
pulled out a nug and i busted it up and
i put it in my pipe and i got half a hit
and i just put it down
it's ridiculous my wife comes around the
corner and she goes what's that smell
and i said oh it's and i don't want a
name because i'll get you know yeah but
it's one that everybody has to have or
you're just a complete [ __ ] right if
you're not grabbing this one you're a
[ __ ] okay yeah
and i just said and so i you know i was
really polite but i said then i called
the next day i said i just don't see any
connection i mean what are we going to
do like redo your soil
i mean
there's just more issues here than i can
even
yeah i need like the biggest spreadsheet
known to god to even get into the
science of why this thing's [ __ ] up so
yeah
i wish you the best and sure enough one
season was over that was the first year
it went legal here there was funny money
everywhere from uh asian banks from
european banks
i mean it was insane and who did they
hire a grocery store clerk that that's
your grow guy
really
oh good well you need another cal mag
lockout and handle this one you know
yeah there's no there's no purpose in
consulting for someone that's going to
hire idiots uh all along the side of you
to perform you know complex [ __ ]
yeah and i'm and i'm enough of an
egotist and a clown i just don't
tolerate pools lightly i mean hey go do
whatever you want i wish you the best
you know uh instant karma whatever you
know you gotta have the audit
but i'm here to grow real medicine
yeah exactly i'm not here the whole hemp
industry is like that too the whole hemp
industry i i just made my my entrance
into the hemp industry last year and i
was shocked at how many people um are
playing grower in that i really thought
i never [ __ ] with it i figured they're
people that are that are better than i
would be at doing it because they've
been studying specifically hemp longer
working with it longer i figured they
had that [ __ ] [ __ ] dialed in and boy
was i confused when i got in there and
saw the people were just playing
constantly playing
i don't know
all i know is
wild world
without
you know proprietary this and i can't
tell you that and you know i mean
you think let's think about it this way
the issues facing the human race isn't
whether johnny gets his tank on is how
are we going to feed
people
and if this crap work
they'd be sitting in front of the u.n
picking up checks for billions of
dollars
on solving
world hunger right
right
i mean to me it
it's that simple
it is that simple
so
that's why like on my new product i'm
donating
percent
of my compensation
to an agency that plants forests around
the world so um
that's beautiful
i just think you know i just think
hey i want everybody to get their dank
on it and if uh
some like newt line i want to do a line
called cooch newts
spelled
c-o-o-t-s with n-o-o-t-s cooch newts you
know
and i'll just
say look this is what you want i'm
feeding
i'm feeding uh your your deal man your
dharma whatever it is you think you have
to do to grow a plant
i don't know well it's
instagram shut me down
thank you very much and goodbye
everybody
it's it's my honor to have you on and
i'd love to have you on again anytime
man pleasure
thank you very much bye-bye
thank you fred
what a treat that was [ __ ] he's so smart
i'm gonna have to go re-watch that
several times um if any of you can play
that and record it the only reason i
can't do it myself is because i get a
lot of messages and they'll pop up in
the recording
if any of you can record that
and uh at least get me somehow get me
the video whether it's your email or
whatever i will put it up on youtube
because i think that one's a very
important one uh thanks for everyone
stopping in and thanks again to cootes
that was our first conversation that
we've had
so yeah it was a privilege and an honor
um
take care guys have a happy friday oh
yeah [ __ ] super
you