Jules all free seeds wisely but every
time you know if you do this every time
you're not just to get one packet free
seeds I'm hooking you up as the new
lines come out and everything because
that's how we do our friends that help
us you know what I mean so it should be
done yeah man that was that was some
heavy heavy info and I loved it I loved
it like I don't know that there's anyone
smarter in this industry right now than
Mooney yeah all right Thank You mr.
Johnny Snipes recording this for
everyone so now we can upload it to
YouTube and have it live and not just
live but recorded post recorded
pre-recorded post recorded for anyone to
watch it anytime so yeah thank you very
much
d so yeah I've told you guys about some
of my craziness going on with my
landlord and [ __ ] finally have all that
settled everything's gonna be safe taken
care of I'm really stoked like I said I
have a bunch of seeded plants those are
going out of town like with my father
and and the other stuff's gonna go
somewhere else the the veg stuff so I'm
really stoked that it's amazing to have
such good friends that are willing to do
stuff like that for me there's a leading
cannabis channels they can suck my dick
yeah we're gonna be having Mooney on
more often and probably DSG labs and a
few others I'd like to have on and just
man I think people come to these live
feeds because they want they want to
learn they want to learn about breeding
and they want to learn about cannabis in
general and you know there are channels
like bubble man's that talk about s
extracts or hashed Church you know but
yeah I have to move this stuff out but
as far as breeders go I don't think
there's anyone teaching breeding I
really don't and and considering how
many people call themselves breeders you
know Mike does some live feeds that are
excellent and and of course there are
breeders who are more shy about being on
camera and I understand that because
there are some amazing breeders but he
just got banned from YouTube for 90 days
damn that sucks
what's up green dragon yeah strain
history tissue culture tech anything
that has to do with breeding or it can
help reading I want to I want to I want
to be the best source of info for that
for everyone and when I bring on guys
like Mooney I'm learning with you guys
you know can you really teach breeding
you could teach breeding basics you
could teach breeding terminology you
could teach breeding you teach
everything except the hands-on stuff
really
you can't teach people how to select you
can't teach people how to properly test
their lines stuff like that it's really
hard to do you know you have it or you
don't either
understand the plant you don't and you
cannot teach ethics exactly bittersweet
you can't teach breeding ethics I can
try but I can't instill that in anyone
but I can teach you I can teach you all
the basics of breeding words that you
should know
you know terminology and I can give you
advice on where to get more info to
learn even further but nothing replaces
hands-on approach to breeding and like I
said you know I've been getting a lot of
questions from new up-and-coming
breeders people that are new to
everything and they want advice lay down
marry and they want to they want advice
on what they should start doing and I
gave the advice you know if you want to
see evolution in action quick and you
want to see your trait selections done
fast
practice on Auto flowers you know and I
think a lot of people didn't get the
reason why it's just because auto
flowers have a quicker germination to
flower to finishing flower time than
anything else so you can get through
several crops very very quickly and you
could do it while having your plants in
24 hours veg if you want yeah but the
other thing is and I and I say this from
time to time learn the bass lines learn
the bass lines if you want to become a
full and complete breeder to be able to
recognize those bass lines and other
lines recognize those traits learn how
to select those traits if that's the
trait you want learn the bass lines that
and bass lines being skunk one be
familiar with multiple kinds of Afghan
ease haze of course original haze
Northern Lights which can also you know
Afghan ease and Northern Lights a pretty
pretty similar for all intents and
purposes most learn lights that you see
are 2 X 5 that that's the most common or
the lights that you're going to see or 5
X 2 I don't remember how it was written
and what else skunk haze run likes
puh-puh-puh buh-buh-buh Afghani I know
I'm forgetting a major one here
well what's the major when I'm
forgetting anyway learn the baselines
that's gonna help you so so much in the
future for breeding and and I was lucky
that my mentor taught me that I don't
think many people teach that Northern
Lights number six is quite different
that's from Tyco trichome technologies
what's a mr. Cuban yeah blueberry isn't
necessarily baseline but it's a good one
to learn however I highly recommend not
running the new blueberry which is very
very in economic I recommend the old
blueberry sativa lies cush is would be
involved with the Afghan ease and lights
so that kind of covers that but just
learn those baselines even public push
cuz Bubba push isn't so much different
stuff people don't realize that once you
learn those lines even Super Skunk would
be one then you will have doggies not a
baseline now not even um
once you learn those you'll be able to
identify everything on that note what's
the makeup of right Barry right Barry
was just like every other [ __ ]
legendary line it was a bag seed
actually was a jar seat if you want to
get technical was that came out of jar a
jar it was at pnc no no no no no where
was i working was it called it was a bcc
beneficial pair collective San Diego I
was doing I was growing in the back for
them the blood that they were selling
but they would also buy but bring it in
this dude who he's a well-known older
breeder in San Diego and he brought in
some cherry cone Kush which is his
strain and it was really good really
dang but it didn't smell like cherries
at all so I was never sure why I called
it that and then he brought in what was
labeled as Strawberry Cough and I asked
I said what is this because I saw it had
seeds in it he said oh that's actually
blueberry and I smelled it and smelled
like peanut butter so I was even more
confused but that peanut butter [ __ ] was
[ __ ] day so I picked the seeds out of
it brought him home popped him trying to
just get fee knows of that that peanut
butter run it see it was life but out
came these beautiful gorgeous purple
blueberry syrup plants and that would
that was how she was born so it's
supposed to be a blueberry it's probably
blueberry P 91 I'm guessing because of
the peanut oil traits but yeah that's
the genesis of ryut berry that's my baby
one of my many babies
oh [ __ ] you give it what a bastard
talk about horses [ __ ] genetics
of blueberry muffin blueberry muffin is
just a phenotype or a cut is the right
berry phenotype from right berry OG
which was right Barry frost Asst like
the original og crossed you Pakistani
JIT Rolly the green female green lemon
FINA anyone done a side by side with the
dark heart release of what his they're
they're fake blueberry muffins why would
they did why would he do that we already
know where they're [ __ ] [ __ ] came
from and who he did it and it has no
relation to mine it's [ __ ] [ __ ]
it's a they're a [ __ ] yeah this has no
relation to mine they just took a
well-established name slapped it on
their [ __ ] new [ __ ] and are
trying to push it as legit I mean there
is no comparison because it's so
drastically different I didn't know
people were calling sunshine daydream
the blueberry muffin cut but I don't I
don't think that there's any way that I
it's one of those times when I just have
to realize that I didn't pick an
original name by calling it blueberry
muffin because it's just it's something
that people want to slap on everything
so I just don't give a [ __ ] anymore
about the term or any of it
I'm not sure where the Humboldt seed PO
is from and not to be confused with
Humboldt seed organisation Humboldt Seco
are the ones naming lines like Jack hare
or they have nothing to do with Jack
Herer or very little to do with Jack air
they took my blueberry muffin cut
slapped it on one of their lines they've
done that with a bunch of [ __ ] they're
just uh all-around pieces of [ __ ] and I
don't you know no HSC not hso hso4 fine
they've never done anything like that
Humboldt seed company are [ __ ] I got
blue baby [ __ ] I do not have blueberry
butt holes though I do need to come out
of my shell don't I what do I think
about 10k Jack um it depends on which
one you're asking about there's the
original 10k Jack from Oregon which was
a lemon Jack Herer it was very much a
traditional lemon Jack hair and I mean
that's one of the common phenotypes you
find in Jack here is the lemon Jack it
wasn't massively yielding but it was it
was a solid bud you know very very
Norton like dominance in the bud
structure probably closer to stunk in
the actual structure of the plant very
little haze in it but man it's [ __ ]
its stellar weed man it's one of the
best lemons I've ever grown there's also
10k Jack which was named by Green Dave
and it was a a Jack Herer cut that came
from Bodie that was just called Jack
Herer he called that 10k and that is
closer to say like a Jack the Ripper
Chernobyl looking string and it's very
lime
I don't know Kuban um as long as they
keep your Cuban ass out and I think
we're good
the panic pit yeah
who has that I think my buddy kaya has
some panic pift run out and shown on
Instagram
the original kaya see we got death by
lemons I'm not sure the ten came from
Bodhi yeah it's it's it's very similar
to Jack the Ripper in looks but it's
purple kind of like Chernobyl and it
looks like the golden ticket cut and who
looks - very limey I don't know I don't
know much about buddy's lines anymore
just because like we just were good
friends but we both kind of keep our
heads down and do our own things you
know so I don't I don't memorize all his
lines and he has a lot that he puts out
so I would just be too hard to keep
trapped to be honest yeah I'm sure it's
good I have never seen an orange gelato
strain so I don't think all of you a lot
of strains are orange because I've never
seen that in orange gelato there might
be one or two but I don't know about
them
ooh
Oh things tipping there we go
his world of seeds
no they're terrible company there
there's [ __ ] they the real Seco is very
good world of seeds not so good one
second here
why are you puffing at me Mary okay so
someone asked the difference I wanted to
make sure that I have a right someone
wanted that asked the difference between
strawberry roadkill and roadkill
switchblade strawberry roadkill
okay so strawberry switchblade don't the
main difference between the two is the
strawberry switchblade incorporates the
double black doja as well in it which
has a lot of like reddish purple traits
or magenta even and strawberry
switchblade is extreme extreme
strawberry extreme whereas the
strawberry cream Afghani is it's still
very strawberry but it's more focused on
yield and resin production whereas that
the roadkill
switchblade is is a little bit less
yield but way more strawberry it's hard
to explain because they're both very
strawberry yeah
the the switchblade will always have the
double black Doge incorporated into it
motor growth 15 you're asking me for
something way later more recently made
and I don't know about it don't haven't
used it don't care again I don't know
much about bodis Lyons guys that have
come out within the past few years I
wish I could answer it but I just
there's so many that come out I don't
it's impossible to keep track of it I
have my own company that I run and make
seeds with that I have a hard enough
time keeping track of myself you know
what I mean real lemon tree railroad
lemon tree is lemon diesel oh is that
right yeah Oregon lemon diesel it's just
the same cut renamed sfe OG and candy
been done a long time ago by cat and
[ __ ] so who gives a [ __ ] someone already
did it probably did it better who made
it is that Jimmy nits
I shouldn't be mean like that because I
mean the guy the guy's been around a
while and I'm sure it's great it's just
it's been done before and I don't know
why people just picked up on it now
that whole height thing you know if
people were knowledgeable they'd be like
oh that's already been done and I could
have already had it 90 times over
captain kripp released those chem d sfe
I wish I could remember the name offhand
but I think it was just chem vs Fe it
wasn't a name and I know that it's
probably been done a thousand times
between captain cramp and Jimmy nits say
it like that's a common combination the
Kem's and SF ease I would think that it
would be very similar to chem 91 you
know I've never heard of Pittsburg cat
piss but the San Diego cat piss I'm
familiar with but I think that's just
one of those terms kind of like skunk or
whatever that people use like if a old
plant back in the day smelled like cat
piss they would call it cat piss so
there's a lot of regional campuses I'm
not familiar with the Pittsburgh one
storing seeds for long term preservation
if you are gonna store seeds and not
touch them for and you know you're not
gonna touch them for say 10 to 15 years
or your own - you're gonna storm and
you're gonna take them out the second
you want to pop them freezers okay for
that but you don't want to come in and
out doing that [ __ ] you know you don't
want to take it in and out of the
freezer that's not good for it
long-term storage fridge work great or
anywhere that is a cool dark dry
environment will work realistically
there's my water married you stole my
[ __ ] water well damn it oh damn god
damn it weird weird you sleeping on my
water buffer
mmm I guess I don't have one okay come
on Marie lay down lay down don't use
this excuse to get up late Oh Marie
little [ __ ] bad boy he knows I can't
jump up and get him so now he's being a
dick the cut called push for that Bodhi
uses sorry for another bell I don't mind
Bodhi questions I just don't know a lot
about his strains but the cush 4 is an
old Nevel strain if I remember correctly
and I do believe he got it from Jim
Ortega other than that I don't there's
not a lot of info about push for out
there yeah that was an old Jim Ortega
line if I remember correctly
Jim Ortega I met on mr. nice when he was
using the name dogmas nice guy but yeah
I don't I it's not one that I'm really
it's not one that pops up often it's a
very rare rare rare cut however it's
said to be it's said to be the basis of
a lot of push lines which I'm not sure
how true that is
there's also some lines that I'm gonna
get to look at from the scientist which
is really cool that's someone I know has
finally gotten those packs very rare old
[ __ ] and I'm curious to see what's going
to be in there I don't think a lot of
people know that term but I'll just
leave it at that for right now and I'll
bring it up later when I have more info
first ever cross is there any specific
minerals renewed sighs should push more
to help with seed production if you're
feeding your plant for seeds feed it
like a tomato beetle lots of nitrogen
your veg that helps them
what about 4d I have no idea where does
the name Oh G originated from I just
think it means like original I think
that's really what it means like og
could this is the old cush og cush
that's typical it's not over grow it's
not ocean grown any of that [ __ ] there's
just though the original og perhaps
perhaps perhaps perhaps what's the white
in white Tonto cookies I think it's just
white Tahoe the white
what is oh gee 18 that's a DNA strain I
you know I think it was from bears
selection karma said they knew more
about that than I do but again I don't
pay attention to [ __ ] lame ass [ __ ]
ass companies and I mean [ __ ] ass in
the nicest way that has nothing to do
with homosexuality one of those [ __ ]
that have used that word to refer to dip
shits DNA is that they're pieces of [ __ ]
they've always been pieces of [ __ ] they
bait and switch their lines and that all
that info is out there and if people are
still buying that [ __ ]
it's on them to [ __ ] suck it up and
realize they just bought a load of [ __ ]
that isn't what they say it's gonna be
overgrow cush that's right I had crybaby
watched the I had crybaby watch the
video of Steve Tuck talking about how he
helped create oh gee cush what do you
think about the white I see a lot of
breeders using it but I hate it
personally as a flower okay um the white
is an excellent breeder however it does
take a few crop of bat crossings to
whatever you cross the white to in order
to get rid of that that mushroom eat
earthy taste and and that's not ideal
what's ideal from the white is its resin
production it's a it's solid it's solid
structure it's uh it's a great plant as
far as that goes but I don't like the
taste smell or high from the white but
breeding wise it's an excellent breeder
and like like that this goes with all
things there are plants that are
excellent growers and terrible breeders
rogue blue floors one it's not
predictable you're gonna see a lot of
boo Fifi nose pop out when you cross
Gorilla Glue for to anything however
with with certain lines they breed
better than bro and the white would be
one what's up Mooney
that's right they'll do it Friday
and we have someone recording these now
so we're gonna have it up on YouTube
finally yeah you know people don't
realize that when they're buying ice
ones they're not they're not buying
direct copies of the clone mother that's
not how it works unless the plum mother
was picked from a line that was made
very very very very stable in uniform
you know so like a deep chunk s-1 what
resemble its mother very well whereas a
guerrilla glue for s1 you're lucky if
you ever see that same phenotype again
um Jack Herer I like some Jack Harris
but Jack Herer has thousands of
phenotypes so and I definitely don't
like all of them so it's it's kind of a
bowl a broad statement to cover by
saying yes I like Jack Herer people
think that p90 1s ones they all kind of
revolve around that mom but the the it's
it's weird different you'll see less
peanut oil sometimes more skunky more
skunky less peanut oil but they all tend
to kind of scale around that mom any
thoughts on the cube or Starfighter I
don't know about the cube as far as like
I never I've never grown it Starfighter
same thing never grew it but when those
seeds were originally sold you could
still buy the [ __ ] parents and seed
so I didn't understand why people are
paying a bunch of money for something
that you could buy the parents of the
seed stock for from and it was just an
f1 hybrid so you would see the same
exact results pretty much it would just
be a wide-open
shotgun result you know and that's what
you would seem a Starfighter anyways I
know mike has found a good Starfighter
and they use that and but a lot of those
star fighters were not very good so yeah
yeah I noticed Dan Kannamma has been
pushing those blues this one blues
pretty hard they look they look cool the
ones that he's had with right very how
long did the broadleaf Phoenix continue
in the f generation a 5 is when we
started seeing more of the city
kick in to be true breeding subject I'm
not hungry right now I'm doing the thing
for the Nike I'm doing that live feed
right now what yeah you were driving so
I don't need it right now I don't have
space for it you haven't been good
Murray you know you're just doing his
own thing actually just isn't listening
cuz they're driving hey do smeels del
Taco
yeah once once moody's in LA once he's
living down there we're gonna we're
gonna have the full-time podcast it's
finally starting I know people have been
asking for it for a long time
but you know how long do I take skunk
spray chem it depends on the phenotype
just like everything else different
females go different lengths and I take
it as long as it needs to go I don't do
the whole week counting thing I just run
plants until they're finished I've never
understood that I mean I guess it's good
to try to have things planned out but as
you learn how seedlings go you should
know that there are several different
phenotypes and just giving you a number
would be again a shotgun effect of just
trying to guess at what you're gonna get
yeah that makes real filly real filly
that makes sense what's up Joey how you
doing brother did you did you see Gold
Coast pee pee his pants did you make him
pee pee his pants I hope you did
it's hard not to think of ethos when
people think of s1 glue
look that guy koukin bucum guys a [ __ ]
bi itch
what a question you guys got that aren't
specifically about Bodhi seed lines and
I have no idea about anymore cuz he's a
you know like I said and it's not any
disrespect to Bodhi but he's my boy I
love him I love him to the end of the
moon and back but I just it's hard to
keep track of my own lines let alone his
you know yeah you know apprenticea with
a good breeder is gonna be a hard thing
to do because a lot of the good breeders
are older guys and paranoid of people
and we've all been [ __ ] over a lot by
a lot of people especially people that
we've helped our apprenticed yeah dying
breeds II keep I can talk about z-cube I
actually can talk about Z cube z cube is
okay so the Z cubes I have grown in seen
are very tall plants very lanky very
leggy plants into the moon and if stars
but you're further I love you further
friend it's actually further than that
it's very leggy it has hard dense buds
but they stay about golf ball-sized
berry for very [ __ ] resinous however
the skittles trait with the the sweet
skittle smell it's I haven't found it in
any busy cubes I ran so I'm not sure if
that was their intention with the line
but I'm thinking with this get those
lines it's something that they wanted
and didn't get but it is very uniform
even for an f1 they were all pretty
uniform and as was their black rose' no
not doing anymore sour grapes grape
stomper I did that nine years ago
released it and to not much fanfare and
then later on gauge during released the
bx1
and then claimed he created it because
you know and people bought it ate it up
and still repeat the gauge green made
grapes doctor to this day
that was made by our buddy Jojo Rizzo
it's a black beard bring Jim in but with
all that said about Zeke you I can say
it's [ __ ] good it's a good line it's
very good line it's worth growing I've
been very surprised with the dying breed
stuff usually when a company pops up I
don't I don't buy the hype automatically
like a lot of people are like oh what's
up zip zip zap zow you know like with
all disease and just all about it and I
hung back and I said you know I'm gonna
wait until I grow some of this [ __ ]
before I uh Chi does not have the panic
piff picks what does he have up he has
panicked something it might just be 7 1
Oh panic then I'm not sure if he has the
panic pit 4 7 1 Oh panic it's been a
while but yeah III I had to grow up for
myself and yeah man I'm impressed
the black rose' is probably the most
impressive thing that they have done
dragon fruit I have popped I haven't run
yet though
we'll see I'll give you I'll give you a
report on that later but the z-cube in
black rose' and watermelon skittles is
okay it's not bad it's it's as good as
anything you could get from from most
common places but I think the black
rose' is special I think that one is the
special one as is their gas pedal to
their gas pedals [ __ ] amazing the
chem defy herbology that was one of the
most beautiful lines I've ever seen I
got a female from that it was just
[ __ ] gorgeous absolutely [ __ ]
gorgeous so again I'm not working them
into lines or anything I just wanted to
see what was up with it
the watermelons giggles in it didn't get
watermelon from it at all at all from
anything that I grew from it it was
slightly sweet like Dutch sweet so I
think there was some Dutch sweetness in
it I don't know I don't know what she'll
be is but I know the sham D and that was
just a term
we used to refer to anything that was
Paul Kennedy that wasn't oh Sh I'll OD
no I don't know he had gas pedals the
[ __ ] I'm not in a lie
to have black rose' gas pedals he cubes
very good but black rose' and gas pedal
were phenomenal be [ __ ] nominal I
don't know who did the fireball oh gee
I'm not sure whose that is but one thing
I will say with black rose' is that I
didn't see a single purple Fino in any
of it and they're all super uniform it's
just one of those lines and sometimes in
f1 you'll see it a lot where it's a -
poly hybrids crossed and you'll get a
very uniform line but and then f2 it
turns into craziness lemon Versace I've
seen pictures of that and I didn't
didn't appeal to me it's not black rose
it's black rose a black rose is a
different line and I've seen stuff
called California black rose' but this
seed pack was just said black rose' so
you know with them I'm not sure if it's
California black rose' and black rose'
is just a shortened term or if black
rose' was something different
and then there's also rose a so yeah
there's there's rose a is different than
California black rose' and I'm not sure
if California black rose' and black
rose' are the same thing yeah see I
Minds just says black rose' on it and it
was in one of the that's like a
cardboard cylinder thing and just as
black rose' on it yeah I don't know if
it's California black rose' or black
rose' I've seen green Dave's Grove
California black rose' and his was like
deep purple and beautiful none of these
were remote they didn't look anything
like that not even close not even close
to what Dave's looked like so I'm
assuming it's a different line but I
don't know for sure
no black rose is not a black rose cross
Rose a I'm 99% sure
and they're probably to tell me I'm
wrong but I'm 99% sure about this it
does not increase science yeah it's
Russian cush Oz cush in the old Mendo
line effects which is the I think mother
to purple effects by not so dog but yeah
effects Oz cush and Russian cush it came
out and saying though it came out
[ __ ] and say it's very different
what about white rhino oh my god google
it Jesus Christ Cody come on I think
there's enough info about white rhino
out there that I don't need to even talk
about white [ __ ] rhino that's a
pretty well covered strength buddy okay
what other stuff we got clockwork orange
I talked about that just a few days ago
I'm gonna bust everyone's balls Brin
just cuz I can mm-hmm
not dasa fix no just to fix tell us more
about medicine man oh oh you got me
technicality on the white rhino uh-huh
Las Vegas lemon is that the lemon skunk
I don't know what that is probably the
whole chitral skunk of assume like most
lemon skunks are I like those oblivia
obvious straight yeah you're so sweet
you're both wait what do I think of haze
which haze man Oh haze man is the Google
info up to stand - Matt standards on
white rhino it is you did mr. Matt elite
cannabis you didn't listen to [ __ ]
bruce long enough and by the way I'm
gonna say everyone should listen to
[ __ ] [ __ ] Bruce everybody go
YouTube [ __ ] Bruce best rapper on
earth
um let's see I already did the right
berry story you missed it before he came
in you missed it
San Diego Green crack now that I know
it's different from cush well there's
any other green crack we've always kind
of thought it was the same thing and
that's and it always kind of made me
wonder why the cush was called a cush
but Danny of Green crack is either drove
on a papaya crossed to something else
but it lines up closer with so mango and
probably so mangoes Super Skunk or
papaya Super Skunk um I don't know much
about NorCal campus I only know San
Diego campus yeah it's hard to say dank
man I'm not sure what that could
possibly be you need a lot more than
that to look at it and kind of get an
idea and with so many new companies just
Paul and Chuck and 90 lines together
it's really getting harder to do that
that identification just from either a
description or from just looking at it
it's easy it's easier to break it down
to base lines but I couldn't tell you
exactly what it is I can tell you base
lines usually though
great banana dank um do you remember
what's in that that was I didn't sell
much of that line I'm pretty sure it was
like the shock something or I can't
remember off the top of my head yeah you
can try to yeah you could DME a picture
of it but there's no there's no
guarantee hey it's you you [ __ ]
the the lightest of the lime is going to
be the lime light
I think that carries the heaviest lime
traits of any of my lines I'm not
currently selling sprite or limes I
guess it's called slider because I mr.
Beldon instead of spider I misspelled it
when I was printing out the tabs and I
just got lazy and I was like all right
[ __ ] it
Matt Rhys is also a rat so who gives a
[ __ ] about Matt Rhys but yeah I don't
offer those for sale just because I've
been passing him out for free to
everyone but limelight for sure is the
most Lyme a ver a doe stuff great pie
absolutely I think that that that is the
[ __ ] most killer thing that that has
come out that I have experienced from
his stuff
what's up Jill and not many real people
may have but yeah Matt Rhys is a [ __ ]
rat it's on paper it's bad I need I need
a lime stand at the fair it is rat rise
unfortunately I've had a few people
confuse me for Matt rise which really
sucks like if there's anyone I I would
not want to be confused with it's that
that rat piece-of-shit
bull res thank God thank God they don't
confuse me for [ __ ] res I've run a
lot of top dog packs yes I have over the
years nothing new but yeah pasta for
sure yeah that's that's the one that I
run is there's only one real cut of
great pie hairy palms got one seed of it
and that one seed that he popped was the
it was a great pie it was really really
lucky it was amazing yeah well once you
start seeing amber trichomes Denali that
means that degradation from THC to CBN
has started to occur so you want it when
it's most cloudy least amber that's what
you want to go for and if that's where
you like the smoke to be some people
like CBN heavy smoke though that is
indeed the one I used to make black
banana pie not black pie but I hear my
black Y is equally as amazing yeah I
don't really have a black pie that was a
joke
yeah there there's a bunch of crosses I
wanted to do with my um my my chocolate
time ale but I didn't because it won't
sell however I'm working on a few places
for that to go I'm gonna give it to
Cuban to work some lines and it's going
to go to another location
where I can work some lines with it
finally you feel less cloudy trichomes
on horace given more sativa hybrid high
i think it just gives you a different
high but i don't think that there's any
high associated with sativa or indica
that is accurate it's a very it's bad
you can't associate a specific guy with
indica or a specific I was sativa
there's no way that doesn't doesn't play
out that way unfortunately but that's
how most people do refer to it but
that's they if you have any knowledge
and have grown out a lot of different
lines that you would cause it to even a
lot of different lines you would call
indica and a lot of different lines
you'd call hybrid you'd find sativas
that have what you would call an indica
high you'd find indicas to have what
you'd call hybrid high so it's really
hard to say on that give it a little
miracle
yeah it is an old wives tale that's for
sure it's gonna stick around till time
immemorial though because collective's
one people who own and run collectives
for the most part are uneducated and
they will always call [ __ ] indica sativa
or hybrid and they'll be the first ones
to [ __ ] act like used-car salesmen
and tell you exactly how that lines
gonna affect you and that is [ __ ]
[ __ ] and double should I've ever
heard
everybody has a different body chemistry
everybody's receptors interact
differently with different strains so
it's just it's stupid it's stupid it's
it's reckless to in many senses it's
reckless because a lot of people have
you know medical conditions that they
require cannabis to alleviate the pains
of or whatever you know the symptoms of
and these people are recklessly telling
them that this will do that and that is
that's reckless ok let see what else got
whatever that weird mutation
malformation on the monkey haze someone
said it was a trait seen in the opt I'm
not sure what you're referring to
is it the crinkle leaf which I mean the
crinkly if you can find a deep chunk
anywhere but I don't know or you're
referring to sure you can tell more on
the leaf structure whether it's an it
occurs to you but no the the term indica
and sativa is kind of out the window
monkey haze if I remember was the black
deep chunk Fino cross to tom hills haze
and Tom Hill he made this way later
right right before he stopped making
seeds or not stop making seeds but
before I don't know I don't even know if
he make seeds anymore but that was it
was way later when he made that I
remember you had already you chunk had
already stopped being on the market by
the time monkey Hayes came out
yeah I don't know how many times I could
say different different but the terms
indica and sativa really don't have a
place in this market or in cannabis
anymore specifically referring to
effects or structure or type because I
can absolutely show you a [ __ ] even a
tie with a broadleaf slightly broadleaf
tie that with narcotic effects that
would be more narcotic than what most
people would associate with like above a
push so that alone shuts down that whole
indica sativa hybrid type thing you know
what I mean like it just doesn't make
any sense there is not there is not nor
has there ever been just three types of
cannabis it was a really for the time
and the knowledge with cannabis it
worked for a while but it definitely has
no place in now
yeah committed I think you're missing
the whole point on it there's it's not
indica sativa nor should have ever been
referred to that it's just the fact is
that our education wasn't complete at
the time and that's why it was called
the way it was let me know when you get
that done you like em I'd like to see it
man but it's not just about poly hybrids
taking over indica sativa when I'm
referring to as landraces even that have
similar effects to what people would
call an indica whereas it is a sativa so
you can't quantify it that way you know
what I mean and that was it's always
been that way but people's education
hadn't caught up to what cannabis
actually was and how it works if that
makes sense
the is there a guidebook or that
indicates kind of annoyed and terpene
profiles and how it affects that again
everybody has different body chemistry
everybody has a bought different body
chemistry there's no book that can tell
you which way a certain terpenes can
affect your body chemistry because it's
so vastly different so yeah that's the
answer to that what else we got
the indigent term was originally
developed for India that's correct
indicas were developed for Indian
subcontinent cultivars yeah it's kind of
more about right seeds like being it's
like indica sativa hybrid right seeds so
yeah and then there's like type 1 type 2
type 3 and now there's type 4 which is
just right seeds so yeah pretty much
just you know if yeah right seats yep
personal body chemistry plays the
biggest role of anything and that's why
you when you go into a collective and
they tell you how somebody's gonna
affect you you should slap them in the
[ __ ] face tell them not to be so
goddamn reckless I saw another question
somewhere yeah sativa is simply Latin
for cultivated correct elaborate on
males that throw a single set of pistols
on a whole plant what what that would
mean if you have a set a male throwing a
set of pistols on one single spot of the
plant it means for some reason ethylene
was directed to methylate yeah yeah
ethylene was directed and not blocked
for whatever reason that hormone was
released in that particular region of
the plant and that's what causes it to
throw pistols most males release enough
to Brennan on their own and they block
ethylene so they can be a true male
that's how it usually works however
sometimes it's not always the case and
for some reason and it's not always the
same reason ethylenes let in inter
brothers blocked on a single branch and
it could be something from light leaks
or for some reason nutrients are getting
trapped in that one area and excel
if nitrogen's causing that to happen
there's a thousand reasons that cause
that to happen it doesn't necessarily
mean that the plant is always a herm but
it does mean that for some reason it is
letting that trade through now there's
the argument and I I don't know
scientifically I honestly don't know how
accurate it is
I know DJ short talked about it in his
book saying that he likes males that
herm because it leads to more female
offspring in the progeny because it has
a a leaning towards letting more
ethylene in to cause female production
it means like like the the progeny is
predetermined to be ethylene heavy if
that makes sense yeah I don't know if
it's true or not though I I did it once
with I was a head of blue sativa line
blue velvet and I crossed it to a c99
male because there was of trying out the
DJ short technique and seen if that
worked the blue velvet would her him
from time to time and the c99 was a
hermaphroditic male and from the progeny
we didn't see any harms but there wasn't
much it was a slight but only only
slight and I didn't have enough of a
population to run to really get an idea
of if it was truly female dominant so
uh-huh I don't smoke a lot of CBD so I
don't know about the lucid dreams if you
eat a bunch of Fenton although you have
some [ __ ] lucid [ __ ] dreams
I remember the Afghan occur
I remember the Afghan occur quite well
I'm growing outside and I'm getting
hollow main stems and I got no other
problems any idea is that bad no hollow
stems I mean there's no difference
between Hollow or not Hollow like as far
as it being bad or good there's a
difference but it's not bad nor good one
is it necessarily more hippie than the
drug type it's just old it's it's an old
terminology it's old thought processes
back when they were still trying to keep
hemp as a separate cultivar from the
drug type and they would say oh this
one's more of a drug type you know
selecting out of hand this one's more of
a drug type cos got the hollow stem you
know this is from a long time ago
shouldn't it's it's not even remotely
relevant anymore not remotely relevant
so don't worry about that how wide of
generations a variation on s one seed
there's no way to to say that because it
depends on one let me see if I can break
this down because I try to explain this
a lot and a lot of people don't get it
let's say you are going to choose the
clone yourself that you're gonna s1 from
the seed line so let's say you have some
let's go with skittles let's just say
skittles was a line right it was a it
was an f1 line and you're like okay I
want to pick this phyno from skittles
because it is [ __ ] awesome and I want
to s on it and start to lock down the
traits from this specific Fino now you
go to do it you reverse it the plants
will come out pretty plentiful and and
and different well while variants
because the skittles has a lot in it and
it's a poly hybrid and the line wasn't
heavily worked it was an f1 hybrid it's
not like it's an f6 it's an f1 so you're
gonna see wide variance swing not quite
as wide as out crossing it obviously cuz
you're not bringing in more genetics
you're keeping it at the
genetics however your students see that
wide swing however let's say you go to
s1 deep chunk because deep chunk is a
heavily worked line to rush down to
roughly for 3 to 4 phenotypes that
majorly show themselves probably five or
six but three to four that make that
that show up the most often you're gonna
see much less variance than that because
you chose it from a worked line and
hopefully that helps you describe that
or understand that clearer you subscribe
to the idea that picking late showing
males is always better because early
showing Mouse yeah no I don't just I
don't subscribe to that at all I choose
my males based on a few things but some
of them are superstitious and I'm gonna
be real like that a lot of the male's
that I pick it's all on superstition and
I don't know until I run the progeny if
that was correct but you got to start
somewhere right I like to keep that
proprietary of what my actual choosing
is but it needless to say it's
superstitious but yeah you have to you
have to when it comes to choosing else
you never know until you run the progeny
and a lot of the times the males that
end up being the most effective in the
out cross of the plants that I run
weren't my initial choices that's God
that's gotten to be less and less and
I've gotten better at it over the years
however still that that tends to show up
to find an outlier of deep chunk what
you need to do is do do like five or six
F gens of open pollination and you'll
find those outliers they'll start
popping out that's how you work the line
back out is through open pollination
exactly cry baby I think a lot people
like when I hear people say oh I always
choose my males that when they have the
the the late flowering males that have
like hollow stands like all that [ __ ] is
just as good as [ __ ] flinging [ __ ] at
at a plant and whatever has the largest
amount of [ __ ] on it you pick like that
it is the same thing it really is it's a
wing and a prayer
and then but the only thing that matters
is running on
finding out if it's accurate in the way
you want it and being willing to drop
the lines that aren't good I'm in town
driving around need that grief
oh poor sick meds right poor [ __ ]
sick meds I'm driving around your town I
need that green crack that you know but
that one where I wiped your name off it
and [ __ ] s titude your line if I could
said it was my s1 yeah I need that one I
need that one
you missed the joke Rin you missed the
joke you're late on the joke [ __ ]
sick meds any original white cut yep
still have the white I've always kept
the white I love it I love it for
breeding in certain things I can have
reversed males palm be sterile reversed
males pollen is almost always sterile
[Music]
well the pistols are mostly sterile I
should say not their pollen or reverse
smell shouldn't have fallen a reversed
female can have sterile pollen sometimes
a lot of is more sterile than others but
yeah it's it's definitely a lot harder
than people think to reverse it's easy
to get a plant to reverse it's not easy
necessarily to collect said reverse
pollen and sometimes a lot of its do it
looks like I have one minute remaining
so I hope you guys have a rad weekend I
just wanted to pop on and chill if you
remind me next time gas fad will tell
you about the the platinum alien orange
cookies and all the other [ __ ] next
Friday I believe is the the Mooney part
3 and we are going to have this [ __ ]
recorded this time because my buddy's
helping me now
what I share I don't even know you why
would I share anything with you people
be [ __ ] crazy
and he's ex waiter
you