welcome to breeders Syndicate the only
cannabis Show Breaking Down the myths
and history in cannabis I'm Matthew seed
maker for over a decade and a half and
this is my journey in defining my truth
in this wild world of cannabis I invite
you to join me and the can Illuminati by
strapping into the passenger seat but be
warned it's not always pretty with the
invasion of corporate culture into
cannabis it's getting even more muddy
which is why I've made it my mission to
have a permanent record before all the
history is lost and buried under a pile
of
cookies
we're the traditional Market
The Syndicate is a collection of seed
makers that want to push back against
all the smoke and mirrors in doing so we
will continue to ruffle the feathers of
those who oppose and my personal mission
has become much bigger than myself
welcome to the Cannabis Underground
this is the revolution
so I just got in
brand new
here we go
C2
of some creations
peace
the flower and then this is my um rip
attachment the normal bowl is actually
my favorite Bowl it's uh slotted
has a built-in filter
super thick and solid like
I don't worry about breaking it you know
it's it's super solid but um really
really proud to be working with these
guys on the new pieces and these are
going to be available soon for anyone to
have at a super affordable price which
was the the idea like my favorite piece
you know and being able to offer it an
affordable price to anyone who's a fan
of the show so
in honor of that we're going to use
the old vertex I talk about it all the
time a lot of people don't know what I'm
referring to this is the heat wand for
the rip
my rip master
um
my old friend irie eyes told me about
this back in the day and the story goes
um we're going to the can Illuminati
party and he was I don't know if he is
flying out to the party from LA but
resin lung had to stop by his place and
pick up his special bong
for in this special wand that he used
and I was like oh my God what a what a
yuppie dude what are you doing and I had
this plan where I was gonna like pretend
to break his bong because he's so like
anal about it needed to ship it or like
have someone pick it up and then we get
to the party and someone had I think
Denali had outdoor Blue Bonnet in the
first year
and um
I got to try it with this and it
completely changed my whole point of
view on smoking vaping
flavors how you can assess them all of
it changed instantly so when I'm I don't
use it daily but when I'm like really
really wanting to figure out like what
something really tastes like and a
really really assess the high
you can't go wrong with the rip wand
um they've been having trouble sourcing
some of the parts for this for a long
time I know there's people working on
other ones but this so far this is my
best and the favorite
here we go uh this is ba 10 from
big ear and I can't remember what ba
stands for though
anyway let's see Born Again born again
there you go
thank you
hmm
actually has a really good flavor I
thought it was going to be very super
silver hazy but actually
like minty Christmas
yeah that's really good
it smells a lot like super silver haze
like a normal super silver haze the the
normal expression that goes around and
cut form out here but
ma'am it has a different flavor that's
really really good and unique
best I can go is like minty Christmas
not chocolate but almost like a
peppermint but not peppermint I I don't
know it's good though anyways
keep your eye out I'll make posts when
they become available so you can get
your own
yeah yeah come on
there we go
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge
we hope you join our Union of breeders
and Growers come check it out