foreign
[Music]
ER Syndicate where we explore the
history of a clandestine scene Through
The Eyes of the folks who lived in I'm
Matthew owner of Riot seeds I'll
occasionally be joined by my co-host not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
welcome to the underground
hey what's up everyone welcome to
breeders Syndicate I'm Matthew this is
my fellow host not so dog good evening
everyone we are here for another weekend
of uh fun fact-filled Journeys in uh
strain history
so tonight we were thinking about
covering something that we we don't
normally talk about a whole hell of a
lot as far as like getting deep into the
details of cookies since it's a modern
lime you know like we try to spend our
our time on older lines for the most
part A lot of the bass lines but cookies
I feel has become uh somewhat of a
baseline now For Better or For Worse uh
what do you think on that
um I agree with you Matt and I certainly
uh picked you know starting
um his history a long time ago simply
because there was way less people to get
pissed and complain uh about what we
were talking about and you know it's
it's also one of those things that um
it's probably not well known by a lot of
people you know and there's a lot of
disparate facts and little bits and
pieces that you gather up
um and so we've been slowly working our
way towards more modern stuff
and uh you know cookies is obviously and
like that whole family that it spawned
uh is is a big part of cannabis these
days uh and it's it um you know it's a
lot more delicate uh because cookies is
also like you know intending on being a
global brand and there's a lot of
business and money behind it and it's
not as simple of like a clandestine
story as maybe some of the older stories
are
um you know and but uh and all the
people are still alive and around as
well yeah yeah you know
um so there's a lot of different angles
we could attack it from and we'll we'll
pick some of them and go from there
I was thinking like a um let's start
with a quick discussion on the culture
in 2009 roughly when cookies was
starting to gain it's a foothold you
know
um what kind of stuff was going on in
NorCal the Bay Area when cookies was
blowing up it was a little bit during
the purple craze and all that yeah or
was it slightly um no I think it was
later okay I think it was I think it was
later I mean like for let's put it this
way for you what would you consider the
start of like I heard about this thin
mint cut
I didn't start hearing about it until
right around then okay so let's just
let's just say you know
um obviously like as as with anything
there's people that are in the know and
then it spreads slowly and then
eventually it becomes more common
knowledge and then it's like a famous
thing right yeah uh so you know at that
time I I still lived uh in the same area
that I do now I still lived in Mendocino
County so the bay is only where all this
kind of begins is like only a couple of
two and a half hours south of us for the
most part okay um and the two things are
pretty tightly related in a lot of ways
um there was a lot of back and forth uh
in the Cannabis scenes between the Bay
Area and Mendo and Humboldt especially
right yeah uh and I would say
honestly probably in the 2009 2008
2009-2010 era I would say that era for
the both the bay and Mendocino County uh
was you know it was still significantly
a gas era yeah uh I would say that the
the Diesels and the headbands and the
cushes especially uh were all in high
demand uh getting good pricing right and
lots and lots of people were growing
them and that was sort of like the the
bread and butter if you were okay
that's kind of like
I mean it's obviously there's way more
to it than that is but in terms of like
what was the the big Dynamic back then
um you know I mean so 2008 2009 you know
there was an enormous amount of kush
being grown in the Hills by me
um that was all destined for clubs down
by you yeah right yeah
you know SoCal area there was a big oval
in California uh the bay was sort of a
meeting ground in the middle
um you know and and stuff like that and
so you know the bay was sort of like the
Hustler area the bay was where a lot of
all the NorCal weed flowed into
yeah you know and all that and so a lot
of the people in the bay were Hustlers
even if they were you know there were
you know there was warehouses and stuff
like that here or there but like land
places were expensive and it was the
city and it wasn't as easy to be
um you know the way you could be saying
Humboldt or Mendo or somewhere a little
bit more rural yeah
so who are some of the the players in
the early cookie scene do we want to go
over that at all or
well I mean I think I mean there's you
know there's uh
there's really well-known players yeah
obviously and then there's a few people
that aren't particularly as well known
yeah um and you know we could obviously
step in a bunch of landmines on this one
um because all these players are still
active and around yeah and I'm sure they
have their own take on it
um and their own version of it you know
and so they'd probably also be quick to
point out any kind of small
discrepancies yeah uh that might pop up
as well to try to like discredit the
whole thing or whatever so
um you know because cookies is not just
it's not like talking about a lot of the
other strains uh in cannabis cookies is
like the one that formed a brand yeah
you know it was like it was like the
first modern cannabis brand in that
regard and you know in the cookie stores
and fame and it happened like you know
we could maybe talk about like the where
cannabis was at
when it popped up
that's what I was talking about the
culture the culture
so I mean as far as as far as my neck of
the woods in Northern California
um it was uh the green Rush was
massively on in my area
2008 2009 2010 were booming times for
indoor light depth full outdoor of all
kinds of things all over my neck of the
woods what's that indoor indoor pound
rate Circa 2008 2009.
uh I mean like for high quality the do
the prices people would have been seeing
for Quality OG cushion or like you could
you could I mean you could get I could
get 4200 like in my neighborhood yeah
exactly okay for ends you know yeah
especially for desirable things you know
like um you know gassy strains certainly
uh certainly Kush
um you know there was a lot of there was
a lot of game back then where people
from Southern California their entire
career was like coming up to my neck of
the woods buying things at that and
going down to dispensaries in the
southern part of the state and you know
giving them to then those dispensaries
for three 400 margin 500 margin
so that was big business then there was
that was full deaf years depths were big
then there was still droughts back then
so you know depths commanded good
pricing uh you did you did things well
and it was one of those it was
definitely a gas era I mean not that
there wasn't lots of things being grown
but there was an enormous demand for
both Kush and diesels of various kinds
so all kinds of permutations of those
got grown quite a bit because they
because a lot of the the people coming
up and then you know if if you wanted to
leave your area
the vast majority of people that would
leave Sonoma County or Mendo or Humboldt
or wherever if they wanted to go
somewhere and hustle their stuff they
generally went to the Bay yeah well that
was San Francisco or the East Bay in
Oakland somewhere right around there and
the bay was sort of like a a collection
ground for everybody from SoCal coming
up but that didn't want to go all the
way up into the hills I mean there was
people from all over
in the bay looking to get it was sort of
a Clearing House
for where a lot of the weed uh from my
region ended up at least momentarily
even if it was just passing through on
its way to somewhere else
like say dispensaries in San Diego or
you know uh or LA or anywhere like that
right
it was was booming in the bay during
those years if I remember correctly the
Oracle the GDP all of that like a staple
of that Bay Area yeah it was a staple
and I mean I would also say it was
starting to get by then it was starting
to get phased out yeah um in favor of uh
cush and you know I mean cush was
getting still
um pretty damn high prices in Southern
California down down back yeah so if you
had access to cuts
um you know it moved easily and you got
a good price point you know and that was
certainly the height of uh the the gas
diesel craze too so there was a lot of
that sloshing around
um Urkel and GDP and and Grape Ape and
Mendo p and all that stuff I think that
was more like 2005 2006 6 2007 and then
like the wave of gas
really started to come through so what
do you think was the was the
um
what do you think made what became
cookies appealing in a time where yield
was still relatively important maybe not
the most important because OG had taken
dominance and it wasn't like a power
yielder for most people but what do you
think uh drove the necessity for cookies
all of a sudden that drive and hype when
there was already OG Kush and there was
already a like you say a waning demand
for GDP and Urkel
um well I think it was a number of
factors and I think
one one thing you can say about it is
that Americans are pretty tribal right
um but mostly we're not tribal like uh
we're not tribal in the way that a lot
of other countries are tribal like we're
a weird mishmash of cultures so we get
tribal around like sports teams and
stuff like that right
um and one of the things that like I
think pushed it was that I would say
it's probably fair to say in California
that LA and SoCal was considered like
kushland yeah yeah even if it was
produced other places like The Craze the
money the rep all that different types
of stuff La gotta got it right yep and
for the bay uh cookies was really
something that like all of a sudden was
the base
okay you know the bay wasn't just like a
clearing ground for the Emerald Triangle
it wasn't just like a pass-through it
was something they could claim as their
own yeah it was very much a bay set of
cuts and so just like that like you're
gonna have fans of it and we just like
you have fans like the San Francisco
Giants or the Oakland A's or the Raiders
you know or anything like that like
that's our [ __ ]
right this is unique to us and then on
top of that since it become since it
sort of started there the people that
were in the know and all the people that
first got it were kind of from there
yeah right so humans like to feel like
they're part of something special right
yeah for sure everybody likes to beat
huh fomo well everybody likes to feel
like they're on the In Crowd on some on
some aspect of things you know and a lot
of the history of a lot of the history
of the of of that that became you know
and it made people famous too right yeah
um and so I do think that cookies came
along at a really weird time in cannabis
in the sense that
um it was a sea change in my opinion
right where probably before cookies
uh this isn't going to make cookie sound
that good but before cookies
um most weed was judged on its nose and
effect
right uh and looks wasn't that big of a
deal
right I mean I I can't tell you how many
times I would have people come up to my
neck of the woods and they would open up
a contractor bag of Sour and they would
stick their head in it and look up and
say this will work yeah and it was
before they even really like dug around
I mean they could still find something
in it that they didn't like but for the
most part if the nose hit them like a
hammer in the face yeah you were almost
all the way there
right was super important and cookies
like you know is extremely photogenic
and it came about kind of at the uh at
the end of of a certain era where
um you know IG started happening and
these different social media platforms
started happening right and uh it looked
gorgeous
yeah
right and you you can't you know
anything you're looking at on Instagram
or anything else you can't smell it you
can't smoke it you can't but you can see
it yeah and cookies uh and a lot of its
children are extremely photogenic
they're beautiful right I know that was
the first thing that truly caught my eye
was well
I'd seen stuff similar I remember uh you
know there was stuff that would come out
of different Combos and we'll get into
that later that I'd seemed similar but
I'd never seen anything quite capture
all of
several traits in One Bud but I also saw
the yield and thought there's no way
this is going to catch on there's just
no [ __ ] way this is gonna catch on
you know
yeah I mean and I think some of it too
is you know they uh they got it to some
hip-hop artists and they got it and they
and they got it wrapped about and you
know there's if you get it to if you get
things to cultural trendsetters right
yeah then other people might want it
yeah you know and there was a lot there
was a lot of well-developed Clubs
um selling a lot of indoor in 2008 2009
2010 all that that era right there was a
bunch of Bay Area clubs
um and back then if you had an active
medical card that checked out you could
go make a deal with a club yep
you didn't have to have like today you
didn't have to have a bunch of permits
and a bunch of special rules and
regulations you literally had a doctor's
note and you set up an account and you
were allowed to I mean that was kind of
the way 215 worked yeah right was you
were allowed to supply dispensaries
right yeah and so there were and you
know and what people ended up calling
top shelf ended up being indoor
yeah you know not always there was a lot
of light depth back then that made top
shelf and stuff like that but I think
you know when you're buying something at
a store or something that looks really
attractive is a big seller yeah and it
was different
right it was very different
um the way cookies looks the way it's
buds form uh they're very dense they're
very tight
um they look really pretty uh the way
that it has a tendency to color up
really like accents the THC you can see
the crystal it has a lot of visible
Crystal yeah you know
um and it did kind of have like an off
cookie dough type of sweet aroma
and I think it's the first line that
like modern marketing really mattered
with
yeah
in a way yeah you were posting something
up there for a minute but I I couldn't
see what it was no I was just getting it
ready it's it's a it's the video where
they first explain the genetics behind
cookies and whatnot so whenever we're
ready to get into that part I'm going to
toss that up so we can hear it from some
of the First videos ever posted by them
uh the cookie crew so maybe I'll throw
in something like this a little bit too
where
um I uh
Matt and I did a Thanksgiving show on
sour because we figured if you're you
know fighting on Thanksgiving with
families pretty traditional so if we
talk about something that gets people
riled up that'll work
um and cookies is also probably gonna
rile people up and there's a bunch of
big players that are involved in cookies
and they all have their versions and
stories and whatnot and so you know take
this as sort of like General tidbits
rather than some like completely
chronological
you know attempt to lay out the history
yeah right
um because you know the history with
cookies like I said it's not just about
the weed anymore it's about different
people's careers
yep now yep you know and lots of careers
were set up by different stories lots of
stories are conflicting
um I've heard all kinds of stories from
beginning to end but what like I've I've
said in many of our shows before I've
learned a lot of times you can if you
grow enough progeny enough plants enough
seeds of a certain line the plants will
tell you exactly what they are if you
have enough experience and know enough
about the bass lines the plants will
tell you exactly what they are and
that's what I've always been more
interested in when it comes to cookies
not the people behind it not the players
behind it but what it actually is and
what we're seeing when it breeds you
know that's where I always run too so
that's where that's where I'm mostly
going to focus my portion of uh stuff is
when I talk about like the the breeding
traits and how I see them breed and
whatnot but we can cover some of that
historical aspect
um yeah so do you want me just to fire
up the video now or do you want to cover
anything else in the beginning precursor
no I think the beginning part I think
like if we're talking about like setting
the stage for what happened yeah uh we
probably you know it's probably it's
it's there was a bunch of just there was
a 215 was probably was probably the
height of 215. yeah the height you know
is really when it came out a height of
215 error there was a lot of explosion
of cannabis going on there was a lot of
new Growers coming into the scene there
was a lot of younger people getting
involved it had spread to the point and
become chill enough to the point even
though you could totally get busted on
any number of different levels that all
kinds of people were jumping into it
that hadn't wanted to before yeah
business was booming dispensaries were
booming everything was booming and if if
I remember correctly like the first cut
I had heard of was cherry pie out of all
those of that group I mean they had as
you know F1 derb and a few other things
that were in their Circle but the first
one that I heard about before cookies or
any of that was the Cherry Pie and that
was that was what I was most familiar
with uh online before the cookies kind
of exploded and it had a similar look
but it was more OG looking to me than
the the nug structure of the cookies was
that something you guys saw up there uh
do you remember a certain date of it
popping up or any of that yeah I mean I
um
you know I'll I'm gonna I'll dance
around certain aspects of it just
because of the of what we're at but I
can say that there are some people that
were intimately involved in cookies that
I have gone way back with right and I
knew
um uh you know years and years and years
before this stuff came about so there
was certain things that I saw
um before cookies became famous I mean
one of the one of the guys uh that's
involved
um for instance
um he gave me the Flow Rider yeah and I
want to say 2004 spring 2004 or
something like that
um and so that was the first actual like
living in Northern California I was a
little bit uh behind the cush wave
um in terms of like access to cuts that
were specifically Kush
um but that was the first one that I
used to that I used to
um uh I used to rock you know and so
that was that was four or five years
before cookies even popped up yeah right
and it just so happens because that same
crew had that cut that that kush Cut Is
the is the cushion cookie yeah right
that's the question so that's so and I I
just believe it just because of who it
came from and who had access to it and
all that different types of stuff I
don't have any I there's a lot of stuff
that with cookie that's a little
mysterious that one I think is pretty
standard yeah you know now what could
what cut exactly Flowrider is you know
is it is it a a cut of OG masquerading
under a different name is it a different
cut from Florida all that type of stuff
that that's a debate I suppose I got a
question
huh when you when you got it did they
call it flow writer did they call it
Florida OG do they call it Flo Rida or
did how did that happen where did that
put on it to be perfectly honest
um I uh
you know I got it as I got it as OG kush
yeah okay
um and then you know I got interested in
Kush and I'd heard a bunch of different
things and I went back to him and I
asked him so I hear there's a couple
different ones which one is it right
yeah yeah and you know he he said it was
I mean I'll probably mangle this
pronunciation but I never heard the word
Florida OG yeah right
um although it was a play on that I you
know it was it was a Florida
yeah almost almost like how uh uh uh you
know uh somebody with an accent would
say Florida yeah I love your southern
accent by the way that's good it's
terrible you know but anyway
um supposedly and I don't know if this
is true or not supposedly it was it was
it was sent from Jacksonville Florida to
the Bay
yeah
you know
um and at the time I thought my buddy
was like all generous uh for giving it
to me but what I realized way later was
that
um he was gonna he was giving me the
same price he was giving me for diesels
and other things you know which was low
fours and then he was taking it to LA
and like making mad loot off it yeah um
so I didn't get it like on some you know
it but that that that's the first one
it's still one of the best OG's I know
of to be honest uh the OG and cookies is
a really nice cut
so that was kind of my first that was
kind of my first uh as far as things
that were in cookie that I personally
possessed
um Flo that that kush cut is probably
the first one yeah you know
and I think what happened is uh in a
nutshell
um we can bounce around and there's a
lot of depth to all this but almost like
the like the diesel story I think there
was there was multiple accidental
pollinations
yeah that you know this this Herm down
to this we grew up seeds this thing got
named this we you know we played around
with it a couple a year and a half later
this Herms onto this you know so on and
so forth and then you know
um yeah we have some pretty good video
of well yeah pop it up they of them well
certain ones come in certain sections
but basically of them
um making it very clear that it was
probably her accidents because they say
they have no interest in breeding at all
so but what let's pop up the first one
this is uh this is I believe [ __ ] and
burner and uh Powers up Kenny Kenny
Powers they call him no not the guy with
the mullet much different guy uh and
they are discussing in a club I believe
the original video was called big
burner's bigger business episode one
um and yeah this is them discussing it
so let's pop it up here
break it down Jacob bro let them know
something what do they want to know I
mean first of all I see some YouTube
Vlogs where they said cookies got cherry
pie is that true
clear that up no
I'm just saying there's a lot of [ __ ] to
clear so let them go break it down baby
preach what do they want to know I mean
let's let them know what cookies is
first of all there's a lot of like weed
magazines and and like all kinds of
crazy [ __ ] that are just putting false
the relationship between cherry pie and
cookies directly is it's like I would
say more but like a brother and a sister
relationship they have the same parents
one of the same parent one of the half
of the parent is uh the F1 Durban
crossed with that
um with a granddaddy would make the
Cherry Pie F1 Durbin
crossed with the OG they give you the
cookie so that's where they get that's
where they get that that relationship
right there so that's what you know here
we go there's no there's no cherry pie
it's the dirt it's the F1 dirt and
that's what we're breaking it down an
easy macaron real fast bro all right
break it down bro broke it down for easy
math equation for
everybody out there it's the F1 there
plus the Flo Rida Kush
equals
cookies Girl Scouts baby
and let them know what F1 derb is oh
it's like a cross it's F1 and Durban
Poison right yeah
it's not in your bag
not regular Durban Poison you don't have
this
in order to have real cookies you would
have to have what like to have real
cookies like the Real Girl Scout cookies
the ones that the football stick to the
[ __ ] hand [ __ ] crazy tasty thin
mint that's why we call it cookies a
thin mint taste you gotta have F1 Durbin
poison cross together with the right OG
that's a different kind of OG so break
it down chicken bro let them know
something what do they want I mean first
of all I see some YouTube Vlogs where
they said cookies got Cherry Pie and is
that true
to clear that up no
I'm just saying there's a lot of [ __ ] to
clear so let me break it down baby
preach we really want to know I mean
let's let them know what cookies is
first of all there's a lot of like weed
magazines and and like all kinds of
crazy [ __ ] that are just putting false
the relationship between cherry pie and
cookies directly is it's like I would
say more but like a brother and a sister
relationship so basically it was
supposed to be the GDP and
um and and F Wonder making cherry pie
what's your thoughts on that
um that is uh that is not what I know of
okay and that might cause a bunch of so
what I think happened
realistically is
I don't think they wanted anyone to know
okay
um because I don't think they wanted
anyone to like try to recreate what they
had
and I think it's fair to say that no
matter who they might be currently
um back then
um the guys that that made it famous
were more Hustlers than they were
Growers and breeders yeah right they
were more people that that moved things
around that like they they were deeply
involved in the weed scene and stuff
like that but you know they they were
more middlemen than they were like
someone like you or me yeah who was
producing it you know making seeds you
know growing for Market all that
different types of stuff they just
weren't that way and so I think they
were concerned both that they didn't
want to give anybody credit all credit
with cookies starts with cookie fam
right
um and like a lot of places as we as
we've talked about many before times on
this show uh use you know use you work
off what you get first right you you get
work from other people and you get bag
seed or you get this or you get that and
then it gets famous and then what
happens
you want to make it seem like it all
originated from you
yeah right and I also think that maybe
even back then like I don't even think
they all had their story straight with
one another I doubt that they really
even knew what pollinated what I don't
think those guys could truly identify a
Herm in a room what was herming on what
and I think they did a lot of guesswork
personally like I
there ain't the brightest
well I don't think necessarily speaking
it's not the brightest but imagine
I'll be fair and I'll just say that
imagine that like your your story starts
with bagseed
yeah
right and now you have to now you have
this famous thing and it's blowing up
and you know like you're starting to
breed and do some different stuff with
it because you're trying to Market it in
a certain way but like all the steps
that got you to where it begins you
didn't actually do yeah right like I
mean for instance it's pretty well known
that Berner was a bud tender
um he didn't grow at all yeah right he
knew rappers and he had a small hip-hop
career that he was trying to work on
um and he was an outlet and he hyped
stuff and he moved stuff yeah and he he
made that into like you know he's a bit
obviously he's the face of cookie now
right
um but he's like yeah I mean he's the
one on um Forbes you know yeah
everything he's the face and you know
and that wasn't I don't even think that
was done intentionally like it was it
was almost like I think that as these
there's like a lot of things you know
there's there's a loose collection of
people
right and as Fame comes and there's no
contracts and there's no formal you know
organization everybody starts reaching
for everything they can get yeah and
there was winners and losers in that uh
at least so far there's some people that
are super well known and there's a few
people that were probably like more
responsible at least for the beginning
parts that aren't very well known at all
and that seems to me to be a um a common
theme in the history of cookies whether
you're at the beginning or you're making
your way down the road to you know the
the lemonade era and all that it sounds
like it's a repeating story that there
are a lot of really uh sometimes even
really talented people doing some work
behind the scenes that um don't get the
shine so yeah I mean well yeah there was
an there was an errand there was an ERA
too where back then especially
um
it was all about who wanted to show
their face yeah there was a couple
people that did not want to show their
face
and so as a result like barely anybody
knows who they are and people like
Berner and you know and [ __ ] and stuff
like that who were wanted to be famous
and wanted to use this to make
themselves famous yeah
um they became the face of it
right one got a raptor out of it and
yeah yeah you know and and became CEO of
cookies or whatever and you know and he
wasn't even involved in any of the
growing of cookies or any of the
breeding or anything like that he was
the guy that got you decent tickets for
it and you know and gave it to Wiz
Khalifa and these different people that
would hype it up and then these famous
people had it and he helped put it on
the map
you know and so when the people that
actually own cookies decided to like you
know form the brand they got the face of
it
they didn't really care necessarily so
much about like you know who was the
most involved or who who you know yeah
they cared about they needed a
spokesperson yep
a lot of major corporations do that
that's that's very common yep you know
and Berner was looking to be famous and
you know it was a good spokesperson
yeah
right
and I mean there was you know I used to
I used to joke that like there used to
be a bunch of people in the bay that
thought that the eighth of cookies they
were buying was like personally
hand-watered by butter yeah yeah I heard
that a lot people would get in big
arguments so they'd be like no no he's
growing it come on back in the day it
was a real bad you know and there was
there there was there was you know there
was definitely crew in the cookie fam
that was growing it yeah but that just
wasn't his angle yeah
you know they're just that just wasn't
his angle you know so
um and uh you know and and so as as a
result of all this Fame and stuff like
that there's a there's another
um there's another aspect of it where
all of them tried to make as much of it
as they could as out of out of it as
they could yeah of course right you know
I mean it spawned it didn't just spawn
cookie I mean it spawned although that
came later it spawned sherbinski's yes
you know and the sure brand and all that
different types of stuff and gelato and
yeah and and you know and you know so
there's like a I mean this could be like
a multiple
multiple you know episode show I suppose
depending on what angle you want to take
on it
um but I I will say going back I do
think that part of the
what's the best way to put it part of
the confusion about cookie is that in
the beginning some of them honestly
didn't know all the steps yeah and I and
I do think that they also wanted to
obscure a bit what they did know
because they didn't want anybody else to
either get credit or you know go out and
grab those things and start making
things because as everyone's aware right
um you know cookie seeds and cookie
hybrids and OG KB and then forum and
animal and all these different things
that were coming out they all commanded
top dollar yeah so there was a lot of
money on the line
and they were always terrified of their
secret and their control of it getting
out
yep because again it got famous and it
got famous at this weird time where
things were transitioning but it was
still that 215 gray area time where
nobody owned it yeah
right it was very punk rock like nobody
nobody owned it no but there was no
contracts there was no documentation
there was no there was a loose group of
friends yeah that was only shortly to
come
right so there and there was really
wasn't a way I mean there was even a
thing where like
they would I don't you know they
wouldn't even let
um they kept they kept burner away from
the crows yeah you know and they gave
him the clothing company which ended up
being a dumb thing because he made a
[ __ ] ton of money off selling 150
t-shirts yeah he was the the real winner
in that one you know and and it also
didn't have any risk because it wasn't
weed it was just clothing
yeah so I wanted to show a picture too
of the F Wonder real quick this is a
picture this is from uh the Instagram
account F1 Durbin but this is exactly
what it looks like how it breeds
um it's very true to form on this a lot
of people question whether it's a real
cut or not it does exist it's existed
for a long time
um when we grew it it was heavily Merlot
wine but I'm not so good at smelling
like aniseed in these Terps and uh yeah
I mean I I think it's probably very easy
to to uh have that in there I know some
people smell Coca-Cola type Terps too
with that Merlot wine smell but yeah
this is it
um I I think it's not very well
documented so I wanted to sneak it in
here while we were still talking about
the uh predecessors
I think it it ties into
um like I said the multiple accidental
pollinations
you know uh that occurred
um and so the farther back you go in the
cookie story uh the murkier it becomes
um there are certain things that that I
think we know for sure there are certain
things that are known that aren't very
well known right uh there's certain
things I might even dance around just
because they're stored like you know as
as any tale that involves a bunch of
friends over a long period of time you
know there's parts that are pertinent
and there's parts that
you know
um could ruffle some feathers I suppose
but yeah and there's stuff that you
think and that I I probably disagree
with you know like it in what's actually
in specific ones and specific things oh
I mean it'll be interesting about you
know we won't say what exactly but like
you know there was this week between CSI
Matt and myself there was debates going
back and forth on on lineage of certain
things yeah um and people that have been
Skeptics maybe even coming around to
certain theories yeah or being more open
to it because they they smelled certain
things or saw certain traits and they
were like whoa you know and to me like I
I don't know why I don't why would you
want to dance around I think we don't
need to dance around it particularly on
this specific one because I think it
answers a lot of questions there's been
a lot of is it okay if I just enter in a
little bit I mean you know sure we can
you know go for it I suppose yeah I mean
because we're already going to do the um
the F12 reversal at csis and we're going
to answer a lot of questions with it at
least to get an idea of what happens
when you cross a the F1 derb and that
Florida OG or the Flow Rider
um or if you cross F1 derp and GDP
um looking at the F1 derb I I mean
growing it when I did I didn't I didn't
have a lot of insight into it uh I grew
it seeded it immediately lost it pretty
quick and I also didn't have the same
experience that I did that I do now
looking back when I was growing it and
one of the main question of cookies I
think that that me you and CSI talk
about is where is all the black and
purple coming from I mean we know Urkel
can kick purples and that's in in my
opinion at least Urkel is the main main
force behind cookies and the look The
Shape a lot of it
um but it's not really well known for
consistently and and being a true
breeding purple breeder
um there's a lot of green coming out of
purple or purple purple and GDP much the
same but there is a consistent true
breeding black trait in that line and
and you know we had talked about deep
Chunk we had talked about
um maybe it is just circle maybe it's
like this recessive shape being brought
up and it's been slammed into each other
enough that is just consistently
bringing black now
um or maybe Mendo perps
you know and what we know about Mendo
perps is it's it's it expresses a lot of
different uh smells in the S ones one of
those is heavy anise
you know
and that's always very interesting and I
think uh the fact that it breeds true to
Black in a lot of cases
um is another interesting point to that
what's your thoughts on it
um I will admit that uh
this is a little political or whatever
but I will admit that um I did not
believe for a long time
uh some of the stuff Matt was saying uh
in terms of not that I thought I was
lying or anything like that I just I you
know I just didn't I just didn't quite
see it quite as much and then
um you know different stuff starts
coming to light in various aspects and
you know things start bubbling up or
whatever and uh
and I I do tend to believe now that uh
Mendo p is in there somewhere yeah I do
um you know and it's simply because you
know there's there's a lot of
connections between like Mendo and our
crew uh and those Bay Area cats in one
way or another like I said I mean I have
a long-running relationship back then
with uh one of the guys
um that we did a lot of exchanging of
um we had a we had a cut called Anis
that used to get pushed through the bay
quite a bit and it was did you say the
anus
um which was which was uh which was a
strangely which was a Mendo perps uh
Durbin poison
yeah interesting thing that we made that
hurts yeah
and so you know you know people should
know that with anything like there's
certain things that are that are
speculation and there's certain things
that I know for fact yeah right and so
you want to always be clear about the
two
um I I tend to think that it's in there
I tend to think not that it's in I don't
think it got in there late I think it
got in there early yeah
you know uh it was an early contributor
um and I do know something that's not
particularly well known uh that I guess
I could spouse or whatever
um I know what the mother plant that
cookies came out of was
what's that
um so the seeds that uh became thin mint
right that I guess started the the
cookie craze or or what have you right
um they were grown by my friend
and uh uh they were rolling up a joint
in the bay uh one of my oldest friends
was actually in the room with with these
guys at the time and some seeds fell out
of a cherry Kush Bud okay
okay and those seeds uh [ __ ] ended up
uh making thin mint
so I wonder so Cherry cush now this is
different than the Cherry Pie right yes
so supposedly
um Cherry Kush is
um cherry pie uh Herms onto the
Flowrider gotcha
right and see from that they called
Cherry Kush that makes sense cherry pie
is known to do that little cherry pie
not only Herms uh cherry pie throws
actual male full male pollen sacks like
you would like live like not just
bananas but actual it can pop full male
flowers at times right yes it's a tricky
one yeah
um and
um you know so so I know what the mom is
you know yeah I and as a result of that
I like I know what room it actually was
it actually the the room was grown in
Willits which is a little town in
Mendocino County about 20 minutes north
of me yeah
um and it it came out of a relatively
small room and there was only three
things in the room and two of them were
uh were uh Cherry Pie and and that and
that kush cut
uh the other one was Elvis oh strange I
remember Elvis yeah the other one was
Elvis there was only three things in
there
um and so we know what the mom was so
they were rocking Elvis and they didn't
use that they used all the suckers
well it's not that they used yeah you're
right you're right yeah it happened on
there I think
to be honest I think the first
intentional cookie breeding like by them
came when they started messing around
with sherbert like when they started
messing around
you know in 2009 2010 2011 12 like that
era yeah right I think before they
didn't really know you know they didn't
even have it
right it was different people had it it
was getting moved to different people
it's not like certain people weren't
smoking it or having it or whatever but
it was like I think thin mint was sort
of the basis for them to like take off
with it yeah if you will
um
and uh and so you know I wish I could
actually see comments uh while I was I'm
talking there are some people that are
dropping some stuff that I wanna that I
would like to speak on but
um I have to toggle back and forth
between uh Matt's beautiful face and uh
you don't want to do that you don't want
to miss seeing my face I know so that's
why it's so hard for me to read comments
so I apologize sometimes I'll see him if
Matt pops them up because he pins them
or something yeah it's um there's a lot
of stuff about like always be flowering
and flux and uh Frost boss and all those
guys people just plug in names trying to
guess it who's who
um I mean all good names all good names
I suppose I I don't know if uh you know
there's a there's a part of me that
wonders how specific to get on certain
things and and what to stay like
slightly mysterious on or whatever but
um there was a couple names there was
even a a dude's name that started with a
c in there that was definitely involved
on a certain level
um but I know I'm I am 99.9 sure
that uh what became thin mint came out
of cherry cherry Kush so one thing I
want to add here is um when it came to
the forums when it came to Girl Scout
cookies hitting the forums a lot of
people are used to hearing the term
Forum cut now when Girl Scout cookies
hit the forums thin mint wasn't
something being passed around or bandied
about the name really wasn't something
popping up yet
um the first time we saw it was I
believe it was always be flowering
passing it
to someone either directly to Lumpy's
lump status or
or to someone to lump status and that
was the first time a lot of people
really got a good look like a really
good look at big blown up grows of
cookies and they were some of the most
beautiful and I do believe those are
still up there on icy mag if anybody
wants to go check them out um lump
status has some beautiful pictures up
there but yeah um The Forum cut was the
one that
the cut that became called form cut was
the one that tended to circulate um then
mint didn't start circulating until much
later
wanted to add that in there because a
lot of people were asking about uh The
Forum and when it came well yeah I mean
we me and uh uh a homie of mine on this
show all just called tuna uh tuna and I
actually grew some of the first cookie
um up in Mendocino uh because those guys
were all stuck in like six and eight and
ten lighters or whatever and they were
trying to get uh they were trying to get
uh obviously more of it at the time you
know uh and they were so paranoid about
anybody knowing what it was uh I think
they made it I mean I think they made us
call it girl I'd have to ask him uh
gravity
oh interesting because because they
didn't want anybody on our scene any of
our workers
they made sure that like we could never
talk to anybody that was on our farm
about like this was special or this was
new they were terrified of it getting
out yeah
um and so and they were pretty
controlling on it for a long time so I'm
not surprised that thin mint took a
minute to get out
um I think what Screwed cookie in that
regard is that uh in cookie lines
there's hermaphrodism
then back seats get out
and that's in a lot of ways that's how
cookie kind of spread it first they were
not passing it out to friends they were
not sharing it they were not they had a
thing that made a lot of money
and was hyping and that was their Ticket
to Ride and they didn't want to share it
yeah
you know so I'm not surprised that I'm
not surprised that the real thin mint
sort of took some time to bubble out
right yeah uh because one of the things
that's kind of funny one of the things
that swore me off of cookies for a few
years was we ran a couple big Greenies
couple big depths of it
uh and it freaking it harmed uh and
seated
and then they were devastated because
they didn't want seeded weed to get out
yeah right so they didn't want us to
sell it so you can imagine how fun it is
to have a couple greenhouses of weed
that they don't want you to sell yeah it
was kind of it was kind of before like
the the modern hash era had sort of
taken off again right so it wasn't like
you could just be like oh we'll just
wash it right that it really wasn't it
really wasn't that era yet right
um where there was like a like a whole
bunch of hash like there was you know
there was water hash and there was some
BHO and there was Keith and stuff but it
wasn't like all the
the Modern Gear that people are used to
yeah it wasn't like the secret cups
blown it up quite yet I don't think
there wasn't even like you know bang
like you know that was like the if you
were smoking it back then you were
probably smoking a glowing Cherry Banger
and dropping unpurged BHO into it or
something like that you know yeah that's
it wasn't it was it was the snap crackle
and pop era you know uh there was uh it
was it was we're going to hell for the
[ __ ] we made and sold as BH early on I
have ignorance you know ignorance is it
people didn't know at the time yeah I
don't think you know people and you know
and then we didn't have vacuum ovens and
all that different types of stuff it was
um coffee filter water bottle weed in it
shoot [ __ ] I mean the worst thing was
was was you know uh this is getting off
tangent but like PVC tubes was the
standard with uh with silk screen and
then you would you know you would put a
cap on it you would drill a hole through
the cap and then you would like like pop
um you know cans of butane through
and yeah and then and then all of a
sudden people discovered that like after
you do that for a while the PVC isn't
smooth anymore on the inside yeah no
weird how that works
so a little polyvinyl chloride or
whatever into your mix
but that's that I mean that's way off
topic but
um but I just mean in the sense that
like uh I discovered uh pretty early on
that cookie did not like food sunlight
uh and was prone to hermaphrodism yeah
you know and I think all the early cuts
that got out were a lot of them were bag
seed
I would think so
you know and then they got and then you
know we're talking about form and then
they got named I mean we see this with
diesel like we've talked about this
we've seen this with chem dog we've seen
it with a bunch of stuff where we're
just bag seed bag seed bag seed
proliferates on cuts that are kind of
held tight in little Cruise back seats
start slowly proliferating you know I
remember when this was happening with
cookies uh the cookies crew kept
referring to everything as fortune
cookies like you're lucky you got that
seed in that bag so it's fortune cookies
that's not real cooking they're just
fortune cookies that was the slander
evolved non cookie fam approved cuts
well yeah because it was one of those
things where if it wasn't branded
through them it wasn't them sure and
they they certainly weren't going to
admit that their stuff had gotten out
either yeah you know and so there's a
bunch of rumors we don't need it's not
like I'm some expert where I can tell
you the origins of forum exactly or ogkb
and how it exactly popped up and through
where and how I mean there's a there's a
lot of you know like a lot of these
things there's a lot of circles involved
you know small circles that can overlap
at times you know and there was
definitely circles and Mendo that had
aspects going on with them and those you
know and there was circles in the bay
yeah and in some cases some of those
people own places in both places
the bay and by my area yeah you know
um and so as a result of that you know I
don't think I don't know if if most
people ever heard of like what bud
itself The Thin Mint was found in
because I don't think they wanted to
give up what the mom was yeah
you know
um but I'm night like I said I'm 99 sure
that it came out of it came out of chair
of cherry Kush what's funny yeah it
makes sense and what's funny to me is
like it's almost like that Old Dutch way
of thinking where Neville would put his
the lineage out because he was a breeder
and he knew it would be even if you know
what the parents are unless you had
these exact clones
you're still going to have a tough time
making a line that represents the same
exact line that I'm selling seeds of you
know sure a lot of these other people
they didn't they weren't as deep into
breeding so they're thinking if you know
my recipe you can make my my recipe you
can make my food you know and yeah if
you know what country if you know what
cut the mom was you can get that cut and
then you're halfway there maybe yeah
maybe and then you've got the money yep
yeah in all reality even if you grab two
of the uh same cuts and reverse them if
you're popping seeds the likelihood
you're going to run into that same exact
expression in your environments very low
but that's you know that was years away
from them figuring that [ __ ] out
so I you know I know what buddy came out
of I know what strains were in the room
do I know if if it if that those seeds
were from an S1 of that of that plant no
do I know if it was the the Kush harmed
onto that plant no you know do I know if
the Elvis was involved I don't think it
was but no you know but I know it's
those three and I know what what butt it
came out of yeah
you know and I don't think and I don't
even think amongst their initial crew
um they spread it out very much like a
[ __ ] didn't even tell the person it
came from for over a year that he had
found it
but that's how it goes right that's how
it goes yeah he didn't I I think it took
so there's always been there's always
been uh intentional opaque you know
intent intentional you know uh fog if
you will
you know
uh I mean so looking at cookies from a a
just a purely and when I talk about
cookies I'm going to talk about not
necessarily the The Thin Mint because I
don't think most people like I know it's
out there people have it yes you know
but most people experience The Forum uh
in general so when I want to talk about
cookies most people when they think of
cookies think of the Forum cut
and when we look at that from a breeding
aspect what I tend to see in it is
purple Urkle
and OG Kush and the reason that I tend
to see this is because out of doing
myself having made several different OG
kush and purple Urkle hybrids and OG
Kush GDP having run a bunch and what I'd
seen was this constant
right around the Cookie's expression
showing up these small yielding cushy
looking purple things you know slightly
gassy sometimes more grape honestly a
lot of times when I'd see something look
more close to cookies it would be more
grapey but finding one that looked like
that with gas was really really unique
but to me for a long time that's what I
thought the recipe was that was it
that's all you ever needed but I do
think I do think Mendo perps comes into
play heavily you know
um well I mean if I if I had to make
like a uh
like an educated guess I suppose of what
maybe happened is you know I think that
you know it's almost like parallel lines
that come back together
right so you have a situation where
maybe maybe you've got something like um
uh maybe you've got something like F1
derb yeah okay whatever they say that is
and that thing Herms onto that thing
Herms onto uh uh kush yeah right
um and that's a plan and then you know
you've got F1 derb and that Herms onto
GDP or or something close to that right
or Urkel and and you've got cherry pie
right
um
and then that thing Herms on to that
thing Herms on to cush again
right and now you've got Cherry Kush
yeah and then something Herms again and
puts seeds in Cherry Kush and now you've
got cherry and now you've got
possible thin mint you know what else
you have nail time
we got some video types homie yeah I I
mangle the English language so I have a
hard time specifically on nailing [ __ ]
on that one so bad but
um you know but I I think that I think
that all those cats were determined to
be famous yeah and they saw their movie
and they took with it and then all these
questions that come out and people want
to be like okay so have you been in your
basement for the last 15 years making
this yeah and they certainly didn't want
to be like well we stumbled upon it at
the very end
and we were getting different things
from different friends and friends were
growing it and we were moving weed and
this was happening and that was
happening and then I got the seed seeded
bud
yeah and so I'm we're a cookie fam
yeah yeah that's a that's a nice way to
end that statement right and boom here
we go you know and so so I mean I'm just
even trying to be fair to them like sure
their mission was to like build you know
they had an idea that they could build a
brand and they could get famous and they
could you know sell a lot of weed
especially probably in the beginning it
was wow if we control this we can get
crazy dollar at all these clubs on the
top shelf yeah so let's produce as much
of it as we can
right and get top dollar everywhere yeah
I think that's really how it started and
then The Branding aspect came along and
IG and this came along and these
different things started happening and
they started to realize that maybe there
was maybe with the way things were
heading and legalization and all that
like maybe they could become famous yeah
maybe they could become rich off it
you know
um and you know so obviously like burner
and [ __ ] are well known uh sherb is
pretty well known
um you know but there's a couple other
people uh that aren't very well known
that probably had more to do with it
than anything at least in the beginning
yeah right
um but they didn't want their faces to
be shown
um maybe because they were Bay Area
Hustlers at the time
yeah and they didn't want they didn't
you know and and you know I I've said
this before on on the cast too it's like
it's a very different skill set from the
90s through the 2000s
um of staying under underground and
staying with your face not visible and
staying safe and then flipping into I'm
gonna create a cult of personality I'm
going to be famous everyone's going to
know my face associated with weed yeah
that was a big transition
and it turns out that the people that
wanted to stay uh secret aren't very
well known and the people that wanted to
stick their face over everything and
talk and be at all the events are
household names in the weed Community
yeah however you want to say that you
know but I mean that's how it goes in
any business not just weed it's any like
the the front man's always going to be
the one that that gets the shine it just
is what it is
I mean you know it's but it's it's
different in weed because I think uh you
know there's a part of it where
there was risk involved yeah and and you
know when I and when I say Hustler it's
like that you know they
there was a lot of gray area then
yeah
so you know people were in intently not
trying to get in trouble
yeah you know and so some people took
that route and some people took the fame
route and you know I think when they
started you know they started trying to
breed with it
like basically based off the fact that
they had this one cut and now they were
famous yeah and some people took the
route where they tell on the black
market people at local business meetings
um so we haven't gotten to gelato or
Sunset sherbet yet do you want to touch
on those
we can touch on the sherb I suppose well
I mean I think
um yeah we'll start with sure let's
start with sure I mean that happened
first right yeah yeah
anyway
um so sure supposedly
um by the I I didn't get to ask
sherbinsky himself what sure what Sunset
sherbet is he said it was made in his
garage
during sunsets I believe
um no it was it was made uh The District
in San Francisco that he lived in is
called the sunset district oh maybe
that's what he meant by Sunset yeah
because that was my bad it's called if
you live there and you're from the bay
you do you tell people I live in the
sunset okay it's just it's like a
neighborhood you know that would be why
yeah that's that's exactly why so okay
it's it's named after the neighborhood
I've seen a few different things I've
seen
um Burmese cush cross to the Flo Rida OG
um
I seen pink panties crossed oh I'm sorry
it was pink panties across the floor at
OG but I've seen different things for
pink panties on what exactly pink
panties is whether it's really Burmese
cush cross to Flo Rida OG or it's a
Burmese Kush crust or something else you
I don't I don't remember have you run
that one yet or not
the the pink panties yeah the Burmese
Kush what do you which one you're
talking about yeah yeah the pink panties
which are supposed to be
um a Burmese cush Cross of some sort I I
it's it's it's in the stock but it has
not made its way into the bloom yeah
it's it's not
I remember when I first got it I was
really stoked just to kind of get a good
idea of what it looked like and it
reminded me a lot of a um a lower resin
blackberry kush
yeah it's not that that does not sound I
had better Terps it had better chirps in
blackberry kush it's not like a total
knock on it I see why someone would have
used it for for the Terps but it it
wasn't super resinous
um
didn't have a great bud structure it
wasn't super dense it was pretty it was
purple and it had a great pink stock
like pink stripe stock with purple
stripes down it was really pretty that
way in veg
um but I believe that's what's supposed
to be half a sunset sure
if I'm correct
um and the other half
I don't remember does anybody else
remember do you remember
yeah I mean it I I think you know I mean
I think they've acknowledged that it's
like I think it's they they say it's
that cross to thin mint that's what I
that's right tin mint and pink panties
yeah because it's all because it's like
they cookies never never really varied
very far from the uh from the the root
yeah you know uh they they didn't I mean
that's part of the issue too is it's
it's not really they have like a family
or a line they had they started with a
couple of cuts yeah you know
um I mean like even like gelato right
gelato is is you know sherbet back to
thin mint yes
right I believe so he said uh made by
reversing Sherbert hitting the GSC and
and he said that originally they were
trying to reverse
thin mint onto sherb but that failed
so sure on to thin mint worked so they
said they tried it two different ways
did he say if he were did he say he
reversed Sherbert or did he say they had
a sherbet yes he said reverse Sherbert
yes reversed sherbert
intentional reversal of sherbert and um
some in in you know like in a typical La
garage blown it up type thing like I've
always done no I was done like I said it
was it was I I mean I believe them in
the sense
in in the sense that uh uh sherbinsky
had a six slider in the in the um in the
sunset District right and [ __ ] and
various people they were they were
looking for places to do breeding okay
they were looking for places to like
okay so they have this cookies thing
right there's a bunch of demand they're
getting a bunch of loot from selling it
all over to these dispensaries and
everything else and they wanted to take
it in different places and start
creating seeds because seeds was
starting to be booming business right
yeah and so they worked out a deal I
don't know exactly know what it was
where they brought in sherb and they
brought all the cuts over there and they
start and they used his
um his garage for a few times yeah
and because it happened at his house
um all of a sudden he's sherbinsky
you know I will say he was the he was
the one person out of everyone because I
hit up everyone for this show to see if
they wanted to leave any comments or
they'd respond about different genetics
he was the only one that was nice enough
to respond and and um no no I just
wanted to say it for everyone watching
he was the only one out of those dudes
that was nice enough to respond so take
that for what it is I I appreciated that
part
you know but I do I you know I think he
had I mean I think even on like his
Instagram stories or whatever he's like
gone to the the sunset district and like
pointed out the house that it started oh
yeah yeah you know type of thing he you
know he had a sick he had a six maybe a
six or an eight lighter or something
like that in the sunset
um and you know and he he was buddies
with those guys and so they you know
they started doing some breeding work
over there yeah right so obviously they
have a collab or a partnership going or
whatever else and out of that collab and
partnership eventually came uh sherbert
uh which they named Sunset Sherbert
because of the region of San Francisco
it came out of so it has another Bay
tie-in right I always wondered that now
it makes way more sense with the sunset
yeah because you're not from here you're
not you're yeah from down in in
California desert hell yeah um but yeah
yeah the Sun the sunset is the sunset is
a beautiful District uh beautiful
neighborhood
um in the in San Francisco
um and it was I don't want to say it was
affordable then but it was one of the it
was one of the neighborhoods that you
could actually kind of like live in and
get away with something like that for a
bit Yeah like there's some really
wealthy neighborhoods in SF and there's
some really crappy ones that one was
like a decent one you know and it
borders the you know it goes all the way
to the ocean and stuff like that
um and so it's a cool spot
and uh they um you know there's so yeah
again I think much like the second wave
in Amsterdam like
um like serious seeds and Luke from
Paradise and those guys uh we you know
where like even 25 30 years later they
still don't want to give you lineage
hints
you know yeah I don't think strabinsky
or [ __ ] or any of those guys really
wants to give out exactly what the
secret sauce is okay because I don't
think it benefits them like they're not
like they don't take that aspect they
take the much more modern aspect of Hyde
how you did it to some degree
right because they don't want anyone out
there making reproductions yeah or
trying to find the plants that they used
um and so you know and and as as a
result of that obviously like the rename
game is strong
which is pervasive throughout cannabis
so that thing that you I never saw
Burmese Kush
yeah
you know
um not that that doesn't mean it doesn't
exist or anything like that but it was
it was an Adam Dunn thing that was real
popular for a while as anyone does any
of your friends you've you've seen it
yeah buku yeah is popular yeah it's
popular yeah it was really popular
during that time especially in Colorado
and and stuff like that but yeah it was
one of the early OG Kush crosses that
that people could get like MK Ultra and
Burmese Kush so that's why people were
running it I think that's why people
were running it back then yeah because
it was one of the few you could get that
supposedly had OG Kush in it Goji Kush
in it yeah I mean as far as I know I
could be wrong I do think that the the
primary Kush and all these cookie things
is that is that OG Is That Flow that
flow cut because that's the one that
they had that was their house and they
had it years before you know they had it
years before that the whole cookie thing
even started it was kind of like their
thing you know it's really nice yeah so
um and I've heard you know I don't know
if I want to even speak you know maybe
um it would be it would be best if it
came from sure probably I've definitely
heard some different things over the
years as to like what could have been
involved in sherbert
um I've even heard that Sherbert in the
beginning was a regular line
interesting yeah
that there was that there was that there
was male sherberts
there was there was maybe some male
sherbs at first and I do think so if you
reverse some things maybe they picked
like an exceptional female yeah
and chose to take that one to back to
the thin mint again
yeah you know when they when they wanted
to make gelato or whatever but
um I think he's probably more famous for
gelato now than he is for
sure yeah I would think even though his
name is I think the gelatos kind of like
were a wave and you know there was
probably half a dozen phinos
um from you know that that they made
popular yeah from kind of like one batch
of seed right yeah 45 41 42
33 you know I think oh here here you go
I think you plant seeds who numbered
exceed one through 300 or one through
twenty hear it one through eighty well
we did about I think only like 19 didn't
work
no it worked well did it like yeah I was
hearing it I couldn't hear it this time
oh I was 15 seeds on this final hunt and
the number 20 was just popping
when you plant seeds at the end the 20
was just popping yeah
um I'm not sure if that I think that was
related to like Blanco or something
later on but yeah that's always a good
quote to bring yeah I mean you know uh I
don't I don't think you know I don't
think Berner has ever grown
yeah I doubt it I I remember some of the
the early days at the cookie Collective
when they started popping those up and
people would take pictures of like the
plants in the windows because they'd put
like display clones in the windows and
they'd just be covered in pm and it's
like dude if if this dude was a grower
he should be able to spot that I mean I
get his Bud tenders weren't you know but
dude have you ever been here you know I
I don't mean this to be like a a diss at
all on Burner specifically I just I I
mean I I just mean in the sense that
well because I'm not gonna diss somebody
that doesn't grow
yeah you know that pretends yeah sure
but you know I don't think I don't even
know you know I think I think Berner is
out there to be a hype man burner's out
there to promote a brand and he's done a
really he's he certainly is you know uh
promoted it well yes he has it's well
known he is good at that there's not too
many corners of the weed world that
don't know about cookies yeah I mean
what they know about cookies might vary
that's very true yeah but but the fact
but you know they uh
um you know and right now they're trying
to be like a multi-state organization or
whatever and
um and they're trying to be a clothing
brand and a weed store brand and I think
like the cookies brand is as far move
beyond what our interest is is oh yeah
which is the genetic I don't think you
know they're
um you know uh our interest is mostly on
this show is obviously genetics plant
makeup how plants breed how plants smoke
um all that type of stuff I will say
personally my word we're halfway through
the show or whatever but
um I am not that big a fan of cookie and
and cookie genetics to be honest I mean
we've been talking about it for a while
or whatever but
um if I had a jar of a bunch of famous
things you know
um cookies is not what I would be
reaching for very often no yeah if I had
a jar of 15 things cookies would not be
in the top 15 of everythings I've smoked
nothing cookies there's been cool unique
stuff I've been able to do with it that
I kind of like like the the the uh the
cookie Berry diesel that ended up being
the the blue cookies cut I loved that
one
um but it's few and far between where
I'm like wow this is good enough to
really say it's super super unique and
worth carrying on when it comes to
cookie stuff
uh yeah I mean I and that's just like
that's just my personal opinion really
like it's it's not like but I just find
that like I really like weed that burns
well uh a lot of cookies is like too to
me it's too dense to like burn that
great yeah um and I think that in the
looks I think that cookies suffered from
people making mistakes not knowing what
they were doing early on and I think
they lost the high
yeah I mean one of the reasons I think
ogkb became so famous even though it's
like a mutant grows like an inch a month
you know it's a huge pain in the ass but
it actually worked yeah it was one of
the few cookies lines you know as far as
like cookies goes I think the ones that
actually get you stoned are maybe like
OG KB and and real animal cookies yeah
yeah that's what I know but I think the
real animal cookies gets its buzz from
the kush yeah it's it's mostly OG Kush
anyways it's mostly it's it's like
mostly OG Kush with like some you know
some other elements to it or whatever
and uh but I think a lot to me a lot of
cookie plants and a lot of cookie
hybrids and a lot of sherb and all that
um the high isn't particularly unique or
potent
um and it doesn't last that long
I don't know what I don't know what huh
I got something for you sure I want you
to create a line I want you to create
a line that's truly unique in your mind
but you have to use cookies
you want to make the ultimate special
unique cookies line you have anything at
your disposal in the Clone world
what are you gonna choose
um
well
and if you're trying to make something
unique off cookies
um when I look at plants I I look at
there's very few plants to me that have
it all
yeah right uh that in that regard and
what I mean by that in terms of like you
know every every good trait you can
think of from structure to Bud size to
resin content to buzz to flavor to it
doesn't mold or it doesn't hurt there's
all these classifications right yeah and
so when you're breeding you're kind of
like well
I'm going to look at what do I like
about this plant
and what is it missing yeah right and
and so maybe so with cookies I'd look at
cookies and I'd be like well it grows
like [ __ ] uh it doesn't like food or
sunlight
um and it doesn't get me that high right
um but it has a bunch of cool smells it
certainly has a bunch of cool Hues of
purple and different types of stuff that
can pop out in it it's bud structure is
pretty nice
um so I would try to breed it with
something that would give it from a
production standpoint although this
wouldn't be very necessary as far as a
smoker goes but from like a Grower's
perspective you would probably want to
breed it with something that would give
it some stretch and some Vigor yeah
right where it could handle a little bit
more food and handle a little bit more
light
uh and but from a from a consumption
perspective I would be looking to cross
it with the most potent thing I could
think of
uh that wouldn't [ __ ] up its overall
structure okay right
um
well you know in the sense of like I
wouldn't necessarily like cross it like
with a Neville's Haze yeah yeah
you know
um although I suppose that could work
but like it it it would it would
probably mess up the the qualities that
cookie has
right
um so I'd be looking for something that
like packed a rare punch like
um like the uh if you wanted to stay
cushy you could do that 56 day headband
you could throw it on some you could
throw it on some chem D
um which is you know which is which is
pretty and super potent but I would be
looking to inject potency in it like the
GMO that's a good good direction that
we've seen
yeah yeah exactly uh chemd I mean that's
that's obviously chemd by Cookie right I
mean yeah we at least a chemd expression
by cookies I don't know if they had
chemd in Spain
you know whatever whatever the case may
be yeah yeah
um it it uh you know that's that's kind
of what you're looking for right you're
looking to add some potency to it yeah
right and obviously like if that is the
case and they did use G uh chemd or a
derivative of it uh GMO got pretty
famous yeah it did I mean it even got
famous in the sense it did something
that I think is super rare which is it
got famous as a cut that takes 12 weeks
yeah it did yeah and that is rare and in
my opinion anything in the 12 to 16 week
range it's really really hard to get
famous because it's longer running than
most people want to go yeah
you know and I think people were willing
to run GMO for that long because it
dumped they it yielded like crazy and
especially when it came to Hash yields
and washing and stuff like that it
dumped really high yeah so it made those
extra three or four weeks really
valuable
but I would be looking to add potency to
cookie personally
and then as a secondary measure I would
try to make it not grow like [ __ ] that's
a good measure
I mean you know growing in Mendo
um you know uh it it kind of hates the
Sun yeah I wish I swear to God in the
gorilla days I wish I had cookie then
cookie would have done amazing in like
Manzanita patches
and on the edge of forest yeah yeah I
could see it would have really done good
because it's dense it doesn't it does
well in low light conditions you know I
knew people early on in cookie days that
would grow one strain directly
underneath the light and cookie all the
way around it on the edges oh wow and
they would get really big yields per
light off that way interesting because
they'd get a decent yield off like the
bright parts and then the other aspects
that were a little like shaded or
whatever that were on the outskirts the
cookie yielded just fine if people are
taking shots with aspect today they're
gonna die
um
so I was thinking because I I remember
seeing uh Tom Hills Hayes cross to the
Deep junk that he did and it actually
ended up looking like cookies
so that Haze of his cross to cookies
might actually be really interesting and
keep a lot of the beautiful form that
cookies has
well I don't know only he would really
know after after doing a bunch of
crosses with it if you could keep some
of the high from that Haze in there I
mean I'm a huge Haze head don't get me
wrong the reason why I eliminated it is
because it adds this jungle element
does and you could probably find
something that you really liked but
you'd better be willing to look yeah
that's the thing with Hayes right you
have to dig you have to look and so
that's a more complicated subject in
terms of uh but yeah in terms of in
terms of haze you're looking for things
that make the bud nicer make it shorter
make it take not as long
yeah but still keep some of those Buzz
elements that you're after
the only other thing I would probably go
after would be Appalachia just because I
I still think that's probably one of the
fastest best uh lines out there right
now for hybridizing I think that would
be I don't know if it would necessarily
go super unique necessarily though
um that is so funny dude there is this
thing I've been looking in the comments
and I was like I should hit up this guy
J cash and ask him to message me and
it's [ __ ] Tom you didn't know that
the whole time no yeah no that's the
whole time yeah yeah
but that that's pretty funny yeah
but yeah no I mean I I uh
um I I I I think I think uh a Haze by
Cookie would be super cool so I don't
think it's a deep chunk by cookies
didn't I do that
I think I did that
I think I did that and it was it was
just a it molded like just a horrible
mold machine
yeah I mean whether it's from something
like Kim D or a headband or a haze
depending on what kind of buzz you're
after you know I wouldn't do Kush
specifically I would go chems just
because there's so much cush already it
would just I didn't read and that has
been bred into it or whatever I think
you'd be better off going for a
different potent indica
uh family
you know
um because inbreeding is hard and that's
kind of what Screwed cookie a bit is is
inbreeding yeah you know and not going
far enough outside and certainly Hayes
would add a wild new bunch of genetics
that they've never messed with yeah
um but you're really what you're
searching for is that invisible High I
forgot that that Phil Tia Rojo did some
of those crosses he did like uh
a Bubba Haze I think he did a cookie
series he did an OG Haze a few different
ones that were really cool someone just
mentioned that in the comments
yeah I mean so I I think
I don't I I would I would cross into
some kind of chem
and see where it went you know and I did
like the chem 91 animal cookies that I
ran that was pretty exceptional it was
um it reminded me of a chem 91 without
the shitty uh
trait of eating itself but it it looked
just like chem 91 but a lot more red
yeah I think our our homies CSI is
certainly with the Forum cut and stuff
like that is done
has certainly made some of those hybrids
yeah um and he's been pretty excited
about some of them uh chem 91 mixed with
cookie is hilarious because it's got all
the buzz you could ever want and it's
one of the uglier things out there
um so you're mixing it with something
that's like really pretty and doesn't
have the buzz yeah so you're sort of
definitely hoping for the looks from the
cookie and the wall up from the chem 91.
but it's probably in there yeah um the
only reason why I suggested chems or
something like that is just to keep the
whole thing the the structure manageable
yeah definitely
like
mandible manageable trying to get to the
manageable
very good I get distracted by comments
yes you do it's okay that's why we keep
you away from them uh but I look but I
mean it's I uh you know
I don't know we'll see I mean we we
might have you know that'll probably be
a different episode or something like
that but amongst the crew you know we
have some some of the interesting pieces
of this you know yeah
um I thought this was an interesting one
too huh just also along the lines of
like the Appalachia cookies would be
like a c99 cookies and I don't remember
I'm sure someone's made that but I off
the top of my head I can't remember who
would have made that and that that
I mean
I don't think it would give you anything
super unique with c99 cookies just like
you know but it is an appellation give
you like a much better structure oh yeah
Appalachia could kill it because you got
the candy in it so we already know what
chemd and cookies do and uh with green
crack
yeah I mean that actually might be a
good one because you'd have you'd have
structure and potency if you could find
the right mix exactly exactly and really
good yields it could definitely increase
the yields
I love Haze uh sorry Mr soul but uh c99
is not on my bucket list of uh of hazes
to keep I get why people like 1999 with
Haze myself but it is
I don't get it but I don't just bred
away from all the good parts of it yeah
it's he went for chunky and quick I get
so much skunk one high from c99 that I
just don't like it I associate with
skunk one much more than Haze because of
that
um I get why people would I think he
bred for looks
quickness and weight
who who Soul there I mean I'm sorry it
would be Sly yeah maybe I mean I think
they I think they had a few seeds and
popped them and gave out the cuts I
don't think they bred for [ __ ]
I think you don't believe any you don't
believe any of the cubing [ __ ] or
anything like that well I mean if if
they're if their goal was to cube to
make a line an inbred I mean because
it's so wrong but you know yeah yeah but
I mean if their goal was to make a seed
line that's uniform then they epically
failed they epically failed because c99
is just shitloads of femos so yeah I
mean
I don't know I mean like I I have more
faith that Sly could have done good
breeding work as opposed to Seoul who
was learning to breed in car or to grow
and get grow tents in Colorado and uh to
late
2010-11 so yeah
I don't know that that's just my
personal opinion I had a lot of insight
into seeing that and I was one of those
people who um absolutely believed word
for word that Soul knew a [ __ ] until I
met him and then I realized oh my God
who wears Sly who's this guy how did he
[ __ ] get pushed out of the equation
that's just my thing uh I mean I you
know that's a different subject too but
it is true that uh in the forums
um there was a number of people that got
pretty famous
and it was sort of the first time that
weed people could get a little famous
in that way yeah right
um and you knew what you knew about them
through what their Persona you most most
of these people didn't you didn't know
them in real life yeah so you know names
like Vic high or or Tom Hill or or uh
you know Sly or you know DJ Short or
whatever you know these people are like
producing seeds and making offerings and
people are growing their stuff out and
some of them got super famous right
but you don't know him in real life yeah
I mean I didn't even know Tom Hill was
my dad I found that out later in life
it's super weird well don't start rumors
people Papa Was a Rolling Stone yeah
Papa Was a Rolling Stone Papa Was a
Rolling Stone uh but yeah you know and
so it's like on forums especially ig's
the same way it's like you only know
what I mean you only know what people
present themselves as yeah for sure I
mean when you start to do a show like we
do
um people get you know dozens of hours
of you chatting so maybe they can form a
slightly like more nuanced opinion yeah
but you know posts Forum posts and IG
posts and all that that can be heavily
curated around an image or around a a
you know a phantom even you know yep uh
there's lots of things that you don't
see
yeah unfortunately I think uh
I think a lot of people
make very I mean I I guess that's what
even what I did is I was getting on the
forums I made very
um
I made a lot of assumptions about people
based on how I saw them interacting with
what they were presenting and
and luckily you know during the time
when I when I was first starting there
weren't a lot of seed makers so I got to
meet a lot of them in person and that's
when I realized how much was smoke and
mirrors and even when I talked to people
about me and stuff in my life and what I
present everything is what I want to
show you know nobody wants to show you
the dude you know having trouble taking
a [ __ ] because he didn't eat enough
fiber you know nobody wants to see that
part
um it's all curated to it I don't want
to see that either I actually FaceTime
not so while I'm doing
oh my God so but yeah I mean it it it's
true it's it's um you know there are
some people that will stun you uh with
the level of knowledge that they have
about the plant and about reading when
you meet them and there are people that
will stun you into oh my God right this
is like the Forest Gump of wheat yeah
yeah isn't that your nickname this
person just yeah that's yeah I think
just stumbled around and bumped into a
bunch of cool [ __ ] along the way but he
was totally you know yeah he was
completely oblivious and half aware the
whole time you know yeah um that's me
you know uh just stumbling stumbling
blindly around into one thing or another
and see I kind of felt like that's how I
did though like I I don't feel like I
had any right to be in the crew that I
was with in San Diego or have access to
the the cuts that I did early on looking
back I'm like you know a lot of people
spend years you know trying to hunt down
pure kush and stuff and that was just
there you know or Hog's Breath that was
just there
um well I think that's what a lot of
this is it's just knocking around
stumbling around and hoping you don't
constantly run into someone who's gonna
screw you
yeah I mean and to be fair to everyone I
will say
that while Matt and I have you know we
there's plenty of stories over and over
and over again about how bad seed rules
the game and how people accidents happen
and become very famous
I'm having a hard time thinking of
someone who just simply said oh my God I
got hella lucky
yeah I partied all weekend my room
hermed I got a few seeds I popped them
holy [ __ ] it was there got super famous
I didn't even breed before that I was
pissed off when it when it when it got
seeded because I was worried that it was
going to affect my price point and it's
the most famous thing I've ever done in
my life and it was a total accident and
uh you know one person I can think of
but he changed the story later on to be
a much like
calculator I will say calculator he came
out first and I'm not even a [ __ ]
breeder I don't know what the [ __ ] I'm
doing this thing's good you know with
the mac and uh after that story change
you know as far as rage for three days
and my light timer went off the wrong
way and I I came back and passed out
from the concert and took me two days to
check on my room and then
you know and and and and I'm so all the
accidents that have happened or whatever
uh you know basically it's like after
you get famous people start trying to
add intention and care and that they
were some reclusive garage genius
carefully mixing these things together
until they finally got a product to show
the world
yeah right
um and that's not typically how it works
uh typically when you do that you fail
um and uh you know and and it was a
bunch of work for nothing yeah um not
that you might not make good work uh
that's not what I'm saying but yeah um
getting famous is weird
yeah and getting famous and you know
having a strain take off
is uh it's not something that you really
totally control no I I I I rarely I mean
I don't think people really capture
lightning in a bottle twice unless
they're already rich you know if you're
already rich and you can put on a good
marketing campaign you can push yourself
to a good spot we've seen that with rare
daintenance and several other companies
as they started brand new company big
ads in High Times bam they're at the top
you know
um but yeah I mean it is really hard to
to push hype on
a cannabis Community pre-instagram it
was yeah I mean and even if you push
hype unless it's something that catches
the Public's flavor and eye anyway yeah
I you know that's why we see so many
strains that get hyped and for six
months or a year or 16 months or
something they'd catch a good ticket and
then the community's like ah
yep I don't know about that one and it's
like how many of how many of things in
the last three or four years that have
been hyped since things went legal do
you think are still going to be hype
weed 10 years from now yeah or have a
Resurgence there's a lot of them that
got hyped and they got a marketing
machine turned on and then it you know
and I mean take it's like uh it's hard
enough in weed to have a one it's like
music right
you can diss one hit wonders all you
want yeah most musicians never even get
that far
yeah one to have one big hit
yeah right that like everybody knows the
song
most musicians don't get that that's
rare you know and then it's and then
most big bands and most acts maybe they
stay together four to seven years
yeah it's the rare ones that are
together 15 20 25 30 and stay relevant
throughout that time those are like
unicorns yeah because I mean even in
marriages it's hard to put up with
someone for a set amount of years and be
live that close to them and have that
many disagreements and not kill each
other so yeah I watched it yeah it's
crazy but then there's but then there's
also staying in the public eye and the
public still liking the new things that
you're doing after time yeah and so and
so if you want to apply that to to weed
or whatever
um you know like let's let's stay in
cookie and this isn't meant to be a disc
to him by any means so don't take it
that way but you know what is sherbinski
done since sure been gelato
and when did those things
come out
yeah
you know it's been over 10 years right
you know a lot of what [ __ ] and on
those guys made
um with cookies it turns out that they
didn't even actually make it right yeah
they've had they've they've basically
have taken under their brand various
house breeders at different times
yeah I don't know who they all are but
at one point it was sea Junkie you know
at one point it was freaking uh what's
his name uh compound I love the fact
that they hired
a breeder who couldn't even [ __ ] grow
which means there were two middlemen
between the seed maker and the buyer
that is just when you hear that that is
just I love it yeah you know and you
know they've got uh Kenny Powers who's
actually pretty nice uh who's been
playing around on a small level for them
in the background for a long time and
making things for them
um but as far as you know I mean you
know what the last the most famous thing
that jig has done in the last five or
six years is probably like rip everybody
off for Candy Rain because they didn't
do a germ test before they sold the
seeds and then everybody found out that
you know basically half of them wouldn't
Sprout and then a bunch of them were
mutants one of the awesome videos I was
going to include was Kenny Powers saying
how he's from the streets so he doesn't
enter into any of that genetic [ __ ] yeah
I mean that's my favorite blog they uh
you know it's it's kind of like cookies
is like you know they you see them open
in New York or whatever and it's like
get the band back together again all the
friends are older they they've got gray
in their hair now but it all kind of you
know catapulted them into a different
world than the last 10 or 15 years than
it would have otherwise yeah
you know and and I think it's the same
thing it's it's an issue for you and
everybody else too it's like you talk
about it you talk about it we have
private chats about it where in the 90s
um you could have seed companies that
had the same eight or ten lines
for five ten years
and Matt will joke with me that if he
doesn't come out with something every
eight months people think he retired or
died oh yeah yeah
right yeah I mean I did that six-month
Hiatus off Instagram and literally
people were like yeah he's done dude why
yep who you know it doesn't take much to
to fall out of the public eye
yeah and then and then on top of that
right it's like so going back to like
the the one hit wonder right you go see
some one-hit wonder band at a casino
right and they're still on Tour 20 years
later and what do you know they're gonna
play for sure
that one hit that one hit you're gonna
hear it and so for a lot of these
breeders and this is an issue in this is
an issue in breeding in general right
and so this is this is not to throw
shade but typically a breeder gets
famous for a specific line or a specific
cut or whatever it might be
and then they just remixed that same cut
forever yeah
right
yeah it used to be the standard that
that used to be what it used to be the
standard like you know across to
everything like NorCal icmag or whatever
it got famous for OG KB
and instead of branching off in
different directions over time you know
he's like you know as far as a few
months ago or whatever he was like
there's more ogkb coming down the
pipeline
I like coaching KP I'm not I'm not
dissing it I'm just saying that like
that's typically what happens is you the
thing you get famous off of
yeah you start doing variations on that
theme forever I did that with uh the
Clockwork Orange for for a long time and
it just it seems like that is what you
like the the typical seed company thing
you do yeah you don't like the swamp the
you know the swamp boys with TK they've
branched out recently and done different
things I was wondering why they didn't
do more with the white
because I mean that was like their [ __ ]
and like the Chrome's Blockhead I always
thought that would be cool to bring back
yeah they didn't I mean but I just I
just mean that like typically look at
like dying breed with Skittles you know
or the Skittles crew like what's the
Skittles crew gonna do next yeah and is
it gonna have the same impact work with
snitches
you know what's what's what are they
going to do next yeah yeah for sure and
and so it's an issue with like all BR
like if breeders are lucky enough that
like one line gets hella famous
yeah it's risky to just be like this is
totally unknown I'm going in a totally
different direction this isn't what I'm
known for at all
yeah but this is where my interest is
now and I made that hit eight years ago
and I'm not remixing it anymore yep it's
just in the past and you can get it if
you want but this is the direction I'm
going in now yeah that doesn't really
happen very often in weed no I I you
know and and I can just comment on this
a little bit because when I made that
decision with the Clockwork I also had
to come to the realization that
it can disappear like maybe no one will
take interest in it after it's gone
maybe what if it just drops and that's
that maybe you know but there's also the
case of what if someone I don't like
runs with it
this is my baby this is our Flagship
what if someone I don't like there's all
kinds of things that went through my
head at that and then as a breeder when
you're making that decision uh to to
work with something that's not so
popular or something that someone else
has worked with for years that you can
still get that is a big decision to make
it's hard to break away from from what
sells no those are all the cuts that I
like the not so popular ones yeah right
um yeah but I mean and that's the thing
though is that what's funny is that if
you are a non-commercial breeder right
you have total freedom to do whatever
the [ __ ] you want yeah
because you can because you're just
making it for you and your friends yeah
but if you're a commercial breeder and
you get into all that and you get into
all the packaging and you get into like
I mean now it's kind of ending the gray
area because everybody has to be fully
legal and and regulated but like that
whole era where you're buying a booth
you know and you're doing all this
different stuff and all that like
there's a lot of expense that goes into
it yeah you know and so a lot of people
breeding just want to hit they just want
to get on base they want a good hit they
want a good they want to next this is my
next release right yeah and so you look
at a lot of people's breeding stock and
you're like oh that's the three things
you're basing everything on
yeah and then what if you're in your 30s
and you want to still be doing it in
your 50s and 60s you're just gonna have
20 or 30 years off the same basic [ __ ]
the smartest thing that
anyone's ever told me as it relates to
cannabis and being a a seed company was
from CSI and he said never tie yourself
to one clone never ever tie yourself to
one clone
said the second you do that the second
you're locked into one clone and if
someone else gets that you're no longer
important and if you tied yourself to
one clone you can't you can't create new
you know I thought that was brilliant
but there's also a thing of like were
you a breeder and something happened
along the way that you got famous while
you were already a breeder like say take
something like I don't know you know
star dog yeah right like JJ was you know
top dog was already a breeder yeah you
know and making a bunch of crosses when
stardog got famous yeah right but take
something like uh like Skittles or like
a lot of breeders they get they start
breeding when they have a famous cut
yeah that other people can't get access
to yeah and so what happens when your
whole breeding career is based upon
access I mean I remember you know I
can't remember it was 10 years ago now
eight years ago or something when
Skittles was first hitting the scene and
we would go to Emerald cup
and that would be a line
waiting to buy you know 10 seeds for
three to five hundred dollars of
Skittles hybrids because nobody could
get five yeah mostly five yeah a lot of
them
you know and um and you know so some of
those guys became breeders at like
cookie or Skittles or whatever when they
got a famous cut yeah
you know I mean NorCal probably became
you know a breeder when it was like all
of a sudden OG KB was the [ __ ]
and people wanted it real bad yeah and
they'll be like well I won't give it to
you but I'll give you hybrids
you know so did you become a breeder to
breed or did you get a hold of something
famous and you're like man I could also
make money selling seeds off this [ __ ]
yeah
because then what do you do next what's
your next album gonna look like
that's where it goes I mean that's why
you see a lot of these dudes scramble
right sure you know and it's like it's
the same thing in music it's like how do
you stay relevant over 20 30 years
you have to keep Reinventing yourself
always you look at the you look at the
history of seed breeding uh who's ever
you know uh the next person that does
that will be the first
yeah
who's who's really even over a 20-year
period who's stayed relevant
that's a hard one
I would have to say probably you know
the the one that I remember you know
even though people always joking me that
I'm it is Neville
right because yes yes but you can laugh
but it's like you know he started in
1985. yeah with all those things and
then in probably like in 98
right so you know what is that 13 years
later or something he released mango
Haze Super Silver Haze and Knuckles yeah
and certainly you know especially
counting the super silver haze that had
massive impact
yeah right
but think of somebody think of somebody
else that like 15 years after they got
famous came up with something that also
made them Super Famous again yeah the
hard one
you know most people are retired or
busted or or you know over it you know
and even dealing with the public is the
in that long is a huge pain in the ass
yeah there's a lot of uh older breeders
that I've tried to come get back out
work with the public again and they just
want nothing to do with it just because
it's just not worth it it's not they've
seen what I've dealt with they've seen
when other people dealt with they're
like no huh
announcement me so far yeah exactly or
like release something and I'm like oh
yeah that's all the stuff you go through
and all the things you tell me it just
sounds swell yeah you know
really swell so we're hitting the almost
uh end of the show we got to end it
before the two hour mark and we're right
about there
um I think we've covered a lot of this
is there anything else you wanted to run
into while we still have time oh yeah I
guess we do I guess we are coming close
um you know there was uh there's
obviously a lot more that you could talk
about with cookies sure I don't want to
say we just scratched the surface but
it's Matt and I do a pretty like
free-flowing uh where does the
conversation take us kind of style
um there's a lot of like cultural impact
that it had there's a lot more depth in
breeding there's different things that
we could have brought up
um because it's one of the big it's you
know there's uh you know there's a lot
to it right yeah some of it we danced
around some of we avoided some of it
just isn't our interest you know Matt
and I's interest is much more the the
plant side of things than the than the
people Nest some you know in certain
aspects right
um but you know there's uh I do think
that there's a lot of rumor out there
about it I do think we dropped a few
tidbits that I'm pretty confident uh
people will find interesting tonight so
that I think that's neat
um there is a dude uh
there's a dude on on IG I'll shout out
for a second sure um uh his name's
Buckshot Hill
um his family's been growing for a long
time
um and he's trying to hunt through and
find some old like early Pearl and
different stuff like that that his
family used to grow and he was young and
his great uncle just died this week uh
and his great uncle
is uh as he says I didn't know him but
he said he was an OG grower
um and he was part of the Kate Wolf
festival for a long time which is a Folk
Festival that the hog farm family throws
up at the Black Oak Ranch in Laytonville
in Mendo so he was part of that extended
family for a long time and apparently
he's been growing for decades and he
just passed away it at a ripe old age so
uh condolences to his family
um and we are losing a lot of that first
gen the rest in peace fellow Outlaw
Growers yeah fellow Outlaw Growers rest
in peace moment of silence
and if you have
old people in your family or community
that have been growing for a really long
time and have stories try to get those
stories from them yeah because once
they're gone they're gone and most of
our weed history is oral and you never
know what little tidbits or different
pieces of information that might fit
into a puzzle
um are sitting in those people's heads
yeah you know most people don't know
that not so's biggest Fascination uh
revolves around oral too which is
it is it is a fascination of mine uh
because you know uh
um you know human writing is a fairly
modern invention and for most of human
history all history was oral yeah right
and wheat history because it was illicit
and clandestine and illegal for the most
part uh wasn't exactly written down you
didn't have a bunch of people getting on
camera like we are now and talking about
it until recently so most of the people
involved in the 60s 70s and 80s are
still mysterious yeah and they're and
they're older now
you know we're going to be working on
some in the next coming up episodes
um we've been doing a lot of networking
and communicating with people on the
back end so there's a lot of stuff I'm
really excited to tell you guys about in
the future but I don't want to jinx it
so yeah hopefully we'll have some cool
new shows coming up soon
um definitely go check out the site
right cease.com we have
um we just did the Appalachia drop sold
out within 20 seconds literally 20
seconds sold out we're gonna restock
those we have uh the the Santa Cruz
wreck the the blue dream train wreck
restock and
um some smell boat stuff restock so go
check that out
um yeah you want to say anything else
before we're done I'm just always happy
that people give us their Friday night
and their time uh whether they're
watching it live or whether they watch
it on replay uh you know anybody that
fellow nerds out with strain history uh
plant history and and our weird little
niche thank you very much
your generous generous time you share
with us on these uh long Fridays so
cheers everyone have a great night
[Music]
foreign
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeders syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times and interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotsseeds.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray for making
your own feminized seeds