thank you
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate where we
explore the history of a clandestine
scene Through The Eyes of the folks who
lived in I'm Matthew owner of Riot seeds
I'll occasionally be joined by my
co-host not soja breeder and grower from
Mendocino
welcome to the underground
[Music]
welcome to breeder Syndicate strain
reviews today we will be reviewing Santa
Cruz goat farms Santa Cruz wreck a
hybrid of Santa Cruz blue dream and
Arcata train wreck first off I should
start by saying if I had you know a top
10 list of desert island strains Santa
Cruz Blue Dream cut and Arcata train
wreck would probably be somewhere in
that list so when I first heard Santa
Cruz goat farm was doing a hybrid of the
Santa Cruz Blue Dream cut and the Arcata
train wreck first off I was like how do
you know you've got the Santa Cruz blue
dream
granted he's from Santa Cruz but in many
many years I haven't seen that exact
specific cut it's been a long time since
I've seen it and um but he's pretty
confident he showed me some pictures it
looks right but a lot of the Santa Cruz
Blue Dream stuff looks identical but
when you go to smoke it it's way
different the the scent profiles
drastically different and the quality of
the high is is drastically different so
I'm always skeptical and for one like
for the first time in years someone
delivered he has the Santa Cruz Blue
Dream he brought me bud of it pure and
hybrids and all kinds of stuff so some
of that is what I'm reviewing today so
this is the Santa Cruz wreck it's a
hybrid of Arcata train wreck and the
Santa Cruz Blue Dream cut the Santa Cruz
Blue Dream cut was a super silver haze
and DJ blueberry cut hybrid and it was a
very specific selection and
um you know the the original Santa Cruz
blue dream was a little bit of berry a
little bit of terpenolene and a lot of
complexity almost like dryer sheets all
kinds of weird beautiful notes in there
so I'm going to give this a crack and
see what we smell upon first crack here
so I yeah
so it has the dryer sheet smell of blue
dream that I it's what I would call it
you can definitely smell some Berry you
can definitely smell a little bit of
terpinoline because I mean it's a hybrid
of train wreck and blue dream
not so strong on the lemon in this one
um but this is this is some seriously
beautiful Bud
um again it's not like cookies density
but it's still got good density like
blue dream had uh train wreck usually
brings a little bit of looseness to the
hybrids that it's involved in but it
really didn't impact the density of this
Bud
um it's very very resinous again train
wreck brings a lot of resin more resin
than people are accustomed to seeing to
and narrow leaf type plants and blue
dream as well Mega resin bomb for a
narrow leaf plant so these two combined
made for uh
this is
this is exceptional like there are so
many smells deep in this
there's like a low cotton candy smell
with the like the best smell like when
you're standing next to like a wall that
has a dryer and dryer sheets are in it
and it's blowing the air out
with some Berry interpinally it is so
hard to describe it may be one of the
more complex things that I've tried to
describe on here now so far which there
aren't a lot yet but it's one of the
harder ones I've always had a
time describing blue dream so I'm going
to break it up now it's breaking up real
nice I don't need a grinder it's still
super sticky like all of Santa Cruz goat
farms uh weed it's cured super sticky I
believe this is a three month cure on
this and it is still super sticky it's
not moist it's not like at risk of you
know molding or anything it's just
really really resinous and sticky and
cured perfectly it's not it's not like
you know breaking up to dust in my
fingers like a lot of weed does uh
that's improperly cured or dried this is
proper [ __ ] so Props to him on the hat
and I'll give you a flavor report here
in one second I forgot it all broken up
but I'm I've I've smoked a little bit of
it before a few days ago
and it's my go-to right now if that says
anything I've I love this drain
um I'm already growing it we already
have some popped running in the grow
um I I really want this cut of it too
because this is fire so uh yeah I'll
give it a burn here and see how it
tastes
it's like an explosion of
fruit dryer sheets because that dry
sheet taste comes through so well it's a
beautiful happy like real flavorful it's
not
soapy
um you can taste the berry on the back
end a little bit lots of it doesn't
taste as heavy as terpenoline as you
would think for a hybrid of Blue Dream
and train wreck I'm getting a lot of the
fruity
this is some amazing stuff this is
special
this is special
the you know
the high again reminds me a lot of um
the silver Pearl from Ohio that pipsweed
brought to the table to our crew and
it's it's it's definitely one of my top
fives as far as I it's just
got the best quality high and this has
that too it's kind of making me chatty a
little obnoxious not feeling tired I'm
not feeling it behind my eyes I'm
feeling it more in my chest and
um I love that I love a good
clear-headed chatty up what people would
traditionally call a sativa type high so
yeah this is this is a solid six out of
five
um there's not a lot that I get in Smoke
where I'm just mind blown by it and
where I want more and more and then I
pop it immediately so
um this is one of those rare occasions
where I want to work it into the Bonnet
lines I want to do some stuff with this
uh maybe even more so than just the
straight Santa Cruz blue dream so uh
yeah be sure to check it out we have we
have the stock of it on rightseeds.com
check it out shout out to my buddy pack
from Santa Cruz goat farm this is the
[ __ ]
want more breeder Syndicate be sure to
check out our patreon by going to Google
and searching breeders syndicate patreon
we have a secret Discord where we are
available at most times in interact
daily there are a lot of perks to be had
there so check it out need seeds check
out riotseats.com where you can get our
seeds and our reversal spray from making
your own feminized seeds
[Music]
foreign