warning everything you're about to see
in this video is for educational and
entertainment purposes only this crap is
rated R don't watch this if you're under
the age of 18 don't W everything in here
is fake everything in here is a prop
don't try to recreate this at home we're
trying to learn some stuff most of this
stuff could be fake most of it could be
make believe that am I real who who am I
I don't even know where I'm at right now
so like I said warning turn this video
off if you're got kids in the room get
them out
quick what up fam it's me your boy Chuck
dog back with episode number six of
breeder Syndicate TV today we're going
to be reviewing permanent marker we're
going to be talking about silica we're
going to be talking about some new seeds
from bitter uh and Bittersweet and we're
going to be talking about a few other
things we eat tips and some trap stories
so if that's your thing if you like
these episodes if you've been having fun
with Chuck dog let me know in the
comment section throw me up a like throw
me up a subscribe that would be great
also tune in to the Friday shows with me
and Matt where we talk about history
breeding and other things like that I
don't really contribute a lot but I
still have fun being on there with Matt
and hanging out with you guys and gals
so you know we're going to jump into it
right now I'm actually smoking on some
of that permanent marker right now uh
you know a lot of people really like it
it's a more modern uh you know genetic
um from what I understand on the
internet and talking with farmer Dan
before the show it's some kind of uh you
know Sher jealousy or biscotti jealousy
sure B of some kind whatever I didn't
really get a lot of buscatti from this
either does Dan from the stuff that he's
experienced farmer Dan's growing out a
few crosses he's got some experience
with thee got some experience with the
Skittles he's got some experience with
the permanent markers a little bit so I
asked him about it and stuff and he
really likes it but that's a homegrown
version of it you know currently today
I'm going to be smoking a w version of
it I picked up a little a like a little
weirdo it's the SE junky one he's saying
SE junkie what the heck Chuck who are
you why you what do you I don't [ __ ]
with them really but like at the end of
the day you guys in the last video with
the blue Zushi you were like that ain't
even really blue so you know I don't
know I don't know about modern genetics
and I'm going to get stuff wrong I don't
grow this stuff so at the end of the day
that's yall want to do a little review
you say you like permanent markers so
this is the closest thing I could really
find so if I get it wrong or if this
really ain't the right permanent markers
or whatever that may be be the case I'm
dealing with W weed we got two more
weeks until Harvest and then we're gonna
talk about TK we're gonna talk about
skunk dog skank dog I should say from C
drip Rob we're going to talk about Sour
Diesel crosses to the pure OG kushes
from CSI talk about Blue Sour we'll talk
about some other stuff I pop a little
bit of hype stuff too I ain't going to
leave you hype guys out we ain't going
to just talk about old school genetics
20 years ago or whatever we're going to
talk about a little bit of everything
and Branch out we got to bring them we
got to spread the community out a little
bit more you know we're too Niche you
know people get butt hurt and then you
know half the Discord is mad they want
to go leave and start their own [ __ ]
which is cool people you grown men and
women you can do whatever you want but
we got to we got to bridge out we're
going to make this community bigger
we're going to build an army we're going
to be stronger we're going to work
together there's too much uh bickering
and drama in the community let's bring
it together with Chuck dog you know if
if if somebody else ain't going to do it
I'm going to do it you know but anyways
got that little eight of the permanent
markers been smoking on it for a day or
two I'll be honest I wish I could show
you buds but
you know oh YouTube don't like us very
much so I talked with Dan like I said a
little bit we've been hashing it out and
I'm pretty sure this is permanent marker
when I pull it out I smell it I get that
permanent marker uh of Vibes you know
that's what we're talking about today we
were talking about some permanent Mark
so you know I wouldn't say it's as
powerful as this right here obviously
but you know we we're we we like to
consider ourselves uh you know glorified
scent experts around here so we got the
per the marker for reference I can't
even get this bag open I didn't eat my
waties I should put my purse down I know
I know but I got it open but I mean
guys it smells like Sher to me I mean
howse you really say
it I was thinking about this for three
days how you know what to tell y'all
about it I mean does it smoke good is it
great does it smell great I mean it
smells like sherb I mean sherb to me can
kind of smell anywhere from like kind of
pix candy flavors
to uh that kind of almost I wouldn't say
Citrus it ain't full on like that but
it's kind of got that like uh yeah that
kind of tropical citrusy sherb smell
that that's pretty common I feel like
that in most of them and and it's really
in tune with a lot of stuff that's
already on the market modern Market or
in in in the wreck uh the wreck weed
stores or whatever basically at least
here in Michigan it's a there's a lot of
stuff out there so it's like I don't
really understand the hype about it I
get the imagery and the idea and the you
know it's kind of cool for about 5
Seconds that your weed smells a little
bit like a permanent marker but it's
really not for me uh and I'm not dunking
on it cuz you know at the end of the day
this ain't a homegrown this ain't this
could very well not be the cut this
could very well be uh something else who
knows who really who really knows am I
getting biscotti from it I like biscotti
kind of it's all right for more of a
modern strain I really
really kind of like it uh but I don't
really get that from this and and that's
that's that's kind of disappointing but
the sherb side of it it's sure uh you
know you could get something like this
from pretty much anything out there if
you wanting to recreated or or you know
if I was going to smoke something like
this I would probably cross do some kind
of Chuck and uh Chuck it to something
with a little bit more potency so you
can go in and really you know dial it in
and pick you know don't let these guys
guys make selections for you go out
there and pop some seeds you guys grow
your own make your own trucks find the
tailored plant for you that works for
you the best don't buy this kind of
stuff I you know if you want to you can
I'm not trying to hate on it cuz there
are people that like it you know shout
out Dan and maybe that's the secret you
got to grow some at home obviously get
that get that right let me know in the
comments below do y'all like permanent
marker do you got some stuff you're
growing at home that that's permanent
marker or Cross of some kind of rip my
dick off let me know I'll go check it
out I'll pop some seeds I'm not you know
we're going to pop seeds excuse me we're
going to pop seeds we're going to grow
different plants I I want to know I'm
trying to learn I'm trying to put on a
show for you guys so we can't just stay
in one little niche Lane and just keep
popping sour plants and TK we got to
grow other stuff you know or whatever
you know do we got to support other
people not you know these these these
[ __ ] and [ __ ] out here no but we
can check some crosses and some trucks
out uh some different you know different
Plants and Things so let me know in the
comment section below what what is Chuck
do dog got to do to get some good
permanent marker cuz I'll be honest this
ain't really it for me I'll give this a
four out of 10 the overall smoke isn't
really bad it's pretty smooth and stuff
but it I guess the hype behind it is
just more of for me is more of a
disappointment uh because you know I've
tried other other plants that are
similar to that that I've been homegrown
and I've grown myself shout out local
you're uh sure best one uh cross I think
it was to the P90 or the sweet PE I mean
dude anything with p91 in it kicks up
that freaking potency that flavor I
really lik it I like I really enjoyed
growing you know that cuz you could find
that Sher sherb kind of vibe in it or
whatever you're looking for and but
still get some potency too there was
some runchy ones in there I like some
runchy stuff I want to smell some tuna
bro I want to smell some dirty butthole
I want to smell some feet bro when I'm
smoking weed I want some r cheese I want
some armpits bad breath I want skunks
rubbers I want you know I don't really
get into a lot of these other more
modern flavors I mean they're cool to
try here or there especially but uh you
know a lot of fruity stuff unless it's
really on point I'm not really into it I
want something runchy make me feel like
a dirty dog down in there on my hands
and knes by between her
legs just going to town you know that's
what I want to feel like I want to smell
runchy I want to feel like a dirty
little skate dog anyways uh but you know
visually it's cool looking manicure real
manicure trim Bud uh the pictures online
were some people had if it was really
the Perman Market real cool it's just a
visual plant it works good for the
market modern day Market because of it's
visually appealing uh and the name I
think there's a lot of a lot of it you
know a lot of the guys say they like the
permanent marker out in C and stuff and
maybe it's is the cut it's something
different I don't really know like I
said let me know in the comment section
but I don't really think it's for me I
would rather just sit here and smell the
Sharpie you know if I want to get the
permanent Market takes me back to oh man
I used to H Huff all the well it takes
me back bro it just takes me back to the
good old days when things were simple
and the the vagina flow like wine you
know uh but anyways what I get get it
again probably not if you like it let me
know give me some more information down
in the comment section below and maybe
we'll talk about it on the show next
time but you know I'm going to roll me
up something a little bit different
while we while we do this transition cuz
I just you
know I don't really find the eights when
you're buying an eight a m hour bag I
don't really find much difference in
bulk uh weed buying bulk from like a
deli style or buy whatever a prepackaged
bulk deal at a cheaper rate I don't find
much difference in potency or overall
quality Mo for most of the time when it
comes to a lot of this [ __ ] so save
yourself a few bucks I think that eth
was like 20 bucks or 25 bucks with tax
save yourself some money and they got
freaking half ounces in there for like
40 bucks they're better weed than that
you're getting a half ounce you're
saving yourself money and you know
you're get more points so you're saving
some money even more you're getting free
stuff so yeah don't don't waste if
you're coming to Michigan if you're from
down from the south you're trying to get
to a place where you can buy some weed I
know you you guys down there in the
South you or anybody you like the woods
if you were an Outdoorsman person you
like Lakes you like fishing you like
beautiful women you like good food you
like pizzas you like subs or whatever
they call them up here gy roll Gyros
hogies sliders I don't really know but
it's all good to me it goes in here and
comes out the you know it's all good
though but if you like that kind of
stuff you know and you're coming up here
to try some some wreck weed you might be
disappointed especially you growing your
own stuff at home but like I said just
don't fall for the little eighth
packaging deal get yourself some bulk
flour and save yourself some money and
enjoy it roll some big blunts big joints
big bong grips whatever you're doing
just save yourself some money and some
time and some headache and and go with
something you know like I said some bulk
flour there's a a lot of options out
there especially in in some of these
stores uh don't get lured into the the
whole eighth buying little myar eth game
but that being said I been went off on
another little tangent so I need to
picked me out something here to smoke
but we're going to jump in to I got
notes today y'all I had to I had to
write some notes because I can't I can't
keep on track with the everything so
we're going to show
off bitter Bittersweet y'all know
Bittersweet right the old G King p91 s
man he done sent us some new seeds that
i' I've been excited I've been seeing
them pop up on the Discord and I'm
excited for them you know I'm really
pumped but he sent me some of these
seeds that I'm
super super ready to Super ready to pop
bro I'mma pop these I meant to pop them
last night but I got in making love to
my woman and howling at the moon and I
just I got distracted so but we got the
Yoko unaa Zuna Yoko unaa I can't talk
y'all which is the p91 S1 times uh Dolce
Vita and if you don't know what Dolce
Vita is it's the Irene times the
strawberry cream which is really cool
I'm excited for that I'm hoping to get
some strawberry turbs that would be
really cool and I'm a guy that loves
cream all flavors types wherever it
comes out of I enjoy a good creaming and
there we go we got got it right there in
the f2s that's going to be I do say is
it Dolce I think doce VA I can't talk
y'all mom's got the hook on fin but my
speech and stuff I've been I got kicked
in the jaw on time by a zebra my dad
used to have a zebra when mared kids
it's a long story and maybe we'll go
into that another time but I got kicked
in the jaw on a z any know my shit's
[ __ ] up it's Hur from me to
talk and then we got hell sing which is
the Death Star times dose Vita which
dude if you like funky turps I mean
death star let's go bro and then we got
the Irene Kush BX which I also love
Irene dude I grew out the Irene S1 from
CSI last year and they were a pain in
ass but once they got rocking they were
awesome and finished out to be some of
the better plants that I grew out last
year so I really really enjoy them shout
out bidder you're the man uh thanks for
the p91 S work uh S1 work and everything
dude that you guys have done you and
Matt and everybody that's has kept the
p91 around so you know everything that
y'all done and Shout Out local uh with
the sweet pee and everything I
appreciate y'all uh that's a great plant
if you don't know anything about p91 get
check it out go get some crosses of it
it's freaking awesome and konzo man
shout out Peanut cush dude peanut Kush
Is Awesome as well I really liked uh
konzo work with with the with the p it's
been really great uh also I wanted to
talk about the uh H&amp;L 500 grow contest
we're doing the judging as we speak we
got 12 people that made it to the end
and they're looking beautiful maybe if
we're allowed um to post some of the
pictures or if people don't care or mind
that I post some of them I got to get
permission from them but maybe we'll do
like a little video montage for you guys
uh on one of these videos or one of the
episodes cuz they really are beautiful
plant if you don't know what I'm talking
about uh they're growing the the um the
Kim 91 times the mango hazes and dude
these things are chonger spear throwing
son of a guns they're really nice uh and
like I said we're running the judging
right now there's going to be a belt for
the winner we've already done a contest
before that's had a belt we did a
growing Solo cups uh and we're also
currently running a pck uh goat farm
grow contest as well it's a mystery one
so we're always doing fun stuff in the
Discord over on breeders Syndicate 3.0
so make sure you join the patreon
there's a link in the patreon it's $5 I
know you're saying it costs money Chuck
dog well I don't know about y'all but
I've been involved with a lot of
communities that were free and really uh
it let all the riff raff in if you can't
afford $5 how the heck are you growing
weed because it's a money sync in itself
especially these days so uh you know
join the the Discord if you don't like
talking if you're introverted person
that's really cool too you don't have to
get in there and talk we ain't going to
kick you out if you don't talk nothing
like that so come in there and use it as
a search engine you can come in there
and search the little search box you got
a box you got a question put a little
keyword in there and help figure
something you're like me you got
problems with pm and all this stuff all
the time you got questions you you run
into something you lose your mind like
what the heck am I going to do well join
the Discord and we'll help you out you
know there's a bunch of good uh
knowledge women and and men in there
that know a lot shout out peachers the
edible Queen uh so yeah join the Discord
with a lot of good information and and
join some of the contests there's prizes
free seeds there's going to be belts
there's going to be bragging RS all that
kind of stuff y'all so join the Discord
uh you know today and you and you won't
regret it I promise uh and then you know
this topic is a little bit uh
controversial some people say you need
it some people say you don't need it
some people say they use it and they
don't see results but I want to talk
about some silica today it's not
something I have historically used or
ever have a lot of experience with in my
garden a lot of times I'm just relying
on what I got going in in my my my soil
mix and the and just basically can of a
and b and a few few other little
products from my my micronutrients and
stuff like that but somebody left a
comment on my last video talking about
silica and you know just asking do I use
it and and I had to say no I I actually
don't I do know somewhat a little bit
about it that people have had mixed
results with it some people use it some
people don't is it
necessary I would say probably not
obviously because I've been growing
without it just fine does it help your
garden I think if you got your p's and
your Q's on point if you're using the
right uh if you you know if your garden
is where it needs to be and everything
is properly balanced just like bidder
was telling me you know I I actually
went ahead and picked up some power SI
and started implementing into my garden
and and I and maybe I'm losing my mind
but within 6 to8 hours I swear every
plant in my grow veg in my veg my
veg tent all had more rigidity to them I
don't know if I'm losing I know you're
saying there's no way that that was
those you know uh the little Cil plant
bodies were deposited into the Cil walls
or whatever that fast Chuck you don't
know you're losing it bro well I asked
bitter and he said it is possible if you
got it dialed in right you could see
results that quick but that being said
there's a couple different forms of
silica you know let's let's maybe dive
into that a little bit because there are
some more you know plant uh you know
plant ready more available to the plant
I guess I said say my bad I can't talk I
took some edibles a little bit ago my
old lady and I we made some little you
know little coconut oils little coconut
butter and uh I put some in my coffee I
got to say and uh I'm a little bit it's
it's starting to kick in I'm a little
lit right now but that being said I want
to jump into the the different forms of
it I'm kind of talk about it and if I
get something wrong as usual let me know
down in the chat I'm not an expert so
please don't take my advice uh look to
some of the people that know more than
me I'm learning along with y'all so this
is this has been great so please leave
stuff in the comments if you got
something you want me to check out you
got something you want me to look into
or maybe something you think I might
need to implement in my garden I mean
you know I'm not going to do every
little thing but I'll pick and choose
what I think I you know that's cool or
maybe a good idea and do some research
just like we did with the Sila so I got
to talking the bidder I got to talking
some of the other guys some people were
saying they didn't see a difference I
saw the difference that's all I could
say I feel like I see a difference now
it's been almost what two weeks a week
and a half two weeks I feel like I'm um
I'm seeing a difference so that being
said I wanted to jump into uh you know a
couple the the different forms of it
real quick I took some notes here for
you guys cuz I'm a big dummy you know
I'm I'm not that good with with
remembering stuff I'm not that good at
communicating to be honest with you I
can't talk I'm from the south I got a
overbite like I said got kicked by a
zebra in in my jaw but we're going to go
through it so the first form of it which
is the more common form of about that a
lot of us use or see or or maybe when
you're first learning about silica uh
you you might think you when you get to
looking at the prices let's just say
that you might say well that one's for
me Chuck the potassium uh silic
silicates for me bro that is you know
$30 $40 a little bottle a little gallon
bottle bro that's one and done that's
easy Chuck well there's different forms
of it and like I said we're going to go
through it that's not going to be your
best form of it but it can any any form
of it is going to help I do think and to
a certain degree that's that's me saying
from my own experience so I don't know
some people you know if you're running
in it depends on what you're running in
if you're organic guy if you're running
in a different setup you might not see
the results you might have it uh some
form of silica in some other product you
use so you might not need this product
and and most people probably aren't
going to use it and we're going to talk
about the benefits of it as after we get
done talking about the different forms
of it I'm a country guy takes me a
second to get through stuff I'll give
you a long long drawn out uh explanation
so potassium silicate and what is it
it's a water soluble salt form of silica
wiely used used in Hydroponic and soil
systems it raises pH due to its alkaline
nature and must be added uh separately
from other nutrients to avoid
precipitation so basically what that
means is you want to add this first all
you got to do when you're mixing up your
nutrients is put your silica product in
first cuz it's going to make your pH
Spike then you're going to add your base
nutrients then you're going to add your
C mag and then anything else after that
it's pretty easy peasy simple you don't
have to think much about it but you do
got to make sure you get it right and
keep it tight you know you need to
really be careful and make sure you're
putting your stuff in in the right
orders uh but the benefits it strength
strengthens your cell balls it improves
your stem rigidity and it also helps
protect uh you know from Pest and
disease giving a little bit extra re uh
resistance you know basically the it's
like almost like armoring itself out you
know like kind of making it hard like
would you want to chew on a a real hard
uh silica fi uh material or would you
want to go and get the next soft little
thing so the the idea is they just don't
want to eat it and and the pest and
things will move on with the mold uh you
know just I guess a little I think it's
a Stam or stemon or I forget what the
little thing is a little probe that
comes down from a mold if you look at
the stuff underneath the microscope it's
kind of cool actually but it basically
comes down and sticks that that that uh
little it's basically an anchoring it
anchors to the plant and and then that's
when you know how it attaches itself to
the plant but I guess the idea is it's
just it can't basically attach itself
because it's just so strong [ __ ] strong
rough you know after they circumcised
type thing the rough skin left over that
kind of rough strong rigid you know uh
but
yeah so we're going to jump over into
the sodium silicate and basically it's
less common than the pottassium silicate
due to sodium's potential for toxicity
and high amounts um and then we got what
people really should probably be using
the most I think is from what I
understand from understood from my
research uh is uh silicate
acid soic so I can't say that right
y'all soic cicc acid I can't say that
description the plant available form of
silica absorbed as a
mono monoy I can't talk y'all mono cicc
acids there we go found in specialized
sub supplements like power SI and
extreme silica highly soluble and
effective form
or H highly soluable and effective folio
application and but you can also
obviously feed it you know feed it
through just like you normally would and
uh I guess yeah so we we've been using
power SI and it's been great so that's
going to be your your more uh the what
you want to use it's also going to be
it's going to be your better form of it
but it's also going to be your more
expensive form of it too so don't be
surprised when you look at it uh because
it is more more concentrated it'll go
further
and it it is a little bit more expensive
but I definitely think there that's
going to be your best option and I think
Mills make some there's a couple other
brands I'm not real familiar with those
Brands so you do need to do yourself a
little bit of research and and deep dive
into that a little bit more I'm I'm just
getting Tongue Tied tied all all up
today you guys I can't really say it
let's see if we could try it one last
time sois Sissa I we give up I don't
care drop it in the comments let me
know then you can ALS also got dious
Earth which I don't really I know some
of you organic guys and stuff use that I
don't use that uh you know you can use
it for pest control and stuff like that
and I'm assuming it breaks down as well
into the soil a little bit but I I
couldn't couldn't imagine it would be
super available right away but what the
heck do I know I don't really know so
maybe look into the doation Earth stuff
um but that being said you know if you
want to try implementing it into your
garden silica might be for you uh you
know it's going to help your plant be
stronger outside especially people like
to really use it outside because it's
going to make it uh supposedly more
drought resistant um stronger uh in the
winds uh it can deal with colder
temperatures better Pest and molds and
stuff I don't know it just sounds like a
Bene beneficial thing all the way around
for me like I'm up in Michigan I get
mold I get a few pests here and there
especially Outdoors so like why wouldn't
I want to add it it goes a long way
you're not like you're you're mainly
just using it in veg some people use it
all the way through but some people
there's people out there that say that
it can make your buds too dense I don't
know you know there some people say
that's bull crap and don't have that
problem so you know take it with a grain
of salt try it out see if it works for
you like we were saying there's a
different forms of it
uh you know I can't really say it the
proper way maybe you guys can you know
your most common forms are going to be
your your potassium silicate which is
like you're you're going to know the
difference cuz you're going to see a
bottle of it it's going to be 2030 $40
whereas uh you know the Sol soltic asset
is going to be more ex expensive I'm
sure you guys are getting a good good uh
show out of me trying to pronounce this
stuff
monosilicic acid there we go all those
C's too many C's right there two two C's
two eyes to many eyes
monosilicic acid there we go don't help
with the Edibles of course but we'll
make it
through that being said I'm having a
blast learning about this stuff you know
a lot of times I see people talking
about this stuff and it's hard to jump
into a conversation just the way my
brain work I got that ADHD so it's just
the way it is it's hard for me to jump
in and absorb some of this stuff but but
the show is causing me to have to go
down these rabbit holes and and check
out you know check out some different
stuff um that being said uh that's
pretty much it for a silica I mean you
want to implement it in your vegetative
growth growth more than anything or
outside you want to streng strengthen up
your plant you want to get a little bit
more resistance to B molds and and Pest
and things like that drought
tolerant uh you know cold to tolerance
better I don't know guys if you if you
if you got the money to do it implement
it try it out you can make it go a long
way uh you know it is what it is and
always make sure you're putting it in
first because it meeses what your it
messes with your pH okay uh what else we
got for you guys today I've done lost my
train thought here going on a deep dive
on the silica see oh another thing I
wanted to start doing in these episodes
is maybe something else like a segment
this I don't really know how I'm going
to do it yet but as right now I'm kind
of thinking what did I learn this week
is what it's going to be called and
basically just hanging out with Matt on
the show uh learning about breeding
techniques and Seed making techniques
whatever you want to call them chucking
I'm a glorified chucker that's what I
call myself and I'm proud of it but I
asked him I said Matt I was digging on
the forums I saw bod uh sometimes would
uh you know pollinate his females and
then he throw them back in the veg and
he said yeah you can do that and uh we
talked about that we got in I didn't
know you could do that and and from what
he was saying it's some it'll definitely
finish up so your seeds will finish up
and then the benefits of it is you'll
have a plant that's basically reved so
you could take Cuts then or you could
reveg the whole plant and throw it back
in the flow Harvest your seeds and throw
that whole thing back into flow I
thought that was really cool uh you know
and I and also uh we we were talking
about um where I'm losing oh you can
also uh over pollinate just like you can
underp pollinate when you're making
seeds which I didn't know that I always
knew you could under pollinate or or
just you know pollinate too early or
pull your plant your mail or your
reversal your reverse plant too soon or
however you're doing it or if you're
dusting on there's several ways you can
pollinate plants but he was basically
saying you know if you over pollinate
you can really you can get a lot of
immature seeds as well which I kind of
am seeing that a little bit now some of
my plants I kind of pushed it I I let
that mother [ __ ] probably
pollinate for like two weeks bro we
definitely over pollinated which I
didn't even know was a thing so
something I learned this week I thought
that was cool I definitely underp
pollinated a lot or prematurely
ejaculated a few times in my life and
that sucks um but yeah it is what it is
is um as far as the grow content the
grow videos that's coming I've been
waiting on my freaking webcam and my
little microphones stuff are going on
two weeks from Amazon what's going on
with Amazon y'all they're supposed to be
fast it's slow as hell uh I got the the
better stuff and everything and they
taking forever I had loads show up drop
off a lot of my stuff for me here in
this garage so we can get it cracking
lacking get some grows going like I said
we'll have some videos rocking out for
y'all doing that kind of stuff showing
some plants off I can't wait to pop some
of these freaking strawberry cream
crosses uh some of these uh p91 S1
crosses dude I mean dude shout out
bitter I'm hyped for that I'm hyped for
more sour stuff I'm hyped for more Kim I
got some Kim 91 that's content coming up
here soon we did the S1 and who knows
maybe we even could track down a cut or
two uh I don't know we're going to try
to do some stuff we're going to try to
figure it out you guys don't get Cuts
pop seeds it's all you really needs but
for entertainment and uh you know trying
to trying to do a little research maybe
we'll look into doing some some
different stuff like that maybe we'll
get get in a little bit deeper but for
the meantime we're just having some fun
and like I said uh just trying to learn
some stuff so I really appreciate y'all
supporting me I think we're going to
jump into a few weed eater tips real
quick I'm going to finish rolling this I
promise know while we're at it if you're
looking for a a good grow book I don't
know all of them Matt has a good video
on them where he talks about a lot of
the good grow books from back in the day
and some of the better ones today but
for me I like to always have my
marijuana botney from Mr Rob Clark up on
hand I don't use it a whole lot but I
have looked back on it a few times and
if I don't know if especially if I can't
find something in the Discord a lot of
times I'm leaning into the Discord to
figure out what I need or asking guys
like bidder H&amp;L Pac Matt
the Breeders asking them what they do
you know and trying to learn from that
take a graen take take a little bit of
this take a little bit of that and apply
it to what I I'm learning and and how I
learn and just rock out with it you know
anyways we're going to jump into the
weed eater tips I know you guys like
that last episode and I figure you know
why can't we talk about weed eaters we
all use them right at least if you
growing weed you probably got to like do
some maintenance outside if you own a
property you want to look better hey you
want it to stand tall when somebody
stands by go you know Drives By you want
them to to to look good and all that
stuff so we're going to do some weed
eater advice maybe some mowing tips
things like that last episode we talked
about how to string a speed head fed
weed eater really quickly so you can get
to rocking you lose your string you run
out of string another thing if I like to
do especially back when I was mowing and
weeding I carry a little piece of the
four five foot piece of string and I'd
fill me up one of them little bottles
with with some uh two cycle uh you know
some weed or some some juice fill me up
with some gas and I put that little
bottle in my pocket the other guys they
wore fanny packs I ain't wearing no damn
fanny pack but I put it in my pocket and
I carry a string with me so when you're
out 20 20 clicks down a fence weed and
you and you run out of string because
the jack ass day before didn't fill up
your weed eater uh you're good to go so
that being said I want to talk about
weed eaters again for a
minute a lot of people don't know this
but when you're weeding there's a proper
way to walk the head on most common weed
eaters is going
counterclockwise so the way you want to
walk to where you get a smooth cut to
where that
head that head is moving along that
grass just perfect especially when
you're up against a wall or or rocks or
whatever you want to you want to get a
real clean cut so you don't got to sit
there doing all this if you're doing all
this especially if it's been cut before
if you're doing all this back and forth
stuff you're not doing it right you know
the mo the right way to weed eat is
actually to walk sideways to always walk
left or to walk backwards going left if
you're going right say say you're
looking at your house or whatever you're
about to weed e the way you want to do
it is go left always there's a couple
reasons for that that's the way the
design the way the head spins if you go
right it's going to dig into the ground
it's going to get it's going to do all
this it's going to make your chop your
cut look real crappy you want it to look
like a green glass Lake Grass Lake of
water smooth as ice on a calm day you
know what I
mean and if you go right it's going to
screw you up a lot of people see me weed
eating and shorts saying [ __ ] like dude
how do you stand weed eating in shorts
bro like don't that [ __ ] hit your legs
I'm going to tell you a secret fam when
you walk left all the debris thrown
right so if you're walking the right way
not only are you not getting [ __ ] on
your legs you're also not throwing rocks
into your window if you go if you go
right and you face that weeder forward
and you try to go fast as you can you're
going to throw you're going to throw
rocks you not only going to throw on
yourself you throw it through a window
I've done it before I've seen it done
before you know it's easy to do so
always you want to walk left you walk
with the sideway stance or backwards
just saying backwards Chuck weeding
backwards what kind of weeding is hard
enough well it's called stamina Brothers
I hear you guys you know and I see a lot
of people in the comment saying well you
know my back hurts when I weeded well
you don't that's why we talked about
last time you don't have to have a steel
a steel is not going to be the best for
everybody I see little sissies out there
with the straps on and the doing all
like or there's different styles of weed
eaters but that being said that's why
you go with a lighter uh you know like a
shawa you go with a lighter one with a
uh if you're a shorter guy you can
adjust the handles it's got a shorter
Rod uh you know so you can kind of
really you want to tailor your weer to
you you know you're not trying to buy
the best weer on the market because it's
got the name Steel on it I'm sorry
Steel's a great product but you got to
really think about what you're buying
they're not made for everybody they're
heavy they're bigger they're not made
for for shorter people really uh so make
sure you're getting a tailored weed
eater for yourself so I rock out with
shaas I walk rock out with SH I've had
hus aaras before I've had echos or
whatever there a couple different other
brands but you know they're all about
the same if you if you're doing
residential stuff but like I said I like
to go with a lightweight shawa for
residential stuff I like to go with a
steel for for real heavy stuff some
people like to use a disc cutter or
Cutters and stuff I like to use them too
but when you're working with with uh you
know guys that just get out of jail or
addicts and stuff like that no
disrespect cuz I got them in my family
but at the end of the day they they come
in [ __ ] up the next day they slice
their legs off they slice my legs off so
you know weed eater is a little bit
safer uh that being said uh I better not
catch you guys out with no damn battery
poed or electric uh weeders if I see you
got one of those I don't know if I could
be your friend really but yeah walk left
walk backwards I kid you not I would
weed eat all day long for 8 to 12 hours
walking backwards and my calves were
huge I could run damn near backwards
with that weeder I put them headphones
in TNT just
pumping just just destroying that grass
F and you know when when you're doing
that too especially if you're doing this
for a business you're throwing the grass
away from the the house so where your
blower guy could come in with the leaf
blower and blow it out real easy and and
it also you keep yourself clean you keep
your truck clean doing it that way you
can weeded in flip flops damn near you
can weeded in shorts so it's just a
little tip I'm teaching youall how to
improve stuff we're going to talk about
edging we're going to talk about
beveling we're going to be talking about
different St stuff that comes uh with
weed eating and and Mowing and you know
maintaining your yard I'm not a weed
expert but I'm a certified weed eater
expert I have mowed commercially and
residential for many years uh I spent a
lot of time on on Zero Turns scags uh
rights uh xmarks John deers whatever you
know Echo uh whatever the purple Puff
Dragon company I don't know I've been on
a lot of stuff you guys uh so we're
going to talk about that we're going to
improve your garden we're going to talk
about cleaning up leaves we're going to
talk about cleaning up your yard and
making it look tall Stand Tall but I
think I want to jump over into a trap
story real quick I was thinking about
doing two but we ran on a little bit
longer with the weedy tip so we're going
to talk about some trap stories and I
think I'm going to take us back to the
cabin once again and this actually
happened before my time running through
the field throwing all my plants out cuz
I thought I was about to get raided if
you haven't heard that
story go back and listen to that one I
think I was in it in the last episode
I'm not really sure
but this one's the same place but this
was probably 6 months to a year before
that time and I have been growing I
think it was Girl Scout cookie
s1's and uh what was it c c
o
and I saw Bells from CSI I had them
inside they got real big I took them
outside I had me a little garden uh
basically I live in a log cabin on the
top of perched up on a hill with a long
gravel driveway down at the bottom
there's a one lane road with a bridge
that will cross over a big creek I lived
up in the woods I had a big giant
tobacco and and soy being the field
behind me that we farm and uh yeah just
my neigh I got a couple neighbors but
they're all down the road and uh so I'm
growing weed out there I've done had uh
you know too much fun really growing I
got too many plants going down down
there in Kentucky bro you know this has
been a few years back or
whatever uh but had too many plants
going but I'm having a good time I'm out
there messing with mushrooms I'm out
there messing with my plants having a
good old time with my Daisy Dukes raised
up to my freaking balls no shirt no
shoes getting tan getting sexy having a
good time drinking liquor
smoking and uh working on my plants
there's nothing better than being
outside messing with weed plants I I
love it something about that sun good
Kentucky sun on you just getting a
little tan working out there smoking
thinking about titties and just the way
plants grow outside I love it just easy
peasy sun does all the work and there's
just not much to it dude you know you
got your problems with Pest and PM
though so it is you got your pitfalls of
grown outside let's not make it let's
not get it twisted there's stuff that
you know either way pros and cons of
both situations but M growing got four
or five foot plants and Sun's going down
and I'm doing my water thing taking care
of my mushrooms [ __ ] like that and we
got a a a pallet like a pallet wood a
4x4 pallet wood fence all the way around
our cabin that kept the dogs in and we
had a gate and K people out and stuff
whatever you know just a fence we saved
some money and built a whole fence out
of literally uh TST wire and uh pallets
so my Garden's in the corner facing the
field out the back door and I have my
little Garden in the corner and I'm
growing how probably had 10 15 plants
out there and the sun goes
down and uh we're hanging out
everything's cool old lady makes some
food we're watching some
TV we got dogs so anytime dog barks I
look out the window see what's going on
not cuz necessary paranoid I just want
to be prepared so I mean you know I'm
not up to no good really so I'm like
what the hell's going on so I look
outside I don't see nothing in my
driveway so I'm like
cool sometimes C how you know or
whatever so or the Pome gets on a por so
the dogs
Bart so look at the other window just on
the other side of the room facing my one
neighbor that I could see
and they probably got a quarter mile or
a half mile long driveway bro it's
paved and this is just after the dark so
it's you know it's dark out and I see
four lights four cars and four
lights rolling up that driveway bro I'm
talking like right on each other's ass
like rolling up there and I'm we've been
living there for a long time so I knew
you know I'd see people come and go and
it was always just one car my mind being
way it is I said dude that looks like
the police and I taught her and I said I
said is that and they pull up I could
see them pull up to the house but the
way they were driving the way they were
on each other moving like a little Squad
bro there was just the way they were the
way the lights in Kentucky at the time
they were using the the Ford Tauruses so
you I think is what they were the for
Ford tus so you can tell the way the
light there were certain way the lights
were and on the back uh the way the
lights were set up you could tell with
the the rear end lights or whatever tail
lights
so I'm like that looks like the the the
police and they go up to that
house
and they got their spotlights on and
they're knocking on the door and my
neighbor single woman with some kids she
comes out she's talking to them and
[ __ ] and this is probably I don't know 3
400 yards away I don't know maybe more
but I you know I could make stuff out
because I got porch lights on and
everything and the cop lights all that
[ __ ] were on
and they weren't there but like five
minutes and I was like I was telling her
I was like what the [ __ ] are they doing
and uh they're out I can see them
walking out in the field that they got a
big front yard like a massive one like
probably four or five acres and they're
out there looking around and they're
making their way towards the the
neighbor in
between them and and us there's a big
barn and a field there another neighbor
owns but his house isn't located there
and they're their way towards my my
property and I told her I said man like
they're going to come over here they're
looking for something you know and uh
she's like no you'd be all right they're
just they' be
fine well I don't know something my gut
told me
like dude what the hell you know they're
gonna come up here so I always get
myself in sh situations like that and
just being where I'm from you don't want
to get caught [ __ ] so it's like I'd
rather sacrifice my
grow and be able to sleep in my own bed
than you know go to jail for some plants
so I'm watching and sure enough bro they
get back in the car and they start
cruising down that driveway and instead
of going right back towards town where
they came from they they all they start
slowly turning left and I told her I
said they're coming up here just the way
they were moving and that's
probably quarter mile
maybe from like the way like when they
leave that driveway I can see them drive
to my driveway down by the bridge and
they come up then they got to come up my
[ __ ] and uh I told her let's said
they're coming up here and my plants at
this time like four or five foot tall
right and A Pet's only 4 foot tall 4 FO
3 in something like that and uh sure
enough bro they're they're cruising real
slow Spotlight so I run outside dude
and I grabbed them plants start grabbing
them bro was me and they're [ __ ] in
five gallons bro so I'm getting two
three at a time Max bringing them inside
and
uh like I said I probably had 14 15 of
them out there and uh I get a couple in
a couple runs in I look outside and sure
enough bro they're like stopped in front
of my house and they start slowly
driving up the driveway my shit's steep
so like you need to be in a truck almost
to get up our [ __ ] so they're in these
little cars I taking them a minute and
the water that washes down this driveway
will wash out real big ruts so it's it's
kind of rough you know it's like Creek
Rock driveway type thing and
uh they're driving up at real slow and
I'm [ __ ] and I'm I told her I said
they're coming and I could see them with
the spotlights you know I'm in the cut
bro so when they show up they use
Spotlight Spotlight and everything
looking and
uh I'm running these plants inside dude
and I probably get down to like the last
four you know and I could hear them bro
come up at gravel you know sound of the
cars and start seeing lights close and
I'm I'm in between my cabin and like the
back facing the field where you park and
then they're coming up the drive on the
front they can't see me because the
cabin essentially block blocking the
view in the way it's like kind of coming
up a hill and uh I run two plants and
I'm and I run I'm about to run back
outside and they're they're literally
out in front of our cabin and the way
you had to like you had to kind of curve
around this big curve and it there's a
bunch of trees and bushes you can't
really see and then once you come to the
back you can see like the the cabin and
the gate and you can see all in the
whole yard basically and uh bro I go go
out that dog door and I'm bar I'm I'm
crawling like a little crab bro like a
chip wall spider monkey going through
the grass bro and getting over to that
plant and I grabb them plant and I just
break them in half dude and I pull them
down and I got them plants and I'm just
dragging them behind me and bro as I'm
doing this like you know how pallets are
you can kind of see through them or
whatever and I can see his cop bro they
all four kind of like pull up but the
one he stops right there and that curve
where you could kind of see into the
yard there was an opening to like the
the weeds and the bushes and [ __ ] and
shine a spotlight in my yard bro like
right over top of me bro and I'm I'm
crawling I I stop I [ __ ] Spotlight and I
I had to turn all the porch lights and
everything off so it's pitch black other
than his Spotlight so he's looking and
thank God like all the plants and [ __ ]
were like at basically at that pallet
level so like as I'm growing and he
can't really see me you know and uh
they're sitting there I can hear them
talking they roll their windows down I
can hear them talking and [ __ ] and I get
back to the porch and I can't I didn't
want to try to get up and they see me so
I just lay there for a minute
and uh I was like man I got to get
inside cuz if they get out and start
looking around I got these two big pot
plants here you know I'm [ __ ] so I just
like all my strength just break them bro
break the [ __ ] the you know outside
you get 3 4 inch stock bro I break it
and uh I just slowly bro I meant using
like stuff on the porch let cover I
slowly crawl through that dog door like
a little worm bro and I get in there and
I'm like I I'm sweating [ __ ] bricks
you know and got all my plants
congregated right there I told her I'm
like let's get these in the bathroom you
know and I look outside and uh they're
starting to pull down the driveway and
they're leaving bro and it's like I told
her I was like man we just did it I just
did it again I do this [ __ ] to myself I
did in Kentucky bro you get I've had so
many close calls that c alone probably
four or five times bro with with police
and like weird [ __ ] there's people
parked in my driveway go down there and
visit them we'll talk about that one
next time and uh but yeah just weird
[ __ ] so I told her I said I done did it
again and got all paranoid and [ __ ] cuz
every time I do it she's like just chill
be all right I'm like I'm not going to
jail dude I got these plants out here
these guys are looking around comea find
out on Facebook she doing some [ __ ] on
Facebook and the neighbor was on there
posting about how somebody that had
passed away a few houses down son was uh
on a on a binge bro so he's going around
breaking in people's houses and stuff
well he had come up to my neighbor's
house and try to force his way in when
when she opened the door so that's why
the cops even had come up there so I did
all this for nothing bro but anyways I
appreciate y'all I'm going to get off
here and get my hooked on phic back out
get Mom's over here and and practice a
little bit I feel like a piece of [ __ ]
cuz I can't pronounce words and really
just overall disappointed in my
myself you know I'm disappointed in the
weed I'm disappointed in myself and I
just need mom's loving and we pull out
the hook on phics and you know go over
it and and try to get this
pronunciations right for you
guys next time but we're going to try it
one more
time
silic acid mono
asset
monotic AET mono cisic AET mono cisic
cisic cisic all right we got it cisic I
think I don't know anyways if you like
what the show if you like the stories if
there's parts that you don't like
whatever tell me down in the comment
section below I really appreciate the
support I really appreciate the the
likes the comments and stuff it really
does make me want to make more episodes
if for something you want to see me talk
about I'll try my best to do some
research if I don't know about it and
we'll talk about it and we'll do some
learning I'm going dive into some of
these bitter crosses tonight I'm going
to go smoke a little bit more smoke
maybe grab on a titty or two I
appreciate all the the viewership like I
said and uh you know if you're from the
South if you're from out west if you're
from the north if you're from Canada
South America Australia uh South Africa
wherever I appreciate you shout out to
all my homies down south shout out to
everybody in Kentucky and as always baby
shout out Missin baby go check out
Matt's website join the
Discord until next time next Sunday for
episode 7 I'll see you then have a good
weekend and thanks a lot I appreciate
you choke dog over and out by boys