that's gonna be a fascinating book my
friend the sequel right so you got away
- yeah it's like the second album it's
like yeah great work but [ __ ] [ __ ]
that's happening now is even yeah more
exciting so exceptional exceptional
there's a lot going on now which is kind
of interesting it's like this crazy flip
between all the people who are trying to
run their small operations like we
always did in California we had we lost
all our farms in California a few years
ago and due to all kinds of reasons
mostly legal and zoning and all this
[ __ ] and yeah when these larger
operations are going there seems to be a
big split in the community but for me
I'd I'd rather work with some of those
guys who want to do bigger operations
and then keep them real yeah I'd rather
be in it than out of it and for me
everybody should be able to grow
whatever the hell they like to put the
pressure on those big guys there should
be product everywhere I never want to be
able to grow whatever the hell they want
in my opinion so you know that's that's
the only way if everyone's freaking out
about these big rows coming on the only
way is to have 70% of the production
come from small growers exactly the
pressure back on those people absolutely
you have the people that have been
making the community run the whole time
get together do a Voltron grow you know
I mean that's that's the only way to
fight corporations is to become to
become the opposition and not
necessarily be a be cutthroat like them
but you just do it right yourself with
the guys who have been pushing it all
along yeah and you you're allowed to do
it and you should be allowed to do it
but there's also that thing is you know
you can brew you around there but who
does right so there's a place for the
for the other side too but it's up to
the smaller growers to keep the bigger
growers accountable for what quality is
absolutely they're like dinosaurs it
takes them a long time to turn around
and move and get genetics and you know
so do
Vantage is always with the little guy as
long as they're organized you know yeah
that's kind of where I'm from you know
and even though I'm running a couple of
big green houses doesn't mean I don't
feel that and that's still where my
heart is
I bet I'd also be nuts not to take that
opportunity to run those big green
houses just for the ability to grow our
seeds from you guys camera all those
other guys you know and then helping
that breeding process and then pass
those cuts back yeah I don't know if I
told you but I'm gonna be bringing a
bunch of rare African strains that
haven't been haven't been grown like
outside of Africa a lot of people you
know have the Malawi's and the same
strains of Malawi that have been passed
around but I have a lot of different
stuff I'm bringing out there I've been
sitting on for a long time because I
have zero outdoor space and I want them
to be able to grow where they're
happiest that's that's the most
important thing and you do such great
cultivation out there and and I think
that's a place for them so their years
to grow when you want you know well I
mean there's you know the R&amp;D space that
we have with camera and my friend Gordon
Danna elephant head farm you know it's
he's all into it he's the guy who helped
write some of the laws that the better
side of the laws in Arizona he's the
best guy you'll ever meet in any three
anywhere in the world and he wants to
grow a bunch of seeds he wants us to
make a bunch of seeds and he's been
throwing colloidal silver around for 40
years he's like he's made crosses of
Swasey Zand pure tires and pure Hayes's
that we made back in the late 90s and
he's like eight generations in he still
doesn't know what he's doing but the
stuffs great it's like that's amazing
it's like one of those people you know
so he he's a really good person in
Arizona that we can do research in it's
also where we can make seeds to that's
so amazing yeah that's where the heart
is and that's where we'll put that stuff
that's beautiful that's where it needs
to go man I mean I could I think they're
right here but I could it just wouldn't
be happy there there'd be no point in it
I couldn't see it at its best
expressions and it would get lost and it
would be selfish and
overall I think it would be selfish for
me to grow it in try to grow it indoors
and not be happy I'd be selfish to the
whole wheat world so let's get that out
there I think it's off yeah now that
would be amazing and it's also I mean
all these genetics it's it's I mean I'm
helping on four or five operations here
and there and every single one needs
they have different clearances right
like how special is the genetics do I
want to put them there you know I mean
and the ones I get all the special ones
are the real dance earth the real guys
you know absolutely because they don't
even want the the corpora guys don't
even want that other stuff no absolutely
juice you know so it's really kind of
important to put the right stuff in the
right place and that's kind of where our
angle still is you know like keeping it
real so yeah I see sure bin skis in here
that's awesome
he's probably the only guy I got if I'm
being honest he's the only guy I have a
ton of respect from that is involved
with the cookie guys he's the only one
doing real work out of those guys and I
have a lot of respect for that dude so
that's really cool bigger I mean a jig
or two I think so you know I have a
magical yet thing that both it's an
amazing opportunity I mean I've got that
cookie clone really really early on yeah
it's like yeah you put this in your
green eise's and you'll have no problem
you know right yeah and it's it's very
easy to grow and I think that's what's
been a major appeal to it even the shirt
the gelato all that stuff's really easy
to grow but exceptional and the resin
production is next-level yeah yeah
nonsense
there's no pistols to rot in my MIDI
that's like exactly solid known as long
as long as you you're able to like you
see the inside of the flowers you know
that's that's the only thing like boots
on that monsoon season here it's like I
have to be yeah not have anything hiding
inside any flower that I don't know
what's in it you know so during monsoon
it's the case of
I'm only gonna grow stuff I can look
inside absolutely about patients don't
get a surprise yeah the cookies no geez
are off the menu for 12 weeks and then
full force again so we're doing a bunch
of Nigerians a bunch of Hayes's bunch of
easier cycle we have like 13 weeks of
solid sativa runs that'll be amazing all
selection you know all our own selection
systems that'll be [ __ ] amazing
so back in back in Amsterdam what was
what were some of the first strange you
were crying when you were when you're
out there and and just getting into
growing I used to grow and do other
stuff cannabis early nineties but the
cannabis college in 97 we mostly worked
with all the skunk man's F ones which we
later developed first serious weed stuff
was there some Adams THC psycho Martha
Toni stuff we had a show gross everybody
had a little section you know 50 plants
in the garden and a big steak next to it
which which Heath company came from and
we plant 30 seeds of each variety and
people would go for a tour and then
they'd go across the street to buy the
seeds because they'd see a grown from
seed I won the most inch more
interesting ones were we cross all the
scum and stuff with with all the
different Ingram eyes widows Oh like a
super widow line I bet there were there
was some pretty interesting stuff like
that original pays with that white widow
came I like 50% resin wait no yield by
50% resin way I bet you know the really
nice Terps and so that was for me
interesting at the time and then all the
FFTs and stuff as well from Dave stuff
was good herb has a question for you
what is the best strain you've ever
grown that's a hard question I'm sure
anything pops the forefront
depends where I was maybe it's you're
partial to I like I like an hour five
days skunks I mean we developed our
online of it you had the super Silver
Haze we have the Jack Herer
sings a legend there in every now and
again a cut came out paying cut so my
dream was always anybody who had beef
I'm gonna get you know a couple of
hundred of their seeds three-way seeds
and then just rework them and cross them
together like Ingham eyes white widow
Scots white widow will be like across
them together I'm healing some beef a
silver thing right yeah you know so I
kind of like that but that's always been
my go-to that three-way really yeah I
remember delta nine labs did some stuff
with their fruit of the gods if I
remember correctly there was another
stunt or light haze and I found some
they're like I ran a shitload of those
but there were two or three females in
there that were [ __ ] exceptional that
stood out among the rest and that
combination just seems to bring winners
yeah you never you never forget those
though yes there's something about him
it still bugs me to this day
because I mean Eddie got robbed at
gunpoint and they took like 55 gallons
worth of seeds yes so now you know bunch
of other guys collecting a whole bunch
of new yeah I still have some of the old
Northern Lights Brown caves but they're
the German Airy germination rates kind
of [ __ ] but I'll bring them yeah yeah if
we pull it all together and put it all
on the table and we're all sitting
around the table we can start looking at
it and having a giggle you know like
create these different lines and stuff
so yeah pretty cool I think you know
something's going to come out of this oh
yeah I can't wait I really can't wait to
go to the facility and hang out with you
guys for a few days and get to see it
all and play around and learn from each
other yeah any time any time and there's
a couple of states to pick from that
stuff that's so crazy
cool I'll go go fly my drone again
thanks for coming on short it's an
absolute honor and an honor
yeah great shouting would you alright
talk to you soon
so thanks to short for coming on any
time he comes on does exceptional that
was the first time and in fact guys a
repository of knowledge absolute
repository of knowledge and the amount
of hands-on work that he experiences
with all these different strains is a
fork next level my theory on that
hermaphroditism in strains today I think
it's more to do with a mass amount of
new growers not quite knowing what
they're getting into not quite knowing
how to feed plants going with bottle
schedules and all that [ __ ] I'd love to
bring sure bond is he still in here I
would [ __ ] love to bring sure bond
yeah but I think it has more to do with
new growers not knowing how to feed
plants feeding them like tomatoes and
just really not knowing what direction
they're going and also being the
majority of the people who are growing
you don't hear a lot of older growers
bitching about firms because we just
deal with it
you know that we realize that's part of
growing you know something's not happy
in our environment we either acclimate
it because it's really special and we
know that or we just move on and toss it
and it's just whatever you know hook if
you see a herd of happen it's usually
because of something to do with the
environment or how it's being fed any of
that expression almost everything can be
acclimated to not herb whereas like
autoflowering traits and stuff like that
that's a that for me that's a sure toss
you know but yeah I mean I've seen I've
seen some companies get just scalped
over the years scalped and raked of the
Hearn thing and it's usually the ones
who