welcome to breeder Syndicate 2.0 where
we explore the history of a clandestine
scene researching everything from
Cannabis string history old smuggling
Tales from the first person perspective
to breeding science and news on current
subculture
I'm your host Matthew and I'll
occasionally be joined by my homie not
so dog breeder and grower from Mendocino
to speak on these subjects and sometimes
interview other participants our goal is
to document this history before it's
written by corporations and others who
just weren't there
let's start writing some wrongs welcome
to the underground
we joined this conversation already in
progress and it kind of ends abruptly
too so uh yeah
let's get to it
just keeping all right dude how you been
good it's a little bit earlier for you
guys there yeah yeah Antonio think he
just got out of the bed Matt just told
me but I've been up since six eight I
don't know what the [ __ ] deal is he's
lying he's rolled out of bed
um
yeah so um let's see
I I just hit record and I figure we're
just gonna have a conversation and just
like go through seeds and just see where
it leads us on conversations
yeah okay yeah and I I kind of split the
seeds while you can record are you
recording now yeah okay so I did
um did you want to do your intro thing
or nah it's okay so uh I did kind of go
through the seeds and I figured there
was certain ones you might be interested
in there's certain ones you probably
don't really care much about they were
again
I never classed my classified myself as
a breeder I was a seed maker yeah not a
thing right except for a couple little
projects I did for myself where I was
looking for
certain characteristics
for myself and for my crew sure and then
also in turn for
um the general public because I honestly
think they would benefit from what I was
chasing sure but a lot of the genetics
even the stuff I found is just you know
somebody who's in Amsterdam they they
brought back yeah a few packs of this a
few packs of that we grew them out uh
crossbred put f1s out on the market for
I think it was six seeds I sent you some
of those catalogs yeah yeah yeah dude
those are also 16 or 25 bucks or
something like that yeah right just to
kind of and I'll send you some more
stuff like
Chris who was the founder of the great
canana he Emporium and um hemp Nation so
uh getting one of the earlier I'm gonna
I go out there and say well I think
you're the first seed bank in Canada
that openly sold seeds on the uh uh on
the market yeah uh even though it was
just through retail and uh
um
our website or his website yeah and uh
it was you know we're gonna go back to
like
95. everything had to be we didn't have
any kind of this Wicks or whatever
everything he was doing the entire
website through raw code okay yeah I
remember doing that yeah it was quite
the process to uh do this so it was uh
it's pretty nice to uh you know 95s
early 95 is early for HDM and you know
and this again this is going to bring up
what we spoke about the very first time
we spoke because I called my black
dominant 95 my Widow 98.
uh that's right and then we started do
looking into it with Shawnee kids and he
was just like nah Dominic didn't come
out till 96.
so I was like that's [ __ ] up that I
would mislabel that because I literally
been calling that since 95. yeah and uh
so I talked to Chris about it and I was
like this is a seed catalog that I
remember it in what was on the cover
um
and we were able to pull out one of the
old hemp Nation uh seed menus yeah and
there's black domino and it was in this
was from May of 96. yep so which means I
would have bought those seeds and
sprouted them most likely in late 95
yeah in order to uh grow them out enough
to to reproduce them to reproduce you
know what would hot what would happen
often is they would release new lines in
and around the Cannabis Cup right which
was back then in you know the last week
of November yeah November yeah so like
there could be a thing where you're like
oh it's you know it I got it in 95 right
right but it was released on November
27th
1995. so it literally came out like a
month before the you know this was in
the 95 catalog yeah yeah that's what
we've when we found the catalog it said
95. so the website says 96. so then I
was thinking about that also because
most of the people traveling from here
to Amsterdam were going for the cup yeah
so
that's when they're buying all the seed
so they would have brought the seed back
to us in like you say early December uh
95. yeah yeah I mean like in the Jack
Herer for instance I mean obviously like
95 they had that whole themed cup based
on him yeah um they did the worldwide
release of the Jack Herrera line at the
cup
right so it was it was one of those
times like for the Dutch or whatever
where you could get a lot of free
publicity there was already all the
cameramen you know and all the ad guys
we're already there so you'd get a lot
of free press on the new new right so I
kind of viewed it as like that was at
least on the in the 90s era it was
pretty traditional for them
you know and then on top of that too
maybe they had a line that was like that
was about to come out but they'd enter
it into the cup and then it would win
something and then the seeds would be
immediately available right and you'd
see those like super glossy multi-page
Center folds and High Times right and it
was all about driving interest right and
it was a business and stuff and you know
it kind of this kind of brings me to my
my other topic before we really get into
the uh the bag of beans here is you know
um I was talking with Matt too like I
had some some friends reach out and kind
of question some of the things that I
was the way I was remembering them and
then so it got me thinking about that
the bd95 I was like I swear it's 95 and
it took me months you know well yeah for
for Chris to dig out some of her old
hemnation stuff to see well no here's
the BD on that right so and what I was
trying to explain to you know uh people
that have have questions about how some
of us recall certain stories or certain
events and I think not so you talked
about this a few times in the past where
a lot of people were like secretive and
they didn't want to share the stories
right and then there was people like me
that wanted to share the stories don't
mind sharing the stories
and if somebody
remembers it differently then at least
here we're giving them a platform we're
giving I'm trying to invoke the
conversation you know don't text me on
my cell phone and say Hey listen what
you said was wrong right and if if
that's the case then correct me and I'll
come online or whenever I talk to
anybody in newspaper magazine whatever
I'll correct it kind of thing but I can
only regurgitate how I remember things
and I don't you know if I mispronounce
somebody's name or I have a date wrong
or you know
like the story that we were talking
about last time with the seeds that we
used in Switzerland yeah this is a story
so that's why I was asking if you guys
know anybody that was working with
Neville back then that could collaborate
or confirm that uh that story be great
because this is what I've heard and you
know what if I misspeak or something
like that there's when you air this
there's a whole bunch of comments people
can comment correct us so we know that
exactly you can change certain things
don't get upset you know I mean it did
you know I didn't have a riff uh for
um get established because of this but
it did bring up some you know
um conversation sure you know they got a
heated conversation but it got like oh
no that's not how it happened well don't
tell me how you remember it I'll tell
you how I remember it and we can get it
to figure it out already out there kind
of Matt Matt and I deal with this all
the time and it is a good it is a good
time to chat about it because we're
always open to like someone remembering
something different or new information
it comes to light most of the time we
talk it's more like this is the best
that we know right now right right and
memories are
yeah memories memories are funny things
you know and we'd like to say that
memories are etched in stone and stuff
like that but you know like they're just
not right and then you start thinking
back to like
um 25 30 years ago or you know even 20
years ago or whatever and you know what
what's real
right and and that and that that's
definitely part of it because I mean we
have there's certain stories where it's
like people get all upset about you know
one camp or another but the fact of the
matter is is there was two or three guys
there and they don't agree on all parts
right so if they don't agree on all
parts and they were indisputably the
people involved yeah how does the rest
of you figure out which which tale you
want to believe right right
it festers in us like you know the story
and I've regurgitated stories numerous
times hence why I wrote a book because I
put it out there
so if somebody does remember something
different like you know sorry it's in
print now but yeah I've had this
conversation
for 20 30 years uh prior to and this is
how it's always been told kind of thing
and uh you know
I I put it as especially with cannabis
because listen when we get super high
and we have conversations or events
happen sometimes we might not remember
them that well period let alone
correctly
but uh you know we look at our elders
elders that before the internet before
newspapers before you know magazines
before we would you know there was this
elder sitting in circles when I did went
to rainbow gatherings with the uh the
camp we stayed with was granola Funk and
they would set up a stage and it's the
rainbow gathering there's no newspapers
going around it was if you wanted to
learn the history of the rainbow Trail
you go to granola Funk every night at
six o'clock or eight o'clock and
there'll be a stage set up which was
built from you know uh logs we find on
the trees we find on the ground
and uh the elders would tell the story
yeah and that's all that we have so with
cannabis because it was so secretive
because of the laws being so
um
uh part of who said what yeah it became
secretive and the stories do get muffled
and the stories do get
um uh jumbled so again I invite people
to post stuff if they hear something UI
or somebody else says even if it's at
another podcast or you read it in a a
magazine article
if you have two cents add it because
absolutely everybody's two cents will
add up to a dollar someday yeah I mean
for sure we kind of look at it too like
uh you know that whole vibe that you
just that you were just you know
speaking of is kind of the way we look
at things yeah where like it's basically
just like it's like a lot of these chats
and stuff are conversation starters and
we absolutely welcome like more info or
differing points of view or tidbits that
get added that like ad that get weaved
in
I find that like the people that get
really Huffy about it
um generally are the ones where like
they're making money off their
reputation
or they're selling seeds or they get
locked into one particular historical
tale right that suits them and then they
end up having to defend that one right
and I think it's you know I think
there's a lot of damage done in this
industry because like you're saying when
it comes business you know and business
interferes with friendships which has
happened numerous times in this um in
this the movement again that got
developed by the industry I have some
really close friends that were part of
the very beginning of this that do speak
out when the the right time comes right
but a lot of them are just you know a
lot of them
are weathered by this by this industry
now and I took a shitload of heat when I
uh joined in Diva right but when I was
living in Diva with uh with these two
business suits [ __ ] shiny shoes
[ __ ] that you know people are
like oh you're selling out you're
selling out right now it's like wait a
second is it selling out
yes I am going to get paid quite quite
well but
what else am I supposed to do here like
if you're not happy with the direction
that the ship is going telling from the
sidelines means jack [ __ ] that's not and
you're not making a change get on the
[ __ ] boat and help steer it in the
right direction if you're just bitching
from the sidelines sorry I don't I don't
[ __ ] got any time for you kind of
thing get on the [ __ ] boat and and
correct us so and help us steer it into
the [ __ ] direction that you believe
it should be in and because some of
these people are old deep friends of
mine I invite that I would love for them
to come together even though I know some
of them can't because of outside of this
uh the Cannabis Community yeah
that that that weld will never will
never happen but
um we need to kind of keep this these
stories this journey alive and the only
way we can do it is if the elders
regurgitate how they understand it
exactly there's there's a lot of Elders
in here I talked to Doc sumac right
Roddy Hedding right he uh he's from this
area he wrote one of the first grow
guides grow your own Stone oh grow your
own Stone that's right yep right super
[ __ ] nice guy super freaky
[ __ ] right still not in the
industry he's in the hemp and you know
still but
you know I would sit and just listen to
him you know like that dude I wanted to
hear his version from the 50s and the
city or the 60s and the 70s yeah because
there is nothing like he wrote it and
grow your own Stone High Times was out
uh in the in the 70s and some stories
got out but not now today
this [ __ ] podcast there's in there's
websites there's so much out there that
we could you know fill in all these
blanks and yeah maybe I am wrong in some
of the the stories because this is but
this is how I remember it and please
correct me if uh if I'm misunderstanding
the the at least you have the balls to
be wrong and to stand up and like you
know remember something wrong and then
take accountability a lot of people
don't even have the balls to do that and
they just like to point and just I wish
they would stand up too it's not really
my end of things but Matt Matt loves
like like murder shows and Murder
Mysteries and all that type of stuff and
one of the things that they've
discovered is one of the absolute worst
kinds of testimony is eyewitness
testimony right because the memory is so
funny
and it can and it can change over time
and it can be influenced over time and
you can be convinced and have your
memory change and the other part of it
that's important for people to realize
is that you know when you know this
might sound a little grandiose or
whatever but if you're involved in any
kind of like interesting thing in
history
most people don't realize they're
involved in it at the time
right like nobody we didn't realize when
we were all younger messing around with
this stuff that people were going to
want to know granular details right of
some of these things right you know and
that that plays a role too it's not like
we all knew that hey we should really
document this as we're going in fact as
you were saying with the with the
underground nature of things you know
notes were a bust yeah yeah exactly yeah
he went opposite and you kept a million
pictures
I always kept notes and I recorded
things so if I was involved there was
really good notes if I wasn't involved
and I it's just I'm going by uh what
I've seen and what I've heard
then you know what it's it's part of uh
part of law like if you you wanna you
know you wanna ice the goalie kind of
thing where you want to prolong how long
till you put a witness on the stand
if you're the defense yeah because you
want that person's memory to get foggy
you want that in person's memory to
maybe be influenced by other things or
you know remember the gist of the story
but maybe not the details and like you
say like all these stories we have are
little grains and for the longest time
we were playing in a small sandbox
yeah now we're on we're on beaches of
endless grains of sand where there's so
much more out there and there's so many
people involved that you know the few of
us that were sitting in that little
sandbox we only remember so much and
we're going back to the uh for me the
80s I started growing pot in the mid 80s
I talk about that too all the time where
it was like I kind of feel like at least
for like America for for a while there
like hippies and the Grateful Dead and
that kind of Highway it was the the
primary path in cannabis yeah oh yeah
there's not any it's not anymore but for
an era there you know like you know
hippie circles and groups of friends and
and all and then on top of that people
don't realize that like you could go
meet somebody on dead tour and chat and
you were somewhat anonymous because they
didn't know where you lived yeah they
didn't know who you were really they
weren't from your hometown you weren't
going to get ray aided necessarily and
so you know people would bring their
weed on the on the tour and stuff and so
like there there's you know now it's
like you as you were saying like weed's
a super highway and like that's just one
lane yeah you know there's a bunch of
other lanes now and with the Grateful
Dead thing too like the the Shakedown
Street was where the stories that's
where the elders sat and told the story
to the Next Generation but there was a
lot of us out there now I wasn't on dead
tour but you know obviously lots of uh
good friends Not only would I when I did
my travels
up and down the East Coast I didn't just
bring the pot I brought the seed too
because for me
I like this this type of cannabis right
and I and this seed grows this type of
cannabis well Crossing International
lines or on dead tour
chances of DEA or anybody like that
infiltrating Shakedown or something like
that you don't want to travel with
[ __ ] large amounts of pox so when you
you find somebody that's like-minded
that has good pot and has the right Vibe
or the right stories you pass that seat
along to that person and say Hey listen
when we're dead comes through here next
year I'm gonna call you up or I'm gonna
you we're gonna find each other you know
bring me some of this
you know and you can spread that seed
and give me some of your seed and if
when you're in Buffalo or something like
that or you're in Orlando
look me up I'll be around I'm gonna have
your seat right so we would do that not
only just for the story but for the for
the ability for us to share in genetics
but also
uh not you know for a safety reason
almost basically to you know pass out
cuttings I was I went through a phase
where I was like I don't want anybody to
really have my cuttings and stuff like
that I'm a little worried about it and
we were talking about that with the moms
I had at the end of my uh mom Garden I
was somewhere close to 150 moms yeah
it's a lot over at least 100 of them I
had for years
and I and
probably 30 of them I've had for
decades
yeah that I've kept and I was always
like yeah you know and this is something
else I think I sent you in a in a
private message was you know when I was
doing that uh I don't really want to
have anybody go I was like they're going
to bastrize it they're going to [ __ ] it
up it's going to kill the name [ __ ] like
that
well then my that I lost that Mom well I
didn't give it to anybody right so then
I was like okay you know what I got this
guy Yoda I'm going to give him my
genetics you know and he keeps him I
came I keep two of every [ __ ] plan
right so that means and when I have a
130 150 plants that means I have 300
moms not just flowering 300 moms yeah
about your numbers and [ __ ] like that
you know yeah that comes into play
to different people
and I what I did learn also is never
tell
you know grower a that you gave it to
grow would be as well right what's that
why
grower bees like well you gave it to
grower a so I just killed it I I didn't
have space I didn't have time and then
I'm just totally true thrower a [ __ ]
just did the same [ __ ] thing and now
I have that [ __ ] strain and I lost
like I lost my chemo from 96. yeah
and I'm just like and I found some chemo
seeds
you know I don't know which ones they
are the UBC or again I think there's an
Ottawa cut
again called chemo was it the [ __ ]
chemo you know in our seed [ __ ]
catalog there's a story that chemo was
developed to fight cancer and and I
think they said Ontario yeah and I was
like where the [ __ ] that story come from
it's written in the hemp Nation [ __ ]
um
uh catalog so I was just like really
like
I I did hear about G13 you know I heard
you know there are certain medical
strains being grown in California that
made it up here and you know and then
the whole like M39 that whole list of
the M's and stuff like that like
there's people out there that know the
the truth of where this came from
and it could have been like my purple
Power Plant my purple power plant is not
a power plant yeah right it's purple
Power Plant because it was a cutting
given to me a guy had no idea what it
was old-time farmer just not smoking
this strain we've been growing for the
last [ __ ] 20 years or 10 years and I
grew it out it grew just like a a power
plant structure I was [ __ ] went
purple
I don't know what to call it so I call
it a triple P purple Power Plant people
like oh yeah I love power plants like
well this isn't power play like at least
I'll be honest about it I just named it
this because it fit the description it
was easy for me to uh remember was that
the PPP that went around Canada
I don't know because there was because
there was a PPP that went around that
people called like pure power plant
purple Power Plant
it might have like I did this I named
that
probably 12
at least 12 years ago probably more
maybe no it's long enough before I was
married so probably 15 years ago you
know yeah and it was just again at this
time again I was spreading the wealth I
mean you and my members all my members
at the London compassion Society have
access to all my genetics we don't hold
them back from them never have so if
they wanted it or they ended up with it
um whoever they gave it to you know good
on them luckily some I got some strains
back that way I was like ah you know we
lost it put it on our website hey were
you growing this strain
and they say I wasn't but I gave it to
my brother-in-law I can ask him he still
has it get it back to us kind of that's
awesome you know the whole thing about
keeping our seeds protected and you know
um and like again when we get into the
seeds here which we probably should soon
is
um I want I you know it's going to piss
people off but I want to see genetics
um
rescued yeah because some of these
people don't have these genetics you
know yeah I mean as a collector myself
like the hardest thing it's really easy
to spread things out when like they're
having their moment in the Sun and
they're popular and people can make
money off them the hard part is like hey
I'm gonna give you this hold on to it
keep it in your mom room even when it's
unpopular and it's maybe just head stash
for you and nobody else wants it right
because everybody wants it when it's
heads has its moment in the Sun and it's
popular and they can sell it and they
can do stuff with it but it's like who's
gonna hold on to it when it's just
unpopular and kind of a pain in the ass
and taking up space right and so that's
the weird thing is everybody wants
someone else to do that work right so
that it's available to them when they
want it right see I did it I had to do
it a little bit different again because
of the amount of clients that we had
um I would sit with my staff and say
Okay
um this is what's in the garden now this
is what's uh coming next and this is
what's after that and we would have to
figure out okay well this strain is one
of the popular sellers we want to grow
it every other Harvest or every third
Harvest depending on how many uh lights
we were going to dedicate to it but we
would have to you know especially with
you know
I think we have we keep at least 25 to
30 strains on our menu
and we produce all of them right so we
would have to predict when that strain
we think is going to get down low enough
that we never run out of it so I would
have to predict I had literally almost
two years of
um
of a list of what I was going to be
growing because I had to
so we didn't run out of it on our menu
so I did keep all those strains and then
again it's not like I'm you it's not
like okay we're gonna go over that
strain I couldn't just say I'm going to
grow a strain I have to pull out the mom
or moms get that big enough
to take the cuttings off of them and
have the cuttings ready for when the
time comes to flower room so I can have
the Harvest in by this particular date
which is four and a half from now so
that means in about a year or in six in
14 months I have to start the taking the
cuttings out of the mom room put them
into the veg or you know it's actually
one of the big problems that we have
right now in like what and like how they
arrange to like California legal market
right that you most people like you know
the nursery and the cultivation for
flower is separate right they're
separate they're separate businesses
they're licenses and so like a nursery
might have a hundred plants you know
that they're that they have in their in
their collection but they only pick
eight or nine to like have that many
moms to offer up that season right right
and so it's like actually like quite
limiting because they're trying to plan
it and like you can be like oh I want to
grow this right but man like the
nurseries that I want they didn't choose
that one right to Market this year so I
can't I can't get enough of them so
therefore it can't go in my garden so
therefore it's not going to hit the menu
anywhere well and that was an issue also
like you're saying with what's uh what's
the new phase uh the what's hot on the
market right now we had to keep that
into consideration with the center as
well because they're like oh well you
know the um the poop breath is uh is is
huge right now everybody's asking for it
say okay well you know let's see if we
can find a cutting okay I can get a
cutting but that means it's not going to
be on our menu for six months and is it
going to be popular by the time you Mom
it up anymore so I'm just like so for me
I was like what what is our staple what
do we need and I will keep a certain
amount of Lights available for what's
new
or what you know that's going to be a
tester right because
we'll grow it out it's going to take you
know
um
minimum four months four to five months
to get a an okay Harvest where we can
put it out there to the to our clients
and then they could say yeah this is a
winner then we're like okay we're gonna
throw it in the next rotation
because we we like it it's new it's
fresh it's hot
it's going to be another three months
until we can have it um on the menu but
um and if it's not you know we have
another one so it was it was kind of a
it was a it was a quite the chess game
it was it was a huge pain in the ass I
don't miss it at all honestly but uh you
know
it was a uh it was a a hard way to
grow when it's not you're not going for
the magazines you're not grown for the
internet you're going for medicine and
you're growing and you're growing for I
think we're we're 1200 clients or
something like that luckily not all of
them use a use us
uh like we would like them to in I guess
in a sense but supplying that many uh
clients on a regular basis would be
close to Impossible yeah I bet going
into you know
um darker markets yeah so but anyways
um so yeah I get back to the seeds I
know that's what we kind of wanted to do
and and uh we're gonna talk on and
offline I think about some of this sure
this stuff because you know you we're
going to hear names that I have that the
original breeders of these strains are
definitely going to want yeah and you
will get yeah okay they're not going to
get my seed
but I would like to
see if I can resurrect these seeds if I
could save these seeds they're top on
the list they exactly will get uh
any of the seed if there's any males or
females
that I have access to that I will have
access to then the original breeders of
these strains get those cuts they get
the
um the males females and I would like to
do an open pollination just to save the
genetics I know it's going to be a
smorgasbord of God knows everything's in
there but
if there's a hundred seeds if there's a
thousand seeds
that what they're looking for is in
there and if it comes from any of the
cuts
any of the sorry the the plants male or
female that come from it 100 every uh
every breeder gets those and I'm not in
the same business I'm not here to sell
seeds I'm not here to sell their strains
I'm here to save their strains
um and uh I know some of them say well
just send me the original seeds well no
they're my seeds I paid for them
I want to make I want to say I want to
make sure they're going to who I feel is
capable
and because my seeds are old and they
weren't stored properly chances are you
know when I spoke to some of them
already they're like yeah don't worry
about the [ __ ] they're dead but some
of them were like oh did you storm
properly and I was like no not really
they're like
they're not overly interested anymore
okay and some of them
um as we spoke private privately are
willing to you know send people to come
talk to me about getting their genetics
back kind of thing yeah no I'm not going
to leave these people out they're the
the focus for this but yeah these are
seeds that
um that I own the seed I don't own The
Strain the genetic gets back to uh who
it rightfully belongs to uh I mean the
fun the funny part about that is some
people might not even be interested in
getting them a lot more yeah because
they wouldn't want to ever admit that
they needed it well some of them will
admit to need it but they're just like
Pete you know what that back then you
know it's nothing compared to what we're
producing today that's like when people
offer me my old stuff I'm the same way
I'm like well you know 15 years ago I
was doing something totally different
I'm really into what I'm doing now so
now go ahead and run with it yeah and uh
and but again I'll give them that uh
that offer because I was more mentioning
that like some seed banks are like oh we
have all the original parents yeah you
know I I know some of these guys don't
have any of these seed yeah I haven't
had for probably a decade or more
and it wasn't even part of their
breeding program as far as I know it
wasn't part of that breeding program
some of some of it was yeah something
that some of it wasn't and uh same thing
I might have 10 seeds I might have four
C's like the chemo I think I only have
like four four or five C's and little
tiny seeds kind of thing so you know
that doesn't belong to anybody that I
know of and if somebody says oh I
developed that that's mine [ __ ] hit
me up man if I get seeds I'll send you a
[ __ ] I'll send you seats I don't have
a [ __ ] issue with that kind of thing
you know you have to kind of back it up
a little bit but yeah you know a little
you know really strange I know who they
are you know yeah I thought about it too
because when I was starting in diva
and I was like listen I'm bringing all
my genetics and I have 15 years of data
that I've collected on the medical uses
of these strains right yeah grown in the
method that I grow them in and that
helps me or was planned to help me a lot
with getting into the legal Medical
Market where we can't advertise that
this strain works for this medical
condition but there's kind of a loophole
I believe that if you
have testimony from somebody that has
the same illness or ailment as you and
uses this strain you know eighty percent
of the time they they go this is their
go-to indica and this is their go-to
sativa so we can give you that
information
yeah we can't say it works for your
condition but if I have 15 years of data
and I could say listen you know out of
the
um 80 clients that have the same
condition as you over the last 10 years
they 80 or 60 of the time they went to
this and then 20 they went to this and
then 20 they went to this so it gives
them a starting point at least
to have a genetic that um that works for
them what I'm getting to is these
genetics don't belong to me the plants
belong to me but the genetics don't so
if I bring in a genetic from you know if
it was some Scentsy seed or one of you
know the big Amsterdam companies I don't
give a [ __ ] honestly but if it's one of
the you know what I call the old you
know the from the movement in this area
in North America you know I would like
to reach out to that person I might not
ask permission
more or less saying what can I do uh to
uh
you know give you peace so if it is
something that you know that I'm going
to be using my strawberry diesel right
I'll reach out to Strawberry diesel guy
and say listen you know what I have to
take that's I've been growing the strain
for 11 years
um
we're gonna grow it in the lp Market you
know you're going to see your strain on
the legal Market
um
what can I give you be yeah kind of
thing right like if if it's a big seller
and we're making lots of money off it
sure fairly well because I'm the one on
the boat helping steer this ship you're
you're part of the you're one of the
paddlers in a sense you should get paid
I'm not [ __ ] screw anybody but I'm
also here to not here to you know bend
over and say listen you know yeah it's
your strain I won't grow it
sorry like I have it I'm I'm using it
for medicinal reasons it's a little bit
different I agree if you know I you know
like what buddy did to Steve in in
Amsterdam where he takes Steve's Sweet
Tooth and and enters the Cannabis Cup
yeah yeah you tell Steve to [ __ ] himself
pretty much right like yeah co-ops this
whole strain yeah I mean seed politics
it's it's one of those things where it's
you with the way seeds work and the way
clones and everything else work it's
like you can hoard it
or then once you let it out into the
into the world it's kind of the honor
System from then yeah yeah and like I
said I I've had no problem uh keeping
track of some of the people that gave me
their these genetics you know and um
I would piece them out somehow you know
whether it be
uh like in these this case here with the
seeds if I get any uh plants from these
seeds they 100 get if they want 100 get
whatever they want from it they won't
get all of them they're not going to get
the exclusivity of it you know but if
they say well listen Pete you know I
don't really want to see my seed out
there being sold on on a market fine I'm
not here to do that I'm not I'm here to
save the genetics if they want to do it
great you know I think it'd be kind of
dumb to uh horde stuff like that
especially because we're talking about
strains from
15 years ago yeah you know they they
didn't care that much now but now they
think it's a money thing
money you know is maybe dictating with
some and some it's it's the respect
because they deserve so much like tons
of [ __ ] respect in this in this uh
industry because they're from the
movement
and they kind of got you know
left on the Wayside whether it be their
fault or not their fault right like a
lot of us tried to get in and just tied
our our uh a line to the wrong boat and
that boat sank or went [ __ ] South
like they did within Diva you know I
gave [ __ ] my uh my name luckily not
my genetics to a diva and um once they
raised their [ __ ] 45 million dollars
they were like yeah we don't really need
you anymore
yeah and uh [ __ ] kicked me off the
boat kind of thing I saw that happen so
often yes so many good people there's so
many good people and it deserves so much
better well you see in California
California's getting killed right now
yeah that's happened everywhere it's
happened in college it's happened
basically in almost every legal yeah I
mean every place and like my my home
state New York my friends are like let's
get in let's get in I'm just like
[ __ ] dude like New York New York is
[ __ ] huge it's going to be [ __ ]
Mass money you know and you get you know
you get the uh uh the [ __ ]
um up in Canada we had canopy
um that was going around bullying and
pushing around everybody it was a big um
one out of the states I think they might
have started
Colorado or California and they opened
up a shop in New York just waiting for
the license but they had enough money
they couldn't sell pot pure relief maybe
or uh
it's a really common one acreage
Holdings perhaps no they're old one of
those big devils yeah it was uh yeah
I'll try to remember who it was but I
know they had uh
um like a flagship in New York in
Manhattan
ready to get a license and then before
New York was even talking about what
would you need to get a license and they
went in and uh
um opened up shop selling
[ __ ]
uh t-shirts and hats I think right like
I don't know what else they could have
sold at that time I'm going to try to
Google at the same time that I talk to
you guys but
um if we start getting into the politics
of how it goes state by state we'll
really get off subject no it would I and
I know like when I was uh out in
Colorado
right after they legalized
and uh back then obviously they couldn't
use Banks right so everybody was getting
paid like their CEO that we met with and
she helped actually write a lot of the
uh the bills for other states because
everybody's trying to follow in Colorado
yeah in their footsteps kind of thing
and uh she would get paid in the checks
you have to go to a cash check in place
she's probably making
a couple hundred grand a year and go
into it check cashing Cash in place to
cash your check because you can't bring
it to a bank yeah you know like no
federally insured place you know or
trying to get paid cash a couple hundred
grand a year in cash and you're a CEO
you're not a [ __ ] hot head you're
[ __ ] you're brought in for your
business uh mine not for your cannabis
mind that kind of thing so it's still a
big issue in America oh yeah without a
doubt without a doubt I mean that's
going to be the biggest thing like our
biggest LP up here being canopy which
was uh
um Tweed Stardust we announced at canopy
growth there was rumor that they were
going to think or we're thinking about
starting their own bank
because they
had they were worth hundreds of millions
of dollars if not you know half a
billion dollars
and other companies like in Diva we're
getting kicked out of banks
yeah right we had you know millions of
dollars in their in there and they're
like yeah you know what come and get it
we don't we won't I got kicked out of
I've been kicked out of three Banks now
in uh in Canada you know I've been
denied uh mortgages when I put up three
times what the mortgage was for in in
assets but because of what I did for a
living even though it was fully legal
and it was a publicly traded company
the bank wouldn't touch me yeah because
you know uh reputational risk
kind of [ __ ] so anyways I know we're
getting way off topic so
um
what do you want to start with
uh just wherever you grab well
there's gonna be
sorry there's gonna be
stuff that I think is interesting to me
and then there's going to be the stuff
that
um
um might be interesting to some I know
this okay so this came up it's gonna be
kind of hard I don't know if you can see
the names it's kind of hard to see the
name so cream sortica oh cool right so
that's interesting this is a seed that
we did in Switzerland okay I think Steve
brought it in from
this
guy and now this guy's name was
uh start with a j his name is Jay he's
the douchebag I was talking he lives on
Sunshine Coast now uh but I don't think
it came from him but it came through a
mutual friend whose name is a color and
it's the red color but
um I think that's where this seed came
from
I don't know if I brought these back I
didn't bring these back from Switzerland
I think I I ended up maybe getting these
after Switzerland I ended up uh working
on a greenhouse Farm in the interior
um north of Kamloops that
the guy that was growing the
cream soda cup most likely gave me these
beans
kind of thing and they look good but
this is this might be a strain that
could be of interest to some sure not to
the because I wouldn't know you I I
wouldn't even give it the guy that would
have made these seeds yeah yeah didn't
give a [ __ ] about them and I really
don't give a [ __ ] about him
um so yeah I'd be into that one that's
cool yeah and again like I said we'll
figure out a whole bunch of that so so
now
we were talking about Mighty Mite yeah
right yeah and uh so these seeds here
from
uh
from May 2002 they're a Hindu Kush cross
Mighty might
being in Southwestern Ontario where like
you were saying we need to get our stuff
in out of the fields
mid-september if possible right yeah
yeah because of the the cold the frost
and stuff like that uh we we were and
this is from Yoda uh who's still like
I've mentioned before so I'm gonna give
some of my genetics too to hold yeah um
this is his breathing now his breeding
wasn't super specific or anything he was
just like you know I got a Mighty Mite
I'm gonna cross it with a whole bunch of
[ __ ] because I want to speed up now
Crossing with the Kush the Hindu Kush
which is also a fairly fast train faster
strain it was making uh and this is
going O2 we didn't have the Kush craze
by that time yeah no maybe for a second
you could talk about Mighty might
because while Matt and I might be real
familiar with it yeah most people
especially in the US and stuff it
probably predates them and they probably
have maybe heard about it but don't know
very much about why it was popular or
why it became such a Canadian thing yeah
I think I think it's basically what I
was just saying too is because these
strains that were fast you know and we
didn't want the [ __ ] ruderalis crap
right because it was crap but the uh the
fact that you know could clone it you
know with Mighty might uh it was a very
easily clonable plant it because of its
structure but most importantly
for us it's we need things that finish
quickly and I wanted to
we would use that in our um I'm going to
say breeding but in our seed making we
were looking for these
um uh early you know ideally early
September strength before the thieves
get out there before the police get out
there and before the frost comes
so I mean as far as the history goes in
Mighty might I that's I'd leave that a
little bit more to The Experts sure
these were just but that's fine it got
it got famous basically because it came
in
in the season that was appropriate for
where you guys are at yeah 100 100 and
that's the same thing with that Golden
Boy right so yeah see a bunch of things
Golden Boy I have a string called Boris
which was a um and I just saw that too
AK-47 Golden Boy
no I don't have that strain but I want
to find out the lineage on this Golden
Boy so again story I was told and I ran
this by HB
um about you know because it really that
was our that worked in at M Nation we're
pretty sure it came through one of his
connections okay now that's when this
whole triple SC
uh name was was attached to it yeah okay
but it was attached to it coming out of
Ontario not out of Amsterdam so it was
either he was over there and got this
seed
from the triple FC guys in the
you know the 80s and the 90s what this
was would have been when we got it would
have been
mid mid
90s Maybe 96.
I have pictures of it
um
and I'm gonna say mid 90s give or take a
few years kind of thing so
what is it I don't know but this we knew
that when we did quote inside [ __ ] 45
days you know it was uh it was finishing
up so we I'd love to see some pictures
of it sometime yeah it's not but they're
not not good pictures
really weird strain it was very [ __ ]
that pistoly the gentleman that was
growing it I think he even has tin foil
on the walls it was going back that far
awesome kind of thing yeah
um it wasn't Phototron years but it was
like the first time of HID lighting
being brought into closets yeah trying
to make it as reflective as possible
yeah I mean my first part I was a uh was
a gutted refrigerator
you know that's awesome and yeah lined
with tinfoil and uh
um fluorescent lights yeah because we
didn't have and we basically built a
Phototron in our garage back in New York
do it yeah don't do it dude and uh toast
who was my roommate back then we were
both [ __ ] Surfer skate or pothead
kind of guys and uh he was the first
person that I knew that grew uh under
hid right so 400 watt in his closet you
know I lived with those uh and he was
using four inch Rockwell cubes in
um
in tupperware dishes
you know under a 400 right so uh we got
off topic again
but um yeah so I think with the Golden
Boy that's again where you we're going
to see that name come up in my seed
collection yeah because
of the speed it up whatever I was uh
gonna grow it with
um
so here like okay so we got another
block Domino so this is a black dominant
female
and we had a sweet tooth number three
cross blueberry male
oh that sounds like that almost sounds
like what
I can't remember who was talking about
it was describing as black or sweet
what was it sweet tooth four some one of
the weird sweets
It's one of the sweet tooths had black
domino inserted and it was like sweet
paint grapefruit blueberry black domino
and it was only for a brief little bit I
don't know 2.2 or that doesn't sound
familiar to me but again if you're
trying to get into breed of Steve's head
what he was doing what he was looking
for
um going back to this this would also
probably be a seed that came out in the
mid 90s or was yeah it was made in the
mid 90s by us about me is my handwriting
um
and back then I was selling uh Sol seeds
in London for Steve where you'll see
that I have
very very hold on a second oh well
so like yeah so that's the
sweet who is that sweet tooth number
four yeah yeah
now there's a bunch of seed there and
that's the one that Gary stole from
Barney's farm and entered in the cup is
the Sweet Tooth number four oh really we
went with yeah I thought it was a three
really it was a four I thought he sells
it he sells it as four so maybe it
wasn't yeah this is this is where I was
saying before so I got like a vial
inside a vial so which don't know
exactly what that means but this is
where you know it'd be nice to get
people like Steve on these forums if you
can control his temper that um
because he has a lot of this knowledge
of you know what he was doing what he
was going after because he was one of
the first he was the first breeder
that I became friends with he was the
guy that was actually breeding for
genetics not for seed production I mean
he was reading for seeds to sell but you
know he was actually putting the the
time in the energy into so again any of
these seeds that I get started
he gets first [ __ ] dips he might come
to me and say well Pete am I straight am
I see my strain I want all of it you're
not going to get all of it because I'm
going to keep some for myself not to
sell not to [ __ ] uh uh put it out
there that's his their his genetics he
can do what he wants but
you know I wanna like I said earlier you
do you keep all your genetics and your
[ __ ] in your uh back pocket
you [ __ ] lose your pants you lose
that strength kind of thing so that's
the funny thing too where it's like when
it comes to seed breeding too it's like
people are like I'm gonna breed and I'm
gonna sell these things yeah but then I
still have control or dip reading right
everything that happens from that point
on I own all the males you regret the
seed for me kind of it's almost like a
Monsanto type of thing yeah yeah where
you're like you don't really own any of
it I'm gonna let you grow it and smoke
it but it pretty much mine still even
though you paid me for it right well I
think that's where it kind of gets
[ __ ] up yeah that's kind of what I was
pointing out for sure
okay so this is something else oh
it's going to be I wish I had better
cameras so staying on the SLO stuff
because I did a lot you know again Steve
and I uh friendship goes back quite a
long time and like I said he was one of
the first
people that was a breeder yeah kind of
thing
um
he would sell me his seed
oh going this way uh so this is the
what is that can you see David wait a
second no but it's a shishka berry
number three oh [ __ ] three interesting
and then
shift two
and again in his uh packaging because he
he was a little little vials and then
I got shishka Berry first generation oh
wow right
now this is where I get confused I was
talking to Red about it uh which can be
a little bit of a uh
uh sensitive topic but um it was
I just knew there was a yellow and a red
line yeah right that's as far as my
extent went to so when I was going
through these seeds I was just like well
this is in Steve's writing
this isn't Steve's well writing
Packaging and then the sister Berry
first generation is in my writing right
so
what's what like did he have three
different and I think red actually even
tried to explain it to me
but uh we were talking about a few
different things and again why I think
you know people like red who has a lot
of knowledge in
who is really doing what yeah and his
versions of it which I will strongly
agree with
98 of the time but like you say we I I
100 agree with I should say that I'm 98
agree with what I'm saying because it's
what I how I understand it so you know
when it comes to these seeds I know
Steve would be like well then my season
I'll learn back
they are your seeds and if anything
comes from them you get 100 of
everything but I'm keeping some for
myself because I bought these seats from
you yeah right
um I I like the old stuff I don't grow
for the [ __ ] uh highest THC or a
certain turf or or to sell seeds right I
will make sure like that you know he
doesn't want this seed sold he has the
seed company he's a sea breeder you
don't [ __ ] step on somebody's Toes
that way yeah there is genetics you can
have them but I want to do what I can to
save him so I can uh so I have them for
myself or again
if and when the time comes there might
be a time that I'm like [ __ ] it you know
what
I'm moving I'm gonna be in [ __ ] you
know someplace in Europe I'm not going
to grow anymore [ __ ] I'm deluding my
seed [ __ ] catalog take everything I
don't give a [ __ ] anymore I'm not at
that point yet when that point comes I'm
not going to say okay I'm selling my
collection I'm going to say well I'm
going to say I have
certain people's genetics are yours kind
of thing if you don't care then sure
I'll put them out there and I'll [ __ ]
spread the spread the wealth 100
. but like I say I have a a sweet tooth
I'll just say
so sweet tooth number one oh it says
Sweet Tooth number one or number two but
there's only like five seeds in a little
[ __ ] baggie oh interesting yeah you
know again and that to me I just want to
throw this in there before I forget yeah
like going through like uh
um old seed collections yeah is very
much like that it's like here's some
chicken scratch that only the guy that
put it in there could ever decipher
here's a weird code God he gave me this
oh no you know I remember this weird
vial right and this weird vial with this
SK on it this means this right but if
you were someone else trying to decipher
some some one of your friends's seed
collections it would almost be
impossible yeah like you pretty much
need them it's almost like hieroglyphics
you would almost need them there to
interpret it for you because if you just
got it without any and and I even think
I mean there was a thing where
um you know Matt when you and I were
talking about uh how we found out that
like you know when Neville sold his seed
collection to Shanti uh he got pissed at
him and then just stopped explaining all
the coats yeah yeah and I didn't know
what he had and then you didn't know
what he had because yeah there was all
these weird codes I was um
um I think it was it was breeder Steve
that when I
was [ __ ] like 10 years ago or
something like that I was like oh I got
these old seeds of yours I'm I haven't
stored them properly
um and he put me in touch with some guy
on the west coast and the deal was that
he gets to keep and do whatever he wants
with with the seeds that he recovers and
I just said well no I'm not going to do
that like that you I understand because
then again he was a friend of Steve's I
would imagine but it all right for if I
sent him to him
he could have he could have [ __ ] me he
could have [ __ ] Steve sure right so
every every every embryonic rescue guy I
have ever worked with has [ __ ] me
right oh I'll tell you that and all of
them were from the west coast and there
have been a few so yeah
like I'm just like you know I want to
take my mom I got this old thing and if
it you're gonna pay me a lot of money to
to rescue this thing yeah and if it
doesn't work I get the money and if it
does work I get the money and I get the
genetics yeah that's the deal I'm on
wheat deal it's a great deal for me the
worst case scenario I make a bunch of
money the best case whatever you get I
already have it right and I mean like
you say with the with the the chicken
scratch and I I've done that like
because I told uh the what I think was
the one deal break or what
excuse me was is
I'm going to send you all the seeds
but they're numbered
there's not
and I did this with my when I was
hoarding my genetics people were like oh
you know I need cuttings I say okay
you're gonna get the LCS number six
and you're gonna get LCS number 18.
you're like what is it they're like I'll
tell you when you harvest the plant
and I know that you're not [ __ ]
because nobody's gonna say well yeah I
got Cuts I'm gonna sell you cuttings
yeah but people like well what are they
like I don't know but I know they're
good well no I don't want them yeah
right so I was gonna do that and it was
like no no you can't do that we need to
know what the strains are that we're
growing but we're going to try to
resurrect or save and um I just said no
that's not going to work for me and
did that piss off people yeah I'm sure
I'm pissed I piss off a lot of people
all the time I'm really [ __ ] you know
what I don't give a [ __ ] anymore like
you know I'm doing baby I've saved these
seeds for [ __ ]
20 some odd years right you're gonna get
pissed off at me now that I'm not
turning them over to you you know sorry
but you know I would after that long you
get to be the custodian yeah and I I
don't mind [ __ ] giving them back
after they're saved and they're secured
and they're not gonna get [ __ ]
um pasteurized and stuff like that I'm
not gonna just you know
um
let anybody like there'll be there'll be
conditions
of what what is what I mean and if
somebody like the one guy is like listen
if you're true to your word that you're
going to be
um
honest then you if you want me to trust
you then you have to trust me and I am
going to send you
um my uh
uh my golden Haze
but I'm not going to tell you it's
golden Haze I'm going to tell you it's
you know it's a code and then when
you're like yeah it's resurrected okay
send it back to me then you know
um I'm gonna know what it is and if uh
if it's my strain and I'm like okay you
can have it I'll tell you what the [ __ ]
it is but there's gonna be certain ones
that I can't do best of luck I don't
know who the [ __ ] Eric is so
who is this so yeah so grapefruit
see again like you were saying we get
trash so what I started doing with this
stuff is I started reaching out to
um friends yeah okay who's this so it
says grapefruit SLO probably Sweet Tooth
um
best of luck sorry I missed you Eric
so this somebody that
probably had bought grapefruit seeds for
me yeah ended up [ __ ] growing them in
his [ __ ] backyard or something and he
said well this is what it could be so
you know are they worth keeping I think
100 because it might be that one Sweet
Tooth [ __ ] plant in there yes he's
been looking for it yeah you know if
you're gonna pop a bunch of Sweet Tooth
you might as well pop that one with them
and see if it's not all of it and it's
not up to me because I remember sweet
tooth that I grew but I don't remember
the sweet tooth that Steve grew or red
group you know like they and when I was
talking with uh with red about this I
was just like well
you know is
is this shishka Berry like I wanted
cinnamon Nook I grew out the
shishenberry and I was just like
kind of doesn't look like the red or the
yellow line and he's like send me a
[ __ ] nug I'll tell you which one it
is I fortunately never did it but no I
still have a package to send red too
myself well I was talking about right
here though and this is when he has the
pungent skunk yeah that's the one I want
to see that I want to know what's in
that yeah so that when I told red he
that's the only one he really showed
interest in he's like oh dude where they
probably store it I was like no sorry
dude he's like ah [ __ ] so same thing you
know
um with certain people right now they're
super busy in life they're super [ __ ]
focused on their family and uh providing
and uh for them and so on if I have the
ability to to send these seeds to
somebody and say listen you know you're
going to do through uh teacher culture
embryo embryology whatever they call it
salvation
then
when Nazi when those plants if these
seeds pop then I want you know a copy of
each cutting and if we're going to breed
and breed them open breed and send
[ __ ]
the sand red [ __ ] all the [ __ ] he
wants does he still want it
maybe he's you know but maybe at certain
times they might just say ah [ __ ] it you
know what that's yesteryears and now one
of the one of these uh old breeders said
that to me recently he's like ah you
know what Pete like the [ __ ] we're on
to such better things like that's old
history nobody cares about that anymore
yeah well
I do right because that's where I'm at
right I care a lot about the old Scentsy
stuff you know yeah oh hillbilly have
you ever hillbilly
um so again rumor has it I'm going to
say now magic carpet by hillbilly uh
Salmon Creek
um
his first name is Steve okay I wasn't
going to say his name but oh yeah I
thought you were trying to guess it I'm
like here
he's public with his name he's fine okay
well I don't even know where he's at
like he's California right oh god oh I
think he's he sounds like he's from
Kentucky but yeah okay well I thought he
came again rumor has it
um that he was one of the seed providers
of the first legal
marijuana Garden in Canada okay that was
in flinflan Manitoba in that old
um mine
right I forget Nemo I don't know why I
forget the name of it the company but
basically it was when Health Canada was
trying to set up the the failure of the
metal of the marijuana community so what
they were doing was they had
I just had tipped my tongue too they
were sod growers that got the license
and um
and again that's where people know
different please type in
um
they were only allowed to sell seeds
that were confiscated by the RCMP
and okay that's all they could grow
right so they knew where the seed was
coming from it wasn't supporting the
black market
um
and the guy that was growing it
was proved some crap shitty sitting on
his shelf for [ __ ] years and then
all of a sudden the pot started getting
better the guy had you know we saw
pictures of the gardens phenomenal
[ __ ] facility he had tons of money
millions of dollars he was in the most
secure it was more secure than our
[ __ ] National mint way in and one way
out and it was two kilometers below the
ground right it wasn't like you could
just [ __ ] drive a tank through his
car yeah through his door kind of [ __ ]
right and uh supposedly these seeds made
it in
through a back door and that's why the
guy's pot started uh
uh
um did it revolve around harijuana
no I don't even know what the strains
were back then okay that was what what
shmeep schmuck that's a good name for
him was uh was most known for was the
harijuana and train Iraq like he came
down I know he was in the medical scene
in California for a little bit and one
of our friends
again how I remember hearing that the
genetics came from California
to this guy called hillbilly genetics
and we're able to make their their way
into Flint lawn kind of okay yeah that
makes sense and you know if it was uh
again if somebody knows this uh Steve
guy if he's out there and uh has a
contact to him you know please let him
know because again those two strings
that I just mentioned
um
you know I bought them the history if he
wants them back you know
um he's more than welcome to whatever
[ __ ] seed or plant comes from these
genetics right like it's it's about
sharing
for me this box of seeds I have is for
sharing the genetics right so when we
get into certain things like
the berry berry right yeah yeah which is
these two pictures behind me my first my
first centerfold in High Times
um I got lots of these seats I love this
plant it's not stable by any stretch of
the imagination it's not bad but I would
say I mean it's probably like a uh
probably back cross
maybe three times two or three times so
it's not bad yeah again I wasn't a
breeder I was a seed producer kind of
thing so sometimes I might have a you
know a little bit
of a different intention and therefore I
wasn't going crazy like some of the
people I'm in Steve telling me that he
when he chose the male this resinous
blueberry male he was actually smoking
male flowers or or because of the uh
because it was a resin producing male
okay that's right his famous resin
producing blueberry male yeah right and
so I he was like yeah I've smoked I mean
made sense like I don't know what you'd
be smoking have you but whatever has
resin on it sure you know that way
you're going to get some of the
flavor some of the Terps are going to be
in that resin you know
so maybe that was uh
um
was uh a little bit more than I was
doing I was just saying wow this is
[ __ ] great pot
less [ __ ] I got a mail of it I got a
female of it left so I can do that I
really like this female I'm gonna
because I'm gonna grow it again I'm
gonna try to find a male that best
record reproduces represents the the mom
I'm gonna cross it back again right what
was in the berry berry no [ __ ] idea
no idea no idea no idea I just uh it
came for me when I came to me
um which a lot of genetics did because
we had a seed bank
we were the only ones
finally Canada yeah doing it right this
is before Mark was uh dark enemy was
selling anything
um
so it was a you know somebody came in
and said oh look you know try this stuff
it's awesome grow it out like holy [ __ ]
is that awesome you know same with the
force right Boris was another trade no
idea where it came from again I didn't
really care about the names names are
the least of my concern right I was
worried about what It produced and for
uh medicinal
and for well for medicinal bag like I
would say bag appeal but it had a hit
um a few
criterias for us right one we need it to
be medicinally uh useful two we needed
to yield so we can get people to grow it
for us because the deal we made with all
of our Growers is we get you a legal
license to grow a certain amount of
plants you keep fifty percent of the uh
the Harvest to to pay for everything and
the other 50 goes to the center yeah
right and the client that you're growing
for never pays a dime for [ __ ]
anything he gets all the pop for free
and you get a high yielding you know
great plant the center will take will
will will buy all the pot
but half of it comes to us at no cost
yeah kind of thing right so it kind of
it helps us pay our bills
and and keep to be a a not
not-for-profit Society we're not
non-profit but we're registered as a
not-for-profit society uh it was that
gold that triangle that I was trying to
create even with growth shops bringing
in local Grow shops saying
um if you give our medical Growers
discounts then we'll send you all our
medical Growers yeah and um you know the
Growers if you're going to sell just to
us you get a discount from the grow shop
and we're going to pay you fair value
and we'll take all the pot right so we
made and then the the client
never had to pay for pot
yeah that is pretty red yeah right so it
was it was a way to kind of
um
kind of get
everybody what they want and make sure
everybody's happy because if one person
in that uh triangle wasn't happy it
falls apart yep right so make sure that
everybody's happy and again that's what
I'm I'm I try to do all the time and
sometimes people get pissed off at me
for it but you know [ __ ] them kind of
thing welcome
um
okay so this says NYPD Boris but
underneath it it's
it says there's a DMP fillow so the
Philo taxi are you familiar that's a I
think that's I'm not sure if I'm
pronouncing it right Philo taxi follow
taxi yeah yeah right when relation
leaves instead of being two brackets it
has a third bracket yeah right so Theory
being
you're gonna get a third more pot off a
plan if it's going to be
triple bracket instead of a double
bracket kind of thing so anytime I saw
that I I got excited I was like oh
there's a file there let's
um less save it male female just so we
can use it to cross into some of our
genetics to see if we can we can
recreate that uh that and I think it's I
don't think we ever were able to
honestly I think it was we were chasing
a dream kind of thing because I don't
know
um if it's stress related or what cause
if it was a trait or if it was stress
related or anything I don't know what it
was I I thought it was a trait but it
was like one in
in my experience like one in 500
yeah probably at least one in 500 that
you would actually see it yeah kind of
thing it wasn't something that we saw
very often so when I did see it it was
fairly so like I would set these aside
[Music]
um
and it's it just says NY NYPD Boris but
the uh DMB was
um I don't know if I can say his name
he's not on the thing he's a super nice
guy yeah something Millennium bud no his
name is Dan Miller he's a [ __ ] oh
okay yeah yeah that's a famous strain
though Dan Miller bud
it can't be yeah it is I've heard of it
upstairs apartment kind of thing yeah no
I it's it's definitely like an old
strain list and stuff that's the only
thing I would have heard of it yeah okay
because this is a local kid here who I
just ran into not that long ago I I he's
in my book actually and uh short story
was he was one of the Growers for the
nation beef uh not uh LCS
and he was part of the what we say the
honor guard like he was Nation family
yeah and uh he just uh he came with a
cutting that on an ebb and flow table
just produced these big fat massive CR
encrusted uh colas is it so perfect sea
of green perfect for the you know the
the
um the gorilla back you know basement
Gardens that are all running ebb and
flow you know short sea of green type of
plants yeah and uh so we we just started
calling it The DMB because we named it
after him because he didn't know what it
was it was um a cutting that came from
him so when we saw it and I was like
well that's what we need for
um our
um you know a black market our Gardens
that we were trying to get uh as much
out of as little spot as possible kind
of doing the sea of green kind of thing
not worried about plant counts and [ __ ]
like that and DMB was was a strain right
even when I was growing one of my one of
my rooms which was just a bedroom in one
of my Apartments
when people came by I just told them
that was his initials that's my roommate
they weren't allowed in the room as I
got he locks the doors you know he's
away a lot kind of [ __ ] but yeah the Dan
Miller Bud was actually a garden but I
told people and he's a super [ __ ]
good guy he uh he left the nation a
little sour unfortunately but um
hopefully I resurrected that
relationship because he was just one of
those people that you know same thing if
these seeds get uh reproduced or get
saved he'd be the first one on the phone
saying hey dude
it's not the DMB but it has the DMV in
it so if we do an open pop uh
pollination there's a chance one of
those seeds is going to be your strain
and you can have as much as you want
kind of thing so I put them aside to
kind of be so this is something else
that came up when we would when I sent
you that and I don't know if you can
post the and I can send you a few more
actually the menu that we had back in
the Great Canadian Emporium so uh early
mid 90s to uh mid 90s okay which one
specifically because I could put them up
here yeah so basically any of the ones
but this one here has
um this is how we used to sell the seeds
right just a little well should say that
this is how we sold some of the seeds
and then they all just went into little
uh the gram vials yeah selling but so
this here is
uh an Afghani black domino
Scentsy skunk
right nice so we were growing the
the block dominant Scentsy skunk we
crossed Blacktown with so much [ __ ] we
bet loved
the nug uh we really love the
description that Scentsy put in their
catalog Andrew our uh our minister of uh
uh
uh he was our artist he's the one that
actually when you look at all the
artwork from hemp Nation had Emporium
days he's uh he's the artist
um yeah I I want to meet that guy I want
to use some of that art like modern
times that is awesome yeah
the NYPD like he did characters of all
of us right characters and I didn't have
dreads back then but I had
um I'd wear my hair in braided uh uh
pigtails I guess because anytime I went
out into the bush and I had to wear my
backpack I had super long hair so I
would braid on each side so it wouldn't
get stuck in the backpack yeah and uh so
he would he drew a picture of me
you know with my braids and it's the
release of the NYPD uh Cult of
administer of Agriculture Sunday
cannabis talks stuff like that but you
know you'll see I I did find a few of
these uh these Blends and again
these are
f1s these are we didn't breed these as
much as we wanted to uh spread the seed
but
that's it I just remember the uh that
sensu skunk
was huge for us back then you know what
was it like it was a it was like
it was you know how the super skunk has
that really pungent smell the uh skunk
one has that big Cola
um this this Scentsy seemed to have like
a little bit of the two where it was it
was
um it had the it had the smell but it
had the the structure and but didn't
have the weight didn't have the big fat
nugs where the dominant did so the
Domino you know being a really greasy
really
um
more singular even though we did I have
pictures of a super cropping uh plant
that we did of the Domino and the skunk
one how would you describe the smell of
your Dominic cut
it was uh it was pretty nasty very kind
of tarry kind of nice [ __ ] rubber
kind of smell so that more noxious end
yeah like it was it wasn't fruity by the
the least of it it was pretty [ __ ]
that sounds it was very sorry kind of
yeah it smelled like asphalt kind of
stuff kind of so but it also you know
when we super cropped it one plant would
give us
[ __ ] I think the one plant was like
three quarters of a pound inside
and four feet tall
right off the ground yeah that's nice
pictures of it but it was super cropped
and it probably vegged for
two months yeah I was bending and
breaking and the skunk one same thing
you know we weren't popping might have
topped once
but everything else was just [ __ ]
bent down yeah and and tied down and the
super do you call that low stress
training is that like a term for it
today I call it high stress State
training like yeah exactly yeah
and and and LST are totally different
yeah so what we were doing is that's why
I would call high stress because we were
breaking like we were twisting and
turning uh we weren't bending down we
were breaking the inside herd oh so you
were popping that's super cropping to me
is when you break the inside yeah yeah
and then it reforms and it makes like a
nut Palace yeah that's different that's
not I mean when we did the super
cropping article and now supercrockman
I'm not going to say take claim to it
because it was shown to me by two local
Growers yeah but when we did the article
in high times before solma did his super
cropping which was just a reproduction
of what my of what the the
um article of about me I guess would be
um it's you don't want that knuckle okay
the knuckle is a weak point right it's a
strength point but it's also a weak
point what you want is to have a knuckle
on top of a knuckle on top of a knuckle
so it the the the branch doesn't do this
doesn't do this right angle it does this
Bend right so it's just like it's a
knuckle here a knuckle like I don't know
if you have it there's a knuckle here a
knuckle here knuckle here knuckle here
because I'm bending and breaking and
then that plant [ __ ] like flattens
out
so just just so people that don't know
generally super cropping is you're like
breaking the inner herd yeah but you're
trying to leave like the outside
like that is unbroken so you're trying
you're not trying to snap it so the
outside breaks you're trying to snap it
so you get an inner break yeah but go
outside and then this is what Matt is
saying low stress training is basically
just bending it over and tying it
without any kind of breaking with that
yeah just like you just you're just
redirecting where the hormones go
because of height yeah yeah and you you
know people that tie my guy used to tie
two by fours to his plant tops and the
two by four would be you know six inches
off the ground when he was done because
he'd have eight branches tied to it and
the next day be three inches off the
ground and next maybe two inches off the
ground and then eventually it's sitting
on the ground right that's the low
stress
um we would still do that at certain
times but the theory that I came up with
why this worked
was because of this local kid that I met
uh through the guys that showed me the
super cropping technique and when he was
born his art his late he had a he was
grown in a deformity where his legs were
crossed inside his mother's womb and
when he was born he couldn't walk
obviously his legs were [ __ ] buckled
up his [ __ ] his uh soles of his feet
were pretty much turning upwards and for
the first so many years of his life
every year or six months or whatever
they would go in and they would break
the bone straighten it and then go and
break the bone and then straighten it
and then break the bone again so brutal
yeah it took his legs from being this
kind of bent in and every time it just
broke it open broke it open broke it
open straightened it straightened it
until he could walk yeah well
I don't know if you have a broken bone
can't break a bone in the same place
twice
it's physically impossible
right because you get such a calcium
buildup
on that so if we could bring if you
could break your arm
uh 20 times you can form your arm to be
whatever shape you want it to be right
so if you break it if you have your arm
and it's broken
where am I and then you break it and you
set it this way and then you set it this
way and then you set it this way your
forearm will be bent like that and
sturdy yeah you know
we did the same that's what we do it do
with the plant we were super cropping it
and at the very beginning you can't
Twist and Turn you have to just pinch
yeah you just go around it because it's
so soft tissue and you just slowly pinch
and you don't pinch in the same way on
the same side and same angle you rotate
you rotate yeah
until the whole plant is like this and
then the next day you're going to see
that nut that shoot pop up and it's
going to be sitting like this
right where it's going to be kind of
bent up and then eventually you know
that's going to be strong enough that
you can have your main Cola
two feet off the ground four feet or
three feet from the center of where your
plant is and not have to use any tomato
cages not have to use anything because
that that uh inside herd is one solid so
you know when you you harvest the plant
you cut it down you can see sometimes
that Center
um canal in the middle of a in the
middle of your branch sure well when we
were super cropping especially towards
the end of it when we were doing it with
the big moms it would take two people
we'd have one guy holding a broomstick
and the other guy [ __ ] push until you
hear that snap
come back we'd snap it the other way and
stuff like that right like
when you went to cut that plant down you
couldn't use [ __ ] scissors to cut the
[ __ ] branches off yeah there's a
[ __ ] saw because it was solid kind of
thing so we would uh so the block Domino
is great for that the skunk one was
great for that
um but I get you know what it was the
black dominant that was like the key
to it and uh
I know I do have pictures of this the
one group black dominant plant that this
kid grew and he's a mutual friend of
Shawnee kids and mine yeah we were
speaking about them last time uh till
we'll just call them till for now but um
um
he was an epileptic that didn't leave
his house very much so he was perfect
candidate to show this technique too
sure hey [ __ ] trained all these
plants and you know if he if he wanted
to you know if he had the focus he could
have created you know
two pounds off of three plants onto one
light kind of thing yeah but you could
it's super cropping is designed for
people like right now in Canada we can
have four plants yeah but if you have a
basement that has seven foot ceilings
four plants isn't going to give you very
much exactly yeah you know I know one
guy that has uh one plant per thousand
watt and each plant covers you know
probably a five foot by five foot space
I don't think he's growing anymore but
um you know was I don't know if he was
super cropping either but that's what
SuperCraft movies intend for that's why
um Kyle uh flew me to Amsterdam and had
me talk at the Cannabis Cup and that was
the my topic my topic was basically
super cropping and and why and how kind
of that's so wild yeah really early take
on it
um
oh here's your [ __ ] I can't you can't
feminine self-pollination so they're G8
so the golden Haze okay so that's my
strain and it just says self-pollinated
which to me means hermaphrodite yeah
yeah I would not want to grow this
[ __ ] plant yeah I totally grow them
yeah
I ain't scared of no [ __ ] hurts I'm
[ __ ] petrified of them right and then
all the gifts
this was the uh the skipper so Skipper
was uh hemp Nation Honor Guard passed
away from uh from uh pancreatic cancer
was a client at the center but he was
one of the guys that
when we when I say Honor Guard uh Chris
will kind of elaborate on this too if he
ever comes on the show
no matter what I had no matter where I
was these guys
were allowed to come into my store and
take whatever the [ __ ] they want off the
show behind the counter they could walk
in and say Pete I need [ __ ] 500 bucks
you know it's like if it's in the till
it's yours like it's you you don't pay
for you want a bong you come and you
take a bong you know you need weed I
give you weed yeah so Skipper was one of
the first if not the first Honor Guard
person yeah I I do that at my friend's
record store except that he doesn't like
that I do that yeah I try to just go in
and just take what I want it's pretty
cool yeah well these guys there's a few
people in this town
uh uh that have that anybody from hemp
Nation family yeah knew whether they
took advantage of or not if they walked
into organic traveler my head shop yeah
they take whatever the [ __ ] they want
like they built me
they are the foundations to
um
to
to what we are they they lay they're the
ones that kind of lay down to for us to
to bring to blaze this path that we're
on so
when again and this was probably when I
was being a little bit more protective
of my genetics but skip said Hey listen
you know like I wanna I wanna grow your
your
um your golden Haze in my backyard all
right he's like and I have this uh blue
skunk
and I have a male of it I want to cross
it and it's just like well I don't have
seeds of the golden Haze other than
self-pollinated
but I said you know what if you want to
do that you do it kind of thing and he
gave me
you know I probably gave you as many
suits as I wanted but I only have maybe
15 seeds left and I just call it the GHB
which is a unique name
indeed yeah indeed
again we're going back to like the early
mid 90s sure
having a moment in the sun then
I didn't in Canada I was just like
listen it's golden Haze crosses the blue
skunk so I'm calling it GHB yeah there
you go yeah
and it's a sativa dominant one right so
he had an Indica dominant one he had
steva he liked the sativa one I named
strain the skipper schema right because
his name was skip kind of thing so same
thing genetics that mean [ __ ] all the
some will mean [ __ ] all anybody but if
they grow these out if they find that
golden Haze
I guarantee you're gonna [ __ ] love it
just because of
what's in it and what like how it
produces what it does yeah because it
was that fruity sativa fast flowering
short fat plant which you just you don't
you don't care I wanted to I wanted to
interject something because anybody
anybody that was growing in the 90s you
just you just uh threw out like what I
would think is like a very common
you know it's like sort of uh sort of
viewpoint which is oh man this thing's
self-pollinated or it made some seeds
I'm not that interested in these because
this will screw up the rest of my stuff
because of how it was made yeah and
we've had a sea change in uh in in
whether that's acceptable most people
that started growing in the 90s that was
The View
was hermaphrodism was going to introduce
something weird
and then you know Matt is one of the
card carrying original members of gender
fluidity is good
and we should we should we should not
hate on this form of breeding yep maybe
I'm old school but chicks with dicks I'm
not a big Keen of chicks with dicks
with the times bro it's very it's you
know
I go to a party and I want to hang out
with chicks I don't want to [ __ ] be
surprised you just gotta suck it that's
what not so told me anyways
he's so mad you know but you know you
know in all seriousness you know Matt
Matt can tell you that he got a lot of
pushback and a lot of hate when he
started pushing feminized breeding at
first oh God because it was considered
to be a cheat code it was considered to
be weakening
messaging tools I was ruining genetics
it was it was scandalous behavior my
favorite my favorite was that I was
ruining what God intended to be natural
and I'd point out actually they started
out intersex so I think I'm putting them
back to normal
you know what I mean like yeah I didn't
see it and any of that I didn't get that
deep I basically said
you know when I'm growing and especially
in larger scale anything over a few
plants actually or with somebody with
especially my uh clients that don't know
what to look for where if a banana pops
out
then I got CD pot and I know that's
unpractical you know I'm not going to
proceeding yeah right so if I see that
scene like I said earlier I believe and
I honestly believe this to be true that
95 of what we grow are
Hermie to one to a certain percentage to
a certain degree yeah right where some
might be you just have to sneeze and it
[ __ ] shoots out a banana some that
you have to [ __ ] go as far as you
know colonial silver or gelberic acid or
something that you really have to
[ __ ] stress it to produce that flower
I know you said there's different ways
and methods now but in my old school
mentality
that's what I always thought I thought
they're producing feminized not female
feminized seeds and there's a big
difference between an all-female seed
pack
and a feminized feminized seeds means
you're not going to get a male it
doesn't say you're not going to get a
hermaphrodite it's I think it's a very
high likely that if you are going to
have any hiccups in your
Garden if you especially outdoors I
would never put a feminized seized
outdoor because it's so out of your
control or in somebody's Garden that is
not you know
um on top of everything and
knowledgeable where they can keep a
perfect environment and watering
schedule and temperature and and
um feed program all that kind of thing
where you any kind of stress it's going
to trigger it sooner to produce seed and
produce pollen that's going to give you
a self-pollinated plant or an alpha
breeding sure it's great for breeding
I'll give him that but not for me I
tried I tried my best over the past 15
years to completely destroy the term
feminized because I always thought it
was really really bad term I thought I
thought female seeds was a bad term I
thought reversed made the most sense
because you're reversing the sex on a
plant and that's describing the action
but what to expect it you shouldn't be
telling people what to expect because
there's absolutely every possibility
that a plant can be you know have female
chromosomes and pop up completely
looking male
and uh the way the legal Market Works
currently
um all the stuff that I've been involved
in that does any kind of large-scale
seed popping yeah it's all feminized
seed yeah because nobody wants to get
out there and be like I have so I'm
gonna have somewhere between 30 and 70
percent be males yeah so I'm gonna have
a crew spend weeks out there every every
day going and hacking down boys before
they throw pollen right yeah anyway
because some of them are gonna some of
them are gonna be
um fake you know I don't want to say
fake males but like uh even better for
it yeah even with even with feminized
populations and I've I've popped you
know some pretty large groups at this
point occasionally you'll get what looks
like a true male yeah like not a
hermaphrodite not not something with
male and female flowers but something
that actually looks like a true male
plant they do pop up right but that's
what I was getting at too where you know
and again this is with lack of knowledge
but
um where you have or what I believe to
have a
female plant and a male plant and when
you uh when you do the when you have a
hermaphrodite because we're dealing with
a mother and a father we're bringing
into two two chromosomes
there's a very there's a very Mo very
good life likelihood that we're going to
have both of them carry over
right and in cannabis especially being a
a seed bearing plant that will uh go
into the ability to self-pollinate to
continue its life throughout the season
or throughout
um and I think again why I think it's
written into Genesis into the Bible is
you know for this reason where it's one
of those unique plants that if it thinks
that oh [ __ ] you know there's only
females around we're not going to be
able to reproduce they're going to flip
one of those females to produce some
pollen and therefore have drop seed for
the following uh season kind of that's
what I think makes hermaphrodism so hard
and people get all angry about it where
I'm like okay so this plan has existed
for millions of years yeah and this was
a super successful like strategy for it
to be able to make seeds at times when
something might have happened right
right and then sometime in the 90s we
were like oh we don't want this anymore
so 30 30 years ago people were like you
know let's get away from this thousands
of years of selection right and when
everybody was was growing seeded weed
and you know all the Thai and all the
Colombian and all the Mexican and
everything else was fully seeded who
cares if there was hermaphrodites no
exactly I think you already you already
were getting flour full of seed yeah so
it really wasn't actually it came to is
this you know for people like myself
that started smoking pot in the
depending on memory it's either the late
70s 79 or 80 81.
um that we had to get the credit card
and the [ __ ] album cover out yeah
[ __ ] and pull out all that Seed where
the [ __ ] you think I got my seed to
start everything that I started with was
you know got a great bag of [ __ ] weed
didn't know where the [ __ ] came from
probably was compressed has seeds in it
I don't want I mean they I'm gonna grow
them they might finish they might not I
don't know right but we did breed a lot
of [ __ ] [ __ ] a lot of [ __ ] into this
plant we bred CBD out of the [ __ ]
plant pretty much right because we were
so full we went through the stage of
focusing so much on THC
focusing so much on just strong females
right that uh we we lost track of you
know the beauty of the versatility of
this plant well do you know what do you
know what CBD was before testing
it was just weeds that didn't work yeah
yeah it was hemp you know it wasn't like
we were like oh that is CBD in it you're
like oh this one doesn't get me high
well we're going to eliminate this one
this one doesn't work good it's gone I
have
um you know people ask me like oh what
was you know what's your favorite pot
and I was like you know what we used to
buy our pot on this on B15 which was a
Street in East Rockaway New York
and uh it was the five dollar
um
oh yeah some of our first catalogs yeah
which is remind me I think this strain
is on that too
but
people ask me like what is your favorite
uh some of your favorite pot and I was
like this brickweed that we got back in
like [ __ ] uh
uh 82-83 because it got me super high
didn't get me stoned got me super high
and I want I like that getting that
super high yeah so if you go back go
back to that uh so this is us you know
showing people how to germinate seeds so
on so if you know the go back one yeah
that one so if you look on there
I have
you might be able to see there's a
purple star
s right which I wouldn't be surprised if
we because you can see we did a lot of
the skunk one crosses there
right again in the G13
uh the Willies Wonder
purple star Hindu Kush so I have purple
star on this and I also have
the skunk one on there but what you'll
also notice is like when you get into
like the uh s50 s48 The Golden Boy The
Golden Boy was something that I
crossed a lot of stuff with because I
wanted that
um
um that quick I want I you know I love
the purple star it's short fast you know
um that silver haze Mexican sativa I
grew this one this Mexican sativa
Outdoors here along the uh along the
Cliffs of Lake Erie
I had this great Garden because you
could be you could hang it on the on the
beach or on the boat like be out on the
boat and you couldn't see the garden
because of the slope was
um away it sloped away from the the lake
so I grew these big huge massive sativas
I got a problem I don't give a [ __ ] I'm
not you know I go for fun
um especially there was I get to go to
the beach and hang out with chicks and
and so on and um
and then erosion came and it took down a
good section of the garden and then
you'd be cruising down like October into
November
down the coast and you'd look up and
there'd be these huge wall of [ __ ]
these sativa plants these Mexican sativa
plants that were just starting to flower
in like mid-november
right wow you're gonna finish but they
were these wall of cannabis that exposed
my entire Garden to to the world yeah
kind of thing but you know I like I want
that sativa this is again chasing that
B15 [ __ ] brickweed
they were again they were Mexican it was
all Mexican [ __ ] pot coming up to New
York back then you know the mystery mix
I love that yeah the mystery mix is just
a little bit of God knows what kind of
[ __ ] it would be like either we just
forgot or like there was extra seeds or
you know where we put them in packs of
six and we had three of these left over
throw them in the [ __ ] mystery seed
you know
the um so there was a lot of uh what is
that so yeah so these women get to our
limited supplies kind of stuff right so
um
we try to do like we tried to make this
a seed company that sold again it's it's
hard we sold seeds we didn't sell
genetics right we were trying to show
you
um how to grow and again when we came in
with
um uh overgrow the government
right so like yeah so Willie's
um and then back out there we go he's
Zippity Do so Zippity is another Skipper
strain The Bongo which is another strain
that kind of came out but I thought
is it is that the menu that has the um
uh
Humboldt County Indica skunk one
Northern Lights five by Humboldt County
Indica now again what's Humboldt County
indica
some guy [ __ ] you know was out in
Humboldt and [ __ ] grabbed a bag of
[ __ ] crazy Indica pot and brought
back the sea maybe you know was it
you're from that area did you ever hear
of somebody say oh this is a humble kind
of Indica that's oh I mean dude when I I
think I may have mentioned it on the
previous show or something but like on
dead tour one of the most common things
you'd ever hear was what kind of weed is
this and they'd be like oh it's Humboldt
County outdoor organic nugs yeah yeah
okay it was kind of it was like it was
like one of those catch phrases right
like oh it's that it's that Humboldt
County Indica it's that Humboldt County
outdoor it's that good good it's that
what you want
you know and who knows if it was but it
was just like that was the that was the
if you weren't from California that was
the famous place that good weed came
from
right see that's not that cartoon guy
there the marching seat that was the
overgrowth of government uh yeah I I
want I want to borrow this from this
artist I want to talk to him see if
he'll let us use it and this is awesome
because he's like like I said he's I
don't even think I sent you all of them
um
because I'm not sure exactly which ones
uh Chris sent me
but um like I said a lot of them that he
sent me
were um like just some of the purple
star stuff
the black dominant stuff
that's my dog
um
yeah I'll have to send you some more
because there's tons of stuff that he
sent me
um
that I think you have a lot of the the
stuff there
it is pretty cool with the seed the
angry seed with the Army and the bong
and and he's charging you know that's
it's a good it's a it's a good cannabis
image so I just sent you something else
on Signal I don't know if you can get it
but it has a again has some more of our
um
our version of
why nation was formed okay basically
what it was is I think we kind of you
know back in the Reagan days we had oh
no backstory to that Nixon coined that
War on Drugs right and they saw cannabis
as a [ __ ] uh schedule one [ __ ]
same as heroin cocaine drug
right it was well it was it was more
like
weed was people that used weed didn't
vote for Nixon right people that used
weed were minorities and anti-war
protesters and Dems and groups that they
had issues with at the time right so it
was a youthful club and that they could
use it to attack groups that didn't
affect them
well pretty much with um
with the uh the War on Drugs you know we
took it as
you know a war against us
right I suppose them so we formed hemp
Nation nation was formed and built in a
regiment that was militant in a sense
right so the marching seed right the one
uh artwork I just sent you is uh HB post
dreads uh in a tank you know that has a
bong as its um Cannon kind of thing yeah
and it's because we were there to fight
the battle right so I feel that way I
mean I think that uh that well one of
the things I almost thought about
mentioning it was that you know because
because you're a a citizen of both
places yeah right you've been able to
move back and forth right where a lot of
us get trapped on one side of the other
fighting the battle you know you get
wrapped up in something and they're like
oh no you can't come back here anymore
not you no you know
you stay oh yeah so that's one there so
see with the cannon right like we we
formed like I was Minister oh it shows
they are me on the left too as minister
of Agriculture right yeah oh my God
but I just wear tanked off and [ __ ] like
that but uh so I was the minister of
Agriculture and on Sundays I would have
um the little grow talks grow seminars
kind of thing and we would you know with
the mental panel there we'd show you
know how to set up a little Garden in
your closet stuff like that right so
yeah Sundays from one till five
yeah
um and it was the tank yeah and that's
the tank and that's us behind them right
like so he because Chris was ahead and
you can see the bong has the water in
the whole [ __ ] bit yeah it's so funny
you know and it that that's what I say
like the the coin overgrow the
government
um came from and there will be uh more
artwork that will actually show it
um
what the hell was Andrew saying so
he was like
minister of defense that was his thing
right so we had minister of knowledge
which was Sarah and she took care of the
library in the museum and then we had
minister of Labor which is Billy he took
care of the retail store our minister of
Agriculture I took care of the seeds and
minister of defense and that was Andrew
who was quite
angry here's the angriest of us all but
the way that the government was treating
us kind of thing and because of his
super [ __ ] Talent he put it to um
to drawings and if you walked into hemp
Nation back in the day one we had the
hemp Nation flag that's there right the
pot leaf the green pot leaf
right uh in the in the red uh red bars
like
um but then that was
probably like
20 feet by 40 feet in our front window
right so we like there like I'm getting
back to which we were
we were fighting the war on drugs and we
formed the nation and Chris Kristen have
a Ministry he was a grand Cola
um he was he was that he was the [ __ ]
the one that told us
kind of what we were doing and how did
yeah how to do it but what he wanted to
see done yeah you know
so uh getting back to scenes because I
know we were getting pretty long on our
time
I found my chemo seats oh awesome and
now
they're in this little [ __ ] container
and it's just written chemo and there's
um
there's how many seasons there's like
five seeds and they're little tiny
[ __ ] seats yeah
which I think is the uh UBC because the
the
Ottawa cut
which
you know I thought the chemo came from I
I believe 100 I was wrong or we were
wrong when we thought that
um wasn't really chemo but it was a
chemo that we knew yeah and it was
better than the [ __ ] chemo
man it was a [ __ ] crazy strong fat
nasty [ __ ] plant nug
where the UBC chemo was very quaint and
pink and floral like it was it didn't
have that same Rusty [ __ ] greasy
smell yeah but uh that's a good way to
describe something rusty yeah it didn't
know like it was nice it was like a I
don't even know it's like you would get
hit with a [ __ ] metal pipe kind of
high it was [ __ ] crazy strong kind of
stuff so now this is the other thing you
guys know the history on gelato right
yeah okay I came across seeds
that I can't even but I'm pretty sure
and it's hard you won't be able to see
it I don't think but I swear it says
gelato
now these seeds are from
the 90s this CPAC box was from the 90s
they wouldn't be related you know
probably just a similar name yeah if
again this is where I was kind of
getting at before where
why is it called gelato well a guy grew
a [ __ ] plant a seed
Tate smoked it [ __ ] tastes like gelato
yeah gelato yeah so maybe that's what it
is I don't know
um but again where did gelato come from
how was it made
[ __ ] like that uh go through quickly
again the nebula uh oh yeah yeah that's
cool because I really like Luke and him
and I get along quite well I'd probably
get along best with Luke out of all the
uh
um
see people there Aryan whose name I
don't even know if I'm pronouncing
properly because some comb origin but um
I always call them Ari he's never
corrected me I think that's right Ariane
yeah Aryan my New York accent doesn't
let me say certain words certain ways
yeah can't say cauliflower yeah reason
um
I really like him I really like Luke as
a person so I love I love his genetics
okay I've heard that a lot too about him
that people really do like him and then
the Homegrown fantasies the blue haze
that's cool yeah so now so with the the
blue haze here
these seeds in here are not the
seeds from the pack gotcha these seeds
in this pack are from when we grew out
the the blue haze
and we picked a male and a female
to pollinate my golden Haze that we said
before the skipper yeah well we captive
uh we kept we chose one of the females
and read our own blue haze yeah so it's
not going to be the exact it's not their
seed but it's a seed that we use to make
their seeds so gotcha being uh maybe not
an open population where we used all the
males and all the females we did choose
a female I'm sorry we choose we put more
thought into the male than we did the
female we chose the best female but we
were looking for that male that I would
want to grow across with the golden or
skip one and it crosses the golden Haze
um and then we get it so what time is
that oh so then we get into like
um oh that's new too
um
uh so the the
skunk one nice from Scentsy again going
back to that age yep
um and then
we on that last catalog you'll see that
we we carry the skunk one so these are
one seeds that I made
using the skunk one seeds from Amsterdam
again
breeding for seed production not for uh
genetic uh sure and then we did
the the pure skunk
okay Earth appear from Flying Dutchman
yeah so same thing so did it did it do
what we wanted
um
because I keep calling him Eddie I don't
know who's Flying Dutchman Eddie it is
Eddie okay so okay 100 he was again
wanted from what I'm told one of the
original skunk
uh
uh holders let's say in sellers over
there yeah but so he was one that had
like let's say the oldest lineage in
Amsterdam for the skunk one
um I was hanging out with one of his
staff
in 90
what did I speak to I think it was
90 99
it was 99.
um guys hanging out with chick again
um and I know that word Gigolo came up
in some sort of host someplace right
that
um Karen from the Amsterdam hired me as
a gigolo yeah something about that right
and it's true I mean I [ __ ] Khmer has
pictures of me wearing a pink [ __ ]
thong what a badass yeah well I wore it
I mean I [ __ ] live yeah that's
awesome I was working with and I was
like she's like you're paying for me to
be here
um I kind of know why because the years
before I would go around and [ __ ]
pick up all the [ __ ] cutest [ __ ]
pot girls from usually all the booths
other Seasons hence why Tony from sag
probably doesn't like me very much if he
even remembers this but
um
but she sold all female apparel because
she had sativa sisters uh bed and
breakfast in Vancouver right so it was
an animus related Airbnb for before
their airbnbs and
um and she had the amphi MC to seed uh
seed company so I was like well I can't
wear any of the shirts or anything I was
like [ __ ] it you know what I'll wear a
pink thong under my pants right I wasn't
walking around in [ __ ] the cup with a
pink thong and you know when it came
time so for photos you know I'd hike the
thong up a little bit and pull my hands
up a little bit so you could see it and
and it's got to be a little bit sexy
yeah listen the girls liked it dude
whatever works you know I was like oh
[ __ ] yeah it worked dude I was getting
[ __ ] God knows everything
lucky I didn't come back with something
more than seeds from that trip but uh
you know oh just talking about come here
I just found uh
right so again one of the like I used to
sell his seat for for him as well
um I don't think I did much I thought
you know
um this is totally random but I saw
earlier on your Seed Catalog yeah that
you were offering that you guys it looks
like you guys did like some like early
Pearl and some other like reproductions
of those yeah yeah do you have any of
that stuff left I don't I didn't see any
of that so far in my uh my Runnings
um
I did find the remember we were talking
about the green Spirit yeah right so I
found that we did a blueberry green
Spirit kind of seed back then
um green Spirit was Big Bud skunk one
Matt is that what it was yeah I think so
yeah right yeah it sounds familiar uh
big bud skunk one I think I think it was
based I think it was that big skunk that
Neville had and then it went and then I
think you were talking about it earlier
I think big skunk turned into Scentsy
skunk
yes and then I think since and then it
needed another rebranding and so it
became green Spirit you know right I
knew the rebranding part of it where the
name came from
um but you know again
names or names to a certain degree but
the Early Girl early Pearl anything that
said early in it we liked we wanted sure
so when people were coming back if we
knew people were going to Amsterdam like
dude pick up the early Pearl pick up the
Early Girl pick up [ __ ] anything that
they say finishes in you know under 50
or 50 55 days kind of thing we need that
for our outdoor right we need for our
indoor too because we wanted we didn't
want to [ __ ] grow out
um 14-week [ __ ] trades but for me
hence why you'll see that you know the
Mexican sativas and all these other
[ __ ] up strains that you just can't
grow people don't grow unfortunately and
stopped growing
unfortunately like yeah where we've got
we've kind of bred these sativas out of
what we're you know now we're kicking
ourselves in the ass saying well we need
to start you know bringing them back in
because you people want to get high you
don't want to get Stoner it's not you
know there's there's a lot of people
even today there's famous people that
are like they have a hard cut off at
nine nine or ten weeks is like the upper
limit of how long most people will let
their strain go
right
um even 12 is rare for most people like
you tell someone it takes 12 weeks
they're not interested and then there's
some people who take it to 12 no matter
what no matter yeah no matter what
people have their sweet spots yeah they
do oh that's something else so again
another [ __ ] because yeah oh there
you go there you go the early Century
star kind of stuff right again unopened
um
and you know what's funny about that is
is that's one of the things that it got
released I think in 95 or 96 yeah yeah
and uh Luke will still not reveal what
he what made it yeah oh really no no
won't say a word you won't say a word
even though even though it was 27 years
ago or something like that or 28 years
ago and it's like so ancient at this
point he still won't be I took this and
this and made Scentsy stuff yeah nobody
could possibly remake it either I'm
gonna try I'll try
I'll send him a picture of that I'll
make sure I sell this number and I'm
going to ask him you know what he made
now that'd be cool he asked me not to
reveal it I'm not going to reveal it
yeah of course but
um I would like no I never even thought
about it I just like [ __ ] I like his
[ __ ] his eye I like what he's looking
for yeah I love this sidekick uh oh I
mean I'm not always trying to like throw
him under the bus or anything like oh
yeah but I like Simon from serious seeds
but he's never revealed what AK-47 or
Kali Mist has in it either yeah and
those things are just as old yeah it's
like come on dude it's been almost three
decades just tell us what it's not like
I can get how in the mid 90s they were
like I'm not going to tell you what's in
the secret sauce because I don't want
someone to steal it but now it's been so
long good luck finding the parents
anyway let's find the ingredients to
make the sauce no there's no way but but
it probably comes down to is they just
don't want to admit
who they got it from who got jobs for
what or just the fact that like oh this
came from Neville and this came from
this person or this came from like they
don't they just don't want to say
um well see I got some of his Belladonna
too say yeah that's cool oh yeah look at
that good score I mean it's something
again what they are and I thought that
I've sent that to uh to rent because I
didn't even know we made them fast fear
oh that's cool
these are this is what we we uh won the
well when when the college game in
second or third with it or something
like that placed yeah and it was [ __ ]
outdoor replaced with that's pretty cool
right and it wasn't because the pot was
that good I think it's because I was a
[ __ ] Gigolo [ __ ] that way and it was
honor the goddess here and I yeah this
is my story why I say Steve stole my
medal is because I hope he sees this and
he's gonna [ __ ] at me and I don't give
up he's going to laugh at it too because
he's good they they know it's true we
grew out the uh in the outdoor field
we grew out all those old Neville
strains again going by the story I've
been told
um
the Ortega was a very large part of it
um because it had the biggest uh uh
probably history yeah and appeal but
then there was the the fast fatty the
fast Spear and the Nightingale that were
these really tall gangly [ __ ] uh
sativas
well I like to tears I was in the field
every day working I wanted to smoke
sativas I didn't want to get stoned I
couldn't afford to get stoned I wanted
to get high
so when um when it came time to enter
the cup
all those guys
said nothing they want nothing to do
with the fast Spirit they wouldn't smoke
it didn't get them high I didn't want to
smoke I didn't smoke the Ortega because
it got me too stoned yeah I would spoke
to sativa and they're like yeah dude
this doesn't [ __ ] garbage garbage if
you want to take it take it but you know
so I took it because I wanted it yeah I
also knew that it was honor the goddess
the girls you know Hillary was part of
the uh the one of the judges one of her
Sidekicks I forget her name beautiful
little blonde girl was
um was uh was also asked to be a judge
you know and
I knew that's what they're after it was
organically grown
outdoor so full sun organically grown
sativa
that's Penny remover
you know so I we we won now did we win
because it was best part no we won
because there was [ __ ] these
Canadians were dumb enough to [ __ ]
fly
kilos of cannabis in their backpacks
into [ __ ] Amsterdam
we didn't have a coffee shop to sell it
out of
right so we had to sell stickers for 40
guilders and you got a free eighth of
pot yeah you know and it was a way like
we were getting in trouble because you
can't sell pot at the Cannabis Cup right
it was wherever it was being held I
forget what it's called but um you know
so we were finding you know buy a
sticker we sold these one-hitters at
Shockwave glass made for us and and um
and it was uh
it was
um
a type of pot that I knew was gonna
[ __ ]
be
loved by the judges and the story and so
I played up all that and that's I think
why
we won the cup it had nothing to do
really so much with the big in Gray pot
you know it didn't but it got the girls
dancing
and that's that's what was selling that
kind of thing so
um so yeah we talked about science so I
kept his chronic right because Simon
when I when I was saying earlier I I did
a little I was invited to talk at the
Cannabis Cup about Canadian cultivation
it was mainly supercropping and um
I don't know even what Simon was talking
about but him and I shared shared a
stage
and um and I think Steve was invited uh
when he he was at the cup so they asked
him to speak as well and um
it's when I picked up the Russian
because it was the AK-47 was this huge
deal but he
kept raving about the Russian and it was
fairly new and I I this is might have
been a few years old I'm not sure when
it came out but
I believe it came out in like the mid
late 90s and this would have been 99
yeah and uh he react and raved about it
so much that uh we brought backseat and
are you talking about the white russian
yeah
and I still growing and I still love it
it's it was one of our it's one of our
best sellers at the center you have an
old white russian cut yeah dude yeah
okay I think it's the [ __ ] the bomb
[ __ ] white russian is a AK-47 by
White Widow it's a it's a good line dude
it's so I mean the one thing I'll say
about Simon is that you know he
basically sold the same six strains for
like 20 years or something
and uh I think the chronic is terrible
but yeah the bubble gum and the AK-47
and the Kali Mist and the white russian
are all real like in the other era
they're all really nice do you know uh
the XXX
strength I I mean I know of it but I
I've never had any experience where is
it from because I always thought it was
from time because he has his triple X in
the [ __ ] in the logo logo right yeah
yeah I don't know where that can
collects for
I don't I don't have any not I don't
have any I don't have any like tidbits
on that one or whatever but oh man I can
say that that his his
AK-47 and his Cali mist and white
russian in the 90s yeah they were
phenomenal pot in that era yeah and they
were winning
they were really there he had really
good strengths the um
again that's how is your phone going to
die it is but yeah I'm gonna I'm gonna
be here until it just it's I'm like well
I'm gonna go through I only have a few
more stuff because you don't care about
Butch's beaver I don't know what it is
but it's from the state because it has a
Marlboro [ __ ] symbol on it
um
it says Nevada City California
hmm latitude
so well I've never even heard of Nevada
City no I don't know right did we just
lose him because of his home yeah yeah
his phone he's all right all right
um
so then the other things that we get to
is
um oh we were talking about uh with uh
Sol this like this is his
Plum Bud the plumber yeah I remember you
mentioned it yeah again I'm not sure
um
what it is I have my speculation but
after certain conversations it would be
something that Steve or red might be
able to
um explain more I have I thought it was
and I just thought it was a a Fino of a
certain cross that that Steve did that
you know where the sweet tooth came from
um
I'm not sure
um and then this one's called blonde
bastard
um
says uh stb M3 which
is
a strawberry blonde that you had
um in Switzerland and
I thought it was crossed with
the
uh
it's whatever the the mail from the uh
Louis
which um
I think this was the tooth so yeah I
think this was with
and that's where I think the SB stands
for so I think it's those sweet tooth
crossed with the strawberry strawberry
blonde and it says SD stb so sweet tooth
blonde yeah blonde or back cross but it
has the M3 and maybe maybe I can ask red
he might know because that would be my
right so it might be the because it if I
remember correctly
Steve had a a sweet tooth mail
okay thank you again this would be
better for Steve for Steve or for red
but they stuck in the corner behind a
fan and [ __ ] hit it and it just
flooded the whole room and and um that's
where you know they made the Louie and
they made a few other strains yeah at
least that's right and then sticking
with his stuff is uh the big Funk and
the Sweet Tooth number four but these
are these are males from him because
they're actually in uh the core class
how we used to mail them yeah before and
then the last but not least is the uh
blueberry now very cool where are the
these are coming from that same era just
judging by what they're packaged in yeah
so judging by the
uh big funk
right which is which is uh spice of life
early genetics
um
what blueberry was coming through then
and were though how closely DJ was
working with those guys at that time I
would imagine this is probably from that
era judging by you know it's um
they all came in the same envelope from
the same era kind of thing so it's not
I don't know if it's uh the 93 you know
but the 93 like I I just keep it is as a
um
as a mom yeah dude I think it would be
cool to do an open pollination with that
throw the 93 his mom cut in there and
yeah like I had some of his like apple
pie stuff some of the stuff he released
last year or the year before yeah he
doesn't even touch that anymore that was
someone else doing it all yeah I
understand that too I understand that uh
who was doing it but you know the fact
that
the uh
you know that what's in it the thing is
you know do they breed have they bred
out
What DJ was
looking for
because now they're breeding for what
they're looking for
it's it's just what I'll say is like
after going spinning tens of thousands
of dollars on blueberry and DJ Short
Stuff and hunting it very specific I
wanted a blueberry plant that looked
like blueberry purple that smelled like
blueberry jam you know just the whole
and I it didn't find that in anything
directly from DJ Short I found that from
hybrids of DJ Short Stuff or people that
worked his lines further that weren't
him and weren't his son but I found it
and I did find it eventually and other
stuff that had his work in it like you
couldn't find it without his work in it
I don't think
my B93 doesn't go uh blue doesn't go
purple but it has that
pint of blueberry not that fake
blueberry smell but yeah the blueberry
really rich [ __ ] blueberry smell yeah
um
and again Jay it comes from that era
which that that seed I wouldn't be
surprised if I had a few of those seeds
so I would maybe those seeds are from
that that early 90s yeah kind of thing
so but um
that's it for what I kind of pulled out
for you guys except for no I did a a
sweet tooth blueberry berry berry cross
because I really like that Berry that's
awesome I'm not going to get into all
the other stuff because a lot of this
stuff probably won't really
overly interest uh anybody
but it'll give you an idea of what my
goals were yeah my phone my uh my
thing's gonna die too unfortunately
want to sit at the table with the
syndicate check out our patreon and our
link tree or description below our merch
site is officially live we have all
sorts of shirts hoodies and goodies to
sort you out and shipping is super fast
and most importantly the quality is top
notch I've been saving old designs for
years for this purpose so please check
it out syndicatehere.com we also have an
underground Syndicate Discord where we
get together and solve old strain
history together daily it's an amazing
community of learning away from IG and
it's an amazing resource for old
catalogs and knowledge we hope you join
our Union of breeders and Growers come
check it out